Rym: It's Tuesday, May 19th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we go further.
Rym: We're talking about Rolling Stock.
Rym: A card game about stock and company trading.
Rym: Orthogonally adjacent to train games.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So traditionally, during normal times, GeekNights, like the beginning of the show, tends to turn into Bike Nights because we bike a lot in the summer.
Rym: And here we go again.
Rym: I was biking over the weekend.
Rym: I actually finally went up to that South County Trail and wanted to see sort of just riding on it.
Scott: It looked to me like you went on the Croton Aqueduct Trail and not on the County Trail.
Rym: I mean the Croton Aqueduct Trail is really short and we used that to get to the South County Trail.
Scott: No, I looked at your Strava and you went onto the Croton Aqueduct Trail, which is quite long and continues very far north.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Paved the whole way we were riding on.
Rym: There's only one tiny segment that was not paved.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, no, the County Trailway, I saw on your Strava you turned left, which is Croton Aqueduct.
Scott: If the County Trailway goes only north and more east, you made the sharp left turn.
Scott: But either way, yeah, there's all kinds of awesome trails up there.
Rym: Yeah, we followed it all the way north.
Rym: We were going to go all the way to Tarrytown, but then we just headed back because we didn't start early enough for having enough food on us.
Scott: Yeah, that's always the problem, right?
Scott: It's like I used to be able to just go all the way up to Brewster and take the train home and stop and eat food at places on the way and pee at places on the way, but now without all those places and, you know, train, questionable, right?
Rym: Well, just bring your own food and pee in the woods.
Scott: Yeah, but then the problem is it's still, even if I do that, let's say I get to Brewster, 60 miles north.
Rym: And bike 60 more miles back south?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Or just stick a tent in your panniers and just pop the tent up and sleep tonight.
Scott: There's nowhere to put a tent in Brewster, first of all.
Rym: Just put it on the trail, side of the road.
Scott: Yeah, it's not like that, side of the road.
Rym: Just put it in a Walmart parking lot.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: I doubt anyone will hassle you.
Scott: I don't even think there's a Walmart up there.
Scott: It's such a sad place.
Scott: But yeah, it's like getting home, even if I can physically get home, which I probably could, it's not, you know, it takes way long to get home, right?
Scott: It's like that's two days of biking almost in one day.
Rym: But the funniest thing is there's that section of the trail that's not finished yet, like it's not paved, so there's no way, like there's no good way to get across it.
Rym: Like there's a route around it and it's a fine road route.
Rym: Or there's a really direct way, which is a wooded trail.
Rym: We passed two road bikers who were clearly trying to get to the nice paved bike trail and clearly could not ride their road bikes on the non-paved dirt trail and were basically just walking their bikes along it until they got to the end about a mile and a half.
Scott: Right, well in Van Cortlandt Park, there is the old Putnam Trail, which as soon as you exit Van Cortlandt Park to the north becomes the county trailway, and then it's also the Croton whatever which sort of splits off to the left somewhere and, you know, the golf course is further north.
Scott: But yeah, the old Putnam Trail in the park is basically mud and they're currently repaving it, but obviously that repaving I think is now behind schedule.
Scott: Well the repaving is now-- Last I heard, it was not open yet.
Rym: Well it's not rideable.
Rym: It's basically they've put the packed rock and foundation down but they haven't paved anything, so it's worse than just mud or dirt.
Rym: It's not rideable at all.
Scott: Yeah, I've ridden through it on a road bike in the mud, which is already unpleasant.
Scott: But yeah, right now I would just take the route around the park and enter the--.
Scott: There's a spot you can enter the trailway this north of the park, like in Yonkers, at this cul-de-sac-y, dead-end-y kind of spot.
Rym: Yeah, there's a lot of entries to that whole trail system, just like at a random dead-end street in a suburban-looking town.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, once you start getting like further north, it's like the trail just goes straight through.
Scott: I think it's Yorktown Heights.
Scott: It basically goes right through the middle of the town, like right next to the playground and people's houses.
Scott: And then I think even further north, it's like the way it sort of goes is like you'll be in the woods and then you'll pop out and you'll have to like cross some street.
Scott: That's like some street.
Scott: It's like it's not necessarily all 100% in the woods, even though you're clearly on a trail.
Scott: It's like on one side of the street, it's like there's a stick in the middle.
Scott: It's like one of those kind of situations to prevent cars from getting in.
Rym: On the other side, just in the Bronx, there's a lot of-- And it's like Sprain Brook, there's all these good bikeways.
Rym: But even then, you'll go for a while and then it's all right.
Rym: You just have to brave running across the freeway really quick and then you can continue on the trail.
Scott: There's only one spot.
Scott: I know if you take the county trail way correctly that you have to run across the freeway-ish.
Rym: That's if you go more east like toward Pelham Bay Park and then you head north from there.
Scott: Oh, you're talking about over there.
Scott: I'm saying-- I'm talking about like in the Bronx-- On the county trail way, there's a point at which you're on Route 100 and you're supposed to be biking in the shoulder of Route 100, which is fine, right?
Scott: It's not a super much used highway, but it is definitely a highway, right?
Scott: And there's one spot where you got to cross it.
Scott: And the way you cross it is sort of across--.
Scott: No, there's a crosswalk, kind of.
Scott: And then there's a ramp, so like you're standing on the edge of this highway, the ramp, and you're waiting.
Scott: And it's like you sort of look, and as long as no cars are coming around, you go for it.
Scott: And now you're on the opposite shoulder.
Scott: That's how you're supposed to use it.
Scott: So anyway, it's a little sketchy.
Rym: Tuesday, we talk about things other than biking.
Rym: We actually are doing stuff, so you got any news?
Rym: I got a ton.
Scott: There's a ton of news, but I sent you all the newses, and now I forget which ones we sent.
Rym: All right, what I'll start with is, obviously since cons are shutting down and everything's trouble, Evo 2020 is going to be Evo Online 2020.
Rym: Not Evo Online, but Evo.
Rym: Biting games.
Scott: Yeah, the fighting game, you know, effectively fighting game world championships, which I think is what Evo counts as now, basically.
Rym: Basically, this is like the Super Bowl World Series of fighting games.
Scott: Right, and every year they have the Evo tournament, and it includes many different fighting games.
Scott: And there's a different slate of fighting games every time.
Rym: And if you win any one of these tournaments, that's real.
Rym: You are a world champion, no one's going to dispute that.
Scott: No.
Scott: The thing is, this year, because it's going online, they had to remove some games that could not be played online, and they added some games that could be played online.
Scott: Of course, even the best fighting games, their online netcode, the latency matters a lot in a fighting game, down to the fractions of a second.
Scott: So there is some questionable things with regards to how legit is this.
Scott: Would the result have been the same if they played in person?
Scott: But the results are still fair, because everyone's playing online with the same conditions, as though some people may have better internet than others, and that's just sort of a shame.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time, that's very similar to if someone in lower tier sports has better equipment, better bike, better skis, that happens.
Scott: Yeah, maybe.
Rym: But yeah, so they've added a bunch of games, they've changed some stuff around, some stuff like Samurai Showdown, Soulcalibur 6, that's all in there.
Rym: But they added some open tournaments for games that were not originally going to be part of the lineup, Killer Instinct, Mortal Kombat 11, which I'm hearing good things about, I should try it.
Scott: Yeah, go ahead, do that.
Rym: I mean, it looks fun, people are liking it.
Rym: Skullgirls 2nd Encore, and Bems Fightin' Herds, the bootleg pony game that got shut down for copyright, and then Lauren Faust actually helped them change the character designs so they could still make the game, because the game was good.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But, in all our discussion, the thing we're beating around the bush, the buried lead, notice I didn't say anything about Smash Brothers.
Scott: No, so Smash Brothers, you know, is a pretty new Smash Brothers game out these days.
Rym: Yeah, I hear the community around Smash Brothers is very fervent, very dedicated, very serious.
Scott: Yeah, you don't say.
Scott: But anyway, the point is, Smash Brothers, right, online, everyone knows it sucks.
Rym: But it sucks for like ten different reasons.
Scott: No, it sucks for pretty much one reason, is that Nintendo Online sucks.
Rym: Yes, but the two reasons are, the netcode is bad, like it doesn't work, even if you get it to work and play online, like, lag is a weird problem, but secondarily...
Scott: That's just Nintendo Online sucks, okay, what else?
Rym: Well, no, I'm saying that the technology of Nintendo Online sucks, and independently of that, the interface and structure of Nintendo Online sucks, like how it works from the user experience, even if the netcode were perfect.
Rym: Really hard to like... I just read, there's a big article talking about all the problems of doing online Smash tournaments, like it's really hard.
Scott: If there wasn't any weird, you know, netcode problems, you could hold a Smash tournament online.
Rym: Apparently people who try have said that it's actually a big problem, it's hard to get the right players to join the matches at the right times, things like notifications just don't go out, things are inconsistent.
Scott: Why are notifications, notifications should be sent outside the game?
Rym: Because they're trying to invite someone to, like, the match to make it happen, and it just doesn't work.
Rym: I've never tried to play it online, because I never had Nintendo Online, nor would I ever, ever play Smash Brothers online with anyone.
Scott: No, I would not play Smash Brothers online, but yeah, I'm pretty sure that all those problems are just under the umbrella of Nintendo Online sucks.
Scott: You have to pay $20 a year for it, or in our case, cheat and get a family plan, and get a ton of people into it to pay way less than, because it's not worth even really that much money at all.
Rym: In fact, once the Animal Crossing train dies down, I'd probably stop even paying for the family plan, because that's literally the only gain.
Scott: You didn't even pay me for the family plan.
Rym: Oh yeah, I guess I should.
Scott: But you get, you know, you do get your Tetris 99, you should try that out.
Scott: And you get some NES and SNES games you can play.
Rym: Oh, you mean the SNES and NES games that I already have on a really good emulator?
Scott: You do, but you can play them on the Switch.
Rym: Oh yeah, maybe if I had to go somewhere and needed to play that, and I didn't have access to my laptop, or I couldn't even go anywhere.
Scott: Yeah, you can play Super Metroid, like, on a plane, within your hands, without a laptop on the little table, you know, slightly more convenient.
Rym: Yeah?
Rym: Or I could just put my little laptop on there and have the emulator, and it'll just work.
Scott: Slightly, slightly less convenient.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm bringing my laptop anyway.
Scott: Bring a Switch anyway.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: But the funniest thing about all this is, the Smash Brothers fandom is pretty known for pretending Smash has zero problems, and being mad when people call those problems out.
Scott: You say this, but I haven't seen any people saying that.
Scott: Most of the people I've seen talking about this are pretty much just like, "Yes, we all know that Nintendo Online sucks, serves Nintendo
Scott: right.".
Rym: Did you look at the Twitter thread that followed from the announcement of Evo Online?
Rym: Because it starts with people being excited, like, "Yay, something's gonna
Rym: happen!".
Rym: And then there's this long string of people who are talking about their excitement for the Smash Tournament part of it.
Rym: People didn't notice for a while that Smash wasn't removed from the lineup, because Evo didn't make a big deal about removing Smash, nor will they give any official reason as to why they removed it.
Scott: They won't say, they're just- Why don't they make the official- why don't they do- come on, that's cowardly.
Scott: They specifically have not- They are specifically not including Smash because this internet sucks.
Rym: Yep, they pointedly- Did not say anything about it, and refused to say anything about it, at least as of, like, Dateline 6pm Eastern Time on the 19th.
Scott: Cowards boo.
Rym: Now, what's funny is that every single article about this on every single site I found says the same thing, which says, basically, they didn't say why, but we're assuming it's because of the terrible netcode, and the fact that Nintendo Online basically doesn't work.
Scott: Pretty much, yeah.
Rym: But, at the same time, there is a sort of broader problem that fighting games in particular, just by the nature of how they tend to be, have a lot more problems with netcode than, like, FPSs, because as precise as FPSs need to be, there's a lot of reasons why they're actually pretty tolerant of high lag and non-deterministic latency in a way that a lot of fighting games just really aren't.
Scott: No, because a fighting game is literally about speed, right?
Scott: Yup, frame timing.
Scott: And the games are fast, and even the lag introduced by, like, an LCD TV is a problem, and they have to often play with CRTs to get, you know, no lag and high enough frame rates.
Rym: And, like, pros are reacting to near-frame perfect timing cues to then make near-frame perfect inputs.
Scott: Games also, you know, demand frame perfect inputs.
Scott: It's like, "Oh, you want to block that attack?
Scott: You better push this button on this exact frame of this animation, otherwise it won't block, you'll get
Scott: hit.".
Scott: And the pros, they're the pros because they can do it, right?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: So then they need to be in a situation where, yeah, they can do it, but to do it, there has to be no lag, otherwise they're going to push the button too early or too late.
Rym: Yup, but I'm just wondering in the long run, as there's more and more online tournaments, like, I feel like the requirement of physical proximity for most people to consider fighting game tournaments to be legit will sort of put a ceiling on how big fighting games can be as esports compared to almost any other kind of game.
Scott: I think it actually, in a way, helps fighting games in that you aren't going to be, like, much like in the real world, right, sports-wise, right?
Scott: You think about fighting sports, right?
Scott: Boxing, right?
Scott: You know, you don't have boxing every day like you have baseball, right?
Scott: Boxing is, like, you know, at least disregarding its brutality and the fact that we should not have it anymore.
Scott: You know, boxing is like a big event.
Scott: that's rare, right?
Scott: It's like there's going to be a big fight, right?
Scott: Pay-per-view, big deal, right?
Scott: They're coming together, people are actually going to hurt each other, oh my god.
Scott: And even people who are fans of other sports, it's like, alright, it's time for the boxing, here it comes, once a few times a year, maybe, if you're lucky, right?
Scott: So, fighting games are not going to be the ones that the sport that's, like, there every day, like baseball, right?
Scott: The way that, like, your Overwatch might be, right?
Scott: The fighting game is going to be the EVO once a year, here we go, fighting game time, let's go, right?
Scott: And then you forget about it until it comes back.
Scott: Yep,
Rym: but at the same time, there's definitely a ceiling on the interest in things like boxing and MMA, like, there's a fervent community and most people don't care that much, or only care when they hear buzz, like it breaks into their mainstream media bubble and they hear buzz, like that Ronda Rousey fight, everyone's like, ooh, there's going to be this fight.
Scott: Yeah, sure, that's fine, but, you know, if you box, you can still make a ton of money, right?
Scott: So people will still do it.
Scott: People still do, I mean, yeah, but people still do the same.
Rym: It seems like it's on a long decline.
Scott: Oh, yeah, definitely, especially right now.
Scott: It's not being helped.
Rym: Yeah, you can't really distance that unless you're Charlie Chaplin.
Scott: Yeah, you can, it's called the marathon, that's distance boxing, run away.
Rym: That's my go-to fighting strategy.
Rym: So, a game that you may never have heard of called Crucible is launching tomorrow.
Scott: Right, so, people might not know the whole story here, so Amazon had been trying to get in the games business for quite a while, and there was a game they were working on called Breakaway, and I was following that game because the concept of the game seemed really cool.
Scott: What it was was a game designed to be an esport, which was some sort of combination of, like, it was actually a ball and, like, some MOBA-ish actiony gaming going on, right?
Scott: So, you'd be fighting the other people, but really, you'd be trying to get the ball to the other end.
Scott: And, you know, it seemed like the concept was good, but the game never launched.
Scott: It was, like, an alpha or something that I didn't get into, and then that was sort of it.
Scott: Or maybe I did play, like, once in the alpha, and then whatever, anyway.
Rym: Yeah, I kind of just ignored it, and every now and then you'd mention, like, that it existed, and I'd just promptly forget.
Scott: It was unique and an interesting concept, but it didn't happen.
Scott: I actually met someone at MAGFest who really wanted to tell me what kind of a fiasco it was.
Rym: Oh, yeah!
Rym: We gotta talk to that guy!
Scott: They were close to it, or they worked on it or something, but yeah, so that was a thing.
Scott: Amazon now is trying again.
Scott: They are publishing this game called Crucible.
Scott: The developer is someone else.
Scott: The game's just on Steam.
Scott: It'll be free to play starting tomorrow at May 20th, 2020.
Scott: So, for most of you, that's now.
Scott: I imagine, you know, the live watchers, not so much, right?
Scott: But this game is actually another idea that I did have conceptually.
Scott: And since it's free to play, I'll give it a shot.
Scott: Worst case, I delete it immediately, right?
Scott: No big deal.
Scott: And it has a few different play modes, but the play mode that's most interesting is the obvious idea, I don't know why, I think only one company tried it before and didn't succeed with it, which is to take a MOBA, but instead of having an RTS, it'd be an FPS, right?
Scott: So, you have a map, you go around, right?
Scott: There's NPCs coming at you.
Scott: You got NPCs going at the other team, right?
Scott: You shoot the NPCs and level up.
Scott: You capture points.
Scott: When you capture the points on the map for your team, they generate XP for your team, like a fountain, right?
Scott: You have a few abilities that, you know, regen on cooldowns, just like a MOBA, right?
Scott: You get higher XP, you unlock, you upgrade your characters, your team gets stronger, and eventually you take the whole map and destroy the other team's base or whatever it is, right?
Rym: I'm leery for the sole reason of, I've never found multiplayer team versus games where there's like local XP within a match to be worth it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, it just-
Rym: 'Cause it tends to be a snowball of, like, the game will usually just come down to an optimization of that XP advancement compared to the rate the other team is doing it, and that tends-
Scott: That is true, but, you know, you have the also, right, the situations where it's like you're fighting the other team directly, right?
Scott: You can do that immediately, right?
Scott: So, you know, it depends on how they do it, but the fact that it's an FPS and a MOBA I think is still- Well, it's a third person shooter.
Scott: Right, but that is still vastly more appealing than RTS controls of a little dude, like it's fucking- That is true.
Rym: I feel like if we're gonna like something that's like Dota adjacent, it would be something like this.
Scott: Right, I still think that these, you know, the MOBA concept, right, at its core is juicy fun.
Scott: It's just that every single implementation of it so far gets, like, these details wrong, at least in my opinion, right?
Rym: Not for- they're making tons of money, so not wrong and everything, but, you know- Like, they tend to focus on, like, the leveling up aspects, they tend to focus on, like, these background things.
Rym: I hate these- I hate the concept of fighting, like, random goons that are weak on one of the lanes, like in the forest, just to level up.
Scott: Like, it seems like- Well, you're probably gonna be doing that in this game, but actually that's only one of the modes, so it has some other modes that could be interesting.
Scott: I think there was a Battle Royale-ish mode that involved two player teams and, you know, shrinking circles.
Scott: So it seems like they're doing a little bit of a shotgun approach with this game, where they got their 10 characters or however many, and they're trying to not do what the other FP- they're not trying to be Counter Strike, like the Valorant is, they're not trying to do what Overwatch is doing, right?
Scott: They got different game modes.
Scott: they're gonna try.
Rym: And that's the part, actually, I'm excited about, because you can still trace all the popular multiplayer FPSs, trace from, like, five lineages, and all the popular esport games in this space between MOBAs, FPSs, everything, they still trace from, like, less than 10 lineages.
Scott: Right, so they're gonna- they're trying new game modes that we haven't seen before, necessarily, at least this- not, you know, I guess they're not 100% unique, but you get the idea.
Scott: So, free to play, I'll give this a shot tomorrow.
Rym: Yeah, I'll give it a shot, it doesn't look like it has any malware in it.
Scott: Eh, not yet.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So, speaking of- So you talked about EVO being cancelled.
Rym: Yep, oh yes, I guess we should talk about how Gen Con- Well, it's not cancelled, but yeah, right, so EVO is not cancelled, it's going online.
Rym: Gen Con can't go online, 'cause you're not- what are you gonna do, put everyone in TTS and Discord?
Scott: I think they're gonna try, but they're not gonna succeed.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: I think there's a sidebar there, or that, well, maybe we'll do another show on, 'cause I feel like we're gonna be in this boat for a while, but, uh, if you haven't noticed, a lot of conventions are trying to do online formats, and honestly, they're all kind of boring, or bad, or, like, not really worth engaging with, or, more importantly, not actually different from how cons already are.
Rym: Like, if you, like, most cons, when they try to go online, they're just like, "Okay, we'll have a panel track,
Rym: online.".
Rym: Like, yeah, PAX already streams a bunch of the panel rooms, MagFest puts all the panels up on YouTube, like, it's not like they're taking questions from the stream.
Rym: And in fact, they end up being worse, because as bad as the video recording is at most cons, the only thing worse than that is the average convention panelist attempting to record themselves at home.
Scott: Yeah, well, I mean, they're usually all streaming themselves to a central location, which is then putting together a multi-person stream.
Rym: Yep, which then runs into weird lag issues, they tend to have all the same, like, it's basically all the awkwardness of the kind of poorly run, poorly moderated panels that typify a lot of conventions, coupled with the extra awkwardness of talking lag and online streaming difficulties.
Scott: Well, I see what a lot, one technique a lot of people actually use is to run a Zoom call, right, or use whatever kind of app like that.
Rym: Just record that, basically.
Scott: Right, the person doing the streaming opens up OBS, and basically is capturing different parts of the screen and inserting those into the OBS in different sections.
Scott: So it's like, yeah, it's actually Zoom, and they're just inserting each of the squares into their streaming layout, right?
Scott: So you don't realize it's Zoom, or whatever other app they're using, Google Meet or whatever.
Scott: So that's how they do.
Rym: But yeah, it's interesting that basically no one's been able to come up with a format that works, because there already is an online convention format, and people just don't engage with it that much.
Scott: No.
Scott: But yeah, so that convention is not happening.
Scott: The Essen spiel is not happening.
Scott: They're trying to try to do something digital as well.
Scott: Every convention that's cancelled is trying to do something digital, right?
Rym: The Animicons are the worst hit, because almost any content any panelist would have in an Animicon is going to get copyrighted immediately.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Annacy, the French animation film festival, is going online.
Scott: This is not Tuesday News, but whatever.
Scott: They're charging, I think, the equivalent of, what, $15?
Scott: So you buy a digital ticket, and then you can watch the film festival films online on their site between times and dates.
Scott: And this is only interesting news for nerds, because it includes that C.G.
Scott: Lupin movie.
Scott: We don't know yet if it includes English subtitles.
Scott: But we do know someone made a little Twitter thread telling you how to navigate and get signed up, because it's all in French.
Scott: But yeah, whatever convention it is that you're interested in, it's pretty much just, if it hasn't been cancelled or we didn't mention it's cancelled, pretend it is.
Rym: I mean, considering that Gen Con is in the beginning of August, pretty sure that there's no PAX West at this point, because PAX West is not that long after that.
Rym: Also, PAX West still, by now, on a normal year, we'd have already submitted our panels, we'd already have a hotel somewhere, we'd probably already have our flights booked, and since none of that's happened yet, they're not even taking panel submissions, odds are pretty low.
Rym: there's going to be a PAX West, or really any PAX's this year, I think.
Rym: I still think PAX Australia has the best chance of happening.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: We got any news?
Rym: Yeah, so another news, speaking of malware.
Scott: How many news is we gonna do here?
Rym: Doom Eternal, the last news, I guess.
Rym: So Doom Eternal, I played a little bit of it, looked pretty fun, Scott beat it, just gonna review it, and an update came down.
Rym: Did we review it already or no?
Rym: No, because I didn't finish it.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: How far did you get?
Rym: A few hours in.
Rym: I ended up getting a refund from Steam, so I can't finish it now.
Rym: Because, so Doom Eternal came out, it was a pretty good game.
Rym: from what everyone has said, you seem to like it, everyone had good things to say about it.
Rym: And then, they added in an update, a Denuvo anti-cheat, the same kind of bullshit that makes Valorant an unplayable, dangerous game.
Scott: Right, so there used to be, it used to be.
Scott: the problem was a lot of these games would include these DRM packages.
Rym: Ubisoft would do that, I remember.
Scott: I think Denuvo actually even made one of them, I don't remember.
Rym: Are you surprised?
Scott: That's right, the name sounds familiar.
Scott: The point is, these DRM packages would be all sorts of, you know, in order to prevent you from pirating the game, they would take elevated privileges on your computer and do shady biz to make sure you weren't pirating the game.
Scott: Because otherwise, you know, you have administrator access over your own computer, you could obviously fool any program running with a lower privilege.
Scott: So it's hard to make a DRM that's not running at an elevated privilege level, which also means there's any security vulnerabilities or shady biz, it might, I don't know, spy on your keyboard, right?
Scott: Because it has such elevated privileges on your computer.
Scott: So, anti-cheat software runs into the same problem, right, in order to make sure that you're not cheating, right, because I could run a cheat program at elevated privileges that could manipulate the game running at a regular privilege level.
Scott: The game can't know or do anything about that because that's how computers work and that's not going to change ever and it shouldn't.
Scott: So the result, there's a loud noise outside.
Rym: Uh oh, uh oh.
Scott: Yep, yep, anyway, the result is that, you know, you get a game like Doom Eternal that got some multiplayer, they don't want you cheating, and they include this anti-cheat package in there, and what do you know?
Scott: The anti-cheat package is basically malware, you can't trust it.
Rym: Yep, it runs at kernel level, we talked about this on a GeekNights episode a long time ago, we were talking about like ring zero and like what all that terminology means, but basically as mega god super admin access to your PC.
Scott: Yep, so yeah, I uninstalled, after I beat, I didn't even have to like find out this news and then uninstall, I basically uninstalled Doom Eternal after I beat it.
Scott: So, but yeah, Doom Eternal never got that update, but you know, usually what happens historically is that all of the programs out there that have the DRM, they eventually remove it from their game.
Rym: Yep, they might not necessarily remove it from your PC though.
Scott: Well no no no, they remove it from their game and there's an update.
Scott: because once the game is old enough and it's being sold at a low price, right, they're not making that much money off the game anymore, and I believe, not 100% sure, that the game developer/publisher still has to pay the DRM company for the license ongoing, right?
Scott: So there comes a point at which it's not worth it for them to pay for the DRM and their game anymore and that's why it gets removed from a lot of games somewhere down the line.
Scott: And then you'd save to install the game again because DRM's gone, or buy it at the stupor's Steam sale for five bucks.
Scott: Anti-cheat however, right, is gonna be interesting because, well, cheating doesn't go away, right, but there is a license fee, presuming that it's the same model, right?
Scott: So, is it gonna be like when Doom Eternal multiplayer is no longer popular and no one cares about it, they'll stop paying and then put out a release that doesn't have this in it?
Rym: I mean, we don't actually know if they're paying or not.
Scott: I'm just guessing, right?
Rym: Because it wouldn't be super shocking if this kernel-level stuff, they'd happily let you run it without any license fees because there's maybe other ways to monetize it in the future.
Scott: The point is, if you are playing Doom Eternal on PC, which is where you should play it if you're gonna play it, and it is a good game, you should take care to sandbox it, run it on a PC that you don't care about, uninstall the shit right away, et cetera, be aware.
Scott: I don't think there's a good way to sandbox it.
Scott: Try to play it with an old update.
Rym: Yeah, I think the only way to be safe was if you bought it and played it and are still playing it but did not let it update and never let it update again.
Scott: Yeah, see if you can prevent Steam from updating it and then play the game anyway, because as long as you don't want to do the online multiplayer, right, which I don't see any reason why you'd want to.
Rym: It looked like an okay mode.
Rym: Well, the funniest thing was multiple people said they didn't even know it had multiplayer, which was kind of funny.
Scott: I knew it had it because the other one had it, but it's like, who cares about it?
Scott: It's a single-player game first and foremost, right?
Scott: It's like, who gives a shit about the multiplayer?
Scott: Why did they even bother to include it?
Rym: Well, I mean, I feel like Doom is ripe for good multiplayer in general.
Scott: It is, but I feel like the reason, the only guess I can have, right, is that when you play the single-player, you unlock stuff like skins and things like that, but skins have no meaning in a single-player game where you can't see yourself, really, right?
Scott: So I feel like the multiplayer almost was serving the single-player.
Scott: It's like, yeah, here's the incentive to find secrets in the single-player that give you useless stuff like skins and badges or whatever, is to play this multiplayer we made.
Scott: To make you want the things, otherwise it's like, alright, I got skins, what are we doing for?
Rym: But the sad thing is, if you let it update, you wouldn't even know that this was added.
Rym: There's no notification or anything.
Rym: It just auto-deploys.
Scott: Yep, I mean, you should definitely keep in mind, all games once you install from Steam or anywhere else, any kind of Epic stores or whatever, you need to be aware of what other things those games are installing.
Scott: Sometimes it's just Visual C++ redistributable, which is fine.
Rym: Sometimes it's DirectX.
Scott: Yeah, DirectX, that's fine, right?
Scott: .net something, that's fine.
Scott: But sometimes it's de nouveau anti-cheat, and that's not fine.
Scott: I'm not saying you want to cheat either, right?
Scott: Cheating is also a problem.
Rym: Oh yeah, cheating has ruined a lot of games permanently.
Rym: Cheating just destroys an online game.
Scott: But how do you, there's this battle here, it's like, to stop cheating, right?
Scott: This anti-cheat, despite all its evil, does seem to be somewhat effective, right?
Rym: Well, you'd say that, but at the same time, other games don't have kernel-level cheat detection like Overwatch.
Scott: Those games have more cheating.
Rym: Overwatch does not have a cheating problem.
Rym: Like, no one, there are not good, verified reports of cheating, really.
Rym: People get caught and banned pretty quick.
Scott: Yeah, well, I also don't think that, you know, the Doom company or whatever is putting as much effort into community management and their multiplayer.
Scott: Because it's not a big multiplayer thing, it's just like a side story.
Rym: Yeah, they don't have like a squad.
Rym: that's like looking through reported data to figure out if someone's cheating.
Scott: There isn't a Doom multiplayer league with big followers and a whole thing going on.
Rym: But it is like, I just like, many of you might be too young to remember.
Rym: I remember as a kid, like, play a game of Quake 2, go to a random server, like half the people there are running aimbots.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Like, just straight up, every Counter-Strike game was full of hackers.
Rym: Like, I remember once I was playing Counter-Strike and the match- It's definitely less bad than in those days.
Rym: Yep, the match started and a dude instantly appeared in our spawn, knifed us all to death at hyper speed, and then proceeded to start screaming in the voice chat until everyone disconnected.
Rym: Like, I just remember that moment.
Rym: You just have to know, like, the IP addresses of the good servers where no one cheats.
Rym: So yeah, the problem is, long term, like, you know, to do the GeekNights thing, let's go to the far future.
Rym: There is a certain kind of cheating that literally could not ever be stopped by any software solution.
Scott: Like Robot Arm?
Rym: Robot Arm.
Rym: You could have a computer that controls a robot arm on a mouse with a USB that pretends to be a keyboard.
Rym: Or even just, it's two USBs, one pretends to be a keyboard, one pretends to be a mouse, and has a camera pointed at the screen.
Rym: Or it just takes in an HDMI input and reads that visual field, and that's enough.
Rym: You could make an aimbot with that and that alone.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, this is a real thing.
Scott: I've definitely seen demos of it in the past.
Scott: They literally, they had a camera looking at the screen, and a robot arm on a mouse, and, you know, hitting the buttons on the keyboard, and it was playing quick, right?
Scott: So it's like, no software on the computer could detect that.
Scott: All that's happening is inputs on a mouse and keyboard that are, for the computer's perspective, are no different than inputs from a human being with their hands on a mouse and keyboard.
Scott: It's just, there's another computer that is looking at a screen and perfectly aiming a mouse and getting headshots.
Scott: So it's like, no anti-cheat software can stop that.
Scott: We need a different way.
Rym: I actually just now came up with a way that would kind of work.
Scott: The point is, the true path to stopping all cheating in online games must stop that kind of cheating.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Of course, then you get to the point of, what if it's just a human cyborg playing the game?
Rym: Is that cheating?
Scott: No, that's just, you have to play in a different league.
Rym: Ah, but how do you know?
Rym: How do you make some rando use a credit card to buy Doom as a cyborg or a regular human?
Scott: It's the same reason you have weight classes in boxing again, right?
Scott: It's the same deal.
Scott: If I got cyborg arm, I gotta play in the cyborg baseball league.
Scott: I can't play in the human baseball league.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: The one interesting thing is, the games that have a well-structured tournament scene, there's almost this like, cheating can't really do anything for you because if you get ranked too high, people pay attention to you and figure out you're cheating.
Rym: And it's like, now that you can show up to a tournament, you get invited to a tournament, you're fucked.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: But I did come up with a way, and then we can move on to the rest of the show, a way to solve the robot arm problem.
Rym: You require people who play, kind of like how certain team games, like, you almost need to require people to at least use the voice chat or at least listen in there.
Scott: There's too many problems with that.
Rym: Yeah, you could require that players have a webcam pointed at their hands to be able to play the game.
Scott: What if someone doesn't have hands?
Rym: Ah, then you have an, it has to be pointed at whatever adaptive device they're using to play the game.
Scott: What if they're using some like, mouth control thing because they're like, disabled?
Rym: Then you gotta have a webcam pointed at that.
Scott: What if they don't want to show you their face?
Rym: Well, then they can't play in the guaranteed no cheating league.
Scott: What if that's not very accessible now, is it?
Scott: It's an ableist league.
Scott: you got there.
Rym: Well, but is it?
Rym: you're requiring someone to prove that they're playing the game as opposed to a robot playing the game for them?
Scott: Uh huh.
Scott: Also, that video could also be fake too.
Rym: That would be hard to say.
Rym: That's the kind of thing that's difficult to fake because post hoc analysis could show if the keystrokes don't line up.
Rym: I mean, piano players freak out if they see like one wrong note watching a movie where someone happens to touch a piano for a second.
Scott: I could say that I'm using my, you know, my tongue controller because I'm a paraplegic when I'm not.
Scott: And someone off to the side has their hands on their mouse and keyboard because your league's not ableist, you're not going to kick me out.
Scott: Yeah, but then in a post hoc review, if somebody keeps you cheating- You're going to kick me out of your league because I don't have a webcam?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: You provide a webcam to anyone who can't afford one.
Scott: Buy this video game.
Scott: Get a free webcam.
Rym: Yeah, when you buy the video game, it comes with the webcam that prevents cheating.
Rym: The webcam also has a spike in it and the spike is deployed to finish and prevent future cheating once you are detected cheating.
Scott: Way too many problems with your plan here.
Rym: It's better than your plan of 100% server side, which also isn't really feasible for a lot of reasons.
Scott: I definitely think it is.
Scott: That doesn't stop robot arm, nor does it stop cyborg, nor does it- Oh no, it doesn't stop robot- no, it doesn't stop those.
Scott: Not at all.
Rym: I remember even at RIT we wouldn't let- we had a tournament at an anime club night.
Rym: We wouldn't let that one Rando use his control- he brought his own controller and he got really butter when we wouldn't let him use it because he might have programmed macros into it.
Rym: But anyway, it's time for Things of the Day.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: So, uh, most people- I don't know how to guess not most people, but a lot of people, when they get a pen in their hand and they're doodlin', there is some sort of, like, innate thing that are- I don't think it's, um, you know, biological.
Scott: I definitely think it's societal.
Rym: It's definitely cultural.
Scott: Right, cultural.
Scott: It's just this, like, subconscious, like, thing that will move your hand and draw a penis.
Scott: And I've seen this infect a lot of people.
Scott: And the thing is, it might not actually happen, but as soon as you, like, suggest to someone, draw a penis or don't draw a penis or phallus or- you mention anything phallic in any way while someone's drawing.
Scott: And, you know, you play, like, TKO or whatever, it's like penises come out.
Scott: You play draw a phallus, penises come out.
Scott: It just happens with any group you play with.
Scott: It's just a thing.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Uh, so someone made this website and it has machine learning that looks at what you're drawing.
Scott: It's just a big surface in your web browser that you can draw on.
Scott: And it used machine learning to look at what you're drawing and it comments on what you're drawing and it's quite shockingly good at recognizing what you're drawing.
Scott: As long as you don't draw anything too complicated.
Scott: Like, I drew a fire and it said, "Is that a
Scott: fireplace?"
Scott: And I drew some logs and it's like, "Oh, a
Scott: campfire.".
Scott: I drew a palm tree.
Scott: It knew a palm tree.
Scott: It knew a fish.
Scott: It knew a basketball.
Scott: It knew all kinds of stuff.
Scott: I drew a car, person.
Scott: It just knew what I was drawing and made funny comments on it in a portal, GLaDOS kind of way.
Scott: But the website is, I believe, don'tdrawpenis.com.
Scott: And you try to draw a penis on this website and see what happens.
Rym: So I was able to and I've replicated it a few times.
Rym: It was pretty easy to draw a penis as long as I drew it attached to a stick figure.
Scott: But yeah, it mostly detects if you're drawing a standalone penis.
Rym: I also enjoy playing it.
Rym: The voice reminds me of the Zombicon voice.
Rym: It's this calm voice that's just like, "Ah, you have drawn a
Rym: tooth.".
Rym: Some drawings may be artistic in nature.
Rym: It's a vaguely surreal, fun experience just to doodle around on this thing.
Rym: So my thing of the day, pretty brief.
Rym: You're probably all familiar with SimCity.
Rym: But that technology was used, and there's a whole article here.
Rym: I'm not going to explain the whole article.
Rym: You can just read this.
Rym: This person did all the research.
Rym: But it talks about how SimCity was used as sort of the blueprint to make serious games to train people in real-world things other than just building fake, simplistic cities.
Scott: Well, I imagine there were many jobs that basically amount to being a SimCity boss, mayor, right?
Rym: Well, the example is SimRefinery, of which very few screenshots remain, that was in this category of games that most people are not really familiar with, like serious games.
Rym: But these are games or entertainment software or interactive software of some kind that is used primarily to train people or to simulate things for various serious purposes.
Rym: This tradition goes back a long time.
Rym: War games were basically that.
Rym: And things like that still exist today.
Rym: Like the military, spy organizations, manufacturers, all sorts of organizations around the world will either make, get other people to make, or otherwise use games for these purposes.
Rym: And this is an article talking about the lineage of how SimCity ended up evolving into being one of these games when some of the people from the company split off to make serious games.
Rym: And sort of just a long history of that.
Rym: The craziest thing is, there are only like two images known on Earth of SimRefinery.
Rym: Like no one has the code, no one has an emulated version of it, like it's just gone as far as I can tell.
Rym: Granted, I didn't do any research, I'm purely basing it on this article, but this is just an interesting, fascinating space.
Rym: And this is also a space where there are jobs and like you could work in this place, like this kind of thing.
Rym: You could literally, your job could be game designer for the government or game designer for a giant tech company for internal games that will never be released to the outside world to solve very specific problems.
Scott: I don't know why you wouldn't release your game to the outside world, because if it's true that your game does train people to do the job, right?
Scott: Then you could, it's like if you need employees, which a lot of people do for specialized things, it's like you put that out there, someone might play it for fun.
Scott: And then you'll be like, "Oh, who's the best at this
Scott: game?".
Scott: And you'll be like, "Boom, you're
Scott: hired."
Scott: Right?
Rym: Well, some of them include specifically secret or sensitive information.
Scott: Maybe that shouldn't be in the training?
Rym: Well, I mean, what if you're trained in a spy?
Scott: Use fake secret information.
Rym: But what if the secret information is like operational tactics?
Rym: You're training someone in operational tactics that are not public for a reason.
Scott: Oh, okay, the tactics themselves are not public.
Rym: Yeah, like the thing, the techniques they're teaching you are themselves things that normal people are not supposed to know.
Scott: You could put the game out there with some other tactics that are fine to share.
Rym: Or you get into the situation like SWAT, Police Quest SWAT, which kind of was just a, "Here's how to be a SWAT officer.
Rym: This is how a SWAT team actually busts into your
Rym: house.".
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So this is just a cool article you should read.
Rym: You might learn a lot of things you didn't know about serious gaming.
Rym: And how to run an oil refinery?
Rym: Yeah, if we can find that game.
Rym: I want to see an AGDQ of Sim Refinery.
Rym: But the point that makes this the most interesting and is something that we kind of talk about a lot when we review games is the idea of your working or mental model of a system.
Rym: Like, when I play a board game, I develop a mental model or a series of heuristics around the game that help me understand it because I can't fully understand the state of the game.
Rym: And these games don't try to be a totally realistic simulation.
Rym: Their primary goal, at least in the types of serious games this article talks about, the primary goal is specifically to help the players start to build their own mental model of a complex system, if not necessarily getting to the point of them having a model that's accurate to the real system.
Rym: It'll get them further along or more ready to start to model the real system.
Rym: Like, you play SimCity, you start to build a mental model of how cities work, it's not that accurate, but it's not that inaccurate.
Rym: So yeah, I'm at a moment, we're stuck at home, doing vague livestreams as we can, trying to make content, gonna work on some stuff as we keep saying, join our forum.
Scott: Yeah, this weekend is like a big weekend for everyone.
Scott: So not only, I guess I don't have to work Friday, I don't know about other people.
Rym: I mean, yeah, most people have to work Friday.
Scott: In the United States, there's not gonna be work for a lot of people on Monday either.
Scott: So even though you're working at home, now you can be at home and not have to even think about whatever your job is if you're working from home.
Scott: If you're lucky enough.
Rym: I'm gonna do some more tests with that teleprompter and set up some more of my streaming infrastructure.
Scott: Right, so that gives us time to keep working on content making because you don't gotta do anything else.
Scott: All the time that I used to spend making a panel at a convention, it's like, well, maybe I'll just, you know, do something else.
Rym: Yeah, at some point I'm gonna start writing new panels and just videoing them, but that'll be in a little bit.
Rym: That'll be a lot easier when Scott and I can visit each other and then we can at least do a normal GeekNights panel together.
Scott: You could do a one-person panel.
Rym: Yeah, I got some one-person panels.
Rym: I'm actually thinking about doing something that I...
Scott: I'll do a one-person panel.
Scott: We'll see who's better.
Rym: Oh, we could definitely do that.
Rym: I mean, the only one I've ever done is I made that Five Nights at Freddy's one that I'm still pretty proud of and actually seems to still get a lot of views.
Scott: Oh, it's probably people just searching for Five Nights at Freddy's.
Rym: Yeah, but it was a video...
Scott: What's really hot right now?
Rym: Not train games.
Rym: That's just us.
Scott: Yeah, do the Valorant thing.
Scott: Do a Valorant panel.
Rym: I can't because I don't want to play it.
Scott: Well, you don't have to play it to do a panel.
Rym: Make a YouTube video.
Scott: If you just make a YouTube video, this is Valorant in the title.
Scott: It'll show up in a Valorant search and then say some stuff.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not into that.
Rym: It has to be a good panel.
Scott: I'm just saying.
Rym: I feel like what I want to do is that thing that I keep talking about a lot in panels, but I've never done a panel about it specifically.
Rym: I always talk about how Overwatch did a lot of what Team Fortress 2 did, but somehow Team Fortress 2 just collapsed and yet Overwatch succeeded in the game design of two very similar games and how these tiny, tiny differences between the two ended up having radical consequences for how they actually played.
Rym: That'd probably take a few weeks to get all the data together to put that up.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: We'll see what we do.
Rym: Anything else?
Rym: We're not really reading through the tale of Hanzo at the moment.
Scott: We are not reading the tale of Genji, which is our current book club book selection, though I might soon.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: Yeah, I mean, got a long weekend.
Scott: If it gets warmer, I'll bike, obviously, but if I'm not biking, I can't go to the beach, so I guess the beach sitting time will be replaced with more biking and sitting on the balcony reading, maybe?
Rym: I might bike up on those trails and then just stop and read for a while before I bike home.
Rym: I might just bike to the park and read a little bit.
Rym: We'll see.
Scott: We can go read in the middle of Yorktown, huh?
Rym: All right, so the games we've been reviewing lately are the games that we can easily play semi-asynchronously online.
Scott: Asynchronously games online are difficult because you need to get a lot of people together with technology and such and such.
Scott: Asynchronous games are on websites.
Scott: You take your turn whenever you've got time.
Scott: You can do it while you're at work, right?
Scott: Perfect game for stuck at home.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So we've been playing these train games and now we've moved on to a game that I've known about for a long time.
Rym: Like I kind of knew the deal.
Scott: I've heard the name of it before.
Rym: I'd seen it, but I just hadn't played it.
Rym: And because of all the things we said about 1889 and 1846 and 2038, those three reviews you can read or listen to.
Rym: There are transcriptions on YouTube, it looks like.
Rym: I didn't check how good they are, but I saw them there.
Rym: But you can check those reviews out.
Rym: But one of our complaints about the train games is around how we really like the stock stuff more so than the operating round is almost just like bookkeeping.
Rym: So now we played rolling stock where the bookkeeping and the so-called operating round is abstracted away to almost nothing.
Rym: And this game is basically just about the companies and the stock shenanigans.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So in most of the 18X train games, you start the game with some sort of auction for private companies.
Scott: And as the game goes on, those private companies are folded into public companies and they disappear.
Scott: That's the end of them.
Scott: Their purpose is that in a non-random game, because these games have no randomness whatsoever, to sort of start the game in an asymmetric way.
Scott: Not just the turn order already provides some asymmetry, but the fact that you have to start by auctioning off these unique private companies and everyone gets however many they end up buying.
Scott: It means that everyone starts in an asymmetric position, which sort of is then the spark that sets off the asymmetric non-random game.
Rym: Like the grain of sand inside of a pearl.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So in rolling stock, the way this game works is much like the 18XX games, it starts off with an auction for private companies, but that auction for private companies continues throughout the game.
Scott: There is a stack of private companies and they keep turning out new ones and each turn, one of the phases, the important phase where most of the game happens, is an auction for the currently available private companies between all of the players.
Scott: The players can use their money in this auction.
Scott: The money in your personal wallet.
Scott: The public corporations that absorb the private companies cannot bid in this auction.
Scott: So what happens is the flow of the game is people start with money, there's no public companies whatsoever, you participate in these auctions to acquire private companies.
Scott: The private companies spit out money, but much like these private companies, while also serving the purpose of the private companies in other 18XX games, they also serve as abstractions of the trains.
Rym: They have just an income and they have synergies with other companies, like every company will have synergies with some of the other companies.
Scott: Well, hold on, you're getting ahead of yourself here, right?
Scott: So the private companies spit out money and they rust, like the trains do.
Scott: Over time, the amount of money they spit out goes down.
Rym: And you have to get rid of them.
Rym: It'll give you income, like $3.
Rym: every turn, you just get $3, awesome, that's cool.
Rym: But then, as the game goes on, their income drops and drops and eventually becomes negative.
Scott: Yeah, and then you want to dump them.
Scott: Much like the trains in an 18XX game.
Scott: You get a train, the train that you bought, that a company bought generates revenues that turn into dividends, and then the train rusts and it goes out of the game and you have to buy new trains.
Scott: Also, in an 18XX game, you usually have tracks, right?
Scott: And what the tracks do is, you know, based on your position on the board, sort of determines how much money different trains can get, right?
Scott: Two companies might have the same trains, but one with a better board position might be spitting out more money because it's better aligned on the map.
Scott: Rolling stock, the private companies, again, abstract away the map because they have the synergies that Rym mentioned.
Rym: Yup, so Company A, if you own both Company A and Company B together in a corporation, they get like a little bonus to how much income they generate.
Scott: Right, so Company A, if you just hold onto it privately to yourself, will spit out X dollars.
Scott: Company B might also just spit out X dollars.
Scott: You hold onto them yourself and you just get the income that they spit out until they rust and you get rid of them.
Scott: No big deal, right?
Scott: If that was the whole game, then the whole game would just be bid for the best private companies, the end, and hold on, right?
Scott: There would be no public companies.
Rym: It would basically just be Pizarro or it would just be the auctions in Power Grid and nothing else.
Scott: Right, so what you do is you form public companies.
Scott: You can form them just whenever arbitrarily.
Scott: I kind of like that.
Scott: There's not like these specified ones like 18XX says.
Scott: You're just like, "Oh, I'll start the bear company.
Scott: I'll start the wheel
Scott: company."
Scott: Whatever, right?
Scott: And when you start those companies, you have a stock price, right?
Scott: Because now they're public.
Scott: People can buy shares.
Scott: You issue shares.
Scott: Money goes into the company.
Scott: It has its own wallet.
Scott: And the corporation, this public, can absorb the private corporations.
Scott: And in fact, to form one, you must start by putting a private company into it.
Scott: And then that income that the private company was spitting out now goes into the public company's wallet.
Scott: But if private companies that synergize with each other because they are abstractly in good positions together on the map that doesn't exist, right?
Scott: They go well together.
Scott: They will spit out bonus dollars that add up to a lot of dollars.
Rym: And the fiction is like these two railways interconnect with each other or like this airline would actually overlap with like these rail routes that complete.
Rym: But honestly, the theme literally does not matter at all.
Rym: These are just acronyms that synergize with other acronyms and they all have colors.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But if the right acronyms get into the same company together, more money comes out.
Scott: So by starting the public company, you can get more value from those synergies than just holding on to money fountains for your personal gain.
Rym: Now, starting a company like starting a corporation is pretty cool because it's a real IPO.
Rym: Like if you do it, you put the company that you own personally into this corporation, you pick one like bear or wheel.
Scott: It goes it goes public.
Rym: And the other way the IPO works is basically you get a share and the bank gets a share and you pay your money to the company for that share and the bank pays its money to the company for that share.
Rym: So by IPO, you basically get other investors in.
Rym: Now, the company has more cash than just what you put into it.
Rym: The whole point of an IPO is to raise capital.
Rym: It does.
Rym: It's a pretty elegant mechanism.
Rym: how it works.
Scott: And then what you can also do is, you know, you started this, you know, I took one of my companies that I won at auction.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I put it into the company.
Scott: It went public.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And in exchange, because I gave up a private company, it's no longer under my control.
Scott: I'm given a share in that company.
Scott: So I didn't really lose anything because that share has the value is the is the exchange I get for the company.
Rym: You also pick the price.
Rym: The company opens ad.
Rym: What is the starting price of this stock?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, if you're the president, yeah, you can issue more shares, all this stuff.
Scott: But the point is, is that now that the public company has one private company in it, the way it gets more private, because in order to have the synergies, it has to have more than one private company in it.
Scott: The way it gets more than one is that you can, if you're the president, right, you can decide which private companies that public company will buy with its money, just acquisition.
Rym: You can buy them from other corporations, or you can buy them from players, which means if you're the president of a company, you can buy a corporation that you, the player, own directly and just agree to it.
Rym: You just be corrupt as hell.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That is basically the flow of the game.
Scott: is you buy private companies in this auction, corporations, public ones cannot participate in the auction.
Scott: Therefore, you take your money, you buy companies, you put some of them into, they go public together, create synergy to create more value.
Scott: You then get money out, right?
Scott: This is the important part because you have to make sure because the only way you can participate in the auctions for more companies is if you personally have money in your wallet, right, owning shares, you can't use that money in an auction unless you sell the share and you can't sell your last share in a corporation.
Scott: You know, money that's in the company's wallet, right, because it got a, because the bank bought some shares, right, which gave the company money that you can't use that to buy companies at the auction.
Scott: You need money in your personal wallet to participate in the auction.
Scott: And then you buy companies in the auction and now, well, now you'd have enough money to buy another company, right?
Scott: You sell the company you bought to the corporation to get the money out of the corporate wallet into your personal wallet for the next auction.
Rym: There's only four ways to get money into your personal wallet.
Rym: Like there's not a lot of ways to get money back in this game.
Rym: You either own a company that's just spitting out revenue, which is not going to help you in the long run.
Scott: It helps some, depends.
Scott: If a company isn't really doing any synergy, then there's really, I don't see much reason to have it be in a public company.
Scott: You might as well just keep it on your own.
Rym: I guess unless you use the IPO to have more money than you could have otherwise to acquire something somewhere else.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: If you, you might want to use a low synergy company as the IPO company, but yeah, otherwise you're going to get the better value just by holding it, right?
Rym: You can, uh, like Scott said, you can buy companies, your corporation can buy companies from you or other players.
Rym: Corporations might buy a company from you if that's the one they want.
Scott: You can buy any which way.
Scott: Always.
Rym: Number three, every round, one of the things you do is decide how many dividends to issue.
Rym: So if you say the dividend is $4, the corporation pays $4 to each shareholder on record, which as you might recall, since the bank gets half the shares, unless other people have bought shares, you own a share and a bank owes the share.
Rym: If you do a dividend of $4, you get $4, the bank gets $4, the company loses $8.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The other way is obviously it's a stock game.
Scott: You could own shares that increase in value and then sell.
Rym: Now this is where the game is.
Scott: That is hard.
Rym: 18XX games have a abstracted and like it's so abstracted that it's realistic, but only in an obtuse way stock market.
Rym: Most games have just completely fake stock markets.
Rym: The stock market, the way stock prices work in this game is shockingly realistic.
Scott: It's pretty real.
Scott: It's not a hundred percent real because it's still an abstract.
Rym: But it's real close to the real world because basically there's a lot of parts.
Scott: There's a lot of parts of it that are very real.
Rym: I'll describe it vaguely because you can read the rules.
Rym: Like we'll link to a PDF.
Scott: If someone buys, there's a, there's a line of prices.
Scott: No two stocks can have the same price, right?
Scott: If someone buys a share, you go up to the next available price, which might mean jumping over other companies if they have the prices that are right in front of you, right?
Scott: When you sell a share, it moves down in price to the next available price.
Scott: However, if when you buy a share, right, it moves up, but you pay where it moved to.
Scott: And when you sell, you get the money of where it moved to.
Scott: You don't get the money of where it moved from.
Rym: Just like the real stock market, the price.
Rym: you see, if you look at what's the price of a stock, that's just the last price it traded at effectively.
Rym: So say star corporation is sitting at $28.
Rym: I want to buy a share.
Rym: The next price up on the chart is 31.
Rym: So it costs $31 to buy a share and then the price becomes 31.
Rym: Want to buy another share?
Rym: I got to pay 34 more dollars and the price moves up to 34.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Whereas in 18XX, it's like you can sell five shares all at once.
Scott: You get the list price for all those shares and then the price moves down a whole bunch.
Scott: Which I guess.
Rym: in olden times and shitty early stock markets, you could do stuff like that.
Rym: I sell Scott a share and then before Scott can tell anyone, I send a rider on a horse to sell Joey Jojo a share and I sell them both the shares at the same price.
Rym: And until they talk to each other, they have no idea they got screwed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But in 18XX, if the price of a company is 100 and you got four shares, you can sell all four and get $400.
Scott: In this game, it's like, no, you go around buying or selling one share at a time.
Scott: The only annoying rule is you can't sell the final share of a company if no one else has a share in it.
Scott: And then, yeah, you can just buy one, sell one, buy one, sell one.
Scott: But obviously if you buy, sell, buy, sell, you're just losing hemorrhage.
Scott: You're just hemorrhaging money.
Rym: Just like in the real stock market, the whole idea of a bid ask.
Rym: You know, the spread, there's a bid price and an ask price.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The price is 20.
Scott: I'll buy a share.
Scott: Well, you paid 21.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, now I'll sell that share.
Scott: Here's $20.
Scott: You lost a dollar.
Scott: Right?
Scott: The price is 20 again.
Scott: It's like, uh, so yeah, that's how that works.
Scott: So in order to make, in order to make money in stocks, you need to buy several shares of a company, issue more of them, then issue dividends over a long period of time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you have to make sure though, that the total value of the company itself, there's these little charts on each of the stock prices cards, right?
Scott: That's why they're unique.
Scott: And it will tell you if your company is this much value at the end of the turn, it will move up one, up two, down one or down two, right?
Scott: So the value, the total value of the company's holdings.
Rym: Which is its cash on hand plus the value of all the companies it owns.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The total value of what the company has going on determines relative to its stock price, whether it's undervalued or overvalued and that will move.
Rym: If your company has a ton of cash, but not a lot of companies, you can pay out big dividends and that stock price is going to tank because the investors know that you just have a bunch of cash and you're squandering it.
Scott: But if the company has like super low cash, right?
Scott: But has a ton of companies in it, then it's, first of all, those companies are generating probably a lot of synergistic income every turn that you can pay out in dividends.
Scott: But whether they do or not, those companies have value and thus the stock price will move according to that value to the right position regardless of where it started.
Scott: It'll slowly get to where it belongs relative to how much it's worth.
Scott: So if you can buy low and sell high, you can make money by selling shares at the right time as long as you were able to issue enough shares.
Scott: I made the mistake in the first game.
Scott: I opened a company.
Scott: It had two shares, one for me, one for the bank.
Scott: No one else bought a share.
Scott: I didn't issue more.
Scott: I couldn't buy more.
Scott: So my price went way up, but I could never sell my only share of the company, even though it was very valuable.
Rym: Even worse, if you issue...
Scott: And I couldn't make any money and I couldn't participate in the auction and then I was done.
Rym: If you issue new shares, that drives the price down and it dilutes your dividends.
Rym: So if I issue another share, now there's three shares.
Rym: Issue another share, now there's four shares.
Rym: Every time you issue a share, the bank gives the share price to the company.
Rym: like you issued another share.
Rym: It's out there.
Rym: But now if I pay a dividend, if there's five shares out there, a $1 dividend cost me $5 and if I only own one share, I only get one of those dollars.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the things about this game... There's more rules, but that's pretty much the game.
Scott: Well, the one key thing is that those private companies that come out in the auction are set up in a deck and they're set up into different sections of different colors.
Scott: And as you get to the... each color is like the next phase of the game, right?
Scott: As the colors are... you get through each set of colors.
Scott: And while each little set is shuffled, the colors are in a certain order.
Scott: So the companies just get more expensive as the game goes on.
Scott: The price keeps going up.
Scott: And it's huge.
Rym: Like early companies have an income of like $2 and it costs like $8.
Rym: The later companies have an income... like an income of like $12 and they cost like $60 to buy.
Scott: There are big, big jumps between the colors, right?
Scott: Big jumps.
Scott: So the result of that is that even if you're competing well with the other players in the game, right?
Scott: The game can beat you, right?
Scott: If you don't keep enough money in your wallet, if you don't have a way to get money into your personal coffers, and they get to like the next color, the prices on those companies in the next color might be so high that you have no conceivable, no possible route, literally no possible route to ever be able to buy one of those, even if nobody was competing with you in the auctions.
Scott: Because you just... it's just like, well, that costs $40 minimum.
Scott: There is no way for me to ever get $40 ever in this game.
Scott: I'm just done, right?
Scott: You have to play this game in such a way that you stay afloat, right?
Scott: It's like you're not fighting with the other people so much, right?
Scott: You're trying to tread water and after you successfully continue to tread water as the seas continuously rise and never stop rising, if you can continue treading water and stay alive in the game, then you can fight with the other people and try to dunk their heads up.
Scott: But, if I just, the first game I played, I just drowned on my own.
Rym: We both drowned.
Rym: Scott and I just, damn, we both hit a point where, well, there's literally no way for us to ever buy anything for the rest of this game.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, I think that the problems I see in this game, because it does have a lot of fun parts, right?
Scott: I enjoyed this game.
Rym: I would play it again.
Rym: I want to play it again.
Rym: However, I think it is deeply and fatally flawed in a number of ways that some people may be tolerant of, but I'm definitely not.
Rym: You know in Power Grid?
Rym: We talked about this a long time ago.
Rym: Power Grid's a really fun game, but once you get good at it, like really good at it, the game literally comes down to, I spent 100% of my dollars this turn.
Rym: Scott had one dollar left over that turn.
Rym: Scott's probably losing the game now because the game becomes very dollar tight.
Rym: Like, that's the level of granularity of success.
Rym: This game, but Power Grid is only like that at high tiers of play.
Rym: This game is like that no matter what.
Rym: If you are off by a dollar in the first auction, you might just mathematically be eliminated from the game.
Scott: Right, so I think that, you know, I'm not opposed to being eliminated from the game.
Scott: I know a lot of people hate player elimination.
Scott: Ah, I love it.
Scott: Right, I think this game, one of its flaws, it doesn't have player elimination.
Scott: It needs it, because you could be stuck in a game where you literally cannot affect the game anymore, but you are not officially eliminated.
Scott: And so, if you wanted to play to the official conclusion of the game, every game we've played of this, it has reached a point where we've just said, "Oh yes, obviously that player's won and there's nothing anyone could do about
Scott: it.".
Scott: Even though the game is far from officially over, and we just end it.
Scott: And it's like, well that's really, that's like you play Monopoly, right?
Scott: Monopoly has the exact same fatal flaw.
Scott: That's the worst thing.
Scott: that is wrong with Monopoly is also wrong with this game.
Scott: That is not a good thing.
Rym: Secondly, around, these games definitely are very spreadsheet heavy in that the game itself is very like mathematically pure and you can calculate things, but in some games
Scott: there's no randomness, except for the cards coming from the deck, what order will they appear, and you can see the future on those, so it's not very random.
Rym: But the trouble is, oh lord, total aside, I'll get back to this later, people are commenting on our train game reviews on BoardGameGeek.
Rym: I didn't know that was even a thing.
Rym: Interesting, I'm going to skim those comments in a minute.
Scott: Have fun with that.
Rym: Basically, some games, it's just analysis paralysis.
Rym: You can calculate so far, but doing a multi-turn full calculation of all player actions and possibilities will maybe give you a 1% higher chance of winning the game.
Rym: So it's not worth it socially.
Scott: People talk about analysis paralysis a lot, and the usual pattern you see is exactly what Rym described, is that if you play the game and you are good at it, you have some heuristics for what's a good move, what's a bad move, you can play pretty well.
Scott: You can get close to optimal play or maybe even optimal play by making a quick decision or just looking around at your options and sort of picking the best one with various methods.
Scott: But if you sit there and analyze every possible option down to the last dollar, down to every cent, down to the individual victory points, and say, aha, I thought of one that got me four victory points, it only took me 30 seconds to find that move, but I spent 10 minutes, I found a move that gets me five victory points.
Rym: Everdell has that problem to the nth degree.
Rym: You literally can just fucking sit there forever, and you might actually find a path through all those unique and semi-unique cards that gets you one more victory point than the other options.
Rym: But that is table stakes in this game.
Rym: You have to do that to even be able to engage with the game.
Scott: You have to do analysis, paralysis, math, math, math, math, math, spend a lot of time thinking, down to the last dollar, exactly how much am I going to spend in this auction, what's my turn order, what stock price will I open this company at, how many shares will I issue.
Scott: There's so many options of things you can do.
Scott: You have to explore each and every one of them, you know, spreadsheet all the way out before you make your move, because a failure to do so won't mean one less victory point or one less dollar.
Rym: It means your chance of victory literally crashes to zero that turn.
Rym: It crashes from 90% to 5% and then from 5% to 0% over two turns.
Rym: Right.
Scott: It means, well, that means you're not going to have enough, you know, the next turn, the cheapest private company available will cost a minimum of $21, and you'll have $20, so you can't even participate.
Scott: If you even had the, and that's the thing, if you had the $21, right, that could, you know, to buy that cheapest company, you might not buy it.
Scott: Someone else with like $30 might just buy it for $22.
Scott: But you matter.
Scott: You force them to buy that company.
Scott: They couldn't buy another company because that would mean letting you have that one, right?
Scott: If they chose a different company for say, you know, $27 that you couldn't even afford, they got that at face value, but now they're giving you the $21 at face value helping you out a ton.
Scott: So now they have to buy that $21 to keep you out of it, right?
Scott: And when they do so, they have to buy it for $22 above face value because to not bid $22 would mean you could get it in there for $21 based on the turn order possibly, right?
Scott: So having enough money to just clear that edge every single time requires a lot of analysis just to stay in the game.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But even then, even if, even once you get to that point, because the game is so dollar tight, what'll happen is even if you make a slight miscalculation, but otherwise you're staying ahead of that ledge, like you're playing the game well.
Rym: You've learned it, you're spread sheeting it, you're doing your math, you're not going to get screwed.
Rym: Like you can engage in the game meaningfully all the way to the end.
Rym: You're behind by $2 of net worth by the third round.
Rym: You'll never catch up.
Rym: There's no way to catch up because since the game is so locked tight, while there's this, like I could make a million corporations, corporations can sell stuff between each other.
Rym: There's all this stuff that can happen in the stock market.
Rym: I could like unload a company that sucks on someone and then like sell all the stock and do cool stuff.
Scott: Someone could be trying to start a new company and buy all the privates from their old company into the new one and you could try to buy that old company out before they're able to transfer and steal all the private companies.
Rym: They issue extra shares, but in practice, and I was looking around online and it's not just our games.
Rym: It seems like that's pretty common.
Rym: Very rarely do shenanigans like that happen because they can't often happen if the players are all actually playing well.
Rym: They seem to only happen in games of this where all the players are doing very badly or for whatever reason, some of the players are making very poor decisions.
Scott: Yes, if you, like we said, do all that analysis, you can basically protect yourself from any sort of shenanigans that could possibly happen.
Scott: There's no really like an attack someone can do that you can't defend against.
Scott: The only thing that someone can do in this game is to gang up on you with some sort of politics situation.
Scott: Some cooperations of people who are not in first place could unseat someone in first place.
Scott: Put their monies together in some way.
Scott: Just like someone who has been mathematically eliminated from the game early could do some king making in this game.
Scott: I like a king making, but I only like it personally when the king making happens and the person doing the king making still has a chance to win.
Rym: Yeah, I see where you're going with that.
Scott: They've chosen this political path through the game.
Scott: even though they could, they themselves could still win after following that path.
Scott: If somebody king makes and either a) sacrifices all their chance to win to do so or b) king makes after already having crossed the point where they could no longer win.
Scott: Like, "Well, I can't win this game.
Scott: I'm gonna put all my stuff in with Rym to make him win or to make Rym
Scott: lose.".
Scott: That just seems like a spoiler and it's like now you're not winning and losing based on your own merit.
Rym: If you're behind but you've played competently, you're not just derping around in the game, then holding back winners and just trying to keep the game going gives you some chance, some avenue to sneak a win in if everyone else stalemates.
Rym: There are still more plausible paths to victory than in games like this.
Rym: But there's also this problem that I see where there's all these shenanigans that seem really fun.
Rym: Like in 18 XX games, the most fun thing in the world to do is to fuck someone over and force them to buy a train or force someone to own a company they don't want to own.
Rym: But if the players are even remotely careful, you really can't pull that off.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: It only happens to people who are new at the game or don't know what's up.
Scott: Once I learned that, it took me quite a while to figure out how that worked.
Scott: But basically that doesn't happen to me anymore.
Scott: I'm like perfectly protected.
Rym: You can't throw a shitty company at me in 1889.
Rym: Like it just can't happen.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: I know how it works now and now it never happens and I can't do it to anyone else because they know better.
Rym: But then we get into a situation where I like the train game, but the most fun of the table is when the turn starts and someone says, "Oh shit, I see what's about to
Rym: happen.".
Rym: And then someone gets screwed by that, but you never see that happen when everyone's good.
Rym: Again, unless people are making mistakes.
Rym: So we have this broader problem of there are fun systems and levers in these games, much like Sellers of Catan where trading is really fun.
Rym: Where if you get good at the game, you'd never pull that lever again.
Rym: Like you know that lever is just poison.
Rym: There's no reason to ever touch it.
Scott: Well, it's like, you know, I think baseball actually is an example of a game that has a lot of the same things going on.
Scott: If you ever watch a Little League Baseball game, something that happens a lot in not the lowest level of Little League, which is just kids who aren't, but like the middle school kids who like could be really good high school players might be-
Rym: Like they're trying, but they can't hit home runs yet because they're tiny, tiny kids.
Scott: Well, they can in the little tiny field.
Scott: But the point is some things that you'll see happen, for example, are like successful steals of home, right?
Scott: Some things else that you'll see is that kids will get a walk, right?
Scott: So the pitcher will walk the batter.
Scott: The kid will run to first base, even though they just got walked.
Scott: And they'll just keep running to second, like without stopping.
Scott: And this will often fool a pitcher, right?
Scott: Who is not, you know, who's just a kid who isn't aware of that.
Rym: In high school, my go-to move was I would walk casually toward first when I got walked, and then I'd walk a little bit past it, and then I would just suddenly sprint to second and no one ever was able to stop me.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In Major League Baseball, you see that never.
Rym: You haven't seen stealing home in like, it's super, super rare, but it hasn't been common since- Like if a pickle happens in a professional baseball game, that is the highlight of the fucking month.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: It happens pretty rarely.
Scott: Pickles happen a little bit, but they're still pretty rare these days.
Rym: But even not that often, pickles are one of the most fun parts of baseball, but they really can't happen unless you make a mistake.
Scott: Right, so that's what I'm saying.
Scott: is that rolling stock, even if your players aren't pro, right?
Scott: Because the bar to just stay in.
Scott: the game is high, anyone who's not pro can't do anything in this game.
Scott: So as a result, you only get the game where everyone's pro and only boring stuff happens, right?
Scott: The exciting stuff.
Scott: I'm really curious, right?
Scott: I mean, I have tons of ideas on how to sort of take the core of these games to a different game.
Rym: Yeah, and if you didn't notice, we're playing a lot of these games lately for research for an idea we have.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm just thinking like, what if you just, instead of making the game money tight, right?
Scott: What if everyone started the game with like a fucking thousand dollars, right?
Scott: Just don't change anything else.
Scott: Just make everyone a fucking tycoon.
Scott: Like you're rich.
Scott: Money's not tight.
Scott: Alright, now bid on these companies, right?
Scott: It's like if you don't do, it doesn't matter how much money you start with as long as everyone starts the same.
Scott: And it's like, well, you can't just sit on your thousand dollars because if you want to win, you have to increase your money somehow.
Rym: But also it means now there's a lot more dynamics around issuing more shares and buying shares and fucking other people's shares over.
Scott: Everyone's rich.
Scott: You can't kick anyone out of the game because they're all fucking rich.
Scott: You just have to work the system to make more money than someone else.
Scott: Despite being more rich, right?
Scott: That you can't kick anyone out.
Scott: They're not going to go bankrupt.
Scott: They're a zillionaire.
Scott: Everyone's a zillionaire.
Scott: You're feuding tycoons.
Scott: But you still have to play the game because you still have to make, get to a thousand and one dollars somehow.
Scott: Like what did- You're not going to get it by sitting.
Scott: But instead- Unless you hope everyone else loses money and you'll just sit.
Rym: Which is what disappoints me the most is we can form all these companies, but there's almost never a reason to form more of them.
Scott: You're like, you can't- Later in the game there is, but there isn't a reason to form like a whole bunch.
Scott: It's like you could legally form like five companies right away, but like that won't do anything except make you lose.
Rym: And in fact, in the last game we played, I formed a big company that's actually doing really well late game.
Rym: Only because why not?
Rym: I mean, I was already guaranteed losing the game and it was just a system I could interact with.
Rym: Starcorp doesn't matter or mean anything to anyone.
Scott: The first game I played, I started the company and I followed the basic heuristic of trying to make a stock price go up.
Scott: So I did.
Scott: I got a company and it made its stock price go way, way up.
Scott: I was trying to roleplay a responsible corporate executive.
Rym: Now you got to roleplay a jerk.
Scott: And that absolutely did not work and I just got completely screwed.
Scott: So it's like the, not only do you have to spreadsheet the whole game to stay in it, but your basic, you know, real world heuristics of own a company and make the stock price go up.
Scott: That's good.
Scott: It's like, no, it's not, right?
Scott: You have to do, non-intuitive things are the way forward, right?
Rym: Of course, Chris points out in the chat that I kind of agree with.
Rym: If you started people with too much money in this game, I feel like never investing and never doing anything except maybe buying a couple of companies would actually be an optimal strategy because of the math.
Rym: Cause I remember this happened when I was a kid in middle school, this one random day, it was in like the eighth grade advanced math class and they busted out monopoly.
Rym: They made us break into groups and they were like, everyone play monopoly.
Rym: And, uh, the winner from each table will like get a lottery ticket to get a thing.
Rym: Like there was a prize, like there's a real prize that people wanted, like a serious prize.
Rym: I don't remember what the prize was.
Rym: It was like, it was, it was like the equivalent of like, don't have to do homework for a couple of weeks.
Rym: Like it was some big deal thing.
Rym: So everyone starts trying to play monopoly and at our table, I'm like, guys, monopoly sucks.
Rym: We don't want to play it.
Rym: Uh, let's show, and there was a secondary prize.
Rym: Here's the other piece.
Rym: The secondary prize was whatever player had the most money among all the winners would win some other prize in addition.
Rym: So I just said, let's all just agree that we never take any actions in this game.
Rym: There's a guaranteed five way tie for first.
Rym: And all we do is go around collecting the $200 from go over and over and over again.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: And uh, yeah, we made sure there was a five way tie at our table and we had an order of magnitude more money than anyone else.
Rym: And the prize was canceled.
Rym: Everything was called off and we all got in trouble.
Scott: Well, they should have thought about what they were doing.
Scott: I would have, I would, if I saw kids doing that, I would be like, you got you guys, I'm getting you five prizes.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That if I were a teacher, I would definitely reward the kids who were subversive in clever ways.
Scott: I mean, we could, that's, I think our show is over, but definitely there is, you know, they think one of the great injustices of that.
Scott: I think a lot of Pete nerds, especially right.
Scott: I've experienced in American school is adults punishing children for children being smarter.
Scott: It's like, you're there to learn.
Scott: And then they punish you for knowing more than adults do right.
Scott: A good adults will reward children who are smart, outsmart adults and say, good job.
Scott: As long as the kids didn't cause harm that much.
Rym: The reward could be like the teacher aside being like, yo kid, you don't have to do homework for the next two weeks.
Rym: Don't tell anyone that would have been enough.
Rym: I would have stopped causing trouble, but yeah, rolling stock.
Rym: If you want to play this game, rolling stock.net has an online implementation because the game is so abstract.
Rym: It's you don't need anything.
Rym: The fiction of this game is meeting.
Rym: No, no, no.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: You can read a PDF to get the complete, the sever as a few PDFs that are available to read the whole rules.
Scott: And then you can play online for free.
Scott: If you want to play this online for free, contact us and we'll play, I'll play with you.
Scott: Uh, well we can chat and we can talk to you and I'll give you tips based on my two or three plays of it.
Scott: But I think the game is only much like the 18XX games.
Rym: I like it, but I think it is fatally and deeply flawed in specific and profound ways.
Rym: While I enjoy it and it's interesting, it is more instructive than it is enjoyable.
Rym: Like I am learning things about game design playing these games.
Rym: I'm also seeing the flaws in them.
Rym: And I still feel like doing 18XX games and this, there is a game that can be made that is good in the traditional sense, not just good in the "I want to bang my head against the spreadsheet and see what happens" sense.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, I think that's because all these games have in common some core mechanics that do not exist at all in other genres of games.
Scott: Period.
Scott: Right?
Scott: And so if we can extract those and just fix all the stuff around them and get rid of the problems, then you can make a truly unique, amazing, popular game.
Rym: Which I still think comes down to, you can't actually be a tabletop game.
Rym: It needs to have primarily tabletop sensibility, but real-time markets or slightly more complex stock markets that don't have fiddly rules, like no two companies can be the same price at the same time.
Rym: That would go a long way toward making this better.
Scott: I think there are ways to do it, but anyway, let's go find something.
Rym: Yeah, I'm getting hungry.
Rym: So yeah, stay safe out there, enjoy some rolling stock.
Rym: If you guys want to play, we will play a game and we can all be in misery together as literally no one can afford the last companies.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are... And a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their name.
Rym: You may notice I stutter in these from time to time.
Rym: The new interface actually only shows the first, like, 10 or 11 characters of your names.
Rym: And I actually have to hover over each one to get a tooltip to see the full name.
Rym: Or I have to export a CSV, which I am far too lazy to do.
Rym: We're going to try some new stuff with the stream to get the sync a little bit better and maybe up the quality a little bit.
Rym: We're working on some ways to do live panels.
Rym: As you might have heard a little bit of, Scott and I are thinking about doing a dueling panels contest.
Rym: Where each of us is going to put together a solo video panel or video essay and then we'll just fight to see which one of us did a better one.
Rym: But all that's in the future.
Rym: For now, I leave you with...