Rym: It's Tuesday, May 5th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We're talking about the third of the 18xx games that we have actually played 1889 history of Shikoku railways from 2004. let's do this.
Scott: How is this the third one?
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's the second one.
Rym: if we reviewed 1846 raised for the Midwest Yeah, and we also reviewed 2038 tycoons of the asteroid though, but I played this before I played 2038.
Rym: I also played this before I played 2038 and this this one I've only now.
Rym: I've played this now three times But I'd only ever played it once when we got to the point of playing 2038.
Scott: I've played this one I think maybe a few more times than you.
Rym: yeah It's funny because I like this one more with.
Scott: this is the one I've now played the most.
Rym: yeah I like this one more when I will get to in the review.
Rym: I like it more when I'm playing the beginning in the middle of the game But 1846 still has a more pleasant endgame.
Scott: I mean that's true for me for most games Period the beginnings are fun.
Rym: Yeah, I look forward to.
Rym: I think that.
Rym: sit that live sieve game We're playing the one on the fractal map.
Rym: I feel like the continuation of that will be fun.
Scott: I feel like I'm already Not doing great.
Rym: Well all of us are not doing great.
Rym: as long as the Alliance of the three of us I don't know what out.
Scott: What does Alex do that?
Scott: He always has so much better.
Scott: He's better at the Sim City in than us.
Scott: What is he doing?
Rym: more cities faster?
Scott: I built so many settlers this time.
Scott: How many settlers I settled?
Rym: maybe you're doing okay, then?
Scott: No, I'm not my you know.
Scott: look at the top right thingy.
Rym: well join the Alliance.
Rym: the Triple Alliance can't lose.
Scott: Science is good.
Scott: My science is good, but everything else is kind of me all right.
Rym: well ally with me.
Rym: We'll do some science alliances and get even more science.
Rym: mmm Giant death robots can beat an unlimited number of earlier units sure.
Rym: So I need hammers the one thing you know in this whole quarantine.
Rym: We're generally stuck at home.
Rym: I get outside to run and bike but not much else.
Rym: but The weird thing is on one hand there's almost no one driving like there is no traffic.
Rym: It's to the point that New York feels weird.
Rym: the I mostly hear birds.
Rym: One car driving down the street is enough to stink up the whole street like you can smell it coming like.
Rym: it's weird But despite there being almost no cars.
Rym: It feels like there are way more car accidents Mmm.
Scott: I have witnessed two car accidents like in the last week and a half Because almost everyone who's out there driving is like Oh empty road drive like a nut.
Rym: yep I I'd.
Rym: so I think I have seen not the majority But like a good 30% of all the cars I've encountered while I'm out just running red lights with impunity because there's no cops anywhere Like people just roll into red lights, but those dirt bikes are everywhere.
Rym: But I wondered is that just me noticing it because there's so few cars?
Rym: Maybe there was this like there was a lot of accidents.
Rym: another.
Scott: so there were many such cars driving like that.
Scott: You know those people have been on the road.
Scott: They were on the road last year But they're usually on the road late at night, or there's traffic.
Rym: They can't go fast or there's cops.
Scott: They would still do it on the occasional empty road, but now they're just doing it everywhere.
Rym: Yeah But I wondered is there a thing like is are the drivers who are out now actually worse?
Rym: and as I was thinking this I saw An article think it was the Washington Post that was basically like Traffic fatalities are 2x normal despite the fact that traffic is down like 90%.
Rym: So despite there being all those no cars on the road in Boston the number of fatalities due to car accidents is skyrocketing.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but no surprise, but the the other thing I saw shortly after that It's a tweet from Steve bowler who's like a really important VR guy like he knows this stuff.
Rym: cool, dude, but uh Yeah, this random tweet where there's this image from Florida from yesterday when a bunch of the social distancing restrictions eased up and There was a gigantic weird car accident immediately, but if you look at the four pictures of this accident There does not appear to be any way.
Rym: physics could have caused the accident to appear this way Like there's one car stacked on top of two other cars in a conformance that could only have come from above.
Rym: Okay, so the tweet the dude was basically like Lord has done it.
Rym: Lord has created a car accident that cannot be paced back together from the wreckage.
Rym: photos like this makes no sense.
Rym: the crazy thing is.
Rym: I remember from my childhood witnessing an accident that looked the end result of this looked exactly like this.
Rym: and When I was working at IBM seeing in a strip mall in Poughkeepsie an accident that also looked Exactly like this.
Rym: It's in like a particular archetype of accident that always has the exact same cause and happens the exact same way.
Rym: I went searching around.
Rym: I found all those all their images of similar accidents with people being like how the hell could that happen?
Rym: So I want to briefly before we get into the show explain exactly how this accident happens every time it happens.
Scott: Well, I want to briefly say that it's not an accident.
Scott: It is.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it's a collision.
Rym: 99% of all car Incidents are collisions where a human being is specifically there's no such thing as a car accident.
Rym: Well, here's an example of a car accident.
Rym: due to a cosmic ray The car's computer light crashes and the driver loses control at the exact moment a child was running in front of the car.
Rym: Like that could be an accident But otherwise either the child ran out too late and it was technically the child's fault or the person driving More likely was not actually paying attention or was going too fast.
Rym: But anyway this car collision this kind of thing you look at these images if you ever see an act of that thing that looks Like this what usually happens is an older person.
Rym: Let's say someone who is not Probably shouldn't be driving anymore is driving.
Scott: We shouldn't be driving anymore.
Rym: It's driving on the road.
Rym: This accident always happens in a parking lot 99% of the time in a strip mall.
Rym: But the person is driving on the regular road has stopped or parked or something and then is about to start again.
Rym: Instead of hitting the brake when they expected to they hit the gas while simultaneously Still being in reverse instead of in Drive.
Rym: They then start accelerating rapidly backward.
Rym: They then panic because they don't realize that they're holding down the accelerator and they start jamming it down even further and or pumping Because they think it's the brake.
Rym: thus continue to accelerate backwards until eventually they either flip the car or More likely run off the road by hitting a curb.
Rym: if you live in suburbia when they hit the curb The car will actually jump at this Angle like you've seen in movies when someone does a stunt where they kind of jump a car.
Rym: The car will then go backwards at an angle over the median and land on multiple parked cars in a parking lot in a strip mall.
Rym: The fact that I've literally seen this happen once in my life and seen the aftermath of it and sure enough I'm looking at the tweet that I'm linking to.
Rym: Someone has already posted security camera footage from a road further away where you clearly see this car Driving backward down the road and then suddenly veering and flipping backward into the strip mall Ta-da, I Really hate that van cars.
Rym: Yep All right, you got any news since it's gaming day and we're not talking about What was that game where you just crash blaze burnout something the game we were playing up in Albany What you drive a car and crash it.
Rym: that's basically the whole game burnout.
Scott: it's like a hundred games like that.
Rym: I think it's burnout specifically.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I don't know Tons of car games or the or you're supposed to intentionally crash.
Rym: No, no burnout.
Rym: We were playing that mode of burnout where the only goal is to set up an elaborate crash.
Rym: There's no other part of the game.
Scott: Okay, there are several games like that.
Scott: any name.
Scott: one That isn't burn karmic karmageddon.
Rym: karmageddon is a but there's a game beyond.
Rym: the crashes are the are part of achieving a greater goal.
Rym: They are not the sole goal.
Scott: It's a sub game of Grand Theft Auto.
Rym: Yeah burnout.
Rym: It's the game.
Scott: Any demolition derby type game?
Rym: Ah demolition derby.
Rym: The goal is to be the last man standing But I'm talking about video game, oh, yeah, there is a demolition derby video game.
Rym: it's an arcade cabinet.
Rym: It's a cocktail cabinet and there's also a stand-up version.
Rym: It was that cedar point in the classic arcade.
Rym: I played it every year for much of my life.
Scott: So what video game news?
Scott: There's some small video game.
Scott: news is that I you know, I guess some of them could be big but I don't want to talk about them too much because The the info is still comes like this supposed to Nintendo leak and a related Mario 64 native builds from leaked source code supposedly.
Scott: But I don't know.
Scott: we're gonna see what's real and what's not and talk about that in two weeks because that is big if true But still too soon to go into any great depth on that one Without saying something probably.
Scott: Yeah And then you got.
Scott: you got the biggest deal in gaming right now Is that Valorant game from riot.
Scott: who are the people who make League of Legends?
Scott: Free to play?
Scott: they made a free-to-play FPS.
Scott: It's basically like Counter-Strike Counter-Strike Plus.
Scott: it's Counter-Strike Plus overwatch you.
Scott: it plays like overwatch But you're trying to plant the bomb.
Rym: like counter-strike it plays more like strike and not much like overwatch.
Rym: Most of it is around some Counter-Strike valve.
Scott: people worked on it.
Rym: Yeah, but it's like if you watch this gameplay.
Rym: It's all about precise head-clicking and recoil patterns of guns as opposed to the ostentatious ridiculous like action quake overwatch Alright, but anyway That's that's a thing people and there's all kinds of related stories around that game.
Scott: because people are fighting for closed beta keys.
Scott: You can get big like soon like yeah, well people waited in line to play portal to it.
Scott: pexy's true People if you apparently if you're someone who streams it on twitch if you watch their stream it like hands out keys.
Scott: So people have been playing Streaming recorded footage on their twitch channels to keep the key fountain flowing basically Stuff like that.
Scott: it has some invasive anti-cheat stuff going on.
Rym: Yeah, the 10 cent thing that I don't super trust.
Scott: Yeah, there's all kinds of shenanigans going on with this game.
Scott: It's the biggest game right now.
Scott: I'm not touching it with the 10-foot pole.
Rym: Just you know Don't you like Counter-Strike?
Scott: I?
Scott: Think I don't need to play.
Scott: a different guy can just play Counter-Strike.
Rym: you want to play Counter-Strike this weekend.
Scott: Why not not really have better things to do?
Scott: the play counter-strike you kid.
Rym: I just I feel like Valorant would and Counter-Strike and Overwatch would all be pretty up your alley, and I don't know why you don't play them.
Scott: I got better things to do.
Rym: I play for our train games Yeah, why not?
Rym: I'll probably try Valorant, but Overwatch is definitely more my job.
Scott: You install that on your computer.
Scott: go ahead.
Rym: I mean at this point can't really trust computers anyway.
Rym: If I do if I need to do something I trust I'm gonna bust out one of my old computers.
Scott: Yeah, I'll make.
Scott: I'll make an SSH keys on my Apple to gs.
Scott: watch out Take five hours to make one key, but it'll make it and no one's got that.
Scott: I have to use my RAM.
Scott: I'll have to use the entire RAM expansion card to hold the primary the prime numbers in RAM anyway.
Scott: So yes, I want to talk about.
Scott: actually this is game that came out just recently called the cloudpunk.
Scott: I saw this game at PAX East in a booth, and I said oh that looks like a cyberpunk II shadowrun kind of deal.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I saw this too, and I'm looking at the screenshots and So I said alright.
Scott: Well.
Scott: You know I'll play.
Scott: maybe play that one day.
Scott: I took the.
Scott: I took the card from the booth right and I remembered it and it came out and since Normally, I probably wouldn't have bought it or played it Remembered it or waited for a sale.
Scott: Maybe or something, but because we trapped inside what nothing to do Bought that game for 20 bucks.
Scott: So my initial impression was oh Man, it's 20 bucks right.
Scott: It's like so.
Scott: I thought I was gonna get a shatter run kind of deal, right?
Scott: But what actually it turned out to be was sort of a walking sim.
Scott: You know that people say walking simulator, right?
Scott: It's actually a walking hovercar simulator.
Scott: Just talk to people Right exactly.
Scott: so you're the.
Scott: there's a big map and the map is separated into zones Right and each zone is like a. it's like a cyberpunk neighborhood right with big buildings, and you know holographic Advertisements and all kinds of stuff.
Scott: right.
Scott: yeah And you're in this.
Scott: you're in this hovercar, and you drive it around a very carbon Dallas cab.
Rym: feel
Scott: Very Blade Runner really right and you know you can drive it all around all you want and if you go to a parking spot The car auto parks you push a and then you get out of the car And you can walk around the area you parked in.
Scott: right and the areas are a little bit mazy, right?
Scott: There's like ramps connecting things cuz you're way up in the sky.
Scott: You're not near the ground right And you can go to different.
Scott: You know Can't really go in.
Scott: too many things is mostly talking to people outside.
Scott: Right you can buy ramen you can buy drugs you can sell stuff.
Scott: you can talk to people You know.
Scott: look walk around look around You can.
Scott: there's like items on the ground you can collect.
Scott: right if you walk all the way around and to all the areas You know and the environments are pretty incredible that the you're in.
Scott: basically when you're walking around It's not like you've been transported like a lot of games.
Scott: It's like get out of the car, and it transports you into like a separate place.
Rym: So it's always the same world same.
Scott: It's all in the same.
Scott: It's like if you're in the car hovering.
Scott: you can like see the people walking around And then you get out of the car, and there's the same person you just saw man.
Scott: You know.
Scott: they just separate it by the different zones.
Scott: car wise you have to take the car You know into do like a portal to get the next neighborhood, and then it loads the other zone.
Scott: the whole game Isn't loaded at once right?
Scott: But really so.
Scott: as I started to play I was kind of disappointed.
Scott: I spent 20 bucks, and it you know it wasn't very shadow runny right?
Scott: you know Shadowrun has some combat.
Scott: you know this base had no game at all right in terms of like no nothing skill testing, right?
Scott: I mean I guess if you really suck at the driving It would cost you more money because you'd have to go to the gas station a lot And you'd have to repair your car a lot.
Scott: But you it's like I didn't.
Scott: there's no dying that I'm aware of.
Scott: I don't know what happens if you run out of gas or Destroy the car because that never happened to me.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's not a difficulty game right.
Scott: It's it's a go from place to place pressing a to get the story to continue game.
Scott: And at first I was disappointed in that that it cost 20 bucks, but then as I kept playing my disappointment Disappeared because a this game is long like eight hours.
Scott: It took me To get through this whole game right.
Scott: It's like it keeps going right to.
Scott: the environments are like Crazy like they put so much work into the environments.
Scott: the characters the voice acting the art.
Scott: It's sort of pixel voxel II But it's the the the little square the cubes that make up the world are sort of like.
Scott: Think of it as like small Lego, so it's high-res You know like those mini Legos you get that are like you make it really tiny thing.
Rym: Yeah, I got a few of those.
Scott: It's like that so it.
Scott: so the lack of the resolution there doesn't hurt the the atmosphere right.
Scott: It still feels like super cyberpunk like you're in cyberpunk world.
Scott: you can do cyberpunk stuff.
Scott: You are free to just sort of go wherever and do whatever right, but nothing really happens unless you either find a side quest or Go to the next mission waypoint.
Scott: The game does have some annoyances in it, but they're minor right It does have a little bit of.
Scott: you know collect all the bits from each area But you don't have to do that.
Scott: if you don't want to I will gladly not do that.
Scott: But really what the game is is it's like oh, I'd like I didn't realize it at first But it's something I wanted That I didn't realize it that it was.
Scott: that's what it was.
Scott: is that it's a JRPG without any random encounters.
Scott: You walk around you talk to people.
Scott: you right You get to do fun driving.
Scott: Yeah, you know it's like you can't really die You don't have to grind or anything right and it's funny.
Rym: That's one thing I like about those Final Fantasy randomizers is you can use them to basically play Final Fantasy without random encounters.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: there's no encounters.
Scott: basically the only skill challenging things in the game that that were there where there were like two or three deliveries that had timers on them and those are very annoying actually because One of them was difficult One where you had to deliver like the still beating heart like before the battery runs out and like 60 seconds or something.
Scott: It's like you go to like the the prosthetic company.
Scott: They print it out and hand it to you Then you have to get it somewhere in 60 seconds.
Scott: It's like that.
Scott: I didn't succeed at that.
Scott: I wonder what happens if you do.
Scott: But yeah, there's like a plot.
Scott: the characters are compelling You know there's a and the thing is you know the game gives you some decisions to make plot wise And it usually the way the decisions are made is.
Scott: it's like Okay for this delivery drive from here to there And that's all you can do is the game won't progress if you don't drive to the next spot.
Scott: right, but sometimes They're like okay You could choose two different spots to drive to.
Scott: you can.
Scott: you can deliver the package or throw it in the garbage right?
Scott: choose what to do here and The thing that was pretty good writing wise I think in the game is that all of those Every single time the game gave you some sort of choice to make in those regards including the very end of the game Which is also a choice?
Scott: and I think this is also part of the message of the game is every single one of them is There was no clear good bad answer.
Rym: The are you all are there?
Rym: are you history's greatest monster, or are you a paragon of virtue right exactly?
Scott: and like in Fallout 3 It's like oh kill all the dudes or Convince the dudes right.
Scott: it's like clear good bad.
Rym: Here is a human revolution where it was like do you destroy science or do you destroy?
Rym: Culture or do you kill yourself right?
Scott: so I'll give you just one example.
Scott: That's not a spoiler or anything.
Scott: there was some.
Scott: there was some Android who you met on a previous mission.
Scott: Who's who is like a vacuum cleaner and it was now somehow running a building right right?
Scott: And they call you in distress And they want you to pull this switch that will put the building on lockdown because there's some virus spreading in the building All right topical and so you want up.
Scott: so you at first you're right assuming They're telling the truth.
Scott: you want to sort of lock down the building to help the people who are inside.
Scott: But also this dude is probably lying right.
Scott: So maybe you shouldn't pull the switch.
Scott: Maybe you should actually like you know cut power to this dude Right but then maybe the people in the building will be in trouble even though this dude's probably shady Right and up to no good, and you're not sure.
Rym: Right all right what?
Scott: and you had you got to choose one or the other or leave.
Scott: I guess you don't really leave it alone Right cuz it's a side quest so you don't have to.
Scott: you could just do nothing.
Scott: you can select.
Scott: you can just leave those Way points on your mat forever and never touch them.
Scott: But that would be strange if you did that.
Scott: Yeah, if you like cyberpunk atmosphere if you like a JRPG with no combat no grinding no nonsense.
Scott: If you got 20 bucks If you like a plot cyberpunk story If you like making decisions if you like walking around collecting stuff Yep, genre tags cyberpunk sci-fi futuristic atmospheric indie.
Scott: Yeah, cloudpunk You know great voice acting You know the.
Scott: I think the actually the biggest annoyance is that there were a lot of times where you like You'll do a mission you'll get back in the car And then the characters are all talking and you just have to basically sit and wait for all the talking to finish The next waypoint, so it's like there's a lot of sitting and waiting right going on.
Rym: Yeah, but I guess if there's a story where people will talk to each other and you'll overhear them How do you really avoid that yeah?
Scott: I know you it's usually talking to you or with you.
Scott: But yeah You know I don't want to say what a plus But you know if you're trapped inside with $20 all right play it and you got and you have eight hours There's a lot worse you could do.
Rym: Meanwhile I pretty much just keep playing overwatch other than all these other like multiplayer games were playing with our own group Not playing a lot of single-player games.
Rym: I will be cranking through doom eternal because that's definitely up my alley.
Scott: I played that a couple weeks ago.
Rym: Yeah, I'll play it so we can review it.
Rym: Maybe the next show.
Rym: so Overwatch is making a bunch of tweaks to those hero pools and some of the things they're doing are things that Scott wanted them to Do.
Rym: oh interesting they're focusing more on like Ban the characters that are the most used just a force everybody's jimmies to get rustled.
Rym: That's right like data-driven But there's a bad.
Rym: But they're also.
Rym: it looks like they're gonna remove the hero pools from all the competitive play below a certain level and They made this point about how basically every one of those lower skill tiers They use all the heroes and what they didn't say is because they are terrible at this game.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: Here's the money shot quote.
Rym: Competitive play at lower skill tiers already sees a tremendous amount of hero composition diversity in their matches.
Scott: Well, I mean the truth is is that people who aren't people who are good at the game Right are people who are trying to win and someone who's trying to win is going to choose the character on the Pareto frontier.
Scott: Someone who doesn't care about being good right is going to choose their favorite character regardless of how good or strong that character is.
Scott: and that is why at lower skill levels you will always see a bigger mix because People who suck are right.
Scott: if people who are good don't pick shitty characters They'll just pick the strongest one though.
Rym: It's fast.
Scott: care if they don't care if they hate that character.
Scott: it's like maybe you know they they're in their life like they're.
Scott: They're a big-time metal person.
Scott: They like you know so like they would love to pick the skull dude, right?
Scott: But like if the cute one is the strongest they're like I'll take the cute bear.
Scott: It's the strongest one.
Scott: I'm picking it right.
Rym: I pick Pokemon based solely on looks.
Scott: I Mean me too, but I'm not trying to win Pokemon Right, but you know it's someone who doesn't trying to win.
Scott: It's like I like skull dude.
Scott: I'm picking skull dude no matter what skull dude every time.
Scott: don't care if skull dudes the worst of the best That's my guy.
Scott: Yeah, all right.
Scott: and that person who does that is going to be lower ranked because Right.
Rym: yep, though.
Rym: What's interesting is that there's still certain heroes that would get rotated out all the time.
Rym: It's just this is more fodder for that panel We wanted to do.
Rym: we did a draft version of that whole competitive versus casual thing and how they really can't coexist With all these tweaks.
Rym: they still can't apply even remotely similar rules to skilled players and unskilled players.
Rym: And the worst part is there's still the problem of that like middle third of players who say they're skill based who?
Rym: Who say they're trying to play to win?
Rym: But actually aren't and then get mad.
Rym: if the game if the aim coddles them they get mad.
Rym: But if the game shows them that they're actually bad they also get mad.
Rym: There's no way to make them happy.
Rym: I think that's the group we need to excise from gaming entirely, but like low silver scrubs Well, it's it's.
Scott: you know the problem there.
Rym: I make them only play with each other forever.
Rym: you should be a shadow band to the low tier silvers for the rest of your.
Scott: You know what an excise those people right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: There's still people who deserve to play games and have fun.
Scott: Well.
Scott: They're Want to be better.
Scott: they're trying to be better But maybe their talent is low their discipline is low.
Scott: their ability to practice and improve is low.
Scott: Their willingness to you know Change themselves.
Rym: well, I guess it's a lot of learn.
Rym: I guess there is a fine line.
Rym: a lot of people are in those tiers in all games Not just overwatch, but there's that particular tear the to quote that Hanzo thing We talked about a long time ago.
Rym: the angriest people in the world I think a good.
Rym: like maybe half of them Maybe even two-thirds rotate in and out of that tear either on the way up or on the way down or are playing kind of Casually don't care that much.
Rym: But then there's like that set of people who get increasingly aggrieved and start to become a negative influence on the game and everyone else's Experiences.
Rym: there's.
Scott: no I think what you see people.
Scott: There's a stereotype You'll see in a lot of like sports movies of the the kid who's has a lot of talent and promise or has some sort Of natural whatever right.
Scott: mighty dogs said that then it's all cocky and unresponsive to coaching or advice and isn't a team player right?
Scott: and I think that's what you'll see in those right.
Scott: It's like okay They have some natural talent or skill or something that is putting them above the bottom people.
Rym: They know how to fly they can.
Scott: she can beat up on the bottom people right it's but they're unresponsive to coaching Learning expect.
Scott: they think that they're because they're beating up on these people.
Scott: right yeah, they feel like they're good You know.
Scott: and it's like Actually, you're only middle good.
Rym: But I guess it's only a problem once they get to the point of being aggrieved and lashing out at other players.
Scott: right.
Scott: well Because if they're only playing against you know You know people worse than them they can beat up on them, and they don't get mad.
Scott: Yeah, they feel like yes This is the correct result.
Scott: I have one right And then once you find it find someone is actually good.
Scott: It's like hey, right.
Scott: Yeah, their belief about their own skill level was inaccurate.
Rym: But I've noticed something.
Scott: what I was getting they have they don't have the ability to improve and get better Or the openness or for some reason that's that they've hit their limit right.
Scott: so now they're mad.
Rym: so The where I'm going with this is one thing I've observed.
Rym: I've been playing now since the quarantine a lot more overwatch again The community and the way people are interacting with each other in the game and in the voice chat.
Rym: It's just like getting better and better and better as time goes on like everyone's super polite Everyone's chill and I think the main like almost sole reason for that is the hero is not the hero pool necessarily, but the roll lock thing because Consistently no matter what hour of the day I play at any time There is a 10 to 30 minute wait to be a DPS player And there's zero way to be a healer or a tank.
Scott: I think that that is partially correct But I think you are not giving enough credit To the number of shitty people who have left overwatch to go play that Valorant game.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I'm wondering.
Rym: I didn't want to say that out loud because when I say
Scott: I'll say that
Rym: out loud when I said I'm gonna play Valorant But what I mean is I want to go play Valorant to see if that's where all the low Silver's are still being
Scott: Absolutely all the shit.
Scott: all the people who are bored of overwatch have left to play Valorant.
Rym: Maybe they evolve into.
Rym: well overwatch was bad anyway.
Rym: I'm gonna play a real game with recoil.
Scott: If you can't get better at you know the game you're playing right.
Scott: you're gonna go switch switch games.
Scott: But that's how it is.
Rym: the specific thing that's happening is that because of the hero like the love of the rolox if I play A tank I'm like an upper silver low gold.
Rym: so I play at a rank where the DPS and the healers are also at my Same level meaning the scrubs are basically all gongs.
Rym: the scrubs are almost all DPS players anyway.
Rym: Meanwhile if I play DPS the Variability of skill is so great that I can pretty much end up dunking on anyone If but I have to wait 10 to 30 minutes to play even a single match in DPS, so I don't bother
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: but the fact that the
Scott: it seems like a problem that should be solved also.
Rym: Yeah, they're trying to solve the fact that there's a long wait to play DPS.
Rym: But the problem the reason there's a long way to play DPS is that a lot of people only want to play DPS.
Scott: Why would?
Scott: why would you want to play DPS more than the other ones?
Rym: I don't know because DPS is where Reaper like the badass guy with the shotguns is.
Rym: it's the like high damage output.
Rym: Ostensibly it's the highest skill characters even though in fact I think tanks are more important to the survival of a team, but I digress.
Scott: there's line.
Scott: I think.
Scott: I think perhaps the problem is that the characters who are DPS are perhaps more fun to play Some to a degree.
Scott: but I think I think I think you just have to make it less fun to be DP.
Rym: I think all the characters are equally more fun to be the other things.
Rym: They're just fun to play in different ways.
Rym: And I think a lot of players healthily like to play.
Rym: all different kinds of players will rotate from all three.
Rym: Like when I go into queue, I just say put me wherever.
Rym: I literally don't care Because I literally don't care for whatever reason.
Rym: there's a significant subset of people who seem to be clustered almost entirely In that loose silver tier that want to play DPS.
Rym: if you get above that tier You don't have this problem.
Rym: And if you're below that tier you also have this problem.
Rym: It's that tears.
Scott: you don't have to wait 30 minutes if you're if you get to a higher rank
Rym: exactly or if you're a lower rank It's only if you're in this like one band Where a lot of players are where the majority of the player
Scott: the way you are because you're waiting.
Rym: Well, yes, because I've only played a few DPS matches.
Rym: Oh because the rank is separate for each thing exactly because the rank is separate for each thing.
Rym: if I play gold tank My DPS on my team are gold DPS.
Rym: They've ascended above that fray.
Scott: So even if you're not gold DPS, let's say you suck at DPS.
Scott: Yep, but you're gold something else.
Rym: So good players are rising in ranks in all the roles.
Rym: Scrubs only play DPS and are stuck in the scrub tier of DPS.
Scott: Well, and also you might get stuck though not be necessarily because of suckage but because of waiting.
Rym: Yeah, because we can't rank up if you can't play games yep, but people seem to be willing to wait.
Rym: the wait times for DPS are static and That what if they made it?
Scott: what if they made it so that you could wait in a in the DPS queue and Also play as another one at the same time so you can play as a tank and then when that game ends You're still in the DPS queue.
Rym: They're starting to do something like that where you can play non-competitive games while you're waiting But you can't play competitive games while you're waiting because there's.
Rym: no you can't interrupt a competitive game.
Scott: no, you don't interrupt it right?
Scott: is?
Rym: you would have the Okay, basically get credit for time served while you're playing the other match.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: Yeah, so when you come out, right?
Scott: So it's like, okay Let's say somehow while you're in your match you end up number one in the DPS queue.
Scott: You would just stay number one.
Scott: Yeah, so your match ends and then once your other match ends you would go into the next game that starts.
Rym: Yep, right So yeah I'll link to the article that talks about some of these changes but Waiting.
Rym: the long wait for DPS seems to me the primary problem they're trying to solve now.
Scott: I think that's.
Scott: the solution though is just you can play another real game and just stay in line.
Rym: Yep The other solution would be I just got to get my ranking matches out early get to upper silver low gold And then I don't have to worry about this problem.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: and last and least I just want to.
Rym: there was a scare a little while ago where Everyone on Twitter was losing the shit saying Valve had a source code leak.
Rym: if you play any source games your computer is gonna get hacked.
Rym: That story was such bullshit And I'm so disappointed in so many people who I saw just blindly saying this vulnerability was there and making shit up.
Rym: like the amount of shit people made up about that valve leak was ridiculous.
Rym: and it's telling that Once the real info like came out and there were no significant hacking incidents No one rejected redacted any of their articles.
Rym: They just went quiet.
Scott: There was definitely not a lot of Fear.
Scott: there was a lot of fear when the initial fake story and not much on the you know Comeback story.
Scott: So since we did talk about it before.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: Let us let us redact.
Scott: I mean we didn't really say anything.
Scott: why we said we're not sure about this.
Rym: There are no known verified RCs as a result of this leak?
Scott: and also what did the truth turn out to be?
Scott: do we have a link?
Rym: there is Stalling to this?
Rym: there is that one valve officially said it is completely safe to play these games.
Rym: The source code was old and there are no specific RC vulnerabilities known in that code, which a lot of people are looking at.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: All right, I mean be lying Yeah, but at the same time a source code leak does not guarantee an RCE In fact, especially when the clients are just interfacing with API's.
Rym: knowing the source code of the system behind that API in no way means that you have a way to Remotely execute code on the server that thing's running on.
Scott: Well, no but you would you might be able to I find of all I believe the way that the the way that it would supposedly work would Be that you would run say Counter-strike server that was had had you know?
Scott: Purposefully installed malware zone and that way anyone who ended up playing on your counter-strike server You could then your your server that you set up is now attacking all your players who you like.
Scott: It's like a honey.
Scott: Yeah, you know which in the old days would be yes come play on my server.
Scott: when your game connects to my server I'll get you.
Rym: Yeah, remember quick - there are all these mods and shit that would just download files to your PC to make it Work, that's still kind of the way it works though.
Rym: Yeah it is but even then There's no verified remote code execution that anyone pulled off.
Rym: nor was there any description of what how one was even plausible Other than vague like people who are smart like us Assuming like well, I guess this is the kind of thing that could happen but no one actually had any evidence at all.
Scott: The way I mean when the original thing came out what I what I had read was That yeah, they saw they looked at the source code and found one that they could do Unverified.
Rym: no one ever verified that claim.
Scott: Well, you know, that's what they said.
Scott: Yeah I'm one said and this code is like the source code was so old So it's like how do you know that that's still valve?
Rym: also officially pretty quickly said yes This is the leak that happened in 2018. it's the exact same code that was leaked then and Most of this news about it started to move into the story blaming like this one particular Dude for the leak who clearly had nothing to do with it Like it was a. it was a weird situation.
Scott: It almost feels like I did read that too.
Scott: There was a dude who was response.
Scott: It was like a valve Like a reporter, right and I guess he was like he had to like deny.
Scott: he's like.
Scott: no I had nothing to do with this.
Scott: No, it's not me.
Scott: No, because I guess he's like the known person for that sort of stuff.
Scott: Yes I don't know.
Rym: but basically not only does it all seem like it was a big nothing burger But it seemed for whatever reason.
Rym: it seems like this was an orchestrated like false news Like someone pushed this narrative and a bunch of people blindly like retweeted it and shared it.
Scott: We'll go get your Twitter PI Hat on and find the original, you know spreaders on fortune or whatever.
Rym: Yeah I just don't care that much cuz I don't play either of these.
Rym: get like tf2.
Rym: I would definitely never play again.
Rym: and CS go.
Rym: I was playing the other day.
Rym: still an okay game, but I feel like Valorant is probably gonna completely eat CS go.
Scott: No, I don't know about that.
Rym: kids counter-strike has survived everything it has but it is what I was playing at the other day.
Rym: The people who are playing counter-strike are quite a community.
Rym: Yeah, that is those were some people that I interacted with.
Scott: good Yeah, like fucking kind of people do you think are playing?
Rym: Yeah, it's uh And I feel like the people who are playing it who are not in the professional scene because the professional scene seems actually pretty fine.
Rym: But if you just join like a random CS go match like It's hard to describe.
Rym: It's not bad in the ways.
Rym: You're expecting me to say it is weird and uncomfortable the interactions that occur on those servers, but anyway, it's time for Things of the day.
Rym: So there have been a lot of implementations of pong over the years.
Rym: You know pong like the first real video game the game that despite being basically the first video game is still today A fantastic game that could be a fantastic e-sport with zero changes.
Rym: So this video outlines an implementation of pong.
Rym: There's been a lot of implementations of pong over the years.
Rym: This implementation is a handheld pong from 1977 that is smaller than a Nintendo switch.
Rym: Okay, that's kind of amazing.
Scott: What kind of display does it have?
Rym: Uh, so that's that's that's uh, that's why this is amazing.
Scott: The display would really be the limit to the limiting factors.
Rym: so if you look at it as a display has obviously kind of like gay a handheld games from that era has Basically all these physical components all over it Like physical score counter and everything.
Rym: But there's a glowing red dot that will bounce back and forth and you can bounce it by hitting the buttons on the left and right.
Rym: the sole Electronic component of this game is a tiny battery that lights that LED.
Rym: Everything else is not electro mechanical.
Rym: It is purely mechanical.
Rym: You wind the game up and which winds up a spring and then when you play the game You move the paddles by hitting buttons on the two sides that physically move components that you can't see.
Rym: and there's this complicated arm mechanism that will that has an LED on the end of it and it'll just trace the ball back and forth based on where you Pushed the buttons and what it bounced off of.
Rym: the entire game is 100% mechanical.
Rym: There's just a tiny battery powering a single LED.
Rym: There's no other electronic component at all.
Rym: This is Barely ingenious to make a portable pong in 19.
Scott: How well does it work though?
Rym: It works perfectly.
Rym: It's just not a great game Because the paddles could only be in three different three positions on each side Mmm, but it works.
Rym: it is technically like.
Rym: it's an implementation of pong.
Rym: how its implemented is pretty fascinating.
Rym: it's a. it's a case study in how to build a game with the tools that you got and how to be clever and creative in light of Extremely challenging technical and material science considerations.
Scott: I mean if you think about it right at the same time that there was NES there was also tiger LCD, right?
Rym: I remembered we're not like they were.
Rym: they were.
Rym: they were worth negative amounts of money.
Rym: those tiger LCDs.
Rym: those things were garbage.
Scott: They weren't garbage until the gameboy arrived.
Rym: I would argue they were worse than nothing before the gameboy came out.
Scott: No, the gameboy is what killed tiger LCD.
Rym: anyway I think the only people who like tiger LCD were the people who had them and didn't want to admit that they were literally unplayable garbage.
Scott: Some of them were better than others.
Rym: Yes, that is true.
Rym: that is technically true.
Scott: in this actually I think there's an Aladdin one that was like actually quite good.
Rym: I would argue that Those equivalent games that just had ball bearings in them were better.
Rym: The worst ball bearing game was better than the best tiger LCD game.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Rym: fight me Let's do a show on those ball bearings games.
Scott: Let's do a show on tiger LCD game.
Rym: Let's do a show on both.
Rym: We can probably get a pile of both of them on eBay for like zero dollars.
Scott: I could just get the ones I have it.
Scott: I don't know if they're still there.
Rym: Oh, yeah I don't know.
Rym: I don't know if I actually my mom might still have all those ball bearing games.
Scott: Tiger LCD games may or may not be in Connecticut.
Rym: that that's two GeekNights episodes.
Scott: Anyway, we might have done a tiger LCD episode.
Rym: We might have.
Rym: so do you got?
Scott: what do I have?
Scott: So, you know, we love industrial accidents here our GeekNights.
Scott: Oh, yes, like you We don't like it when people get hurt, but we like YouTube videos of large large things breaking.
Scott: So, I don't know who got hurt here.
Scott: I'm sorry, if anyone did get hurt.
Scott: I'm not aware of what damages there were to people But this collapse of a crane is too impressive.
Scott: So here's the situation.
Scott: is you have this Floating boat right a floating boat.
Rym: Well, I mean there are not floating boats like summer.
Scott: sure It's a boat with a crane on it and the purpose of the boat with the crane on it is to build offshore wind farms.
Scott: So the crane, you know next to it is a barge and on the barge are pieces of the you know, the wind You know, whatever you call it turbine, right?
Scott: Yeah So the crane the crane boat is gonna lift the things off the barge.
Scott: The barge moves out of the way and then they use the crane and whatever to erect the giant.
Rym: Yeah, so good news before you continue base.
Rym: I dug her on the YouTube comments, which one are extremely accurate and like fascinating.
Rym: I'm actually gonna read also racist.
Rym: I have not run into that yet.
Scott: There are a lot of them complaining like a Chinese steel.
Rym: I've not seen any comment that says anything.
Scott: like when I read the comments half of them were like racist construction workers being like that Chinese steel and then people were applying like it's German steel mine sorted by top comments not Chronological.
Rym: maybe that's the difference.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I haven't read the comment anyway.
Rym: This was a load test of the crane Correct.
Scott: they were testing the crane to see how good it was and it wasn't good enough.
Scott: Yeah You can read.
Scott: I don't want to.
Scott: I don't want to describe what the exact breakage was because I am NOT a crane expert.
Rym: Looks like the hook block failed under load.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: So there's like a from what you can see in the video, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, there's a behind the crane, right?
Scott: So it's your look.
Scott: you're looking at the back of the crane.
Scott: It's lifting something on the other side of the boat, right.
Scott: so deeper into the video than you can see Is the thing it's lifting and you know all the cables that are you know, going up to the top of the crane are tied down Behind the crane.
Scott: you can see like these little triangles Right behind the.
Scott: you see them there.
Scott: They're like little and there's a thing that's tied down there and I guess it comes loose I think.
Scott: Read the comments for expert opinion.
Scott: Don't trust my opinion on what went wrong.
Rym: I love when an expert just rolls in somewhere and it's just like looks like the entire hook block broke during a hundred ten percent SWL load.
Rym: yes You can see what's on that left yellow block.
Rym: this sort of released all the tension in the boom suddenly making it crash back into the a-frame Probably a casting or forging error Something like that.
Scott: So sure Yeah, you can just watch this video though.
Scott: It's 23 seconds long and not a waste of 23 seconds of your life.
Rym: I like how it like the droop is actually kind of funny like it's comedic the like slow way that it droops.
Rym: Yep, that's why it's a good video Yep, but also in general one thing you can bear in mind whenever you find videos that are about industrial tests that fail those very rarely have any injuries or deaths because it's still.
Scott: it's still a shame that this is even though this is a test that Is still a very expensive thing that took a long time to make and was many many millions of dollars probably in damages.
Rym: So fun fact.
Rym: because I'm into elevators.
Rym: Did you know that all elevators get multiple levels of failure testing?
Rym: Including a test that they basically the final test that elevators get on.
Rym: They do this on a varying basis depending where you are in the world.
Rym: laws are different everywhere But there's all these different mechanisms that prevent elevators from falling.
Rym: the final tests for certifying elevators involves literally removing Every single one of those fail backs every safety mechanism every electrical control.
Rym: Everything is removed Except the final one like the last ditch one and then They basically run a drop test to see if the elevator will have a problem and if there's a problem in anything in the elevator.
Rym: the video of what happens is terrifying and Elevators fail that test kind of often Relative to how often you'd expect them to fail that test.
Scott: Why didn't you put your knowing that test skin is gonna happen?
Scott: Wouldn't you put your most effort into that final safety?
Rym: That's but the fact that an elevator can't really go live until even that test has happened.
Rym: That is why people don't die when elevators fall.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: but basically the video if you ever see one of those tests fail is you're in the top of the elevator where like all the Machinery is and suddenly that's so.
Scott: that's where you want to be.
Rym: You don't want to be at the bottom Yeah, and you basically just see like everything go crazy and cables start like flailing everywhere and you see the cables go All the way down to the bottom.
Rym: Yep All right in the meta moment.
Rym: We're hanging out.
Rym: Not a lot we can do can't go to any cons.
Rym: Not the earliest con we would even consider Possibly going to depending on situations would be in September with PAX West and even that anyone knows any online Cons that want to have us.
Rym: let us know We will bring our panels.
Rym: we can stream them live.
Rym: Yep, as soon as we can meet in person safely We'll probably start just videoing live panels and just doing them for the internet.
Scott: Who knows I feel like we'll do that.
Scott: say who can say what we'll do.
Rym: I mean, I plan to do that.
Rym: We're playing do that.
Rym: Anyway, the problem is right now We can't even really like meet in person Mm-hmm.
Rym: I guess we could do the panel six feet apart in a park somewhere.
Scott: Am I gonna get you sacred?
Scott: You Got you got something you want to tell me.
Rym: Hey, you never know you never know.
Rym: We'll see how things go, but we're not going to any cons anytime soon.
Rym: So if you're hoping to see us at like Connecticut or anything that have thank icon anything that was essentially gonna.
Scott: Yeah, whether the con is can announced its cancellation or not.
Scott: We're not gonna be there.
Scott: There is currently no con on our schedule.
Scott: That is confirmed.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The earliest Possibility is PAX West not saying that that will happen or that we will be the low percent chance Earliest possible chance.
Scott: we will be at any convention for the foreseeable book club book is tale of Genji But I don't even know if I'm gonna get to go to a beach to read it once it starts getting a little warmer.
Rym: I might just start reading in the park like when I'm out biking.
Scott: So yes, something like that could definitely happen.
Scott: Yeah What else is meta you should?
Scott: we're working on a code of conduct.
Scott: still you should come To our forum and this code of conduct it implies to you because it is not just for our forum Which you should join it implies to all GeekNights Community spaces.
Scott: so like if we have a game night if we have a meetup at a convention if we any Absolutely any GeekNights community space these rules will apply And you will be expected to abide by them if you wish to participate in any of those spaces.
Scott: So if you're happy just listening to GeekNights and never interacting with our community Then it doesn't concern you.
Scott: but but if you want to be a part of our community Like we'll block you from everything if you want to be a part of our community Even if we just want to tweet with us on Twitter You know also you should speaking of our community.
Scott: You should come to our discord.
Scott: I have people have been Doing stuff in there.
Scott: They've been streaming games to and with each other the listeners getting together Often so you could get in there with them and abide by the guidelines that are not yet set in stone But we are seeking your input to finalize them, and they won't ever truly be finalized.
Scott: They will just merely be revised enough to go live and then continue to be revised From here until eternity because you never know what will happen.
Scott: There'll be some new form of Discrimination against cyborg people that we will have to you know put a rules against or something right.
Rym: yeah At least until we eventually replace all humans with cyborgs and then transcend into a new trans human.
Scott: Go ahead the code of conduct is on github And there is also a thread on the forum so you can.
Scott: you can come and give your feedback About it to us in any way that you feel comfortable doing so including anonymously.
Scott: or what have you yeah?
Rym: I only had to ban one person whose feedback Against the code of com of code of conduct was itself a violation of the code of conduct as written.
Scott: yeah, right.
Scott: well Even though this particular code of conduct is not yet live right we still have basic rules that are always in place, right?
Rym: I mean like if you're not it's not like.
Scott: our communities are not an unsafe place because we haven't put these rules in yet.
Scott: We're just codifying sort of what the existing spirit is.
Scott: at least that's the goal right.
Rym: yep, so yeah, let's get into it.
Rym: We played another train game.
Rym: We played the strain game many times, but now that I've played it multiple times in a row Not at a convention with no time pressure I have a lot more deep insight into it and a lot more thoughts about the 18xx genre as a whole.
Scott: Right there is still so many 18xx games We haven't played and there is so much more for us to learn which is why I keep playing them despite having many criticisms.
Scott: But yeah, 18 is 1846 which is the one we first played and did a show on.
Scott: yep This is the second one I played actually which is 1889 which is history of Shikoku railways.
Scott: So Shikoku is this island in Japan that I yeah that I always remember because I was watching an anime and there was a joke in the anime about an old lady who couldn't hear and Someone and they asked the old lady asked someone where they were from and they said Shikoku.
Scott: Or no, I think they someone said G Goku which is the Japanese Right and the old lady was like oh you're from Shikoku Because they sound Shikoku is a Japanese an island of Japan.
Scott: that is Shikoku literally translates to four districts.
Scott: So it has four districts right sort of north south east and west and it's sort of cut in half by these mountain range.
Scott: You can just look at it on a map and you'll see what I'm talking about.
Scott: You'll be like, oh that place.
Scott: I know that I've seen it on maps of Japan before.
Scott: Yeah, that's Shikoku.
Scott: So this game is about.
Scott: Shikoku was mostly served transportation wise by ferries And then in the 1800s, obviously like Oh around 1889 or so began to be served.
Scott: it began to be served by trains and That would take you between the places on Shikoku and this game is an evil game of capitalism.
Scott: About that takes place on that geography in that time period.
Rym: All right, so 18 xx games we're not gonna get into the whole story.
Rym: You can listen to our 1846 episode which was our introduction to the genre.
Rym: But they're train games.
Scott: They're like archetypical train games when you think about Right when you think about oh those old guys at the game store playing train games.
Scott: This is that game.
Scott: This is what it is.
Scott: Right the myth of mystery has been revealed.
Scott: It's not some mysterious place anymore.
Scott: This is how the game is and the fundamental thing about all these train games and the thing that draws me to them all Regardless of the details or problems is the fundamental mechanic of the meta game being the real game?
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: You would look at this game or any of these games and say aha.
Scott: There's this map There's these trains.
Scott: you're trying to run trains To get the longest to get long routes that are worth a lot of points and that you would be thinking is that is the real Game, but no that game you're thinking of is Raro tycoon, right?
Scott: Raro tycoon is the game.
Scott: Yeah, you want to run the trains and get the most money.
Rym: This game is more about extracting wealth from the system into your own personal coffers while fucking over other players with a spreadsheet.
Scott: right, so take Raro tycoon and No longer are you.
Scott: is each player a train company?
Scott: You are now instead a stock Investor wealthy person right tycoon and literal tycoon.
Scott: the players of the Raro tycoon are actually these Abstract company objects and you buy and sell shares in them.
Scott: You might at one point be the president of one in which case you will decide what it does.
Scott: on its turn.
Rym: You might be the president of two or three or or or all or none And you are.
Scott: you know, you see you might take the turn of a company once in a while here and there But you're simply just trying to not make one company better or worse necessarily.
Scott: You are simply trying to take the most money out of the system and into your pocket.
Rym: Yep, your money is not the company's money.
Scott: You want to own shares in the valuable companies?
Scott: You want to.
Scott: when trains are required to be purchased you want someone else to have to purchase them?
Scott: And then you want to get the revenues for when those trains run and passengers pay to get on them, right?
Scott: When tracks have to be laid through the mountains you want someone else to dig the tunnel and you want to run your train through it.
Scott: Or better yet You want them to dig the tunnel and then put a blocking token so that they can't run their train?
Scott: Yeah, only you can.
Scott: this is the kind of game this is And they're all.
Rym: what makes eight?
Rym: Yeah All these 18xx games are basically that same fundamental theme but with crook like rules are crook slightly.
Rym: So like in some games the companies if they like someone buys enough stock to start one They start with all the money that they could have started with from the bag.
Rym: in other games Players put it in right?
Rym: So what makes 1889 different from the other ones, right?
Scott: Well, I'm not gonna go into all the details of everything that makes it different because I don't know them all.
Rym: Yep, we're gonna focus more like how it feels like.
Rym: why how does it feel different to play right?
Scott: 1889 is mostly from what I've heard based a lot on 1830 which I think is the original 18xx game with a few minor Changes and obviously the map is different and the trains are a little different, right?
Scott: But the first big difference is that you know, what does it?
Scott: this is concept of a company floating, right?
Scott: So it's you know, every company starts with no one owning any shares and you start buying shares Right.
Scott: and and you when you when enough shares of a company have been bought regardless of who bought them the company comes into existence and can start playing the game and The company has its own money, which is separate from players money.
Scott: So in 1846, which we did an episode on long ago, which I'll link to Right.
Scott: The way it works is that you buy IPO shares and I forget how many you have to buy to make the company float but it's some number and then the company will have money equal to The money spent on those IPO shares sort of like the real world, right?
Scott: Like if I buy an IPO share for $100 the company now has $100 to invest in it that it can use right?
Scott: But then you know after the company floats there are still IPO shares sitting there.
Scott: And if you were to say buy one in 1846 that would put more money into the company.
Scott: right when you bought more shares in 1889.
Scott: Let's say a company opens at seventy dollars, right?
Rym: So you're sending the initial share price at seventy dollars a share Right.
Scott: So and I buy five of the shares.
Scott: so three hundred and fifty dollars is spent on buying shares.
Scott: The other five shares are still there Available to be purchased at seventy dollars each.
Scott: the IPO shares the five That I did not buy that someone else could buy later or I can buy or whatever the company immediately.
Scott: as soon as it floats the company will immediately go open and it will have $700 in its coffers.
Scott: right buying those additional IPO shares will not put money into the company.
Scott: the company starts with its full amount of money from all the shares even though only five have been purchased and When those remaining five are purchased that money just goes to the bank, right?
Scott: and what this means is that you can sort of get you get this mechanic happening.
Scott: that doesn't happen in 1846 so much.
Scott: where You want to just float a company?
Scott: suddenly all that money you spent is doubled but it's in a company and you want to yank that money out of that company and Into your wallet.
Rym: You can't just embezzle it directly.
Rym: You can't just steal it Can't do that like you need the company to buy a smaller company that you own personally from you at an exorbitant rate or you need to invest in a second company and then Basically have that company.
Rym: once you trick some other morons into investing into that company with you You have your original company.
Rym: buy Something from that company for like a dollar like buy all the company's trains and then sell all that company shares and fuck it.
Scott: Yep Things like that happen Exactly, and the main thing in this the main rule in this game is that if a company has no trains It must buy a train at the end of its turn, right?
Scott: And if a company does not have enough money in its coffers to buy a train The president of that company must contribute to buy the cheapest train available.
Rym: So from their wallet On top of that different trains like you can only buy trains in sequence and there's like a level 2 a level 3 a level 4 Train.
Rym: once you buy certain trains of certain levels all the trains of certain earlier levels Just instantly disappear and are gone forever and worth nothing, right?
Scott: So the game starts.
Scott: only the two trains are available the weakest train.
Scott: they can only go to two spots, right?
Scott: So they don't collect a lot of money.
Scott: They just go from point A to point B like a shuttle.
Scott: And so let's say a company loads up on two trains.
Scott: Well, as soon as I think a four train is bought those two trains will all disappear from the game.
Scott: Yep So if a company is full of two trains and it doesn't have enough money Then as soon as someone else buys a four train that company has no trains and has to buy one.
Scott: So that the trick you want to do would would be be the owner of the company with the two trains.
Scott: It suddenly doubles money.
Scott: There's a big fountain of money in that company Because it just it floated.
Scott: you want to use all the money from that company to buy trains From this other company that you started your second company.
Scott: so you moved all the money from company a that has the shit trains to Company B, which has the good trains.
Scott: Oh, right and then company a loses all its trains.
Scott: But luckily by the time that happens you sold your shares in that shitty company I know someone else is the president and now they are forced to Purchase a train with the money from their wallet.
Scott: and now you're ahead.
Scott: Yes Your wallet is full of money that you didn't spend on trains.
Rym: you spent some company money on trains And then you can use that money to buy more stocks and rinse and repeat and everyone's right.
Scott: and now that right?
Scott: How can that person now who just lost all the money in their wallet buying trains by you know out of pocket?
Scott: Invest in stocks right there their funds are depleted.
Rym: Yeah You get the stock out of this game pretty easily if they're not careful.
Rym: and The game is always tense as soon as anyone has two companies.
Rym: They could.
Rym: There's a lot of ways they could screw everybody else over Right.
Scott: So I think the major the major things going on in this game is that the turn order Matters too much.
Rym: that is probably like what one thing.
Scott: this is true of I think all the 18xx games But it's especially true of this one.
Rym: Yeah, and that's sort of this interesting fatal flaw and why we want to talk about this game.
Rym: because I enjoy 18xx games.
Rym: I enjoyed this one more than the other ones.
Rym: like this is I think my favorite.
Scott: Oh, I enjoy it, but but I still have problems with it.
Rym: Yeah, but what we're realizing is that there are specific
Scott: mechanics
Rym: in these games that we like but there are other mechanics in these games that either obscure the reality of those mechanics or are kind of broken or Arbitrary or limit how much you can engage with the fun parts of the game.
Scott: So I felt like you would think that like choosing the right stocks to buy like figuring out their values into the future Would be like a really good heuristic that you would want in this game.
Scott: It would only help if everyone playing the game had never played 1889 before sure But that only helps you a little bit.
Scott: that helps you like a tiny amount.
Rym: Yeah When we were playing our game before All four of us knew which stock was the hot stock.
Rym: at all times No one disagreed about the value of anything at any point, right?
Scott: It's like it was pretty much obvious Like if you have money to buy a stock and you're gonna buy one which one to buy?
Scott: there wasn't.
Scott: it wasn't a hard decision And it didn't change the course of the game.
Scott: that significantly what changes the course of the game significantly is like well I'm going third therefore blah.
Scott: Yeah layer or that was much more important.
Scott: Who was gonna win?
Rym: this is my real problem.
Rym: like the the deep flaw of all 18xx games Is that the basic game like operating the trains like there's not much there, which is fine.
Rym: the stock rounds are the real game, but the stock rounds can be extremely massively disrupted by specific things that can happen in those otherwise unimportant Operating rounds.
Rym: like someone buys the next train that rusts a bunch of trains.
Rym: Now the whole game state is broken.
Scott: But well because it's not just the turn order of this of the that you have in the stock round.
Scott: there's a separate turn order of Which order the companies will take their turn in the company round?
Rym: Yeah, but you can't manipulate the turn order of the stock round during the operating round.
Scott: But you can write the stock round is determined.
Scott: basically there's an order that's set randomly at the start of the game and there's a first player marker and Basically whoever takes the last stock action buying or sell and or selling and then everyone passes The next person after the person who took the last action, so let's say I buy a stock everyone else passes.
Scott: Then I pass.
Scott: yeah, whoever is to my left is gonna now go first.
Scott: the order is always the same.
Rym: It's like clockwise around the table And that's the fundamental thing that I feel is holding these games back from being great Generally as opposed to being great in this extremely narrow niche Right.
Scott: The second thing is so the order that the companies operate is from most valuable to least valuable.
Rym: Yeah There's this whole complicated market.
Rym: Listen to our 1846 episode.
Scott: We'll talk about that.
Scott: because because companies can only buy trains on their turn They can't at the end of their turn also, they can't sell trains, right?
Scott: so if you want if you have two companies and you want company a to sort of take trains away from company B and Company B to then buy a good train with all of the money that it has now and then get rid of company a You need to make sure that company a that's gonna do the buying Right to pull the shitty trains into itself has to be more valuable than company B so that it goes first.
Rym: Yep But at the same time you also have to make sure that other companies that could buy a train in the wrong order Don't exist and operate before you and fuck it up, right?
Scott: It's like I want to buy a for train.
Scott: Well, there's only a few of those in the game.
Scott: If too many other players go before you they'll buy all the for trains up before it's your turn.
Rym: but if too many You might buy the for train and then other people can execute their plans and move right into the sixes and you get rusted And one of your companies and it's your bankrupt, right?
Scott: So that turn order just matters so much and you can pay attention to it and manipulate it which is a skill, right?
Rym: but you have very few levers with which to manipulate it and you're very much at the mercy of the other players and Physical turn order.
Scott: Yes, you do have few levers with which to manipulate it But you can see it so you can at least avoid falling into its trap, right?
Scott: If you're watching it closely, but the biggest problem is that it's just disappointing not to say that that's a bad game.
Scott: It's just like you come to the train game wanting to do train stuff and it's like you're not doing train stuff.
Rym: You're doing turn order stuff, but then I think oh well What I actually want to do like you realize the fun of this game is the corporate Shenanigans and the stock stuff like that's real fun.
Rym: But then you're like, oh, how do I execute the plan?
Rym: How do I fuck Scott over loot this company leave him with the shell the rotting husk?
Rym: Like how do I pull that off?
Rym: You know how to pull it off but the only way to actually execute it is to manipulate the turn order.
Rym: thus the turn order becomes the primary driver of success or failure.
Rym: But even worse the turn order becomes the primary determiner of whether or not you even have the option to do the fun part of the game.
Scott: So the second thing in this game is that It is not as bad as monopoly.
Scott: But we talked about this in a lot of our panels.
Scott: Oh, yeah The games that are over but they're not over right.
Scott: so a perfectly designed game of any kind a sport You know a children's game whatever Pong is actually like.
Rym: the first video game is a hundred percent perfect in this regard.
Scott: Right Pong which and well tennis is perfect.
Scott: Which is why Pong is perfect?
Scott: because they're the same a game at the start of the game.
Scott: a perfectly designed game.
Scott: all Participants teams or players right in an ortho game by the way a game with winning and losing.
Scott: Yep Should have a perfectly equal chance of winning.
Rym: So right now player player skill is a separate factor here.
Scott: We're talking about in terms of reactions that a player game state Yes, we're talking about based on game state alone at the start of a game Right all.
Scott: if it's a four player game all of the four players should have a 25% chance to win.
Scott: if it's a two player Game at the start of the game.
Scott: Both players have a 50% chance to win.
Scott: right then as soon as or before right one or more of the players reaches a Hundred percent chance to win the game should end.
Scott: if someone is at a hundred percent chance to win and the game has not yet Ended they're still playing the game which is for example what happens in Monopoly.
Scott: You've won the game.
Scott: your chance of winning is a hundred percent, but other players have not yet gone bankrupt.
Scott: So the game is not officially over the game is.
Scott: you're continuing to play a game meaninglessly.
Scott: garbage time.
Scott: That is a bad game design.
Scott: It is also a bad game design if one or more players have an extremely low or zero Percent chance to win and they are still playing and not eliminated.
Rym: Yep So I think 18. what happens of the three we've played suffers from that the most.
Rym: It's hard to say cuz 2038 I am incapable of reaching the end of that cave.
Scott: Well, I think part yeah, I think at 2038 we weren't cape We only played it once and we weren't capable of necessarily Feeling the percent chance to win, right?
Scott: So like if you don't realize if no one is good enough to realize that they have won or lost already Then the game can actually continue to be fun.
Scott: Yeah as you continue playing.
Rym: we talked about that way back way back in a review of railroad tycoon.
Rym: how even if you're losing the Manipulation of the game state is fun enough to where people tend to not care that they're losing or even real that right?
Scott: Well, that's losing should be fun.
Scott: right is that the game should be fun.
Scott: Even if you are losing and know it.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm saying is that if you don't know you're losing right then the game can still be fun.
Scott: If it wouldn't be fun if you knew you were losing exactly right or if you knew you'd already won Right.
Scott: The game could potentially still be fun like 1846 didn't know?
Scott: you already won.
Rym: I feel like there are more players have a little more agency in the very end of the game to alter the final sorting.
Rym: but in 1889 like the game ends and then it's just.
Rym: it's a spreadsheet of Alright, the last operating rounds 3x revenue that player wins and we know the game's over.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like, you know, you might get I got burnt.
Scott: I made a mistake early, right?
Scott: And that's every time I played these games.
Scott: I've never won ever not even once but I keep playing them.
Scott: Anyway, because every time I play I learn I make some horrible mistake that makes me lose And I learn and I don't make the same mistake again, and I just keep doing it and I make mistakes later.
Scott: Right, but unlike go which is the same exact learning pattern I hate playing go even though I respect go as a game is because in go there's too many cycles Right, and there's no heuristic.
Scott: I don't actually learn.
Scott: Well, I'll play go and lose and not know why I lost.
Scott: Yep If I play 1886 or 1889 I Just lost a game that took a couple days.
Scott: I learned 10 different things I did wrong and I'll never do any of those things more than once again.
Rym: And we're playing this online implementation so we can actually step back through the log like I'm looking at the first game.
Rym: we played the three-player one just to have It up on the screen.
Rym: I just look back through the log and you can pinpoint the exact moment a player made the mistake.
Scott: that loses them the game Right and notice how those mistakes I made in the first three-player game.
Scott: I did not make in the second one.
Rym: Yeah, the second one you made a mistake way later.
Rym: the problem was the mistakes you made in the second game set me up to get completely screwed when up to that point I had a chance of winning Right.
Scott: I think that I'll get to that later.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So so what the point is is that in this game, right?
Scott: I had made a mistake and lost relatively early.
Scott: I knew my percent chance of winning was basically zero.
Scott: once I had made that mistake It was still fun to continue playing to some extent.
Scott: but the game that's a that's a poor game design.
Scott: The game should have eliminated me or ended the game, right?
Scott: And then B we had reached a point in the game where we knew who won but the game was not yet over.
Scott: You had to do two more sets of whatever just doing math to figure to reveal who had won.
Scott: But the game should have ended because someone so interestingly at least 1889.
Rym: one of the rules is if a player actually goes bankrupt the gate It's not that they're eliminated the game just immediately and that is a good rule.
Rym: that if you do actually go fully bankrupt the game I feel like let's say the fiction there is the government comes in is like what the fuck just happened in here.
Scott: Yes, exactly.
Scott: That is perfect.
Scott: That actually happened to me the first time I played Or the second time I forget second time.
Scott: But anyway, the point is that that's a good rule.
Scott: But you could get really close to bankrupt without being bankrupt and the game would continue but you would be suffering and losing the whole time.
Scott: Stuck in this game for no reason.
Rym: Yep Now that I guess the other.
Rym: the interesting thing about the games is that the stock rounds as fun as they are They're extremely constrained in very specific ways to where a lot of the clever things you think you'd be able to do you really can't because you can sell any number of shares or Buy and or buy exactly one share,
Scott: right?
Scott: You can sell a whole bunch and buy one.
Scott: you can buy one then sell a whole bunch.
Scott: Usually you would sell first to get the money to buy with.
Scott: yeah, right?
Scott: Doesn't really matter what the order is, right?
Scott: But basically you can buy exactly one share and you can sell as many as you want and you kept it.
Scott: You can't mix them up.
Scott: You can't like sell buy sell Yeah, sell buy or buy sell and then it's the next person's turn and you can only buy one total share.
Scott: This is why the turn order matters a lot.
Scott: I can't just come in.
Scott: I mean I guess the turnator might matter more if you could buy as many as you want.
Scott: cuz like I go first I buy ten shares.
Rym: Yeah, but but that that's where the turn order that stock round is a little is not quite granular enough Coupled with all these other rules that really can straight like there's rails on the game get it.
Rym: but the rails are things like If once someone's selling stock because you never Trump buy and sell stock between players You're basically always selling it to the market and buying it back from the market.
Rym: But there's all these rules like no one player can own more than 60% of any company.
Rym: No one player No one can sell stock into the market.
Rym: Once there is 50% of the shares of that stock in the market There's all these sort of guardrails that prevent a lot of potentially interesting things from happening.
Rym: I know the reality of why those rules are in place is because with these rules as written The game does not work and breaks without those rules.
Rym: But I feel like a better designed stock round could remove a lot of those restrictions and let players go a little more hog wild while still being Interesting and while still giving players the agency to pull off those ridiculous maneuvers without giving other players No chance to defend themselves.
Rym: There's a sweet spot there that no one has found.
Scott: Yep You know I'm not sure if it's people trying who designed these games trying to stick to some sort of historical.
Rym: Oh There is definitely a little bit of trying to go cult design and that a lot of 18xx games Do things because other 18xx games a person liked did them.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it's definitely it's.
Scott: it feels a lot like You know, there was D&D and that everyone had their D&D mod.
Scott: Yeah, right 18xx is like.
Scott: well there was the original 18xx game and then everyone published their little mod and Actually made them into real games as opposed to just their home brew, right?
Scott: So it's like it's like here's a whole world of every single person's D&D homebrew where they change the rules Just the way they like.
Scott: but they have you know, they've changed them in ways that do significantly make them different.
Rym: games Like 1846 and 1889 come.
Rym: I engage with them completely differently.
Rym: I feel completely differently about them while I'm playing.
Scott: I like them both equally for different reasons Yep, but they're still at their core the same sort of thing, right?
Scott: It's not a bigger divergence, right?
Scott: It's like fixing D&D with by making Pathfinder.
Scott: Yeah, it feels different, but it's still the same thing.
Scott: It's a turn-based miniatures combat RPG kind of thing.
Scott: Yeah, right Even though you you you shimmied it over and fix them and that's the thing.
Rym: without you didn't leave the arena without some testing and some Fuzzing around and doing some math.
Rym: It's hard to tell from play Which of those guardrail rules are there because someone found a problem and that was their solution.
Rym: Versus which ones were basically copy pasted from a different 18xx game, right?
Scott: It's very what I think is what I think is missing from a lot of these games.
Scott: Is that a?
Scott: They're clearly political games because they're multiplayer games where you can interact with each other.
Rym: We played Chris had a choice of which of the two other players who because they like we're playing this online implementation.
Rym: one cool thing it does is it shows that any time the total worth of any player because in the end your score is how much money you personally have Including all us here the value of your stocks Yeah.
Rym: So it shows that at Every pointer in the game and there was a critical turn where you are already done You were out of the game.
Rym: your worth was like half everyone else's But the rest of us were basically equal in worth.
Rym: and on that round Chris dumped a bunch of the stock and a company that I own the most of instead of someone else which pulled me way down.
Rym: There's.
Rym: that is a political decision.
Rym: I like that about these games.
Rym: Like I don't want them to become a political.
Rym: That's a very different kind of game.
Rym: But the politics is definitely there though.
Rym: I think what are a lot of players?
Rym: It's highly obfuscated by the mechanics.
Rym: I think a lot of players think these games are more deterministic than they are and Don't understand.
Scott: There's no randomness.
Scott: Yeah, there's no randomness other than the original turn order.
Scott: Yep, right.
Scott: So I think that what I want what I want politics wise is I wish there were more enforceable Politics just a little bit right?
Scott: So for example, let's say two people Bought too many private companies in the original auction and they can't float alone, right?
Scott: But they could float together, right if they wanted to.
Scott: but because of turn order one person the person who goes first would have by The first share help and then that next person is not Man, they don't they can't.
Scott: there's nothing to enforce them to say you're floating.
Rym: this game Scott starts to float.
Rym: a company is like room.
Rym: I can float this if you help me and I'm like, yeah sure comes to my Turn I float a different company.
Rym: Fuck you Right.
Scott: It's just no there's nothing to do about it, right?
Scott: I wish there was some.
Scott: I'm sure it's some of these.
Scott: 18xx have deal-making.
Scott: Yeah, there shouldn't be just free wheelie deal.
Rym: deal make no cuz they're just making us general up like a badge.
Rym: that are real confluence.
Scott: Yeah, no, no.
Scott: No, I don't want that level of stuff But I do want there should be some sort of.
Scott: you know, there is a solution.
Scott: There's a very especially That also helps you with that problem of your chance to win is low You clearly see another winner if you could make a for sure alliance right of some kind.
Scott: that's somewhat enforceable.
Scott: or as actual in-game Effect there is a specific solution that I pass to coming back that I almost want to try to Write down and try to play 1889.
Rym: I might just play it by myself just to make sure the math all works.
Rym: There's an elegant solution to that.
Rym: But before I reveal my elegant solution, I want to back up to another point you made about the politics.
Rym: one flaw in these games is that political risk Which what I mean by that is there are actions you can take in this game that are not that do not expose you to Political risk meaning because you bought 10% of a company.
Rym: No one can just arbitrarily fuck you over because of that.
Rym: But once you buy 20% of a company that someone else owns depending on turn order You've opened yourself up to political risk where another player may have.
Scott: if you have a better turn order You haven't opened yourself up But at least not in the next round.
Scott: because and but then if the turn order word?
Scott: because as long as you can make it To the next round you could just sell the shares and you're safe.
Rym: There's almost no Operational risk and minimal market risk in this game.
Rym: The only risk you can actually expose yourself to is political risk Which means that generally if you're tied or slightly behind the only options you have to get ahead.
Rym: There's no Like risk assessment you can do because all the actions that only incur market risk will not Be enough to matter.
Rym: so you end up having to expose yourself to political risk.
Rym: But there's no low-level political risk in this game.
Rym: If you expose yourself to a political risk in this game either you're fine, or you're completely fucked.
Rym: There's almost no little ground can't any point.
Scott: You can't actually climb in this game.
Scott: All you can do is push other people down.
Scott: See if you push everyone else down because they expose themselves and got burned and you're left on top Yeah, you've got all this money.
Scott: You can buy all the shares.
Scott: You will just naturally rise.
Scott: all the companies just rise.
Rym: so I got burned once in the late game, which is fine.
Rym: That's what you expect.
Rym: So now I was behind a little bit.
Rym: the two players who were ahead of me were neck and neck and there was nothing I could Do to push down both of them and due to the way the stocks evolved I ended up not being able to push down either of them in any meaningful way.
Rym: Meanwhile you were basically out of the game.
Rym: pushing you down would help me a little but it wouldn't hurt.
Rym: It's like hurting you doesn't matter and helping me doesn't help you to hurt me.
Scott: Yep, I can help you to hurt me if I've already taken a hurt exactly but simultaneously I'm already out.
Rym: there was no action.
Rym: We could take together to try to rise up together Because it was late-game.
Scott: there were no not with not.
Scott: what they've not with the rules is written.
Rym: Yeah, exactly Those are the kinds I think.
Scott: the other things is that if you want to I would either.
Scott: So because the turn order is so important.
Scott: I think I would either a put in more direct turn order Mitigation or management mechanics.
Scott: so for example you might bid on turn order you might.
Scott: Everyone starts at the same amount of money right, but if going first is better Why should the first player start with the same amount of money right?
Scott: It's like a basic board game.
Scott: balance thing.
Scott: right is like Puerto Rico the first three people get in to go.
Scott: the last two people Get corn cuz going.
Scott: last is worse.
Scott: Yeah, so the corn balances it out, right?
Scott: It's like this simple stuff like that to mitigate that turn order thing a little bit yeah, but you can't mitigate it too much without making others and even changes to the or or Eliminate turn order and make it more about simultaneous actions.
Scott: if you eliminate turn order now the game is actually about.
Scott: that's what I'm on.
Rym: I want to workshop and try not about turn order with the idea of a simultaneous market.
Rym: like you basically write a limit price On a bunch of orders you've reveal them all simultaneously.
Rym: players orders execute against each other and then anything that doesn't execute against a player executes against the back.
Rym: there's a system you could come up with but one of my worries is that if you remove that obfuscation and remove the player turn order and Made the stock rounds like more of a game I think what happens is you reveal how little Most of the other mechanics matter to the point that they can be completely eliminated And you've made a completely different game.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's what it is.
Scott: is that all of the 18 excess games.
Scott: I've played it's that there is these multiple It's.
Scott: it's hard to develop heuristics and make decisions because the thing you're directly Interacting with is is sort of hiding the truth.
Rym: You know what it's like.
Scott: It's like playing always talk about how it's it right.
Scott: well people talk about it's a spreadsheet game right, but it's like well, okay There's a lot of spreadsheet games out there.
Scott: You know people are talking about like you know Eve or whatever Eve online right.
Scott: the way this spreadsheet works.
Scott: Is that your the inputs you have right?
Scott: It's like you're taking turns messing with the spreadsheet first of all.
Scott: so when you when you get to mess with it matters a ton.
Scott: Oh because who knows what it's gonna look like by the time you get your hands on it?
Scott: You could only put an inputs on the far left Right.
Scott: those inputs directly affect things like on page two of the spreadsheet.
Scott: So you're looking at page one and page two right and you're like okay?
Scott: I'll take this on page one.
Scott: this happens on page two.
Scott: I type this on page one this up And that's where you're thinking right when you're when you're new to these games.
Scott: But actually page two is affecting something on page three and maybe even page four and that's what the real game is and you Can't see that because it's not told to you.
Scott: You have to just like dig deep and be like oh Buying this share here Right means that the value that is the tenth share in this company's the end of the stock round.
Scott: it will bump up.
Scott: it will Bump up.
Scott: therefore it will go first.
Scott: It is someone else's company.
Scott: They get to go first.
Scott: therefore that company will be able to put a token on that spot on the train track Which means that the company that goes after it is gonna Its trains are gonna run shittily because that token will be blocking them.
Scott: right.
Scott: so it's like oh You're thinking when you made that decision Right just like oh that company.
Scott: That's a valuable share.
Scott: It's gonna increase in value.
Scott: Why wouldn't I buy a sound investment right?
Scott: But actually you have fucked over this other company quite a bit because of the token situation on the map.
Scott: Right by buying a share Which is you can't see that kind of thing.
Scott: how are you concerned?
Rym: on obvious you get to the situation where you can see it?
Rym: but you have no agency to manipulate the turn order to avoid it because of Some other player passed and now there's like there's literally no way to get the player to your left to take an action before you pass.
Rym: There's no way to go first.
Scott: Right it's like okay now that I've seen that this token thing is a possibility right.
Scott: What can I do?
Scott: It's like you're not.
Scott: there's no move you make.
Scott: that's like they get ahead.
Rym: move It's the overt disaster disaster or fuck someone else and get way ahead.
Scott: It's basically don't step on landmine Yes Right.
Scott: and then hope try to get other players to step on your land mines that you set.
Scott: now don't think they steps.
Scott: all you know What this?
Scott: everyone's.
Scott: everyone's always walking forward.
Rym: 18xx games are just spy versus spy on the NES Kind.
Scott: that's what this game.
Scott: everyone's.
Scott: everyone is always marching forward Right and you sort of snowball as you move forward because the more money you have the more money you make in a stock market Right the more shares you own.
Scott: right.
Scott: all the shares are moving up.
Scott: mostly they can move down a little bit but but can't really like lose all your money on a bad event.
Rym: despite the fact that we Just spent like 45 minutes kind of like really nitpicking all these fiddly rules and complaining about them.
Rym: These games are still very fun.
Scott: Yeah I think that's the thing that's that makes this such so much discussion about them.
Scott: is that there's this core that is crazy fun Right and you you learn something new every time that you can Unlike go where you lose.
Scott: you don't know why you lost.
Scott: you lose every time and you know why you lost and you keep improving.
Scott: Which gives you this fun?
Scott: Cycle of learning every single time.
Scott: right you get lots even if you lose.
Scott: right you get this Sort of reward.
Scott: right you don't feel bad about it.
Scott: it's fun to play and What you?
Scott: there's a strong desire, which is why every time we talk about these games I feel like people who play these games.
Scott: when I see them talk they talk about the game Whereas when me and Rym talk we talk about how to fix the game.
Scott: yep, and the read.
Scott: we do that for every game But we do it especially for these games because there's this sort of disappointment and also sort of Excitement of having like you found a buried treasure, but we need to drag it out of the dungeon.
Rym: Yeah, because like the game's bad.
Rym: We don't nitpick the mechanics.
Rym: We look at the mechanics like wow fuck this game, and we don't exactly don't want to save it.
Rym: We're happy to let it die.
Scott: we don't even we're like.
Scott: we're like oh man look at this great stuff We found in this 18xx game.
Scott: How the hell do we get this good stuff out and not and and remove all this mess.
Scott: wait a minute.
Rym: so if 18xx games are just Are just five or spy on the NES then you and I playing 18xx games is just torchbearer.
Rym: We're just trying to get the stock round and the operating round out of the dungeon somehow.
Scott: Well there are games out there the city of the big shoulders.
Rym: They always leave something be.
Scott: I learned about this.
Scott: other one recently Called what was?
Scott: I forget what it was called, but basically it's a game where there's still.
Scott: they'd have that meta game of stock buying and then operating right and I think That's a good that people have recognized that you could take that meta structure where the meta game is the real game Around some other game.
Scott: that could be literally anything like you could take carcass Oh, and I'd be like all right instead of you being a color We're gonna buy stocks in the different colors and then after we've done buying stocks Whoever has the most stocks in a color will place the tile and the meeple for that color.
Rym: Yeah, and then shareholders get victory points split among themselves.
Scott: Right exactly, and it's like you know.
Scott: you could just play the stock carcass on like that.
Scott: right you do it to any game.
Scott: So that's been recognized and done, but I think there is so much potential in that model that has been Unfulfilled.
Scott: yeah Desire to work on that.
Rym: for whatever reason 18xx games have touched the face of God in all these places But they haven't quite pulled it all together under coherent experience.
Scott: It's like they're sitting on the face of God, but they don't know it.
Scott: Like they're riding around on a giant turtle, but they don't know they're on giant turtle.
Rym: I think it's partly because the games are.
Scott: it's like I see the turtle and I'm like oh my god How do I ride on the turtle.
Rym: but also I've noticed that the community around these games?
Rym: Tends to hyper focus on the games themselves, and it's relatively small.
Rym: And I'm not saying they don't recognize flaws in the games and have opinions about them.
Scott: But they have to be very all have different opinions with which ones they like the best and you know.
Rym: But there's very little like willingness to discuss radical changes to the games like that doesn't I know.
Scott: they want to play 18xx They want to play what it is.
Scott: They don't want to play.
Scott: They don't want to just take these certain parts that we like where we like parts.
Scott: They like everything that's in there.
Rym: So to get back to the thing I said before then I think we've talked about this game enough.
Rym: The way to fix that binding problem without making it a game where we're just making deals forever like binding deals is to add Without changing any other rule in 1889.
Rym: I think this would work.
Rym: you add the concept players a third option during the stock round.
Rym: you can buy You can sell or you can sell a futures contract to another player.
Scott: Well there is one that there's a New York one that has short selling.
Rym: yeah short sell.
Rym: well I have ideas about short selling But that doesn't solve the problem of you.
Rym: and I want to make a deal to float a company Right with a futures contract.
Rym: the way it would work is I would sell you.
Rym: let's say we want to flow I want to float a company.
Rym: I want to get you to agree to help me float that company you actually want to.
Rym: but the game has non-binding rules And we both know whichever one of us moves first the other one's just gonna fuck them over and go over someone else Right.
Scott: so that's the best move.
Rym: so I sell you a futures contract.
Rym: I say for $300.
Rym: I Will sell you a contract where in x-turns or in one turn or I gotta figure out the details on this you Must buy three shares of that company from me or this or ice or have them Now.
Rym: buy them from me.
Scott: Alright you give me cash now.
Rym: now I have your cash and my cash.
Rym: you have a futures contract.
Rym: You are obligated to buy those shares from me.
Rym: I am obligated to sell them to you.
Rym: we have agreed on the price of that transaction and cash was exchanged accordingly.
Rym: and then as I buy all the stock I go through the whole float.
Rym: I float the whole thing and then I hand those shares over to you for the agreed-upon price.
Scott: Right two turns later.
Scott: Here's the shares.
Rym: yep And yeah, I think that would work without changing any other rule in 1889 But I don't know if I am non lazy enough to try it.
Scott: Yeah, who knows?
Rym: Play testing is the is the hard part of game making yep And you can only get so far just reading your own rules and playing your game in your mind or playing it against yourself.
Rym: Yep, that's a good way to design a game that only you are good at sure All right, so yeah 1889. now we've talked about three of these different train games.
Rym: if I had to rank them 1889 still my favorite then 1846 and 2038 is without a digital implementation Unplayable by me.
Scott: I just haven't played enough of them to have a real opinion on favorite.
Rym: Yeah Well, I'm I do want to play.
Rym: I want to play.
Scott: do you want to yeah?
Scott: I do want to call attention to on the GMT games website There is currently it's sort of.
Scott: it's not.
Scott: it's not a Kickstarter But basically they have this program They call the p500 program where when enough copies of a game are pre-ordered then they make the game.
Scott: So there is a game 1833 ne which is 1833, New England Rariting in New England and it is an 18xx game and it's on a New England map.
Scott: and They are have already been 734 orders of this game and if you order it now it'll cost you $58.
Scott: you wait It'll cost you $84.
Scott: so I ordered it already for $58.
Scott: I'll play that but And it's an 18xx game and not a New England map.
Scott: And I think that it also comes with an 1846 like mini expansion.
Scott: so if you already have 1846 or if you have a friend who has 1846 then You're good to go.
Scott: and also the designer of 1833, New England is Tom Lehman who has made almost most of the great games.
Scott: you know.
Scott: so You know race for the galaxy.
Scott: I think right pretty sure that's the guy Right.
Scott: yeah for the galaxy pandemic great.
Scott: Did he make pandemic also, maybe yeah?
Rym: I'm just.
Rym: I'm looking at the map of 1833 ne right now.
Rym: Yeah, I got distracted.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website At front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But for different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Rym: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are As soon as this sort Returns the correct list of names there we go.
Rym: Ellenjoy said to me nickel Mardi Gras need just like a dude guy shirts option linkage.
Rym: you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: But she packed my suitcase and sent me on my way.
Rym: Clinton Walton Jay Vance ran for New Zealand Ryan parent rope and letter Nicholas Brando.
Rym: the thirst for hydrated Gannon Dread lives had a break.
Rym: Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Thomas on Shervin Harle and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names.
Rym: So we are continuing to stream the show.
Rym: we're continuing to improve our pipeline.
Rym: the teleprompters set up this weekend.
Rym: I'm gonna be doing some further testing to Continue some new things we're working on.
Rym: stay tuned.
Rym: I don't think we'll review any more train games until we play a new one.
Rym: I don't know if we'll play a new one anytime soon, but now I leave you with.
Scott: Look who's riding the man?
Scott: 200 feet is pretty.
Scott: How Goes up When you see it you won't believe it.
Rym: the men XL 200 get to the point.