Rym: It's Monday, August 17th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We have an update from 2007.
Rym: We are revisiting the topic of removable media.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: so, uh Yesterday like I do every weekend.
Rym: I ran a half marathon and At one point I was near the RFK bridge like coming over the bridge back from Randall's Island like 10 miles into this run Feeling great like going faster than usual cuz it's cool out and there's a cop car sitting there.
Rym: So I yell defund the police and black lives matter at this cop car And they yell something at me and then I flip them off because they're being weird and I keep running.
Rym: They do a screeching u-turn and start following me slowly.
Rym: Yeah, so I just I turn and I just keep running and I run up a one-way street and they can't follow me.
Rym: That's the end of that.
Rym: then I'm on the I'm based on Vernon Boulevard like in the homestretch like my last mile and A cop car which I now realize is the same cop car Pulls into the bike lane behind me and follows me for like a mile very slowly and they keep doing their siren a little bit.
Scott: What what what?
Scott: Yeah, they love that.
Rym: Yep, and then they start yelling at me out the window.
Rym: Hey fuck.
Rym: Oh, what's your problem?
Rym: Is the exact words they said?
Rym: they kept kept yelling it.
Rym: So I stopped away from them and the guys like come here and I'm like, am I free to leave?
Rym: Am I free to leave?
Rym: I did the whole.
Rym: am I being detained?
Rym: Am I being detained?
Rym: Am I free to leave?
Scott: So it's so annoying that like that is simultaneously right the right thing to do.
Scott: Well, it's also a thing that assholes.
Rym: It's also a thing that sob sits to.
Scott: it's like I learned that you know Correct thing to do from like shitty white libertarian assholes, right and it's like, ah, so it's like.
Scott: it's so dirty But it's also the right thing to do in the US and the United States.
Rym: So Eventually, they finally are like yes, you're free to leave.
Rym: so I'd start running again.
Rym: They waited in the bike lane for a while and then gun their engine and charged me with the car swerved away at the last Second and splashed me with a giant wave of water and then they sped off down the street ran a red light and turned left.
Scott: Yeah, that's what cops do.
Rym: So I called 9-1-1 and I learned some things.
Rym: So one in New York, if you call 9-1-1 New York City or New York City on the police They go into a different mode.
Rym: They do not forward it to the police.
Scott: They forward a mode a different mode where they write your name down in the book So that I'm sure my name is in a book somewhere now.
Rym: but instead the the 9-1-1 operator got like really worried and like called someone else into the conference call from the internal affairs division and got a detective on the line with me and basically a cop.
Rym: This is a cop in IAV like a different share.
Rym: She was kind of awesome.
Rym: She Basically, I described what happened ending to be awesome.
Scott: She was like she's like who exactly do I need to high-five later?
Rym: No, she actually took my formal complaint and I will have the likely Privilege of testifying against these two cops at a later date in an internal hearing Uh-huh.
Rym: So yeah, because basically very surprised if that anything comes about say so basically what was interesting is one.
Rym: they thought they put me on hold at one point and They had a conversation where they was clear.
Rym: They did not think I could hear them.
Rym: Mm-hmm The detective lady who sounded like a black woman Was basically she was saying things to the effect of this shit again.
Rym: Who who what can?
Rym: what cars were in that area?
Rym: There are only two cars in the story.
Rym: I want to know which one of them was on the story of Boulevard and Vernon Boulevard and she was like she was mad.
Rym: And then then there's like that there's and also the 9-1 operator was like, oh, yeah I got the call for this and they exchange all these codes and it was a long conversation.
Rym: Then like she's like, okay I'm gonna get this guy back out and then it cuts back to.
Rym: They get quiet and then they call me back in and they're very like professional and like normal again, and that was really funny.
Rym: I wish I could I wish I could have recorded that but it was a 911 calls and my phone was like in that weird No one calls her a public.
Rym: Yeah, so I could do an f.o.i.a.
Rym: And get the audio of this.
Scott: Yeah, if you should because otherwise I'm piling a whole salt cellar full of salt and any Rym stories like no That that part happened pretty straight up.
Rym: and what then when detective got back on what she basically said to me was Asking if I'm being detained was the right thing to do.
Rym: That's the only reason I probably have a case Mmm, because it's like.
Scott: I said, it's the right thing to do, but it's also that.
Rym: And then she was like did they give you did you give you an opportunity?
Rym: To ask for their badge number?
Rym: after they said you were free to leave and I said no they immediately left.
Rym: and then she was Like that is the second part.
Rym: We'll get back to you so we'll see what happens.
Scott: I mean, it's not illegal to just yell at cops.
Rym: Nope, exactly, but it is according to that detective lady assault to splash someone on purpose with your car Really?
Rym: Yeah That is technically.
Scott: you prove that they splashed you with their car.
Rym: I will see because there were some way.
Scott: how much how much were you splashed?
Rym: So they backed up and they gunned it through the bike lane at high and they're half.
Scott: there happened to be a puddle thing.
Rym: Oh, it was during that rainstorm.
Rym: I was running after that giant rainstorm Sunday.
Rym: It was like a god.
Rym: it was to the point that I got a guy who was running like further back Stopped and were like, holy shit.
Rym: Are you okay?
Rym: I actually got his details.
Rym: He was a witness and I gave those details to the cop.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: So all that was.
Rym: that was a fun Sunday.
Rym: So then I just finished my run and went home like normal.
Scott: All right, I biked over the the Tappan Zee Bridge again.
Rym: We're thinking about doing that this coming weekend.
Rym: We're gonna go up in the up Jersey down New York.
Rym: seems like they're right.
Scott: Well, that's well, that's what I did.
Scott: And so there were.
Scott: there were two problems, right?
Scott: It's a problem.
Scott: One is the route that I used.
Scott: I was not aware of this one Hill, but I got to.
Scott: You know Elevation wise the hill was you know, it was the tallest hill of the ride But it wasn't that much taller than the first big hill and it wasn't.
Scott: you know The elevation of the first hill was not a problem.
Scott: Yeah The problem was the steepness of the second Hill.
Scott: It was like I look at it and it's like looks like it's straight up Google Street View.
Scott: It doesn't look as scary And the straight up part wasn't actually that long.
Scott: It was like this the hill just starts with a straight-up part, right?
Scott: Like it starts with a straight-up part and that straight-up part was just too steep And I had to like walk that tiny little straight-up part and then I went week a week a week a week on the rest Of the hill, you know, no problem.
Rym: So actually the previous weekend right after the hurricane We went up this.
Rym: we went up from Van Cortlandt Park.
Rym: We went past that fence that everyone tore down and took the South County Trailway extension like all the way north.
Scott: How did you get?
Scott: I couldn't get through.
Scott: so here's the thing.
Rym: It's open.
Rym: So people just cut the fence.
Rym: It's just open.
Scott: No, no, no, no.
Scott: No, so on the way back Right my way back.
Scott: I was coming down the county trail where the trees still blocking it and I can't know There's no trees.
Scott: There was at least one chainsaw it up, you know cleaned away tree during the part.
Rym: That's the part that's technically open.
Rym: All right, they did not clean up any trees and the part that's technically closed.
Scott: Anyway, so I point is I was coming down south and I get to the end of the county trail way to where the Putnam Trail Begins and there's that little fence there, right?
Scott: No, there was like a mega fence completely surrounding it on all sides and I couldn't get around.
Rym: there's a path.
Rym: I've seen that fence.
Rym: I have pictures of it.
Rym: not to the right.
Rym: There's a path.
Rym: people have cut a hole in the fence and marked it.
Scott: I could not see any way through.
Rym: we've gone through that hole multiple times.
Rym: In fact, right there in the north You'll see a bunch of other people also using this path.
Scott: I was on the north side trying to get through the fence and I couldn't get through.
Rym: It's a. you have to walk like two or three minutes like out of your way But there's a little path that goes around that fence that people keep.
Rym: every time they patch it up people cut it again.
Rym: I've used it many times.
Scott: I couldn't get through the fence.
Scott: I tried anyway.
Rym: That is definitely open.
Scott: It was a hundred percent sealed fence.
Rym: It was definitely not so.
Rym: but if you got in there The one thing you order it into is there are five Separate trees that are huge and are blocking the path so bad that you'll have to like Climb up on top of the tree like get someone to hand your bike up to you toss your bike down the other side.
Scott: Anyway, that would have been better than what I had to do Which is go way around like on some weird roads like on a fence But there's like me but like on the edge of the park between the highway and I know where that is.
Rym: I know that bullshit.
Rym: you can kind of get to the motion Lou, but not quite.
Scott: They eventually got to the marshal.
Scott: then I was fine.
Rym: Yeah, but you're like Trail for a while.
Scott: getting from getting from that fence to the marshal ooh without being able to go through the fence was Shité.
Rym: I'm pretty sure I have a Strava of me doing that one time with Emily before we learned the gnosis of Just go around the fence.
Rym: There's a path.
Scott: I couldn't get through the fence.
Scott: Yeah, that fence will be down soon enough though They finished the paving.
Rym: it looks like uh, no They're the paving was not done because we've.
Rym: we rode that whole path the weekend before you took your ride.
Rym: They did finish the bridges.
Rym: But there's a lot more paving work that has to be done and it's filled with this.
Rym: sound trees.
Scott: There's still mud action going on there.
Rym: you have to walk through the mud a few times to get around Other fences they've put up and to get
Scott: just literally like put literally any other way to get her like a legit way Just like make a temporary detour of some kind so that you can get from there.
Scott: It's like just somewhere else in the park, but it's like no from that fence.
Scott: if you don't break through the fence there's literally nothing to do besides hike in the woods and get muddy.
Scott: one time is a Temporary path of some kind to the to the West we go.
Rym: we took the secret path.
Rym: We biked all the way south and we got to the bottom.
Rym: There's a big fence blocking the entrance to VanCotland Park.
Rym: So we were trapped.
Rym: We were ready to go all the way back up and around From like the end of the way at the bot at the bottom near the golf course entrance.
Scott: There's also big mega fence.
Rym: Yeah, so we we got there at a time when the fence was in place and you know what.
Rym: there was there two other bikers One of whom had some wire cutters and he was literally snipping the fence one by one.
Rym: Yeah, he caught a big hole in the fence, but it was taking him a while.
Rym: So we went back.
Rym: There's a secret path to the right over there Like hundred yards before the dead end and if you go right you can get into the golf course and around and get back out.
Scott: Mmm, it's still annoying.
Rym: I know all the secret paths to use that bootleg bike path.
Scott: It's not how it's supposed to be legit.
Rym: It's not done yet.
Rym: So it's bootleg.
Scott: It should be done.
Scott: What's taking us all over it?
Rym: I think is the reason it's not done.
Scott: No, it just gives you know, they've been working.
Scott: They've not been work.
Scott: you see I think is if cove is your excuse they should have made zero progress on it, right?
Scott: But they've actually made a ton of progress on it.
Scott: Someone's working on it.
Scott: Well, if you think it's safe enough to work on it, then it's safe enough to finish it, right?
Rym: I think you're just taking them a while because there's less people Distributed.
Scott: I wouldn't I wouldn't complain if they had done no work on it.
Scott: I'd be like, oh that's understandable They've done no work on this clearly.
Scott: It's not safe to come out here work.
Rym: Oh, I can.
Rym: actually I can shows I could share something about that because what I noticed was every time we use that path There was more progress until the hurricane Once all the trees were down like like there's.
Rym: you should see I got some pictures of these fucking trees that are down across that thing.
Rym: They no one is available to chainsaw up those trees.
Scott: They're only chainsaw trees on the county trail.
Rym: They only chainsaw trees and public trails not in not yet open trails.
Rym: They prioritize because there aren't that many people who can go change all those trees.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, that's our bike nights is back guys.
Rym: That's the story.
Scott: And more bike nights news, I got the the fancy bike trainers.
Rym: Oh, how is it?
Rym: Cuz we got to get something before.
Rym: I feel like late fall.
Rym: Everyone's gonna buy bike trainers.
Rym: They're all gonna be sold out.
Scott: I mean, it's not here yet, but you should definitely.
Scott: I already know that it's the best one.
Scott: The point is I'm gonna get some Zwift action going on.
Scott: So look for some Zwift streaming.
Scott: if you don't know what Google for zwift As the alt, you know, you're down the bike road if you're doing Zwift All Right, so I guess it's Monday.
Rym: we should I go out some news.
Rym: there is pretty much like the biggest news.
Rym: This is the biggest news in gaming.
Rym: It's also Some of the biggest news in tech because of the escalation that has occurred not just would have been big news anyway But because of the escalation this is more.
Scott: Yeah, so we recently talked about the antitrust hearing in the house how it's one of the best Hearings we've seen recently, you know, there's some you know, some good ones in the past.
Scott: There's also a good one, right.
Scott: and how?
Scott: Apple, you know Apple in terms of antitrust is a lot less to complain about than say Google or Facebook, right?
Scott: Or right, but there's still with something to complain about which is mostly the App Store, right?
Scott: In that yeah, they charge if you have a store an app in the App Store, right?
Scott: First of all, you cannot get your app onto Apple's App Store unless Apple approves Yep, and secondly if you do put an app in Apple's App Store They make you you know Do things like use Apple login.
Scott: or especially the biggest one is if you want to collect money from your customers in your app let's say you know your Amazon and you have a Kindle app and you want to sell books or Your Rym and you want to you make a special podcast app and you want to sell podcasts.
Scott: now Right.
Scott: or you make a video game and you put it in the App Store and you want to sell gambling All of that money.
Scott: if people spend the money directly in the app You can make people go to like your website to spend the money and therefore in the app There is no way to spend money.
Scott: The Apple is okay with that But if you want people to give you money directly in the app, you must do it the Apple way right and You Apple takes a 30% cut.
Scott: They also take a 30% cut of the price of your app itself.
Scott: So if your game that you're selling in the App Store is 20 bucks What's 30% of 20 bucks like now?
Rym: on one hand one could argue that Apple does not have a novelty 75 but Apple does not have a monopoly on smartphones.
Rym: So this like the only monopoly here ostensibly is that Apple has a boutique device?
Rym: That is not even the majority device in this space.
Rym: And if you use their boutique device, you're beholden to their weird rules in their closed walled garden ecosystem.
Rym: Like if you don't like it, you could go to Android Could be made.
Scott: that is the argument that Apple makes.
Rym: indeed Yeah, and it's kind of a fair argument because Apple is not even the majority market share compared to Android for a lot of reasons Right, but it's funny how it's like Apple.
Scott: It's like when you see an Apple keynote app, right and they're reporting all like their numbers.
Scott: They're like look at how many phones we sold.
Scott: Look how much share we have.
Scott: Look how great we are.
Scott: big big numbers and that the antitrust hearing they're like, oh, no, we we're so small We didn't sell the most phones.
Scott: We we don't have the most market share.
Scott: It's like which one is it bro, which one is it Tim Apple?
Scott: are you big or small?
Scott: Make up your mind.
Rym: I'm looking for good numbers.
Rym: They're actually weirdly hard to find in a cursory Google.
Scott: I Was measuring in different, you know metrics.
Rym: I saw it.
Rym: I just did one Google.
Rym: one said Android 75% iOS 25% and another one said Android 51%.
Scott: so Yep, exactly You have to pay like a you know, some sort of group to get numbers.
Scott: You can maybe trust.
Rym: Yeah So but all this aside, so yeah Apple Basically kicked well, so really epic games with fortnight played a game with Apple.
Rym: They seem to try to get Apple to kick them out to then trigger this lawsuit and they seem to have Follow-up responses prepared for the things Apple was likely to do.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's the big news.
Scott: So it seems like what happened.
Scott: is You know epic?
Scott: who makes fortnight and the epic game store and such things Right.
Scott: They were like, alright, we're tired of Apple taking a 30% cut of all our fortnight monies for our mobile app.
Scott: Right and Google taking a cut of all our monies, you know, whatever.
Scott: so, you know What?
Scott: if we you know put in our app right away to for people to pay us directly?
Scott: It's like well, it wouldn't get approved in the App Store.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: Well, here's we can get around that We'll make our app so we can update it, you know what.
Scott: so that we don't have to push out an App Store update We'll make like, you know, we'll do a back-end push, right?
Scott: We'll run the shop part off the back end and that way we can surprise and put that in our game In our app without having to push an App Store update and get approval.
Scott: and they're like, alright Well, then Apple's just gonna kick us out of the store.
Scott: What do we do then?
Scott: Ah, then we'll sue them.
Scott: Yeah But then Apple will take away all our developer access and we won't even be able to Continue because there are other people who are making apps for the App Store that are approved and totally legit Using the Unreal Engine.
Scott: we have a whole team of people working on the Unreal Engine Right and making sure that the Unreal Engine can build iOS apps.
Rym: the Unreal Engine remember is run by epic games.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So you're an independent developer.
Scott: you pay or for free.
Scott: use the Unreal Engine to make iOS games Right or make a game that's multi-platform including iOS and you want your game to be approved in the App Store, right?
Scott: So you use Unreal Engine you make a game.
Scott: Let's say we made GeekNights the game using the Unreal Engine.
Scott: Okay well, there's people at epic working on the Unreal Engine and They need Apple development kits so that they can make sure the Unreal Engine works, you know and Builds iOS apps properly so that all the other people using Unreal Engine to make iOS apps right are gonna be okay.
Scott: If they lose all our developer access.
Scott: Well, then that means that whole team of people who work on the iOS aspects of Unreal Engine Can't work because all their Apple development kits stop working and they will not be able to update the unreal tournament developer the Unreal Engine development kits To people who are developing iOS apps with that engine.
Rym: So a fundamental question here is gonna come down to Can Apple Take these kinds of actions against their like boutique market share in their web garden or not, right?
Scott: so epic saw all these things in advance and rather than have their lawyers like Scramble overnight to respond to each thing that Apple or Google would do right in response to them.
Scott: They prepared all the things in advance.
Scott: We're assuming though, right?
Scott: They definitely did.
Rym: you can just tell yeah We don't have any special knowledge here.
Scott: I have not proven that they have done this.
Rym: Also, we're not lawyers and we're not right legal advice.
Scott: I'd ever seen lawyers in my whole life prepare responses this quickly to things Yeah, they could be overworking the lawyers.
Scott: I guess that's a possibility, right?
Scott: But it's like.
Scott: basically.
Scott: it's like you're seeing responses like BAM.
Scott: It's like yeah, I don't.
Rym: well So either.
Scott: hey, they've set everything up and they said okay, they do this we do that They did this we do that we and they're moving things around laws and one of yours to the hospital.
Rym: You sent an answer the morgue.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: That's how they're doing it.
Rym: So what I have in front of me right now is Epic has filed for basically an injunction or like a restraining order.
Rym: They're basically saying we need an immediate remedy to the fact that Apple is cutting the Unreal Engine off From the Apple Store like they're filing a pro like a motion here and the preliminary statement in this injunction is really funny.
Rym: quote Just over two weeks ago Apple's CEO Tim Cook was asked during a congressional hearing whether Apple is quote ever Retaliated against or disadvantaged a developer who went public about their frustrations with the App Store.
Rym: Mr Cook testified.
Rym: quote.
Rym: we do not retaliate or bully people.
Rym: It's strongly against our company culture.
Scott: But I didn't say that I heard him say that live.
Rym: but Apple has John Just that and then it goes in like it uses the word ferociously.
Rym: It's it's a pretty good.
Scott: Yeah, they're basically coming.
Scott: so not only are they they're going to court not only to argue that Apple is violating antitrust law with their App Store policy, but also that Tim Cook is guilty of perjury.
Rym: But at the same time, I don't know how I want this lawsuit to go.
Scott: Yeah, it's bad.
Scott: I mean on the one hand it's like I don't like, you know, it's like we might sound like we're saying Yeah, if they go after them, but it's like I am because Apple should be broken up and should yes As powerful as it is epic also bad.
Scott: This is like.
Scott: this is not a situation where it's like I'm rooting for either side.
Scott: I'm rooting for certain outcomes.
Rym: Yeah I would like an outcome where App Store is above a certain line on any platform Have to allow third parties and cannot prevent.
Scott: I would like the court to say yeah Apple.
Scott: You must let anyone side load apps on to my iOS.
Scott: You can't right.
Rym: Yeah, that would be fine with me Even if Apple could still keep their 30% cut of the store Right.
Scott: I'm saying it's like if you have a platform that is or a market or something that is too big you must allow You know people to sell on the thing, you know, too bad.
Scott: Yeah You know if users want to compromise their own security right and their own stability of their own devices that's on them.
Scott: That's.
Scott: I'm okay with that right now.
Rym: Google has also now banned fortnight from their App Store.
Rym: I don't think that one's moving as quickly Like there aren't as many rapid developments as there are in the different.
Scott: the key difference there is like okay at fortnight Epic doesn't want to let Google take a cut right of the of the money.
Scott: But you can still get fortnight on Android by side loading or installing some other store or some shit.
Scott: It's just can't get it in the Google store where that you would have to get quote.
Rym: Well fortnight remains available on Android.
Rym: we can no longer make it available on play because it violates our policies.
Rym: Yep Exactly now Google apparently also said they're open to discussing the issue with epic games.
Scott: So Right.
Scott: Well, that's another thing right?
Scott: So on the one hand right for all of Apple's shitty policies Right for the most part, right?
Scott: They have actually, you know in the past they've been guilty of not doing this.
Scott: You know, I can name some instances like involving Spotify and Apple watches but as of now Right Apple if you submit an app to the App Store it goes through the same process as even.
Scott: You know.
Scott: Apple said this during the hearing.
Scott: and it is true as of now that even Apple's own apps, right?
Scott: It's like the calculator app go through the same approval process, right?
Scott: But of course that doesn't include taking a 30% cut because they get a cut of their own shit.
Scott: Also their own also their own apps are free.
Rym: now I'm pretty sure that 30% cut is one of the like.
Rym: that is probably crucial to Apple's business plan And I don't think Apple is even the same company without that cut.
Scott: No, not at all.
Rym: But yeah, all big companies.
Scott: So right, of course But you're you can anything that you could do.
Scott: when you're developing an iOS app Apple could do and Apple is not Doing anything more.
Scott: they're not using like unpub you know API's that you're not allowed to use or whatever they have in the past.
Scott: Yeah, as of now they are not supposedly right?
Scott: There's the same requirements.
Scott: But you look at Google.
Scott: I say oh Google's willing to like negotiate here.
Scott: It's like okay, but that means that Google is holding different people different standards, right?
Scott: It's good Like oh you're gonna negotiate with epic and let them get away with something on the Google Play Store and get a special deal That a small-time developer can't get right can't get that deal.
Scott: I'm just a small time.
Scott: I'm not big and I'm not fortnight.
Scott: Yeah, that's also bull.
Scott: That's also bullshit right.
Rym: quote left unchecked Apple's actions where it will irreparably damage epic's reputation Among fortnight users will be catastrophic for the future of the separate Unreal Engine business.
Rym: if the Unreal Engine can no longer support Apple platforms The software developers that use it will be forced to use alternative.
Rym: the damage to your legal ease after that Point is the damage will be unquantifiable and irreparable.
Rym: That's something you see in this kind of lawsuit.
Rym: a lot that language, right?
Scott: So the point is you look at like two different monopolies the Google and the apples, right and even the epic to some extent Right, they're not monopoly.
Scott: They're just too big right and it's like yeah, they all do different things and all those things are bad.
Scott: There's no there's no good thing.
Scott: It's not like oh, they're doing something different.
Scott: Therefore.
Scott: They're good.
Scott: It's like no They're just bad at a different way.
Rym: Of course, they are in other avenues like with steam.
Rym: They're challenging.
Rym: steam's like absolute hegemony of online stores.
Rym: pretty well Yeah, steam also bad taking a big ol cut but as a consumer, I only want to go to one place.
Rym: That's right, that's all the conflicting motivations of people.
Scott: that's Amazon's big thing.
Scott: It's like Oh Amazon.
Scott: Yeah, Amazon fucks everyone over except for their customer.
Scott: Yeah, and that's why you keep buying shit on Amazon.
Scott: Well one day and the next day you're like this break up Amazon.
Scott: They're big even monopoly.
Rym: I try to buy science on non Amazon platforms when I can but oftentimes I can't and I'm basically willing to do anything before I will go to a physical store even before COVID.
Rym: I just hate going to physical stores.
Rym: That's all I want.
Scott: build my stuff.
Scott: I was just.
Scott: I was just looking to buy a bike helmet.
Scott: Right because my helmet is it died again.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I couldn't replace the fuzz again for like the third time And it's like the bike shop was too crowded.
Scott: Yeah, and the bike shops do?
Scott: they have the helmet I want.
Scott: do they have it in the color and size that I want?
Scott: that?
Scott: Hasn't been you know touched by anyone's covid miss, right?
Scott: It's like well, I guess I gotta buy one online direct for the manufacturer.
Scott: Sorry local bike shop, right?
Scott: Have an amazing selection of helmets even in non-covid time, honestly, I pretty much like lately Anything any technology.
Rym: I always buy directly from the manufacturer.
Rym: if that is an option and if that's not an option that I buy it from Amazon.
Scott: Yeah, you know what you can do.
Rym: but that's like big technology stuff partly because of the the scammers I keep running into on Amazon buying technology All right.
Scott: Well, we managed to kill the whole news with one news.
Scott: So yeah move on You might skip the other ones.
Rym: you probably don't care about that Secure boot grub outage yet.
Rym: Not you know that problem.
Rym: So just get right into things of the day.
Rym: so, uh, we live in Queens, uh There are things that I love about living in the city that I don't get to do right now because of the quarantine.
Rym: So we've stumbled onto this YouTube channel and it seems like it's just like Compilations like it gets a bunch of videos from all the internet like makes a compilation.
Rym: but the compilation series that they're making Really just hit me right in the nostalgic kidney.
Rym: It's called only in New York and their kids are still making them even during the quarantine.
Rym: It's just here are random like five or six second clips of video From all over New York City and it's basically if you watch one of these.
Rym: I'll link to one.
Rym: They're like ten minutes long.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: this is why I live in New York.
Rym: It's like here's someone with a cute dog on the subway.
Rym: Here's someone riding a 10-foot tall unicycle down the west side highway for some reason.
Rym: Here's a cool busker.
Rym: Here's someone shaving their legs in their car while driving Like parked in traffic in Manhattan.
Rym: It's just it's.
Rym: it's the fabric of life in New York that I love and miss.
Rym: but the moment in this video that actually got me the worst was we're just watching it and It was a subway drama situation.
Rym: But during the subway drama, it was like the low-key drama.
Rym: We're like nothing.
Rym: No one's gonna get hurt but there's some drama happening and the person recording the video is recording like a selfie and They're just looking at the camera with that.
Rym: Look the look of.
Rym: there's some shit going down behind me And I really just want to close my eyes and ignore it.
Rym: Yep, but then I hear the sound of the subway doors closing and I realized I have not heard that sound since March.
Rym: Yeah These videos are weird like especially watching the videos like we watch a bunch of them.
Rym: They're all just like normal New York, but then you see like the quarantine start to happen and then the videos are very different.
Rym: Mm-hmm Sam I think of the day.
Scott: this whole channel is just like very have a lot of video like that just on my hard drive.
Rym: So, oh, yeah, I got a lot of like some shits going down.
Rym: I'm gonna video it in case either world star happens or I need to like help someone file charges against the cops.
Scott: But you know, I just I have lots of videos that could go on that channel probably Yeah archive but just to dig them out would be way too much effort.
Rym: yeah, like if I go back there's video from last year that I just remember where I was walking to Hebrew know and Two cars almost got into an accident and like five people got out of both of the cars and almost had a street brawl Mm-hmm.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: What do I have?
Scott: So everybody knows back in the day playing Minesweeper on their Windows 3.1 Windows 95 PC, right?
Scott: Yeah, I don't think Minesweeper still comes with Windows.
Scott: It does not.
Scott: that is a shame.
Scott: I'm sure you can get it if you want to play Minesweeper.
Scott: There's probably just a website you can go to to play Minesweeper, right?
Scott: But people don't know.
Scott: is that Minesweeper?
Scott: that the way the game worked?
Scott: It was theoretically possible that at the end of a game of Minesweeper You could be in a situation where it was not logically possible to determine where the final mines were.
Scott: You would have to guess like there was no option but to guess.
Scott: it would be in one of two spots And you have to guess and you might win or lose right?
Scott: and that was very disappointing because you'd be like hey I used my skills of deduction to figure out where every mine was using the clues And I got this far, but now there's no.
Scott: whether I win or lose is just a coin toss.
Scott: That's bullshit, right?
Scott: I want to be able to decide my way to the end.
Scott: People also don't know that you know Minesweeper.
Scott: What if you start a game of Minesweeper and the first click is on a mine?
Rym: I didn't know that was possible.
Rym: I always assumed it set the seed when you click because I never knew.
Rym: I've never seen that happen in my life.
Scott: Here's why in Windows Minesweeper the old Microsoft Minesweeper the only one you've played probably right if Your first click happens to be a mine.
Scott: It rerolls the seed until it's not a mine Does.
Scott: my favorite was something like that it rolls a seed But then if your first click happens to be a mine it will reroll.
Rym: I think I broke it.
Rym: I Was reroll I was playing with it a whole bunch and now the link is dead.
Scott: Oh, no, it will reroll a whole bunch until You know, yeah, I think I brought it back.
Rym: It's good.
Scott: They brought it anyway anyway anyway, so my thing of the day is Someone made this ingenious thing which is way better than you think.
Scott: pure skill Minesweeper.
Scott: So obviously it eliminates that problem at the end of the game and beginning of the game right where you know It's like oh, yeah, you don't want to get burned just by luck at the end right, but it goes actually a step further.
Scott: What it does is is all right.
Scott: well if we're going to allow this rerolling of the of the mines Nonsense right then what we're going to do Is not only at the end of the game.
Scott: right if you're stuck in a situation where you have to guess?
Scott: Right and there's no other option, but guessing.
Scott: we're going to make your guess always be a good guess right?
Scott: It's like you had to guess.
Scott: we're not going to screw you over.
Scott: you recognized in the game that guessing was necessary.
Scott: you clicked and guessed.
Scott: Congratulations, we're going to make sure you don't.
Scott: we're going to move the mines out of the way and give you a successful click.
Scott: Right whether that's the first click at the end of beginning or at the end Right.
Scott: you had to guess the first click of the game.
Scott: you have to guess right.
Scott: the last click.
Scott: you might have to guess Depending on the scenario.
Scott: Yeah, you won't.
Scott: you won't lose if you have to guess right?
Scott: We won't screw you over.
Scott: but what if you're in a situation where you don't have to guess there is a way to figure it out and You say you're too lazy Or you don't you're not good enough And you don't realize that there is a way to figure it out And you just go ahead and guess when you didn't have to guess.
Scott: The game will also reroll to put the mines and in the way and punish you.
Scott: It's like that is brilliant.
Scott: It's like oh you clicked on that spot.
Scott: Yeah, well guess what there wasn't a mine there in that spot.
Scott: But you clicked that spot and you there was no way for you to have known that that was a safe spot.
Scott: You click you click that spot, but you it wait there wasn't a mine.
Scott: You were lucky, but You couldn't have known that there wasn't a mine.
Scott: There's no way for you to know that that was safe.
Scott: And you weren't forced to guess in this scenario because you could have clicked over here.
Scott: You knew that this other spot was safe.
Scott: We're putting a mine there.
Scott: You're dead buddy.
Scott: You suck And that's pure skill minesweeper.
Scott: check it out to get your minesweeper fix.
Scott: rip Microsoft solitaire I mean rut Microsoft minesweeper.
Scott: Hello pure skill minesweeper.
Rym: Yeah, it's pretty good.
Rym: I was poking at it.
Rym: Yep All right in the meta moment.
Rym: We're not really reading the book club book right now.
Scott: Nope We are appearing at the crunchyroll online convention.
Scott: When is that?
Scott: Where is that?
Rym: I haven't posted a schedule yet, but it is the way.
Rym: I think I just posted the news.
Rym: It's coming up like soon like beginning of September and okay, whatever that is.
Rym: We'll have a never-before-seen panel.
Rym: It's like a newer highly evolved rarified version of our judge anime by its cover.
Scott: It's a seen many times before panel.
Rym: Well, so basically instead of doing just judging a bunch of anime like we're doing on YouTube We took way back when we did this at anime Boston in person.
Rym: What we did is we spent like 10 minutes explaining how we judge and then we've judged everything.
Rym: We basically made the whole panel about how we judge and went kind of deeper into.
Scott: Basically the mostly the same thing is the anime Boston.
Scott: It's not a whole new panel.
Scott: It's a slight.
Scott: it's barely tweaked from what we've done in the.
Rym: I looked at those old slides.
Rym: We did it a lot better this time.
Scott: I mean just doing something better.
Scott: You can't say there's a whole new never before seen.
Scott: I didn't say never before seen.
Rym: we did a lot more.
Scott: exactly the words you Use there are just been recorded in this pod Unless you edit them out and this whole section out before you upload it.
Rym: But there is a lot of never resort before seen content because we expanded upon all those examples and went deeper with a lot more You're sure.
Scott: Anyway, we are also recording a panel for the packs online convention.
Scott: No, no duh.
Scott: Yeah We're obviously doing that.
Rym: Where is the finish line?
Rym: This one is completely new.
Rym: In fact, we haven't even finished the slides yet and we're recording a 100% new panel that I've been working on slowly.
Scott: You know, I had the idea before the virus times.
Scott: then there was a virus.
Scott: We probably would have done it like PAX West West.
Rym: this would have been a PAX West panel.
Rym: Yep In fact, I think I even put it in for packs wet like I was planning on doing it.
Scott: a PAX West Yeah, but anyway, I wrote this panel over a long period of time.
Rym: I'm currently editing and tweaking like we're getting ready almost a year ago.
Scott: But yeah It's about the panel is about right.
Scott: you're designing a game and no matter what game you're designing There needs to be some rule in the game that says the game ends when this happens, right?
Scott: When does hockey end after the third 20-minute period of play, right?
Scott: That's when it ends.
Scott: When does monopoly end when everyone's bankrupt except one person?
Scott: That's right.
Scott: You have to make up this rule No matter what game you're making video game When does it end when Ganon dies and you pick up the Triforce after the prince, you know, Princess Zelda, right?
Scott: There has to be a rule for when the game ends Assuming that you are designing an ortho game a game in which there are multiple players competing to win and or lose and be ranked.
Scott: How do you design this rule?
Scott: a good way and not a bad way?
Scott: That is what this panel is about such a small narrow focus One hours worth of content and so check the panel out if you want to know that.
Rym: Yeah, and we're still writing it.
Rym: So we're still getting simple for writing like details like fill it in.
Scott: It's like 99.
Scott: It's 99% done.
Scott: It's a good flow.
Rym: What's cool is that this is a topic we in a lot of our recent talks for like the last four ish years Will edge into and talk about the surface level.
Rym: but then we move on.
Scott: there's a lot of panels in the past There's a lot of panels in the past.
Scott: We've talked about games that have bad endings or go on too long go too short.
Scott: We've talked about quitting.
Scott: quit is related to ending right.
Rym: take your damn turn.
Rym: where we talk about exactly why some games go on too long.
Scott: Yeah, this you know.
Scott: length of games all of that ties into ending, right?
Scott: So now we're just gonna focus on the actual ending part.
Rym: Yeah, it should be a good time.
Scott: Yep, all right other meta anything.
Rym: follow us in all the places like Google GeekNights.
Rym: if you're not you're already listening to this podcast.
Scott: you have found us on all the place.
Rym: somehow you found us.
Rym: So yeah, whatever you did to find this just look around in the same area and you'll find there's there's.
Scott: there's a social network Or any kind of thing that you use.
Scott: guess what we're there.
Rym: Oh We don't use a snapchat.
Rym: Is that still around the kids using snapchat?
Scott: I don't think we're on snapchat.
Rym: No Yeah, so there you go.
Rym: We're not there.
Rym: I guess we're technically on Facebook, but not that I would know I don't have a Facebook account.
Scott: I only rehab the Facebook account because of that page.
Rym: so in a in an ancient time I'll link to this episode.
Rym: on January 29th 7 1 13 years ago.
Rym: We had already been podcasting for like two years.
Rym: Yeah, and two.
Rym: we did a show called Removable media.
Rym: I'm sure.
Rym: in fact, I'm gonna read it tonight.
Rym: on GeekNights We talk about floppy drives CD roms DVDs cassettes and more.
Rym: a hundred percent of those things are obsolete.
Scott: Yeah, funnily enough in only in only 13 years.
Rym: The funny weird thing is when I went to this old episode My thing one thing of the day is just gone.
Rym: The other one is there this Frank Zappa thing like.
Rym: it's on YouTube.
Rym: It's still up, but we were talking about an Apple antitrust lawsuit in Norway.
Scott: Yeah, cuz.
Scott: that the Apple iTunes DRM on the music at the time meant that you could only listen to songs bought in iTunes on iPods and nor was like no no no.
Scott: if people buy music from iTunes They should be able to play it on any audio device.
Scott: You're that's antitrust a violation in Norway.
Scott: And then they fixed it by removing the music DRM in the Apple store and iTunes and that doesn't matter anymore Cuz.
Scott: now everyone has Apple music and Spotify.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: That's the follow-up but Back, then we probably talked about the history a bit based on you know, we mentioned floppies and whatever.
Rym: We don't need to get into the history too much.
Scott: But this is in the old episode.
Rym: Yeah, but this episode will be interesting not from the perspective of me talking about my use of a zip drive for so long but more about.
Rym: 2007 was a long time ago and the world is radically different in a lot of ways.
Rym: Technology is radically different.
Rym: how people interact with technology is right Radically different.
Rym: so What is removable media look like now in the year 2020?
Rym: Cuz like I Don't really use removable media except SD cards in cameras.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: That's the only removal I have for the most part in 2020.
Scott: Most people don't need any removable media or very little because You know the the kind of read-only Removable media some people out there is still using boo-rays for whatever reason.
Scott: I don't know, right?
Scott: They just just opposed to.
Scott: you know, they really want to own that plastic useless.
Rym: There is one one use case for boo-ray.
Scott: if you want to watch a movie without gradient problems in the dark spaces Sure, or if you want to be the person who rips the boo-ray for everyone else to watch with their pirated copy You're the pirate.
Scott: err for everyone else.
Scott: That's the reason.
Scott: But yeah, so people aren't buying things on removable media anymore, right?
Scott: People when they need to transfer their own data around to other devices Which is what we're mostly gonna talk about today, right?
Scott: You most people could just use a cloud service of some kind.
Scott: right use your Dropbox your Google Drive Your you know, Adobe creative cloud your iCloud, right?
Rym: Normal people like before we talk about us a normal person takes pictures with their phone.
Rym: They're already uploaded to the cloud somewhere and then if they're on their PC.
Rym: They go to like whatever thing their phone was doing to mess with their photos.
Scott: I call it photo.
Scott: people use airdrop on iPhones to send things directly.
Scott: Yeah, people just text photos to each other Alright, they just Facebook message photos to each other, right?
Scott: It's like, you know music people don't really have mp3s anymore But if they did they could just sent, you know transfer them the same way.
Scott: You know, usually you'll just send a link to the song on Spotify or whatever Apple music Whatever it is, you send a link in a text message, right?
Scott: It's like there is very little reason to use removable media.
Scott: The only reasons to use removable media these days is if you have some non computer Recording device and you need to transfer a large amount of data Which would be too large or too slow to transfer over the network Yep, or if you have a device that has in itself limited storage capacity You can enhance its storage capacity for example a Nintendo switch usually with a micro SD card and then you could use that micro SD card as to transfer some things if you needed to or To back up if you needed to.
Scott: but usually you're just expanding the storage of the one device and that's it Yep.
Rym: So like I have these three Marantz's that we use for GeekNights like audio recording on the go like at conventions That takes compact flash.
Rym: So I have a whole bunch of compact flash cards that I'll use for that for the foreseeable future.
Scott: Mm-hmm, but nothing new would use compact flash.
Scott: Nope, right.
Scott: even the latest and greatest cameras which you used to be that when you buy the Ultra Pro cameras They had compact flash.
Scott: They're pretty much all.
Scott: SD now is as these plenty fast plenty big.
Scott: There is.
Scott: I think Nikon might have a special memory card that they might still use in some cameras, but for the most part It's like everything has SD slots.
Rym: now, you know the highest end stuff now Have a different use case but what they'll often use like if you like.
Rym: if we had all our if our cameras are all like one step bigger or two steps bigger and We're recording a lot of video.
Rym: We wouldn't be rotating SD cards We'd be capped.
Rym: we'd be basically having the camera send the raw video to some sort of device that's filled with hard drives.
Rym: Yeah, you see you can see that.
Rym: go Google for this stuff.
Rym: You'll find like people will sell What basically is a suitcase that you plug like an SDI cable into it or like five SDI cables into it?
Rym: And it just records video to a whole bunch of spinning hard drives inside of itself or SD Okay, or like flash hard drives inside of itself.
Scott: Yeah, well because hard drives, you know in 2007 we were mostly, you know to get an.
Scott: You know a solid-state drive was a big deal.
Rym: Yeah, I had like a 256 gigabyte Solid-state drive that I barely got windows and stuff installed on.
Scott: I want to say I think I had a 16 gig one.
Rym: Maybe look actually yeah, that was pre 256.
Rym: That was probably 30.
Scott: I think that I think in 2007 if I even had one at all, I think my first solid-state drive was a 16 gig one.
Scott: but anyway Yeah, so nowadays you don't really need most people don't need a magnetic drive in any device they have because they don't have that much data.
Scott: You're having solid-state drives and solid-state drives are so small these days that you can just put them in devices and Like so you don't.
Scott: really you can get a lot of storage with no moving parts like my GoPro.
Rym: I have two Micro SD cards that are 256 gigabytes each.
Rym: they cost like nothing.
Rym: They're the size of my pinky fingernail.
Scott: Yeah, it's like alright.
Scott: Well.
Scott: I guess we don't need store.
Scott: You know it's like.
Rym: I Know it's interesting in 2007. one thing.
Scott: I just looked it up the Nikon d5 Which is like the big monster giant.
Scott: Nikon has a compact flash slot and an xqd Slot which is the special Nikon thing it doesn't have.
Scott: it doesn't have SD.
Rym: Oh wow that's amazing.
Scott: Yeah, so that's a thing.
Rym: yep, so in terms of our actual usage like the only other thing.
Rym: I really use as like Removal media for in the modern era Was a USB stick for like quickly moving a file around like oh, I gotta follow my laptop.
Rym: Let me go put it on my desktop.
Rym: But I have gigabit ethernet like inside of my apartment, and I have a NAS inside of my apartment.
Rym: anything on my laptop either goes up to Google Cloud or Up to any of my other cloud providers, or just goes up to my NAS and now I can access it from any computer.
Rym: and even worse like Nowhere I work will let you plug a USB stick into anything.
Rym: So it's not like I can use it to transfer files like the home from work or anything.
Rym: Really, I have no use for a USB stick like.
Rym: I don't have any working USB sticks except for a dish full of old ones That I guess I should go see if there's anything interesting on them, and then just delete them all throw them away.
Scott: I use USB sticks for very Rare occasions right?
Rym: I used to put a backup copy of our panels on a USB stick That I would keep in my pocket when we travel to a convention.
Rym: So if all our luggage got lost and all their technology broke That USB stick plus borrowing a laptop from someone would be enough to do the panel.
Rym: I don't even bother with that anymore.
Scott: Nope Because the panel's backed up on the internet.
Scott: I could run the panel off my phone if I had to.
Scott: I get the panel from Google slides.
Rym: Yeah, I download a PDF to the lab in case Google goes down.
Scott: I have an HDMI output from my phone that I can run the panel with just the phone and nothing else.
Rym: Yeah, right Like that panel exists in so many places.
Scott: Okay, so actually I just looked up again.
Scott: I talked about.
Scott: I looked at the Nikon d5.
Scott: I wasn't aware.
Scott: the Nikon d6 is out.
Scott: it also does not have SD But the Nikon that's.
Scott: that's like a mega DSLR like a giant that frickin thing right the Nikon d850 Which would be like a normal DSLR.
Rym: Oh, I just looked in my Amazon history from 2007.
Rym: I spent $36 on a 2 gigabyte USB stick Wow.
Rym: and on December 18th 2007 Wow a Kensington data traveler 2 gigabyte USB Drive.
Rym: Yeah, that's more than the harmonica.
Rym: I bought at the same time Yep, so I think that basically what comes down to is if you are a normal person who does not Book a physical book that had a map of the subway and a map of New York City in it.
Scott: Oh, yeah the NFT.
Scott: in 2020 you Might just need a maybe some SD cards and you're good to go for all your external storage.
Scott: Like if you really want to back up your stuff.
Scott: You know because you have stuff to be backed up and the cloud backup is not sufficient for your personal needs But you don't have a lot of data, so I don't see why a couple cloud backups wouldn't be sufficient quick to upload.
Rym: Shit, you know what else.
Rym: I bought in 2007 a portable DVD player With an LCD screen that could play a DVD directly.
Scott: Wow Yeah, you could just back up your life to like an SD card and put that in a safe place and you're good to go Right.
Rym: Yeah In this middle era between this show and the last time we talked about this with my old laptop One thing I started doing is I stopped using USB sticks because my laptop had an SD slot.
Rym: So I would just use SD cards the way I used to use USB sticks.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Rym: Yeah, now I don't even do that.
Rym: But there was a time when I did.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, nowadays if you are a person who has a lot of data if you got photos you're gonna use SD cards.
Scott: Yeah, and you might need like a NAS or some kind of larger store, but that's not removable, right?
Scott: We've done NAS shows twice, right?
Scott: You're just gonna be something to back those up to maybe like a larger portable hard drive.
Scott: There are some storage devices these days that have their own network access, right?
Scott: It's like they have their own Wi-Fi access so you can connect your phone to them wirelessly.
Scott: You know assuming all you've got is a phone and the storage device you can connect your phone to the storage device with Wi-Fi and Send data back and forth usually with an app to back up the phone or load things from the storage device to the phone You know, so that's that's the thing if you have if you're doing stuff on the go.
Scott: But yeah, it's like removable media is?
Scott: it's like first the physical media died, right?
Scott: But what is physical media other than read only removable media?
Scott: Yeah, so it's like if we don't need physical media anymore, you know, it's because we're downloading everything.
Scott: Well, that means the network is so good that I don't need removable media to trick You know because really is just a way to transfer and store right.
Scott: so like I can use the network and to store everything.
Scott: every device has storage and I have cloud storage.
Scott: So it's stored on every place.
Scott: I want it to be heard.
Rym: Scott and I had to record a panel for the crunchyroll Expo that judge anime panel remotely.
Rym: So at the end of that I had 50 gigabytes of video and Scott had 50 gigabytes of video.
Rym: in the olden times We would have to put Scott would have to like put that on a SD card or USB stick and physically get it to me.
Rym: Scott just uploaded it To Google and then I downloaded it Like yeah, was it?
Rym: it just work.
Scott: Well, that is that is because we both have files, right?
Scott: So you both have fast internet.
Scott: if I still had slow internet that would have taken so long.
Scott: Yeah, it might have still been faster to transfer using physical to bike it over here, right?
Scott: So if you we could have used the SD cards, all right So.
Scott: but if you look there are still some cases where people have to transfer so much data that even the fast Internet or you know, even a LAN is too slow.
Scott: and in these cases there are many services being offered.
Scott: Amazon offers one I know I think Google does as well Maybe where they will send you a hard drive or a storage device of some kind that you then plug in to your local Network or local devices fill it up and mail it back to them.
Scott: And if you are sending enough terabytes of data terabytes then the cost of doing this which is actually not that high Becomes and the speed it becomes worthwhile.
Scott: because if for you to do the network transfer, you know It would have been faster because yeah local transfer is still faster than network transfer even if you have gigabit Ethernet connection, it's like well, you know, it's like a Frickin, you know USB C cables can go faster than that, right?
Scott: So, you know East Ada can go faster than that.
Scott: Yeah Plugging maybe I can plug something in directly to a PCI Express slot, you know MVNO or whatever it is called these days.
Rym: I just can't get over this to me and NVMe?
Scott: No is mobile voice something that NVMe is?
Scott: the is the thing I was thinking.
Scott: You can see why I would confuse the two.
Rym: at least I hope yeah, but at least in our like Professional use cases like we have no real uses for physical media day-to-day.
Rym: like in 2007 I carried a USB stick on my keychain all the time just in case with like some critical files and stuff.
Scott: in 1997 I carried a plastic container full of floppy disks that I still have.
Rym: I carried the same around.
Rym: I had.
Rym: I'd had like it had important games and important files for school.
Rym: It had my mud client at RIT I and when I was a freshman, I had one zip disk that I would put put into the internal zip drive of my PC and All my visual basic projects for my programming classes were on that zip disk.
Rym: and then I take it to the lab Which also had an internal zip drive?
Rym: Mmm, and then RIT set up the network better so I could access remote shares over the RIT network And then that zip drive was just a waste of money and I never used it again.
Rym: Yeah, they set that up by the end of our freshman year if I recall correctly.
Scott: So my prediction here is actually that Given another 13 years, right?
Scott: The capacity of the SD cards, right?
Scott: It's if they can make it.
Scott: if they've reached a limit they reach a limit.
Scott: But if they I'm not sure if they will or not.
Scott: But if they don't reach a limit or if the limit is high enough You're gonna have like maybe terabyte SD card or something.
Rym: Well, here's one way to go.
Rym: camera Remember video like the camcorder we used to use for gig nights It had an SD card slot.
Rym: But it's selling point because back then SD cards were tiny was that it had a hard drive in it.
Rym: And the idea was you record directly in camera and the camera itself Plugs into a computer via the much faster USB to get the data off of it, right?
Scott: So if the if you can get storage that small that large You're not gonna need removable storage because you're never gonna fill up any device.
Rym: You've got The fast cable coming out of that device, whatever it is, right?
Scott: You only need a way to transfer between devices, right?
Scott: That's fast.
Scott: And I think well probably that networks.
Scott: I think you're just getting it faster.
Scott: Also, especially if you know, we look at 5g There's gonna be a 6g right, you know.
Scott: And plus the potential of 5g speed wise is really way up there compared to what they're actually gonna give us.
Scott: but over time They'll make it faster.
Scott: They'll actually give us, you know more of the full 13 years.
Scott: Yeah, it's gonna get faster Right.
Scott: So what you're gonna see is like transfer between devices will be so fast that you won't ever Rare like almost never need to use some other mechanism to transfer data other than just wireless connection.
Scott: Right, it's like oh, okay I recorded a 4k video on my camera and it's already on my computer because Transferring it was as fast as writing it to the storage.
Scott: Yeah, I know to the camera.
Scott: It's like, okay, you know great.
Scott: Oh Yeah, like my camera I can push a button on it and it can just live stream the video itself, right?
Rym: We're getting there like the newer version.
Rym: Okay, my camcorder is a little old at this point already because times flying.
Rym: but and also I bought it toward the end of its Like life cycle because I knew a new one was coming out and it was way cheap because of that.
Rym: But the newer version of my camcorder has RTMP streaming and Wi-Fi just built in.
Rym: plug an ethernet cable into it It'll the stream RTMP over that ethernet cable Wi-Fi.
Rym: It'll just do it.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Now RTMP is not going to.
Rym: you're not gonna stream.
Rym: You're like 8k 60 video over that shit.
Rym: No, but if you're like I'll record in 4k to the SD card on a future camera like that.
Rym: But a lot of the time what I'm doing is live streaming where I don't need that quality the dual 13.
Scott: in 13 years you will be able to.
Scott: maybe it'll be expensive but you'll be able to live stream like 4k video directly from a phone or other camera like directly to like twitch or whatever just like 4k video.
Scott: You got a camera.
Scott: You don't need any other equipment at all.
Scott: records.
Scott: It records it locally Encodes it streams it at the end There's no there's no lag or any problems and you don't need removable storage to transfer or do anything like that.
Scott: You can just do it everything.
Scott: Yeah fast enough.
Rym: Well, that's one future because the other future is we're hiding in the hollowed-out remains of an abandoned US Postal Service Trying to survive assuming we make it to the future of 30.
Scott: Yeah, that is the level of technology in this one specific area.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, you know, it's weird because it's like, you know, we the cliche has always been you know, at least since the Since the CD I think and since the V since the DVD there's been as cliche of.
Scott: Yeah, old people used records.
Scott: young people use a different thing because before the record and there was what the wax cylinder right there There weren't too many recorded medias before then right the wax cylinder was really well There's a bunch of cool stuff black Right, there weren't too many, right?
Scott: So it's like there's always been this cliche of like.
Scott: this generation used this kind of physical media that generate.
Scott: the previous generation used a different One but we're gonna reach.
Scott: basically we saw the beginning.
Scott: We're gonna see the end where it's like.
Scott: no, they'll be generations and between the generations There weren't any differences in physical media because there was just none.
Scott: They didn't use any.
Scott: this.
Scott: well you should use none and the generation add to them use none.
Rym: There is one place physical media will persist even in that future, but that is the like Archival use cases that are not operational use cases.
Scott: There are not things that everyday people will use their only things that Businesses or other like in that future.
Rym: your cell phone will stream 8k 60 video if you want but the studio camera records a full 3d like Environment in real time and infinite like brain resolution, but that's the thing that has physical media and normally people don't use that.
Scott: So even though this is a repeat show from 13 years ago, I think you know, the situation is drastically changed.
Rym: Well, I might listen to that old episode just to see one.
Rym: That's 2007 where that was.
Rym: that was so long ago We were.
Scott: so hopefully we.
Scott: I'm sure we did something, you know I'm always worried about the old GeekNights episodes because I'm sure we said some shit.
Scott: We should be canceled for oh There.
Rym: but so actually you never listened to the remastered with commentary Beta episodes that I uploaded because I pointed out a few things.
Rym: if we say bad shit We're not not too bad, but we are close.
Rym: multiple times you use you use some words You don't use anymore because you didn't know better.
Rym: Uh, I do.
Rym: we were I Know.
Rym: yeah, I know that we both but but it's not as bad as I expected.
Rym: like it wasn't that bad.
Rym: We were mostly okay, and that was the beta episodes that we didn't think anyone would ever hear.
Rym: But in terms of how much we've changed so I'm uh, I've kind of been looking at my Amazon history Which actually gives me an idea for a Thursday like fun show.
Rym: we should both just go in our online order history Pick like an early year and look at all the shit We ordered that year and talk about like what that what that archaeology is about our lives because you know what else.
Rym: I bought in 2017 or in 2007 Historical maps of the Napoleonic Wars a go board a whole bunch of El Hazzard DVDs And I bought a primer for the LSATs because I was thinking about quitting my tech job and taking the LSATs and going to law school.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, let's do that on a Thursday right at the right that day.
Rym: Well, I'm writing that down right now because otherwise we will not do that But this week is Wednesday.
Scott: We got to do next Thursday.
Rym: We'll do that show if we if we remember that I said this and I look at this note that I just wrote and with That I am super hungry.
Scott: Let's end this too young show.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Zoom in.
Rym: make sure that way was going.
Rym: Yes, it is going.
Rym: let me now sort this.
Rym: Always make the mistake of recording this live and since I'll never edit sometimes.
Rym: Here we go.
Rym: Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol Marty green It's just like a dude guy.
Rym: chartavish and Graham Finch.
Rym: You hold the key to my heart.
Rym: She gave me a kiss and she gave me my ticket.
Rym: Clinton Walton J Bants friend from Zealand Ryan Perrin Nicholas Brando Chris midkiff the thirst for hydrated Gannon dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Sherman our whole and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: Stay tuned.
Rym: this week I'm gonna upload probably a video using our new streaming stuff for the patrons only.
Rym: as I play around with these alternate pipelines A lot of the other projects working on are on hold because it's been much more of a pain in the ass to record our panels for Conventions.
Rym: then we anticipated so we're still working that out, but we got a pretty good pipeline the crunchy roll ones done.
Rym: We're figuring out the packs one this week.
Rym: So once that's all done, we're gonna follow up.
Rym: We got a good interview lined up.
Rym: We got some good shows lined up.
Rym: We got some extra content lined up got some stuff for antenna.
Rym: That'll use these streaming pipelines once we get past the deadlines for these conventions, but for now I leave you Jesus This Near the mysterious top all moment.
Scott: Jesus.
Scott: Mormons believe and Mormon Jesus Through obedience to a Mormon Jesus.
Scott: He was elevated to godhood as Mormon Jesus Mormon teaching Mormonism.