Rym: It's Wednesday October 28th 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are reviewing.
Rym: the comic is Sola.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, I actually went and voted yesterday, you know, they went out to actually do the early voting in person.
Rym: mostly I voted in person because You're outdoors like 99% of the time and considering all the trouble with mail-in ballots.
Rym: I didn't want to risk Anything about my vote being counted and I wanted I think I said this during the results They're gonna release almost immediately after the polls close.
Scott: I think I said this before but you know My mail-in ballot was already confirmed received because I mailed it so long ago, but I may just go vote in person Which is a thing you can legally do in New York.
Scott: Yeah Even if you've sent in a mail-in ballot and what's supposed to happen is when they receive Your when they go to open the mail-in ballots, they'll see that I voted in person and throw it out And if for some reason they make a mistake
Rym: It's
Scott: not a very.
Scott: if I have there's a non-zero chance that I can legally vote twice.
Scott: Why would I not do that?
Rym: It is amazing how different this is in every state Which is like just one of those things is wrong with America and people who didn't grow up.
Scott: It's wrong with America, but it does provide a unique defense against election interference.
Scott: That is true when we are facing Yep, like.
Rym: it'd be really hard to hack the American election because every state is so radically different that like There's a centralized well-designed voting system, you could just attack it directly.
Scott: the surface area is one thing.
Scott: now The surface area is okay.
Scott: You have to attack two hundred and something electoral votes worth of systems Yep.
Rym: But also in terms of like our voting the biggest problem in America right now.
Rym: for those of you who might be outside of this nightmare late capitalist hellscape or at least adjacent to the late capitalist hellscape It's a global hellscape, but our election one of the problems we face Is that a lot of states if you vote by mail?
Rym: They're not even legally allowed to open those envelopes until the morning of the day of the election.
Rym: They can't even get a head start on counting them like.
Rym: nonsense like that is a problem in America.
Rym: So anyway, we went to vote and the amazing thing was we tried to vote on Sunday When it opened and there was like a four-hour line.
Rym: So we bailed.
Rym: we went yesterday Like near the end of the day, but before people actually got off work to try to early vote like in the evening.
Rym: But while people might still be busy and there was a huge line But it was actually only about a two-hour wait.
Rym: So we stayed in it.
Rym: I have never in my life encountered a line that was longer than like ten minutes to vote until this.
Scott: You know, we know we know what the factors are, right?
Scott: So one is obviously more enthusiasm.
Scott: Factor two is the early voting in New York has one-tenth of the locations of this is the regular voting.
Scott: Yeah on Tuesday Election Day.
Scott: There are gonna be ten times as many places to go vote, right?
Scott: Problem three which you just described to me is that when you go to vote when they're at on Election Day You're going to a specific place that knows who's coming.
Scott: Yeah And they have the ballots ready.
Scott: because for that location when you go to early vote They're dealing with such a wider geographic area and different possible ballots.
Scott: Yeah, and since they don't know who's coming they're printing the ballots on demand.
Scott: So you have to go up to them and say mom in district X would number whatever and then they print a ballot appropriate for where you live
Rym: and that's a problem especially in New York City because Like do you know how many congressional districts are within like a short walk of my apartment?
Scott: Yeah, I mean I can walk, you know, most people I think in the United States, right?
Scott: to walk to a place represented by a different member of the federal House of Representatives would be Extremely arduous.
Rym: some states just have one like.
Scott: yeah I can take a subway and go through like a whole pile of them.
Rym: In fact, I did.
Rym: I did this one time I was I took one of my Strava rides and I looked to see how many Congressional representatives I passed through.
Rym: it was four different congressional districts on that bike ride.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I might commute this like at least three or four Some significant number right?
Scott: It might even be more than that.
Rym: Yeah, because the Maloney district actually goes across into part of Manhattan and part of Midtown.
Rym: I'm actually still in that district longer than you might expect Mm-hmm.
Rym: But yeah, so we go.
Rym: we wait two hours.
Rym: There's a long long crowd line.
Rym: I'm confident based on who is in that line that 99.9% of the people are correctly voting for Joe Biden.
Rym: like there were not some people in that line.
Rym: There's only one part of the year.
Rym: well two parts of New York City that vote for Republicans one of those parts of Staten Island which fuck them and the other part is like this one neighborhood in Brooklyn.
Rym: It's the only one.
Rym: it's kind of amazing.
Rym: But I go in.
Rym: Emily gets a ballot goes to vote.
Rym: because they're in New York each ballot is serialized.
Rym: So they have the list of like the number of people who voted and they can serialize that to the number of ballots that were Handed out and then scanned.
Rym: that's one of those like checks on the system.
Rym: Like if those numbers mismatch, they need to do a manual count of the ballots themselves and figure out what happened.
Rym: So I take my ballot that came out of this machine and I go over vote and I fill out the first part of it And then I flip it over because there's a second side.
Scott: second side is to blame this side, too.
Rym: So I go over a voting person there.
Rym: I'm like, yeah, my ballots broken and she's like, oh shit She says she literally goes.
Rym: Oh shit.
Rym: So because now this cause it is no shit how much paperwork they had to fill out because of this.
Rym: Yes, right the ballot that I had from the record and someone's worried about.
Scott: people are worried about so-called voting fraud Right.
Scott: It's like You gotta get past some old lady who's working the polling station in Queens Probably been doing it for like all this paperwork to get one vote past them.
Scott: It's it's really not easy.
Rym: Okay, so what's your guess on how many people I do officially interact with to get a new ballot?
Scott: Mean when I go to polling stations in the city, there's usually only Like there'll be two people at the table of find your district because you don't know it for some reason.
Scott: Then there's two people at the table of here's your ballot.
Rym: Yeah, then there's always one person at the provisional ballot Like I need to sign an affidavit.
Scott: Then there's the person who's help you while you're voting person and that is the help you with the scanner and give you a sticker Person.
Scott: yeah, right.
Scott: So I mean maybe two or three five.
Rym: I interacted by five people who each person had to take me to another person so I could explain what happened to me to both of them and then the second person would take it from there and go over to another person who had a different function.
Rym: and Eventually, we got to the person who's responsible for the machine that prints the ballots Which is in this big lockbox and that person had to key a whole bunch of information into a tiny keypad On the outside of this box to make the machine print another ballot for me And then he had to take my fucked-up ballot and do a bunch of stuff with it somewhere.
Rym: All right, and it'll work.
Scott: sure it doesn't get used because you know It's legal to say fill out the front half and just abstain on the back half.
Rym: Yeah, there was no ban.
Scott: Yes, someone could have scanned that ballot and you know double-voted or whatever.
Rym: Yep, so I voted for Joe Biden under the working parties family line because working families party line because New York is weird Yep, and otherwise straight Democrats because they're the only party interested in governing.
Rym: So I urge you If you have not voted yet, and you're an American Do what you need to do.
Rym: go do it.
Scott: If you have to skip, you know work and make some sacrifice somewhere.
Scott: But if you're legally allowed to do it do it.
Rym: Yeah, you know me I won't stand in line at a Starbucks if there's more than one person in front of me But I stood in that two fucking hour line to vote in a state that literally doesn't matter Because
Scott: I still think you could have waited until on Tuesday.
Scott: I think the lines will be way shorter because even though enthusiasm is high still and that will definitely Increase enthusiastic people are more likely to vote early.
Scott: right people had all this opportunity to vote early.
Scott: So those people aren't showing up Tuesday and there's gonna be ten times as many locations to go to and those locations Won't have to print ballots on demand.
Scott: They'll just have stacks of them right up for you.
Rym: Honestly, my reason was one if anything happens like let's say I get hit by a bus before Election Day I still want voted before I get hit by that bus because that the stakes are that high.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of people are posting on Twitter like, you know, pretty much, you know every possible inspirational story of someone voting Despite hardship.
Scott: I've seen hundred-year-old person vote.
Scott: I've seen I've seen dude with terminal illness Fusion voting right?
Scott: It's like for you know, it's like someone like, you know Like in the worst possible shape right going out of their way to vote.
Scott: and the idea is if that person can vote And you're listening to this You Can do you can do it?
Scott: You're not?
Scott: hopefully hopefully you're not terminally ill.
Scott: if you're terminally ill do not waste the rest of your short life listening to geek.
Rym: You can have someone drop an iPad into your coffin at that point If you have a cancer.
Scott: that's in a late stage, I'm so sorry for you, but why are you wait?
Scott: You're not gonna live that much longer.
Scott: Don't listen.
Rym: We're gonna get an email Keeping me going as GeekNights.
Scott: go eat a delicious food or you know Talk to the people that are important to you or something.
Rym: I guess what I would say is one thing you can't know about someone circumstance cuz.
Rym: we've gotten emails like that before.
Rym: like that happens There's someone out there where something is their thing and that is the joy.
Rym: So if you're that person like sure Like I'd like to talk to you.
Rym: Like if you're that person I feel like talking to us would know.
Scott: don't waste the short time you have left in your life Wasting it talking to stupid old Rym.
Scott: He's got nothing He can tell you.
Rym: I'm saying if you're already at the point to where you're listening to this and that's your thing at the end Then I will actually talk to you on the phone like if that's what you really want.
Rym: Sure, but go vote first.
Scott: So today Rym posts in in a chat right that today.
Scott: he learned, you know, there's that song dude Or a door Right.
Scott: He learned the name of that song was not the name that we thought it was.
Rym: Yeah I always knew it as the Toria Dora song.
Rym: my whole.
Scott: that's what I. that's what I knew it.
Rym: I kind of assumed it was called Toria door.
Rym: I knew it was from turn of dot.
Rym: I didn't fucking know anything else about.
Rym: it's not no turn.
Rym: turn it out.
Rym: It's from Carmen.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So that's enormous from turn of dot.
Rym: I was literally playing the trumpet solo in this and Dorma last night.
Rym: My mind anyway, all right.
Scott: So anyway, so I also because we're in posted that I also learned the name of the song wasn't the name?
Scott: I thought it was right and then I saw I'm like, you know I know that song.
Scott: everyone knows that fucking song right.
Scott: and I said what's it from?
Scott: and I googled I'm like.
Scott: Oh, it's from Carmen Carmen is.
Scott: I know the name of an opera.
Scott: Yeah, have I seen Carmen?
Scott: No, have I?
Scott: do I know the story of it?
Scott: Yes, cuz I read it on Wikipedia today, right?
Scott: I just knew it was a famous opera and I knew that that song was in it.
Scott: and I said, you know I'm willing to bet this famous opera that I have never seen nor listened to probably contains other famous songs that I already know.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like a guarantee pretty much right but it's like I know.
Scott: I'm basically sitting there thinking I guarantee.
Scott: There are songs on the Carmen soundtrack right that I already know.
Scott: 100% chance at least one or two, right?
Scott: But which songs are they?
Scott: what it's like?
Scott: there's so many songs.
Scott: It could be which ones is it?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Let me go to Spotify and double-click on Carmen and find out right I The.
Scott: what is the first thing I hear within the literal first note?
Scott: Do you do you know Carmen?
Scott: Have you seen it?
Rym: Because I haven't I have not actually seen it.
Scott: The literal first song of Carmen is And I'm like, oh my god, I didn't even have to get to track fucking - Most of the opera scene are either terrible long-winded Wagner that I never want to see again or like Rossini stuff.
Scott: So the story of Carmen at least based on the cliff note summary doesn't seem very interesting.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I can tell you.
Rym: my advice on opera is very simple Never choose which opera to see if you haven't seen a lot of opera based on what plot sounds good.
Rym: Choose the opera based on the songs you like.
Rym: that might be in that opera.
Scott: Have the dumbest plots Yeah, so Carmen I kept listening and it was mostly just.
Scott: you know Opera sounds right.
Scott: and then another song comes and I'm like, oh, here's the second one.
Scott: Do you know which one it was?
Scott: No Doo doo doo doo doo doo doo Doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Scott: and then you know the big one right did it.
Scott: That's also fucking Carmen.
Rym: So if The Metropolitan Opera somehow survives which I imagine it will we were literally you and I planning to go on a double date to the Opera right after I was like.
Scott: I was like I will go to an opera.
Scott: It's been so many years.
Scott: Which one will I go to?
Scott: Well Carmen moved itself up on the fucking list.
Rym: I was hoping for.
Rym: I've never seen Carmen so I'd be happy to go.
Scott: so obviously And if the rich people prop up the opera enough, right, I feel like the opera ain't gonna go bankrupt.
Scott: I don't think so either.
Scott: If you have a Spotify or an Apple Music or whatever, go type in
Scott: "Carmen.".
Scott: I didn't even finish this, I didn't even get past the second path here.
Scott: There may be surprises that await here.
Scott: Something else I learned is, you know who wrote "Carmen," the opera, composer, whatever?
Rym: Uh, yeah, so what are you learning?
Rym: I'm actually pulling up some Wikipedias.
Scott: Yeah, you are.
Scott: It's Georges Bizet, right?
Rym: Yeah, Bizet.
Scott: Bizet.
Scott: Apparently, the interesting thing that I read is that this person who made this ridiculously famous opera, uh, like, died after, like, the whatever performance of it.
Scott: Um, and then it became famous afterwards.
Rym: That seems like it's not uncommon just in media in general.
Scott: But, like, it didn't get performed that many times.
Scott: Like, it wasn't a hit yet.
Scott: And then they died, and then it became tremendous.
Rym: I mean, Rocky Horror Picture Show was not really a hit when it came out.
Scott: It's still not a hit, really.
Rym: It's a cult classic.
Scott: That's, yeah, I mean, it's basically people who care about movies have seen it, but in terms of, like, actual number of people who've actually seen it and know it, it's like people may know the name Rocky Horror Picture Show.
Scott: Yeah, I know that name.
Scott: That's the way I knew Carmen yesterday.
Scott: I know that's the name of an opera.
Scott: I know that's the name of a thing, right?
Scott: A movie or something.
Scott: But they don't know it, know it, right?
Scott: And they probably know the time warp and don't know what it's from or that it's even from a thing.
Rym: You know, because I was thinking about the William Tell Overture.
Rym: Most people only know that from, like, TV shows it was in.
Rym: Or, like, the Tori Adar song.
Rym: That song, most people, if you look it up on YouTube, almost all the comments are Five Nights at Freddy's kids being like, "Hey, it's the Five Nights at Freddy's
Rym: song!".
Rym: And one old man is like, "No, it's the song that Martin Prince sings when he's in a cage in that episode of The
Rym: Simpsons.".
Rym: So, there's actually a lot of anime news, like, a ton of it, and most of it is around the fact that Netflix had an infinite number of announcements related to anime and animation recently.
Rym: We're not even going to be able to cover all of these.
Scott: Netflix just did all kinds of anime biz, and they did all the press releases for all their anime biz all at once in a big blomp.
Scott: So, the biggest one.
Scott: "Oh, you want some anime Netflix news?
Scott: Here you
Scott: go!".
Rym: And this is already during, like, this platinum age of animation where I'm watching, like, there is so much good animation out there, and a ton of it is on Netflix.
Rym: I'm just watching it there.
Rym: But the one you all probably care the most about, the one that's getting the most buzz, at least in my circles, is, uh, there's a manga, The Way of the House Husband.
Scott: Yeah, so, I, when I first saw this news, I was slightly confused.
Scott: I'm like, "Have we judged this poorly?
Scott: Why are people
Scott: excited?".
Scott: Because the one that we judged, obviously, was not this one, right?
Scott: We judged an anime, because, obviously, this is not an anime yet, right?
Scott: So, it couldn't have been.
Scott: I was like, that's why I was confused, right?
Scott: I was like, "Because we're only judging anime.
Scott: There's no way I could judge an anime that exists.
Scott: Are they remaking it?
Scott: I don't know,
Scott: right?".
Scott: But the one we judged is the questionable, not good one, where the Yakuza boss forces some Yakuza to get, uh, sex change operations and become idols.
Rym: Yeah, that's not the- that is not the-.
Scott: That is not this.
Scott: This is the one where you see people posting online on Twitter, right, the JPEG of the single page of the manga, where there are two Yakuza complimenting each other's dogs and then wanting to pet them.
Rym: Like, "Alright, your dog is so cute.
Rym: Can I pet
Rym: him?".
Scott: Yeah, that's this one.
Scott: This is gonna be way good, uh, and it definitely, like, an anime adaptation of that, how can that be bad?
Rym: Yeah, I feel like it's gonna be really fun.
Rym: I like it- anytime that trope of, like, a monster or something dangerous ends up in a very, like, simple domestic normal role, is just- that's almost- that's a trope that I just really like, and this seems like it's going to be a good show.
Rym: Netflix rarely seems to pick up stuff that's not good in this regard.
Scott: And they also do a good job of it, right?
Rym: They're not gonna do, like, a, you know- Yeah, it won't be- it won't be the, uh, those 90s OAVs, like the Sanctuary OAV that we will never speak of again and never watch again.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, also, they announced the, you know, last- what, was it the last Wednesday episode?
Scott: We talked about Olympic whatever?
Rym: Oh, yeah, Olympic, uh, Kiklos.
Scott: Right, well, the- and we mentioned how the person who made the original manga of that was more famous for making, uh, Thermae Romae, however you pronounce it, I don't know.
Rym: Thermae Romae works.
Rym: And guess what?
Scott: Netflix is making the anime of Thermae Romae.
Scott: It's like, "Well, I guess I'll watch that instead of reading the manga.
Scott: Thanks a
Scott: lot.".
Rym: Yep, especially considering how good Kiklos is.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, this will probably be a huge, you know, probably even better, right?
Scott: 'Cause the Kiklos one is obviously a low-budget situation.
Scott: Yeah, but the low-budget, I think, is enhancing how good it is for reasons that- Yes, but I think Thermae Romae is a little- is a little less ridiculous, um, even though it bears some similarities.
Rym: So- So, trucking right along from that, there's a- kind of a bigger underpinning to these announcements.
Rym: This is from about a week ago, but, uh, part of what's going on is that Netflix actually announced direct partnerships with Nas, Science Saru, Mappa, and Studio Mir.
Rym: And this is on the heels of announcing their partnerships with Production
Rym: I.G.,
Rym: which includes Bone- oh, and Bones.
Rym: Uh, Netflix is kind of just taking over the Western anime market, and they're also making huge inroads into the actual anime production industry in Japan.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically rather than the old model of "Japan makes anime,".
Scott: and then the Western funimations, you know, whatever, all those companies that went out of business, the genieons, whatever, pioneers, going and licensing those shows for release.
Scott: Instead, we have, basically, the digital distributors, right, just sitting on the companies, being like, "Alright, we got a partnership now, uh, you know, maybe we'll have some input on what you're making, right, it'll go both ways, but, you know, you make it, and it's ours already, right, we're in it from the start, before you even made the show, we're not licensing it after you made it or anything, we're gonna make the show together, and you show it in Japan how you're gonna show it, and we're gonna show it on Netflix over
Scott: here.".
Scott: Right, maybe Japan Netflix, I don't know, with their TV in Japan, whatever, but,
Rym: uh,
Scott: there's no opportunity for a Crunchyroll to get in there, there's not gonna be, like, negotiations or bids for licenses, um, who knows if they'll even
Rym: be- I don't think this bodes well for Funimation or for Crunchyroll in the long run, to be honest.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know how it bodes for, like, you know, um, will the licenses ever expire, 'cause is it even a license, right, they just have it forever, it's like, it's a Netflix show forever, the end, right?
Scott: Um, will anyone get to put out DVDs and boures if they want, you know, what's, is there a merch situation, right, is Netflix gonna come to the anime cons?
Rym: And it was interesting, I was thinking about.
Rym: where am I watching, like, animation, not even just anime, but animation in general, and honestly, like, 70% of all the animation I'm watching lately, like, in the last six months, is on Netflix, and then, like, 10% Crunchyroll, 10% everything else combined.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Meanwhile, the show, the one show, I want a Geek Bite right now, a show that is not on any of those pla- the show is actually, like, on Funimation's platform, I think.
Rym: We ended up watching it.
Scott: You gotta, uh, uh, here's some problems over there.
Rym: That little cough coming in.
Scott: Uh-oh, you weren't standing next to some no mask maskless people in the voting line.
Rym: One, thankfully, living in New York, 100% of the people in that line were, like, mega masked up.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: 'Cause they won't let you in, like, you know, you see those videos in other states where, like, there's people without masks all over, like, inside of- that really does not happen in New York City, except maybe in Staten Island.
Scott: I mean, I see people who might not wear the mask, like, when they're walking down the sidewalk alone or with someone.
Rym: But you see them, like, pull it up as soon as someone else appears on the street.
Scott: Right, but, like, if anyone is going into a place or with a person or whatever, right, or going to a building or any, you know, then no one is not wearing, you know.
Rym: But, uh, when we judged anime, one of the animes we judged was a show called Deca Dense.
Rym: And it looked like a generic fighting show, like, it might be fun, maybe it's, like, I don't know, Attack on Titan, but we basically- Didn't we talk about this a little bit last week, too?
Rym: Yes, we did.
Rym: So, I've actually seen some of it now, because basically what happened was, I was gonna ignore that show unless there was some buzz.
Rym: There was some buzz, there was a lot of buzz.
Scott: I heard the buzz as well, buzz buzz.
Rym: Literally, yeah, I'm a busy little bee.
Rym: Literally everyone who said anything about this show said the same thing.
Rym: It's not what it looks like, just watch it.
Rym: Two episodes in, you'll see why.
Rym: And no one would- no one would spoil anything else about it.
Rym: So I went, and we- turns out we accidentally have a Hulu account.
Rym: So we watched two episodes on Hulu, and sure enough, it starts out, it's good.
Rym: Without the twist, like, if there was nothing special about this show, it actually started out pretty good.
Rym: Like, it was a pretty solid anime, actually better than I expected.
Rym: But the very end of episode one, they show a weird scene, and then the episode ends.
Rym: And all I can think is, wait, that was a weird scene, explain that.
Rym: Then I watched episode two, and by the end of episode two, what that scene is is explained.
Rym: And the show is not even close to what I thought it was about.
Rym: The show is- you gotta watch it.
Rym: That's all I'm gonna say.
Rym: Decadence is a show that needs to be watched.
Scott: Maybe I gotta pirate it, I don't know, 'cause I don't have no Hulu, and I'm not gonna switch my Netflix for Hulu anytime soon.
Rym: Yep, you could- I don't know, we'll figure out a way for you to watch it.
Rym: I've only seen two episodes, but I am deeply intrigued.
Rym: Like, the best way I can describe this is, I'm watching that first episode, and I'm thinking, "Oh, wait, is this an Evangelion?
Rym: Or is this gonna be more like an Attack on Titan?
Rym: Like, which direction is this conflict gonna
Rym: go?".
Scott: I can just watch Evangelion, I can watch that anytime.
Rym: But then it went Mad Max?
Rym: For a brief moment.
Rym: I was like, "Oh, Mad Max?
Rym: That is an interesting play, let's see.
Rym: Like, that's an interesting strategy, let's see how it turns
Rym: out.".
Rym: And then, it goes off the deep end.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: I think it is particularly, specifically, up your alley, personally.
Scott: Okay, maybe.
Rym: Based on what that scene looks like, the style that scene is in, this show is a Scott show, in particular.
Scott: Okay, well, we'll see.
Scott: So, uh, yeah, I have this laundry list- Maybe I should wait till it's 100% out, though, before I start watching it.
Rym: I think it is already out, I think, uh, people have seen it to the end.
Scott: The whole show?
Scott: Oh, okay, alright.
Rym: So, beyond that, other Netflix stuff, like, we're just gonna breeze over these.
Rym: There's a Gorillaz animated movie coming on Netflix.
Rym: There's the Pacific Rym anime that Netflix, I believe, is funding straight up.
Rym: There is Blue-Eyed Samurai, which is an animated action series with a bunch of famous people I don't really know, and a bunch of famous people I do know are all involved in it.
Rym: This is, like, the all-star cast animated show.
Rym: George Takei is even in it.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: We got, uh, this is old news.
Scott: Is that not Netflix?
Rym: An old news from, like, well, old.
Rym: From earlier in October, I don't think we talked about it much, but Bee and Puppycat, season two, where the show kind of goes for real, is on Netflix.
Scott: Yep, we didn't talk about that, but that did happen, yep.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like we talked about it, but we didn't talk about it on the show.
Scott: That's, I think that's correct, yes.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And, uh, last, we actually have some non-anime follow-up with the manga.
Rym: Remember a while back, we talked about the, uh, Utena manga that takes place after the revolution?
Rym: Spoilers, the revolution happens at the end of Utena.
Scott: Yeah, so, all right, so that, we talked about that, but yeah, Chiyo Saito made another volume of Utena manga called Utena After the Revolution, which I presume takes place after the revolution.
Rym: I imagine it's just, uh, it's Saved by the Bell, the college years.
Scott: Yeah, it actually came out.
Scott: It came out, like, earlier this month, but I didn't notice because I didn't receive my copy of it until, like, a couple days ago.
Scott: But it is now in my hands, an English copy, a legitimate English copy of this manga.
Scott: So if you're an Utena fan, I don't know if it's good or bad, I can't say.
Rym: But you know what it is?
Rym: It is more canonical content for your moribund franchise.
Scott: Yeah, so, uh, I'm gonna read it soon just to see what the deal is.
Scott: You'll probably hear from me in two weeks about what it contains, some geek bite or something, or who knows.
Scott: But yeah, it's now available, so if you want to read it, you should do that soon.
Rym: My caution to you, if you liked the Utena anime but have never read the manga, you absolutely have to read the rest of the manga first, because the manga is very different from the anime.
Scott: Yeah, I've only read some of the original Utena manga.
Rym: Like, Black Rose is not really canonically part of the manga, it's like a side story that's tacked on at the end.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know how much this new manga has to do with the old manga, though, versus it has to do with the anime.
Rym: We're gonna find out.
Rym: I believe it just picks right up from the old manga, assuming Black Rose didn't actually happen.
Scott: I'll have to do some research.
Rym: Yeah, I'm just gonna read it, because I've read the manga, it doesn't matter.
Scott: Yeah, maybe I'll re-read the complete old manga first, and then... Because it's not that long, it's only a few volumes, right?
Scott: The original manga?
Rym: Oh yeah, it's not long at all, I have it.
Rym: I could just drop it off at your house if you want to read it.
Scott: It's not like a big 20+ volume deal.
Rym: The other thing I'll caution you is, if you really liked Utena, but you wanted, like, more lore, or answers to burning questions, the manga does not provide that.
Scott: The manga does not have that.
Rym: The manga is Chiyo Saito telling the Chiyo Saito story, which is not the story that the anime tells.
Rym: The anime goes in a very different direction for all the eco-horror reasons we have discussed in the past.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day!
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: Got a very tiny thing of the day here, but it is very high quality, right?
Scott: So what it is is real simple.
Scott: It is a TV commercial, and this TV commercial is, what, 15 seconds long?
Scott: It's real short.
Scott: And they are advertising a brand of sausage that you can eat.
Scott: Basically, I think it's like Slim Jim that comes in a tube, right?
Scott: But some other Japanese brand.
Scott: But the commercial is a Fist of the North Star commercial.
Scott: It is therefore amazing.
Scott: Kenshiro says, "Eat some
Scott: sausage-y.".
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's not actually translated, but I'm going to pretend.
Scott: It says, "You have already eaten
Scott: sausage.".
Rym: I only watched it once.
Rym: I'm not going to play it again while I'm doing the show, but it sounded like he said something different.
Rym: He said like, "Oh
Rym: my.".
Rym: But he said something slightly different there.
Rym: I couldn't tell if that was just-- I think it might have been, "You have already eaten
Rym: sausage.".
Rym: Yeah, I could not tell, and I don't want to play it again, because we're literally live streaming the show.
Rym: But I will listen to it again after.
Scott: The point is, for 15 seconds, you can watch this.
Rym: What I wonder is, if I bite into one of these sausages, will they explode in a pile of gore and blood?
Scott: Your enemy will expire.
Rym: The first-- this is a Twitter post.
Rym: It's Patrick Macias.
Rym: The first reply to his tweet is, quote, "How much blood is there in those sausages, and under how many megapascals of pressure?
Rym: Biting into these has to be very
Rym: risky.".
Scott: I'm pretty sure your opponent will explode when you bite one.
Scott: You wouldn't sell very many if the customers exploded.
Scott: Or maybe you offer one to your opponent.
Scott: Like, you know, that's like a peace offering, but then they explode.
Rym: So my thing of the day from late September, an infinite time in the past, is an official special music video.
Rym: This happened every now and then over the years.
Rym: Like, there is an official Escaflowne one at one point.
Rym: This is an official Pokemon music video.
Rym: So it feels like an AMV, but it is actually official, animated by Bones, to a song.
Rym: Gotcha, Bump of Chicken.
Rym: Don't worry too much about the lyrics.
Rym: What?
Rym: Do not worry too much about why this is called Bump of Chicken.
Rym: I imagine it's like a bump of cocaine.
Scott: Camels have bumps, not chickens.
Rym: But a Bump of Chicken.
Rym: But this is a phenomenal music video.
Rym: The animation is fantastic.
Rym: This will give you such just, like, a gut punch of nostalgia for the entire Pokemon franchise.
Rym: To the level of, if you didn't know, the movie Stand By Me, a classic of, like, Americana growing up movies, probably more important and more noteworthy than the Goonies for a lot of reasons in America.
Rym: The movie Stand By Me is canonically in Pokemon Red, the original Pokemon.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: That is, in fact, true.
Rym: And there is a scene in the very beginning.
Rym: This music video starts with four boys walking on some train tracks about to go find some Pokemon.
Scott: Oh, no.
Rym: This music video is great.
Rym: Judas showed it to us the other night.
Rym: She was like, "Hey, you got to watch
Rym: this.".
Rym: And, yeah, you all got to watch it.
Rym: In the moment?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Stuck inside, still.
Rym: Nothing's changed in the last 48 hours.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: Uh, the book club book is still tailored.
Rym: Opera Club.
Scott: There have to be operas.
Scott: And the problem with the Opera Club is that operas are not necessarily accessible to everyone.
Scott: There are recordings of operas.
Rym: Like, I watch God or Dameron in person, but I watch the rest of the Ring Cycle on, uh, uh, basically on tape.
Scott: Yeah, you can watch them on video.
Scott: But, like, that's the other thing.
Scott: It's like, we're not qualified or knowledgeable to, like, comment on them.
Rym: No, that would be naive commentary.
Rym: We would just review the opera as an entertainment experience.
Scott: It had these three songs, I remember, and I don't, and because they're the famous songs, I don't remember the rest.
Scott: I didn't understand what anyone was saying.
Scott: I read the subtitles and the story was stupid.
Scott: That's gonna be the comment for every single opera.
Rym: Faust, why did you make that terrible deal with the devil?
Rym: What did you think was gonna happen?
Scott: The book was better.
Scott: But, yeah, the, uh, the book club book is still The Tale of Genji.
Scott: I almost read it, but then I read these comic books we're about to talk about instead.
Rym: Yep, uh, I was, uh, not thinking about reading it because I don't have time to read anything.
Rym: Do you know how much shit I gotta do in my day-to-day life?
Scott: You read these comic books.
Rym: Yeah, I read these comic books, like, I only read the first volume.
Rym: I didn't get a time to read the second volume yet.
Scott: All right, well, there's only two volumes that I'm aware of.
Rym: Yeah, which is fine because the first volume is great.
Rym: I got enough to go on with this.
Scott: Is there any other meta moment whatsoever?
Rym: Uh, nothing really.
Rym: Just follow us in all the places.
Rym: Bug us if you don't have a link to our Discord.
Rym: You can also use our GeekNights community forum, but kids mostly hang out in Discords these days.
Scott: Yep, anyway, uh, that's the end of the meta moment.
Scott: Give me a meta moment to go get the comics off the shelf because I forgot to bring them to my desk.
Rym: All right, so, Isola.
Rym: I haven't been following comics much lately because I've been doing a lot of other things.
Rym: Like, most of what's occupying my brain time that is not, like, projects I'm working on are video games and board games and some technology things lately.
Rym: So I've been reading comics.
Rym: Didn't even know this was coming.
Rym: But, uh, Isola, uh, has- Isola?
Scott: I don't know how to pronounce it.
Scott: I-sola?
Rym: I'm going with Isola unless someone tells me otherwise.
Rym: An evil spell has been cast on the Queen of Marr and her Captain of the Guard will do anything to reverse it.
Rym: The only hope lies in an island half a world away, a place known in myth as Isola, the Land of the Dead.
Rym: Gotham Academy creators Brendan Fletcher and Carl Kerschel reunite with a colorist and a letterer to make this thing come alive.
Rym: The funniest thing is the Amazon listing has a sentence at the end that just says, "recommended for fans of Studio Ghibli and the works of Hayao
Rym: Miyazaki.".
Scott: Kinda.
Rym: Yeah, kinda.
Rym: Not a hundred percent.
Rym: Like, that is an oddly specific recommendation to make.
Rym: I guess I see- I see where they're going with that, but it's really- If you're a fan of the Naoshika manga, that's a better, like-.
Scott: Naoshika is definitely the closest to this.
Rym: Because if someone watched Totoro and then thinks they're going to read this, not the best fit, maybe.
Scott: No, not at all.
Scott: So what's the deal here?
Scott: So the creators of this are pretty interesting.
Scott: I'd never heard of them before.
Scott: And I looked them up, and you look at their credits, and their credits don't have any particular item, right?
Scott: That is like, you know, wow, that's like an all-time great kind of thing, right?
Rym: Well, I recognized Carl Kerschel when I looked up his Wikipedia because I've seen him before at conventions.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: I mean, I know the person's- I know their name.
Rym: But I knew him as a DC guy, like.
Rym: I didn't really think beyond that.
Scott: Right, it's like name for me.
Scott: one thing he did, right?
Rym: It's like, you know- Some DC stuff, but he won an Eisner in 2011.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: But it's all this, you know, these are people who are like seasoned professionals in the industry, but they don't have to their name, right?
Scott: Like that, you know, huge title that like everyone knows, right?
Scott: Even people who do work in superhero stuff, right?
Scott: You know, like a Frank Miller has like a Dark Knight Returns.
Scott: Like, oh, he's got a, you know, that's his thing, right?
Rym: A comic person might know like, oh yeah, Gotham Academy or like Teen Titans Year One, but that doesn't break beyond the comic fan people.
Scott: Right, but like, you know, like they have these creators still have tremendous talent, you know, tremendous skills, and they're just doing professional work for hire, right?
Scott: So here they come with their own story, right?
Scott: A new, a brand new property, a unique thing, right?
Scott: You know, published by Image and it's like, whoa, look at that, right?
Scott: Holy snap.
Scott: So what the heck is Isola about, right?
Scott: This thing that, you know, these very talented, you know, comic industry professionals did when they finally would make their own book instead of, you know, just another superhero book, right?
Scott: So the story here is like what Rym said, there is some kingdom, you don't know a queendom, you don't know about a country, a nation, and the queen of that nation, and this is not a spoiler because it's revealed on page like fucking one, has been intentionally, unintentionally, somehow transformed into a tiger, roar, roar, right?
Scott: And the queen's guard, the number one guard of the queens, basically like the equivalent of Oscar from Rose of Versailles, same job, right?
Scott: Royal guard, the only one person, the chief Royal guard person, uh, is accompanying the tiger on a journey.
Scott: So they're running away, um, and trying to keep the queen alive, which is sometimes easy because the queen is a tiger.
Rym: Sometimes difficult because the world is terrifyingly dangerous.
Scott: And because the queen is a tiger and they're like hunters.
Scott: And some people seem to know the queen is a tiger.
Scott: Some people don't, right?
Rym: Like one random person who shows up, it's like, oh, I know, I know.
Scott: It's also a fantasy world full of magic.
Scott: Um, and also there seems to be this terrible secret of space, um, that is revealed very, very early on and that there are, what do they call them?
Scott: There's like a name for them.
Rym: Well, there's the, there's the idea of like.
Rym: who is going to be the in between.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: But no, there's these things called the Hallam, which are these birds.
Scott: They look like Ravens or crows, black birds of some kind, gigantic black birds.
Scott: They are enormous.
Scott: We're talking like, you know, bigger than dinosaur sized, right?
Scott: Like could probably Peck it like an Eva's face.
Scott: Um, uh, so they're out there and they early on, they encounter one that is already deceased somehow.
Rym: And it's notable that the characters are like, I didn't know they could die.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, holy shit.
Scott: And so it's like they're there as like, even after, you know, volume two, right?
Scott: It's like, they're sort of like this looming, not present, but like, you just know they exist in this world threat that sort of hovers over everything because they're mentioned often.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're always like Hallam this and Hallam that.
Scott: Um, you know, even though they're not there, we haven't that direct conflict of giant birds are coming to Peck you right now.
Scott: That hasn't happened.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That would sort of make things end quickly.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But what is happening, like what I like about this comic is it starts in media res and uses proper nouns appropriately.
Rym: And you start to figure out the deal.
Rym: There's like an empire that appears to be collapsing.
Rym: Like you encounter, like the, the equivalent of the Roman legions of this emperor empire are sort of like in disarray, like things are starting to fall down.
Rym: There's ruins, there's other kingdoms out there.
Rym: There's these warrior clans.
Rym: And I do appreciate media that has a lot of those kinds of proper nouns, but just trust you to figure it out and like reveal the story organically instead of having like an origin story or a prelude to explain it all.
Scott: Well, it's not necessarily proper noun leading, right?
Scott: Like.
Scott: sometimes it's just like, yeah, they're hunters, right?
Scott: It's like, it's just an appropriate word to describe the group.
Scott: And the only proper nouns are the ones that for things that need proper nouns, names of countries, names of things that don't exist in the real world, right?
Scott: Names of people, right?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: They're not like- There are a lot of incidental ones.
Rym: Like they bring up circles, like the circle a lot, and you sort of figure out what that really means as it goes on.
Rym: Like why, where this character came from.
Scott: But yeah, it's, it's pretty much, you know, journey of two people together and the thing, the difficulties they encounter along the way.
Scott: And they're your discovery and their discovery, right?
Scott: Of, um, you know, like what the true, what the real deal is, right?
Scott: Cause like, you know, the queen clearly knows more than the guard does.
Rym: The queen is, and there's also a, the guard knows a lot, but the guard's origin is sort of mysterious, like how the guard came into this position.
Rym: There's some romance angles, there's a lot going on.
Scott: And they encounter lots of, you know, interesting figures, like magical old man type of people that know more or less, right?
Scott: And help or hinder their journey along the way.
Scott: There's also the big mystery, right?
Scott: Is this place they're going to, Isola, Isola, whatever, right?
Scott: Is at some times you think Isola is actually just like, you know, heaven is not a real place, right?
Scott: You know, they're going to their, or it's like the land of the dead.
Scott: They're just going out to die somewhere appropriately.
Scott: Or, you know, they're, the journey that they're taking is the important part.
Scott: There isn't at the destination is not real, or it's a magical other land.
Scott: It's not a real land land, or maybe it is a real land land, you know?
Scott: And anytime people they meet along the way talk about it, they always talk ambiguously.
Rym: - But I think the main reason to read this, like the plot is good.
Rym: The characters are good.
Rym: Like the dialogue is all right, but it really focuses on visual storytelling.
Rym: And the words the characters are saying are driving like the things that you can't drive visually because it's a fairly complex world.
Rym: The visual storytelling is pretty phenomenal and the creatures are beautiful.
Rym: Like the pages are just beautiful reading this comic.
Scott: - Yeah, what'll happen often is, you know, there's the parts of the story that are quite, you know, literal, like this is happening, right?
Scott: And then people are often, characters are often in dreams or hallucinations or visions of some kind.
Scott: And you can get a little confusing.
Scott: actually, you know, is this real?
Scott: Is this not real?
Rym: - It's almost like form is function.
Rym: Like you, you, the reader are disoriented by these rapid shifts of context, but the character that you're following is equally disoriented by them.
Scott: - And also the things that are happening, it's like, you know, after the first, like, you know, dreams, you know, kind of, you know, dreamish sequence, right?
Scott: You sort of realize, you know, it doesn't matter if this part is literally happening or is in someone's mind or is a vision or who knows what it is because all of it's real, right?
Scott: It's not, they're not, they're not illusions of lies, right?
Scott: They're visions of true things, right?
Scott: It's like, oh, the dream is showing me something.
Scott: They're learning things, right?
Scott: They're not, you know, being fooled by anyone except when they are, right?
Scott: And then you find this, in that case, there is somebody, there's, you know, there's a visible adversary who is doing the fooling.
Scott: So it's not, that part is not, you know, confusing.
Rym: - But what's interesting too is that it actually moves pretty quick.
Rym: Like, I gave up trying to predict the pace of this almost immediately because things that I thought they were, like, felt like in a comic would be a setup for later got resolved immediately.
Rym: Other things lasted way longer than I expected.
Rym: And even volume one ends in a, it ends in a very different place from what I expected one trade of a comic like this to end at.
Scott: - Yeah, I think what.
Scott: the reason is that, you know, it originally came out as, you know, individual issues, right?
Scott: So each of those issues actually has to have, like, stuff happen in it.
Scott: And all the, normally on a long journey like this, you'd have a lot of that, you know, time spent traveling.
Scott: They don't do any of that.
Scott: They only giving you the destined, you know, they've arrived somewhere and do a thing at the place.
Scott: They meet some people and do a thing at the place.
Scott: You know, the parts where things happen are the only parts, the way you're supposed to play, like, a tabletop RPG properly, right?
Scott: And it's just like, you know, when they're in a place and then as they resolve whatever is happening there and, like, the next page, which would be, I guess, the next issue, I don't know where the issue boundaries are because the trade puts all the covers at the end of the book.
Scott: But it's like they're immediately at a new place, basically, right?
Scott: There's not a lot of time spent, maybe a page or two of, like, we're walking on some cliff rocks and then we see a new place, right?
Scott: And let's go there.
Rym: But there's definitely a house.
Scott: Let's go in it.
Rym: There's definitely the theme of, like, there was an empire that for various reasons is collapsing and there's some sort of ecological catastrophe that may or may not be related to that.
Rym: And there's a very deep transhuman theme the entire way so far.
Scott: You know, it'll be like, oh, we're escaping some hunters.
Scott: We escaped.
Scott: There's some ruins.
Scott: Let's go in the ruins, right?
Scott: Like the next page.
Rym: Oh, there's the head of, like, the legion that was stationed there.
Rym: But, like, the empire doesn't appear to be paying them anymore.
Rym: And, like, it's not really clear what's going on.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Something else that needs to be mentioned, right, is the, you know, the tiger is a queen, right?
Scott: And, you know, the guard, right, is also at least, you know, appears to be someone who is female.
Rym: And they're clearly lovers.
Rym: Clearly.
Scott: Uh, it appears to me the queen 100%, right, is, like, you know, all over the guard.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: The guard may be clueless.
Rym: Well, yeah, the guard might be a disaster in that sense.
Rym: The guard may be clueless.
Rym: I get the impression the queen, like, elevated the guard to be close to her, but propriety prevented her from exploring that relationship.
Rym: And now they're on the road and one's a tiger and we'll see where this goes.
Scott: Yeah, clearly the queen, you know, chose this person to be their guard for, like, reasons, right?
Scott: And those that we know what the reasons are, right?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I don't think there are further plot reasons there, necessarily, because the plot stuff seems to revolve around the queen's brother and whatever the hell he was up to.
Scott: I don't know what he didn't make any sense, right, because they don't they don't reveal too much, right?
Rym: Well, I like that, too.
Rym: Like, there's a scene where they're with the, uh, the animal people in the woods that were the swampy woods at one point being vague here for a reason.
Rym: But even then, like, it's not super clear to the characters or even to the reader exactly why that goes south in a hurry and they get kicked out again.
Rym: And things are very confusing and moving very fast in that regard.
Rym: It's very unclear what anyone wants for real, except the main character, the guard, just wants to turn the queen into a human again.
Rym: And the queen seems to also want to become a human again, but also seems to maybe be becoming something different that might have been intended.
Rym: Like, the plot might have been to make the queen different for a reason.
Scott: Yeah, we just don't know what the reason is.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: I have no idea what anyone wants except the queen and the guard.
Rym: No, everyone else is basically a mystery to me.
Scott: So something on the art that I can't ignore is the coloring in this book is very, very interesting in that when you look at most pages, there are some pages that are exceptions.
Scott: Most pages are basically one or maybe two colors, right?
Scott: Like, you look at the whole page, all the panels on the whole.
Scott: Here's a two page spread.
Scott: Anyone who's watching the stream can maybe see this.
Scott: It's a blue page, right?
Scott: And then it's like, oh, I'll go over here.
Scott: This is a purple page, right?
Scott: See, every single frame in the whole page is purple, right?
Scott: And it's like, OK, here's a purple page with two blue frames.
Rym: And it definitely the color scheme of any given layout definitely has ties to the perspective that you're seeing things from.
Scott: Here's some orange pages, right?
Scott: It's like everything, no matter where you turn.
Scott: And this holds true in volume two as well.
Scott: Yep, holds true in volume two as well.
Scott: Pretty much any page you turn to is one, maybe two colors and different, you know, the hue is the same and all the other variables on color saturation, etc.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Luminance are altered, but it'll be like almost like a solid hue for like a whole page or spreads.
Rym: And it's definitely tied to the mood of the characters or the context of the story in some capacity or whether or not it's in the dream world.
Rym: I'm not actually sure if there is a dream world or if that's more complicated.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You can even see the colors of the trades.
Scott: Trade number one is the green trade and trade number two is the purple trade.
Scott: Even like you don't have to be an artist to see, you know, this like it's such a. it's such like a bold, plain, like in your face artistic decision.
Scott: And it really shows like the strength of the colorist.
Scott: It's like, OK, color, you decide you're going to make these all these four pages in a row, all purple.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But still, everyone has to be able to tell who all the characters are and tell what all the objects are.
Scott: But everything has to be purple, some shade of purple.
Scott: But I also love to put green on this page or red or yellow or brown.
Rym: I enjoy the history.
Scott: You got to make it purple in that context.
Rym: Watching the queen as a tiger try to interact with the other characters and the nonverbal communication.
Rym: The comic is mostly serious, significantly gory and violent.
Rym: Like this is a violent story, but it also at times is extremely funny.
Rym: But that funniness is very brief and sort of punctuates everything else that's going on.
Scott: It's mostly very so far, very, very small amounts of humor.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's there, but it's very tiny.
Scott: It's like a. it's like a dusting.
Rym: Like there's.
Rym: there is a moment when a character who seems to be able to communicate better with the queen is like basically sitting with the queen by himself.
Rym: And he's like, so, yeah, you're definitely completely in love with your guard.
Rym: Right.
Rym: And the queen reacts in an appropriately funny way.
Rym: But then it gets into the transhumanist, like, shall we say, transhumanist nonsense two pages later.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And that just also brings to mind just the facial expressions of every single character.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Are like because there's actually not too many words in a lot of parts of the book.
Rym: Which I appreciate.
Rym: I like that.
Scott: It's like it's, you know, you know, comics in general became less wordy over time.
Rym: You know, you, you little guy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, of like the Silver Age and even, you know, where people would just say what was happening in the panel.
Scott: Instead of just showing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And we learn not comic creators learn not to do that.
Scott: But this goes even further towards, you know, saying really the bare minimum and showing everything with the artwork.
Scott: And so, you know, not just the human facial expressions telling you pretty much everything.
Scott: But to be able to draw the tiger face expressions.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Without showing everything the animal features, they still like you can tell when the queen is pissed.
Scott: This is not like a furry situation, though.
Scott: I guess it might be.
Scott: Well, it's like, yeah, the queen isn't it's not.
Scott: it's not like a tiger person.
Scott: It's just a tiger.
Scott: It's black with blue stripes.
Rym: There are just like there are characters you encounter who are sort of like mishmashes of human and animal traits, but not enough.
Rym: They're not in a stereotypical furry art way, but more in a monstrous and unique style.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: This is this is Siegfried and Roy.
Scott: Like it's a tiger.
Scott: It's not a it's not.
Scott: it's not Tony the tiger.
Scott: That's what I'm trying to say.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But I guess what I would say is like, I don't want to really say much more about it because it's great.
Rym: And if you want to read a comic, you've been reading comics lately and you're OK for something that's a little bit violent, but otherwise beautiful.
Scott: This saga is really worth reading.
Scott: I'm pretty sure Saga is still on hiatus.
Scott: So this is your American not superhero comic to read right now.
Rym: I presume that volume three is coming out, right?
Scott: I presume volume three is coming out.
Scott: At some point.
Scott: I don't know when, but I'll preorder it just like I pre-order one and two.
Scott: I actually didn't preorder one.
Scott: I found out about one afterwards and then I preordered.
Rym: I just bought it on Comixology and read it on my laptop.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That seems like a good idea.
Scott: So, yeah, ESOLA.
Scott: I S O L A. It is the comic to read right now.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Adam McNichol, Marty Granier, Graham Finch, Yule, the Key to My Heart.
Rym: If anything, I could say this cab was rare.
Rym: I actually have to hover over your name if it's longer than, like, 15 characters and wait for the tooltip to pop up to be able to read it.
Rym: That is actually super annoying and sometimes causes me trouble here.
Rym: But anyway, make sure you go out and vote.
Rym: It's kind of important.
Rym: And now I leave you with...