Rym: It's Tuesday December 29th 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are talking about the last 10 years of games.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I'm working this week But it's like the low-key.
Rym: We're like no one's it.
Rym: well because I saved all my vacation days and my job doesn't just kind of the end of the year Like yours does my where my work is closed.
Rym: I ran a company.
Rym: it would fucking close from like Christmas to New Year's every year.
Scott: my previous company and current company closed.
Scott: I would not work somewhere if they were not closed.
Rym: if I had a company would also close in like the peak month like The peak of summer.
Rym: they'd be like a two-week.
Rym: We're just closed.
Rym: go to the beach.
Rym: That's cuz.
Rym: I'm a good person man, but I've had a lot more free time because I finished a bunch of other projects and I got a bunch of things set up and I basically have been playing a lot of Non-overwatch video games again.
Rym: It's kind of weird Okay, but what I've been playing a lot of again is Star Wars squadrons Mm-hmm, and the thing is Star Wars quadrants like we reviewed it already.
Rym: The game's great Like it's everything I wanted but we were.
Rym: uh, I think the game industry term was dog shit And it in terms of our actual play like when me and Scott like all of us are still dog shit at it.
Rym: Ah So since the update that is no longer true.
Scott: I Think that what is how if anything has happened?
Scott: They have simply fixed matchmakings.
Rym: There's a few things they fix.
Rym: So if you haven't played our skills, our bodies didn't suddenly change.
Scott: We didn't practice it, right?
Scott: There's no way we got better at it overnight.
Rym: I actually did practice and got better.
Rym: I've been playing a lot of bunch of solo and I was practicing certain kinds of things and forcing myself to play the a-wing and the tie interceptor even when I was losing and my team was sucking partly because of me.
Rym: It was starting to pay off.
Rym: I also did read a lot more tutorials on things Like.
Rym: I learned how to micro drift pretty well Like I can do those like weird like 90 degree 90 degree turns like around an asteroid like really reliably now.
Rym: But okay, what really happened is this update?
Rym: remember when they released this game?
Rym: They definitely were like hedging their bets because they said things like the game is coming out.
Rym: But it's as is like we're not gonna invest more in the game There aren't gonna be new ships.
Scott: Yeah, the people who are working on it at what it was that company in Canada Right is like it's published by EA but this other company made it and they're basically like, okay, you guys are done now Right.
Scott: We're done paying you money.
Scott: This is you made it.
Scott: It's released the end.
Scott: Yep, right and buy it for 40 bucks or don't.
Rym: but it was a very popular and I think they realized that or whatever whatever decision-making process internally went from.
Rym: Well, let's hedge our bets - okay, the game's big let's actually invest more into it.
Rym: and they made a lot of balance changes a lot of bug fixes and They seem to have fixed the matchmaking because one thing that is very different now is we are playing against people who are around our skill level.
Scott: Yeah Matchmaking is of course always super huge in any game that is skill based with not a lot of luck.
Scott: because You know, if you got wedge antilles out there, right you're just big trouble If you're not, you know.
Rym: and but what's interesting is the changes They made the balance changes not so much the matchmaking but the balance changes.
Rym: they change in ways That's hard to describe and I'm still introspect Like I'm still inspecting as I play and I think about why it feels so different.
Rym: It changed the way the game feels to play and it feels a lot more like the old tie fighter game and it seems to mostly focus around things like They tweaked a bunch of the weapons to where that one rotary like burst cannon thing is not just the god of the game anymore.
Rym: That's good.
Rym: They did some oddly specific things like that that charge up cannon.
Rym: Now when you're charging it you take double damage until you release to prevent people using it to
Scott: couse
Rym: Mm-hmm, so it can only really be used when you're chasing someone as a win more or like attacking a capital ship Like if you're going head-on against someone that weapon is a mistake
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: They also changed the way the capital ships interact with star fighters and how they target such that if you're going fast and Maneuvering a lot.
Rym: It actually takes them a lot longer to lock on to you.
Scott: And yeah I was always.
Scott: I was under the impression that like that the the star destroyers and the capital ships basically weren't actually like Shooting.
Scott: they were just sort of like, you know saying, you know calculating like is there an enemy within Right damage them, you know this percent, you know over time whatever right or stuff like that.
Rym: No, they just work like a normal ship.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: They've got all those turrets.
Rym: those turrets all fire Independently and it has logic for what to target and it basically if you're going fast and maneuvering more like, you know It calculates.
Scott: Okay, this x-wing has been within the range of the Star Destroyer for x seconds.
Scott: Alright animate the turret shooting it guaranteed hitting it and doing this much damage, right?
Rym: It's not Yeah, it's actually like.
Rym: it's very clear if you watch how they behave in-game.
Rym: Like you know the training mode mess with it a little bit that it seems to do a very simple system of prioritizing targets.
Rym: It doesn't seem to do a lot of logic there But it does prioritize targets and it basically seems to disperse its fire among the valid targets within its zone That it has gotten a lock on and it has some.
Rym: the targeting system has some sort of logic where it takes it longer to lock based on how fast you're going and how much you're maneuvering.
Rym: so the end result and I tested this a bunch was that if You fly straight at it by yourself You see like in the distance It'll suddenly fire all of its turrets that can see you at you and this big salvo just like comes at you and only you.
Rym: But if you come at it with a bunch of ships It's it targets all of them at the same time and shoots like a little bit at all of them.
Rym: But if one of the ships you're coming in with is faster than the other ones, it doesn't target the faster ship for a while.
Scott: Mmm,
Rym: and I confirm this experimentally by playing the end result of all these changes though Like I cannot stress enough if you bounced off of this game because it felt too hard the game just feels Way more fun to play and all these balance changes basically made all the different play styles kind of work.
Rym: Like it's kind of shocking how all these tweaks have made the game feel completely differently.
Scott: Small changes make a big difference.
Rym: Yeah, and as a result, I'm diving into this game pretty hard now Like I'm playing it almost every day.
Rym: This game is great.
Rym: So you got got any news?
Scott: Not really, it's not like people are releasing games.
Scott: I'm on the holiday, right?
Scott: They release them before the holiday To sell for the holiday.
Scott: But yeah, I've been playing this game.
Scott: I saw this game at PAX many years ago at least a few years ago when it was like super new not even out yet And it's been in every packs.
Scott: I've been to since then.
Scott: At least video game packs is right.
Scott: somewhere it had a booth.
Scott: They were showing it off and I said that game looks kind of interesting, you know I'll probably play that one day.
Scott: and that day came.
Scott: so the game is graveyard keeper.
Scott: It's a game That you know, it's pixely kind of art.
Scott: It's got sort of Lucas artsy kind of humor.
Scott: You know that kind of thing, right and it's sort of like a harvest moon situation.
Scott: But you are a graveyard keeper and that's all I knew about it.
Scott: So now that I've played it a bunch.
Scott: I haven't beaten it yet It's pretty interesting And there's also some not good things, right?
Scott: So the good thing about it that makes it different from all the other harvest moons rune factories Stardew valleys all those sorts of things.
Scott: right is let's say you're playing rune factory And there's a whole bunch of different systems in all these games, right?
Scott: You know, you got your your your your farming you get your dating you got right?
Scott: There's no dating in graveyard keeper, but you know, it's there's other stuff for you got dungeoning sometimes all kinds of systems but usually you sort of have to or feel like you have to Keep up on all the systems like like in rune factory.
Scott: There's like a day right.
Scott: the day goes around and as you plant some crops You got to water them every day.
Scott: If you miss a day, they'll be shitty your crops, right?
Scott: So every day you have to water them every day and then if they grow you got to harvest them at the exact right day.
Scott: Otherwise, then they start to rot right and you sort of have to keep.
Scott: you know, if you got animals you got to feed them daily, yeah, or every.
Scott: I've got to brush the animals like.
Rym: it's a game loop that I have Never in my life been able to engage with without getting mad at and as I get older I have even less patience for right.
Scott: So what graveyard keeper does is very interesting and that is the same sort of game mechanics, right?
Scott: It's like okay, you know get you know, the materials in a minecraft II sort of way, right?
Scott: Yeah tree take a log build the building to process the log into planks.
Scott: You know five planks and three bits of metal makes a desk or some shit like that, you know the same usual thing, right?
Scott: You know, you need ten pumpkins to do this.
Scott: So you go to you Have you?
Scott: did you plow some land?
Scott: you plant some pumpkin seeds that you bought, right?
Scott: You you put some fertilizer first, right, you know same same shit you do with all these other games.
Scott: but While there is a day in a week this sort of fictional weekly calendar where there's like a different symbol for each day There is no pressure on anything.
Scott: It's like they're like Satan.
Scott: There are quests that you're trying to accomplish.
Scott: for example, like the astrologer.
Scott: it'll be like All right, the astrologer needs some acid to repair a book, right?
Scott: You can just get him the acid Whenever the fuck you can just you could get.
Scott: you could just do everything else in the game.
Scott: I just whenever you feel like getting the acid you can do it, right?
Scott: He's always you know, well the astrologer is only there once a week on a particular day.
Scott: But you know, you can just do it whenever it.
Scott: the quest never goes away You know you if you need say some pumpkins to make the acid which you don't I'm just making an exam.
Rym: That makes me more interested in this game because that's why I can't engage with Stardew Valley, right?
Scott: Let's say you need some pumpkins for something, right?
Scott: The witch the witch actually had a quest.
Scott: we needed to bring her a pumpkin right to make it big.
Scott: So you just you go you dig some land right.
Scott: you plant your pumpkin seed then you can just go focus.
Scott: Let's say you want to focus on this other quest.
Scott: where you need it I don't know.
Scott: you want to build up your.
Scott: you want to make your graveyard nicer for the for the priest, right?
Scott: You just go spend like a whole bunch of days working on your graveyard.
Scott: Just ignoring the pumpkins.
Scott: You just forgotten about them.
Scott: You're not and you're not playing the farming system.
Scott: You're only playing the graveyard system because that's what you feel like doing right now.
Scott: You fully focus on doing this graveyard stuff getting stones carving them putting them in the graveyard getting bodies You know embalming them burying of them, right?
Scott: You're doing though.
Scott: you're interacting with just the system that you're focused on right now, and you just forgot all about the farming system.
Scott: You're not even touching it.
Scott: weeks in game in game weeks have gone by.
Scott: you haven't even checked the farm.
Scott: When you're ready for the farm again, you're like okay my graveyards perfect.
Scott: I completed my graveyard related quests.
Scott: Let's go check on the farm.
Scott: all the pumpkins are just sitting there a plus pumpkins.
Scott: They're just chillin waiting for you.
Scott: They're not rotten or anything, you know, so you can.
Scott: there's many many systems and it is a very time-consuming game.
Scott: but you could just pick which parts of the game you're gonna focus on at any given moment and Fully focus on those and there's no FOMO of with any other part of the game at any time Which is kind of nice.
Scott: and that's I think what keeps me.
Scott: kept me playing it, right?
Scott: um bad parts of this game.
Scott: It there's a lot of systems and this quests relating to all the systems with all those plots and characters And I think partially it's because I bought a bundle with all the DLCs.
Scott: This game takes a long fucking time to play.
Rym: Well, the game is actually on sale right now for like under seven bucks.
Scott: That's only.
Scott: that's without the DLCs.
Scott: But yeah, I bought the.
Scott: I bought so I got it.
Scott: Also this game.
Scott: I don't think there's of the characters in the game I didn't.
Scott: I don't remember if there's any not white characters in this game.
Scott: I don't think there are.
Scott: You also can't like even change your character.
Scott: You're just this white beard dude, right?
Scott: It's that's your character.
Scott: deal with it.
Scott: Also, one of the characters is clearly a Romani type trading dude in the woods And they referred to him with the G racial slur for that Basically as if it's just a normal word there and I don't even know.
Scott: Then you know, they're just using it like it's 1980 something, right?
Scott: So that's a thing.
Scott: But yeah, the only time pressure there is I know I said there was like no pressure.
Scott: There is one thing in the game, you know, it's not there at the beginning of the game, but eventually You get the ability to give sermons in the church And that is like you're there.
Scott: that not only is gonna be like a very strong source of money Which is hard not that easy to get Because it's you can't just sell all your stuff easily because that's like supply and demand and shit like that.
Scott: But it's also the only way that I know of to get the faith resource, which is needed for a lot of things.
Scott: So and you can only do it on I guess Sunday or the day of the week that has the Sun symbol on it.
Scott: So basically even though there's no time pressure on anything You do have to sort of keep an eye on the calendar and be like up.
Scott: It's the Sun day.
Scott: I have to go and just you know, push go to the church and push the one button just to collect my faith, right?
Scott: It's it's that sort of thing and certain NPCs only appear one day of the week, right?
Scott: The astrologer only is on the moon day.
Scott: So if you have any astrologer related business, you got to wait for the moon day and remember and if you miss it It's not a big deal.
Scott: No, you missed it.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you just wait another week and then he'll be back.
Scott: Right, but it is a little bit annoying.
Scott: It's like alright, I guess I can't engage with that system.
Scott: Wait another week before I can go continue that bit, right?
Scott: So if you at single-player only.
Scott: So yeah, if you like that kind of thing, this is an okay game to play.
Scott: It's not perfect.
Scott: It's got some issues.
Scott: Oh another issue was Clearly they didn't like not the all the game has got so many bits going on.
Scott: I did some like plot stuff out of order and like my characters That clearly they weren't supposed like that didn't learn.
Scott: the character said some things as if they knew information And then after that I did a different quest and learned the information Thing before he learned the thing.
Scott: So there's a it's.
Scott: it's not that polished in the in those sorts of areas.
Scott: But yeah, it could see.
Scott: no I saw it a pecs and it looked interesting and I keep playing it.
Scott: So that's something.
Rym: It looks like it's on the switch too.
Rym: So maybe I'll play it on the switch.
Scott: Maybe I don't know if it could be good to play on the switch.
Scott: It's really a mouse and keyboard kind of situation.
Rym: I'll have to look at a video and see exactly how it works on the switch because slay the spire is best on the switch.
Rym: But I don't know about all.
Scott: there's a lot of manipulating inventory screens.
Rym: If it's just a bunch of like radio radio menus, it's not radio.
Scott: Oh you mean on the switch.
Rym: Oh, yeah No, I don't think I wonder what it look like on the switch.
Scott: I don't know what it looks like on the switch.
Scott: I imagine it looks the same and you just use your analog stick instead of a mouse or a touch screen or that sounds actually horrible.
Scott: Yeah, it's a mouse and keyboard game I think.
Scott: but all the other thing is that you know The thing I never ever want to do is touch my switches screen like ever.
Scott: Yeah, there's also you know people talk about like quality of life and these sorts of go.
Rym: the listeners Switch version has terrible load times - okay.
Scott: That's good info.
Scott: good info.
Rym: Well, then it's all.
Rym: it's under seven bucks on Steam's.
Rym: I guess buy it on Steam if you're interested.
Scott: Well, that doesn't include the DLCs.
Scott: But anyway, the last thing is that in terms of quality of life the game does just make itself easy to play.
Scott: like you can eventually Make zombies out of the dead bodies to do a lot of the work for you stuff anymore.
Scott: And like you can.
Scott: just like you can you start with a vineyard and you make grapes and then you make wine But then you can get zombie vineyard and then you can get zombie wine making right and then you just have wine.
Scott: You don't have to do anything, right?
Scott: But there's also like you can build like little container trunks right in different areas.
Scott: So let's say in your vineyard you build a trunk and in the trunk you put your grape seeds and your fertilizer Right and your trellises and whatever.
Scott: then when you go to do stuff in the grape area It basically considers all that stuff to like be in your pocket.
Scott: You don't have to like.
Scott: go get the stuff then, you know, it's just the stuff you just do it, right?
Scott: So it makes itself really convenient.
Scott: in that way.
Scott: let's let's.
Scott: if they if you actually had to manage all the stuff individually instead of just Dump all your equipment in the box and then go crafting.
Scott: I would not have gotten anywhere in this game.
Scott: I would have been like fuck this shit.
Rym: Yep That's the kind of thing like.
Rym: that's the kind of nonsense in Stardew Valley that just keeps.
Rym: I keep bouncing off of that game hard I guess never deal with it.
Scott: I never you know after I've seen it and I'm just never even gonna try it.
Scott: but Some of you do like Stardew Valley.
Scott: there are some of our listeners in our discord who have been playing it multiplayer Starting around, you know week ago.
Rym: Yeah, they're not like you could get in on this.
Scott: Yeah, it's cuz it's vacation times, right?
Scott: So I'm sure they would be happy to play with you fellow listener.
Scott: Multi-value multiplayer Stardew Valley go.
Scott: Yeah, or if there's any other game you want to get going on come to our discord.
Scott: Try to get a game going on.
Rym: So in some really brief news I want to briefly review the overwatch winter wonderland nonsense because they always do these themed events.
Rym: They'll like be special games in the arcade like the non ranked modes.
Rym: Like there's a summer games thing.
Rym: There's a winter thing There's a Halloween thing but they added some games and kind of change things up in the winter game.
Rym: and one thing I've noticed with all these sort of arcade modes is that they're making sometimes radical game design changes and Experimenting a lot in there.
Rym: and the quality of these games the reason I bring this whole thing up are Actually getting really high just in the last year.
Rym: Like they've started to find some gold with alternative modes.
Rym: and the mode in particular that if you're interested in game design I think you should look at is the freeze tag mode that they added.
Rym: Uh-huh It's a four on four versus pick a kid.
Rym: pick any characters you want like whatever and the game is just if you kill a They're frozen.
Rym: You can unfreeze someone by standing next to him and holding use for like four seconds And when one team's completely frozen you win the round.
Rym: it's best of three.
Scott: It's not just pick the deep when you just pick the DPS character to freeze people faster.
Rym: Ah, so, uh, if you win if your team wins a round all the characters You used are now banned for you for the rest of this match.
Rym: Oh We picked the four great characters.
Rym: now what now?
Rym: what fuckers?
Scott: Well, hopefully well, but oh, but if you lose you can keep using them.
Scott: Yes, so in the basically in the first battle, everyone's got the same four great character.
Scott: See, that's the other team wins don't?
Rym: because the characters are all pretty well balanced.
Scott: Like well, you might.
Scott: you might also do it like a tug-of-war where you have your anchors.
Scott: Yeah, you put them at the end.
Scott: But you point is you know, whichever team is like better.
Scott: right if a team is like, oh, you know doing better They lose their characters and then maybe that'll balance out and the other team will get some wins Similar
Rym: to how a gun game was often balanced where as you get further along you get crappier and crappier weapons
Scott: And then you get your last kill with the knife for
Rym: the grenade.
Scott: It's hard to get that last kill with the knife Like you're the best player in the universe.
Scott: all these shitty players still have m4 m4s.
Scott: Yeah, you got your knife now But you're running at it with your knife and they just hose you down over and over and over Even though even though you're way better than they are you're already on knife.
Rym: But you know so funnily enough Overwatch added a gun game mode in that arcade a while ago And it is also like fantastic.
Scott: How many guns are in overwatch?
Rym: Well, the way it works is every time you have to get a kill with every character.
Rym: No, that makes and the last character is the like entirely healing character that has like a little pistol and nothing else.
Rym: Yeah But they randomized the order of the rest of the characters along the way which leads to some interesting Bottlenecks.
Rym: like a lot of people hit the sniper and just can't get past the sniper and they sit there the whole game sniping.
Scott: Mmm Make sense.
Rym: Yeah But I just if you haven't played like if you play overwatch competitively and you haven't looked in that like casual area in a while.
Rym: There is some like really good game design in that casual arcade part of overwatch But I think a lot of people are sleeping on that.
Rym: You should not sleep on.
Rym: they're fantastic.
Scott: Well, you know, this is just sort of like an extension of what you had and say the counter-strike world Mods right and there was to be like they've like Pokemon server or some shit.
Rym: Yeah, or the world the Wow, my counter-strike was the one that always Unnerves me the most in server.
Scott: Yeah, there'd be stuff like that But this is like same thing only made by the people who made the game.
Rym: It's like if only professional modders and they're only giving you the best they think they've got.
Scott: It would be cool though if the there was also community mods somehow but also polished right and not just you know top-down.
Rym: Yeah, the trick is there's a lot of trickiness, you know, you think about like dota.
Scott: dota was community mod, right?
Scott: Oh, you can you can make.
Scott: it was unpolished as hell and it still is.
Rym: Yeah, you can make custom servers up to a point that are pretty customizable.
Rym: But yeah beyond that I don't know if I'm not interested in what the community would make just yet.
Rym: I Remember what happened to TF 2 with the mods tribes to tribes - I said TF 2 because I have a web page open with TF 2 because I was gonna talk about that in our main bed.
Rym: But anyway, it's time for things of the day.
Rym: So check this.
Rym: Mario paint was a game.
Rym: I was obsessed with getting when I was a kid because even in the SNES era I was deep in PC gaming and what always pissed me off about games like Sim City on the SNES Was that mouse didn't have a mouse?
Scott: I was just playing some a little bit at Sim City for like a minute.
Scott: I'm a Mac plus over here.
Rym: Oh, I have this weird urge to play Sim City 2000 again.
Scott: Yeah, me too.
Scott: Too bad.
Scott: It's not multiplayer.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: I don't think it would be good multiplayer.
Rym: You know, how do you play that multiplayer?
Rym: You just both play single-player and after an hour you compare your cities.
Scott: I'll be on cheetah mode in that way.
Rym: so, uh Mario paint was the Super Nintendo game that came with the Super Nintendo Mouse.
Rym: so I was fucking upset.
Rym: I remember like I was that was like top of my Christmas list of mom.
Rym: Just give me this game.
Rym: That's all I want.
Rym: is this game?
Rym: I want nothing else But the Mario paint because my kid brain thought that the mouse would work with any SNES game where that would make sense Which obviously is not true.
Rym: Not true, but Mario paint was Fantastic for its era.
Rym: like that Was a weird thing for Nintendo to put out on the Super Nintendo.
Rym: and you might think but friend get a computer.
Rym: Yeah, computers were not great at things back then.
Rym: Mario paint was actually better than a lot of the like kid drawing software you would ever have access to on a PC.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you think about it, it's like Mario Right at the time Mario paint came out, right?
Scott: What were you gonna have for drawing software on your computer?
Scott: basically MS paint Mac paint.
Scott: right that like, you know What was there?
Scott: there was like print shop deluxe.
Rym: or you want to make music unless you have pirated like cakewalk studio You got nothing.
Scott: Did that exist in 1992?
Scott: I don't know when cakewalk even came out, but you know, you'd be making music with like, you know Commodore 64 MIDI stuff right in that time, you know stuff like that.
Rym: Yeah, so I guess 92 a little bit later than that, but Mario paint basically had baby's first music making program coupled with baby's first drawing program and baby's first Animation where you could like make legit animations like this Mario paint.
Rym: There was a lot going on.
Scott: But what could you if you tried to use a computer from 1990 even 1993 like a 386?
Scott: Yeah, yeah that at 386 or like an a Mac like LC or something like that Maybe a Mac quadra that kind of if you're drawn in logo is the listener just pointed out?
Scott: Yeah, I could be like Matt.
Scott: It would be like Mac OS 7 I think 7 or 8 maybe around that time Probably 7 something it's like.
Scott: yeah, you could do some stuff But first of all those computers would cost thousands and thousands of dollars.
Rym: I can't walk.
Rym: came out for DOS in.
Scott: Okay, not bad.
Rym: Holy shit this DOS interface.
Rym: Oh my god I've never seen the cake.
Scott: Mario paint definitely was a thing where the Absolute power of it was not that high but within the constraints it provided, you know Computationally, right?
Scott: They made.
Scott: they were able to make a vastly superior user interface Within which you could still do a lot, right, you know.
Scott: and because it was easier you could you know, even though it was Computationally less powerful.
Scott: Someone who is you know a kid could do more in Mario paint than they could do and like Photoshop, right?
Scott: If you gave that same kid, you know today's Photoshop, they probably wouldn't be able to do as much with it.
Scott: You know, yeah year old right an eight-year-old could probably make better music and better animation in Mario paint than they could in.
Scott: you know after effects or Garage band or whatever.
Rym: the Mario paint also lets you save your drawings.
Rym: You could save your big drawing you could save your animation.
Scott: You could.
Scott: you ran out of save space eventually.
Rym: No, it was.
Rym: you can only save one drawing one song.
Rym: Yeah, and one and at a safe space, so it wasn't safe space.
Rym: It was whatever you had.
Rym: is what you had when you log back in.
Rym: So, uh, it only had 32 Kilobytes of save RAM and an astute person this YouTube channel bushy tail is where they are.
Rym: this person actually like Thought about this and wondered what would happen and tested it.
Rym: I don't think anyone ever like thought of this before but they basically figured out that all the pixels combined and all the like the minimum possible footprint of All the files that you could make in this game is way more than 32 kilobytes.
Rym: So the game definitely had to be doing some compression on these images which oh so you yeah yeah, so what they did is they Tried to make images and animations with as much entropy as possible to see if they could make something that Mario Paint could not save.
Rym: and they were successful in doing this and make sense.
Rym: Mario Paint actually had logic to detect and handle this and this is a video of Exactly what happens if you try to save?
Rym: Mario Paint when there is too much entropy to compress your images and the little robot Animation just gives up and says data overflow and plays a special sound and then the game crashes.
Scott: My best memory of Mario Paint, even though I did not own a Super Nintendo at the time and did not own Mario Paint.
Scott: I played it at a kid's house who had it and we and we made an animation of MC hammer, but it was only his pants dancing.
Scott: Whoo It's just it was just two legs with with big balloon pants, you know doing like, you know dancing back and forth.
Rym: I made a lot of like Mario World Levels with like Mario jumping around and picking up a Yoshi and stuff and of course fly swatting game, right?
Rym: Yep fly swatting game which existed solely to teach people how to use a mouse because Nintendo was worried that people Who bought this game had never encountered a mouse before.
Scott: it's the same thing.
Rym: Microsoft made solitaire for the same reason and the best part Of this video is there's not many comments like 400 But not many people care about this.
Rym: but at the very bottom There's a comment that says wait, that's the origin of the bot and his song.
Rym: I thought it was from Mario maker.
Scott: Okay, so also a Nintendo thing of the day, I don't know if I've used this before I don't remember it.
Scott: This is actually a video that was the videos from 91.
Scott: So around I guess before Mario Paint, right?
Scott: and The.
Scott: it was uploaded to YouTube in 2009.
Scott: So And it has millions of views But I don't remember seeing it until recently.
Scott: so there you have it.
Scott: and what this is it's a video That Nintendo of America right and people got to remember.
Scott: Nintendo of America mostly is concerned with you know Marketing and distribution.
Scott: They don't really make the games there or anything, right?
Scott: it always has been that way sales right that sort of thing.
Scott: and It was a video that Nintendo of America made in the early 90s for retailers, right because you weren't buying shit online.
Scott: you were buying all the shit at the store Toys R Us department store, right.
Scott: and It was for retailers who didn't know shit about.
Scott: you know, video games, right?
Rym: They're just selling them and back when retail would like provide services like help you pick something describe explain how something works teach you how to use the thing right.
Scott: and it was to educate retailers about technical support for Nintendo products because if somebody had a tech support problem with a Nintendo product in the early 90s and they were not Technologically inclined what the fuck were they gonna do right?
Scott: My Nintendo doesn't work.
Scott: Who are they gonna call, right?
Scott: Are?
Rym: there was a number in the back of every Nintendo game annual like?
Scott: there were no cell phones, right?
Scott: You were calling on your regular landline phones.
Scott: I'm like 800 number, right?
Rym: There was the Nintendo Line.
Scott: Yeah, there was no Google though, right that you could search for answers, right?
Scott: A lot of people were just gonna take their shit back to the store and try to return it and get a new one or Some shit like that, right?
Scott: Rather than try to figure it out.
Scott: And plus back in those days like hooking stuff up to a TV wasn't just an HDMI cable, right?
Scott: Some guys got need some like RF adapter.
Scott: Who knows what you needed back then?
Rym: Well, you needed an RF adapter unless you were the fanciest motherfucker And then you could plug RCA directly into those ports on the side of the NES.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: But yet first of all in this video you're seeing Nintendo's training with these actors pretending to be stupid customers or not always stupid customers, but you know exaggerated customers Or extremely hell or the the far too knowledgeable and too skilled retail employees.
Scott: And just you know, it's to educate retailers about what they should do how they should handle customers.
Scott: You try to bring Nintendo products in with problems and whatnot, right?
Scott: But also in this video, right you're sort of seeing this unrealistic Retail setup where like there's this wall of NES games.
Rym: That's actually literally what the store I went to looked like and I was about to say.
Scott: The only thing unrealistic about that is not that there is a wall of NES games It's only that the wall is so clean and organized.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: right when I would go to Toys R Us back in the day There was a wall of paper slips, yeah little pictures of the box as you would take the paper slip to this booth They had and that was
Rym: like bulletproof glass and there was the wall of actual games in there.
Scott: cuz in that booth was Literally Nintendo games of every Nintendo game just in stacks piled to the seat.
Rym: even worse Somehow if there were no paper slips under a game you wanted that game was sold out.
Rym: Fuck you Yep, but we always went and asked anyway like Each one of those cartridges was 50 late 80s early 90s dollars, you know ish 50 Stacked and they were stacked to the ceiling.
Scott: There was a lot of money in that booth.
Scott: That's why they didn't just leave them out.
Scott: You had to get the piece of paint, right?
Scott: I remember toys the games.
Rym: there were $30 games, but that was like Hogan's Alley.
Rym: there were $45 games was like the normal games 45 or 50 and then 60 to 70 was like hot game on release like Zelda 2 or Mario 3.
Scott: and The worst thing was that you know in those days You know nowadays shovelware is like, you know, the shovelware still exists.
Scott: it existed then.
Scott: it existed before Nintendo did see what shovelware did to the Atari and reduced it significantly By not licensing it.
Scott: but there was still a lot of bad games out there.
Rym: Yes, actually probably had more shovelware than the NES.
Scott: Maybe probably but you know shovelwares today you can tell.
Scott: and also it's a dollar, right?
Scott: It's not a big deal if you accidentally buy a shovelware and the NES if you bought a shovel where that was 50 bucks down The toilet.
Rym: Yeah, that's why our kids the smart kids went to blockbuster and rented games first That's right.
Scott: or in a later era the funko land also known as free babysitting Yes, but hey This I just want people who weren't alive then to see that, you know the pew that beautiful, you know wall that wall.
Rym: I can smell some of these images I can smell the inside of It said it still boggles my mind to like - this must be what people who like were born before Electricity felt like.
Rym: when there's electricity everywhere Like I just think back to like.
Rym: this was my literal reality and what it was like to live in that world compared to this world.
Rym: Yep In the meta moment, we're stuck at home.
Rym: Duh, not much is going on that we could talk about news wise like fuck Mitch McConnell.
Rym: Check out our code of conduct.
Rym: join the GeekNights discord.
Rym: hang out in our live streams.
Rym: There's cool people hanging out in there every show Forum.
Rym: Yeah, our forums good our discords good.
Scott: at Twitter's you can email us I guess if you wanna.
Rym: Yeah, we're hanging out online playing games with people.
Rym: I Follow us individually.
Scott: or you can follow GeekNights itself and all the places that you can follow people on the internet.
Rym: Yeah, we got stuff everywhere.
Rym: We're working on some projects.
Rym: Some are big some are small some you'll see early in the new year Some you may never see hence.
Rym: We're not talking about.
Rym: We don't really have any cons coming up, I guess there's that virtual mag fest But I still don't know what the deal is.
Scott: They haven't really posted but I don't know what the deal is with that either.
Scott: We got no info.
Rym: Yeah There's.
Rym: there's some other online cons That'll probably be happening next year that we're talking to.
Rym: but if there is an online con That you want us to appear at in some fashion and that con is not a pain in the ass to work with Tell them about us or tell us about them and we'll see what happens.
Scott: Yeah Oh the book club book is still the tale of Genji.
Rym: I have not lit the Genji signal.
Scott: the Genji signal has not the the the The gondor whatever that.
Rym: well cuz I'm not I have not lit the beacons cuz I'm.
Scott: that's right.
Rym: the beacon the beacon of Gondor Remains because I've got my hot ass and I'm playing Star Wars.
Rym: So I'm gonna keep playing Star Wars instead of reading the tale of Genji for the time being.
Scott: Yeah, I told Rym like I'm like I'm in the book.
Scott: No, actually, I'm just watching LuPone movie.
Scott: Do you watch the LuPone movie?
Rym: Not yet, but I will before our next Wednesday show.
Scott: All right Well, it's gonna be next year.
Rym: Yeah, it will be next year.
Rym: All right, let's get right into it cuz all these show the rest of the year.
Rym: these end of you end of decade shows have Been going along.
Rym: We've already gone long.
Rym: So let's uh, we'll go long again.
Scott: alright, this is Ben.
Rym: I will just say that in terms of gaming all kinds of gaming the 2010s have been like an Amazing decade the best decade in human history.
Rym: It is hard to express to you out there especially if you were younger than us how Fucking amazing this decade has been for gaming.
Rym: This is a gaming a decade where the Wii U came and went where the 3ds came and went Counter-strike go appeared.
Rym: Yeah PC gaming the renaissance of PC gaming began at the very beginning of this decade and Turned into a PC gaming like Platinum Age.
Rym: This is the greatest PC gaming era in human history hitherto.
Rym: Mmm the true the Nintendo switch like changed the paradigm of what a console is.
Rym: the Wii U try several It's already several years old.
Rym: It doesn't even feel like it but it's old Like I was trying to think back like what happened in the 2010s in gaming and everything.
Rym: We could make a geeked-out podcast for a year That was just talking about the 2010s of gaming and we would not have come did it for 10 years.
Rym: We did do it for 10 years.
Scott: You could just listen to all these episodes.
Rym: We could have done more episodes in these 10 years.
Scott: The point is is that at the in 20 2009 2010?
Scott: What did gaming look like, you know?
Scott: It looked like then?
Scott: I'm pretty sure it was Xbox 360 Right.
Scott: Yeah, was it regular DS not 3ds, right?
Scott: Yes to not come out yet I don't think 3ds was quite.
Rym: I was looking at 2010 in video games.
Rym: Look at me look at the website.
Rym: Mm.
Rym: the Wii was out.
Scott: the Wii was a thing because the Wii was late 2000.
Scott: So the Wii was stills at its and its strength.
Rym: the Wii was strong But it was in its long decline.
Rym: like everyone knew Nintendo had something coming Right.
Scott: the the Wii was there.
Scott: the regular DS was there.
Rym: the the ps3 Slim came out at the end of the previous decade 2009.
Rym: Yeah, right ps3 Xbox 360, right?
Scott: And at this time, you know forget all the things that have happened between then and now.
Scott: right at that moment It was actually like sort of just.
Scott: it wasn't exactly the beginning But like it was still the early times of just indie video games period right.
Scott: the Xbox Was like the before that.
Scott: obviously the indie games have always existed right.
Scott: there have been games from non major publishers But that Xbox indie marketplace that is gone exactly.
Scott: That was not a thing and PC games were hard to run and weird team didn't have seem just didn't let anyone Fucking put their games on Steam.
Scott: right, you know, it wasn't like there wasn't this?
Scott: the itch I/O didn't exist That's for sure.
Scott: It's not that I'm aware of a lot of indie games.
Rym: I played in the 2000s.
Rym: the knots were like here's an exe file from the internet.
Scott: Right exactly if you in deep video games where someone made a game and they're selling it on their own.
Scott: Right that Xbox marketplace was like the first time That you could in a like on a major platform.
Scott: Pretty much anyone could get their game up there and get it for a sale.
Scott: and we were seeing the games You know coming out like, you know, I guess the early ones like the braid.
Rym: braid was right at the end of 2009.
Scott: right You see like your Monaco right we saw that it packs a whole bunch.
Rym: We saw that it packs many many many times.
Rym: I still have those diamonds Right.
Scott: Oh, yeah, right.
Scott: Yeah You know, I guess what else was coming out around then.
Scott: but like it was still like these early days where people starting to be Like hey, I made a video game all on my own.
Scott: What was?
Scott: it was half-minute hero was one of those.
Rym: Oh, yeah, that game was Phenomenal right.
Scott: It was like people just made a game out of nowhere on their own.
Scott: Yeah, and because they were had this plat is store to sell it on.
Scott: it's like oh Well, you can actually sort of like make money making a game on your own if you're lucky and it becomes a huge hit.
Scott: Most of them won't but that became a thing and for the rest of the decade we are now in a place where?
Scott: Especially thanks to steam the Xbox one died.
Scott: but like on switch you get shit.
Scott: Nowadays, like fucking kit, you know.
Scott: cadence of fire.
Scott: Oh, yeah I krypto.
Scott: the necro dancer wasn't a thing in 2010 and now cadence of Hyrule and 20 in 2020. is that you know?
Rym: I'm gonna say, you know what happened in the 2010s this decade.
Rym: it destroyed the concept of game genres like.
Rym: it's the concept still there but We there were so many genre breakers and new genres that formed that.
Rym: I still is the Concept of genres that are really strong But there are there's a lot more of them and there's a lot more games that are described as it's this genre and this genre mixed.
Rym: yes Before that, right?
Scott: We have also seen several genres Die or wane, right?
Scott: So the biggest the biggest death has been the MMORPG at least the classical kind.
Rym: I think the grindy kind is right.
Scott: the Final Fantasy 1. and what's that other one?
Scott: people are playing the Chinese one?
Rym: That Doesn't narrow it down It's that one.
Scott: That's like a big hit.
Scott: the action II won I forget.
Scott: Regardless, you know, it's like the the World of Warcraft style MMO.
Scott: Like is it 100% dead?
Scott: No, of course not.
Scott: They still there but it's like in 2010.
Scott: Like it was like there was a Lord of the Rings MMO.
Scott: It was like so many MMOs, you know, the Elder Scrolls one.
Scott: is that one still exist?
Rym: Contact?
Scott: were there two Star Wars ones?
Scott: I don't even know.
Rym: the end of the previous decade I my primary PC was Linux on the desktop and I was playing like Wii games And I was mostly tabletop and PC games DS games.
Rym: PC gaming was not in a great shape because Team Fortress 2 had come and was not good.
Rym: Like Left 4 Dead 2 was one of the last hurrahs of the end of that decade.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you look at our 20 are our video game episodes from 2010 a lot of them were about old games.
Scott: The only major PC game I see is like Civ 5.
Rym: Yeah But then as you scroll through more episodes, we did like.
Scott: we're talking about a lot of interesting games Right, you know 2011 this half-minute hero Rock of Ages.
Scott: That was another early indie game, right?
Scott: You know Super Meat Boy another one.
Scott: that was 2011 right up.
Scott: and now finally Super Meat Boy forever comes out.
Scott: now He just came out.
Rym: So another big.
Rym: before we do I want to jump around to a lot of different places before we go deep into anything.
Rym: another big change tabletop Exploded in multiple ways like D&D over this decade coalesced into fifth edition, which for all its problems It's probably the best D&D.
Scott: Yeah, I mean D&D itself had a lot of ups and downs.
Rym: fourth edition was just a nightmare.
Scott: Yeah, what we've seen I think as a whole is the emergence of the watch people play an RPG Usually D&D not always though online which led to this Interested in playing the games that didn't exist at all in 2010, even though it could have.
Rym: yeah It should have.
Scott: we're stupid fine sight But now it totally exists in is huge.
Rym: There are several people to do it But look at the beginning of 2010 we have Luke and Jared on the show like in July.
Rym: We have them on multiple times.
Rym: talking about indie RPGs We start like we were really diving in indie RPGs.
Rym: the indie RPG scene has really come into its own in this past decade.
Rym: There are so many top tier indie RPGs out there.
Scott: Yep, I think it still hasn't managed to Like chip away at these sort of like.
Rym: no, you know what I think happened.
Rym: the whole space expanded because the space had contracted for A long time.
Rym: I think RPGs table top RPGs expanded overall.
Rym: So D&D grew a lot but indie RPGs also grew a lot relative to where they were.
Scott: Right, but I think in terms of percentage of the pie I don't like D&D is still in.
Rym: the RPGs are a smaller percentage of the pie But a larger absolute number.
Rym: more people are making enough money doing indie RPGs to make indie RPGs.
Rym: Yes, indeed It's still not a like healthy ecosystem, but it's growing rapidly and it's growing in absolute numbers Even if D&D is still the black monolithic elephant with With a flurry of blows in the room, right?
Scott: And the other thing I think that the story of regular tabletop in the 2010s I think is absolutely got to be like very heavily tied to the story of the Kickstarter board game the Kickstarter.
Rym: like it the Kickstarter caused a renaissance of like Unknown designers and indie games coming out, but it also caused a glut of shovelware relative to other products.
Scott: project types.
Scott: board games are like one of the biggest on Kickstarter.
Scott: like this Disproportionate money for board gaming projects to like movie funding projects, right?
Scott: Even though they're both valid uses of Kickstarter And we saw early in the decade.
Scott: What do I see here?
Scott: on GeekNights, right like Eminent domain and like some other, you know games that were like some of the early Kickstarter games, right?
Scott: Yeah now it's like friggin.
Scott: every board game is some sort of Kickstarter thing.
Scott: You know, they're all you know, the whole industry is about making you know giant game with a bunch of extras in it and all kinds of Course.
Rym: the decade that bubble grew and kind of burst right is definitely I think is is definitely deflating now.
Rym: Finally, I at least I hope it is it seems to be but what's rising now is the like the industry.
Rym: god There's a lot of shovelware.
Rym: There's a lot of the last one year.
Scott: It's playing games online and digitally instead Which already it's always existed.
Scott: But it was never like good enough and you wouldn't do it because you could just play games in person, right?
Scott: but now it's getting better and also the pressure of not being able to play games in person is actually Finally pushed that up.
Rym: But the other thing I've seen accelerate massively in this past decade was People who are more casual and more mainstream tabletop gamers playing the kinds of games that in the previous decade They would never encounter in their lives Like root.
Rym: absolute is that there's a lot of games that are a good example But roots probably most well-known one root got a lot of people to try Grognard wargame mechanics without realizing it and definitely feel like at the start of the decade.
Scott: It was like, okay, you know Settlers has managed to get its way into the hands of a lot of people right Catan.
Scott: Yeah carcass Kind of well-known Right, but we're out here.
Scott: We're playing, you know, right?
Scott: I don't know fucking.
Scott: what was out then.
Rym: Let me look like how to be came out in 2010.
Rym: I Remember we gave fucking talks at PAX.
Rym: is we were like check this shit out Like we talked about how to be like.
Rym: no one had ever made a game like that before because there weren't really games like you A show on Hanabi.
Scott: I think it was later than that.
Rym: It came out in 2010.
Rym: We didn't do show on it right away.
Scott: We did it in 2013.
Rym: seven wonders came out in 2010 Right.
Scott: It's like we were in the seven wonders zone when everyone else is in the Catan zone, right?
Scott: That's like Tudor own horn here.
Scott: It's just because we've been playing settler since 2000 just due to luck and circumstance.
Scott: Yeah and privilege obviously but the So we're just ahead of people.
Scott: but now I feel like the mass board gaming, you know gaming world has Absolutely caught up.
Scott: It's like, you know, you're Azul's your roots, right?
Scott: You're a pandemic.
Rym: they move like they were like carcass settlers was Barely expanded or extended market like not mass market, but not core niche market anymore.
Rym: by the end of the day Those games are all like expanded market and settlers as mass market.
Scott: Yeah, you go to Target now and it's like the games are there right there.
Scott: They are just in the store the real, you know, the real games.
Scott: and in the store all the normal people go Right, not the nerdy people.
Scott: Yeah, there are still obviously even nerdier games that are the kinds that we're playing.
Rym: Well, look at us.
Rym: We're always pushing deeper and further away from the masses.
Scott: That's why we're playing train games, obviously But it's like when tickets a ride came out and we were playing it like a whole bunch in College that game would blow people's minds.
Scott: when we brought it to the table We played tickets a ride in college a whole bunch.
Scott: And it's like ticket to ride is not only not completely dead it's still around.
Scott: and now I think ticket to ride is just like on the shelf in the toy store if there is toys rest is gone, but Any store that it still exists.
Scott: It's like tickets a ride is just like, you know Probably out there just like whatever if all the families are buying it who aren't even you
Rym: know I would say the tabletop gaming ecosystem and industry Evolved Modernized and became mature over the course of this decade in a way that had never been before.
Rym: but that meant some casualties.
Rym: There were big consolidations.
Rym: a lot of publishers went under.
Rym: there was not like that.
Rym: The whole industry has consolidated.
Rym: There aren't that many publishers?
Scott: no, not too many and we're losing.
Scott: we're losing more Hasbro just gobbling everything up just like the tabletop RPGs.
Rym: This wasn't like oh the indie games ate away at the mass market like the book that the long-running games.
Rym: it was that the entire space got bigger like Magic.
Rym: the Gathering kept trucking along bigger than ever and it's just still going.
Rym: and Magic did not lose people to all these other games.
Rym: There's just more people playing tabletop games everywhere.
Rym: Yep, so the the convention scene changed a lot.
Rym: like packs went from the big thing in Seattle to like the Industry-dominating event over the course of that decade packs.
Rym: The first PAX East was in 2010.
Scott: Yep, we did like five really been the decade of packs, right?
Scott: It's like that's barely was like we went.
Scott: our first packs isn't like oh, oh, eight eight.
Scott: Oh nine.
Scott: We went away.
Rym: No nine and then pack.
Rym: We're doing a PAX East.
Rym: Will you come and do panels?
Scott: Packs wasn't mega until like 2013 2014.
Scott: Yeah, it was.
Scott: wasn't even selling out.
Scott: Yeah, exactly It wasn't.
Scott: until a few years in and that so this has been the decade of packs.
Scott: Well, so PAX Unplugged came into existence.
Scott: South and East came into it and Australia.
Rym: every packs That's not PAX West came into existence Exactly.
Scott: They did not exist in the previous decade.
Scott: They just weren't there.
Rym: and you can see in our personal lives Right at the end of the decade We hard pivoted away from all the cons that were in gaming cons and went to a lot of gaming cons mostly packses But also magfest.
Scott: Yep See what else was like the huge thing going on in this decade, right?
Rym: I mean I can talk about.
Rym: you can go deep into a bunch of areas.
Scott: I'm just but yeah, obviously so I mean personally right.
Scott: so my personal pattern of gaming right is in the early part of the decade.
Scott: What was I doing?
Scott: You know, I was playing mostly.
Scott: I would get games for my Wii or DS Yeah, you know.
Scott: and I beat them or not play them all forget they existed somehow Like the other day I was watching I think was a few maybe months ago Actually, I was watching someone speedrun Wario where for the Wii and that Wario where just Wario shake it for the Wii I think and I was like, I feel like I've seen this game.
Scott: I don't I don't remember it.
Scott: It's like it but I seen it and it's like I had it for the Wii.
Scott: I think I played it and beat it and then whenever played it again, right?
Rym: But like at the end of the previous decade table-top wise I like it was only playing old retro games and tabletop games.
Scott: I wasn't playing a lot of video games and right Wasn't playing a lot of video games early in the 2010s at all.
Scott: I was just you know, I'd play these mega games like, you know, Mario Galaxy, whatever.
Scott: when it came out I beat it and be done with it and now Occasionally Civ V came out.
Scott: I played my DS before I went to bed.
Scott: stuff like that.
Rym: Yeah, but as the decade went on what really the thing that my personal journey of gaming the strongest one is that the multi-class Competitive team-based FPS which had been dead.
Scott: one of them Dead Team Fortress 2 genre.
Scott: there was one game that you played.
Rym: There were a lot of.
Rym: there were multiple games in that genre But they were all variants on a theme and it was just kind of dead.
Rym: Team Fortress 2 came out.
Scott: What other?
Scott: Team Fortress 2 came out last decade.
Rym: Yeah He came out and wasn't great and then and and even then those games were only popular among like people who are obsessed with that Specific narrow area of gaming like that was not common for people to play those games.
Scott: TF 2 is for people very guy was really popular and people were playing it with the hats.
Rym: Yeah When TF 2 came out it was like the audience that played.
Rym: TF 2 was not the audience to play those older games.
Rym: Overwatch brought back a type of game that had been pretty much dead and Even in its heyday was not widely played and made it mass-market.
Rym: Mmm, this was the decade.
Rym: the second half of this decade was the decade of actually finally stealing from the Forgotten Masters.
Rym: This was the decade where all the forgotten genres and forgotten games someone with money said I'm gonna pay some people to make a game that does this thing because there aren't any.
Rym: if we just make it someone will play It no one will compete with us.
Rym: and we see that across like all gaming Mm-hmm dead genres was revived.
Scott: Yeah, we didn't get the Pokemon MMO, but we got Pokemon go.
Scott: Pokemon itself does have more multiplayer internet stuff now than it ever has.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah in the past Even though it's not the full MMO that you would imagine right in like this perfect cyber world.
Rym: I still imagine that that's the only unrealized potential.
Scott: that is egregious, but the You know, so I started out, you know, just playing some Nintendo games, right?
Scott: I guess is playing some of those indie games in the Xbox that I had for a while.
Scott: They got rid of.
Scott: right and tabletop wise it's like in 2010 early 2010s We were going to like, you know tabletop game night and playing, you know, a Puerto Rico with some people.
Rym: We just I mean nerd NYC was a thing kind of that.
Rym: those events all kind of died over the course of the 2010s Right.
Scott: We were doing those, you know, sort of smaller time board game meetup things And I saw that trend kind of.
Rym: generally though like smaller board game need meetups declined as the decade went on For a lot of what happened.
Scott: to me personally the reason I abandoned them it was because I spent Four to five years playing netrunner.
Rym: you did you went deep in the netrunner just like I would Right.
Scott: So netrunner was a was a huge game.
Scott: Can I think 2013 is when it started?
Scott: I want to say I'm guessing I feel like 2013 through slate 17 and I've sort of waned off towards.
Rym: I remember you'd go to a netrunner meetup and I would go to nerd NYC and play like German games.
Scott: Well, well cuz netrunner was just a great game that I discovered but also there was activity around it right enough of it.
Scott: and also You know it was like hey instead of going to a board game meetup where I'll play who knows what game and I'll play one game all Night with some drunken people.
Scott: I don't know I can play this game which keeps changing.
Scott: It is really dynamic interesting and deep with people that all know the rules and I'll own the game and I'll really want to play It a lot right and are on a weekly.
Scott: some you know, there was at the peak.
Scott: We were having like a you know tournaments ever like.
Scott: it was big.
Scott: there were two tournaments a month and shit going down.
Scott: It was like very active and then it sort of you know tapered off over time.
Scott: But yeah that occupied a lot of my time.
Scott: that one game and now okay.
Scott: I don't need to go back to that.
Rym: I'm good That isn't that decade cuz by two like in in my younger days there would be like one game usually a competitive game.
Rym: That would dominate all my multiplayer play and I'd like focus on that game and play a lot of single-player games.
Rym: That came back for both of us in the past decade because I like went crazy for overwatch.
Rym: I still kind of play overwatch like every day To the exclusion of a lot of other online games.
Rym: But at the beginning of the decade I did that too because counter-strike go came out at the beginning of the decade.
Rym: Bringing back counter-strike and making it like honestly counter-strike go is probably the second best counter-strike.
Scott: Probably I think one six Pokemon go came into existence.
Scott: I think I mentioned that are.
Rym: yeah Ingress came and went in that time, too.
Rym: I found our review of it.
Rym: We're basically what I my exact words were don't play it.
Rym: It's a candy box sure.
Scott: We saw a lot of All the jackboxes.
Scott: that's all 2010s.
Scott: right that there was.
Scott: I mean there was the original you don't know jack in the 90s Right, but 2010s jackbox, right?
Scott: Yeah, it's a totally different new Revolutionary thing.
Scott: that's been.
Rym: they figured out how to make web sockets kind of just work and no one seems to have mastered this Except them, right?
Scott: obviously 2010s phone games right there are phones in late 2000s But smartphones weren't like I said in a tech episode were not huge.
Rym: I think the 3ds was the last Like super small portable console because phones completely displaced that entire market.
Scott: smartphone adoption It was the thing of the 2010s.
Scott: and thus games on the smartphones.
Scott: The Candy Crush might be the game of the decade.
Scott: honestly, right.
Scott: if you think about it, I don't you know, it's close All right.
Scott: What else would even be close on the on the list in terms of like.
Scott: you have to pick one game to represent the whole?
Scott: Decade for the population of humanity That's like.
Scott: that might be it.
Rym: Yep, but that like the 3ds I think was the last small console that normal people would play.
Rym: and the 3ds Had its ups and downs in this decade like the local Nintendo's bad at that.
Scott: Yep, it was still huge though.
Rym: It was huge.
Rym: The 3d thing obviously didn't matter, but the console itself was fine.
Rym: But now look what happened.
Rym: We've seen this the the industry is segmented into.
Rym: There's basically two consoles that are just gaming PCs That compete with each other pretty much with time limited exclusives that will usually be on Steam.
Rym: eventually There's PC gaming Which is continuing to grow in a big way Like.
Rym: I'm so happy the PC gaming is so big again for a lot of reasons that we've talked about Over the entire decade.
Rym: and then there's Nintendo.
Rym: Nintendo is doing its own thing and the switch is like this perfect marriage of form and function That I think Nintendo found their niche and I doubt they will do anything that does not switch like any time in the foreseeable future.
Scott: Well Nintendo saw you know, the Wii U go poop and they're like, hey, we need to make something right that in an era right where Someone can buy a computer and someone has a phone.
Scott: Yeah, right if someone has We think that a person someone has a computer and a phone we need to make a device that they will buy in addition to those two things.
Scott: And And so they do it right and I think Nintendo's obvious real advantage There is sort of you know, like it just.
Scott: not only is the switch hardware, you know So unique in providing, you know features that and experiences you couldn't get on normal hardware right more commodity hardware.
Scott: It's that they still have their Mario's their Zelda's and all those games.
Scott: Yeah, it's 100% exclusive to their platform You know, so.
Rym: But the other thing they did is With breath of the wild they like broke the concept of what an open-world game could be for everyone who's ever made one up to that point.
Rym: Other notable big things from the decades Sports went from only nerds care to more watch than the Super Bowl.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: Like that is that people aren't like people.
Rym: I don't think realize.
Rym: younger kids already do not seem to realize that Esports didn't fucking exist in the previous decade in any meaningful way.
Scott: No, not in a meaningful way, right?
Scott: There's like what fatality is quick.
Rym: Yeah, like fatality That's one of the only eSports people people could name from that era and even a quick people do a Starcraft.
Scott: Yeah, it was Starcraft and quake and that was pretty much it.
Scott: Yeah now it's everything.
Scott: See I think other notable things right.
Scott: so obviously most recently we've had trained games because of one website But that's just I think a larger in our eyes because we're deep into that and grander scheme.
Scott: It's not actually that big but it is.
Scott: it's it's grown proportion to its previous.
Rym: We've seen Digital implementations of board games become good when previously they were often shitty and Become kind of the most common way.
Rym: Someone will learn to play a popular board game as they'll play it on an app first on their phone or tablet Learn the rules and then move on to playing it with people like.
Rym: that's a thing.
Rym: That wasn't a thing before.
Scott: We've seen the roguelike become a bigger deal in the 2010s, right?
Scott: So many wrote, you know roguelike you should just be net hack.
Scott: Yeah now it's everything but that's it.
Rym: That's another.
Rym: it's like rogue like the cons.
Rym: the things that made rogue interesting mashed into some other genre in some Escape rooms are a big thing.
Scott: if you consider those to be a game.
Scott: Yeah Then many escape rooms like are still a thing now Right, like they've actually been able to sort of hold on to their power in whatever form they take tabletop digital or physical.
Scott: They're all the same sort of same sort of, you know.
Rym: I think that's part of a broader trend where we're in the era where people who are around our age Who actually started going out and making games and founding studios and like doing this stuff?
Rym: So the people who grew up wanting more games and had access to games and were deep into that games Like we have this like second generation of people making those games now.
Scott: Yep, the roll and write game became a thing.
Scott: It's I think it's sort of faded a little bit But there are some recent entry.
Rym: Well, it kind of really turned into a bubble where there were like ten of them published in one like one month I remember like yeah There was it.
Scott: there was an.
Rym: I mean Yahtzee was a rollin right.
Rym: Yahtzee's been around for a while.
Rym: The rollin rights were not played by people who weren't playing old weird games like Yahtzee with their families until this decade.
Scott: right Phenomenon wise goose game was just huge.
Scott: right.
Scott: talking about the indie games, right?
Scott: Starting with the braids we went from braid to goose game, right?
Scott: So You know because I was when I started talking about the indie game, you know revolution of the 2010 So I was mostly thinking about where he came from, but it's like yeah, we got to goose game.
Scott: That's where we are now where something like that is now just known by everybody.
Scott: Everyone knows this game.
Scott: Everyone played that.
Scott: is there anyone who didn't play it?
Scott: No one.
Scott: listen to the show.
Scott: I doubt it.
Rym: I think we though did see the rise and then fall Like kind of hard fall of a lot of rhythm games like rhythm games had a lot of trouble.
Rym: this decade DDR kind of disappeared from non like crazy.
Scott: Rhythm games have bounced back to a more like, you know, but they're more like tablet tapping type rhythm games.
Scott: No, well some of them are but it's like.
Scott: DDR itself has like sort of you know Come off the ground and written gone to a plateau, right?
Scott: You can get that.
Scott: there is that there is the main current DDR machine.
Rym: it exists, right but there aren't our where.
Scott: No, well, there are some but it's it's not where it was in the 2000s where?
Scott: You could get everyone had plastic instruments, right?
Rym: Yeah Like in the very beginning the decade like decade like Rock Band 3 was like the hottest game get dance pads at the store Just normally, right?
Scott: It's like that stuff was all 2000s 2010s.
Scott: everyone threw out their plastic instruments shit and only hardcore people had like.
Rym: people like it like DDR Enthusiasts have special DDR pads.
Rym: No one else plays DDR It has.
Scott: the genre is sort of stable at this like level, right?
Scott: It's probably equal to like the train game situation.
Scott: Yeah, right We're only only.
Scott: the train games are going up from where they are and the rhythm games are going down from where they were.
Scott: But they're.
Rym: you know, it's a niche thing that's holding steady and there has a community and it's there though there are a small number of Rhythm game crossed with something else getting back into that genre mixing stuff like pistol whip is a rhythm rail shooter Mmm.
Scott: Oh speaking of which right?
Scott: It's like yeah, you're you know, wow I'm not a big fan of VR and I was gonna bring this up last.
Rym: Yeah has not reached the art level but VR is like legit expanded market gaming.
Scott: now Yeah, VR is you know, pretty much like yeah people talk it used to be just like oh There's like VR.
Scott: you can buy VR for a zillion dollars in this one game And now it's sort of like alright if you got a pile of money you can play Star Wars in VR.
Scott: Yeah, there's a whole bunch of VR games.
Scott: Star Wars was I think the side
Rym: Between Star Wars and the quest to because the quest in the quest to where you can do VR without a gaming PC and Without a bunch of nerd shit like putting the sensors on the walls It'll just work and they're really popular.
Rym: like this VR is more accessible than high-end PC gaming right now.
Rym: Probably Oculus Quest 2 cost way less than a low-end gaming PC.
Rym: Sure, but my VR is sort of like I have a valve index that is for nerds.
Rym: But Star Wars was probably the first game that was a like expanded market like edging into but not quite mass-market.
Rym: like this game was launched and They just said you know what it works with VR.
Rym: if you have VR any VR headset, it just works.
Rym: We designed it for that, but you don't need it.
Rym: Hmm and that is a big side.
Rym: the next decade I think we're gonna see VR by the end of next decade.
Rym: VR will be mass-market.
Scott: if the world is not It depends right if it remains an expensive thing that is a big fat thing you got to put on your head and But it's already not you could like.
Rym: the quest is cheap and doesn't need a gaming PC.
Rym: It costs less than some gaming consoles.
Scott: How much does it cost?
Rym: let me see the quest one is real cheap.
Scott: It's cost more than a ps5.
Rym: probably less than a ps5.
Rym: Quest 2 is 300 bucks.
Rym: It's way less than a ps5.
Scott: No, that's not too bad, but it's still quite a bit to spend for something with so few games.
Rym: I think that much more than a switch, and there's a.
Scott: But how many games does a switch have right versus how many games the VR games are there?
Rym: Yeah, that's why I'm saying by the end of this coming decade well It depends right.
Scott: so I'm saying if it VR in order for VR to sort of you know It's got upwards momentum for sure right where it.
Scott: you know before it was just like a nothing like people were really Stretching reaching for it right it's like this could be for this could be virtual boy.
Scott: You're buying here with your money, right?
Rym: Now it kind of just works.
Scott: It's not virtual boy - it's definitely reached like I think maybe PSP territory right where it's like It's gonna have a lot of games.
Scott: It's not gonna.
Scott: Just die right.
Scott: It's like it's useful.
Rym: well But even more the studios are all like currently researching to break their big games in the coming decade.
Scott: Yeah, but unlike the PSP there is platform enthusiasm for VR.
Scott: right software developers working on it and such right You know pretty much across the board except for Nintendo.
Scott: right pretty much play.
Scott: You know everyone's into VR, right?
Scott: Yeah, I'm trying to make things for it But I think unless it really it needs like another big bump or two in terms of price down tons of more games
Rym: which is
Scott: What
Rym: what is lacking at the end of this decade is a large enough ecosystem of studios that have mastered the craft of making VR games and mastered the UX and like like the How the game
Scott: works?
Scott: It could.
Scott: but the point is if it doesn't get you know one or two boosts it could be could still go down.
Rym: Right those boosts are dead.
Rym: that R&D is already there.
Rym: those games are already in flight.
Scott: I don't feel like the end of 2030. we could either be saying like VR almost made it.
Scott: No, it didn't make it.
Scott: They got to try again a third time.
Rym: Start displacing some other games by the end of this coming decade.
Scott: Not too confident about that.
Rym: I am very confident.
Scott: go either way.
Scott: Yes, you know you bought a VR.
Scott: That's why you're confident.
Scott: Person who buys the wine rights likes it no matter what it tastes like.
Rym: Now the question is selling like crazy to normal people in fact like crazy.
Scott: How many is it selling?
Rym: well?
Rym: More than we use.
Scott: how many sell?
Scott: more than we use?
Rym: I definitely sold more than we use because the Wii U did sell more than we use.
Scott: how many did it sell?
Rym: It's still selling.
Rym: We don't have the holiday numbers yet.
Scott: Yeah, how many we use sold?
Rym: Why we both saw that chart on we use 101 million.
Scott: We you know that was wheeze.
Rym: Yeah, I was about to say I was gonna say I was like.
Scott: that's not The we use.
Rym: so quest 2 appears to be approaching 10 mil.
Scott: Oh, that's we you games.
Scott: I saw this recently.
Scott: how many we use were sold.
Scott: It was like it was some millions, right?
Scott: Total we sold.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: yeah millions.
Rym: The question was here is to have sold to millet around launch and is tracking to hit 10 mil like oh Yeah, any man.
Scott: so the number of we use sold by the end.
Scott: It was like 5 million.
Rym: All right, so the projected quest 2 numbers by next by sometime next year is double that 10 million we used.
Rym: that's that's the best number I can find.
Rym: they sold out 2 million at launch And then they ran.
Rym: it couldn't make more.
Rym: like they were sold out.
Rym: people couldn't get him right.
Scott: well The Wii U was a failure, so it has to do Million more in next year, that's a that's a better.
Rym: That'll match.
Scott: so that so 2 million.
Rym: it launched 3 million next year In the first in the first year.
Scott: basically All right, so it's not a complete bomb like the Wii U. But you need a lot more than that to be like a smash right here.
Rym: It's not a smash.
Scott: Yeah, it's definitely like nice to attend when it's and it's a will it be tens of millions, right?
Scott: You know they need to make some development that will get that number to the tens of millions and not just the ones.
Rym: I think that is one more Iteration of the hardware that does not require a gaming PC being better because if you have a gaming PC VR is already there.
Rym: But that's not what most people are gonna interact with.
Rym: they're gonna react with these Standalone systems that just work without having to do any gamer nerd nonsense.
Rym: There is some evidence Whereas I'm poking around that The those non PC tethered VR kits are selling to people who don't otherwise have gaming systems.
Scott: It makes sense.
Scott: why would you if you have a gaming system?
Scott: Why would you buy?
Scott: right?
Scott: if you have a gaming system you also want to get your use out of it, right?
Scott: Yeah, why would you?
Rym: So but I think it's.
Rym: it's.
Rym: it's one more iteration of the inside-out tracking hardware for non PC gamer enthusiasts coupled with like two studios Releasing multiple games over the next several years like real games like full-on games.
Rym: We need like five more games.
Rym: They're on a level of half-life Alex.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Rym: So, yeah, that was there anything else big time that happened in the 2010s, I think it's pretty much story is that gaming has become Hugely important to culture and society and as an industry has grown massively.
Rym: There's more players.
Rym: There's more makers.
Rym: the one bad thing But this is not new the same thing was happening in the previous decade.
Rym: The industry is unsustainable in terms of like crunch and working practices and capital Right.
Scott: Also your your gamer gate was in the 2010s.
Rym: That was a gamer harassment like exploded.
Rym: But that's more.
Rym: we'll talk about that more on Thursday I think.
Rym: well that is all in the a brigade was not the thing.
Rym: that was just the like trial run for what really happened.
Scott: Sure, but I think what has happened is on the one hand right the both the the bad.
Scott: You know people in this world right got stronger and you know went to war right and but also You can view it in the other way and that aha the good people weren't just sitting around taking it anymore You know just letting letting the status quo maintain.
Rym: like.
Rym: look at.
Rym: look at how Blizzard has handled harassment issues in their games in this decade Compared to how any fucking company handled that in the previous decade.
Rym: They went.
Rym: the companies are increasingly doing as much of the right thing as they can with like banning first and asking questions later taking reports seriously building reporting and Accountability systems into their games.
Scott: It's not fully developed yet if I could think make an analogy, right?
Scott: Basically, there's been this like wasp hive on the porch.
Scott: It's just been there, right?
Scott: It's just been sitting there this whole time and every time you leave your house you know you watch out for the wasps and that was the what was in.
Scott: that was the saddest quo of the 2000s.
Scott: was you just watching out for the wasps?
Scott: and the 2010s we both tried to get rid of the wasps Actively, right?
Scott: We didn't six necessary succeed completely, right?
Scott: But we did get.
Scott: we got a lot of them, but we also got stung by a lot of wasps.
Scott: Yep Right, and that was the 2010s.
Scott: So Hopefully, I'm hope 2020s.
Scott: We want to see a world where you can walk out on your porch.
Scott: No wasps That's what we're that's our gaming for.
Rym: but I think the sad part is I think that is way beyond gaming.
Rym: I think the gay the gamer culture was just sort of a head like that.
Scott: But the games right gaming the gaming community was a particular nexus.
Scott: that other Community, you know, you know the anime community had its own, you know, but they was much smaller.
Rym: I think part of the difference is the gaming community where this stuff really like germinated was hypersocial online a little bit ahead of Social media.
Rym: Yep, like gamers were harassing each other and gamer hate stuff was happening in social media when gaming was still over represented compared to other things in social media.
Scott: No, all that stuff was 2010s though.
Scott: Yeah thousands.
Scott: Not so much Yep 2000s.
Rym: like harassment was like an Individual person would bother you in a specific game and you couldn't even
Scott: go play counter-strike and people would say racial slurs Yeah,
Rym: and you
Scott: just have
Rym: them and kick them off your servers,
Scott: but they could just tell
Rym: you in real life
Scott: It was just how it was.
Scott: That was just life in the 2000s.
Rym: Yeah I would like play counter-strike on servers that had passwords where people were vetted.
Rym: Yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this end of decade episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, I'm a nickel.
Rym: Martin Grenier link eg a fresh dot net slash tilde Rym slash podcast - beta.
Rym: Graham Finch you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: now go through the last year or so of podcasts and make Rym sing.
Rym: Clinton Walton written from New Zealand.
Rym: Ryan Perrin review mad bull 34 cowards Dread Lily Tenebrae just like a dude guy.
Rym: Chris Reimer Finn Shervin Von Harl and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: we got one more show To do before the end of the year.
Rym: will we do it?
Rym: Because if we do it, we're doing it on New Year's Eve.
Rym: I think we've ever recorded a show on like fucking New Year's Eve.
Rym: Usually we take like these two weeks off, but we'll see probably do something on Thursday.
Rym: Maybe we'll bail.
Rym: They put even odds on me or Scott wanting to bail first.
Rym: But anyway, I have a good new year.
Rym: Have a good holiday.
Rym: We'll see you in 2021.
Rym: Let's hope that this was the bottom of Recent lived experience and now I leave you with.