Rym: It's Thursday, February 13th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight cleaning.
Scott: Let's do this Cuz.
Rym: we're in our 30s and that's what gets us excited.
Rym: That's just I mean, you know People always make those jokes.
Rym: But like it is very funny to me that the things I get like I still get excited about my nerdy shit and video games And anime and like all my nonsense.
Rym: But now I also get excited by things like getting a new armoire or Like cleaning up my apartment.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: That's how life goes anyway You know, it's like you're at work looking at the bad screen.
Scott: you come home.
Scott: Look at the good screen.
Scott: Yeah, it's like anything you do.
Scott: that's not at work, you know, it can be exciting Especially when you have the mentality we do of always trying to do things in the best way.
Scott: Yeah, so even if it's a boring thing You know, it's like you.
Scott: the fun part is not the thing.
Scott: the fun part is, you know Researching trying to find the best one the best technique improving the technique, right?
Scott: You know that sort of thing.
Rym: That's why it's a lot of games like as I get very good at them I tend to lose interest in them.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So, uh speaking of gaming, uh, I'm that weirdo who has two keyboards on his desk.
Rym: Okay, I have my.
Rym: well because I when I type a lot I type really fast and I like good clicky keys.
Rym: So I have the cherry MX blues and my fancy DOS keyboard, but cherry MX blues suck for playing first-person shooters.
Rym: Oh, yeah, they're a big problem for that.
Scott: Oh, you gotta have some Reds.
Rym: Yep, but the Reds suck for typing.
Scott: I mean, they don't suck for typing.
Rym: They're not they don't they're not.
Rym: It's a.
Scott: they're not ideal, but it's fine.
Rym: Well, they're the Ford Escort of typing.
Rym: They're better than a chicklet like light not light years beyond.
Rym: but they're the Ford.
Rym: They're not fine compared to a cherry MX blue.
Scott: They're fine.
Rym: So I have my DOS keyboard and then I also have sitting here almost like one of those old organs a Smaller keyboard without the numpad.
Rym: You don't need that for gaming if that has cherry MX Reds in it.
Rym: That's what I came with.
Rym: so the other day I Turned on my computer and it wouldn't boot Mm-hmm.
Rym: I was just like, uh, that that was scary.
Rym: Yeah, so I fucks with a little bit like won't even get into BIOS.
Rym: So I do the like a low-level troubleshooting and it becomes pretty apparent.
Rym: There's a USB issue up because I notice that both keyboards Every time I turn the power on the caps lock light and the scroll lock light are both a red or blue Depending which keyboard it is.
Rym: one is red one is blue.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: So I unplug the gaming keyboard and everything's fine.
Scott: So probably some sort of short in the keyboard.
Scott: that's messing up the whole thing.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So I had USBs.
Rym: Yep, so I start investigating and I'm not sure.
Rym: I gotta test it now.
Rym: I'm pretty.
Rym: I'm not sure if it's the keyboard or the cable But I noticed something really bad about this keyboard that I never noticed before because it has a detachable cord.
Rym: cool Oh, you can get replace it then Yeah I could and I thought oh I'll replace the cord and see if that fixes it and if it does or doesn't that's my next step.
Rym: So I pull the cord out and then I noticed something I'd never noticed.
Rym: the connector to the keyboard is not USB.
Rym: like you.
Rym: I'm not gonna get into the detail.
Scott: My keyboard has a Mini or micro.
Rym: I forget micro is the good one the tiny one.
Scott: The point is it's mini is the obsolete fucking one.
Rym: That's not used on anything right anymore.
Scott: It's used on quite a few things.
Scott: No, it has been replaced by micro but there is still lots of things that are just not updated Yep, and still come with but not like most things that were would have used mini if they didn't go to micro.
Rym: They never go to a full-size like USB C like the big blocky.
Rym: So, yeah The things I have that have mini on them are all things that are more than like a decade old.
Scott: I have like a rear bike light and you charge it with mini.
Scott: Ah, that's the worst and I have What else has me.
Rym: even my bike stuff is like micro like everything's micro except most of it is.
Scott: but this still occasionally a thing I'm like, oh that's a mini thing.
Rym: Wow But the only things I have that are mini are like decade old bullshit.
Rym: and apparently this one keyboard.
Rym: I don't own a single USB mini cord.
Rym: Oh, I got a lot Yeah, uh, yeah, if you have one, I will borrow it from you guys.
Rym: I got some Yeah, so then I'll find out if this keyboard is broken Which I'll be sad about because I really like this keyboard or if it's just that cord.
Scott: I mean even if the keyboards broken all those switches are perfectly fine.
Rym: You can just fix the board in the probably because there's not many things that can go wrong with a keyboard.
Rym: No, there's a tiny chance something crazy went wrong with it.
Rym: But then at that point I don't care because I can afford to buy a new keyboard and I've had this keyboard for like five years.
Rym: So, uh, yep crisis averted my computer boots.
Rym: fine.
Rym: now The only problem my computer has is that it still can't wake up from sleep without me fussing with it.
Scott: And I gave up the same thing that my stupid HD PC has yep.
Scott: And whereas if it goes to sleep it actually just shuts down.
Scott: Yeah, and now I have to wake it up I have to push the power button.
Scott: I can't let it sleep and push the keyboard buttons to wake it.
Rym: Yeah, but a few months ago.
Scott: I actually tried like I'm a computer professional I know I tried all sorts of crazy shit to fix it and it wouldn't fit.
Rym: I ended up like running Windows debugger shit like digging through system logs.
Rym: Yeah, I determined fuck that problem.
Rym: I don't even care anymore.
Rym: I'll just turn the stupid fucking computer off.
Scott: I just I just leave the HD PC on cuz it's yeah I'm not gonna leave this computer on.
Rym: this computer draws a lot of power.
Rym: Yeah, and if it can't go to sleep, that's a problem.
Rym: Oh, yeah, so got any news.
Scott: Yeah, so You know, we usually if we ever mention like any sort of awards show we usually make fun of it We usually talk about how relevant worthless and garbage they are and that opinion has not changed in any way whatsoever.
Rym: I think I always think back to Penn Jillette saying something to the effect of Every major award show on earth is just the high school.
Rym: Whatever Awards.
Rym: Yeah fancier clothes Exactly everyone in that audience is as bored as you were in high school.
Rym: The only difference is they're being paid a lot of money to look like they're not bored, right?
Scott: So I've actually come.
Scott: you know Korean award shows at first they're even more fake than the award shows we have here like Oscars and Grammys are fake bullshit.
Scott: It's like at least they have like supposedly an Academy of old white dudes like choosing quote the best thing right the Korean like award shows are literally like There's.
Scott: what's the choate?
Scott: the choosing process?
Scott: Whoever is the most popular and never shows up.
Scott: if you show up or giving you an award It's really just an excuse to have a bunch of performances.
Scott: It's the awards are completely fake.
Scott: Yeah, they don't even really try to hide that at all Right.
Scott: It's like and in some ways at first you're like, wow, this is even more fake This is bullshit.
Scott: But then you know what you're like, wait, it's sort of actually good.
Scott: You're because you're being honest and saying yeah, you're just here to watch the performances.
Scott: The awards are just a contrivance.
Scott: yeah, I wish that the award shows in the US would do the same thing, but It's notable because the same thing always seems to happen is that people like us will say You know, these awards are not legitimate.
Scott: They're a bunch of bullshit determined by old white guys.
Scott: Why do you care?
Scott: Who wins them?
Rym: I mean remember why.
Scott: right if someone wins it It's like what are you bragging about?
Scott: a bunch of old white guys chose you whatever.
Rym: remember when?
Rym: Saw big hero six won the Oscar over things like song of the sea.
Rym: Because and there was a quote from one of the people in the Academy who said they didn't watch those quote Chinese films.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, that's the level of the Oscar, right?
Scott: Why would you know that like if I'm big hero six is you know, someone who worked on that?
Scott: It's like you're still proud of making that good thing.
Scott: Yeah, but that giving winning that Oscar gives you me no pride whatsoever because a bullshit award, right?
Scott: But anyway, so what's notable we've still got?
Rym: we won the parsec award in 2000.
Scott: It's also a bullshit award.
Rym: So best anime podcast.
Scott: Alright, so parasite that Rym still hasn't seen one many This weekend.
Scott: it's pretty much the champion of you know, Oscars, right?
Scott: So, you know people are like, yeah finally and not you know, white movie wins, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, I can't go back on what I said and be like, you know, yay Parasite.
Scott: because yay what yay white guys acknowledged it.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: no the take has to be the opposite.
Scott: the opposite take which is correct is not Hooray for parasite.
Scott: it won an Oscar.
Scott: It's Hooray.
Scott: This movie was so good.
Rym: They couldn't ignore it.
Scott: even white old white guys couldn't ignore it.
Scott: We don't care that it won.
Scott: We care that the movie was so strong Right that it punched the old white guys in the face so hard that they couldn't ignore it, right?
Rym: I think there's a much more important takeaway.
Rym: Finally someone made two Oscars kiss, right?
Scott: So another thing I got to say right is that you know people were saying Oh, this is the first thing to win an Oscar.
Scott: That was an English language that had subtitles right at least for Best Picture, right?
Scott: I guess you've there been Oscars for foreign language films.
Scott: Yeah subtitles, right?
Scott: And then I said wait a fucking minute.
Scott: Right film people right are fucking crazy about.
Scott: you know, not even you know Movies that involve non-white dudes.
Scott: We're talking like, you know Fellini's or Curaçao, I guess Curaçao was not white, but he's still an old dude, right?
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're crazy about these foreign movies, right?
Scott: You know seven samurai and eight and a half Film people fucking love those movies.
Scott: That's like a movie any of those old white guys.
Rym: I think they only like them because they're all of those Academy guys.
Scott: Well, I don't like eight and a half.
Scott: But anyway, the point is any of those Academy guys would say that those movies are like, oh so great Oh my god the best right, but if you look then fucking win any Oscars, yeah, right They didn't win the Oscar for Best Picture, right?
Scott: So that made me think of another thing and that is we look at sports, right?
Scott: There's sports.
Scott: You know the subjectivity to them because you know, this thing's like penalties but for the most part their objective, right?
Scott: There was a thing that happened.
Rym: There was a clear winner If you win the Stanley Cup unless pretty much the best team at hockey unless they was cheating going on.
Scott: There shouldn't be any like revoking or undoing right.
Scott: but Oscars Grammys these sorts of things are just completely subjective, right?
Scott: What was the best movie in?
Scott: 1962 right?
Scott: I just picked a random year, right and it's like in 1962.
Scott: They thought it was movie a well given us, you know 60 years of Thinking about it, right if we say wait a minute.
Scott: There was this way better movie in 1962 that didn't win.
Scott: That's a bunch of bullshit.
Scott: There is absolutely no reason for us to not just edit the Oscars and say, you know what?
Scott: No, you didn't win it.
Scott: That was the best movie that year.
Rym: There's no reason not to.
Scott: I saw a great thing pointing out that we should we should be constantly in fact Whatsoever even if you get rid of the white guys that would only affect the legitimacy of well current.
Rym: Well, I would make a much more nuanced point.
Rym: This is much like when we get similarly heated about how conventions track their attendance.
Rym: There's a lot of different ways to count it.
Rym: It's the same thing.
Rym: You can have all these different.
Rym: you could say What was this movie in the of this year in the context of that year and the sensibilities of that time?
Rym: based on a set of criteria versus in light of all But it's still based on.
Scott: at the time their system was still old white guys choosing the same system they have today.
Scott: Yeah, but that's one metric.
Rym: another metric would be so it was the box office gross.
Scott: Not only should we get rid of the old white guys to have different people do the choosing but they should Re-choose for every year ever to give legitimacy to the entire thing.
Rym: The thing is I don't know how many.
Rym: I think Choices wouldn't change much.
Scott: No, I don't think there wouldn't be that many changes, but there would be.
Scott: you know There is still some significant oversights.
Scott: Do you know how many?
Scott: Oscars.
Scott: the Stanley Kubrick won ever Zero, right one one one.
Scott: He won.
Scott: It was like for effects in 2001.
Scott: I saw that Oscar.
Scott: It's in the museum right over there the round one.
Rym: That's kind of wrong.
Scott: I mean, yeah, Stanley Kubrick was a white dude, but that's wrong.
Scott: You can't tell me that right that's right that that's how it should have been.
Scott: we can go back and fix that.
Rym: All right Yeah, I mean mostly I just don't watch the Oscars because they're boring.
Scott: No I haven't watched any of these award shows and it's when I was years and I don't go and look up either what the winners are but you're Inevitably faced with them on Twitter years ago when I went on.
Scott: that also.
Scott: parasite is fucking great and deserved to be the best Picture.
Scott: they got it, right?
Scott: I'm not lying.
Scott: I'm not gonna deny that.
Rym: years ago I went on a week-long ski trip during the Super Bowl and all of us on the trip agreed just to as an experiment See how long we could go not knowing who won the Super Bowl and I made it about a week But that was.
Rym: but that was a Twitter existed, but it was an earlier day of Twitter compared to today.
Rym: I feel like I could not avoid.
Scott: it is a thing even though you might remember that the Chiefs who won the Super Bowl this Year, all right, if you just wait long enough who won the Super Bowl four years ago pick it right up here.
Rym: I don't fucking remember who won the Super Bowl exactly.
Scott: So it's like, you know this bag unless it's a team I think what would we know?
Scott: the parasite won best picture this year, right?
Scott: Well one best picture last year I already forgot that's right.
Rym: So you knowing is only all and I want to say la la land.
Scott: I think that one but the year before.
Scott: nah, I don't think that was last year.
Scott: You're gonna google it.
Scott: and now remember I am gonna google it now 2017.
Rym: Good lord.
Scott: Okay Right.
Scott: So, uh, yeah, you never fucking remember what won last year.
Scott: Knowing isn't a permanent thing.
Rym: Stanley Cup more than a few years ago, unless it's a team.
Rym: I specifically care about.
Scott: I remember teams that have won cups recently But I could not from memory put eat be a hundred percent correct, but each team on the year I would just sort of vaguely, you know get close.
Scott: I'd be like, yeah the caps got drunk.
Scott: That was what two years ago and then I'll lose.
Scott: so his blues caps fucking Someone.
Rym: I know it's because it wasn't.
Scott: there were a bunch of a few penguins ones back there.
Rym: Yeah, it wasn't the Rangers.
Scott: Yeah, well definitely wasn't me.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Hey, we're not out of playoff contention yet, technically anyway.
Rym: So some other news you've probably seen.
Rym: there's multiple cruise ships that are basically under quarantine.
Scott: Well cruise ship is giant full of food luxurious.
Scott: So it's not a bad place to be quite.
Rym: Yes It is so I want unless it runs out of food.
Rym: I want to talk about that because I realize something one Most cruises are awful because they're basically just floating Marriott hotels filled with disease.
Scott: Yes, I'm aware of this but I mean, I'd rather be quarantined in a Marriott Hotel then like, you know, because I'm working less Think of it more like an airplane.
Scott: Most of the people that's a bad place to be quarantined.
Rym: Yeah, most of the people on a cruise ship are in rooms Smaller like half the whole ship is.
Scott: is it an island you can walk around?
Rym: No, you can find your room if there's a quarantine.
Scott: Well, that's some bullshit cuz just quarantine the boat.
Scott: Don't quarantine the individual.
Rym: No because a bunch of people on the boat have a disease.
Scott: Yeah, so let it spread to everyone on the boat.
Scott: No Then we'll die as long as doesn't spread to anyone not on.
Rym: the point is also to protect the people on the boat from the Other people on the boat.
Scott: Well, I mean you could at least Move the people around in a strategic way.
Scott: Yes of like the bottom floor to the diseased people.
Rym: Yeah, so you realize here's the problem with being quarantined on a boat is one.
Rym: most people on cruises are in tiny tiny rooms that are basically just a cot and they're all trapped in these tiny little like Jail, isn't there like a medical area that you can quarantine them in?
Scott: like in?
Scott: you know, like you're like alien, right?
Scott: Room for like six people quarantine the dude who's got the alien is not making like the.
Rym: you know That doesn't work because one disease is like coronavirus spread before you're symptomatic like you're contagious before you're symptomatic and to Unless you go without symptoms for 14 days.
Scott: You might be getting it right because the person's in their quarters, right?
Rym: They don't know who else might have it until they wait 14 days Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's the problem.
Rym: You could bring a little bubble to their door Yeah, but then some other random person might have been exposed to it a day ago and if that person walks around they'll spread it.
Rym: So the people on these boats the only people are having a good time are like the Handful of people who paid a lot of money to have like a room the size of this room as opposed to a cot and a Tiny jail cell because people don't spend any time in the rooms.
Scott: I'm food in the tiny room.
Scott: So the staff are Delivering special meals, but the staff are allowed to move around but you're stuck in your room because the staff.
Rym: I heard the staff quarantine because the staff are Outboard people who are brought in who are definitely not sick and are wearing protective gear.
Scott: So the people who were staff on the boat are generally also quarantined.
Scott: quarantine staff quarters Yeah, so the captain is quarantined and yet they brought in like an alternate captain.
Rym: All I know is the reality is the disease could be on stuff.
Scott: So even if you like let's say not really not not I don't think you.
Rym: do you know anything about the coronavirus?
Scott: the captain was sick and now the captain's quarantined in the captain's cabin.
Scott: and now a temporary captain comes in from the outside who definitely isn't sick and is touching the ship's wheel that the captain coughed all.
Rym: Probably okay.
Rym: Okay, probably okay It's you can touch that you can touch the ship's wheel the so like some of the ships are like Rotating passengers like certain people can go up to the deck for like a half hour just to like walk around a little bit.
Rym: Then they're locked back in their room.
Rym: So it's basically a living hell from what I can gather which just reinforces the idea that
Scott: never going cruises now It was already
Rym: my plan The only cruises I would ever consider are the ones that are like in the Mediterranean that just take you to a bunch of cities But never ever ever.
Rym: the cruise that is a bunch of like Boring people go out to the middle of the ocean and just stand a Marriott for a week like a Princess cruise or whatever.
Rym: Yeah So, uh, yeah, that's all happening In some other news.
Rym: that's kind of a crazy story.
Rym: So I oh I got to talk about it because it was just such a weird thing.
Rym: So there's the pediatrician Okay in America and he committed suicide.
Rym: That's tragic.
Rym: He was beloved by the children who and the families who used him.
Scott: So it was like it was like the best doctor in town.
Scott: Everyone loved them and then they killed.
Rym: he was an anti-vaxxer who Apparently now that his suicide note came out had been faking Vaccinations for anti-vax parents so that they could send their kids dangerously and illegally to school for like a decade.
Rym: Mm-hmm Even worse he might have been giving parents who weren't anti-vax Fake vet like giving their kids fake vaccines because he disagreed with vaccinations so much.
Rym: So now there's this tiny public health crisis because basically any family who used this doctor either might not have immunizations because they're a crazy dangerous family or Might not have immunizations because the doctor was crazy and lied to them.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Why did the doctor kill themselves?
Scott: Was it related to?
Rym: this seems unrelated?
Scott: Okay The doctor seems crazy and apparently well, this is actually a thing I remember when I was in summer camp.
Scott: right when you work in a summer camp something, you know It's like think about at work, right?
Scott: You always get sexual harassment trainings at work.
Scott: Oh, yeah, when you work in a summer camp, they give you spot the pedophile training.
Scott: Yeah Because that's super.
Scott: a lot of people go to work at summer camps because they're pedophiles and a chance to be a relit.
Scott: You know people come and bring their children to you.
Scott: I mean, I'm super bad plays their pedophiles to me.
Rym: I've gotten spot the person who is about to pass out because they're too drunk training, right?
Scott: and basically the description that they give you of someone to watch out for is the person who is like Super too friendly super too.
Scott: Nice right the kind of the kind the kind of description that matches like Popsicles.
Scott: no, not like that.
Scott: That's an obviously creepy person, right?
Scott: But this just I remember the description that they gave and this is at least two different trainings of different people was like my imagining would be like, you know, like a like a nega Ned Flanders like a super friendly kind of person is the kind of attitude that the kind of person who is a Pedophile going to a summer camp would cut what is likely to have that sort of personality To where you would never suspect it was them.
Scott: They were the friendliest nicest person.
Scott: That's how come people get close to them right you when you that right?
Scott: So it's no surprise that other sorts of crazy people anti-vax type people right just cuz you're wrong or dangerous or bad has no effect on your Friendliness or niceness or how close people, you know, in fact, you know cult leaders, right?
Scott: It's like how it works.
Scott: So You know, I don't judge people based on their their niceness friendliness and such Negatively or positively right.
Scott: I can assume that someone's a pedophile or a cult leader or an anti-vaxxer because they're too friendly.
Scott: But I'm just saying there's no relation between that and what the person's really up to.
Rym: so The other interesting thing is it seems like a lot of the people who went to this doctor It was like an open secret among the anti-vaxxer community that that was the doctor to go to to get everything faked.
Rym: Yeah, so I feel like we also need a way for people cuz they're like.
Rym: they interviewed a bunch of people went to the Doctor and one mother was like I knew something was up with that fucko.
Rym: basically, like You need any doctor who expresses like homeopathy interest should probably be like removed from doctoring.
Scott: There's a lot of things you had to do, but we're not doing them.
Scott: Yeah, is that so far down the list of fucked up broken shit?
Scott: Yeah, because right now I'm is the bigger.
Scott: you're fucked up broken shit.
Scott: that let's say you have something big.
Scott: that's fucked up.
Scott: Like I don't know.
Scott: you spilled a hot soup all over your fucking kitchen.
Scott: The whole floor is hot soup, right?
Rym: I got a deal with that like right now.
Scott: Well now let's say a hundred small things break elsewhere in your apartment.
Scott: They ain't getting fixed cuz you're dealing with the hot soup.
Scott: So right we have this major brokenness going on in our country and world.
Scott: We spilled fascism all over the kitchen floor right clap, you know climate changes Fascism diseases right that.
Scott: This so that the number of small broken things is increasing exponentially.
Scott: No one is fixing them because you can't you don't have time.
Rym: So like as much as I still think anyone who practices chiropractic should be charged with fraud And it should not be allowed to be practiced anywhere in the United States.
Rym: That is the least of my concerns right now And I'm not gonna be an activist for can for banning chiropractic and homeopathy And all that nonsense until we get rid of the fascists At least in some better news.
Rym: Scott won't watch the show because he doesn't watch live-action television in the United States ever.
Rym: but the good place Which only had four seasons was a fantastic show.
Rym: it ended.
Rym: It was the exact right number of seasons.
Rym: It didn't go on too long.
Rym: And all I will say is if you did not watch the show and don't know anything about it It is extremely Extremely extremely adjacent to one particular Culture book.
Rym: it is a sci-fi and it is really good.
Scott: I thought it was about like heaven.
Scott: That's why it's the good place and also hell.
Scott: Uh, yeah, so that's all I know about it.
Scott: It basically and I know that this TV show called the house.
Rym: I'll tell you the act.
Rym: I won't spoil.
Scott: That's literally all I know.
Rym: So here's the real plot.
Rym: someone wakes up In like this weird room and it says everything's fine.
Rym: They're like what and this person is like.
Rym: so you're dead and Congratulations, you're in the good place.
Scott: Or are you really?
Scott: I've seen that Twilight Zone episode.
Rym: Oh, so the twist is so.
Rym: it's heaven like it's everything's great for a while.
Rym: Sure.
Scott: It's not.
Rym: Well, I've seen the whole thing.
Rym: It's four seasons law.
Scott: Well, tell me is it the Twilight Zone episode?
Scott: We're just kidding.
Scott: It's hell.
Rym: It's actually way more complicated than you might think.
Rym: Okay, but at the end of the episode the twist is basically the person who were introduced to the main character.
Rym: the whole time Goes to another character and is like so yeah I'm not the person that that angel said I am and I definitely don't belong here.
Rym: So something's fucked up and everyone else clearly belongs there and it's either a mistake or something They don't know.
Scott: so like I guess the equivalent of you know, the I don't forget which Saint is at the gate, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, the main carrot the main I don't know too much.
Scott: You know Jews don't know much about this.
Rym: the main angels name is Michael like.
Rym: it's okay on point there.
Scott: The point is they fucked up somehow and let someone in who is bad Yep, and then what happens?
Rym: and the show would impress me about it.
Scott: You can't imagine too much would happen.
Scott: It would just be a bad person having a good time.
Rym: So yeah That's why it's only four seasons like Any four seasons.
Scott: to tell that you think you should limit it to like the 30 minute twice.
Scott: Well because the cool thing about this show I do get and you should also make two episodes bad guy gets Into heaven and good guy goes to hell.
Scott: the good guy goes to hell's way.
Scott: sad.
Scott: Don't make that never mind.
Scott: So the bad guy goes to heaven one.
Rym: So there is a revelation at one point that the person that heaven thought this other person was is in the bad place.
Rym: Oh, so now the bad person has a has to decide what to do about that.
Scott: uh-oh, and why would the bad?
Scott: just?
Scott: There's a literal God.
Scott: God could just fucking fix it.
Rym: Ah, so much like Gnostic Christianity You never see a god you only see the angels.
Rym: more like a Mettaton situation could still fix it.
Rym: Well, yeah, the show is about that.
Rym: But my point is that in ghost writer going to hell and fight demons enough times It's a show That was made in America with live-action Actors.
Rym: that is a serial but it ends when it's done as opposed to going on for ten more seasons or ending before it resolved.
Scott: Everybody well now knowing more than one sentence about it.
Scott: I like it less All right, the other interesting thing about it is after you watch couple episodes unless you tell me this parts where this ghost writer fighting Demons, then I'm gonna watch it.
Scott: Yeah All I'll say about is that everybody and I don't see ghost writer fighting demons and that's a new ten a horse lie.
Scott: Then I'll kill you literally every time I can send you to the bad place.
Rym: Okay, I think I know where this show is going.
Rym: Like I see what they're doing there it would do a 180 or a 90 degree swerve off into something that I Literally would never have expected and I feel stupid for not having not seen it.
Rym: The last thing I'll say about it.
Rym: Is that Shows like this mostly looking at you Star Trek Tend to have a very human centric like human sensibility focused area where they could do something Way transhumanist and weird.
Rym: right this show Goes into the transhumanist direction.
Rym: Oh, I did not expect.
Scott: I like it slightly more.
Rym: now that I was so happy that That was a direction this show went that I cannot recommend the show enough.
Rym: It is phenomenal Mm-hmm.
Rym: It is some of the best American TV.
Rym: I've seen forever.
Rym: It is easily seen on the high seas.
Rym: I guess there's a legal way to watch it, but I couldn't figure out a way to Netflix show or it's not like NBC.
Rym: Oh That the crazy thing is.
Rym: it's like broadcast TV yet.
Rym: It was a serious good show.
Scott: We'll watch it without ads.
Scott: Yeah, I read anyone who watched it on NBC.
Rym: Yeah, I think like the first seasons on Netflix It must be on one of the things.
Rym: Yeah, you can go to the high seas for the rest.
Scott: I'm sure the NBC.com has it somewhere, right?
Scott: But even if it cost money I highly recommend you log in with your someone's cable account like your mom's cable account and then watch it.
Rym: I'll never forget.
Rym: my favorite thing that Dorkly ever did was every time they said HBO.
Rym: They never they'd like to define replace in every script or any character ever in any show They made ever said the word HBO.
Rym: I've always changed it to my mom's HBO go account.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's right but anyway things Of the day.
Rym: I got two cuz they're just too good and too short.
Rym: Number one, there is a photograph making the rounds cuz it won a wildlife photography award.
Scott: It is a fire.
Scott: every year They give this award.
Scott: It's always a good photo.
Rym: This is the best photo I have ever seen from that series.
Rym: It is just like amazingly framed photograph of two mice having a fight on a subway platform Mm-hmm.
Rym: It is like this photo is just Perfect.
Scott: so really the the thing about this photo I think that makes it Like throttling the other one right is that you look at the how they got the focus, right?
Scott: You can see that the the shot had such a net, you know a narrow field of young, right?
Scott: But they managed, you know narrow depth of field, but they managed to get those tiny mice in focus.
Scott: But meanwhile everything behind and in front is out of focus.
Scott: The only thing that's in the same distance from the camera as the mice is like this bench to the left And even that's still a little bit closer.
Scott: so that pulls like you're complete.
Scott: Your eyes are just completely drawn to the mice and the mice only even better.
Scott: and the rest of the frame is just like letting You know, yeah This is in a subway station of some kind and even better.
Rym: if you zoom in or look at it I can't even tell you where.
Scott: I can just tell you it's not in New York.
Rym: It's the London Underground.
Rym: Okay, you can do.
Rym: I see the logo there.
Rym: Oh, there it is But actually the bench is slightly more in focus than the mice.
Rym: But that actually makes if you zoom in and like look at it in detail.
Rym: But that almost makes it better because it really puts into stark contrast how tiny the mice are.
Scott: Well the tiny but the contrast is really from.
Rym: the mice are also a black silhouette over a lighted background Because the station is is completely white.
Scott: Yeah, well well lit much more well lit than any sort of a New York station.
Rym: Yeah And the mice are just those new lights they put in the Vernon Jackson station that make it like.
Scott: well I guess the Hudson Yard stations bright.
Rym: Yeah, dude, go to Vernon Jackson sometime.
Rym: They put all these new like modern.
Scott: I always wonder what happened.
Scott: Like you think about all these stations are underground, right?
Scott: It's like there's emergency lighting.
Scott: in case we know.
Scott: but imagine if the lights turned out any emergency lights turned out The subway would be pitch black.
Scott: You wouldn't see depends on which line.
Rym: a lot of the lines are so close to the surface.
Rym: There's actually vents you don't know about.
Rym: a lot of light leaks in some of them some of them.
Scott: But I'm saying like Hudson Yards, you will see fucking nothing if all the lights and emergency lights failed.
Scott: really black.
Rym: Yep, you're like two seconds like oh fuck me.
Rym: Literally every 90% of the people down there have a cell phone and we'd be fine.
Scott: Oh, right.
Rym: so my other thing today is a 10-second video of Some amazing Japanese slapstick comedy.
Rym: dude Puts a harmonica in his mouth and tapes his nose shut so he can only breathe through the harmonica and his friend fucking Whales on his shin with a pot.
Rym: Oh Yeah Watch it with the sound on.
Rym: it's funnier than it has any right to be.
Scott: Sorry to anyone who's hard of hearing and cannot appreciate this joke.
Rym: And the moment you think it was funny and you're ready to go like watch it all the way to the end It's only 10 seconds long.
Rym: The last second of this video is twice as funny as the rest of the video.
Rym: Okay So what's your thing today?
Scott: So I wanted to link directly to the thing of the day.
Scott: But the problem is it was three different videos.
Scott: So it's a good opportunity to branch into the meta moment a little bit Post in our forum and in that forum post I embedded the three videos to make it for easy watching and our forum is even if you don't register Publicly visible to the entire internet.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Also our forums kind of rockin.
Scott: Yes over the last weekend was the NWHL all-star game Events a lot of things going on there And so it was the speed skating competitions and all the stuff all that kind of stuff and it was broadcast for completely free on.
Scott: You could just watch it and of course because it was on Twitch this VODs.
Scott: So if you missed it, you can go back and watch it and it came out to three VODs at the end of the day.
Scott: So here's the three VODs in our forum.
Scott: You can watch your one two three Conveniently without having to go to twitch and dig around or anything like that.
Scott: Not bad, and you'll you'll end up in our forum at the same time.
Rym: Yep I remember me and Emily were at the first championship when they gave away the Isabel Cup the first time.
Rym: It was like it was a good time.
Rym: We had.
Rym: it was like standing room only.
Scott: Well, there'll be another one soon.
Rym: Yeah, so in the meta moment the geek knows book club book is the tale of Genji.
Rym: We're powering through it at some point.
Scott: I'm reading right along on the train, but I worry that once bike starts I'll stop reading.
Scott: so one thing cuz I won't be on the train.
Rym: I was going kind of slow cuz I was trying to Be a hundred percent sure who was talking or who was being referred.
Rym: I gave up on that shit.
Rym: cuz I can't tell right.
Scott: I'm at the point where it's like person I know.
Scott: I just need I just need to know who's in the conversation And it's like, okay, these people had a conversation about this.
Scott: I don't know which one said what and it doesn't really matter.
Rym: Yep And I've get especially when a person is referred to through like multiple layers of allegory I if I don't immediately recognize who the character is.
Rym: I don't try to figure it out anymore.
Rym: No unless I'm unless I get confused I just move on.
Scott: Yeah Multiple different ways to refer to the same person.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, I also started reading more about that period.
Rym: now I understand the difference between like why there's a minister of the left and the right Understand the left and the right.
Rym: still I understand it enough to read this book with a lot more context.
Scott: basically Maybe I should research it again in the appendix.
Rym: Imagine there's.
Rym: I'm gonna super simplify and be better wrong.
Scott: There's an emperor says an emperor.
Rym: Yeah, because the administration is so large and complex of a nation of this size without scale without technology.
Rym: yeah coupled with a bunch of Confucianism and like Chinese government ideas that were imported and other things from the era You divide the country into two sides as an arbitrary means of administration.
Rym: You got the left and the right.
Rym: you have equal equivalent offices on both sides Just as a way kind of like Diocletian with the Roman Empire.
Rym: Like let's just split it in two.
Rym: It's kind of like that.
Rym: Okay It just so happens that I don't get it wrong.
Rym: The people who liked Genji were on the left.
Rym: people who didn't like Genji were on the rights.
Rym: All right Oh, that's kind of why he gets into some shit.
Scott: That's helpful.
Rym: Like that actually really helped me understand what's going on, okay That's good info for me and there is a long forward in the book if you go back and read it.
Scott: I did read it, but it didn't help me too much.
Scott: It explains that a little bit.
Scott: I don't remember too much either.
Rym: go read Wikipedia articles about that era and it makes way more sense.
Rym: All right, the forward tries to explain that but gets distracted.
Scott: All right, so some other meta things.
Scott: So first of all, we're trying to update the technology a little bit.
Scott: I got GeekNights onto Spotify So GeekNights is available wherever podcasts are delivered for free and even better.
Scott: This is kind of Google Play.
Scott: We're on iTunes run Spotify every Episode of.
Scott: yes, I went through a lot of spot.
Scott: Lipson's really crappy, but I went through a lot of effort and harassed people.
Scott: Well, I'm gonna qualify that every episode of GeekNights.
Rym: I'm gonna qualify that by what.
Rym: but Lipson is not crappy so much as We are some of the early.
Scott: They don't have an API.
Scott: They only have FTP as a means of integrating with them.
Rym: Well, I've realized something about podcasting in general.
Rym: Almost no one has a professional Technology pipeline for podcast.
Scott: There's one that had a very simple API but had an API.
Scott: Yeah, but post an episode edit an episode and delete enough.
Rym: I've seen the inside of several.
Rym: like professional podcasting organizations Even like super pros are way less automated than we are.
Rym: It's kind of sad.
Rym: like I think are like.
Rym: I literally think Scott and I have a more Technologically sophisticated podcast production pipeline than almost any professional podcaster on earth.
Scott: Anyway, that scares me.
Scott: The point is no one needs API's but us.
Scott: You're listening to you nights already, but it's everywhere Right, and I will take this opportunity to if you notice any technical problems because of the changes I made.
Rym: Yeah, like maybe this episode won't go up cuz the last episode didn't go up right away on the feed.
Rym: It went up everywhere, but the fee.
Scott: Yeah, there are some problems but In case you notice any problems, that's because if we're working on stuff, we'll fix it quickly.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: We're keeping an eye on it.
Rym: We're the middle of kind of a big upgrade of our tech stack in general.
Scott: I'll just remind you of all the different places that you can find GeekNights stuff.
Scott: We got Twitter's.
Scott: Yep, we got two different youtubes.
Scott: Yeah, I think he rims YouTube in my youtube.
Rym: Yeah, we got a patreon which is both a backup for the main show.
Rym: You can always listen there.
Rym: and I want to point out Almost everything we post to the patreon is free.
Rym: Like you don't need to give us any money to access any of that stuff.
Scott: You can go to the patreon without paying.
Scott: if you do pay you'll get.
Scott: you'll give Rym money.
Scott: Don't do that?
Rym: Yeah, you also get some custom stuff.
Rym: you get some Rym's rants.
Rym: you get some really reviews you get.
Rym: for example We did a panel that we didn't video at magfest and I posted the audio of that panel and the slides stuff like that.
Scott: Yeah, we got an Instagram that I'm trying to use, you know, we got pretty much everywhere.
Scott: There's a thing.
Scott: We got a thing and we have a discord and we got the forum on our website.
Scott: Don't forget that one.
Scott: I just mentioned it in the thing of the day part.
Scott: We got discord that was made by a listener and we were kind of a on discord.
Scott: But now it's like well, I guess whatever right?
Rym: Well because all the other things that could do a discord did died anyway, so Yeah, that's basically you know, the unofficial.
Scott: It's the unofficial official GeekNights discord.
Scott: Yep, and what I found out was You know, oh we got.
Scott: I got twitch also, but there's um, when you want to stream video games on YouTube twitch, right?
Scott: It's it's kind of like a hassle, right?
Scott: You got to set up all kinds of stuff.
Scott: You gotta use OBS you get all the stuff.
Scott: What happens is when you have discord installed and open if you start a video game?
Scott: Just launch a video game on Steam or anywhere this gorgeous pops up and is like hey, bro I see you're playing a video game.
Scott: You want to stream that on discord and you literally not even exaggerating you push one fucking button Just one button and just say yes And it immediately boom.
Scott: that game that you're playing is now streaming in a discord channel on the server Right and anyone and I think up to however many people can fit into a discord.
Scott: You know audio chat room can come into that chat room and watch the game that you're streaming and also Chat if they got microphones or listen if they got speakers or headphones.
Scott: and since you know Less people are gonna find you this way if you do this because obviously you're not listed on Twitch or YouTube or anywhere.
Scott: But it's so convenient and easy to do so low effort that I've been doing it because it's just like I'm playing a game on My PC.
Scott: might as well click one fucking button and then oh look listeners happen to pop in and chat.
Scott: Okay, and it's a small number of people.
Scott: so it's totally easy to handle.
Scott: So you should go to the GeekNights official unofficial discord And maybe you'll see a little pop-up sign when I'm streaming a game or someone else's and you can come in chat And you can't find the GeekNights official unofficial discord.
Scott: go the GeekNights forum and ask around to find links to it.
Rym: Yep, I'm gonna link to a bunch of this stuff in this post for this episode.
Scott: It's open to pretty much anyone but then if you're bad you'll get banned.
Rym: So don't be bad Yep, and a lesson least like I don't have to tell you that you got to vote for Democrats in every election if you're an American like basically until or see if the foreseeable future.
Scott: In fact, if you are not an American, you should find a way to illegally vote for Democrats.
Scott: Yeah, and if you are any human being you should find a way to Illegally rig the election for Democrats.
Rym: I mean now apparently it's not illegal to rig our election.
Scott: They voted against all these election security laws, which means The election is not going to be secure.
Scott: So it is our moral duty to rig it in favor of the good.
Scott: Yep, so not even joking.
Scott: I want to remind everyone that back in I go to jail just for suggesting it.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: free speech deal with it.
Rym: So back in May of last year the editorial board of GeekNights unanimously voted Meeting or meeting Scott and I said Warren.
Rym: Yeah, Warren We endorsed Warren like we Do believe.
Rym: Elizabeth Warren is the most qualified candidate in the Democrat field and we want her to be president.
Scott: She is still running if I just decide who of all the people on earth who would be president?
Scott: that is who I would pick.
Scott: Yeah, it is not to say that other candidates aren't also great.
Scott: It's like, you know, all these Bernie people are like super anti.
Scott: everyone else's like, you know, what Bernie is like.
Scott: close.
Scott: second I'll take a old Jewish guy.
Rym: I'll take gonna be a old Jewish Literally any Democrat except Tulsi Gabbard because I think she's a Russian spy, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, I'm not a fan of you know, Biden or him.
Rym: Hold my nose and I'll vote for it.
Scott: But it's like I'll take it.
Rym: I'll take anything blue.
Rym: No matter you vote for the Democrats.
Scott: I literally don't starving I'll eat the fucking McDonald's.
Scott: Yeah, I just want you know, I had enough poison.
Scott: McDonald's is at least not Literal poison, it's just you know metaphorical poison.
Rym: But the point I really want to make is we endorsed Warren but like in the end I'm gonna vote for any Democrat because we're in a literal crisis, but I want to point out something very clear if you don't Join a party in the United States.
Scott: You don't matter at all like nothing man I know if they know influence a lot of people, you know, it's like I used to think this way.
Rym: So I understand a lot of people think this way.
Rym: It's easy to use this.
Scott: I used to follow this line of thinking where it's like I'll be independent.
Scott: cuz I'm independent I hate the party system.
Scott: The party system is bullshit.
Scott: I still believe.
Rym: I do believe that right?
Scott: So I'm gonna be independent and I'll just vote for the person that I think is best in the general election.
Scott: Fuck your party bullshit, right?
Rym: But one party is always the worst party, right?
Scott: But what the literal thing that happens is pretty much in the vast majority of places in the country, right?
Scott: One party just wins.
Scott: in New York.
Scott: You can't win if you're in the Republican Party Which means the at your vote in the general does not matter, right?
Scott: You need to.
Scott: the primary is where you're actually choosing the person.
Scott: So even if you join a party, that's not your party, right?
Scott: Maybe you're a fascist Republican.
Scott: if you live in New York You should join the Democratic Party because then you're actually going to be choosing who's going to win.
Scott: You can choose the more right-wing Democrat and your vote will actually have an impact on who gets elected.
Scott: if you just stay a Republican In New York and keep voting for whoever the fuck fascist they put out there You're not gonna win and you're it's pointless.
Rym: So what I guess what I would say is that the the sink way to put this is Voting is not like this moral choice.
Rym: Like you're not rooting for someone before act way voting is very simple.
Rym: in the u.s There are two power seeking coalitions.
Rym: you pick which one you want to have influence over and then you pick which one You would like to see in power.
Rym: That is the only choice you actually have right?
Scott: I saw people who were like, you know, the you know Their principles right align with Bernie and the principles don't align with anyone else Right, and I get one is crazy because they overlap like 90%.
Scott: No, no, all right, but I'm saying that what that's what that person believes, right?
Scott: Is there?
Scott: they're they're against the other people for principled reasons, right?
Scott: But the point is it's like okay you will you know seek power Right.
Scott: Yeah, if that person and if that if it's not that person you're not going to seek power That means your your principle is now unrepresented in the government, which is much worse.
Rym: Yep, then right voting for the Green Party is literally saying I don't give a fuck.
Rym: Yeah who gets hurt?
Scott: It's like you're just like you're saying.
Scott: I believe my vote doesn't matter.
Scott: So I'll make it matter even less out of spite.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: So there's two coalitions.
Rym: pick the one that's closest to what you are seeking power.
Scott: Your vote is literal power right that you have.
Scott: it's the power you have.
Rym: Yeah to do anything political You want like a far-left radical join the Democrats.
Scott: you don't you don't vote.
Scott: you are not exerting that power at all.
Scott: You're you're.
Scott: you're failing to use your power to move the world your tiny piece of strength, right?
Scott: It's like the tug-of-war and you're just looking at the rope and you're just not pulling either side.
Scott: It's like Okay, well then you Didn't do anything to move it one way or the other.
Scott: Yeah, so now you can't complain about which way it moved at the end.
Rym: So getting into the main bit Cleaning is something that I tried to avoid doing for most of my life Or only did certain kinds of cleaning and not other kind.
Rym: Yeah, like Until I was an adult in my own apartment I don't think I had ever once even considered the idea that the molding needed to be dusted.
Scott: Yeah I own that still.
Rym: I die die die rarely dusts.
Scott: Yeah, and I don't debt when I do dust I don't dust all the things as certain things too hard to dust.
Rym: Yep well, what's?
Rym: it was so I was thinking about this partly because recently I We bought a bunch of new furniture and got rid of much old stuff and like I'm gonna read jiggering a lot of the apartment.
Rym: So I took apart the entire bedroom Deep cleaned it and put it all back together and then it did the same thing for the gig night studio.
Rym: Like I took my entire desk apart.
Rym: I pulled every cable out from under there.
Rym: I put cable routing channels everywhere and while I was doing that I liked it a full deep clean.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So What's your buddy?
Rym: Well, like what's your daily cleaning routine?
Scott: Clean on a daily Daily weekly monthly yearly.
Scott: Well, I mean I should do dishes more daily But what ends up happening is they pile a bit and then I do them.
Scott: So I do them a few times a week.
Scott: a dishwasher dishwasher helps.
Rym: Yeah, I but the dishwasher does 95% of my dishes.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, but I mean I don't run it every day No, but I put everything in the dishwasher as soon as I'm done with it.
Rym: I mean sometimes yeah, oh 100% I never leave dirty stuff out Unless the dishwasher is already full of clean stuff.
Rym: as soon as I break the seal on the clean dishwasher Everything that dishwasher gets put away and dirty stuff immediately goes into it.
Scott: Yeah, I just gotta have time to time to do it.
Scott: Sometimes it's like don't got time.
Rym: It takes less than Four seconds to put something dirty in the dishwasher.
Rym: You don't have four seconds.
Scott: Sometimes you know I go and I sit at a table and I eat and then I don't even bring the plates to the kitchen.
Scott: Wow, okay Later on I'll go collect everything.
Rym: Explains a lot about when we live together in colony.
Scott: Clean it eventually.
Scott: That's not like it goes to the point where it's like a problem.
Scott: It's just you know, I'll clean it the next day or the day after.
Rym: Alright, so is there any?
Rym: because I sweep the apartment every day.
Rym: No Well, I do a quick not like a deep.
Scott: When Wendy carpet is looking meh and like it looks like there's all I get because like the carpets easier to see.
Scott: So if it looks like there's a bunch of garbage on the carpet, then I'll vacuum all the floor Not just the carpet all the floor.
Rym: All right carpet.
Rym: We don't have any carpet.
Scott: I have a rug.
Scott: Yeah, right But if I look at the rug and if the rugs starting to look like there's a bunch of you know Dirt and filth on it, then I will actually clean the counters and tables first because that will sweep some filth.
Scott: important I always go top down like if I'm gonna day now vacuum literally everything.
Rym: Yeah, like if I'm gonna dust I dust first before I do literally anything else.
Rym: Otherwise, there's no point.
Scott: Yeah, I'm just gonna ruin what I just did a vacuum everything.
Rym: But no I sweep the apartment literally every day.
Rym: a quick sweep just to get up all the dust and stuff.
Rym: Hmm and that actually makes a big difference on the general cleanliness of the apartment.
Rym: I'm up once a week, but like a quick like water mop not like janitor mop like working at de Bella's.
Scott: Yeah, I see thing is I don't mop but I wish I had the janitor mop like de Bella's because there's in the kitchen now.
Scott: It'd be nice to have up.
Rym: an unnamed person just pointed out in the live stream chat The dishwasher fills and then it sits there clean a cough.
Rym: Uh-huh An unnamed person just said that.
Rym: just gonna point that out there.
Rym: unnamed person should go back to work Stop wasting time washing pockets And other unnamed person is listening from the other room, right?
Rym: So so when do you mock?
Rym: how often do you like sweet you ever sweep your apartment?
Scott: now use the vacuum?
Rym: Okay I I have been using.
Rym: we have a pretty good vacuum that I just didn't use that often because it's all hardwood and we basically Got really like we only have one rug now and it's in the bunny room for the bunny because rabbits do not like to run On hardwood floors like he hates the hardwood floor.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Then yeah, he'd like going out of the hallway like we had a rug rolled up in the hallway for a while.
Rym: So he would like very carefully walk over the hardwood into the hallway get up on that rug and then run across the rug.
Rym: Mm-hmm, so pretty much got a sweep because there's no other way to keep stuff clean and then mop once a week And that's pretty much it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So the big problem I have right is Bathroom cleaning right?
Scott: Uh, I used to have you know shower curtain right and shower curtains real easy.
Scott: You just don't use solid soap and it doesn't really get scummy quickly at all.
Rym: So weirdly enough I actually went back to using solid soap.
Scott: Anyway, the point is it has the.
Scott: you have a plastic, you know clear sheet on the inside and then the cloth.
Rym: Only one sheet just cloth.
Rym: That's the way to go.
Scott: No, no, no, you gotta have two plastic inside cloth.
Rym: It gets disgusting.
Scott: No, it takes a long time and then you should place it.
Rym: Why would do that waste?
Rym: Why not just have what?
Scott: I have one sheet.
Scott: You never had to clean the cloth you want.
Scott: it always looks great and it never gets wet or dirty or anything.
Rym: Immediately, it never gets dirty and like what?
Scott: Cloth one will get moldy and disgusting.
Rym: So one if it gets even slightly moldy All you do is put it in the washing machine.
Scott: Yeah, I never had to do that.
Scott: Okay It's completely protected and beautiful and perfect and new at all times.
Rym: Nicely when I'm in the shower and I only have to wash it like once every several months.
Scott: You also anyway.
Scott: The other thing is now in the in the bathroom we use the shower in the most.
Scott: we got the glass door.
Rym: Oh, you got to get the squeegee.
Rym: I have a squeegee, but you got to use the squeegee every time you shower.
Rym: There's no point.
Scott: Well, I tried to just you know, even before Forget preventing.
Scott: Um, right just a one-time clean of the glass door.
Scott: It's like I hate.
Scott: I got it.
Scott: I have to do something severe.
Scott: I tried two different ways to clean the glass door and it did not work.
Scott: see that in maintenance cleaning aside the thing that I Need to do that initial clean of the glass door and I'm having a hard time.
Rym: I hate Fully cleaning things like detail like if you do car work like the detail clean.
Rym: There's a reason why if you go to like a car wash They charge you like a dollar to use the machine to like vacuum out your car or whatever.
Rym: But if you want someone to like actually detail clean your car, it's like a hundred bucks.
Rym: Yep, cuz that shit takes forever and is a pain in the ass.
Rym: I hate detail cleaning and you'll notice anywhere I've ever lived like the detail areas like the Inside of the grout in the corner always gets a little shitty because I'm just unwilling to deal with that and then every now And then it gets too bad and then I have a miserable four hours, right?
Scott: Like I see you're doing frequent just kind of quick man clean.
Rym: No frequent quick man cleaning Greatly extends the time before a crisis.
Scott: see I just do Slightly less frequent but extensive cleans like when I go to clean that kitchen.
Scott: It's like I clean every fucking dish.
Scott: I scrub all the counters down till they're super shiny.
Rym: I do that every time I cook.
Rym: I scrub the counters every time I cook only a few time Like I use me on the only scrub while I'm cooking.
Scott: I'm cleaning up the mess like I've lived in the apartment for a few months.
Scott: I'd finally the front for the first time in the new apartment.
Scott: I clean the top of the stove with mr.
Scott: Clean's magic eraser.
Scott: Oh, I do that every few months.
Rym: The one thing I said went back to the shower.
Rym: The one thing that we both did a long time ago is I we try tried to use the like.
Rym: Spray it on the walls every day after you shower and it'll keep the muck away.
Scott: That shit doesn't work at all.
Scott: I don't know if I believe in that.
Scott: I think it didn't work at all didn't exist when I was young and it came into existence sometime when I was maybe in high school middle school and At least it came to my attention at that seemed like all it did was it?
Scott: But it seemed to me like a scam to make you buy more shit.
Rym: It seemed like it didn't prevent mildew which is added yet another layer of scum.
Scott: Anyway, uh One thing I got let's let's stick to the bathroom.
Scott: right so the Turlet.
Rym: All right For the Turlet.
Scott: well, so the Turlet.
Scott: first of all, there's all sorts of like preventative things they sell for the toilet.
Scott: I don't believe any of that garbage.
Rym: Well the one Don't put anything in the top tank.
Scott: No Well, there's also ones were like you put it like a goop on the side of the bowl and right it's all kinds like You know things that they have for toilets like prevent it from getting dirty and those have never were shit in it.
Rym: Just let it get dirty and clean it.
Scott: Yeah Not those have not functioned in my opinion.
Scott: from my experience I did some slight tests.
Rym: About once a week.
Rym: I'll wipe the toilet down just with a toilet paper and then flush it like after I use the toilet Mmm, and then about once every couple weeks I'll use disinfectant and just like clean out the bowl really quick like spray it in there scrub it flush it and then I'm good.
Rym: And like once a month, I'll disinfect the whole thing.
Rym: Like if I spraying it with a chemical.
Scott: Oh you spray it.
Rym: I just spray the whole toilet like the outside to handle everything with like.
Scott: what about this side and the end?
Rym: I just spray everything with disinfectant.
Scott: Okay, so for the inside.
Rym: as soon as I see stuff building up on the inside Yep, I put a noop in there and then I scrub it with a toilet brush, right?
Scott: I get the the stuff in the bottle with the with the gooseneck.
Rym: Yep The gooseneck that's the.
Scott: squeeze it all up in the groove.
Scott: Yeah, right and you got to make sure it a hundred percent covers the inside of the bowl.
Rym: No spots where it's not touching because up in those grooves is where your smells coming from not the bowl.
Scott: And then and then I just wait it's for like 15 minutes and then I go with the toilet brush Yeah, and then I flush it I totally brush the hell out of it and I don't you know tablets or any.
Scott: nah Preventative things just that.
Rym: only if you need to super disinfect.
Rym: And one thing I found is use a plunger or like the toilet brush to get the water out of the bowl like push it Over through the the you neck or the s the thing inside Mmm, so the bowl is empty then put the goop in and let it sit there for longer.
Rym: You don't need to do that.
Rym: often you do that.
Rym: if like there's a problem in the toilet, yeah.
Scott: So then your bathroom probably had like a sink.
Scott: you just spray it and scrub it, right?
Rym: So yeah The one of the thing that changed my life in terms of the bathroom the most is I bought a like pretty nice handheld like stiff bristle bristle scrubber thing and I clean everything but the toilet with that Like I just scrub the inside of my.
Rym: well The problem is the sink in our bathrooms in this building are nice, but they're big and kind of flat.
Rym: So they don't really ever get have water touching all the parts unless I fill them with water.
Rym: So if I don't scrub it gunk will accumulate pretty quickly.
Rym: So I have to scrub it like every couple days.
Rym: Yeah, the problem I have in the new I own this place I would put different sinks in.
Scott: the sinks are good.
Scott: The problem we have is these giant mirrors in the bathrooms.
Scott: Ah, yeah, even with like it's like.
Scott: oh, I got some Windex I got the squeegee.
Scott: I got whatever.
Scott: I can't seem to figure out how to clean the wind the mirror and not leave a bunch Everywhere that.
Scott: so there must be some special way.
Rym: I'm gonna tell you it'll feel a little wasteful.
Rym: But this is the only way to keep a mirror like actually like spotless.
Rym: Uh-huh, so use the Windex like.
Rym: it has to be like real like a moat.
Scott: I got real Windex.
Scott: Yeah, there's Windex.
Scott: Oh spray it all over.
Scott: I think you need.
Rym: Yeah, then take paper towel All right, and wipe it down.
Scott: I've tried to do that and it always gets tricky.
Rym: I Cannot imagine such a scenario.
Rym: I've tried to do that My bathroom right now and you will see zero streaks with that method and no other.
Scott: I'll try the paper towel method again.
Scott: But the last time I tried the paper towel method it didn't work and someone told me I should use newsprint.
Scott: I don't fucking have news don't use newsprint.
Rym: Just use paper towel.
Scott: I'd never even tried that because it sounded so dumb.
Scott: Paper towel did not work.
Rym: I use newsprint as like fine sandpaper for nonsense not for like a mirror, right?
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what they're talking about But I also I clean the the windows the same way.
Scott: But what's annoying is that you know my previous apartment.
Scott: It was possible for me to clean the in and outside of all the windows.
Rym: of all the windows in our apartment.
Rym: I can only clean the ones in the living room the balcony the window.
Rym: here I have no access to the outside at all.
Rym: The building has never cleaned it, right?
Scott: I want the building to come clean the stupid window.
Scott: I can only clean the balcony ones.
Rym: our building can't clean the window because there's a scaffold around it because our facade Failed an inspection and they haven't fixed it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, they there's no facade around our building that they.
Rym: but you know Your facade is not broken.
Scott: No, but but uh, you know if it gets dirty or I'm gonna ask him to clean it.
Rym: Yeah It's.
Rym: uh, I gave up on that.
Rym: I just cleaned the windows in the living room and like the spring and the ball and otherwise this don't bother because New York like the amount of dust in New York compared to almost anywhere else in America.
Rym: You could live is terrifying.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and windows get dirty so fast.
Rym: You can't keep them clean.
Rym: There's no.
Scott: but when they are clean, it's so nice.
Scott: It's like a whole new world.
Rym: Yeah for like a day not for a little while.
Rym: Yeah a couple days depends.
Scott: Alright, is there anything else that we gotta clean?
Scott: We take we clean floors.
Scott: We clean kitchens.
Scott: We clean bathrooms We clean windows.
Rym: So how do you what what method do you.
Rym: do you ever mop?
Rym: Like what method do you use to mop?
Rym: Like how do you mop?
Rym: What kind of mop?
Scott: I just don't mop.
Scott: I don't got a mop.
Rym: You're I feel like you should mop.
Rym: Do you mop your kitchen?
Scott: I want to but I don't got mop.
Rym: Do you want a mop?
Scott: I gotta find the best mop.
Rym: The any microfiber tornado mop is fine.
Scott: Yeah, I used to have one of those didn't work.
Rym: So great How do you know how to mop?
Rym: to explain to me the process that you use to mop with a tornado mop?
Rym: I got it wet with what do you have a?
Rym: do you fill a bucket with water?
Rym: Yeah, you put anything in that water.
Rym: Is it just water?
Scott: I tried both ways.
Rym: Okay, so then what do you do with the mop?
Scott: you get away put the mop in the bucket?
Rym: All right, and then rub the mop all over the floor Like fully a fully soft mop like without wringing it out first.
Scott: you wring it out after but it's full of dirty water.
Scott: You've wring the dirty water out and then you put more clean water on it.
Rym: I don't think you know how to mop.
Scott: Okay, you wring out the clean.
Scott: Oh god.
Rym: I didn't know.
Rym: I realized I didn't know how to mop until I worked at that de Bellas And I had to close.
Scott: but whenever I worked at a food place mopping was easy because it was already like you would just take The yellow bucket with wheels.
Scott: Yeah, right and you had the mop And you could squirt chemical and then there was the squeezy thing on the bucket.
Rym: Yeah, my mop has a squeezy thing on it.
Scott: Yeah, it's right.
Scott: So I squeeze the dirty water out into the like the sink or whatever.
Scott: Okay Yeah, I don't think you know how to mop.
Rym: Okay, I did they but I'd worked at that stupid place.
Rym: They sat me down and they're like here is the way that you have to mop.
Rym: so it'll actually like clean things and we won't Get dinged by the health inspectors.
Rym: and I learned like legit the four different ones.
Rym: So it depends on what kind of mopping you're doing.
Rym: so Basic mopping with a microfiber tornado mop is.
Rym: yet There's a wet version and a dry version of this.
Rym: for the dry version You dunk the mop in the water get it wet.
Rym: clean water mops wet Lift the mop up and shake it until no more water is like drip like water is not dripping out of the mop anymore.
Rym: So it's kind of wet but not sopping wet.
Rym: Mm-hmm Then mop your mop your area.
Rym: if it's a big area break it up into sections with that wet mop Ring it out then dip it in the water again to clean it out and wring it out again in the water.
Rym: Then with the dry rung out mob use it to sop up all the water.
Rym: You just got all over the floor.
Rym: That's like the basic method for like the easiest quick mop.
Scott: I mean that's basically why I did.
Scott: when I'm up to accept I never.
Rym: I never tried amount of muck and dirt.
Scott: I never tried to sop up the water.
Scott: I would I would let the water evaporate.
Rym: No, cuz then there's that water that you left.
Rym: there has most of the dirt still in it.
Rym: That's the problem.
Scott: I was scrubbing pretty hard when I was putting that water down.
Rym: Yeah, and you're gonna leave most of that scrubbed out muck in that water.
Scott: You gotta mop the water back up.
Scott: This stuff should be in the mop.
Rym: No, that's not how mobbing works.
Scott: Then when I went to when I went to wring the mop out in the sink All kinds of filth came out.
Rym: Yeah, but there's more filth down.
Rym: if you don't mop it back up You're leaving a lot of the filth on the floor.
Rym: Uh-huh The other thing is a deep mop is where you actually there's other way like there's disinfecting mop or whatever.
Rym: We live in a house.
Rym: We don't really need to worry about that.
Rym: But the other serious mopping you need to do occasionally especially if you have like a hardwood floor is you get the mop.
Rym: That's basically just like a big sponge on the end and you use chemicals and you like scrub everything with a sponge.
Scott: basically Yeah, that's what.
Scott: that's how my parents wash the kitchen floor.
Scott: I do that like once a year, but they weren't doing what you said of You know going again with the dry one and right.
Scott: they would just be like no one go in the kitchen.
Scott: It's the waters that the floor is wet.
Rym: Bad way to mop in most cases.
Scott: They've mobbed my entire childhood that it would say I'm up in the floor.
Scott: Don't come in the kitchen.
Rym: Okay, that's uh Went to.
Scott: the floor was dry again that everyone come back in.
Rym: I feel like I should link to a bunch of YouTube videos on how to mop.
Rym: maybe the only thing that's annoying is that living in New York mopping like The amount of just grime that gets into my apartment is so much.
Scott: I don't really have to mop the kitchen I don't really to mop anywhere else cuz everywhere else the vacuum it takes care of everything.
Scott: Yeah, cuz we I don't allow anything that needs to be mopped to Lee You know to not be in the kitchen ish area.
Rym: true the kitchen the kitchen is white.
Rym: Like I don't actually mop everything once a week usually like I'll do to pick up dust.
Scott: cuz there's dust I don't need to mop in the office.
Scott: What's in there?
Rym: No nothing though when I'm up in here I'll tear even despite vacuuming and sweeping.
Rym: you would be shocked at how much dust I pull up out of this floor.
Scott: When I mop every week, I mean, yeah dust just comes from everywhere Yeah, but there isn't gonna be like, you know a splash of tomato sauce from when you were cooking on this floor.
Scott: true true Right that you that one needs a mop.
Scott: a vacuum ain't gonna take care of that.
Rym: Yep That's why I'm off the kitchen very frequently.
Rym: Mmm, and I mop with bleach in the bathrooms.
Scott: I don't I don't like to use bleach.
Scott: I like to use it.
Scott: ammonia cleaners.
Rym: ammonia is okay.
Rym: I only use ammonia on glass though.
Scott: I tend to use bleach when I'm disinfecting the thing I try to avoid the bleach is because The Bleach can like sometimes discolor something.
Rym: Yeah, but the bleach will not discolor the tiles in my bathroom.
Rym: That's the only place I use bleach.
Scott: Okay, if you keep it to one place here.
Scott: Okay, it's bathrooms.
Rym: I have a different mop for the bathroom.
Rym: I don't use the mop I use the rest of the house in the bathroom.
Rym: Yeah, and that mop is basically for the bleach.
Scott: You gotta watch out for the ammonia bleach combo.
Scott: No good.
Rym: Yep, it scared.
Rym: It's sad to me how many adults don't know that my grandpa even fucked it up.
Scott: I remember one time we came home and like what the fuck did you do?
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Scott: Even I know how to do that.
Rym: but at the same time like From the other I think I think he was.
Scott: I think what he had done is like he knew that it was bad Right, but he was like it cleans so well Uh-huh, and he was us like he like.
Scott: he knew he had all the windows open and was ventilating and he's like, ah I'll be able to clean everything well and not get poisoned by chlorine.
Scott: Yes Well, I preemptively opened all the windows and turned the fans on.
Scott: now I can clean with the deadly bleach ammonia combo and it's like No, no, you can't fucking kill you.
Scott: It's World War one.
Scott: don't do that.
Rym: But I think part of the problem is that if you don't know chemistry or someone didn't tell you This is dangerous.
Rym: It is not an obvious danger in the world.
Scott: The point is there's no reason to ever combine two cleaning products regardless of ammonia bleach combo.
Scott: There is no reason to combine two cleaning products.
Scott: one will get it done.
Scott: It doesn't get it done.
Scott: It's a shitty cleaning.
Scott: throw that shit out.
Scott: buy something different.
Scott: Don't use two things at the same time in the same place.
Scott: There's no reason to ever also just get something else is good enough on its own and you'll never have a problem.
Rym: While I use bleach on the floor of the bathroom like disinfect everything the one thing I don't clean with bleach is the toilet Because I pee in the toilet and my pee has some ammonia in it.
Rym: Mm-hmm, like I don't know.
Rym: but bleach in the toilet I don't.
Scott: that's something serious to worry about.
Scott: but yeah I usually will buy something that just says no bleach in it because why if I need to bleach something I'll buy some bleach?
Scott: Yeah, I don't really need to do it that often.
Rym: Yeah, I don't I don't you have.
Rym: also you can have a tiny thing of bleach and it'll last you forever because you do not Need a lot of bleach.
Scott: Yeah, even when I do like the thing I'll.
Scott: bleach most often is like white clothing I have.
Scott: I never use bleach for laundry detergent and borax only I'll use the the powdery one.
Rym: Yeah, why though?
Scott: It's super rare.
Scott: It's only if something is super white and I really want to clean it.
Rym: I don't think I have anything that's super white like a white undershirt, but I get super white undershirts.
Scott: I think I had it.
Scott: I think I used it once.
Scott: Yeah, maybe twice right, but I have it.
Rym: Yeah, my real pro we've talked about laundry before so I won't get into it.
Rym: But I've done.
Rym: I use like Unscented like generic detergent and I use borax and that combo is great.
Rym: I didn't use anything else.
Scott: Oh something.
Scott: so just talk about cleaning equipments, right?
Scott: So I bought the best squeegee on Amazon, right?
Scott: I bought.
Rym: I bought the cheapest squeegee on Amazon and gear ago and guess what it broke after one use About like the highest the five-star squeegee.
Scott: Yep For bathroom.
Scott: I like anything that is the scrubbing bubbles brand.
Scott: I just like the little character.
Rym: He's like, alright, you would you had the scrubbing bubbles in colony.
Scott: It's a. it's a little brushy guy with googly eyes.
Scott: Yes, that's definitely the best guy, right?
Rym: I don't think the bubbles do much though.
Rym: I feel like he's lying to you.
Scott: Oh, no, the bubbles just go to make it sound like it's cleaning but I mean it works.
Rym: It's like the scam like if you buy selson blue or off-brand selson blue There's the normal one for dandruff and also versicolor like.
Rym: it works on both.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's just.
Scott: it's just.
Rym: it's an antifungal Yeah, and then there's the medicated one The only difference mental normal one and the medicated one.
Rym: They both have the same amount of the medicine.
Rym: Yeah, that kills the fungus.
Rym: the medicated one just has mints and aloe and stuff in it So it feels more medical.
Scott: Tingly it doesn't know smells minty.
Scott: It has menthol in it.
Rym: Yeah, it'll like make you tingle like people put peroxide in a lot of stuff just to make it feel like it's doing more.
Rym: Yeah, there's even some medicines that taste bad to make it feel like it's doing more.
Scott: Yep, bullshit.
Scott: Yeah, you gotta watch out these all you can look and see what the actual cleaning chemical is or everything else is not And somehow this topic was able to kill more than an hour.
Rym: We're out.
Scott: Oh, I have more to say.
Scott: Let's go.
Scott: I just want to say that, you know when I'm final thoughts with Scott when I'm wiping down the counter, right?
Scott: I used to use a sponge.
Rym: Oh, I know.
Rym: go we upgraded recently.
Scott: I don't like to use you know, anything disposable like a paper towel.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, the problem is burn through too much of it.
Rym: Yeah, the problem is paper towel is the most effective and also like the easiest to deal with and also the most wasteful.
Rym: Yeah, it was the most wasteful and I always felt bad about it.
Rym: So Emily picked up these fancy like reusable paper towels.
Scott: Okay?
Scott: Oh, I've seen those.
Scott: Yeah, they were.
Scott: they're really good Like I remember Kate had them.
Rym: yeah, they're a washcloth effectively that you can use for all the things used for paper towel and Then they dry out use them for like a week or two and when they're disgusting you can still throw them away.
Scott: What I have is I have these school Soy based sort of cloths not microfiber cloths, right which are only good for cleaning certain things.
Scott: Yep They're sort of like, you know, like the the sponges that start out flat.
Scott: you put water and they expand.
Scott: Yeah, imagine if it just didn't expand but it was just like a big square that you could get wet And you could really scrub shit down.
Scott: pretty nice.
Scott: Those things are great.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: That's what I use and also mr Clean's magic eraser on the top of the stove.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I also use mr Clean's magic eraser for scuffs on walls and things.
Scott: the best thing is mr.
Scott: Clean's magic eraser or Equivalent non branded same exact thing.
Scott: No is non.
Scott: It's not chemically acting.
Scott: It's it's just acts on friction.
Scott: it's like this really tiny abrasive thing and You just scrape you just scrub things off.
Scott: you can use it like to get crayon off a wall.
Scott: You can use it in all sorts of crazy stuff without any if you're worried about like chemically damaging or something like that.
Scott: Yep So there you go.
Rym: So my last thing.
Rym: I got a final thought.
Rym: we I deserve are still uses for paper towel like I try to get less but like if you need absorbing mirrors or Cleaning up something like a Mirror when I get home.
Rym: Yeah Like cleaning up something that is like has oil or grease on it that you don't want to get that like into your long.
Scott: I use paper towel more for cooking like pat dry, you know pat dry some chicken or pat dry some shrimpies.
Scott: That's what I use it for the most.
Rym: or to like get the grease off of some bacon.
Scott: I don't use napkins ever.
Scott: I only use paper towel.
Rym: same Napkins are just like an inferior for just boomer things, but we don't useable.
Scott: napkins are okay Yeah, but our fancy party.
Rym: so We tried to get some like much more eco-friendly like I think bamboo based paper towel.
Scott: because if we're gonna use that I want like The least damaging one I buy the one that is the biggest role with the the most Smaller sheets so I can use less at a time.
Rym: Yep I get the ones where I can get like the three inch long like strip at a time instead of the giant square.
Rym: Yeah foot by foot, but we got this eco-friendly bamboo.
Rym: It is so shitty.
Rym: It's like it's worthless.
Rym: we went we went back.
Rym: we're gonna go back to like the big thick like Midwestern suburban like brawny type stuff.
Scott: Yeah, it's like bounty brawn.
Scott: The one I have now is football.
Rym: It's kind of like toilet paper like I bought it around.
Rym: I tried to go with like a really eco-friendly toilet paper.
Rym: Nope, so I had to go back to the Charmin.
Scott: No, I go to the most luxurious Toilet paper.
Rym: You can't use that Wegmans one-ply.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand Ok for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights, which will hopefully appear on Spotify without us having to do any nonsense are Taking a while to sort this.
Rym: still don't like this new UI because doesn't actually show your whole name without me hovering over each line.
Rym: It's kind of annoying.
Rym: I guess I could export it to a CSV, but that feels even more annoying.
Rym: Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Marty green.
Rym: Yeah, just like a dude gags Artavish in link eg you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: I got in one little fight and my mom got scared.
Rym: Clinton Walton my state calm.
Rym: Jay bants Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin for open Lander Nicholas Brandau Chris Mink if Mac the thirst for hydrated Gannon dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Thomas on Sherman von Harl and a whole bunch of other people who don't want me to say their name.
Rym: So, uh, yeah check us out on Spotify.
Rym: We finally got that working fully and it reminded me of the terrifying Huge backlog of GeekNights episodes that we have.
Rym: we've been doing this for a long time and we have made a lot Of episodes and they are all there.
Rym: I scrolled all the way down until it showed me the one from October 31st 2005. so anyway, I leave you with.
Rym: Here's that champagne you ordered mr.
Rym: Simpson.
Scott: Oh Thanks Here.
Rym: Wow an award statue.
Scott: Oh, it's a Grammy.
Rym: Hey, don't throw your garbage down here.