Rym: It's Thursday October 22nd 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight on this spooky October Thursday.
Rym: We are talking about ghosts.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So has anything happened to you in the last 48 hours?
Scott: cuz I got fucking nothing not much Other than the routine things that are happening.
Scott: and you know the world, right?
Scott: There's pretty much only two out of the ordinary things that have happened in my personal experience.
Scott: So first, you know for the podcast over these past months, right?
Scott: I've been using the countryman microphone that we use when we're doing panels.
Scott: You know the same one you see people using for like TED talks.
Rym: Yeah, the countryman e6, which is a expensive Omnidirectional microphone that's kind of a pain in the ass to use like it's really intended to be invisible on a stage.
Rym: It's not really pleasant to use like sitting at your desk.
Scott: No, it's not so it would like hurt my ear and be kind of annoying.
Scott: I am using it when I'm streaming while biking because with what a wireless pack?
Scott: because that makes sense.
Rym: Video because Even though I have a shotgun mic my apartment has a lot of bare walls Right.
Scott: So I think we already talked about the X to you breaking and getting the new audio interface thing Which is really terrific.
Scott: I think I'm very pleased with the audio interface.
Rym: now Welcome welcome to the world of plus four instead of minus ten and someday you'll figure out what that means.
Scott: Yeah, but the point is Because I have this audio interface I can now just use XLR Devices.
Scott: anything with XLR output I can now record on my computer very easily, you know.
Scott: So I can pull instead of wearing the stupid thing on my ear to do a podcast.
Scott: I can now take this as sm57 that I had in the bin or pull it out.
Rym: I don't think we own any 58.
Scott: No, we got the 58 beta or whatever, but I had 57 just lying around.
Scott: so I'm like All right.
Scott: Let me use this instead.
Scott: That's more comfortable than you know, that is the end of third microphone We used for GeekNights.
Rym: that is fine.
Scott: I'm sure no one listening if I even tell the difference.
Rym: No, especially the quality is actually worse lately because we're recording in two different environments So we actually have twice as much background noise.
Rym: That is different.
Rym: Oh Two different background noises to get you and there is more noise out of you.
Rym: the one problem with the thing you're about to talk About but it doesn't matter.
Rym: It's immaterial.
Rym: The quality is fine.
Rym: It has a noise band.
Rym: There's a line of hiss at one very specific frequency that comes from it Mmm filter to remove that.
Scott: So the point is is that with the Countryman the Countryman is a microphone that uses phantom power, right?
Scott: It's like a condensing microphone.
Scott: So if the signal that it sends to the computer is plenty loud.
Scott: It's actually too loud You have to turn it down, right?
Scott: but you know The the this microphone the sm57 right is a dynamic microphone So it doesn't use the phantom power.
Scott: even if the the you know phantom power comes out of there.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: well the microphone just doesn't use it.
Scott: it ignores it and The signal that goes back to the computer is actually a pretty quiet signal Which means I got to go to the preamp that's in my audio interface and turn it up to get more to.
Scott: this is loud enough for recording.
Scott: The problem there is.
Scott: you turn it up.
Scott: You're turning up the noise also.
Scott: so The preamp when it's all the way up or really high up, even if you're not saying anything now, there's like this Right, you want the preamp to be turned down as much as possible.
Scott: That way you hear people talking and not.
Rym: but there has to be some amp somewhere because the signal that comes out of a dynamic Microphone is barely perceptible.
Scott: Yep, so I bought this thing that was much allotted by the internet and people.
Scott: I even talked to some people who said they had One and it was great and it's called the triton fet head.
Scott: There are other products that do similar things with different designs same designs But what it is is it's just a little little tiny guy with XLR input and output.
Scott: I think there was like a cloud lifter.
Scott: That's a similar product as well From a different company and you just stick it in the back of your microphone and then you stick the XLR cable into that.
Scott: So it actually looks like you might not even realize it's a separate product.
Scott: You might really think that's like oh the microphone just has a thing sticking out the bottom of it Right and it's supposed to be that way.
Scott: you mean now like see it in videos and not realize it's being in now recognize it Whereas before you just didn't think about it.
Scott: and what it does is well Got dynamic microphone.
Scott: We got this phantom power.
Scott: That's just being thrown out in the garbage, right?
Scott: Let's take that phantom power and we'll power up these FETs right.
Scott: and then it basically it's an amp.
Scott: It's an it but it's a flat amp.
Scott: There's no dial on it.
Scott: There's no controls.
Scott: It's literally just XLR in XLR out the end.
Rym: It's basically a pre preamp.
Scott: Yeah, it's a pre preamp.
Scott: It just adds like 20-something decibels to the signal going in one direction.
Rym: now You might think why didn't Scott just get a device that has a better preamp in it?
Rym: And the answer is that is crazy fucking expensive You got.
Scott: yeah, really good preamps cost a lot of money.
Scott: This thing was less than $100.
Scott: much less, right?
Scott: And I don't.
Scott: now I don't need any more equipment.
Scott: All right, and all of this is just from one USB 2.0 cable.
Scott: One USB 2.0 cable goes to this device, which is like a big audio interface An XLR cable then this, you know, FET head thing and then a microphone and it all works great.
Scott: So if you have if you want to use an XLR dynamic microphone with your computer You should and it's too quiet.
Scott: Maybe get one of these things.
Scott: It's much better than turning all the volume up everywhere.
Rym: and also you might think oh, why doesn't?
Rym: why don't you just buy a Non-dynamic microphone like get a like get a modern capacitive.
Rym: I cost a lot more and less than $100 like this as beta 87 a that I'm using right here The one that Scott normally uses in the apartment Costs more.
Rym: the difference between this and an sm57 is more than what Scott paid for that pre preamp.
Scott: Right if I didn't have the sm57 already I may have purchased a different microphone instead.
Rym: Yeah Why didn't Rym just stop bike over and give Scott the other beta as every 7a?
Rym: because Rym and Emily are doing a separate podcast?
Rym: I need that microphone here.
Rym: Why doesn't?
Rym: even if you the other Sm57?
Rym: because you know where that other sm57 is in my fucking a desk somewhere at work.
Scott: Yeah, I left it.
Scott: Even if you gave me one of those beta ones I it would probably still need this thing probably not.
Rym: this is a beta 87. a actually outputs a much higher Signal when you just oh, that's good because it's a much better microphone.
Rym: It's modern.
Rym: Yes, I'm 57 dates from Lyndon Johnson's presidency.
Scott: Yeah, it's old.
Rym: And If you find an sm57 from when Lyndon Baines Johnson was president There is literally no difference between that sm57 and today's sm57.
Rym: Mmm, maybe the plastics made a little better like in the in the capsule, but that's probably about it.
Scott: Yeah stuff like, you know, there will be immaterial differences, right, but there won't be any, you know material difference.
Rym: Yep So in the news very sad news, I mean this was a long time coming.
Rym: the man was 92. like that We could live.
Rym: so I'll take I'll take 92 if I was as healthy as James Randi was and as good as in good spirits As he seemed but he was 92. when I'm even like 90 I would take that as a win.
Rym: So the amazing Randy and complain has died of age-related complications.
Rym: He just literally died of old age.
Rym: The man was the legend.
Rym: the man was very important to the skeptic community.
Rym: The man was material in basically Destroying a wide swath of the charlatan industry in the world particularly in the United States and Europe.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there are still people who are charlatans everywhere.
Scott: But it's like, you know The thing that I think James Randi learned and was internally frustrated by is like yeah You can you can educate people.
Scott: right you can help people but some people cannot be helped.
Rym: You would talk about that event horizon Like there's a point in someone's life beyond which no logic can ever reach them again Like they're gone.
Rym: and I just remember seeing an interview from him.
Rym: This interview was like 20 years ago.
Rym: But someone asked him like have you ever changed anyone's mind?
Rym: and he thought about it And I just remember.
Rym: the saddest thing is he actually paused and he said something to the effect of you know It's never happened once.
Rym: the only people I've ever convinced were already convinced and just needed like they needed that final push.
Rym: No one has ever changed their mind because of any of my work.
Rym: I only hope is that can prevent people from getting that far in the first place.
Rym: I'm obviously paraphrasing from an interview that I heard like 15 years ago from five years before that But that's basically what he said.
Scott: Yeah, I mean that definitely describes, you know, my experience right is like I. I already sort of knew that.
Scott: You know There are things in the world that are real and there are things that are world that are fake.
Scott: There's people out there lying and trying to scam you in various ways, right?
Scott: But then, you know, thanks to his educational foundation and his other works, right?
Scott: I was like, oh Now I understand right.
Scott: How do you tell right?
Scott: Oh this fake things.
Scott: I wasn't even thinking about right, you know It's just sort of like you already know, but now you really know, right?
Rym: he also made sure like he did a good job of doing the right kind of outreach.
Rym: and the thing that I think really struck me was he was very patient with very Very crazy people like he really like he would compassionately talk to them like alright you believe you have this power Let's do a test.
Rym: I will work with you to define this test.
Rym: I will bend over backward to help you prove to me that you have powers.
Rym: and Like he never lost his temper.
Rym: He he interacted.
Rym: I think he was you know I mean, I'm sure he lost his temper off-camera and in his personal life.
Rym: But when he was interacting with someone who was trying to prove their stuff he earnestly worked with them because He was trying to convince them.
Rym: He's trying to prove that this stuff is not real.
Scott: But yeah a very important and Wonderful old man.
Scott: Yeah That's also right, you know.
Scott: It's pretty good when you can like.
Scott: if you think about James Randi, right?
Scott: You never think about young James Right, it's like it was like, you know old man was like his only Like remembered form, right?
Scott: Yeah, whereas I think there are a lot of other celebrity important significant figures, right, you know think about I don't know something is still alive, right?
Scott: So Michael Jordan, right?
Scott: You're never gonna like you're not gonna think they're not getting in the newspaper photos of old Michael Jordan Right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I guess it's like he had.
Scott: he had his act which was like the biggest show in the world Right, you know like this legendary eternal figure, but you know what comes down That's the end.
Rym: When were you famous in your life and what you were you famous for and like what sort of career kept?
Rym: Going like James Randi just kept doing this thing for so long.
Scott: He kept right his really huge, you know, the huge star It's like.
Scott: well, he started as a magician, but his big star as the debunking type was like, you know with Johnny Carson and stuff.
Rym: Yeah, when I was born very geller, right?
Rym: Right.
Scott: So basically for more than my entire life He was already old man.
Scott: that Johnny Carson clip.
Scott: It's not like you're seeing a young young James Randi.
Scott: Okay, you're seeing it all an old man and he just kept going his old man for several decades, right?
Rym: so I hope that I am still like Lecturing at Pax's when I'm like 80 something and people are oh, yeah, that's that old guy who talks about games, I guess.
Rym: So, uh you got any news.
Scott: Do we have a news?
Scott: I do but why I trying to remember what it was.
Rym: Yeah arts.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yes So you may be familiar.
Scott: There is a YouTube channel called artsy music and it's not a RTS Why it's a RT Z ie.
Scott: and even if you don't know the name of the channel you may have seen it.
Scott: they post videos consisting usually of vaporwave future funk ish genre music and Visually, right they take a clip for usually from an anime But not always from an anime a very brief clip usually just a few seconds long and loop it Alright, so you've probably seen like the ursa yotaro one with the you know
Rym: For right or right.
Scott: Oh, it's like they all think the three characters lean into each other like one Yeah, three and then it resets one two three, right and you definitely.
Scott: you've almost definitely seen these videos.
Rym: If you're a nerdy, these are like sit there like a tear down in popularity from like lo-fi beats to chill and study - right.
Scott: but this channel Which you know if you've only seen its popular videos has been like an institution for quite a few years now For that particular music scene.
Scott: right because people are in the scene of you know The the vaporwave genre of music or whatever.
Scott: They're following the artists, right?
Scott: They're band camping They're sound clouding, you know, they're in it, right?
Scott: so they don't need they don't need artsy music, but artsy music was instrumental in Getting that music out there, right?
Scott: There's a reason that those people You know can go and fill the pack the clubs when the clubs are open Is because that music became popular because of this one clever YouTube channel that sort of you know improvisationally and copyright-infringingly made Sort of music videos.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Well copyright.
Rym: I mean the car sets music videos this sort of gets.
Rym: You're using my words.
Scott: It's my word.
Scott: I am using your word.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: But they're they're like, you know what?
Rym: These are remind me of a lot.
Rym: they remind me of when you go to like a sort of trendy party or like a trendy bar Lounge that isn't playing loud annoying music but has like quiet music in the background.
Rym: Sometimes places like that will have like a chill like thing that's looping on TVs around or They'll have like a movie with the sound all the way down just sort of playing in the background While the music's playing like things like that.
Rym: It feels like the kind of thing you just put on in the background of a bar and just let it be or like in The back it also.
Scott: Yeah, it also goes towards the traditions of you know.
Scott: And the tropes of this genre of music is that if you do go to the club pretty much any vapor ish artist.
Scott: What they they're usually do is they have behind them typically a projector on the wall behind them And even if they're streaming on Twitch They'll stand in front of a green screen and play behind them some imagery and you'll always see.
Scott: you know DJ with so-and-so.
Scott: here's the tracks they played.
Scott: Visuals by so-and-so like making visuals to go behind DJ's is like a whole thing in and of itself.
Scott: So the artsy music channel a while ago had a little bit of drama Involving a fight between I think the person who runs the channel and maybe their partner or something.
Scott: There's some drama involving like them stealing the login to the channel and changing the pass.
Rym: I wasn't super clear on what happened and who is.
Scott: if I'm still not clear on what happened or what or what?
Scott: That was.
Scott: I couldn't figure out what the heck happened with that either.
Scott: there was drama.
Scott: Regardless the new drama is that Despite being super copyright infringing for several years, right?
Scott: Not only were is the music?
Scott: almost all the music is heavily sampled music and you know They didn't clear those samples right with the original song creators.
Rym: Of course not, you know.
Scott: They're not paying whoever made right the original songs, right?
Scott: If I sample Michael Jackson, right and I you know make us new song Well, it's a very unlikely.
Scott: YouTube will detect that as a Michael Jackson song.
Scott: Yeah, and now they're not gonna be even if you know, I monetize like Michael Jackson's not getting the money.
Scott: So there's that level of copyright infringement that was happening.
Scott: There was also just the anime imagery, you know.
Scott: so what happened just now recently was that show Pro which is Shoko God, and you know Chagak, whatever sure Asia.
Scott: they just they shortened their name to show Pro in Japan.
Rym: You know the big anime company they've come after my youtube channel before.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So show Pro basically came down on artsy with like, you know Copyright and strikes on almost every video.
Scott: that because they're all anime clips, right?
Rym: Yep These clips could not in any way impact their monetization of their properties.
Scott: No watching Sailor Moon transform like half of the Sailor Moon transformation right at a loop Does not in any way impact the sales of Sailor Moon DVDs the best.
Rym: the worst case scenario Is it doesn't impact them more likely or remind someone?
Rym: Oh, yeah Sailor Moon Yeah exists anyway.
Scott: Anyway, so the copyright thing obviously is bullshit, but the channel is gonna die, right?
Scott: It's still up as of now.
Scott: They're making a new channel.
Scott: You can go to the Twitter to learn about it.
Scott: I guess they're gonna avoid a copyright infringement.
Rym: on the new channel Yeah, we'll see how there are some other.
Scott: there are some other channels out there that attempt to do similar thing.
Scott: It's like whack-a-ball.
Rym: There's so many channels that do stuff like this.
Rym: and yeah I guess what says actually this guy?
Rym: this was.
Scott: this was a popular big one that mattered because it was a platform For you know, like basically making something that was an underground scene and getting it known.
Rym: dude That channel is literally how I got into that scene and became interested in that scene.
Rym: was this fucking channel Exactly.
Rym: Those other channels that are doing the same thing weren't successful Like I would literally just put it on in the living room while I was like cooking dinner.
Rym: Yeah, it was just a fun thing Yep.
Scott: So yeah, the channel is probably gonna die soon if it's not dead by the time you hear this.
Scott: and That's.
Scott: it's a sad times and there's so many.
Scott: there's just so many things going on with that.
Scott: Well, this even conflict is Conflegration of like anime music YouTube problems.
Rym: Yeah, right copyright issues.
Scott: Like there's just so many things all coming together into this one story And it's you know, and it segues nicely into my store.
Rym: my news Which is twitch is also having these problems now Basically YouTube.
Rym: a lot of people have used twitch instead of YouTube partly because YouTube has much more Powerful automated copyright enforcement for music and twitch here.
Rym: there too had not so much.
Rym: and basically back in June there was sort of an apocalypse on twitch where like Millions of DMCA notices all came out at once and a ton of streamers like lost their channels or lost a bunch of their old clips.
Rym: there's big trouble.
Rym: a second round of that just happened like a couple days ago.
Rym: and Now it's not just people who might have some incidental music It's also a ton of people who have just streamed video games that happen to include Some licensed music in the video game even in small segments.
Scott: Oh, it makes sense.
Scott: It makes sense.
Rym: Yeah Yep, but it's basically an apocalypse.
Rym: huge channels are being taken down people are losing like a Decade of their like VODs and archives with no way to get them because YouTube for all their problems at least does let you fight Back, like if you get a copyright claim as I'm very familiar with because I fought over a hundred of these over the years You can file a DMCA counterclaim and then you can go back and forth and YouTube like facilitates the process of getting lawyers involved.
Rym: That's the reason why our ten of videos are still up because I've done that repeatedly.
Rym: I've had a lawyer involved at least twice.
Rym: Twitch is not doing that.
Rym: twitch is just deleting any content that gets a copy on a DMCA strike.
Scott: Well, cuz twitch is about live streaming.
Scott: It's not about archiving their VOD feature.
Scott: I could even see them completely removing.
Rym: I'm surprised they still have it cuz it never worked.
Rym: Well, like right.
Scott: I remember originally I like my.
Scott: I don't know This is correct But my memory was that originally twitch didn't have a VOD feature and there was a feature instead Where you would get you would use OAuth to connect twitch to YouTube and twitch would save your video to YouTube and wouldn't be saved on twitch.
Scott: But yet the twitch VODs like because I don't think people realize that legally speaking at least the United States right using Music on a live stream is actually a different license.
Scott: It's a different right royalties payment that using it on a recorded video that can then be played back several times Versus a one-time live stream.
Scott: you pay for that differently Through you know through different channels the different amounts.
Scott: the money goes to different people.
Scott: So That's it.
Scott: That's a thing, right?
Scott: So it's like you might have.
Scott: actually for example I think I did.
Scott: did I talk about the twitch soundtrack app thing that they're coming out with?
Rym: I don't think you did yet cuz we're gonna use that as another house.
Rym: We're gonna talk about.
Scott: okay But yeah, twitch.
Scott: twitch has a thing, you know There have been many attempts in the past by various platforms to provide their their creators.
Scott: They're you know with libraries of royalty-free Light already or already licensed music that they can play safely without being you know taken down or whatever.
Scott: Yeah, but a lot of those are a pain in the ass.
Scott: So they have limited selections.
Rym: or you know They're not great and you can't use it for a VOD for a lot of reasons.
Rym: like you use them license music The license expires.
Scott: now your VOD is fucked right, but twitch has one that they're coming out with.
Scott: it's still in beta.
Scott: I don't know why they just don't let everyone use it right away where basically it hooks into your stream right directly.
Scott: So you're using like this music player and it plays the music on your stream.
Scott: There's like an OBS plug-in and everything and it's actually pretty.
Scott: it actually solves a technological Problem because normally if I want to play Spotify music on my twitch stream through OBS then in OBS I have to play my desktop audio right because Spotify plays Yeah, and then I capture my desktop audio, which is includes the Spotify audio and route that out to the stream.
Rym: Well, like right now I'm routing my desktop audio to OBS to get Scott's audio into the stream, right?
Scott: Sure But let's say that somebody you you forget to turn off.
Scott: you know some instant messaging program and Someone sends you a message and it goes didding.
Scott: now that didding goes through to your stream the twitch soundtrack Thing gets around that because you're not capturing.
Rym: there are other ways to get around that but they're not like people.
Rym: Don't do it for a lot of reasons.
Scott: This is a good and elegant way.
Scott: right the twitch thing will actually Take just the music and send it to just your stream.
Scott: You have to listen to the music locally if you don't want to.
Scott: all right.
Scott: So it's and also the music has all been licensed by you know twitch so that it's safe to play.
Scott: That's why they're providing it to you and there's actually a huge selection.
Scott: But some of the songs in that library are stream only and not VOD safe.
Scott: Yeah So even when twitch does it this, you know the legal and narrow way right to try to set something up for the users.
Scott: It's still not perfect.
Rym: Well the other brother but think about the buried lead of the two stories.
Rym: We just did.
Rym: what's really happening here is Multiple industries just in the last six months or so have started to get extra-aggressive on copyright enforcement in Really really age uses of their IP like they're going at.
Rym: like it was one thing when like the RIA was going after just straight-up Music piracy like I still think music piracy back then was important and changed.
Rym: like there's a lot of discourse to have there.
Rym: But I at least understand why the music industry went after Napster.
Rym: like that makes sense.
Rym: Napster directly took away their revenue of their product, but none of this stuff does at All.
Scott: these are like people these days Depends on which parts.
Rym: background music music that's in a video game That is not uninterrupted to listen to.
Rym: that's incidental to a stream cannot take away revenue, but to your point.
Rym: I'll just put on.
Rym: if I want to hear a song like I think of a random song I'm sitting at my desk like oh I want to listen to X song.
Rym: My go-to is just to type it into YouTube and watch some random exactly.
Scott: Yeah, there are people though who don't use a Spotify.
Scott: They don't use anything.
Scott: They just go to YouTube and they'll make playlists on YouTube and YouTube is their music player.
Scott: Yep On Twitch it's like yeah, if some guy has music playing let's say he's a streamer of out of the overwatch, right?
Scott: Yeah, he's playing some you know music during his overwatch stream.
Scott: Well, it's like.
Scott: on the one hand it's like that is not replacing Listening to that music because you heard a bunch of like pew pew pew Right.
Scott: No one's going to that stream to hear the music but that music is enhancing the stream and making it more watchable Right.
Scott: So the compensation is really in that case the streamer owes Right the person who made the music.
Rym: ah, but think about that old parable of the man who eats the bland rice.
Rym: But he lives over a fish restaurant and the smell of the cooking fish Enhances his enjoyment of the rice.
Rym: Does he owe their fish restaurant money?
Scott: Well here he's you know, he's eating the fish here.
Rym: but is he really eating the fish?
Rym: what could could the people who could the Label that made that music make money that they would not have made if that stream didn't exist?
Scott: Well, but his thing.
Scott: would his stream have as many viewers if it only included the sounds of overwatch?
Scott: Or would it be annoying and less it more painful to watch that stream?
Scott: and the music makes the stream easier to watch.
Scott: now He's got more viewers.
Scott: He's making more money because he's using the person's music.
Rym: but the streaming industry makes so little money to begin with and right well Fully enforced probably would not exist at all.
Rym: Like our streaming culture would disappear Right.
Scott: The other example is obviously someone just has a switch channel where they're a DJ and they're just playing music.
Rym: Yeah, that that's not it's not.
Scott: not all of it is their own music.
Scott: And yeah, that is a replacement.
Scott: like you could just not use Spotify and just go to twitch.
Rym: and well I guess what I've noticed is that?
Rym: Just in the last six or so months a lot of different IP holders are going after increasingly niche and incidental uses of their property That could not in any way affect their monetization.
Rym: No, they got time because they're not doing other things and they might be desperate for revenue because kovat is the world economy.
Scott: Yeah, no concerts.
Scott: I need more.
Scott: I need more money.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I can't tour right now.
Scott: get more and more money go.
Rym: But this is just really Not the right path because all this is gonna do like in the modern internet culture.
Rym: if Music is not used incidentally.
Rym: It's not like the labels.
Rym: make more money.
Rym: instead the music that's not being heard disappears from popular consciousness.
Scott: Yes So but also if someone's if someone makes a song you can't pay them with exposure.
Rym: Yep Well, this is the dueling thing.
Rym: on one hand we need to be able to support the people who make art but on the other hand we need a Statutory way to protect people who remix and make new works that are using parts of original works like.
Rym: we need a Compulsory license for sampling that includes a gratis version for people.
Scott: there are there are like compulsory Let's listen to not like a lot of the places just aren't paying.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: They're just not doing it.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: The compulsory licenses are usually pricing out very small amateur or completely incidental uses Mmm because that attempt to codify that would be an army of lawyers and Congress and like five years of debate minimum like no one's willing to go down that road.
Rym: and I think our culture is getting increasingly broken by draconian copyright enforcement by Owners of IP who are going after uses of their IP that do not materially affect their bottom line.
Scott: It's also a smaller Problem in the world of problems.
Scott: exactly.
Rym: It's something that like I'm mad about and that scene is mad about but some random person on the street is more mad about other things.
Scott: There's a pandemic.
Scott: What do I care about copyright infringement?
Rym: It's always been that way even during the good when the good times.
Rym: I'm making quotes here.
Rym: We're rolling.
Rym: How many people knew what the CBD tPA was?
Rym: how many people still?
Rym: I still know what CBD tPA stood for?
Rym: Because that's how mad I was about it.
Scott: Yep, but yeah, you know you just get you have to in order to solve those kinds of less important problems.
Rym: We had communism.
Scott: Well, you got to make got to solve all the big problems first.
Scott: Then suddenly that will be the biggest problem.
Rym: So incidental to this today I saw a Terrible take that's related to this on Twitter and it's news.
Scott: I think I saw the same.
Scott: I think I saw the same take.
Rym: Yeah because I think I even retweeted.
Rym: but basically what this person said was I'm gonna quote the tweet first because it gets back to one of the things we just talked about.
Rym: quote.
Rym: the real truth is that streamers should be paying the developers and publishers of The games they stream not even music.
Rym: We're talking about the games themselves.
Rym: quote They should be buying a license like any real business and paying for the content they use.
Rym: They think that if I'm playing overwatch and I'm streaming overwatch, I should have to pay licensing fees to blizzard for that privilege, right?
Scott: Well, there's two.
Scott: there's two angles on this, right?
Scott: So I saw another tweet responding to that person.
Scott: Yeah a person Twitter thread, right?
Scott: The response is like look if you're a game developer publisher, right?
Scott: There is literally no better way to spend your advertising marketing budget than to pay Streamers to play your game.
Scott: This is up.
Scott: We're not talking here about like, you know?
Scott: Hey, you know this is for exposure, right?
Scott: This is buying advertising.
Rym: Yeah Here's ten grand.
Rym: play my video game for a month, right?
Scott: If you it that if you have ten grand to spend an advertising your game Giving it to big, you know giving it to convince a big streamer to play your game Translates into more sales of your game than any other way you could spend those ten thousand dollars You know.
Scott: putting ads on YouTube putting a booth at a convention You know any kind of anything that you can think of to advertise your game.
Scott: radio ads TV ads None of those will work as well as just getting some popular streamer to play the game, right?
Scott: So if a streamer playing the game is is literally just advertising the game, right?
Scott: It's like why would the streamer pay the person who made the game?
Rym: They're doing them a huge never mind the fact that 99.9% of streamers make Dozens of dollars streaming.
Rym: There are not many streamers who make real money and most of the streamers you think make real money if you count the hours They put into that bullshit.
Rym: They're not making much money right.
Scott: so yeah on the one hand if you look at it and you say hey the streamer is making their money from these subscriptions and They're using you know, they're.
Scott: they're using this artwork that someone else made for free.
Scott: Right, if you look at that relationship, it's sort of like yeah the streamer probably, you know, I'm playing Mario and People subscribe to me to watch the Mario.
Scott: Then you know, first of all There's the argument that they're there to see me and the Mario to some extent right or they would watch me no matter what?
Scott: I was playing right?
Scott: How much are they paying to see the Mario part, right?
Scott: So there's some portion of that subscription money that belongs to me no matter what I stream because there's there to see me.
Scott: Yep, but even if they're not there to see me, they're mostly there to see the game, you know, okay so some portion of the subscription money could arguably go to Nintendo when I play Mario, but right That's not where the big money comes from.
Scott: even if you're a big-time streamer The subs are not the big money right.
Scott: the big money is those side deals the advertising deals.
Scott: people pay you To drink their product and show their ads on your the side of your stream or play their game.
Scott: Right, that's where the big streaming money comes from.
Scott: and in that relationship Obviously you aren't paying the advert.
Scott: It's like yeah, you paid me to advertise your product now.
Scott: I have to pay you because I'm advertising her your brother.
Scott: It's like it doesn't make.
Rym: and especially because what is someone if you sell a game?
Rym: a game is an experience someone interacts with So it can't.
Rym: it's by definition not the same experience to watch someone else play that game.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like saying like free demos shouldn't exist You can't you know, you're not allowed to give a game away for free Yeah, so this gets like the the yeah.
Rym: at the end the the artists working for exposure argument like gets entangled in there and it's you know, and Big part of this is that too many people are trying to squeeze as like this tiny amount of monetization Out of like.
Rym: they're trying to squeeze the last blood out of that stone instead of fixing the more fundamental problem Like the way everyone's exploited in this entire process.
Rym: Basically, but the reason why this was notable is that the person who said this was Alex Hutchinson Who is and I don't know that person.
Rym: He's the creative director for Google Stadia.
Rym: Okay, yeah Now I did not a little.
Rym: not that I was jazzed about Google Stadia, but I'm definitely less jazzed about Google Stadia.
Scott: I don't know if I could be less jazzed.
Rym: I mean you think that but how many times have I thought well 2020 couldn't really get any worse?
Rym: and then here Yeah but anyway things Of the day, so I'm gonna try to use another spooky thing in the day.
Rym: So if you're not familiar with the band lemon demon, you should be.
Rym: they're a great band though They were.
Rym: they made a bunch of albums and then around 2008 They just kind of disappeared for a long time and then out of nowhere and I want to say 2016 or 2017 they came back with Spirit phone possibly their best album.
Rym: Yeah, okay lemon demon, by the way That's Neil Cisaraga basically because he's literally made everything.
Rym: but lemon demons a legit good band like their albums are great.
Rym: spirit phone has a song in it about a ghost boyfriend called soft fuzzy man and This YouTube channel has made an animated fan video.
Rym: That is a fan made music video to the lemon demon song soft fuzzy man.
Rym: It is both spooky and funny and it's also really well animated.
Rym: Okay, that's my thing of the day.
Scott: Alright, so Adobe's convention Adobe maxed is what they call it.
Scott: I think it happens every once in a while.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'm not pay that much attention to it.
Scott: But that's when they usually make a bunch of announcements.
Scott: They show off all sorts of fancy new features and then the entire Adobe creative suite gets updated for free for everyone for indirect free Cuz you're paying a subscription, but that's when all the updates come out literally every I think creative cloud application got updates vast updates huge ones, but the ones that are really Getting a lot of talk especially amongst people who aren't you know heavy, you know Adobe creative cloud users are the new neural filters in Photoshop, right?
Scott: So Photoshop for years now has had the ability to do many many things But you needed to be very skilled to do a lot of these things, you know You need to learn Photoshop.
Scott: do Photoshop tutorials practice learn tools, right?
Scott: So for example, you want to make a sad person look happy.
Scott: Photoshop could have done that last year the year before, right?
Scott: But it's hard to do now.
Scott: They have literally not.
Scott: this is not an exaggeration.
Scott: You can go to neural filters you can check happiness and there's a slider that goes from left to right and you can You just draw a box around the face.
Scott: So it knows what face you're looking at and you can make the person happier or less happy or older or more Surprised or make their hair thicker.
Rym: it kind of just works.
Scott: It's you know, I mean obviously, you know, you know, if you use it Spent, you know correctly.
Scott: It's it's kind of amazing what it can do and also kind of scary.
Scott: So This person with a YouTube channel that doesn't have too many videos, so I don't know much about them.
Scott: But I do notice that their background is a CompUSA logo and all of their shelves are full of PC game boxes.
Scott: I have never seen that many PC game boxes in one place.
Scott: I've never seen anyone who keeps PC game boxes like back until Even back in the day when I would keep you know console game cases, right?
Scott: It's like the cardboard PC game boxes were useless.
Rym: I would I kept the boxes.
Rym: We had them lined up in a big shelf above the computer.
Scott: It's like you'd buy something like mech warrior 2 and it else.
Scott: a CD jewel case comes out and the cardboard goes in the trash.
Rym: Well, most of those boxes were full of a lot of floppy disks.
Scott: for me Also, most of those boxes were that large so that they could stand out on the shelves at CompUSA anyway.
Scott: So that's what I know about this person.
Scott: But what this person does is they made a funny video?
Scott: where they took a photo of themselves and they went to Photoshop and they really went wild with the Photoshop neural filters to hilarious results.
Scott: And it's only two minutes long, but I was I was laughing.
Scott: Yeah I'm gonna try it out on myself.
Rym: Later in the moment.
Rym: We got nothing going on.
Rym: We'll read the tale of Genji at some point.
Rym: We're not reading anything right now.
Rym: Our panel from PAX online is just on YouTube.
Rym: You can just watch it.
Rym: Stay tuned.
Rym: probably next week.
Rym: I'm gonna put up the panel.
Rym: We did the short panel at mag West our first appearance at mag West the West Coast iteration of mag fest.
Scott: So also I do notice that packs and mag West are both uploading on their YouTube channels Individual videos of various panels not ours.
Scott: I think ours would probably be like last in the list.
Scott: Yeah, they are uploading some.
Scott: they might get to ours at some point.
Rym: Ours is on the YouTube channel already, but it's in the like day six stream.
Scott: They're cutting them up and splitting them out now slowly over time.
Rym: Yeah But what I uploaded is the director's cut that is edited the way we would edit a panel compared to the format I had to use for packs.
Rym: There are no material differences though Like I'm not gonna I think like I edited out one more cough and like camera angles and like zoom anything on slides like that Kind of stuff.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, it's the only other meta I guess we got to say is come look for us on the internet.
Scott: if somehow you're listening to this You don't already know everything there is about GeekNights.
Scott: somehow We got a website.
Scott: We got Twitter.
Scott: We got YouTube.
Scott: We got.
Scott: we gave him got a fucking garbage Facebook.
Scott: We got fucking everything.
Scott: Discord.
Scott: just come and find us, you know YouTube.
Scott: if you could watch this live while it's being recorded You could like.
Scott: we're all over the whole internet.
Scott: You can't miss us.
Scott: Just search for GeekNights or something on your favorite place.
Scott: Come on.
Scott: Yeah, it's not hard.
Rym: All right, let's get right into it.
Rym: then goes Sticking with our movie.
Rym: We did werewolves the other day.
Rym: vampires are too big of a topic like.
Rym: that's a big big topic.
Rym: So I figured this is a good one because goes getting back to James Randi.
Rym: When I was a kid, I didn't believe in Bigfoot.
Rym: Like that was obviously stupid even to my kid.
Rym: brain Didn't believe in a lot of nonsense.
Rym: But when I was a kid, I believe I believed in aliens.
Rym: for I believed in aliens and I believe in ghosts.
Rym: And you know why some bullshit on TV that yes, I watch to Mysteries which I thought was a news broadcast even though it said at the beginning.
Rym: This is not a news broadcast.
Rym: It looked like one to me and my grandma had a giant pile of Fate magazine.
Rym: Fate magazine was in publication.
Rym: ever heard of it really since the 40s.
Rym: It was this magazine that is basically.
Rym: it Is everything James Randi hated on earth.
Rym: it like it.
Rym: an episode an issue would be like new evidence about UFOs.
Rym: Here's a story about a ghost that murdered someone The crystal skull is back and claimed another victim but it was a hundred percent dead serious and presented like real news.
Rym: and my kid brain I'd see like Reader's Digest which not a great magazine, but I digress.
Scott: actually it was weird.
Scott: Like I remember Reading and liking some portion of Reader's Digest when I had access to it at some point in my life It was always in the dentist's offices, but I can't remember a damn thing.
Scott: I ever read in there.
Rym: I remember all of all the I read.
Rym: a lot of readers died.
Rym: Not one thing.
Rym: both my dentist and my orthodontist as a kid had just piles of like 10 year old I think I liked like the form factor of it like this small thing.
Scott: That's all I remember.
Scott: all I remember about it was the form factor.
Scott: I don't remember anything about the content.
Rym: Not one thing In fact, the other thing I remember is at least in the Midwest a lot of people's houses when I visited them Would have a pile of Reader's Digest in the bathroom next to every toilet.
Scott: We didn't have my house.
Scott: We never had our house weird.
Rym: Well, we put it a lot at you're right.
Scott: a lot of houses people had Reader's Digest time magazines TV guides all these sorts of things we house.
Scott: We never had any of those.
Rym: How did you poop?
Rym: How could you talk?
Rym: Could you possibly poop?
Scott: We just never had any of those.
Rym: We are.
Rym: we left in our bathrooms where we had second copies of like Calvin and Hobbes and Bloom County Compilations of comics.
Rym: we always left those in the bathroom instead of the Reader's Digest.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, but fake made fake magazine.
Rym: Basically, my little kid brain would like see that and see like Newsweek and Reader's Digest and all these things and they were all equivalent.
Rym: They must be real.
Rym: Why would adults publish something that was fake?
Rym: So I'd open this thing He'd be like, oh the crystal skull killed someone.
Rym: Oh So I kind of just believed ghosts were real until like fifth grade Like fifth or sixth grade is when I think I'd stop believing that ghosts were real.
Scott: You know, I don't think I ever actually believed ghosts are real.
Scott: But I always liked ghosts and now and like as I got older actually like ghosts more.
Rym: Yeah, I like ghost stories a lot Like.
Rym: I really like a good ghost story.
Scott: So the thing with the ghost right is unlike, you know, the other ones the vampire werewolf, right?
Scott: There isn't like this single firm, you know definition of ghosts.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much like any.
Scott: It doesn't even necessarily have to be back from the dead even though it usually is but it's just sort of an incorporeal You know sentient spirit of some kind.
Scott: Yeah is a ghost, right?
Scott: You know, this is stereotypical vision of a white sheet that can go through walls.
Scott: Yeah, Casper whatever but doesn't have to be that it could just be like, you know, there's this bad juju who's around right?
Scott: You're feeling you know uneasy and something's talking at you.
Scott: It doesn't have an actual appearance, right?
Scott: Yeah But but then you get like and you get stuff like, you know The Holy Ghost or the ghost of Christmas past.
Rym: there are specific ghosts or you get a D&D.
Rym: ghosts and ghasts and ghouls are all different things About D&D.
Scott: Yeah, sure.
Rym: Yeah But I do really really like a good ghost story.
Rym: It's hard like Pete you need a good storyteller.
Rym: a ghost story.
Rym: That's just by itself is not great.
Rym: It has to be written well and have like the right ramp up of tension doesn't have to lead to a jump-scare.
Rym: I like it when they lead leave kind of ambiguous endings.
Rym: But I just I love a story that is supposedly true with quote marks about a ghost or a hunt of some kind Right.
Scott: Well, I mean cuz that's the thing.
Scott: So the ghost, you know an actual ghost like a ghost jumps out at you is not scary Right.
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: There's some sort of incorporeal spirit that can't touch me.
Scott: What can you do?
Scott: make me cold?
Scott: It's like if it comes through my body, it's like, you know, they're not actually frightening.
Rym: Well, it depends what kind of goes.
Rym: what is it goes?
Rym: they can like actually kill you Maybe okay, so usually they're not like most ghost stories.
Rym: The ghost can't actually like kill you.
Scott: Usually we're not you're not directly.
Rym: Yeah Usually when it goes kill someone in a ghost story It's because they the person themselves is so afraid that something else kills them.
Scott: Right exactly.
Scott: So I think the classic ghost story is like The Shining, right?
Scott: Yeah, that's your that's your scary ghost story.
Rym: Those ghosts only do anything to him if they were even real.
Scott: But that's that's exactly it is it's.
Scott: there's just there were dead people Right.
Scott: their spirits though of those dead people are still about despite them being dead and they're probably Upset, right?
Scott: They're not.
Scott: they're not happy having a good time.
Scott: Casper the friendly ghost, you know They could be right and so it's not about the ghost itself right.
Scott: alien is about the alien, right?
Scott: You know zombie movie is about the zombies coming to get you, right?
Rym: Is about sexy ghosts, but that's a.
Scott: I don't know if any of you are even old enough to have seen ghosts Right, but but a classic ghost story That's a scary horror type one right and not a sexy one or a friendly one is Not about ghosts.
Scott: It's about what human is do.
Scott: it's a human story.
Scott: But what do humans do in the presence of Malevolent, you know past dead people, right?
Scott: It's like it's like an environment.
Scott: almost now Here are okay people and they're stuck in a place and that play or you know, not only stuck in a place But they are haunted by Dead people now.
Rym: that is why I persist like when I was a little kid I stopped believing in UFOs around like first or second grade, but ghosts hung on for a while.
Rym: But partly because as a kid I made this sort of connection that Obviously most ghost stories are fake like Bigfoot.
Rym: But I had this vague idea that maybe it's plausible that like if something happens in the world So strongly it would like leave an imprint on the world.
Rym: Probably because like Fate magazine explained ghosts that way at one point and it just seeped into my brain Like I had a kid brain.
Rym: plausible explanation for them.
Rym: But Bigfoot was even to like a kindergartners brain.
Rym: like that is obviously a guy in a gorilla suit.
Scott: Yeah, I don't remember if this was on one of the Like more popular shows like unsolved mysteries or a different show But I remember as a kid seeing a show and the story they told or they retold with actors right reenact Was that this family moved to a new house?
Scott: It was it was out of the house or I think the bunk beds that they bought.
Rym: Wait, I remember a ghost story about haunted bunk beds specifically.
Scott: It was it was something like that.
Scott: Maybe it was the same one.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: and what happened?
Scott: the story was that I remember is pretty simple right.
Scott: is that they either it was either moving into a house or buying this furniture and They suddenly after they bought it, right?
Scott: Bad things start.
Scott: normal, right and not normal, but you know non Supernatural bad things started haunted bunk beds in Wisconsin that tormented the horror account family.
Rym: I remember this photo.
Rym: I think it's this.
Scott: it could be that it could very well be Sick.
Rym: it was depicted in unsolved mysteries in 1988.
Scott: Oh, so it was.
Rym: so it was on You and I watched the same fucking episode of unsolved mysteries in 1988.
Scott: probably This is the only episode on solve mysteries.
Scott: I remember it happens to be a ghost one.
Scott: Oh, no, I think I watched a George Washington's ghost in a hotel one once also.
Scott: I remember that one, too But that was yeah, but basically like the kids kept getting sick things in the house were breaking basically completely Non-supernatural bad things kept happening and then coincidentally they got rid of the beds and the bad things stopped happening.
Rym: Yeah Now obviously in retrospect like the reality is situations like that are usually people making post-hoc correlations because that's what our brains are good at but and also probably exaggerating the bad things that were happening.
Scott: Yeah, but to a kid brain Or to a non-wise adult brain but also the story someone who is not Aligned with the teachings of the great James Randi.
Rym: Yeah But just like the story of like this object has malevolence.
Rym: just like haunted paintings were a thing for a while Remember the hands resist him and the whole early internet like was obsessed with this haunted painting.
Scott: Yep, exactly That sort of thing is like.
Scott: that's actually scary, right?
Scott: It's like I'm not scared by like a dude in a sheet or like a thing coming around going like whoo.
Scott: It's like that's not scary.
Rym: You're scared by the aura.
Scott: It's like right.
Scott: it's like you're living here and just bad shit that's real is just gonna keep happening to you.
Scott: You're gonna keep getting sick.
Scott: It's like I'll get me the fuck out of there.
Scott: All right, that's a bad bad place.
Scott: Don't want to be there?
Rym: Yeah, in fact a while about a year we were at a wedding.
Rym: God it's weird to think back to like pre kovat times when I would like go out to a place.
Rym: but we're out of this really really fun wedding and people are hanging around a campfire late at night and a bunch of them were smoking a joint and ever just like super chill and Someone who wants to start telling ghost stories.
Rym: everyone goes around telling ghost stories and the thing I love the most about ghost stories is that almost everyone even if like most people don't believe in ghosts like literally.
Rym: but Ask almost anyone and they have at least one ghost story that they can just tell Unprompted like hey, do you know any ghost stories?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah the story of the haunted bunk.
Scott: Oh Is that all you gotta say?
Rym: yeah, I was going anywhere with that.
Scott: Okay, like I said The best ghost stories are the ones much like the bunk bed where you don't have to ever.
Scott: when you're telling the ghost story You're like your structure.
Scott: the structure is People enter scenario set the scene right bad things start happening Right.
Scott: Maybe there are dire consequences.
Scott: Maybe people die.
Scott: Maybe they don't.
Scott: it doesn't matter.
Scott: but bad things happen to the people.
Scott: right it escalates things are getting worse The people are getting scared right?
Scott: What is what's?
Scott: what is making all these things happen?
Scott: Yeah, right Discovery right you discover some source of them that could explain the malevolence.
Rym: be it, you know The classic racist burial ground story or you know All the dead people who used to work in this Story in scary stories to tell them the dark that scared my kid brain the most which was just about a family moves into a House.
Rym: they start one night They hear all this noise in the attic and they go up and a chair is like bouncing around by itself And they're freaked out by it, but they go back to bed.
Rym: They're like, whatever that's weird.
Rym: And then like it keeps bouncing around they go up again and eventually it like keeps bouncing around in one spot.
Rym: So they like investigate the area and they see the floorboards where they pull him up and there's a dead body like a skeleton in there Mm-hmm, and then the family's like well fuck this and they just leave the house.
Rym: That's the end like they don't actually solve it.
Scott: But but the point is you're finding some explanation or some reasoning Behind this supernatural source of anger, but you don't need a hard link to link the events to that.
Rym: You just need a soft link.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: There's some thing that was upset in the past that is, you know, disturbed.
Scott: It is not.
Scott: that's why it can't rest.
Scott: Right?
Scott: It's angry right, you know Someone was mistreated in this area somebody, you know They're whole had a life story like such-and-such and then they died.
Scott: and you know There's some connection to this place or this thing, right?
Scott: You know something like that and then you can either a resolve it, you know You appease the ghost so we can so we can pass on right?
Scott: Yeah be at peace.
Scott: or you you flee or destroy it or you know.
Scott: You got multiple endings to choose from.
Scott: you know, choose whichever one you like.
Scott: All right, that's ghost story 101.
Rym: now the other thing I really like about ghost stories though, is that if you take like historical ghost stories and legends and even like popular ghost stories, you can usually categorize them into like a Like.
Rym: there's a limited number of categories of ghosts that are pretty common and you can bucket almost all ghost stories into one of those categories But I'm particularly fascinated by the fact that many of those buckets Have a modern like recently discovered like physiological or psychological trigger like we can explain that kind of ghost story when someone Experienced it directly like when someone has the lived experience with a ghost event Like sleep paralysis is one like.
Rym: a lot of ghost stories boil down to the symptoms of experiencing sleep paralysis specifically Right.
Scott: So somebody at some point in history had sleep paralysis.
Scott: They suffered from it and their explanation from it for it.
Scott: not knowing what sleep paralysis was They said I woke up at night and it couldn't move and I heard noises and I was definitely oh my god It was hot Scott.
Rym: You realize it's worse than that.
Rym: Did you ever experience sleep paralysis or no?
Rym: Thank God No, I've read about it's way creepier than you think.
Rym: it's not just.
Rym: you wake up and can't move.
Rym: you wake up and can't move And many times like the majority of the times you will sense a presence Floating over you and sometimes even see like a shadow shaped like a person Floating over you or someone standing at the foot of your bed.
Rym: It's that specific in its psychological and physiological effects And and you'll also feel a physical has the pressure on your chest that has a physiological cause.
Rym: So if you experience that and and you go to a doctor of your time and the doctor says fuck if I know Nothing that must have been a ghost.
Rym: I can't explain that.
Rym: Can't fault that person for believing in ghosts.
Scott: No, we can't.
Scott: you really can't right.
Scott: but now we know a sleep paralysis.
Rym: Yep Or like in for sound was another one.
Rym: like that unexplained feeling of dread.
Rym: people would get in places where there were certain loo Like really low frequencies.
Rym: There's or ghost orbs that early photographers would talk about and idiot nerds today Still talk about that are literally just.
Rym: they don't know how flashes work and they got a bunch of dust.
Scott: or you know Straight-up illusions, right?
Scott: You know mentalists are very good at getting people to believe that you know the ghost of their loved one is nearby right.
Scott: using various mentalist tricks and seances and those sorts of things are very good at tricking people into like Thinking there's an actual ghost right there by using, you know, technology that creates imagery.
Scott: You know, you can go to the haunted house in Disney World and see ghosts and I didn't know that that was just a you know, a trick of mirrors and light or be like
Rym: One time in high school, I actually remember I was out I was out in the woods.
Rym: It's like haunted mansion haunted mansion.
Rym: Yeah, I was out in the woods just biking like.
Rym: that's what I do a lot at night.
Rym: There was like a biking trail through the woods I would bike through in the middle of the night.
Rym: That was just a thing I would do.
Rym: and I remember one time I was like biking over toward this place to bike around a bit and then meet some kids.
Rym: we're gonna Hang out.
Rym: and I saw like this Very clear like orb of light just come down from the sky into the woods and I was like what the fuck was that?
Rym: And of course, I'm gonna go straight in to figure like go find that like I'm not just gonna let that go.
Scott: Someone on a helicopter drop the flashlight.
Rym: Yeah, I know.
Rym: long story short I eventually figured out that there's there's a pond like kind of like in that area in the woods and I went over there Car a car's headlight reflected off cars headlight Reflected like just the right way and made it look like that.
Rym: because while I was there it happened again And I figured it out and I was like, okay Because the one thing about all the spooky stuff is that like James ready would often also say I wish this stuff were real like Yes, yes and no, right.
Scott: Well, yeah, cuz I do wish it was real because I want to come back and haunt some people But I don't wish it's real because they don't want to get haunted.
Rym: Yep Well, like see our friends go Joe would always say if you just find one thing like you find one vampire Nothing's off the table anymore.
Rym: That's true Fact that we've never found even one is very telling.
Scott: but uh, yeah, so I guess the last thing right is that.
Scott: Well, I'm not the last thing but so because ghosts don't have this like sort of clear definition, right?
Rym: Yeah, not like where we're all.
Rym: like everyone knows the rules or vampires or everyone knows the rules Everything.
Scott: it's almost like every haunted thing in the world That isn't clearly a vampire a mummy a monster, you know, whatever is a ghost.
Scott: It's like this catch-all of them all.
Scott: You know evil things right that that are haunt and horror that aren't you know?
Scott: Visible and corporeal and there they are.
Scott: I can see it and define it is goes goes to just like this Yes, catch all hate I hate has gotten you Sure, you know actually that that makes me obviously different cultures and languages have a lot of different views and I'm not Educated.
Rym: Yeah, well like Japanese ghost stories very very different from American ghost stories American Southern ghost stories are like this particular genre of ghost story.
Rym: But actually I realized another thing about ghost stories that plays off of what you just said.
Rym: I only realized this just now.
Rym: a trope of a lot of good ghost stories Is that in the course of the story?
Rym: Either the person telling the story because they're telling it quote from memory or like the characters Are trying to figure out the rules of the ghost because there are no preconceived rules.
Scott: No, it's all dependent.
Scott: It's dependent on that Discovery of why the spirits are angry.
Scott: It's like ah now we under now we understand this ghost, right?
Scott: This ghost is is such-and-such right but like.
Rym: It's like oh, it's a vampire.
Rym: All right garlic don't invite him in whatever werewolf.
Rym: There's no werewolf movie where people like figure out that silver is the way to get rid of the vampire Or the werewolf.
Scott: It's like right.
Scott: It's like oh, this is a ghost who you know, their boss treated them poorly.
Scott: We need to.
Scott: we need to murder the boss, right?
Scott: Still alive somewhere so the spirit can be at peace right?
Scott: or oh, this is a spirit of somebody Who is an evil person?
Scott: Right, and I guess you know, they can't move on.
Scott: They don't want to go to hell Come up with you know, whatever.
Scott: but that that circumstance of the ghost is gonna change the rules of how you deal with it.
Rym: Mm-hmm And I was about to say we were talking about with like we did the werewolf show.
Rym: Werewolves come go through this cycle of like scary werewolves sexy werewolves.
Rym: werewolves really aren't in pop culture.
Rym: Just like all monsters do.
Rym: Have there been sexy ghosts again since the movie ghost?
Rym: Was that the last time goes?
Scott: I think I mean I. I don't think ghosts occupy all the different categories But you know cute and friendly ghost has always been a thing.
Scott: Definitely.
Rym: I mean Casper is a really really old intellectual property.
Scott: Yeah, you got you got boo that my favorite.
Rym: who is not friendly?
Scott: He is.
Rym: no he's not he's dangerous.
Scott: If you just look at him and he goes.
Scott: Oh, no, it closes eyes.
Rym: Yeah, then you look away and he fucking works you.
Scott: Yeah, don't look away.
Scott: Look at the cute ghost It's not that hard.
Rym: But yeah, well ghost and the unfortunate ghost blowjob from the deleted plot from Ghostbusters I guess spirit phone with your fuzzy, man.
Scott: Yeah, well, yeah Ghostbusters is a good one, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, every time Ghostbusters go they're dealing with something different, right?
Scott: You know Slimer is a ghost but he's like a green slime thing.
Scott: Same lines beetle juice of Marsha for the space off marshmallow.
Scott: man's a ghost but he's like covering this.
Scott: You know, it was on different beetle juice is a ghost.
Rym: that that whole movie is about ghosts.
Scott: Yeah, and that movie is literally about the rules of ghosts and that's a corporeal ghost.
Scott: Yeah, those like you can't see him sometimes right?
Rym: Well, he's corporeal, but the other ones really aren't.
Scott: Sort of are but they're just like they're not always.
Scott: they're not always corporeal.
Scott: But you know the boys are still dead.
Scott: there's still dead people right true better at unrest.
Scott: So they can't carry on.
Scott: so that you know some other, you know, wherever this op-ed points out They boo does not help your argument He's the king of booze.
Scott: He's not afraid anymore.
Rym: But you know, I'm thinking about this to you that we were talking about Like.
Rym: if you find one goes then like the floodgates are open.
Rym: But how that could be a bad thing.
Rym: think about like beetlejuice and Ghostbusters.
Rym: both of those imply They're very like love crafty and existential horror Like Ghostbusters.
Rym: basically is a world where these four schmucks figure out that the cosmic horrors of space literally exist in the form of ghosts?
Scott: Yeah, pretty much Beetlejuice.
Scott: the afterlife is a ghostbusters ghosts, right?
Scott: The Ghostbusters ghosts for the most part are not.
Scott: I Think some of them are represented.
Scott: It's not like Ghostbusters tried that hard in this.
Scott: Yeah in this regards or I have making their mythology Consist including
Rym: the cartoon -
Scott: but yes some of the ghosts and Ghostbusters Clearly like there's the librarian ghost is the ghost of like a dead library
Rym: or the electrocuted guy in the first in the opening scenes of Ghostbusters -
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: That's a yeah.
Rym: Most of them are like these jogging existential horrors that came from like Slimer.
Scott: Slimer isn't like someone's dead pet.
Scott: That was a mess.
Scott: Slimer is some you know, I might have just been a really gross, dude It could have been but it's probably I think.
Rym: but that little blue thing with Cordian neck and the big ears that thing wasn't a person.
Scott: No wasn't not enough not in a it didn't have a previous life It's always goes.
Scott: So I guess uh, just one brief final thing is you know The aesthetic of a ghost right at the person wearing a sheet?
Scott: and I just got to say I really like that Aesthetic of just like this sort of white, you know, not that not because it's white It just just the image like a pac-man ghost right?
Scott: Those aren't white Like Charlie Brown where it is ghost costume Exactly like that aesthetic is like.
Scott: I just like it.
Scott: It's nice.
Rym: Yeah I like the Japanese one to like.
Rym: remember in the episode of Captain Tyler where?
Rym: The ghosts are all around and he's dressed like a ghost and there's that whole plot.
Scott: Far I don't know.
Rym: No, you did.
Rym: You just don't remember you.
Rym: I think you fell asleep.
Rym: That was the last episode we had at RIT.
Rym: We were watching it in my dorm room and I remember you fell asleep and everyone else was watching so you didn't see that episode.
Scott: But yeah, but you know just the aesthetic of the classic ghost imagery.
Scott: you go to the Halloween store and you're like, you know You got like a string of ghosts on like a garland to hang on your door your side of your house or something.
Scott: Yeah, miss lights or in a tree, you know, it's like.
Scott: I like that action.
Scott: That's you know.
Scott: Yeah, it's looks it's bad.
Scott: Like it's better imagery than like, you know that.
Scott: or jack-o'-lantern?
Rym: Yeah, but what about all the Scooby-doo ghosts even though they're all fake and they're all just mirrors and projectors somehow?
Scott: Yeah, I mean skeletons also obviously way up there.
Scott: All right, it's pretty much skeleton and ghosts.
Scott: Those are the top two.
Rym: Mm-hmm I don't think we need to do a show on skeletons though Haven't we?
Rym: if we haven't This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays Night's is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, how do you nickel mario greenia Graham Finch?
Rym: You'll be key to my heart.
Rym: I wasn't for a cab and when it came near Clinton Walton J Bandsmen from New Zealand around parent Chris midkip dread Lily Tenebrae just like a dude guy Chris Reimer Finn Sherman von Horl and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: Yeah, hopefully the you tennis show when we get it up doesn't get copyrighted down considering what's all going on.
Rym: but anyway for now I leave you with Oh.