Rym: It's Wednesday July 8th 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We're talking about that studio trigger Netflix anime BNA.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: I Gotta say though, uh, we're watching Kipo kind of at the same time like that that Like kids show about the post apocalypse.
Rym: I've talked about a gig nights before in Kipo.
Rym: There's like Multiple points where different characters end up in a situation where they have one big beefy arm but like nothing else is weird about them like a normal looking character with one gigantic trogdor arm that happens like enough to where it's a thing in that show and then we watch some BNA and One big beefy arm happens in BNA multiple times as well
Scott: Happened so many times.
Rym: Yep And in the mini recent season of Rick and Morty one beefy arm is actually the like B plot of an entire episode.
Rym: I feel like if your thing is one big beefy arm 2019 to 2020 might be your time.
Scott: What other instances can I think of of the the one beefy arm?
Rym: I guess though is my dog like trogdor?
Scott: Yeah, truck door.
Scott: so far I've got trogdor like three different characters in Kipo bunch of characters in BNA and character in on x-factor in the 90s who is like whose mutant power was just like being like super muscle for like beyond any point of.
Rym: That made sense, but only in one arm.
Scott: No, I think it was pretty much like his whole upper body a tiny legs, but that's just.
Rym: it was like it was like bad.
Scott: It was too little tiny.
Scott: What was that guy's name?
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: I'll look it up.
Rym: Well, it feels like a documentary of just people who skip leg day.
Rym: So I do have an opening bit.
Rym: Oh, his name was literally strong guy Really running out of ideas there for your superheroes.
Rym: Strong guy?
Scott: His first appearance was in New Mutants in 1985.
Rym: Okay, actually strong guy just feels like Venture Brothers with a brick frog.
Rym: So I uh the other day I Ate a food that I have not eaten in more than a decade.
Rym: I cannot remember the last time I ate this food.
Rym: I believe it was while we were at RIT still but okay I got a package of a bunch.
Rym: was it?
Scott: was it a?
Scott: was it the the the Barrens frozen pizza?
Rym: Oh, no No, no, it is not that it was in fact Cheetos.
Scott: Yeah, I don't eat that.
Rym: Yeah, I don't eat that either.
Rym: So when I was a kid though when I was a young kid like high school middle school I would eat like an entire family-sized bag of Cheetos by myself like watching TV.
Scott: I love Cheetos.
Rym: Okay, so obviously I do not particularly care for Cheetos anymore.
Rym: I have not eaten them in a long time.
Rym: But for because we can't like stop to eat out Especially previously in the earlier parts of COVID we had to bring like a lot of food and snacks with us.
Rym: So I bought a like Frito-Lay Box that just had a whole bunch of different like mini packages of various like Frito-Lay things.
Rym: It's a lot of like.
Scott: I bought a box of fig bars and also some stinger waffles.
Rym: I got those two stinger waffles.
Rym: That is the best-kept secret of bikers and runners.
Rym: Stinger waffle will keep you going.
Scott: I love those things But I'm glad I discovered them for free.
Rym: Yeah, I discovered them on the Harlem Valley rail ride.
Rym: I never had one before.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I I think I had one on one ride before that.
Rym: On that ride I remember I stopped and I was looking at the snack thing at the first rest stop and I saw that stinger waffle and I Was like honey waffle.
Rym: that sounds like it's up my alley and I ate it.
Rym: and then the next rest stop I grabbed like three and stuck them in my pocket.
Rym: Yeah, so but we got the snack pack and it's mostly like the stuff I wanted.
Rym: But there's four little bags of Cheetos in there.
Rym: I'm not just gonna throw them away.
Rym: and I was desperately hungry like right after a run the other day.
Rym: So I opened a bag of Cheetos and I ate a food that I have not eaten in over a decade.
Rym: and all I got To say about Cheetos.
Rym: They are not good.
Rym: They are not great Like time-traveling.
Rym: Rym has to return to the year 1994 and smack that shit out of young rims hands.
Scott: good.
Scott: Well, first of all, we know that as you get older your taste buds change and I think that Effects.
Rym: maybe my taste bud my adult taste buds just can't handle the extreme power of Cheetos, right?
Scott: It's like I'll make.
Scott: I'll make fun of adults who are like you onion.
Scott: Yeah But I won't make fun of children.
Scott: who are you onion?
Scott: because I remembered that when I was a kid if I would like put An onion in my mouth.
Scott: It was like ah, right because I kid lively taste buds.
Scott: Whereas now I'm like onion.
Scott: Oh, right.
Rym: Oh now I'm a little bit like George Costanza.
Rym: Like I'll eat onion raw like while I'm cooking I'll just like I'll bite into an apple.
Scott: Yeah, bite into an apple like an onion like a apple.
Rym: I almost said bite into an apple like it's an onion.
Scott: I'll do that, too.
Rym: but Cheetos That is a sad food to have in your body because it tastes fake.
Rym: and then when I actually finished eating the Cheetos It felt like I just had like star foam peanuts in my stomach.
Rym: It was just a bad experience all around.
Rym: I give cheetah Adult Rym gives Cheetos two stars because one star is reserved for that big boy on the New York State Thruway.
Rym: That was the worst meal I've ever eaten on purpose in my entire life.
Rym: I will never forget that I've eaten worse things but not on purpose.
Rym: Okay, I chose that food.
Rym: Anyway, I got some news.
Rym: It is a Animation and comic day after all.
Scott: Yeah, I do have a news.
Scott: What was it?
Scott: I sent it to you.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So a comic that has been gone since.
Scott: when did it go away?
Scott: the 90s?
Scott: Right.
Scott: When did it run?
Scott: 95 Wow.
Rym: Oh, we are family.
Rym: We were obsessed with the far side.
Rym: We bought every like compilation book as they came out like we had them all in the library.
Scott: So when I was a kid 80s 90s, right newspaper comic strip was a thing.
Scott: it's still kind of a thing, but it you you know, it.
Scott: basically it dwindled as I was reading them right as Comics became available in other mediums, especially the webcomic and people start reading the newspaper.
Scott: Yeah pretty much killed this newspaper comic.
Rym: at the same time a lot of good which is ever comics either change like Their process or got worse or like the selection started changing before even before newspaper comic as a whole was dying And newspapers were still a thing.
Scott: They were constantly being you know shrunken.
Scott: right, you know, you look at like early.
Scott: I got over there.
Scott: I got a collection of all these early Frickin Prince Valiance.
Scott: each one of them is a full newspaper page.
Scott: They're enormous, right?
Scott: The books are enormous.
Scott: I'll bring one over.
Rym: if there wasn't audio podcast I got him all over in the bedroom right now.
Rym: But as a kid, right the far side Was amazing because I didn't have modern internet and the far side was like the weird Absurdist humor that it turns out is my favorite kind of humor as an adult.
Scott: Yep There was not the other cotton, you know.
Scott: You would read the newspaper comics and a lot of them were pretty much just like Hallmark card fodder.
Scott: Yeah, you know and you know some of them had something special going on with them.
Scott: Right and those ones are always obvious and stood out and the far side was one of those like far side Calvin and Hobbes.
Rym: Foxtrot like there was like the sub.
Scott: soxtrot was still sort of Hallmark II.
Rym: Foxtrot was The best of the Hallmark II was like I was.
Scott: it was nerdy Hallmark.
Rym: It wasn't really anything creeped in a little bit because I remembered is always like.
Rym: the fact that there was nerdy stuff in that Comic made me read it.
Rym: So I don't really begrudge nerds who get really into something because it speaks to them that way Hmm.
Scott: Hey, but anyway So, yeah, so since 1995 Gary Larson unlike, you know the creator of Calvin Hobbes Who's been hiding somewhere in Ohio in the woods?
Scott: I don't know where you know and people go to find him like a like these the frickin.
Scott: Gary Larson isn't dead or hiding.
Scott: He just wasn't cartooning.
Scott: Yep, right and you know.
Scott: and but now suddenly right Eve after you know 20 plus years of webcomics right He's given in and he's producing a digital comic.
Scott: you can tell he's digitally coloring it just by looking at it.
Rym: Did you read the thing where you talked about like how he reads like?
Rym: Started to learn digital process and how much he loved it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, once you learn that computers are awesome.
Rym: Yeah, it was like, you know, I felt like it was too hard in the old days But I wanted to see how far the technology progressed.
Rym: I'm super paraphrasing because I read this whole interview with him.
Rym: It was very recent.
Rym: and then he was like I got out my pen But my pen sucked and he just bitched a while about how pen sucked.
Rym: and then he was like, I saw I got a tablet.
Rym: I figured I'd try it out and it changed my life.
Rym: It made comics fun again.
Rym: Oh my god, like he talked about it.
Rym: the way we talked about Python when Python emerged In terms of making also something spinner her for 20 plus.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, so yeah the far all.
Scott: Gary Larson is back to cartooning.
Scott: He released three comics yesterday.
Scott: They're right.
Rym: They're not their far side.
Scott: I would not.
Scott: yeah, I mean they're far side.
Scott: ish right single panel Absurdist kind of things.
Scott: you can see the joke in them, but they're not.
Scott: laugh out loud funny They're not.
Scott: if you put them in with the existing far side It's it.
Scott: they would not rank highly.
Scott: I don't think they would.
Rym: they would fit in though They're about that level because I've always liked the far side.
Rym: But the far side was basically superseded by the dada esque nightmare escape of comedy that has arisen since on the internet.
Scott: Exactly, right.
Scott: So and I say nightmare escape with love You know, so it's like we have all these amazing, you know, it's great that comics are no longer being, you know held back by You know publishers and newspapers deciding what gets you know out there and what doesn't.
Scott: that's amazing You know.
Scott: and it's it's great that all the you know, the small time webcomic people have a platform because I love all their shit.
Scott: You know, we have things like webtoon which seems to publish anything that anyone asked them to.
Scott: You know and anyone can make a website and throw it.
Scott: or do you just put their comic on Twitter?
Scott: You don't even need a website.
Scott: But you know, it's also great to have you know old people come back to right?
Scott: It's like let's have.
Scott: you know You know, there's room for everything.
Scott: So, you know having the whole space dominated by the awesome young people is great.
Scott: But you know, we'll have room for one old guy.
Rym: one old guy is the one I'm always excited when someone like rediscovers their art that they'd sort of semi-retired from for reasons Right.
Scott: It's also, you know, I think at one point, you know New York likes to put these different like signs up in the in the city that are just like not necessarily advertisements just sort of like inspirational posters.
Scott: occasionally you'll see I remember ones ones that were like Beethoven.
Scott: he didn't compose shit till he was like 80 or something, right?
Scott: And it's like.
Scott: I don't know how true that is.
Rym: But well, I think a lot of the kind of Monte Cristo was in his 40s before he can do his stride, right?
Scott: It was something like that.
Scott: So it's sort of like, you know, Gary Larson holds that dude.
Scott: He's got to be way old, right?
Rym: It's I actually don't know.
Rym: I don't.
Rym: I've never said I don't even know what he looks like, but I've read nice Nice.
Scott: Yeah, so if 69 year old Gary Larson can make his first webcomic And you are less than 69, right?
Scott: You got a long way to go.
Scott: Don't worry about starting late in life, right?
Rym: Yep So, uh some other news.
Rym: we I enjoy slayers like the anime I've seen I think every slayers OAV and I've only seen the TV show up through try and Scott's only seemed up through.
Rym: next like we you mean Emily we're gonna watch.
Rym: try and we got distracted never really like did it?
Scott: I have the TV also watched two episodes of some other slayer.
Rym: Oh, we watched the revolution Yeah, where the where the weird thing shows up and can also cast dragon slave and then we didn't.
Rym: yeah watch it further I think because it was hard to get episodes like there was something up with it.
Rym: This was a long time No, is it available?
Rym: Probably but you should watch.
Rym: try first like stay in order to rewatch the regular sleep.
Scott: I can rewatch regular slayers As it is a random side note, right?
Scott: So, you know occasionally I've been watching the the link to the past randomizer, right?
Scott: so one of the top players of the link to the past randomizer is somebody whose internet name is Zalgadus son, right?
Scott: So so and it's he doesn't put a space or a hyphen in it or anything.
Scott: It's just like Zalgadus on right?
Scott: So I'm like that person's a slayers fan and I went to their stream and asked them and yeah There's a big time slayer someone who is like noting the honorific.
Rym: That's like someone's like.
Rym: So.
Scott: the one I want to make though is it's hilarious that whatever Zalgadus on is racing and there's like commentators on like a restream.
Rym: There's like always on like they don't get.
Scott: oh They'll just be like Zalga or Zalga Disson or my god, right?
Scott: They think they see.
Scott: it is all one word.
Scott: They don't know.
Scott: so I went to the Zalga's channel to confirm.
Scott: and indeed huge slayers fan, you know That's one thing.
Scott: and also chill dude.
Rym: as far as I can tell Esports commentators are starting to do correctly now.
Rym: I've noticed similar to our real sports like I don't want to say real sports But you know what?
Rym: I mean like an NHL commentator.
Rym: They have like.
Rym: there is an official cheat sheet you have if you're a commentator in a professional sport.
Rym: That is like any name you might have to say.
Rym: here is the phonetic Like how to say it in case you have to say it on air.
Rym: so it's consistent.
Rym: So they don't mess that up that often Esports are doing the same thing with the handles of these characters for obvious reasons.
Rym: I feel like the streaming commentary people.
Rym: that is a very easy thing.
Rym: They could do when they're commenting on streams is ask someone how to pronounce their screen name in advance.
Rym: Otherwise you're gonna get rhyme and a pretch a doing their podcast.
Scott: I Mean my my name intentionally doesn't have a correct pronunciation.
Rym: Yeah, I do know that There are.
Scott: there are.
Scott: you could make various arguments for different ones But I will not officially deem any one of them all wrong and all right Simultaneous in a distant future.
Rym: the Wikipedia article has a section.
Rym: It's unclear whether or not there was a canonical pronunciation of Scott Scott's ground.
Scott: There's a whole section pronouncing Scott's pronouncing Scott's stage name.
Rym: However the fuck you want The question will be in our old age.
Rym: is that section by itself or is that section in a controversy section about us?
Rym: But I'm pretty pumped to read these novels because I've read Segments from them that fans had translated in the past and from what everyone who has read them in Japanese has said.
Rym: the slayers TV show Is super fun and but it's also like it's.
Rym: it's kind of a shonen fighting show That's just hidden like it's buried in many layers.
Rym: It has a lot more.
Scott: it has a lot more comedy going on than other.
Rym: Yes, but it also gets like serious and a weird like we've reviewed slayers in the past.
Rym: Everyone says that the novels are just faster and denser versions of that.
Rym: It's just pop up up go go go like joke a minute.
Rym: Just everyone loves these novels from what I can visual.
Scott: You know those.
Scott: I don't know if they're visual novels or not, but yeah, they're light novels.
Scott: Okay, yeah light novels are short yep and fast.
Rym: so so they're all getting published in English by J Novel Club.
Rym: that was just announced like a little while ago.
Rym: the release is coming in next year.
Rym: in July So July 2021 we can read the first omnibus volume of the slayers novels And they're gonna come out at a pretty good clip after that.
Rym: Cool in some other brief news as you know where there won't be really any conventions this year that are in person But there's gonna be a bunch of conventions online.
Rym: It is highly likely we'll be doing a panel or two at the crunchyroll Expo Which is coming up in early September.
Rym: so keep an eye out for that.
Rym: I don't think that like they haven't published a lot of details about exactly what's gonna happen at the convention yet But the websites up.
Rym: like if you're a nerd who thinks you have a panel to submit like they have all those normal channels There's a very good chance.
Rym: We will be presenting there as well as that packs online I think we talked about in the last show.
Rym: if you are the kind of person Who thinks you can do the kind of things we do like you have something to say about anime or something to say.
Scott: All you gotta do is is push a record button on whatever camera you got.
Scott: your phone is good enough your webcams good enough And then talk about a nerdy thing that you are an expert on.
Scott: if you're a nerd You just got to be something you know a lot about.
Rym: so maybe you watch Maybe you read the entirety of Cromartie, and you figured out some like massive Reading of Cromartie the manga that no one is expressed before and you want to talk about the allegory and nuance of that manga.
Scott: Or maybe you're even just a such a mainstream nerd right.
Scott: It's like you watch Star Wars, and you play some triple-a video game.
Scott: It's like well you play the triple-a video game a whole bunch you better.
Scott: You should probably know a lot about it right which means you should be able to talk about it for like an hour.
Scott: boom Done you got your panel.
Rym: Yeah, here's an idea.
Rym: say you're mainly not an anime fan like you.
Rym: don't go to anime cons But you watch a lot of anime.
Rym: like there are a lot of people who watch a lot of anime would never Self-identify as an anime fan.
Rym: anime is just something they watch.
Rym: I could see a panel being someone like that Just saying like talking about how that fan experience is because a lot of weebs and people like us who are really into the anime We have particular and peculiar tastes.
Rym: sometimes like anime fandom is not Really like what most people who watch anime are like in America.
Rym: I could see that being a cool panel, but it's virtual.
Rym: It's online.
Rym: now's your chance.
Rym: if you've always wanted to do a panel at a con But you couldn't fly out you get stage fright.
Rym: You can make a million takes.
Rym: you can edit your panel if you need to.
Rym: there's a lot of ways to go here.
Rym: Oh, yeah Good times But anyway things of the day, so this is a pretty cool video.
Rym: It's only about two minutes long.
Rym: It's colorized.
Rym: It wasn't filmed in color obviously, but it was colorized with some decent nuance.
Rym: This is just some film footage like candid street film footage of Tokyo around 1913 through 1915. over a hundred years ago, and this is very similar.
Rym: I had a thing of the day a long time ago.
Rym: That was basically a similar thing for New York City from the same time period.
Rym: This is really fascinating to watch because there is in many ways very little difference between how people react to a camera in Tokyo in 1913 and how people react to a camera on the streets of New York City in 1913 right down to a little kid like adults trying to like not look at the camera because they understand what's going on and kids Running over to the camera and jumping up and down and like making a ruckus.
Rym: It's a pretty good video.
Scott: It's pretty cool Alright, so we got so as someone who has owned the entirety of the Akira manga twice Might own it again.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: Is watch the movie several times and all of its different mastered editions, right?
Scott: pretty much, you know everything short of Getting all the Japanese merchandise that was made when I was like, you know less than 10 years old Right, I was not aware of this video.
Scott: that who knows when this video was originally You know made available to the public but it's been online on YouTube since 2017 and I just didn't know about it.
Scott: It's Right.
Scott: Yeah, so but you know, it only has 2.3 K up votes.
Scott: I don't know why it has 12 down votes.
Scott: It only has 53,000 views.
Scott: The point is this is a video From the studio where they were making a Kara.
Scott: you are watching in this video.
Scott: They're painting the backgrounds for the movie.
Scott: They are drawing the cells.
Scott: They are photographing the cells, right?
Scott: There's a. there's a Japanese narrator, but it's been dubbed over in English.
Scott: So the Japanese narration a volume is very quiet and you can't really hear it.
Scott: Not that I could understand it anyway, but the English narrator is obviously Greatly simplifying what the the original narration was.
Rym: this feels very similar to the footage you get if you watch The reluctant dragon from Disney, right?
Scott: But it really doesn't matter what the narrator is saying.
Scott: it's.
Scott: you can see here what it looked like when they were making this movie.
Scott: You know and if people don't know, you know about some of the production details Of Akira the movie right.
Scott: not only did it cost a fortune for the time, right?
Scott: And it got delayed a whole bunch I think and it forced the manga to get delayed because Otomo is working on this instead and such and such.
Scott: but I had heard that it was animated on the ones for the entire movie, right?
Scott: Which means that they drew 24 pictures for every second of animation.
Scott: But in this video it shows them right Photographing cells and when they push the advanced button right for the film.
Scott: You can see the counter goes up by two right and animating on the twos is still Amazing, right?
Scott: Usually things are animated like the threes.
Rym: or well Reddit thread where there's a long debate about whether or not it was on the ones or two.
Scott: Well, here's a video where clearly they advance that frame by two, right?
Scott: I think that's indisputable.
Scott: The number goes up by two on the on the counter, right?
Scott: regardless.
Scott: It also talks about just the absurd number of different colors of paint that were used To make Akira and you can see here.
Scott: Everyone knows the backgrounds in Akira.
Scott: We're always astonishing right especially the city the cityscapes and you can see here the dude with the gold paint and the paintbrush Putting dots right using a special tool to keep the dots in a straight line right to put the the windows on the faraway skyscrapers Right and it's like yeah, this is why no one does this anymore But you can at least there we eat now have we have video footage showing how it was done.
Scott: It wasn't some trick.
Scott: Go watch Akira.
Scott: if you haven't seen it what's wrong with you?
Rym: I can watch Akira again, it's been a while.
Scott: I can watch it again every day.
Rym: Akira is definitely it's.
Rym: it's on that list of movies.
Rym: I Would just probably watch to the end if I started watching any part of it.
Rym: Sure All right in the better moment.
Rym: We're stuck at home.
Rym: We can't do a lot.
Rym: We'll be at some online cons.
Rym: like I said Follow our youtubes you'll see stuff We're working on.
Rym: we're at some point gonna read the tale of Genji But we're not reading a lot right now because we don't have any travel where we would normally read.
Scott: Yeah, read some slayers novels instead.
Rym: Why don't you starting in a year which we'll see if we're still in a quarantine by then considering the way the u.s.
Rym: Is going?
Rym: Oh I'm already looking at not going back to my office until early 2022.
Scott: So yeah, they said for me I will not be forced to go back to the office until mid-september and then after that is question mark, right?
Rym: Yeah, we have.
Rym: we have an September.
Scott: we have like an opt-in where people you can actually like Yeah, you I could if I wanted to have asked and gone back to my office like now ish But they posted a video of like the protocols for going back to the office.
Rym: There's a whole onerous thing.
Rym: Like if you want to go back to the office now was like.
Scott: no It's like.
Scott: it's like why bother?
Scott: what's if no one else's in my coat?
Scott: my team people on my team aren't all gonna be there.
Scott: Then what's the benefit?
Scott: Why should I go through the hassle?
Rym: Yeah, instead I'll be instead of being at a video call from my comfy house I'll be on a video call wearing a mask from an office with other people who are in their comfy houses.
Scott: Yeah, no point.
Rym: Yeah, but I basically I told The people the powers that be that I'm unwilling to return to any office until I get a vaccine Mmm, so that that pushes my date out pretty far and we'll see how things go.
Rym: but uh, yeah, we're making stuff as best we can.
Rym: follow our YouTube channels stay tuned for stuff and let's get right into it.
Rym: BNA is One of those hot new anime.
Scott: I think we talked about it Maybe when it was announced as a news on the show But yeah, definitely talked about it as a news studio studio triggers.
Scott: newest TV show is on Netflix in the u.s Season 1. it's 12 episodes.
Scott: It's called BNA brand.
Scott: It's basically yeah.
Scott: DNA only replace the D with B for beasts.
Scott: Yeah, cuz it's another furry show just like be stars.
Rym: Yeah, Netflix seems to love these and keep o goes out to this.
Scott: is the air just like worries Just like be stars.
Scott: the main character is well, not the main character.
Scott: Actually.
Scott: The second main character is a wolf, dude.
Rym: Yep Our main characters are basically an awesome wolf dude a kitsune a Tanuki and some other things.
Rym: I'm not gonna spoil right?
Scott: So it's studio trigger, you know The people who brought you such for no cop as promare Kill la kill.
Scott: Yeah, a little witch academia, etc.
Scott: This one.
Scott: you can still see a lot of the typical studio trigger Tropes in this show.
Rym: Specific thing that the the gold or white star that appears over things during effect is like all over this thing.
Rym: That's like triggers signature at this point.
Scott: You can see a lot of there.
Scott: There's there.
Scott: it's all over the show.
Rym: I mean inferno can tell you in BNA.
Scott: Yeah, you could just tell that this is a studio trigger show by watching it.
Scott: But the extreme crazy power level right.
Scott: the trigger ometer is lower, right?
Scott: I think I'm promare.
Scott: The trigger ometer is like a full-on turn up to 11.
Scott: Yeah, right and kill la kill.
Rym: It's at like 9 right like six and a half seven on the trigger scale.
Scott: Yeah, right a little like academia.
Scott: It's even lower.
Scott: It's maybe like four or three, right?
Rym: But I guess what I hear.
Scott: it's like five six ish area.
Rym: Like they say kill la kill was just fucking.
Rym: let's go crazy crazy crazy.
Rym: What the fuck is going on.
Rym: promare was that times a million?
Rym: This is more like a Normal anime but like the kind of anime that I was really into when I was getting into anime like the kind of show that I just love.
Rym: but instead of just being Trigger to 11 the entire time it has it's like trigger at six or seven the entire time.
Rym: But individual scenes or episodes will approach the ten trigger scale, right?
Scott: Well, yeah, I think the baseball episode is the most studio trigger Because the baseball episode in certain climax moments of the plot that base the the baseball episode was Extremely a lot like in kill la kill with all the different sports teams, right?
Scott: final the final sports team with like the like the kill II like the bat that explodes and throws shards and Right and and also the catcher on the baseball team the little tiny bear of the little tiny bear is basically Mako Vakanchoku from kill la kill.
Rym: it's the same character living in the poor part of town.
Scott: I wouldn't yeah, I wouldn't be surprised if it was the same voice actor It's the same personality and that character shows up in the baseball episode and then recurs.
Scott: Yeah throughout the rest of this.
Rym: I got a question for you Which of the Bears was your favorite one?
Rym: Was it that one?
Scott: Cuz I mean, I don't really remember the other ones they stood out in my mind.
Rym: There's one that makes this blank face the whole time and there's one who always has his tongue hanging out and it's a tie between Those two for my favorite bear.
Scott: Yeah, the other ones aren't memorable because they don't have names and they don't recur.
Scott: It's only that one the tiny one.
Rym: I like the flamingos - they felt a lot like a mini boss in kill la kill.
Scott: Yeah, they gave the flamingos more.
Scott: I think more screen time and personality than the other Evil baseball team.
Scott: Yeah in that episode Alright, so BNA.
Scott: What the hell is this show about?
Scott: Don't worry about oil anything.
Rym: It's only 12 episodes.
Rym: Just fucking watch it like right?
Scott: It's about Furries, right and it's up.
Scott: It's also.
Rym: it's also about racism X-men.
Rym: Yeah and X-men There's a world.
Scott: some people in the world are humans.
Scott: Some people are beast people.
Scott: beast people are Furries.
Rym: Yeah People it's like a man.
Rym: Oh, they transform world like history books.
Rym: Talk about beast men the whole time.
Scott: All right, they can transform between a human form and a beast form But they're inherently different like species of homo sapien, but there's still sentient people.
Scott: They're just beast people.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: They're just not cute.
Scott: They're just not homo sapiens and they're persecuted by society.
Scott: And so at least in Japan the beast men have the option of going to this city.
Scott: That's been around for 10 years only.
Scott: it's a new city where the beast men can escape and live nominally only with other beast men and Therefore be free to be beast men, but not persecuted within basically a ghetto.
Scott: Yes, exactly, right?
Scott: It's like there's no internet there, right?
Rym: So it's like here you want others of the people who created the city like there's questionable things going on.
Scott: It's a lot like genosha and x-men.
Scott: It's like all you mutants go or you know, whatever.
Scott: It's like okay all you people who are different can go live in this other place and therefore you won't have to face You know direct persecution from people of you know Because you won't see humans.
Scott: They're not there.
Scott: There's no humans living there But your entire city is walled off, you know gets shitty supplies.
Scott: people are living in poverty Right, you know, so you're still facing this sort of systemic persecution from the rest of the world, right?
Scott: There was there's a. there was talk about like bird beast people having trouble like migrating.
Scott: Yeah Sport now right exactly that sort of thing is going on.
Rym: And if the transfer bit like the characters the cool thing is what they sort of transform based on emotion and just whatever they're up To like.
Rym: they're usually human by default But they'll sort of turn into the animal depending on what they're up to and they'll turn into varying degrees of that animal.
Scott: Yep, so what's going on in this?
Scott: the plot the plot is pretty simple.
Scott: There is a human girl who is the main character who became a beast person like she was.
Rym: She was a straight normal human and she became a beast person and she doesn't know why and she's right.
Scott: that is not normal.
Scott: Everyone else is either born a beast person or born a person.
Scott: She was born a person and became a beast person a very strange Powered beast person.
Scott: and so to escape the persecution She runs to the beast people city and when she arrives there She just you know, you slow as the viewer you discover it more quickly than the characters that Shit in the beast city.
Scott: There's definitely crazy secret conspiracies going on where people people are up to new good.
Scott: There's a shady pharmaceutical company.
Scott: That's probably doing bad shit.
Scott: Yeah mayor looks like they're up to bad shit.
Scott: She's a shady.
Rym: She shows up with her goal of but there's like.
Rym: there's a Very clear story here.
Rym: if she shows up Looking to just be safe and look for a cure for being a beast man and slowly starts to come to like being a beast man And like start to integrate herself into the society.
Scott: Yep, there's a shady mafia.
Scott: that's up to no good.
Scott: Basically all these different factions of beast people.
Scott: There's a religion that's up to no good.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Scott: They're all mysteriously up to no good and the humans are obviously way up to way.
Rym: No, but if I had to review the show like in terms of like I really like it.
Rym: This is an a anime hands down.
Scott: It's pretty good.
Rym: It's not a plus.
Rym: That's super rare, but it's definitely an a anime.
Rym: I'd put it in the a-class.
Rym: but the things that make it good as one is animated so well, it looks beautiful.
Rym: It's very nice highly stylized but it makes a lot more sense than some parts of from air do like.
Rym: it is still grounded in like a Choreography in a real world to a degree.
Rym: It also makes uses color and shading like really effectively and to convey a bunch of interesting things and It moves quick.
Rym: It skips over the boring obvious misunderstanding plots and like things you think will take the whole show to get resolved are resolved like in the episode they're Introduced to move on to something else like things.
Scott: that is what I was surprised and pleased by that and that 12 episodes I thought it's like.
Scott: well I guess I'm gonna have to wait for a season two to uncover all these mysteries of the shady biz with the pharmaceutical company and Religion and the Mafia and the all those things.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: no they covered all those in season one.
Rym: like there's no like they're in The beginning.
Rym: there's like oh, there's a mystery of the silver wolf And it's pretty obvious to the viewer that most likely the wolf guy is the silver wolf like they foreshadowed that heavily.
Rym: But the episode where that gets resolved you'll learn what the silver wolf really is and in the same episode a whole bunch of characters Find this out or reveal that they knew the true story, and they all share that information, and then the show just moves on mm-hmm.
Rym: that is I Very refreshed.
Rym: anytime a show moves quick and skips misunderstanding plots.
Rym: That's basically my least favorite plot on earth.
Scott: Yep Let's see what else is going on in this show.
Scott: so oh that's another thing that they move on.
Scott: There's a mystery of the.
Scott: the main character had a friend a human friend from also turned into a beast person who also turned into a beast person and That friend is not present like all you know about them.
Scott: Is it like they were kidnapped or whatever?
Rym: and they show up like and it's a really interesting plot they that character.
Scott: Yeah, it's like the mystery of that.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: Oh is it is the.
Scott: is the friend gonna show up like at the end or something?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: no they show up kind of early on right not super early but they show up.
Rym: they show about it like around halfway through and That also progresses rapidly like that character and that character's arc really just keeps moving at a high pace mm-hmm.
Scott: So you know another thing about this show is that much like a lot of other recent studio trigger anime.
Scott: right it is Going down the gay road.
Rym: Oh, yeah, it is very clear that our main character and her friend There's there was definitely a like romantic attraction there.
Rym: that has.
Rym: I mean I'm trying not to spoil anything.
Scott: the shows only right much like I can kill a kill right.
Scott: It's like there was clearly something going on right in promare.
Scott: It was even more clear right.
Scott: and in BNA, I don't know It's like.
Scott: the only way they could make it more clear is to stop being cowards and make it explicit.
Scott: They always do that thing where it's like.
Scott: yeah, everyone can tell that they're gay.
Scott: There's no hetero relationships going on Right you know you can tell.
Scott: this person is only expressing feelings towards this same sex person same gendered person right.
Scott: Yet, they don't kiss.
Scott: They don't hug.
Scott: They don't actually say they don't.
Scott: you know make they don't do they don't fuck.
Scott: They don't do anything to make the gayness explicit right which is I think it's like.
Scott: on the one hand It's like it's like yay.
Scott: It's a gay show right a gay furry show.
Rym: That's like come on.
Scott: But on the other hand it's like you cowards right.
Scott: yeah, you're not doing it of course.
Rym: at the same time There is an argument to be made that by not just had like you don't have to have a relationship in every show Mmm.
Rym: That's true like there is the trope of shows like to just pair characters off and have relationships be like a Plot of the show alongside everything else.
Rym: so it is all.
Rym: it is a little refreshing.
Rym: that is not a primary plot But that is there.
Rym: Well if you want to hear more about that yeah Breakfast did a podcast about the the gay perspective on BNA.
Scott: yes We have gay friends Made a cup make a gay podcast called gay breakfast And they did an episode of BNA before us, and I'm sure if you listen to that It'll.
Scott: I haven't listened to their episode on it But I'm sure if you did it'll probably be the whole episode talking about pretty much what I just said among other things.
Rym: Though as an aside because I mentioned Kipo I'm not gonna spoil any details, but something very refreshing about that show because it's a kid show.
Rym: an arc starts in an episode where a female character Begins to profess that they like a male character like that typical arc and the male character is like yeah That's cool at all, but I'm gay.
Rym: He just says it like outright and the female character is like oh cool, and then they stay friends like that's it.
Rym: It's explicit it happens immediately the show just moves on and it was a very like refreshing moments for a kids show.
Scott: That's on mainstream TV Yeah, but I do want to point out though the last note about the gayness.
Scott: the gay factor right is that Kill la kill.
Scott: right was Yuri action.
Scott: Yeah, and pro mayor was gay action.
Scott: Yeah, right, and now we got your reaction again.
Rym: Whatever the next trigger show is And loving man here they come look for the M2m action coming back, but I guess the show like the show is a solid anime.
Rym: like the plot is Complex enough to be interesting in the same way that a lot of the anime I like are interesting.
Rym: one thing I noticed in particular.
Rym: I've seen everything, but the last four episodes at this point I watched the whole thing.
Rym: yeah I haven't seen the last four, but I'm I can see the trajectory of where this is going Especially once the history of the beast men and that clearly Byzantine story like Byzantine era story came from.
Scott: Basically the the the tropes of other trigger things right are are in full force.
Scott: It's like all the at.
Scott: the ending which you haven't seen is basically the same ending as other trigger things.
Scott: You know it's like you know and also they are.
Scott: they borrow heavily from other animes, right?
Rym: It's a very macross ending yeah, but whenever the mayor is talking to ogami the wolf They feel so much like when aramaki is talking to the major.
Rym: Yes, exactly like I am the person made the mayor has.
Scott: the mayor has some badass scenes.
Rym: Yeah, the mayor is Big aramaki energy Yep, and I also appreciate the power scales in the show.
Rym: like when there are fights like you know when there's a character Who is supposed to be more powerful than everyone else this show handles that really well.
Rym: the wolf guy is?
Rym: crazy powerful and Whenever that matters.
Rym: like there's a scene where like someone pulls a gun on him I think they spent one frame of animation on him disarming that person Like he moves so fast and is so powerful.
Rym: and the fight scenes in this show when there are fights are Really really dynamic and fun But they're not as abstract as like a promer fight scene.
Rym: like you could draw these fight scenes in a physical space And they would make sense.
Rym: Most of them most of the parts that would be hard to draw or make sense are the shape-changing things that the tanuki does Specifically because she's a shapeshifter.
Scott: Yeah, I think the the one thing is that You know most of the things that happen in this show.
Scott: it doesn't have a lot of originality right like you know It kept me kept making references like ghost in the shell Macross other trigger shows.
Scott: right it feels like almost like a greatest hits of other good anime.
Rym: It's a greatest of what I like about anime the most.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it's it there.
Scott: It's great.
Scott: I didn't say it's the worst hit.
Scott: yeah, right.
Scott: It's greatest hits of other animes sort of combined into one anime.
Rym: Yeah, but yeah, I didn't say there was no like big surprise like it's well-crafted.
Rym: But it's not.
Rym: it does not have any moment like an Evangelion or a cowboy bebop has of.
Rym: well I didn't see that come in and now I got to think about it for a while.
Scott: right I think it.
Scott: you know it's like.
Scott: it's like it's not.
Scott: it's not like oh my god the greatest show.
Scott: It's just like it's an anime.
Scott: It's a great anime.
Scott: Yeah, but it's still.
Scott: Solidly it's on anime.
Scott: It's like we are making an anime here.
Scott: We're doing all the anime things.
Scott: if you're an anime fan.
Scott: You're gonna like this.
Scott: I think if you're not an anime fan this show might be a little a.
Rym: the show is very anime In a good way, but yeah like I'd if I show this to some random person who's never really watched anime I think they might have a little trouble with how fast it moves.
Scott: I Think also that you know the themes and tropes and patterns, and then you know story points and characters.
Scott: They think are gonna miss what I what I really know.
Scott: you're uncomfortable with them.
Rym: There is a lot there's a large number of characters and They're all relatively complex and their dialogues and interactions also move quickly alongside the plot.
Rym: like Characters will not like resist the same conversation multiple times in a row.
Rym: a lot of recent anime have had this weird specific trope of Characters basically spend a long time trying to convince each other of things multiple times.
Rym: this show Blows past that.
Scott: no no no I do like how fast it moves because it doesn't move too fast But it moves fast enough like episode one.
Rym: Why do I do it?
Rym: How do I get cured episode three?
Rym: I'm on the baseball team.
Rym: Let's go right.
Scott: I do wish though it would have slowed down because there are some side characters right who?
Scott: Do not get their time right.
Scott: so there's like a flip flip daughter.
Rym: I wish had more time.
Scott: the Right flips episode.
Scott: flips daughter gets a whole episode, but then you never see her again.
Rym: Yeah, I would like to see her again.
Scott: flip you see occasionally But he never gets his whole episode to learn what I wanted more flip because flip is a lot like why you're gonna get more If you haven't watched the last four episodes.
Scott: you're getting more flaky.
Scott: good good You're getting good flip.
Scott: cuz you're not getting a flip episode where you can learn his deal.
Rym: Because I like because flip is like a kingpin to kind of character like floor like wide whale from venture brothers in that He's a bad guy, but you can understand his motivations.
Scott: He's like very harsh, but fair like I love when him and ogami interact right not saying got to the two beast people Melissa or whatever that run the the.
Scott: Oh Let the land.
Rym: the landlords feel like you can make a show about them where they try date.
Scott: They obviously have enough.
Scott: there's something there.
Scott: You could obviously make two episodes of what about each of them.
Scott: You know how they feel.
Rym: they feel like the characters who like run the bed-and-breakfast in a master Keaton volume.
Rym: Yep, exactly like master Keaton background characters for a story.
Scott: There's all these side characters who I think if the show had gone a little slower Could have still had a fast enough pace to keep things interesting.
Scott: I think the show could have been moving six episodes and done a lot more fun stuff And you could have explored all of those characters and maybe season two will do exactly that because the ending is definitely it's like they they.
Scott: what they've done is the ending is such as not a spoiler.
Scott: the ending is such that all of the Mysteries and plots that have been brought up in season one are wrapped up.
Scott: So you're not left cliffhanged.
Scott: Anyway, right, but the state of the world that is that is in you know The new status quo that they have achieved at the end of season one.
Scott: still it doesn't leave mysteries right about all those things that you were worried about like, you know, the religion and the Pharmaceutical company and all that stuff.
Scott: no mysteries anymore.
Scott: You're good You don't need to watch season two, right?
Scott: But the state of the world is such that there is still the remaining conflict of you know Beast people and humans in the world right not perfectly at peace leaving well open the door for you know seasons.
Scott: However, many they want to make you know, just need to.
Scott: they would just need to bring in new antagonists right to make another season the religion part sort of like.
Rym: I already really like the show but the speed at which the religion part was introduced and then Escalated was part of how I went from.
Rym: this is a really good show - this is a great show because that Was the kind of thing that would in a normal anime take like an Entire half season to build up and that religion goes from 0 to 60 in like two episodes.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: Yeah Beyond that like the sound the voice acting is great.
Rym: The animation is beautiful and A lot of shows that have like animal type characters like anime over the years tend to really skimp out on the animation.
Rym: this show Really doubled doubles down on the animal people acting in animal ways and like little details on how transformed they are like the nails.
Scott: Oh, it's like I mean, I mean the mink.
Scott: the mink needs an.
Rym: oh, she I want a whole series.
Rym: That's just her.
Rym: She's my second favorite character.
Scott: Okay?
Scott: But yeah, if you are a furry if you are an anime fan If you are not you
Rym: ever seen an anime or ever enjoyed an animal person
Scott: And you have Netflix and you have 12 divided by 2 6 less than say 5 to 6 hours of free time and you can click the skip intro and skip outro button.
Scott: Cuz you should intro it.
Rym: you shouldn't click.
Rym: The intro is great and the outro is beautiful.
Scott: Yeah, I'll be only to watch it once they're not like Scott.
Rym: What kind of anime fan are you?
Rym: the rule is you watch the opener every time no matter not.
Scott: They're not good enough to watch more than a couple times.
Scott: I think they're the closer I think and you can burn through this show in like five hours and you're stuck inside not going anywhere.
Scott: I know it.
Scott: So I go to open up your Netflix.
Rym: if you listen to GeekNights You have to watch this show like.
Rym: I cannot imagine the person who's hearing the words We're saying right now.
Rym: who will not enjoy this anime?
Scott: Someone who I know for a fact that there are people who have listened to GeekNights Wednesday Who are not anime fans and actually don't like anime.
Scott: But for some reason that listener listens to this and that person probably won't like this show.
Rym: I'll bet that person will.
Rym: if you don't I want to find out why I want you to mess it.
Rym: email me.
Scott: Okay, if that person exists the non anime fan listening to anime GeekNights.
Rym: yep, this show is just.
Rym: you know that feeling you get like we talked about.
Rym: there's a lot over the last like decade plus of doing GeekNights, but There's a lot of daras.
Rym: We're like we'll watch anime because like we want to review the show or like it's a pretty good show.
Rym: But then there's an anime where at the end of every episode All you want to do is start watching the next episode and those shows are relatively rare.
Rym: as much as I love animation Even really good shows don't always give me that feeling of yeah, I gotta watch another episode.
Rym: This is one of those shows where every episode I finished.
Rym: I just wanted to watch the next one That's that's a high praise and seek out shows like that.
Rym: This gave me the same feeling I got every time I walk when I was watching Gundam seed or when I was watching cowboy bebop.
Scott: All right, well studio trigger of course with another good one.
Scott: you can always you know count on them.
Scott: We'll see what they come with next.
Scott: maybe someone else already knows that they're coming with next night.
Rym: Do your trigger?
Rym: continuing to save anime every year yep?
Scott: BNA on Netflix you know I guess until forever because the Netflix exclusive.
Scott: they made it for Netflix.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website At frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this brand new episode of GeekNights are Ellen Joyce, Henry nickel Marty green.
Rym: He's just like a dude gag short television.
Rym: Cram Finch you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: She gave me a kiss and she gave me my ticket.
Rym: Clinton Walton J Banch for enter New Zealand Ryan Perrin Nicholas Brando Chris Mink if the thirst for hydrated Gannon dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Shervin von Horrell and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names.
Rym: ah Stay safe out there.
Rym: Tonight is the night Wednesdays.
Rym: every other Wednesday when we do GeekNights is a busy day because I work all day.
Rym: We record the show right after work, and then I go straight into a Bernie wheel game.
Rym: So I'm rushing editing this episode so I can get to that game.
Rym: But now I leave you with something that has been referenced again recently on Twitter And I think a lot of younger people don't remember the days of John Madden.
Media: I Like a tower.
Media: John Madden John Madden John Madden John.
Media: Question mark exclamation point.
Media: question mark exclamation point.
Media: question mark 999 999 999.
Media: I'm laughing for real right now.
Media: 999 999 999.
Media: John Madden John Madden John Madden football and mark mark mark.
Media: Hey you hey you hey you hey you hey you John Madden Da da da da da da da da da da da da da Momma Mia pop up here, baby got the diar Oh.