Rym: It's Thursday, June 18th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are talking about Pencils and pens and stationery and if you have any ideas for Thursday shows let us know.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: so uh every like Couple weeks.
Rym: I got to go into a work thing and you know there's a system We use to like put in vacation days or like if you're gonna work from home you flag like I'll be working from home on this particular day and I have to keep just adding like Another month.
Rym: to the end of the time.
Rym: I'm going to be working from home every day, and I just did that today.
Rym: I have 68 work from home days in my calendar currently.
Scott: All right, I mean, I don't I don't have to do that.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I work for a big company, so I got to do stuff like that.
Scott: There's all this sort of tracking why it's one of the many reasons.
Scott: I do not work at any big company.
Rym: That's good though because it's like it just handles stuff pretty like.
Rym: I don't have to talk to a person like if I'm on jury Duty, I just go into this thing and I type some stuff, and it's all just handled like I don't have to tell anyone Don't have to do anything.
Scott: I mean I just sent someone email.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I don't even have to interact with a human.
Scott: Okay Sending is that I like.
Scott: dealing with forms is somehow easier than a slack message like yo jury duty tomorrow.
Rym: It's not a form.
Rym: It's more like just.
Rym: I can have an app that I can use to set things like my calendar.
Scott: I have an available black.
Scott: yeah, that's called Gmail.
Rym: I Just miss it, but it also does things like it'll block phone calls outside of the hours.
Rym: I say I'm gonna be working.
Rym: so like no one can even try to contact me outside of the hours I specifically specify in there, so I set up all these don't have a work phone Problem solved.
Scott: no one can call me ever.
Rym: I have an a role where people do need to be able to call me on occasion.
Scott: If I was a CEO of a company I'd be like no phones.
Rym: One thing I would do if I was a CEO of a company is banned voicemail.
Scott: But most good companies are banning voicemail anyway, so yeah, I'd be getting rid of a lot of that stuff.
Rym: Yeah So yeah again.
Rym: normally we'd talk about open events or whatever.
Rym: But yeah, the world's kind of on fire and the virus is getting world still on fire.
Scott: news at 11.
Rym: Yep, so all I got to say about that is pay attention if you notice We're not talking a lot about anything other than the anti police movement the protests and politics on our social media Because those are kind of more important, but
Scott: I got a virus test today even though I've never had any virus symptom.
Scott: It was free and I can literally see the testing center from my window.
Scott: I'm looking at it right now.
Scott: I'm like well, and they said on the website Every New Yorker should go there.
Scott: I'm like well.
Scott: I'm a New Yorker.
Rym: Yeah, more data is better.
Scott: all right whatever We'll see what it says.
Scott: they should get a result within 48 hours.
Scott: I hope it says Negative, but if it says positive, then it's that it's a bunch of questions.
Scott: right because it's like well Does that mean I'm one of the people who got it with no symptom?
Scott: Yep does that mean?
Scott: I'm gonna get sick soon like you're.
Rym: just it was really good timing.
Rym: I'm gonna start.
Scott: I'm gonna start coughing in a few days.
Scott: Yeah, does it mean I?
Scott: Just spread it to everyone.
Scott: when I went to the grocery store.
Scott: Just now It's like I. I don't know What happens if it comes back positive, but there is.
Scott: they gave me a a what now?
Scott: Brochure that says if it's positive do these things.
Scott: Hopefully I won't have to do those things.
Rym: I'm actually getting next week interestingly enough that companies just like offer like getting everyone to do it I'm getting training in like contact tracing and like how that works and end of the methodology and everything.
Rym: Not like a certification to go like do that for a company or like a hospital, but just to basically fully understand the process I'm really usually just a lot of most of it is like a manual labor kind of thing.
Scott: Okay, talk to the person find out who they were with then call all those people and find out who they were with and which days.
Rym: Yeah, but it's also it's got some cool stuff in it like the current state of like What are the known symptoms and what are the progressions and all that kind of stuff.
Rym: so?
Rym: It's it'll be an interesting thing like I don't know what I'll do with that information But feels like information that might be vaguely useful Can't can't hurt.
Scott: You know I'm having actually you know even though.
Scott: I'm you know the one of the most skeptical people alive And I'm always questioning whether things are real or not real you know even I'm having a hard time telling it's like okay There's some stuff.
Scott: That's clearly bullshit.
Rym: and this stuff That's clearly well like that t-mobile is down because North Korean nonsense.
Rym: that happened earlier in the week where people were like making shit up about exactly.
Scott: But this you know.
Scott: regarding the virus.
Scott: There's a lot of stuff.
Scott: That's like We we don't know.
Scott: and even people I know like my friend who's like you know has a PhD in epidemiology She doesn't know.
Scott: she's like yeah, you know it's.
Scott: it's certainly possible that Asymptomatic people are going around spreading this thing everywhere.
Scott: Yeah, we don't know.
Scott: still we still are not sure.
Rym: well like the way I've heard like in my normal life like if it's an area I know Then I can do primary research with one.
Rym: like if there's one source I can do primary research to see if it's plausible or not.
Rym: If it's an area, I don't know, but it's not the virus.
Rym: I can do what journalists do.
Rym: There's got to be two independent sources before I trust anything like.
Rym: that's a good rule of thumb.
Rym: if you see a news story That seems crazy and only one news organization is talking about it.
Rym: Do not retweet that shit.
Rym: But when it comes to the virus like I'm hesitant to really like retweet or comment or say anything unless I see like four or five independent sources because There's just a lot of fake nonsense going around.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and I don't know anything about that like talk about a domain.
Rym: I don't know a lot about.
Scott: All I know is what I what I read and I only repeat things if I read them on.
Scott: you know very Trusted places otherwise otherwise I'll either don't say anything or I say I heard this.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: like I said, I don't I don't know if you spread it.
Scott: We don't know.
Rym: well like one thing What does it mean if I'm positive?
Scott: I don't freaking know.
Rym: one thing we do know Red states are having huge spikes right now.
Rym: That's so far.
Rym: blue states are not based solely on How they planned to reopen and whether or not they encourage people to wear masks.
Scott: a great example is this story.
Scott: people may have seen this story that talked about Two hairdressers who got.
Scott: they're definitely sick at least according to the story and none of supposedly none of their customers Got sick even though they were open.
Scott: and the story the store that they tell is while the hairdressers are so responsible wearing masks and Washing hands and whatnot that none of the customers got sick.
Scott: therefore I guess masks and hand-washing works, and I'm like do I believe this story.
Scott: I don't freaking know or anything You know it's like.
Scott: I feel like someone who's pushing that story hard.
Scott: is someone who wants Hairdressers to be open?
Rym: yeah, well, that's the thing.
Rym: what the?
Rym: I saw a really interesting article that's not about the virus itself, so I'm more like.
Rym: but it was a statistical study of When the rules change like if a state like reopens or says things are okay Regardless of what the government's saying in a particular area.
Rym: Will the people in that area actually just go out or will they continue to be cautious and they think you know?
Scott: I'm gonna continue to be at least one or two or more phases more cautious than yep.
Rym: well Yeah, so get this.
Rym: that study like Indicated that it bait it boils down to partisanship.
Rym: Democrats will stay home a lot longer than Republicans like.
Rym: that's it.
Rym: That's the sole factor.
Rym: well, that's Good Yeah, well it's good for us Directly, but it's bad for like anyone who's stuck living in a red state who is not evil I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, we're gonna figure out a way to get them out somehow.
Rym: Whatever yep, so wear your mask out there guys and If there's a don't go out.
Scott: unless you have to go out like I want there to be a Pax I want to go to the beach.
Scott: real bad.
Rym: If there is a nerd convention in like Georgia or Florida that's gonna happen in July like I Would encourage you to not go to that convention in July.
Scott: just saying that friend I mentioned to as the PhD has not left their house since March not even one time.
Scott: Wow grocery.
Rym: So actually other than the second week of the quarantine I have not been inside any building except my own apartment building And I've only gone outside to basically run or get takeout from one restaurant and only one.
Scott: I have gone outside to go to the grocery briefly Only on the one Street Broadway that I live on.
Scott: you know a few different Groceries very infrequently right.
Scott: we're talking like less than once a week right.
Scott: like once every few weeks I'll go outside to some grocery or groceries, and I went to the testing center today.
Rym: I will actually tomorrow.
Rym: tomorrow I am going to the vet because they're the vet did finally reopen to do well and non-emergency visit.
Rym: So we're taking the rabbit in to get a bunch of checkups and things that are Overdue because we didn't really want to go to the animal hospital if it wasn't an emergency during the panic across the bridge.
Rym: Yeah, yep, but I'm gonna And I'm gonna bike him over there because I'm not taking a subway.
Scott: Yeah, I've left the apartment to go to the guy.
Scott: I'm in the building now That's it.
Rym: I run every day, but I basically like not.
Rym: so here's there's a fun opening pit.
Rym: There's basically no one outside unless you go to like the waterfront parks like in this part of Queens like nobody's outside except I'm like big main time a day and exacts place like yeah, Queensborough Plaza like north and south There's people and like the waterfront.
Rym: There's people.
Scott: and the bike path It's true for a long gone city Astoria in general is that if you go on a non main street?
Scott: Like 43rd Road, I guess all these streets that aren't that don't have commercial storefronts on them Are typically empty.
Scott: Yeah, most of the time they're way more empty.
Rym: So where I run not only do I not see any people like I can do runs where once I get off Crescent Street I don't see a single human being till I get back to Crescent Street.
Scott: Yeah, Crescent Street's a busy commercial street what you walk one street over off Crescent it's not gonna be anyone there.
Rym: like I'll see between you have to cross, you know Five miles and see between zero and one humans on that entire run.
Rym: but Something novel has happened over the last week.
Rym: those parts of this area where I tend to run where there's no people like warehouses and stuff.
Rym: There are raccoons fucking everywhere Like trash.
Rym: raccoons are taken over the streets.
Rym: in Long Island City that I saw three separate families of raccoons And they were all just chillin.
Rym: one of them looked like they're semi permanently living under a car That clearly has not moved since the quarantine began.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So, uh, yeah got any news.
Scott: Do I have a news?
Scott: Well, oh, yeah, so check this out as I Don't know.
Scott: you may or may not have heard of this product called base camp.
Scott: It's sort of like a project management thing.
Scott: It's been around for a super long time At least I feel like way over 10 years.
Scott: Yeah maybe 15 or so it's.
Scott: and Basically, it's like, you know, the it it's.
Scott: the selling point of these products is like they're sort of like for businesses.
Scott: They're competing with things like Jira.
Scott: They have a whole suite of apps, right?
Scott: And they really sell on their their, you know, some simple what really high polished design And they charge money for their app.
Rym: They're not free Which I'm a fan of like.
Rym: I'm a fan of things that charge you money as opposed to charging you by stealing your data or Giving you ads.
Scott: Yeah, you could.
Scott: actually if you had a company you could just use like only base camp products if you wanted to and it's like It'll cover, you know, it'll replace like everything for you.
Scott: You know, you get your.
Scott: it can replace slack, you know There's message boards this project managing this.
Scott: I think they have time tracking.
Scott: I think they even have some Google Docs competing stuff documentation.
Scott: They got everything, right?
Scott: But you know, obviously they're not as big as the big boys right in all those products, right?
Scott: But anyway, they came out with a new product called hey hey calm they got that URL somehow And it's an email client and it's a really fancy kind of simple Polished and you know beautiful looking email client as you would expect, you know, it is someone who was a Google inbox user.
Scott: That's kind of appealing.
Scott: And of course, it's not free.
Scott: They charge $100 a year to use hey and you get a hey email address and all this stuff, right?
Scott: So like any app.
Scott: you make an app to go in that Apple App Store, right.
Scott: so Apple in the App Store, you know if you have any sort of in-app purchases, right?
Scott: They charge 30%.
Scott: So if I you know sell.
Scott: if I have a game in the App Store and I sell you some coins for my game Apple is taking third and you buy a dollar of coins.
Scott: I only get 60 cents and Apple gets 30 cents.
Rym: That's a pretty big big like we've talked about that before.
Scott: Yeah, so there are obviously Exceptions to where you can get around this, right?
Scott: there are exceptions for if your app is Like an enterprise app of some kind right then you can get around this, right?
Scott: If your app is a reader app, right like a magazine Newspaper book app like the Kindle Amazon app you can on the Apple.
Scott: you can't buy Kindle books in the app.
Scott: You go to amazon.com in your browser in Safari and it won't even like link you to the browser to open it.
Scott: It's like you have to on your own open up your browser.
Rym: You know go all these like workarounds of shenanigans to get around this.
Scott: All right, you can't buy them in the Amazon App either.
Scott: it's like you have to right anyway.
Scott: There's exceptions, right?
Scott: So you would think that like hey Netflix is similar to hey, right?
Scott: It's like it's a consumer product or business product or whatever And you buy the subscription.
Scott: you can't buy a Netflix subscription on your iPhone.
Scott: You have to buy it on netflix.com and then you can use the Netflix app.
Scott: so it's like well there by a hey at subscription on hey calm and then use the hey app.
Scott: and So they got rejected from the App Store and they appealed and Apple rejected them again.
Scott: And you know clearly this is a state at whoever wrote This wasn't just like, you know filling out some form letter right.
Scott: whoever wrote the rejection from Apple clearly understands the whole situation.
Rym: Yep, some escalation occurred here.
Scott: Yeah, they're basically clearly citing these three Exceptions to where you can.
Scott: you know, not you can have an app in the store that you know Where the payment happens somewhere else.
Scott: and there's state.
Scott: they're saying yeah, your app doesn't meet any of the three Exceptions for in-app purchase reader apps multi-platform service, whatever.
Scott: So yeah, it shouldn't be allowed in the App Store.
Scott: Deal with it.
Scott: So I guess their options are a change their app which would basically defeat their business model for this app Right, which is they're selling the user interface.
Scott: They're not selling The email service.
Scott: Yeah of having a hey calm email address Or Not be in the App Store on Apple devices with this app that they already developed.
Scott: so they worked on this app.
Scott: They spent their own money to develop this app, right and now they can't sell it.
Scott: It's like they just wasted all that time and effort all those developers programming for no reason, right?
Scott: They made a thing that will not be used Or they can try to sue Apple.
Scott: Good luck.
Rym: It's just an interesting situation in general that Apple devices for being so ubiquitous are Hard to use in corporate environments.
Rym: when you like run into situations like this Mm-hmm.
Scott: I mean if your app is on the App Store, then it's really easy to use, right?
Rym: Yeah, but only if it can the app stores.
Rym: you got to play these games.
Scott: Well, usually right.
Scott: if you're a if you're a company and you're buying You're choosing what to your company to use.
Scott: you're gonna choose something that has their app in the App Store.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: So basically Because even that wouldn't be a concern if it was a company that just gave everyone like here's your here's your work smartphone Right, um, you know, so you're gonna be choosing things that have iPhone apps, but if you are Making apps for the iPhone, right?
Scott: That's where you're getting screwed if you get locked out because it's like well now It's like like even me someone who you know, do I do?
Scott: I want to do hey calm It's like a kind of you know, not a little bit.
Scott: I probably wouldn't.
Scott: yeah I mean, we're pretty deep in the Google ecosystem even though they say but it's like I do want to go back to the Google Inbox days so that a better user interface for email is appealing to me.
Scott: It might get me to spend money Maybe not on this but you know, yeah, I 1% considered it right but like well They're just they're just not gonna get customers now because they don't have the iPhone app, right?
Scott: It's like why would anyone pay for hey, if you aren't gonna get pay under iPhone?
Scott: Yep, if you unless your whole company is Android and your Android and everybody knows Android Hey is just a non-starter now?
Rym: Well, I mean if I'm Android and you're not I can just email your busted gmail from my awesome Hey via my Android phone and I'm good, right?
Scott: but you'd see the point.
Scott: but if you know if we're a company why would you pay for hey if Our employees with iPhones aren't gonna have have an app, right?
Scott: Yeah, so we're not gonna pay for it at all.
Scott: We'll just stick with something else that has an iPhone app.
Rym: So in some other news, I'm gonna link to this.
Rym: But there's a lot of stories that are telling a similar story.
Rym: This is just one of the myriad I found out there.
Rym: But at the beginning of the quarantine and the crisis And everyone like everyone who could work at home started working from home like everyone sort of tested out their BCP policies and schools all had to go remote and I saw a lot of people saying things like This just proves that we could have been working from home all along.
Rym: This just proves that we could have been running schools from home all along.
Rym: That is not really true.
Rym: Most jobs are not going that well with people working from home compared to how they went Previously.
Rym: things are starting to slow down.
Rym: things are starting to fail.
Rym: things are not working that great.
Rym: But people who are saying that a probably worked jobs that could be done from home Yep, like I do a job where I could do the job a hundred percent from home due to the unique nature of my job There is no technical reason.
Scott: I can't do my job from home But I can't lie.
Scott: I do way less work at home.
Scott: I'm constantly doing other shit.
Rym: Most people are like that.
Rym: but also like even if you're not just goofing off which a lot of goofing off.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not gonna blame anyone.
Rym: the world's on fire.
Rym: You should be goofing off.
Scott: You're not goofing off.
Scott: Something's wrong.
Rym: Everyone's allowed to goof off a little bit.
Rym: The share zone skeleton has good advice.
Rym: steal from work That's right.
Rym: But even if you are working like hard like seven and a half hours plus a lunch break while you're working from home There's a lot of things that just take longer.
Rym: like I am perfectly good writing a like 4,000 word email to an engineer who will then respond with another 4,000 word email and as those emails progress We'll get our work done.
Rym: same thing I've like.
Rym: there's people I can I be where I am with like send you an instant message have a conversation online and that works.
Rym: But I also there are a lot of people I work with who just aren't that effective unless you talk to them in person.
Scott: So fire those people.
Rym: Yeah, but most humans are like.
Rym: that is the problem.
Rym: Most humans like like if you have to have it like five people have a discussion and whiteboard something.
Rym: They just get more done if they're in a room together.
Rym: then if they're all on like a zoom call or something.
Scott: Well, there's also, you know, I think that's a definite also a very white-collar centric perspective.
Rym: Oh, yeah, look at all the jobs that can't work from home.
Rym: Like garbage man can't telecommute.
Rym: We don't have robot bodies to go out and do it.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Most jobs are not.
Rym: I sit number.
Scott: one job in the United States That employs the most people like not company but job position is Driver of vehicle.
Rym: Yeah, then you might think oh the driver drive vehicle from home.
Scott: Well, we have remote control vehicle, you know as much as everyone talks about automatic cars.
Rym: I am shocked that I mean look someone in like Arizona can pilot a drone overseas and murder people.
Rym: I feel like a trucker sitting at home with a hot ass or a steering wheel and a computer could drive a Semi-truck and could even have a backup driver ready to take over if something happens.
Rym: I'm surprised that technology has not moved further Because I think well because it would destroy that sector like wages would go down to nothing.
Rym: that would turn into a minimum wage job.
Scott: Well, I think also the telecommunications.
Rym: But we trust that for fucking drones that murder people, right?
Scott: But there are so few drones true right that you have the bandwidth to control them all on your special Satellite just for controlling.
Scott: the drone drew right you to control every truck in America.
Scott: I don't think we have you know Even just one country even just one state every truck to have a driver at home the bandwidth To send all the video feeds to the driver Yeah and then for the driver to send their control inputs back to the truck.
Rym: 5g the 5g or something with a minimum latency and Reliability.
Scott: it doesn't go down because they have to control the truck literally at every single moment.
Scott: It can't go down for like a few seconds even right and they're the delay that to not.
Rym: well I would cheat a little bit by using current driving technology.
Scott: current Do that I'm just saying.
Scott: is that the bandwidth for the data for all the trucks all those video feeds?
Scott: It just this so met.
Scott: I don't think you they would do something.
Scott: the network as a whole.
Scott: We don't think we have the total capacity.
Scott: Well anyway, I guess my imagine if everyone with a computer opened up ten twitch streams all at once It's like the network that the you know The pipe upstream pipe would start to fill.
Rym: I feel like we could build those pipe, but anyway That's a Monday discussion.
Rym: the point.
Scott: I don't exist now.
Scott: I'm not saying we can't build them I don't exist now.
Rym: the point.
Rym: I want to make is More important.
Rym: even truck drivers if they're like safe driving their trucks feels like they'd be safe.
Rym: You know they're only in their truck.
Rym: They got to stop at rest stops They got a pee they gotta eat they get.
Rym: the truck has to get loaded or not loaded like most people cannot tell a commute.
Rym: But this article is actually talking about specifically education like school because school all went remote even if you Ignore the very real problem that poor kids don't have good internet and poor kids don't have computers.
Rym: Even if you ignore that like gaping problem Remote education just didn't fucking work at all.
Rym: like kids did not learn?
Rym: Of course not and there's a lot of reasons why like on one hand schools
Scott: obvious schools
Rym: are babysitters But now parents have to be the babysitters, which is now affecting the parents performance at work, but the kids just aren't learning like kids in like high school and middle school and elementary school like this year and next year.
Rym: I Don't know what we're gonna.
Rym: Do like.
Rym: they just didn't learn anything.
Rym: Even worse like imagine kids in college.
Rym: RIT's tuition Made sense for us right because we were there.
Rym: the experience at RIT in person was what we were paying for.
Rym: If I was paying that amount of money just to take online Classes the classes that I skipped most of the time when I was there physically I would have dropped out Alrighty, why would you?
Scott: why would you pay that much money for that?
Rym: Yeah, if you're paying that much money for that go like learn online for like Khan Academy or something.
Scott: Well, it's like colleges are always like building shit.
Scott: They're wasting all their money on building buildings.
Scott: Yeah, instantly even though they have enough buildings already because that's what you're paying for is like I'm gonna go live in this place where they've built all this awesome shit, right?
Rym: And live on this amazing campus of learning and up you know and also be embedded with peers to be able to learn together And network and like all those things.
Rym: you're not getting any of that.
Rym: if you're going to go You're like.
Scott: also most things you do at college Right are not just those buildings for fun.
Scott: It's like those buildings were for learning.
Rym: Yeah, like I was like like.
Rym: there were labs that had the equipment.
Rym: I could not get at home.
Scott: Yeah, it's like okay.
Scott: I did computer science.
Scott: I have a computer at home.
Scott: sure I you know a lot, but it's like you know.
Scott: so how much did I need the computer lab?
Scott: I you know I used it a lot, but I didn't have to.
Scott: I could have gone without.
Rym: yeah I had to use the computer lab because I had to like set up ten computers like physical computers and build a network and do Some crap.
Rym: I can't do that.
Scott: I still took frickin chemistry classes.
Scott: You know all kinds of other classes Digital audio class like.
Rym: there was a full recording studio with quiet rooms and everything There were.
Scott: there were lots of facilities for learning that were legitimately used.
Scott: not all of that building stuff is just you know egregious.
Scott: You know college is trying to look fancy.
Scott: Yeah, it's like a lot of that money.
Scott: They spend on actual learning Art class.
Scott: you know it's like okay.
Scott: There were people there who had like but even literally their major.
Scott: their major was like ceramics, right?
Scott: So you go in and it's like.
Scott: it's like you know pottery.
Scott: Yeah, honey.
Scott: Well.
Scott: You know it's like.
Rym: What about the kids who are in packaging science or computer engineering like all right?
Scott: I have to fabricate our RAM chip as my problem this after computers the next biggest thing at RIT was photography.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they had all these dark rooms and all kinds of shit going on there.
Scott: But anyway even all they had were more powerful to the computers most people had even all.
Rym: that is not The worst problem with school.
Rym: the problem this article talks about is like this fundamental problem.
Rym: No one gave a shit, and no one even tried.
Scott: No person.
Rym: teachers barely tried.
Rym: Administrators barely tried.
Rym: schools barely tried kids.
Rym: most like in a lot of districts kids just didn't show up at all and no one cared.
Scott: I mean the psychology of being in a particular place.
Scott: Right it's like you know even if you're a bad kid bad In quotes right yeah bad quotes with an asterisk to a whole Conversation.
Scott: who goes to school and doesn't care and goofs off right.
Scott: there's still that you know.
Scott: Psychology of.
Scott: you're in school.
Scott: now.
Scott: the place of learning yeah Versus.
Scott: it's like if you're at home and the learning is like happening on a screen.
Rym: It's like you're like I know what I was like in middle school.
Rym: I know exactly what would.
Scott: I'm like that.
Scott: now We have meetings at work right.
Scott: and I'm it's like the meeting is happening And I feel like people pay just enough attention to not get caught right to talk when it's their turn.
Scott: Yeah, and then are there?
Scott: is anyone listening to what I'm saying right?
Scott: It's like I think even though I'm barely listening.
Scott: I think I might actually be listening the most.
Scott: I think I reply to things people say more.
Scott: No.
Scott: I don't think anyone's ever replied to anything.
Scott: I said they just.
Scott: You know recognize that you know.
Scott: okay, no one's talking.
Scott: it must be my turn to say something.
Rym: yep I mean, this is all solvable but the problem is it requires us as a society to invest in infrastructure and training and teachers and all these things of our Country has zero interest in funding.
Rym: so uh Maybe we can defund the police and start paying for some of this stuff.
Rym: Sure, but anyway big Things of the day.
Rym: so check this out.
Rym: This is a pretty short video like it's not super long You don't have to get deeply invested in it But it's a high-level walkthrough of how the Soviet Union planned cities and urban spaces Poorly not poorly actually.
Rym: it is fascinating because it's a sort of very direct look at What were Soviet cities which were mostly designed cities like they would have empty land and try to plan a city as opposed to?
Rym: let it grow naturally or let it be driven by private interests.
Rym: and It talks of a lot about the cities and how they were the way they were based on the goals that were given to the planners.
Rym: And the thing that a lot of Americans in particular probably don't know a lot about and this is part that I'm I know a lot About because I'm kind of deeply fascinated with the Soviet Union for a lot of reasons.
Rym: But I'm not saying it was all good over there.
Rym: Don't get me wrong.
Rym: There were problems in the Soviet Union Three big ones.
Rym: Yes but the stated goals of what they were designing their cities for is like this Diametric opposition to what American planned cities were designed for Soviet city and I'm gonna just summarize because you can watch this video.
Rym: But they were designed to under some certain assumptions one that everyone gets a home no matter what.
Rym: there is no homelessness no matter what?
Rym: to Personal space should be minimized and more investment should be put into shared spaces to foster more community.
Rym: Don't put gyms in every apartment building.
Rym: have central gyms that everyone has access to things like that But also the idea that the smallest unit of design should be the micro neighborhood which is basically a unit within which Every single person has equal access to every amenity and every micro unit has every required amenity.
Rym: So if you live in like neighborhood a versus neighborhood Z ANZ both have a gym.
Rym: They both have a pool.
Rym: They both have a hospital.
Rym: They both have schools, etc.
Rym: And Not saying that the Soviet system was perfect, but the American system is also fucking garbage.
Rym: So yeah, we got to figure out a middle ground around this.
Scott: Well, there's also, you know the gap between the stated goals and the reality.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, we see other places who do have these stated goals place, you know I've seen you know cities and especially like in Europe and different places that are building cities in that way.
Rym: But then they're stated go like they'll have gaps.
Rym: the people who plan Will miss something important that would have only arisen from the natural Evolution of a city.
Rym: and now you've built some giant thing that is flawed in some structural way Right.
Scott: or you'd be like the United States where it's like the stated goals of the United States make money for private entrepreneurs Right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: that's not the stated goal of the United States, but the machine that was built It's like they go around and they go and they say oh, yeah the United States It's all about freedom and equality.
Scott: But actually if you look at what the the machine and they built is none of those things.
Scott: It's just like this, you know, the the ideal is just this label.
Scott: Yeah, and so Soviet Union much in the same way It's like, you know, this is what we claim to believe in.
Scott: and then what they actually did doesn't necessarily match up Yep to what they you know.
Rym: But a lot of the concepts of their city design were good and were undermined by other factors like the Cold War World War two Etc.
Scott: the same for the whole world.
Scott: That's why it's World War.
Scott: Yep So what do you guys to the world what do I have?
Scott: All right, so bicycling which we can't avoid on a GeekNights.
Rym: Yeah, I was biking last weekend gonna be biking this weekend.
Scott: So, you know, it's been known for a while because we have a video evidence An indisputable video evidence of this one dude one time who was in a bike race And he did the Superman position on his bike like
Rym: belly on the saddle legs Belly
Scott: on the saddle arms on the handlebars body completely straight feet not on the pedals.
Scott: I think this video was thing of the day at one point now.
Rym: I did that once when I was in high school on a mountain bike on a very gentle grade thinking that out and all I will say is that even with those fat tires and that suspension and this gentle grade that is fucking scary as shit and almost impossible.
Scott: it is Incredibly scary and dangerous to to assume that position the Superman position on a bicycle, but it is supposedly quite Aerodynamic and speedy right as evidenced by the video that we saw.
Rym: the famous soon as he gets his leg up He just starts accelerating.
Scott: but in actual bike races say a tour de France.
Scott: Oh, no one does that.
Scott: Yep, I think it's.
Scott: I believe it might be a illegal.
Rym: it probably should be.
Scott: If it's not illegal, it should be.
Scott: it's too dangerous, but be You can gain a speed advantage and if you're a tour de France because you can pedal right so You want the position that you would you know?
Scott: It's like giving up your feet on the pedals to gain the aerodynamic advantage isn't gonna help.
Rym: that'll only help on like Downgrades that are steeper than a certain amount right.
Scott: it's like you could just pedal harder because you're the world.
Scott: You know you're going for the world championship here.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you know you'll.
Scott: the pedaling is more important, right?
Scott: You don't want to give that up by taking your feet off.
Scott: So the question still is well if you're gonna keep your feet on the pedals and keep pedaling You still want an aerodynamic advantage.
Scott: that what you can get right?
Scott: It's like what's the best I can do?
Rym: because aerodynamics are the primary limiter of speed and endurance in biking right?
Scott: I can't do Superman right, but what can I do right?
Scott: I could put I could get all the way up and you know put the handlebars into my stomach.
Scott: I could put my ass way back behind the seat right.
Scott: It's like there's several different like crouched Positions I can get.
Scott: clearly standing up is not the good one For going downhill right it's sort of obvious right.
Scott: But if I'm gonna crouch down on my bike try to get the aerodynamic and keep my feet on the pedals and keep pedaling We're going downhill.
Scott: What is the best most aerodynamic?
Rym: Oh my god?
Rym: I'm looking at this.
Rym: this link position F and position a are terrifying to me right.
Scott: so position a the Froom.
Scott: So Froom is basically the best cyclist around Chris Froom.
Scott: He's like the best these days.
Scott: is he cheating?
Scott: who knows right?
Scott: That's how cycling is.
Scott: a professional sport is but he's the best around right now.
Scott: and apparently what's interesting is that the position that he uses is Not the fastest.
Scott: It's actually like you know kind of meh Oh wow yeah the fastest position You know is actually also the safest position Which is where you basically?
Scott: Get down on up with your ass under the front of your seat, and you just put your body on top of the top tube.
Scott: So yeah, it's quite fascinating.
Rym: Oh, I would not ride like that though I Mean it's not as safe as keeping your ass in the seat, but but the boys the boys are in a very precarious situation.
Scott: Yeah, well you're you're trying to win a race you're sacrificing the boys already.
Rym: Yeah, that is why I prefer mountain biking to the racing.
Scott: just don't race just yeah slower Don't try to pass Chris Froom On the downhill.
Rym: I love this disconnect between it's.
Scott: what I was fascinating though Is that you would think these professional racing teams would have studied this already and they go into like you know?
Scott: It's like they can't study everything right.
Scott: you know Even the pro cyclists who are studying their teams are figuring everything out best gearing best.
Scott: You know what's the best thing we can possibly do to go faster.
Scott: They still can't look into everything so these independent researchers were able to Figure out the best position for downhill is something that the racers were just doing based on gut.
Scott: yeah What's?
Scott: and apparently the difference you know in was not enough to keep Chris Froom from winning right?
Scott: So it's not that big a deal.
Scott: if you take into account all the factors of cycling This is only giving you a percentage advantage with downhill aerodynamics Only and not with any of the other factors, and yeah, I'm gonna win the cycling race.
Rym: It is also just fascinating.
Rym: looking at different kinds of cycling like Aerodynamics matters so much that like this like these are positions that one would use on a downhill, but Mountain biking like there's a set of different like styles and positions for downhill mountain biking.
Rym: They do not look anything like this.
Scott: because well if you're mountain biking It's about you know the.
Rym: it's about safe.
Rym: It's literally like.
Rym: safety is the primary thing.
Rym: how fast can you go and maintain control?
Rym: so you're right?
Scott: It's you versus like.
Scott: there could be roots and rocks.
Scott: who knows what cut right whereas you're on a road.
Scott: It's like well.
Scott: It's not you versus the road.
Scott: anymore It's you know you're it's versus the people.
Rym: next like sometimes standing straight up is the fastest way to go down like with pedals.
Rym: They're neutral position sometimes like right leg down and like.
Rym: there's all these different positions You can go into but they optimize for safety because it's not.
Rym: are you faster because of wind resistance.
Rym: It's did you make it down?
Scott: Well, you could make it down.
Scott: It's.
Scott: did you make it down in one piece?
Scott: Yep?
Scott: two piece three piece.
Scott: Do I win if my torso gets over the finish line my legs are on the mountain?
Scott: What did my legs make?
Rym: I just imagined like the final form of initial D Where the engine just explodes and the car just goes flying down the mountain and lands upside down the end But then the person's skull falls out the window and rolls over the finish line.
Rym: That's basic.
Rym: that's partly the end of redline skull on fire In the better moment.
Rym: yeah, we're stuck inside.
Rym: Black lives matter.
Rym: donate money to the cause.
Rym: protest if you are safely able to do so.
Scott: I've started putting your highest priority.
Rym: Yep, I've started putting us our standalone anime reviews without the rest of the show on YouTube.
Scott: So if you want to like is that cuz you ran out of board game ones?
Rym: yes, actually all of our board game ones except the ones that are so old that the audio quality is just awful.
Rym: or It's a show where we like spent five minutes on ten different games, but pretty much every board game review We've ever done that was above a certain line of qualities on YouTube, so I've moved on to every anime review.
Rym: We've ever done?
Rym: Okay, so I got master Keaton up last night, and I'm gonna just keep going.
Rym: that was a review we did in.
Scott: Well yep, how about that?
Rym: tale of Genji?
Rym: will read it at some point.
Rym: just stay tuned.
Rym: It's not reading season right now cuz we're stuck inside and working on stuff.
Rym: We are working on stuff so be ready for that.
Rym: We expect to present at the penny arcade expo online as our next convention because I do not think there's any other online Convention we're looking at presenting at before that and I don't think there will be any other conventions anytime soon, so Pax online it is I guess.
Rym: so Uh Yes, that's all I really got.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Scott: It's Thursday all right, so it's the lounge.
Scott: We're gonna talk about some stationery.
Scott: So right so I mean for as long as I've been going to school right cuz you know I grew up in it I got.
Scott: I don't know what kids are doing these days right, but when I grew up in school It's like yeah, I had a computer in kindergarten, but it was one apple two at the back of the classroom.
Rym: right yep Like either time it was fifth grade was the first time I like wrote as school essay on a computer instead of writing it by Hand even in middle school like they made us write shit by hand.
Scott: well like even in college.
Scott: You know it's like computer time was still like a separate time.
Scott: I would take my test on paper, right?
Scott: I think now they're doing compute.
Scott: you would take your test on a computer for a lot of things.
Rym: But yeah, I mean even RIT.
Scott: I did a lot of scan Tron tests and even today You know where I sit at a computer all day.
Scott: I still have notepads.
Scott: I still use pencils and pens and things to write.
Scott: yeah Cuz it's.
Scott: it's often just faster and more convenient than say like opening notepad or whatever app them and making some notes.
Rym: Yeah, especially if I'm gonna take notes cuz when I take notes I tend to also do some diagrams, and I tend to structure my notes a little bit in some fashion.
Rym: Hard to do that in like a notepad or something, but usually not worth the effort to get out the drawing tablet open.
Scott: mischief Right.
Scott: I mean especially consider something like you know.
Scott: I'm looking at my computer.
Scott: There's an IP address.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: It's like well.
Scott: I can copy paste the IP address around the screen.
Scott: I don't need to write that down Yeah, but let's say I need to go type that IP address into a computer in the other room.
Scott: all right It's like.
Scott: what am I gonna do?
Scott: copy and paste it into like an app that I could open on my phone.
Scott: I said to myself Text.
Scott: it's like it's easier.
Scott: a piece of paper still wins over a lot of things.
Scott: You can give a piece of paper to someone else.
Scott: right paper has still has that use.
Scott: I don't really think we still need printers.
Rym: I use my printer about once or twice a month.
Scott: is it to print out like RPG character sheet?
Rym: Yeah, that's 90% of what I do with it.
Rym: occasionally I'll print out recipes even though I have a monitor on the HtPc in the like in the kitchen like around the corner so I can use the screen.
Rym: It's often easy to have something printed out and then if I spill stuff on it or whatever.
Rym: like who cares?
Scott: I saw I did mix up recipe iPad iPad recipe for his paper recipe.
Rym: yep, there's pros and cons to both, but I'll do.
Scott: I read this regardless my whole life.
Scott: Right that I've used paper pens pencils right.
Scott: I've really just sort of liked nice paper pens pencils Yeah, so even what?
Scott: so when I was when I would go actually it's like I didn't want to go back to school But when it was back to school season I really wanted to go to staples and buy some really nice school supplies.
Scott: Oh hell yeah, and I always want to use the nicest newest school supplies.
Scott: as soon as like your pencil starts getting meh I wanted to use a newer pencil.
Rym: Yeah, so elementary school in particular the school like had a lot of weird rules.
Rym: It was like this really strict Catholic school.
Rym: They banned Mechanical pencils when I was in early elementary school.
Rym: like kids were not allowed to have a mechanical pencil.
Rym: you had to have Like a wooden pencil that could be pencil sharp in the normal way.
Rym: it had to be a number two And they were weirdly strict about that.
Rym: like I remember a kid getting in trouble for having a mechanical pencil.
Rym: Alright, thankfully by the time.
Rym: I got out of that Catholic school.
Rym: I never had to encounter that again because mechanical pencils are in my mind.
Rym: Just completely superior.
Rym: I never want to see a wooden pencil that I have to sharpen again in my life.
Scott: I mean I do like a mechanical pencil.
Rym: I hate using them because I have to keep sharpening them because I need a really sharp point or I'm Unhappy and I had to sharpen my pencils so often that it became a problem.
Scott: well So I was using mostly mechanical pencil.
Scott: I even got to the point of buying a fancy drafting pencil.
Rym: Oh, I still I use my.
Rym: I got it up my my unique or auto sharpening mechanical pencil.
Scott: I Had a oto super Pro mecha drafting pencil when I found out about those and it was so fancy and nice.
Scott: And then it like it broke and I was like what the hell this is supposed to be a fancy $20 pencil as some bullshit right.
Rym: ah the unique or is only $10.
Scott: But now I've actually reverted.
Scott: I'm now using fancy wooden pencil right.
Scott: so not only it's a fancy What is it called?
Scott: It's called like the.
Scott: where is it?
Scott: Where'd they go?
Scott: It's hiding on my desk.
Rym: Oh, well you look for that.
Rym: I guess my trouble with those is that mechanical pencils?
Rym: I remember almost every kid always used the point seven.
Rym: here It is it's hiding under the headphone, but point five millimeter was the most superior way.
Scott: So the pencil I have is.
Scott: I bought a whole box of these.
Scott: I have one box at home in one box at work.
Scott: It's the Palomino blackwing pencil.
Scott: It's a wooden pencil right it's but it's like extra nice wood extra nice Lead.
Scott: it has like this weird slogan on the side half the pressure twice the speed.
Scott: I don't know what that's about.
Scott: it feels like a normal pencil to me And it has this giant eraser.
Scott: actually and as the eraser wears out you can pull out more eraser Like the pencil will run out before the eraser run.
Scott: alright alright.
Rym: I I can see I just saw on their website The sharpening implements that they have the well the best sharpener the long point No, no, no.
Scott: is this the oh yeah automatic long point?
Rym: the long point Long point solves a lot of the problems.
Scott: I have with non-mechanical pencils this automatic long point sharpener.
Scott: right It's a typical you know manual It's not.
Scott: the crank pencil sharpener is the kind where you turn the pencil with your hand just a just a blade You know screwed into a to a thing with a hole in it right up.
Scott: But it has two holes number one and number two.
Scott: you sharpen the pencil in number one and number one.
Scott: I'll do it right now.
Scott: Well only sharpen if anyone ever sees this video.
Scott: Yeah, depending on the sharpened the wood right here.
Scott: I'll hold it up.
Scott: Only the wood has been sharpened and then in hole number two only The graphite is being sharpened by hole number two.
Rym: So I can write and write and write and then just and now this is how pointy.
Scott: this is how pointy it gets Right after hole number two.
Scott: It's a good point basically ridiculously pointy.
Scott: And so yes, that's what I've been using as the blackwing pencil as what I've currently arrived at.
Scott: but yeah historically I've used you know mechanical pencil.
Scott: like you know there were ones that had like a clicker on the side.
Scott: I never liked the ones where you would turn and now point in the front those always like unreliable.
Scott: There's also the the classic Bic Mechanical yeah one.
Rym: I use those for a long time especially in like middle school But I always got the 0.5 millimeter cuz 0.7. what I think?
Scott: oh these are 0.7.
Scott: But I just I thought these that I didn't bought these at a drugstore because what these are?
Scott: for the reason I have these RPGs RPG.
Scott: you show up at an RPG.
Scott: not everyone's gonna have pencils for the tabletop RPG.
Scott: So I just bring a hope.
Scott: I have a whole bunch of these just rubber banded together, and I plop them down.
Scott: I'm like boom everyone's got pencils.
Scott: there you go.
Rym: Yeah, but I when I was older like now that I got more money because I was poor for a long time.
Rym: I uh like I'd get the 0.5 millimeter Bix because they were good enough, and they were also really cheap, but Once I realized you could get mechanical pencils that rotate the lead as you click to keep them always relatively sharp.
Rym: That was the revelation of my life, and that's why I'm basically using this pencil forever.
Scott: Mm-hmm all right, so let's go into pen land right.
Scott: so what I was the first pens I remember using a lot were these erasable pen.
Rym: I use those two.
Scott: we had those in elementary school, and I don't like my way.
Rym: I liked them, but they smudged a little bit.
Scott: They did smudge, but I like the way they smell.
Rym: yes They had this very specific smell I can I know like I can envision that smell in my brain knows They still make those even I don't know, but I like those.
Scott: But then after that I would I switched over and I was really into these like Pens with superior ink or like these gel pens.
Rym: right well They still have a ball, but it's like gel is coming out right like it's a little wet after you're right for like a second.
Scott: I actually went back at one point and had this pen which is the pilot GX 300.
Scott: I still have one left.
Scott: They don't make these anymore right and it's just a normal ballpoint retractable pen, but the it's just like what's inside.
Scott: It's a normal ass right just pen right.
Scott: There's nothing exciting about what the you know, but the ink they used in these was a little bit better than other pens And also this this case that you know the actual Plastic and the clicking mechanism and the hold of the pen itself.
Scott: It was just really nice.
Scott: So I guess I still have one of these even though it's super old and not made anymore.
Rym: I like like the uniball like cheapo, whatever But I still I like the gel ink and I like the really really really fine point right.
Scott: so like I switched over to using you know I since they don't make those anymore right I was using more gel type pens right You know they're nice like I have this one here.
Scott: This is from the Muji store.
Scott: It's like a point five green no green ink whatever right, so I'll still get the gel ones for like color situations.
Scott: But actually I've gone back to the regular normal ballpoint right, so this is from the Muji store also, right?
Scott: And it's just a normal ballpoint pen.
Scott: right there's nothing interesting about it Really, it's so plain they.
Scott: but this one the ink that they put in these is like unbelievable, right?
Scott: It's like I kind of want to take the thing out of this pen and put it in that pilot thing.
Scott: It's like it's like some sort of like you know oil some kind of ink like that.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's just extra good ink like it gets so black and so nice-looking And so smooth.
Scott: it's like this like just the comparison next to other ballpoint pens is like a day.
Scott: So in one hand to like an off-the-shelf whatever.
Rym: I use pencils almost exclusively like I really only use pens Now like as of the last year or so when I'm signing things But very rarely if I'm just taking notes through my day-to-day stuff.
Rym: But I used to always think oh well pencil like I can erase it.
Rym: so that makes sense.
Rym: But I realized I almost never erase anything I ever write with a pencil.
Rym: I'll still just cross things out like the eraser is used so rarely that I basically treat pencils like pens now.
Scott: Yeah, it's weird.
Scott: It's like even though the pencil has an eraser, and I use that I do have a separate eraser.
Rym: Yeah, cuz the separate eraser is just better usually.
Scott: yeah last longer like better coverage No less dandy like these blackwing pencils have these giant erasers in them that you can keep pulling out more and more eraser.
Scott: Why do I have separate?
Scott: Right I don't know.
Scott: I just have it.
Scott: But yeah, so for a weird.
Scott: that like you know it's like I had you know a bad ballpoint pen And I was like a ballpoint pen is meh, and I ran away from it.
Scott: Yeah, and I went back, and it's like no actually I like ballpoint pen the most you know even when I remember I think one time I was it when I graduated elementary school I think you know me and my cousins my grandmother got us all these Parker pens Which I guess must have cost like 50 bucks or something.
Scott: they were like fancy metal pens where you would twist them to get the?
Scott: the ball to point to come out right and They had like my name engraved on the side of it.
Scott: and You know the it didn't have a normal You know like springy ink thing in there you to get a special ink thing from Parker.
Scott: Yeah, go into the fancy pen right Parker is sort of like.
Scott: I don't know if they even still exist anymore.
Rym: Oh, yeah, they do.
Scott: I'm on their website Okay, but it's like you know.
Scott: Mont Blanc is like fancy pen right by the way.
Scott: I've never liked fountain pen I've never.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: I just always seemed like a pretentious thing like hard to write with I don't know what the advantage.
Scott: good pen up an island is still around - oh, yeah The Parker pen is I guess sort of just like a cheap right.
Scott: it's like fancy pen But not as expensive as Mont Blanc pen right.
Scott: It's just like a fancy brand Whatever, but you know that pen you know I thought it was fancy right, but actually thinking back to it It's like that ink just got all over the place.
Scott: Yeah, it was just like it wasn't good the worst.
Rym: Oh, I know if you have someone does calligraphy of course like you need a fountain pen Or you need those markers that have the edge right.
Rym: yeah, you know I Hate fountain pens.
Rym: They're just a pain in the ass.
Scott: That's I'm saying.
Scott: I don't understand what the obsession is.
Scott: It's like yeah, okay, you got the skills to use one, but like what's the advantage of it?
Rym: You know what it's like.
Rym: It's like shaving with a straight razor like yeah, that's cool, but you can get a shave.
Rym: That's 99% is good with a safety razor and right exactly.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like yeah, I agree them.
Scott: It's like you know Mach 5 those cartridge razors bullshit.
Scott: Let's get away from that.
Scott: You know garbage right, and it's like okay.
Scott: Well.
Scott: I've wrapped at the safety razor.
Scott: It's like no they're going to the straight razor.
Scott: It's like why it's like you're adding this danger Yeah, and that you're not really gaining right.
Scott: I'm gaining a lot versus that Mach 3. what a safety Here's.
Rym: here's the thing like if I want someone who is a calligraphy expert to calligraphy for me I they should use the fancy fountain pen.
Rym: that'll make it Obviously, but I'm talking about the pretend, but just like a little barbershop Fountain pen for everything all the time like if I go to a barbershop to get a shave yeah use the straight razor.
Rym: I'm paying the expert to give me that extra 1% better shave.
Rym: But exactly in the modern world I don't write things down like anything.
Rym: I write down is either on a role-playing game character sheet or Or I'm signing my name on something or I'm taking notes.
Rym: They're all ephemeral.
Rym: I don't write anything with my hands that is meant to be anything But an ephemeral temporary like note to be discarded once I either digitize it or take care of whatever it is I wrote down.
Scott: I might write a card or a letter.
Scott: Rarely yeah, but it's very rare definitely rarely super rare.
Rym: And also I can type Even like I know shorthand like you've seen my awful handwriting cuz I learned like I can write in like full-on Shorthand that only I can read.
Rym: or someone who like those shorthand.
Rym: But I can type so much faster than I can write.
Rym: I can type so much faster Yeah Like if I have to write more than a sentence it would be.
Scott: the difference is the difference is that even if I'm using my?
Scott: Magic pencil on my iPad right which would theoretically give you complete freedom to write anything Yeah, still gonna take for some for some reason.
Scott: It's like writing with a pencil on a paper is somehow still more free and less Restrictive than yeah.
Rym: well because there's.
Rym: no that the the canvas you've got whatever whatever it is That's it And you just work around it.
Rym: like when I write and take notes.
Rym: the reason I like to use pencils for that purpose is that I'll kind of write notes And I'll structure and I'll jump around in the document and diagrams appear and I'll have arrows right as much as the digital brush.
Scott: The.
Scott: you know that the computer software has built into it as vastly improved And it's like it looks like a real pencil.
Scott: Holy shit, right?
Scott: There's still something that's hard to describe but like you know it's like It's just this.
Scott: it's like you don't have the same freedom.
Scott: Just write whatever when you're using the magic even with magic pencil on iPad pro in the fancy notes app.
Scott: Yeah, still it's still missing something.
Rym: it cannot replace real pencil on real paper And I don't think this will go away for the foreseeable future.
Rym: like in my free quarantine my black life I go to a lot of meetings, and there's takeaways from those meetings.
Rym: I got to remember stuff to do later and making notes is the thing I'm gonna be doing for the foreseeable future.
Rym: Even something simple like remember to do the thing.
Rym: it's way easier just to write.
Scott: I just went to the grocery right now right and I needed four things.
Scott: I wrote them down on a pad really quick tore the paper and walked out yep to open.
Scott: I could have opened my phone gone To like Google Keep or the notes app typed in the four things Right and then looked at my phone in the grocery and saved a piece of paper.
Scott: But that even it's like it's actually slower.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you.
Scott: a computer is all about making things Faster right.
Scott: you know Steve Jobs.
Scott: It's a bicycle for the mind right.
Scott: It's like if it's not making the work faster and easier than why why using the computer yep?
Rym: I like I use a computer if I'm gonna type a diatribe or a screed.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not gonna write my manifesto by hand, but I'll write my note to remember to do the thing Mm-hmm.
Scott: So last thing I'll say about paper right.
Scott: so Obviously in school.
Scott: I was using like you know three ring binder.
Rym: You get you get college ruled even though the school wanted to use wide ruled as even as a little kid I was always like college ruled.
Scott: only I would get like this recycled paper.
Scott: That was like gray right.
Scott: It's all soft and squishy because it worked really well with those erasable pencil.
Scott: I'd always get like the mead like college ruled binder book of paper and use that you could get the note the notebook that with The black and white sort of garbly mess on the.
Scott: you know the ones I'm talking about.
Rym: I know exactly I picture it in my mind.
Scott: I had it right or the spiral notebook right.
Scott: that was a solid color on the front Yeah, but I got the major.
Rym: I got the ones with the perforations.
Scott: I could tear pages out right You know and it's like you know.
Scott: nice those those papers are okay, but it's like you know.
Scott: later in life I discovered wait a minute this fancy paper because we spray fancy paper.
Scott: Just wasn't accessible right.
Scott: It's like we didn't kids know.
Scott: Right now I can go to like Kino Kunia or the Muji store and get like Japanese paper But I find increasingly I don't or I can buy moleskine.
Rym: I did the little thing for a while like I'd carry him around and like I'd use like a notepad I just carried in my pocket, and I could just bust it out any meeting and keep notes.
Rym: But as time goes on I just use literally whatever paper Like yeah anywhere like I just find some papers somewhere.
Rym: Maybe I even literally pull it out of a printer And that's just what I use like it.
Scott: well it I have the same problem with with you know?
Scott: not?
Scott: you know I had the problem a little bit with the yout with the writing utensils.
Scott: But I have the problem big time with the papers and notebooks is that they're a lot like items in a JRPG.
Scott: Yeah, I really covet that fit that elixir.
Scott: I covered it and I buy it.
Scott: It's like oh look at that fancy notebook yoink, but then oh is the square boss worth it should I?
Scott: it's like?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: what will I use this notebook for?
Scott: I have these Notebooks.
Scott: what it's like.
Scott: I got them from make magazine when that was still it.
Scott: I think they're out of business now right they had like makers notebook right.
Scott: so I bought two makers notebooks that are ultra fancy and I started to use one.
Scott: the other ones never been used in the first one I barely used right because it's like.
Scott: you know.
Scott: is it?
Scott: is this worthy of the makers notebook?
Scott: right?
Scott: whatever?
Rym: So what I do at my work What really changed my habits finally was we have hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of conference rooms.
Rym: every conference room has in it a big pile of pre-sharpened pencils just in case you need them and a Giant pile of like 20 page notepads that are small no cover.
Rym: Just like really simple nice paper.
Scott: We like what you get in a hotel conference.
Rym: Yeah But with a few and but there's always a bunch of varieties.
Rym: like some have square some have Like a checkerboard pattern some have hexes some have lines and They're just there.
Rym: and what I find is any meeting I go to.
Rym: I inevitably didn't bring anything with me.
Rym: I grab one of those notepads.
Rym: I take my notes on it I carry it back with them in my desk, and I throw it down.
Rym: you go to another meeting later.
Rym: I write notes on a brand new notepad by the end of the week.
Rym: I've got 12 notepads on my desk And you know what I do.
Rym: I pull the top two or three pages off of each one where I wrote stuff and I do a Reconciliation right.
Rym: look and see.
Rym: is there anything on this paper I need to still deal with?
Rym: then I take all the notepads that are missing a few pages And I just go sneak into a conference room on Friday before I leave and I put them all in the pile And I walk away.
Scott: Right it's like you buy the notebook with the fancy paper.
Scott: It's like is this worthy of the fancy paper?
Scott: you end up writing all my notes.
Scott: It's like I bought this fancy paper because it's so nice to write out.
Scott: end up writing notes on all the shitty pad.
Rym: Yeah, is it sponge worthy?
Scott: because it's like I don't care for right on that one.
Rym: What I want to start doing when we get back into doing RPGs in person is Any all the fancy notebooks.
Rym: I've collected over the years every time.
Rym: There's a big RPG.
Rym: This is gonna go on for a while.
Rym: I'm just gonna take my notes in that book just page by page.
Scott: See that's what I always think is like each little.
Scott: each tiny notebook I have I have like four or five was for a different purpose, right?
Scott: It's like I have a netrunner one.
Scott: Yeah, I wrote all my netrunner stuff in and it's like I didn't finish it.
Scott: But it's like.
Scott: and now it's got a lot of pages in it.
Scott: It's still a perfectly good notebook, but it's like.
Scott: am I gonna put something on?
Scott: that netrunner is done.
Scott: So what do I do with that?
Scott: just leave this, you know?
Scott: 80% unused.
Rym: I say good put a bookmark in it and like when the world starts up again And we play like a blades in the dark game in Queens.
Rym: use that for your blades in the dark game.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like.
Scott: but it's like.
Scott: it just feels me Unorganized and like have two purposes in the same, you know, it's like going one way and now I'm doing another thing.
Rym: Leave you it'll leave you an artifact.
Rym: So years later.
Rym: You'll have a notebook where you're like, hey, what the fuck's this notebook?
Rym: And you'll see hey my netrunner notes and then oh that blades in the dark game.
Rym: I played with Rym and then after that, it's like oh that other RPG.
Scott: I played with Joey Joe, but I already have Several such notebooks for different things and they're each single purpose and they're each only like not even 10% used Right.
Rym: Well, the problem is for RPGs.
Rym: I tend to just keep a Google Doc for each RPG and keep adding to it and Even just have a laptop if I'm at the RPG to type notes in.
Scott: so I think what I'm gonna do though is I'm not buying I have you know written off buying any more and what I'll do yourself to use them.
Scott: I'll force to use all the ones I have because they do have nice papers in them Which is you know, ultra nice and very compatible with the pens and pencils that I've chosen right out ultra smooth and comfortable And I can't really see much improvement in that department, yep I'm gonna use them until they're all done Right, but next when I do eventually buy more notebook when they're all full I'm gonna buy ones where I can tear the pages out because all them all the ones I have now are ones who you can't Really remove the pages nicely.
Scott: And if I could remove the pages then I could for example remove all the netrunner pages Right and then not feel bad.
Scott: I'd almost feel like I have a brand new notebook ready to roll right, ah So I'm gonna get page removable ones In the future whenever that distant future is when I use up all this freaking paper.
Rym: Yeah, the problem is right now because this this Podcast we're recording is a moment in time in the middle of the biggest global pandemic in contemporary history because I don't go anywhere I don't write anything down anymore because I'm always at my computer if I'm doing anything.
Scott: Oh, I still have this pad next to my computer, which is it's actually a post-it pad.
Scott: It's like it's kind of long and has lines on it, but these are sticky Right and I use that for almost everything but my work.
Rym: I guess my head my trouble is my work.
Rym: all my work stuff is Like I don't need because I'm not going to meetings anymore like the work environment So different that I just have one long notepad doc that I can't call my notes in see.
Scott: at work.
Scott: I had some some Muji notebooks that were extra thin right.
Scott: they were all like books right and actually at work I used them up like I actually finished them at work because that's a single.
Scott: They didn't have that many pages in them right, but it's like yeah, you know it's like at work.
Scott: They're single-purpose up there.
Scott: They sit on my desk at work.
Scott: They don't write.
Scott: So there's no worrying about.
Scott: you know work.
Scott: unless I get fired or something right and if I get fired or I quit I leave Them at work.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: it's like yeah, these are yours, but we had a training at work, and I was given This moleskine that is a big blank white pages.
Scott: So I've been since I got that at work, and I finished all the Muji ones at work.
Scott: I'm just using this now because it was given to me for free for work only.
Scott: so When that finishes then I guess I'll have to buy something new for work only.
Rym: yep Well, we'll see if I ever even go back to an office.
Scott: That's also true, but you know the thing.
Scott: the last thing I just want to say is that you know the fancy paper.
Scott: you know it's like you know.
Scott: as nerds We're always fascinated by like Japanese stuff right.
Scott: It's such a nerd.
Scott: you know It's somewhat racist American nerd.
Rym: weaves are really into Japanese type thing even if they're not into anime right.
Scott: But I just can't it.
Scott: despite it being stereotyped or whatever you want to say I don't know what the paper is like in other countries.
Scott: there might be countries with even better paper than Japan right But I just don't have access to that paper.
Scott: But for some reason Japanese paper is just way nicer even It's not even just the paper and like notebooks and stationery right.
Scott: if I buy Gundams and have them delivered from Japan the cardboard box They're delivered in is nicer and smoother and not as rough Right.
Scott: it doesn't have as much like a you.
Scott: a United States cardboard box from like Amazon is like the corrugation.
Scott: It's just sort of like it's scratchy right whereas the box the Gundams come in It's like it's.
Scott: so it's like it just feels nicer.
Scott: the aesthetic of it is like.
Rym: You know the the same way that like oh it depends though like I got my GoPro And it like it was in the Amazon box, but inside of it Well like was another box and that box was super nice.
Scott: paper right right, but I'm talking about the the brown Cardboard not the like.
Scott: Like.
Scott: you buy a ground card by an iPhone right it's like the iPhone technically comes in a cardboard box.
Scott: I think right it's sort of plasticky a little bit, but it's like that what you know.
Scott: the Cardboard Apple's using for the actual product is extra fancy, but I'm like the outer shipping box is So nice like the one you're gonna recycle like right And it's like it's just the paper that they use for everything.
Scott: so nice like there.
Scott: It's like they talk about how their manga paper is so cheap, but it's like actually What is their paper making technology do they do?
Scott: they just care more about the the aesthetic of the the paper right I?
Rym: Don't know yeah, but the hard part is something about.
Rym: I don't know much about paper beyond like the minimum.
Scott: I don't know anything about the paper.
Scott: I just know that like if I buy I understand paper weight Would you or yeah if I buy paper and stationary from a Japanese company?
Scott: It's just nicer.
Scott: That's all I know.
Scott: And when I go to Staples if I go to the Kinokuniya store or Muji to buy stationary all the stuff is super nice And it's super smooth.
Rym: We got to do a double-blind trial to see if this is just.
Scott: if I go to if I go to Staples to buy some paper.
Rym: It's always me right When the world opens up, let's do a double-blind trial.
Rym: I'll get some Muji paper some staples paper, and we're gonna see All right, so I guess actually not a bad idea.
Rym: They'll be good.
Rym: They'll be a good night show.
Rym: yeah Good this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website At frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patreons for this episode of GeekNights are Ellen Joyce, I didn't mean to kill Marty green.
Rym: You just like a dude guy jerks option Graham Finch.
Rym: you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: But she packed my suitcase and sent me on my way at Clinton Walton.
Rym: J Bants ran from New Zealand.
Rym: Ryan parent Nicholas Brando Chris mid kit sailor vista the thirst for hydrated Ganon dread Lily Tenebra Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein sure from unhole and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names.
Rym: Stay safe out there.
Rym: Keep protesting.
Rym: Keep it all up.
Rym: It's working.
Rym: We're getting this dumb reform and we got to get more reform.
Rym: We'll see you on the flip side.
Rym: Maybe we'll start streaming shows again in a few weeks But for the time being we really don't want to distract from everything that's going on.
Rym: But anyway right now and leave you with something a little weird.
Rym: I'm going into battle and I want your strongest Potions.
Rym: My potions are too strong for you traveler potions.
Rym: And tell you I'm going into battle and I want only your strongest potions.
Rym: You can't handle my potions.
Rym: They're too strong for you potion seller.
Scott: Listen to me.
Rym: My potions would kill you traveler.
Rym: you cannot Sell up enough of these games and go and I need you.
Scott: My strongest potions will kill you traveler.
Rym: You can't handle my strongest potions.
Rym: You need to go to a seller that sells weak potions.
Rym: potions.
Rym: seller You take it right now.
Rym: I'm going into battle And I need only your strongest potions.
Rym: You don't know what you ask traveler.
Rym: my strongest potions will kill a dragon.
Scott: Let's blow them back.
Rym: You need a seller That sells weak potions.
Rym: People's fight.
Rym: potions are too strong.
Rym: You can't handle my strongest potions.