Rym: It's Thursday October 8th 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are reviewing the 2020 movie vampires versus the Bronx.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, we were gonna do a show on Tuesday on Star Wars portraits because like that's that's a game we have wanted to exist forever and it's about as good as I hoped it could be.
Rym: like there's a lot to say.
Rym: I There's a big review we want to do but couldn't do the review because I had a plumbing instant as you might have seen me tweet about.
Rym: so basically Sunday night, we're doing our movie night with our friends to watch this movie that we're gonna review and toward the end of that movie A noise happens.
Rym: There's a noise coming from what.
Scott: what noise was it?
Rym: sort of a burbling noise coming from the purple.
Rym: Okay, yeah, so go over and look and there is just sewer water coming up out of the drain like slowly filling the sink.
Scott: So the only way that can happen is if there is a clog beneath but there is still something Landing on that clog water right coming from above because it can't come from below magically, right?
Scott: Well, it there has to be.
Rym: what can?
Rym: that's why in some places, you know that whole thing about the basement toilets.
Rym: That's what those basement toilets are for.
Rym: So if the sewer just comes up it'll flood your basement instead of but the sewer.
Scott: the sewer coming up means that the sewer itself is clogged and water is coming into The sewer hitting that clog and backing up right?
Rym: Yeah, which can't happen.
Rym: I've seen that happen.
Scott: I've explained yeah, but it's not.
Scott: but it's not water coming up right like from say the ocean Whatever the s at the end.
Rym: Well, it's water coming up from water.
Scott: It's um, the water comes down From above gets stuck and it keeps coming and it fills up.
Rym: So that was the case here.
Rym: But it is possible for water to be pressurized from the sewer itself and fight its way back up Especially depending on the plumbing is with no no clog beneath it.
Rym: Yes That happens in a lot of terrifying situations that are thankfully not relevant here then also are rare in places like New York City but are kind of common in More rural places and suburban places with old plug.
Scott: So the clog wasn't just in your sink because it was just in your sink.
Scott: It would only come back up if you turned your water exactly.
Rym: This wasn't like it was.
Rym: I clog the sink and now I can't put water down and if I it's like
Scott: The clog is somewhere at the next level of plumbing and someone else has their water on and that water is hitting that clog and Filling up the pipe and coming out of your drain Because all the drains are connected which means other drains should also be having the same problem.
Rym: Not right necessarily because Billis apartment buildings can sometimes have surprisingly complex plumbing systems and From the information I had it was very difficult to figure out where exactly the pipes go.
Rym: who shares things?
Rym: I have learned now that our apartment is the lowest point On the line where if there's a clog in that line Before beneath the second floor is like connection to that line.
Rym: Our apartment will flood and no one else will.
Rym: So basically there's always one point that is like that in any site, right?
Scott: So you're the lowest on the totem pole of flooding in that it's here like yes.
Rym: Yeah, so I Wasn't.
Scott: it wasn't a building wide clog.
Scott: It was probably someone on your floor.
Rym: Yeah, almost definitely what has been happening?
Rym: because this happened once at the beginning of quarantine.
Rym: Remember when my dishwasher broke.
Rym: what happened was one day.
Rym: so when this I was thinking this is the same thing because I one day I was just like Fucking around in the kitchen and suddenly a bunch of what is clearly industrial drain cleaner comes up out of the sink Like it was acid drain cleaner like not that because when you buy a consumer drain cleaner it's usually a strong base like Drano, but Professional drain cleaner.
Rym: you can get both kinds and there is a professional drain cleaner.
Rym: That's basically just Hydrochloric acid mixed with some stuff.
Rym: It was clearly that All right.
Rym: So in that case someone else probably had a clog and probably tried to deal with it instead of calling the super.
Rym: So it came up.
Rym: our sink called the super.
Rym: they dealt with it.
Rym: That's what destroyed the impeller motor in our dishwasher and we didn't have a dishwasher for much of the early days of quarantine Which was fantastic because we were cooking more than we'd ever cooked in the decade of living here, but whatever.
Rym: So soon as this happens, I call I go downstairs and I tell it that like hey like hey We need some help.
Rym: waters coming up ends and the water just kept coming.
Rym: It didn't stop.
Rym: It was filling the dishwasher and the sink.
Scott: they means that somebody didn't turn their like water off.
Scott: Someone was running water Right above.
Scott: Yeah, right and it was coming all the way down hitting the clog and then filling up the pie Basically anyone above us in the column that supports our kitchen.
Rym: luckily the bathrooms are a separate system thankfully, so there's no problem.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: Okay, anytime anyone use their sink at all our water level just rise.
Rym: Yeah, there was no way to fix this because it's very hard to get emergency plumbers right now in New York because of the quarantine.
Scott: So you have to tell every single person don't use your kitchen water at all up and the building Said they were gonna do that, but they didn't.
Rym: I also overheard when they were talking in Spanish.
Rym: I'm pretty sure they have no way to shut off the hot water anywhere in the building because there are several broken valves Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's just an interesting tidbit.
Rym: I'm gonna remember for the future, but basically what they ended up doing is giving us a shop vac and Emily stayed up all night like literally all night watching the sink cuz about every 15 minutes.
Rym: we have to shop vac out the sink and Shop vac out the dishwasher to prevent our apartment from flooding roll.
Scott: I wonder if there's some way that you can make some sort of a claim either.
Scott: renters insurance?
Rym: I could but I would have to sue the landlord and Do a bunch of stuff with lawyers that would cost me more than what I could get back because the most or just I could withhold.
Scott: You got to sue.
Scott: you could just talk to the landlord first.
Rym: I have this landlord give a shit landlord basically said take it up with the super.
Rym: so unless I sue them There's nothing they will ever do All right, well, yep.
Rym: So, uh all night Emily is shot back in this thing because we can't just leave it.
Scott: because if we ignore it the sinkers Well, then what do you do?
Scott: in the shop vac fills up?
Scott: And why do people?
Rym: why are people running their water at night in their kitchen people if around 3 or 4 a.m They pretty much stopped running their water?
Rym: And the only reason Emily had to stay up the rest of the night was just in case like couldn't risk that Can't risk that disaster.
Rym: So every time we filled the shop vac, which was like every couple every two times this happened We'd roll it into the elevator and the night doorman knew about the situation.
Rym: I was helping us out and he would go drain it in like the like the Industrial sinks in the building and send it back up the elevator for us.
Rym: Why don't you just send it down the bathtub toilet, uh That actually would have been a giant pain because I would have had to run the shop vac in reverse or lift the Extremely heavy shop vac filled with water.
Scott: You don't lift it you run in reverse.
Rym: Yeah, running it in reverse who spews?
Rym: because it's shot backs tend to leak a lot.
Scott: I was not gonna get into a bet into a bathtub.
Rym: Yeah, that that was not gonna fly.
Rym: So we did this whole like shuttle operation.
Rym: all night in the morning Emily fell asleep and I kept an eye on it for the next like five hours while I was trying to get work done.
Scott: Well in the morning, it probably started going real.
Rym: Oh, I was just.
Rym: I was just shot back and constantly and at one point while I was waiting for the shop vac to come back I was bailing water into the bathtub with a bucket.
Rym: So eventually around like noon the plumber at the emergency plumber actually shows up.
Scott: and could you have Could you have right take the top off the shop vac?
Scott: right and run a run a hose from the bottom of the shop vac to the bathtubs to carry a constant I We if this were my house, that is what I would have done.
Rym: The building did not have any tubes long enough to do that like when you were kids like I remember we had floods like that in our house and we had like an industrial shop vac and We would do exactly what you described like that's.
Scott: oh, we actually didn't have a shop vac but what we did have was we actually had a Water pump that you would use to fill or empty the pool the swimming pool Yeah And it's basically just a thing that floats in the pool and you attach a garden hose to it and a power cable to it And it pumps water out the hose.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we are actually cheated with filling the pools because you know My dad was a fire could have put that.
Scott: you could have put that in the sink with a garden hose running over to the Tub and just turn it on.
Rym: my dad was a fireman.
Rym: one time We filled our pool by just plugging in the fire hose and run it over to the pool and it filled the pool.
Scott: That saves a lot of time.
Scott: we did with the garden hose took forever.
Rym: Oh, yeah, if we filled the pool in like an hour like done like yeah, it was amazing.
Rym: That was probably super illegal, but whatever statute of limitations.
Rym: Oh, is it?
Scott: I assume from the bed is mean from the from the fire hydrant?
Rym: Well one we didn't pay that water bill because there's no fire hydrant.
Rym: and two that is definitely a misappropriation of civic infrastructure.
Rym: Yeah, of course I repair.
Rym: we had to paint that fire hydrant ourselves because it was on our property.
Rym: so Anyway, so, uh, eventually the plumber comes and sends us and he explained to me the layout Like I know the layout now of the building and like where all the pipes go.
Rym: cuz he's the plumbers pretty cool.
Rym: so he sent like a 60-foot snake in there and fucked up some terrifying shit that he found in there.
Rym: and Basically someone in our building just sucks and has clearly been putting things down there drain They shouldn't be and caused this problem.
Rym: So he fixed it.
Rym: The water is running fine.
Rym: He leaves Late that night.
Rym: the next night starts up again.
Rym: same problem.
Rym: Then they had to take our whole sink apart because they needed to use the longer snake.
Rym: So they had to take apart like our sink the they had to take apart like they drilled a hole in our drain lines.
Scott: Why do they have to take apart the sink?
Scott: Can't they just go under the sink remove the.
Rym: you know the thing and uh, I don't know if you do you know a lot about plumbing they had to remove the bit that is Inserted into the bottom of a sink that connects to the drain.
Rym: that's actually like a separate bit in sinks like you screw it in.
Rym: Anyway, he took all that apart because he had to get the snake in like the root of the pipes And he sent it even longer snake down and that fixed it again, and he was basically like yeah So if this ever happens again The problem is in the like basement infrastructure of the building and it's gonna be a big problem.
Rym: and then he left Hmm.
Rym: So that was my fun couple of days.
Scott: It sounds like they actually it doesn't sound like a neighbor actually fucked up twice.
Scott: It sounds like the clog was pushed deeper.
Scott: Yeah, push and then claw and then clogged again.
Scott: and now that has been pushed even deeper.
Scott: It's now in a larger pipe and has been gone, but it could happen again if someone shoved something bad again.
Rym: Yeah based on what was coming up out of the drain I think a lot of people just put coffee grounds down the drain like all of them.
Rym: I'm pretty sure that's a big part of it.
Scott: I Guess they could clog if they clump up, right?
Rym: Like if they do it if someone is also pouring grease and fat down the drain which you're not supposed to do in quantity.
Rym: Coffee grounds plus fat in quantity will definitely cause that problem.
Rym: Mm-hmm based on plumbing knowledge that I have and having seen this on the fat bird pictures I've seen in the yeah My dad did a lot of like house contracting on the side when we were kids to pay bills.
Rym: So, uh, I helped with some of that sometimes.
Scott: and why don't you just buy like a giant snake on the internet?
Rym: Yeah, where the hell am I gonna put that?
Rym: also those are very expensive, especially the powered ones.
Scott: You'll make up for it getting in the plumbing business.
Rym: Yeah, I could.
Rym: I do not want to be in the plumbing business though smelly.
Rym: Imagine if this clog had been in the.
Scott: you'd be you'd be it but you'd be a one-note plumber.
Scott: All you do is snake.
Scott: You don't do anything.
Scott: That's called roto-ruder.
Rym: You can just call roto-ruder.
Rym: Those guys don't get paid that much.
Rym: So, yeah got some news.
Scott: Do I have news?
Rym: I forget the NHL draft.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Yeah, so the NHL draft happened.
Scott: It was obviously weird because under normal circumstances you would be just playing hockey by October 8th 7th, whatever day.
Scott: You know as I think we discussed previously the Rangers won the twelve and a half percent lottery And had the first pick.
Scott: they picked the best player.
Scott: It's no surprise to anybody.
Scott: It was interesting because you know, this is the first time they weren't able to hold it in a large Place everyone together.
Scott: So, you know the different teams that to communicate with each other via, you know digital means The players had to celebrate in their homes, right?
Scott: Like, you know, they're just sitting there with a camera pointed at him so people can see their reaction or whatever.
Scott: You know, it was a weird one.
Rym: Yeah, I just I ended up just watching a Twitter feed Anna Fark thread that had like the updates plus your commentary and a few other people's commentary in the discords.
Scott: Yeah, I think somebody called it like a. they had that they.
Scott: what did they call it?
Rym: And I've seen people call it the baby auction.
Scott: Yeah, it was basically like a child.
Scott: So this is something along those lines.
Rym: The only thing I cared about was the Rangers One that we won that had that winning lottery ticket from the draft lottery number one overall pick I'll take it not really deserve because the Rangers are actually a pretty good team During their rebuild.
Scott: but listen, you got to prevent people from tanking, right?
Scott: That is to you know.
Scott: And it worked out the lottery in the first place.
Scott: the best-case scenario and elder instead is giving it to Detroit the worst team Right.
Rym: Yeah, like if we did it in the perfect world, yeah the Detroit and like Buffalo would have gotten like all the good kids.
Scott: Yeah, especially in a year like this where you have one player who's just ridiculously good, right?
Scott: It's like yeah Yeah, I'll see Loughren yay, whatever.
Rym: Yeah But we won that lottery had the winning lottery ticket.
Rym: So the only thing the Rangers did first is cash in that lottery ticket and get that kid and all they have to do Is not break him.
Rym: Just don't hurt that.
Scott: I think the the most interesting thing was what the Commissioner said at the start.
Scott: They plan to.
Scott: their current plan is to somehow start an NHL season on January 1st, and I'm like really?
Scott: How are you gonna do that?
Rym: I don't think there's gonna be a 2021 NHL season because the playoffs only worked because they made this Isolated bubble and only a few teams had to be there and as time went on fewer and fewer teams had to be there.
Rym: They like like a really complicated schedule of like Right group teams together get a bunch of games in group a different set together like it'd be a weird schedule.
Scott: So my prediction for the bubble was that they would start it and not finish it and I was wrong.
Scott: They've finished it.
Scott: so my prediction now would be just what you said It's just not gonna happen, but I think we're gonna have to plus one.
Scott: it right.
Scott: so I think that now the adjusted prediction is this time they're gonna start and not finish.
Rym: Yeah I think this one's much more.
Rym: There are a lot more vectors of the season does not continue when it's every team as opposed to a few teams.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what's gonna be with that.
Scott: You know, some people are really confident.
Scott: someone was.
Scott: I was like I tried to ask like hey, what's the ticket situation gonna be?
Scott: How about you just write it, right?
Scott: When is there gonna be a game I can actually go to?
Rym: Cuz yeah, cuz ever that my biggest fear is if they had if they if New York opens up to where there will be games But it's too early next year.
Rym: I don't know if I trust going Right.
Scott: It's like I'm very determined to be like listen the first game that they allow anyone to go to.
Scott: I want to be there right because that would be a big-time deal, right?
Scott: It's like, you know.
Scott: But at the same time if they decide to be stupid and have a game and let people come when it's not safe to come I ain't gonna go.
Scott: That's ridiculous.
Scott: Why would I do that?
Rym: Well, there's that I saw.
Rym: there's a bunch of stuff.
Rym: I was saying the same thing.
Rym: people's behavior is In that situation across the board like if restaurants or like theaters or anything open is tied directly to whether or not they're Republican Or a Democrat in the United States and generally.
Scott: but like what if they take my money and like here's tickets And I'm like, I'd have to sell them I guess to someone who's willing to go.
Scott: But that feels good.
Rym: scalping tickets during kovat that is like selling the jib the the devil bottle.
Scott: I'm not willing to.
Rym: Maybe It's basically.
Rym: the story is very simply.
Rym: you've got this bottle.
Rym: It gives you fantastic powers But if you die while you still own it you go to hell in the bottle forever.
Rym: There's no way out.
Rym: All right, you can only sell it for less than you paid for it.
Rym: At some point someone's fucked by this bottle.
Rym: if you sell it You have the plausible deniability of well the person I sold it to might sell it to someone else before they die.
Rym: But at some point there is a smallest amount of currency at which time somebody goes to hell.
Rym: how culpable somebody you.
Scott: well, I think what would happen in this case is that unlike the devil bottle right is I would sell it for close to what it cost.
Scott: You know the next person if they decide they don't want to take the risk they sell it for right and then eventually You know It's like everyone along the line is Recouping most of their money and somewhat towards the end of the line is like paying a penny and not use.
Scott: just not using the ticket.
Scott: They're not going to hell.
Scott: They're just basically.
Rym: I feel like someone will use the ticket though.
Rym: I feel like someone will go.
Scott: Well, that's there.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: If we just don't get tickets at all.
Rym: This tickets are still gonna get sold Though maybe they won't because that partisan thing the the study showed very clearly.
Rym: People like Democrats like most people live in New York Won't go to things no matter what the law is if the law says restaurants are open.
Rym: Most people here will not actually go to them.
Rym: some well, but most won't Yep, but in other states like people will go no matter what like.
Rym: they'll even try to go if they're not allowed to.
Scott: We'll see what happened.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Some other news from my home state.
Rym: if you're not aware the state of Michigan is known for a few things.
Rym: their state animal is the Wolverine.
Rym: Michigan is the only state outside of the Civil War to go to it to go to war with another states.
Rym: It had a war with Ohio.
Rym: That was just stupid all around.
Rym: It's the only state that ever tried to invade a foreign country.
Rym: Michigan tried to invade Canada once because Michigan and The northern part of Michigan is filled with militia nutjobs.
Rym: now in the rest of the country There are militia nutjobs, but the Michigan militias are way more dangerous Way heavier armed and way less subject to the scrutiny of the law for a lot of reasons.
Rym: Like they're dangerous to law enforcement.
Rym: They're dangerous to everybody.
Rym: They're just.
Scott: it's really.
Scott: it's a geographical thing, right?
Scott: It's like you look at Michigan.
Rym: You got this hand-shaped kind of thing Up in the top of the fingers that is like Right hills and mining and shit Right like way up towards.
Scott: that goes like if you don't know Detroit is like in the bottom, right?
Scott: It's it's way down.
Rym: almost the entire economy and population of Michigan is in the southeast bottom little corner.
Rym: The whole rest of it is just Hicks, right?
Scott: Yeah, you go to the top right in between Michigan Lake Michigan and Lake Huron right at that pointy part, you know and Parts south of that.
Scott: It's pretty much just the middle of nowhere.
Scott: You know, it's not really.
Scott: you look at a Google satellite view and you'll see it's just green.
Rym: Yeah, it's a huge state.
Rym: But and there's that whole other bit that we in that war with Ohio.
Rym: That's why we won that bit in the top.
Rym: They took it from Wisconsin gave it to us Right here.
Scott: Let's let's zoom in on that area.
Scott: See what kind of towns we can find.
Scott: Here's a town called Petoskey.
Scott: Let's see.
Rym: He's awesome.
Rym: Actually Petoskey is a really fun place to go.
Scott: It has a movie theater and a Home Depot and a Walmart and a Lowe's Petoskey Applebee's Mackinaw and a Buffalo Wild Wing Island Traverse City, basically everything along the coast is also cool.
Rym: It's when you get into that middle part or when you get into the middle part or okay.
Scott: Yeah, Petoskey was on the water.
Scott: Let's pick one in the middle Lewiston Lewiston's in the middle.
Scott: Let's see what they got.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, hey, there's a wild ones.
Scott: Yeah a convenience store a supermarket a post office a hardware Doesn't even have any chains in it.
Rym: Yeah Now look now church got zoom in will go up to that upper peninsula and just zoom in like somewhere in the middle of it.
Rym: there's like in the Squares of roads and like mountains and copper mines.
Scott: I see Gwynn Gwynn UP.
Scott: What are they?
Scott: No new Swansea Larry's family.
Rym: just funny the Petoskey is the first place you mentioned.
Rym: Petoskey just happens to be super awesome.
Scott: It was on the coast.
Scott: That's why it stood out here.
Rym: But yeah, basically the Michigan militias a car wash.
Scott: There's a car wash a lot of reasons in a dollar store super dangerous and organized and big.
Rym: They one of them just legit like had a plan to kidnap the governor of the state and try to stage a coup Like an organized one they arrested.
Scott: thing is even if you do successfully kidnap the governor of the state that does not create a coup Situation.
Scott: well that cuz that's the thing the lieutenant governor would presumably take over or whatever Michigan has.
Rym: Yeah, also, I feel like at the point where a militia has kidnapped the governor of a state.
Rym: I Think the National Guard shows up.
Rym: I think like things escalate rapidly.
Scott: That's what I was gonna say.
Scott: The lieutenant governor would just be like, hey, I ordered the National Guard to go.
Rym: Okay, there's the other thing you gotta remember for a scene as these militias are the one thing they are not is intelligence.
Scott: So But well, I mean it's already showed that they're not intelligent.
Scott: They thought that kidnapping the governor makes you the governor or something.
Rym: Yeah but they seem to have been emboldened because of Trump talking about how Michigan needs to be liberated from its Democratic government and It's like that instigated them.
Rym: That's one point.
Rym: and all this shit show of 2020 but - they're a pretty big militia and I think 13 of their leaders are currently like arrested and The FBI has already said like yeah, this whole organization is going down like here we come.
Rym: it's.
Rym: uh, it's a crazy story and my news is that In any other year, this would have been like the headline for weeks.
Rym: This is barely being covered.
Scott: I don't know if it'd be the headline for weeks because the things like it actually happens pretty often because on this scale It happens pretty often where the law enforcement discovers something horrible and stops it in advance, right?
Scott: Yeah There have been several terrorist incidents.
Scott: would that have been stopped in advance and not just the ones where they trick someone into like where the FBI was the one selling someone bombs right more like here's yeah Here's a terror cell of three people that's real that we found and we stopped them.
Rym: We found their bomb.
Scott: Yeah, it actually it happens right but those stories tend not to be big news.
Scott: The only time they're big news is if the person actually attempts their thing, right?
Scott: So like, you know Fertilizer bomber guy in Times Square, right?
Scott: It's like yeah He just pretty much failed.
Scott: but it's like he attempted his thing and then got caught and therefore is a much bigger news story.
Scott: if they Had just found that guy a day earlier.
Rym: You wouldn't you might not even know about it, you know, so Yeah, but in this case it did that like if you read the whole thing This was a way more organized and serious plot than his typical.
Scott: Oh, yeah It was definitely a big a big-time plot.
Scott: But I'm just saying is that the the bigness of the news is due to the.
Scott: the.
Scott: the non bigness of the news is due To the being caught in advance.
Rym: I Don't think it's just that because this is bigger than any motion you can militia thing.
Rym: that's happened in a long time And I think it's man gets man.
Scott: Man gets stopped from biting dog is not as big a story as man bites dog.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know no matter how big the man or how crazy the dog you should They.
Rym: their plan was actually pretty comprehensive coming down to blowing up a bunch of bridges that they were like.
Rym: This was like a full-on Paramilitary operation.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It doesn't matter that no matter how big the dog or how scary the man Man gets.
Scott: stopped from biting dog is not as big a news story now.
Rym: We're in a news cycle.
Rym: We're like the fly that was showing us.
Rym: Mike Pence's true nature is like the big news and already that's being forgotten.
Scott: No, I mean, that's a that's a. they live situation.
Rym: Yeah I was actually watching that stupid debate because Kamala did a great job.
Rym: But the funniest thing was I'm watching it and then the fly appears and I literally stand up like what the fuck how to fly.
Rym: Get in here and I go over to like hit the TV and I'm like, oh, oh shit.
Rym: It's actually on him.
Scott: Why didn't?
Scott: why didn't he swat it?
Scott: Uh, that's what I don't understand.
Rym: I He might just be even like.
Rym: I don't know that is.
Rym: That is.
Rym: it is weird that he did not notice that because I noticed if a net comes within like a foot of my face I know right like like if we're in a panel and like a fly comes anywhere near the stage.
Rym: We're both like what the fuck fly anyway.
Rym: things Of the day.
Scott: when I was a kid my parents took us on a lot of you know vacations, right?
Scott: But you know, they weren't necessarily.
Scott: they weren't the tiniest vacations, right?
Scott: We weren't Unfortunate and poor we didn't like not go anywhere, but they also weren't the extravagant vacations.
Scott: I know a lot of people went on who had mad moneys, right?
Scott: Yeah, you know, so One of the places we went was the Catskill game farm Which is a place in the Catskills of New York, and it was basically like a mega petting zoo, right?
Scott: It's like they had all kinds of animals going on in there like giraffes even right You know, I don't know this was way back.
Scott: I don't know how well the animals were treated You don't know Right, but this is a place that like had everything from you know sheep up to giraffe, right?
Scott: And you would go there you'd pay admission.
Scott: It wasn't like a zoo.
Scott: It was like a petting zoo like very interactive You know, they called it a game farm, right?
Scott: They didn't call it a zoo.
Scott: I don't think they had a lot of you know, wasn't an educational place necessarily.
Scott: But anyway, apparently I had you know, we joke about it because we know my cousin.
Scott: There was some incidents there where she was very afraid of all the animals.
Scott: You know the place had memories from my family right where it were created there.
Scott: We only went there once though anyway.
Scott: So apparently I you know, I hadn't thought about the place in forever.
Scott: So I didn't realize that it was sold some years ago.
Scott: And when it was sold, you know people tried to rescue as many animals as they could and you know to keep them from getting You know sent to some who knows where.
Rym: that's literally what my mom's job used to be.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, it was sold to some people and those for a very low price and those people attempted to Basically convert it to like an inn, right?
Scott: You know, it's like you would go and stay there and like a fancy kind of in bed-and-breakfast kind of place.
Scott: You know, they renovated some of the buildings on the property.
Scott: It's a large property.
Rym: Yeah, the photos look nice.
Rym: It looks like renovated.
Scott: Yeah, they definitely successfully renovated it.
Rym: you know what it looks like.
Rym: look at these bedrooms rustic chic as in it looks rustic on purpose as opposed to Rustic because it's worn down and rustic.
Scott: Yeah, so they all the animals are gone.
Scott: They've been gone for years, but people renovated it and I noticed just by chance because we were discussing real estate I did a search on like Zillow and I just saw it pop up as like the most expensive property in the Catskills.
Scott: at two million dollars It was for sale.
Scott: So it seems that I guess because of the kovat situation or just because of bad business No one's staying at this in.
Scott: So They lost their investment and they're trying to recoup it.
Scott: So I was like, hey listen, you know, I understand you lost your.
Scott: you made a bad investment But you just sort of you just have to take a loss on that.
Scott: You're not gonna be able to make back your money.
Scott: No one's paying two million dollars for that.
Rym: I mean two million dollars could almost buy a two-bedroom apartment in my neighborhood.
Scott: it's like But apparently there's a pending offer.
Scott: I don't know how big the offer is.
Scott: I don't know if it's two million dollars or not, but somebody's offered to buy it according to the internet, which is fascinating.
Scott: so I wonder if the people who tried to do the renovation are gonna just take a loss how big a loss they're gonna take.
Scott: but It's interesting just to see this, you know, sort of like.
Scott: it's sort of like the action park, right?
Scott: It's like usually we see these abandoned amusement park type places.
Scott: Just be abandoned.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: please slowly decline
Scott: Right, it's like you look at like the splendid China in Orlando, which is a place We also went which is owned by the China or was owned by the Chinese government might still be I don't know but they set up a propaganda ish amusement park in in Orlando right to.
Scott: that celebrates China Has like fake terracotta warriors and that sort of thing, right?
Scott: We went there And that place I'm pretty sure is still just abandoned.
Scott: I don't know who owns it But it's weird to see one Abandoned be owned and tried to actually be used or done something with especially at a time like this.
Rym: Fuck is a three-quarter bathroom as opposed to a full.
Rym: I know a full and a half bath.
Rym: I've no idea what a three-quarter bath is.
Scott: I don't know if you google it and find out I am right now, but but yeah Has a shower but no tub, okay Okay, but yeah go and check out the Zillow posting for the castle game farm.
Scott: You can also google it on the internet and read about the history of the castle.
Scott: It's an interesting kind of place that I think people who aren't from New York Or aren't older don't even know exists and don't even think about.
Rym: but there are a lot of things that are within like a day trip of New York that exists primarily to serve kids who live in the New York area and like go upstate to Experience nature and such.
Scott: well, there's a lot of things in the Catskills Specifically, especially in the era before you know cheaper commercial more widely available commercial flight.
Scott: The many people who lived in New York and you know this New York area Needed to go on vacations and there are many leisurely destinations.
Scott: Same reason Atlantic City existed like people couldn't just fly to Vegas for a long time Especially in the Catskills this place like Lake Compounce in Connecticut, which I think is still open.
Scott: That were like these leisurely vacation resort type places and especially in the Catskills The culture of going there is completely gone and a lot of those places are abandoned closed out of business.
Rym: Goodbye, there are the region like.
Rym: there are places like that.
Scott: They are very fascinating.
Rym: There are places like that everywhere like Cedar Point was one of those places.
Rym: The only reason it survived is that it became a roller coaster park in the era When people could actually just fly to Florida instead of going to Lake Erie.
Scott: Right, it's like if you weren't worse.
Scott: there were places that were leisurely destinations that were worth going to because they were within range.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah, but as soon as if you're not the best thing in range Well, people can just fly to a better thing.
Scott: So you have to be like the best thing, you know, that's like I wouldn't have gone to Cedar Point.
Rym: We couldn't afford that.
Rym: We would have gone to whatever like Six Flags was near us.
Rym: We just it's like.
Scott: you have to either be worth flying to like Disney World people come from all over Or you have to be good enough that someone who can fly Right is who or is decided not to fly or can't afford to fly will choose you Right, and there's not too many people left because so many people are flying so not too many of those things can exist locally.
Scott: Yep So but yeah, the abandoned ones are fascinating.
Rym: So my thing of the day I got to back up a little bit to the concept of BMX bikes.
Rym: Uh BMX biking wasn't really a thing until the early 80s like late 70s.
Scott: Oh the early that is that is true.
Scott: In fact my town in the in the 90s had a BMX track at one of the parks.
Scott: It might still be.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we had one too.
Rym: I had a BMX bike and I went there and there were certain kids.
Scott: I didn't I wasn't one of those kids but I knew some kids were.
Scott: it's like they were on they like.
Scott: they went there and Competed officially.
Scott: It was almost like a little league level competitive.
Rym: Oh, yeah, my middle school had a BMX team.
Rym: It was the school supported it, but it was like a little one.
Scott: It didn't have anything to do with the school.
Scott: It was.
Scott: I don't know who ran it, but it was ours.
Rym: We did.
Rym: it was a third-party thing, but the school like endorsed it and kids from the school would go to it.
Scott: But here was.
Scott: I Found it on.
Scott: I found it on Google.
Scott: Yep, Trumbull BMX track.
Scott: I found it.
Rym: There it is but I feel like it's interesting because Before like our generation like me and Scott born in the early 80s We grew up during the literal beginning and peak of BMX biking.
Rym: So today most kids get like a tricycle and then they basically get like a mountain bike or a cruiser next.
Rym: When we were kid and before that it was similar when we were kids Every kid got a BMX bike before they got a bigger bike like BMX bike was the step above trike for most kids.
Scott: Because yeah, I think before before mountain because mountain bikes are actually a relatively recent invention.
Rym: Yeah, they were like before.
Rym: Before that were like hacked together monstrosities that didn't like a custom.
Scott: It's like before the Toys R Us racks are filled with mountain bikes They were filled with BMX bikes basic and before that they were filled with Cruiser bikes.
Scott: Yeah, so yeah.
Scott: But the BMX biking that you know that style was basically, you know more like a motocross, but you pedal.
Rym: Yeah, it literally just stands for it's a bicycle motocross.
Scott: Yes, it's just a dirt track with a bunch of hills excite bikes around Like that.
Scott: you race around by pedaling you do jumps that sort of thing and that was like.
Rym: but the problem was it's not bad because the thing about BMX biking was that most kids did not actually BMX bike on BMX courses.
Rym: they got BMX bikes But then they ride them around the neighborhood and BMX bikes actually really suck at that.
Rym: but that like they sure do.
Rym: Yep so my thing of the day is This archive of the totally rad fad of 80s BMX and this is like All the.
Scott: it was a totally rad fad.
Scott: just
Rym: the style the advertising the counterculture the culture like the Advertisements that got kids into it the celebrities from it the aesthetics of it the everything It's just all
Scott: definitely has a particular aesthetic of like a checkered flag and like yeah, that's like super That's kind of it's cut, you know.
Scott: at the time it was a little bit cheesy But now it's kind of retro cheesy cool or like really like badly clashing colors like the color scheme of BM.
Rym: Oh, yeah, right.
Scott: It's all about bright colors like neon
Rym: zinc NASCAR, but on a shitty looking bike
Scott: Exactly, but he
Rym: was huge like as a kid like we had like I had some BMX like racer trading cards like the capitalist system was really trying to sell kids on how cool BMX was and it worked on us for a long time and This webpage just shows that.
Rym: is that Somewhat adjacent to monster truck as well, which I was also very into as a kid.
Rym: I thought that was a career I could have be a monster truck driver, which technically I guess good That is a career you could have.
Rym: I think it pays that much Huh?
Scott: I don't know how much it pays but it's a career you can have.
Rym: also a fun fact I went to many monster truck shows.
Rym: I never went to.
Scott: I went to zero.
Scott: I only saw the commercial.
Rym: I went to so many going.
Rym: I even went to like low tier like semi amateur ones.
Rym: But I also went to a lot of demolition derbies as a kid.
Rym: I grew up in Michigan.
Rym: What do you want?
Rym: Yeah, but I Never once saw grave digger actually complete a course.
Rym: every time grave digger was there it either broke down Before the race or broke down in the race.
Rym: I never saw it finish a race.
Rym: even once my entire life even though it was my favorite car Wasn't Bigfoot like the big one.
Rym: Yeah Bigfoot was like the Hulk Hogan and that's what everyone liked great.
Scott: So grave digger was like the undertaker dig.
Rym: Yeah, great Literally grave jigger was.
Rym: the people who liked the undertaker tended to like grave digger The same way that kids today was like, I don't know Reaper from overwatch.
Rym: I was that kid.
Rym: Everyone's got their Bigfoot shirt and I'm the kid with like the grave digger shirt.
Rym: like ah, I like the cool car.
Rym: Anyway in the meta moment the GeekNights book club book, we're not reading the tale again because we're not reading anything nothing at all.
Rym: I have not read fiction in like two months.
Rym: I'm just reading nonfiction.
Rym: only to uh Have I read any fiction?
Rym: cuz I read some comics.
Scott: I've read comics.
Scott: I've been reading some comics but in terms Rose when is the last prose fiction?
Scott: I read probably chapters of the Tale of Genji.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Also chapters.
Rym: In fact, you know what I last read.
Rym: I read a whole chapter of the Tale of Genji on the way back from PAX East Which was literally the start of quarantine and that was the last time.
Scott: I may have read some around then as well.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, I was on the Amtrak the Acela and I've read that that was it.
Rym: That was the last time I read.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, we'll read it at some point.
Rym: stay tuned.
Rym: blame COVID.
Rym: We just did another panel.
Rym: I'm gonna try to get the video of a director's cut of the panel We did at PAX online up on our YouTube channel this weekend, maybe like Tuesday or Wednesday at the latest But I don't know otherwise.
Rym: we got no conventions coming up.
Rym: we're getting into the cold dark times.
Rym: We're getting into the times where normally we have a bunch of travel and vacations.
Rym: GeekNights gets interrupted a bunch But I ain't going anywhere.
Scott: Nope You know, I don't want to shit talk.
Scott: So I'm not gonna.
Scott: but I will say that you know I was under the impression that my work was going to increase the number of vacation days We could hold over to next year.
Scott: who they?
Rym: but they lied but did not confirm right?
Scott: Right, right They basically said they.
Scott: well they said pretty much You know, hold on we're gonna be making it in some Messaging about that around the block too many times to trust that.
Scott: right, so, you know, they basically said well, we'll say something about that soon, but like my My product manager recently that's my said that he was.
Scott: he was pressured to use PTO Which he hadn't used all year.
Scott: So he's taking off next week.
Scott: So this is making me think they're there, you know.
Rym: Hopefully we had like a lot of days like way too many saved up, right?
Scott: Well, the point is I might end up not working most of December, right?
Scott: So I can't shit talk and say yeah, if I don't work most of December, I'm gonna do some stuff But if I don't work for most of December, it is likely I'll do something.
Scott: Yep I hope I mean I might not but I would feel guilty if I didn't make even one thing.
Rym: Oh my god I'm still like kovat messes up my sense of time like this quarantine to be in the house.
Rym: Like I Feel like every time I'm relaxing like even though I'm just playing Star Wars.
Rym: I'm thinking I should really be like making a panel editing some stuff like putting more GeekNights.
Scott: I made a panel during.
Scott: I already did my coat.
Rym: We did a bunch of panels already.
Scott: You're you're gonna upload.
Rym: Yeah, but I want.
Rym: but I had a bunch of solo panels I wanted to do.
Rym: I want to start the utenna thing, but I don't have time.
Rym: Well, you'll have some time.
Rym: We'll see if you do anything.
Scott: So if I have time, yeah, we'll see.
Rym: I don't have time so it can't be joint projects.
Rym: I have no more free time than I normally would Mmm, so yeah, let's get right into it.
Rym: It's a spooky times time to watch spooky stuff and we got together with a bunch of our friends and we watch Vampires versus the Brock's.
Rym: We'll get to spoilers at the end because I want to talk about like the things that happen in this movie But to review it first don't worry.
Scott: No spoilers Yeah, so this is a movie that is Netflix exclusive.
Scott: I think Netflix made it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's a pretty.
Scott: it's a pretty short movie.
Rym: I think I don't think it's that long like it looks like they started on it in 2018 but then they cut a deal with Netflix to like get it fully made and like that's.
Rym: you could read the story and Basically, it's a story pretty straightforward.
Scott: Where there are vampires in the Bronx, that's not a spoiler.
Scott: It's in the title And it's in the.
Scott: it's in the summary.
Scott: right the vampires are also committing gentrification.
Scott: they're buying up properties and Converting them from say, you know a bodega into you know a bone and thread.
Scott: is it?
Scott: is it a food place or is it a?
Rym: The worst part is one of the fake gentrification things was that butter store.
Rym: and while my brain said Simultaneously that is some gentrifying bullshit a part of my brain said I would shop there.
Scott: I would go buy fancy butter I would buy fancy butter and make cookies out of it.
Scott: Yeah anyway.
Scott: So it's a. it's a you know, it's a pretty.
Scott: It's Not like a super complex movie is a straightforward Vampire movie.
Scott: In fact, I will say it is I would say it's at the level of like a made-for-tv movie the kind of thing you'd see on like wonderful world of Disney.
Rym: I'd say it's a full step above that.
Rym: It is actually at the level of quality of the Lost Boys.
Scott: Well, I mean I would say right on time out Like The acting is better than one of those TV movies for certain.
Rym: Yeah, but you're right in terms of the plot.
Rym: It is fairly straightforward.
Rym: The few twists are right.
Rym: good, but they're not like.
Rym: there's not Citizen Kane twists Yeah, not even close, right?
Rym: But the Lost Boys 2 is a very straightforward plot.
Rym: kid move kid is in town finds vampires vampire shit happens vampire confrontation happens.
Rym: end of movie.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much right it's.
Scott: it's a movie about some kids, you know, they live in the Bronx.
Scott: they discover these problems You know, they fight their problems with the help of the community right the community bands together.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much exactly what you expect really straightforward But with that simple formula that doesn't really have you know Too much clever or new or interesting about the formula wise right.
Scott: the execution It's like wow, you know you did.
Scott: you took that cookie cutter, right and you just like cut out the best damn cookie, right?
Scott: It's like the cookie.
Scott: It's like you cut the edges of the cookie cutter.
Scott: Perfect the thickness of the cookie Perfectly uniform right.
Scott: the dough and the flavor of the cookie as good as it could be in a plain old butter cookie Which is still damn tasty.
Rym: I want to eat that like the characters and like their chatter with each other like are just great.
Rym: Like the characters are really compelling really fun.
Rym: They're deep enough without like everyone having a long origin story nonsense.
Rym: Like it just hits all the right beats.
Scott: They missed on a few things.
Scott: There were some characters that could have had more screen time.
Scott: Maybe some that had too much.
Rym: one of them should have had one bust out moment and killed a vampire.
Scott: Yeah, but they didn't.
Rym: I was hoping the priest would do more but the priest was funny enough.
Rym: I Did hope he did more also I hope do you I hope he would show up and be the dad or the grandpa from Lost Boys That like I expected that to happen.
Rym: That was the only thing.
Rym: I expect this movie to do that.
Rym: It did not do.
Scott: Yep The movie is extremely New York II and extremely Bronx II, right?
Scott: So if you're not From the New York or spend a lot of time in New York or from the Bronx You might learn some stuff about New York and the Bronx like
Rym: all those things like the kids hanging out in the bodega Like randomly in the back room like yeah, that's New York like that.
Scott: That's like there's a lot of genuine New York stuff in this movie.
Scott: That is like absolutely, you know No one's looking at that and saying that's not New York.
Scott: Like no that that's.
Scott: yeah This is what I know.
Rym: Ghostbusters is very Manhattan like super like set in Manhattan Capital M. this movie is that for the Bronx, right?
Scott: But I think that Ghostbusters if you know nothing about New York, you don't really lose anything.
Rym: Yeah, like you don't need to know that's tavern on the green.
Rym: But if you're in New York, you do like.
Rym: you got a little extra context, right?
Scott: But I think that if you're not familiar with New York Nothing major is going to be lost on you in this movie, but some small things will be right.
Scott: So for example, there's a scene where somebody throws a Timberland boot.
Scott: vampire, right Spoiler On the one hand right?
Scott: It's like nothing is lost on the humor of someone throwing a boot at a vampire, right?
Scott: It's like that's gonna work no matter who you are.
Scott: No matter what your background is, right?
Scott: You're gonna laugh at that.
Scott: Hopefully.
Scott: But if you're New York II you realize the relevance of the Timberland boot Specifically in New York, right?
Scott: It's like part of the New York uniform, you know.
Scott: Okay Right.
Scott: It's like especially in the cold or the winter months, right?
Scott: Like Timberlands and like, you know, one of those black pea coats that is like that's a New Yorker No matter where.
Scott: if they're standing in a tropical island, you know, that's a New Yorker.
Rym: or like Why is everyone suddenly going to church in the middle of the night?
Rym: Because of these kids like there's a scene around that like yeah, that would happen.
Rym: Yeah, it's like that.
Rym: would you know happen?
Scott: exactly, so You know, I think if you're not from New York, you might miss very small things.
Rym: I think it'll be a lot like people who like a lot of Like similar, right, I think it's true.
Scott: Maybe it's more true to say you're not missing anything if you're not New York II But if you are New York II you're gaining something right the special.
Scott: this special sweet You know spice is added to Tease the palette of a New Yorker in this movie.
Rym: Well, like when I was a kid Like I'd like Seinfeld like there's a show I watch but are?
Rym: there's the episode where George Costanza has to like Double park the cars and deal with the cars.
Rym: That did not make any sense to me as a kid like as a kid like I didn't get it.
Rym: I could not understand what the hell the plot of that episode was Because that's really like that's a New York thing and only a New York thing.
Rym: all to decide parking and all that nonsense.
Rym: Yep, exactly, but this movie does not have any moment like that where you'll just be like what the fuck.
Rym: Except maybe the fact that the community would literally like get church to happen because of an incident like that.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So also the vampires in this movie.
Scott: It's not ultra gory, right?
Rym: So you're not gonna be exactly as gory as the Lost Boys from 1987.
Scott: like that level The vampires are very classical Vampires in terms of the rules around them.
Scott: Yeah, you know and it's actually nice that the Characters in the movie are not dumb, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, you know, usually horror movie You got if you're getting upset because people are playing dumb.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: no These characters like Oh vampires.
Scott: We know all the things about vampires.
Scott: One of the kids reads horror novels.
Scott: He knows right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like don't invite them in they don't fucking invite them in.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: this is why I keep bringing up the Lost Boys because not only is this movie like superficially similar to Lost Boys Like it's almost the same plot.
Rym: people are in a town There's vampires.
Rym: the kids figure it out.
Rym: the adults don't like.
Rym: how do you deal with it?
Rym: But there are some scenes that are beat-for-beat Identical scenes in this movie to scenes in the Lost Boys and there are also.
Rym: you can almost map most of the characters one-to-one.
Rym: Not all the characters obviously because this movie is very New York but there are many characters that map one-to-one like the Character who is legit a vampire hunter in the Lost Boys.
Rym: the same thing There's like the kids who like actually are vampire hunters and like go through the list of what to do with vampires.
Rym: The characters are smart and they go to the church to seal holy water.
Rym: that happens in both of these movies And I think yeah, it's.
Scott: It's basically, you know, I mean to say it's just lost boys for 2020.
Scott: Why would you watch the Lost Boys now?
Scott: Just watch this instead.
Scott: kind of true.
Rym: Yeah kind of true.
Rym: Also this movie like Lost Boys is not a diverse movie.
Rym: It was 1987 Hollywood like yeah set in a Wildwood esque place.
Rym: But vampires versus the Bronx is just a solid horror movie horror comedy.
Rym: Like it's worth watching.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think there's a lot of horror going on.
Rym: Quote horror genre because it's got Dracula's in it.
Rym: But it is not a horror movie so much as it is a. it's mostly a comedy.
Rym: Yeah, it's got touching moments.
Rym: It's a good.
Rym: it's a good movie.
Rym: Like watch it.
Rym: There's no reason not to watch.
Rym: I think right.
Scott: I think it's like if you're looking for like a great movie like, you know This is not where you should go.
Scott: But if it's you're here in the Halloween season, right?
Scott: Why do you?
Scott: you're gonna watch the same old same old over again, right?
Scott: You know, you're gonna watch something like what Garfield Halloween special Pumpkin Law, you know, you're gonna watch, you know some sort of you know, just Halloween.
Scott: Why not watch something new That fits the same bill.
Rym: How have you never seen event horizon?
Rym: Well, I was dealing with the sink.
Rym: I overheard everyone talking about what movie we were gonna watch.
Rym: How have no I was like no one in our crew seen event horizon Is it?
Scott: is it that good that I should go say?
Rym: Yeah, it's like.
Rym: it's like a classic for a reason horror space horror movie.
Scott: I don't even know if I. maybe I have seen it.
Scott: I just don't know it.
Scott: I don't know but it's uh, it's.
Rym: there's.
Rym: There's portal to hell stuff going on All right.
Scott: Sure, whatever.
Rym: All right anyway, but yeah spoilers past this point because I want to talk about specific stuff in this movie.
Rym: So stop listening.
Rym: if you haven't watched it because the movie is great There's no reason not to watch it.
Rym: and now we're gonna.
Scott: the movie won't be ruined.
Scott: Even if it's spoiled.
Rym: No, I mean like spoilers they beat the van.
Rym: everything at the end, right?
Scott: It's like it's.
Scott: everything that happens in the movie is kind of obvious.
Scott: There's.
Scott: no there's no surprises really.
Scott: if you're Unless you're a kid, then you'll be surprised.
Rym: There's two scenes.
Rym: I want to be an adult.
Scott: Nothing will surprise you.
Rym: The funniest scene to me is when the priest looks up and sees that the three kids are missing Just the way he reacted to.
Rym: that was like the funniest scene in the whole movie But also the way that they they should.
Scott: they use the camera to be from the first-person perspective of the priest.
Rym: Right, there's like pants like an around kid one kid to kid three like he's scanning almost like the Terminator.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Scott: So that was pretty.
Scott: but and then they were mad that he stole.
Scott: they stole his sprite.
Scott: But really they just stole the sprite bottles to put holy water.
Rym: But my favorite scene I think is when they're all in the apartment and the vampire shows up and the kid Tells the mom like don't she's a vampire and the mom believes the kid.
Rym: the mom is just like yeah Like.
Rym: immediately the mom is like, okay, I'm actually gonna listen and I think that's one of the primary themes of this movie.
Rym: This is almost a deconstruction of horror movies because most horror movies especially horror movies made by white people with white people Always have the plot of no one believes the kids.
Rym: People in the community don't trust each other at the start.
Scott: at the start people didn't believe the kids right.
Scott: so much Right, they didn't leave the kids but what they did do?
Rym: they trusted that there was something up because of the way the kids were acting.
Rym: there's the theme in this movie that the community in the Bronx is very close-knit and the supposition the vampires had that no one would notice people missing from the Bronx is only true if you ignore the fact that the People in the Bronx will notice and that that community is way tighter than probably most other like many other communities in New York City.
Scott: Mmm for a lot of reasons like yeah, and you could say I did really appreciate that.
Scott: the end It's like how many horror movies end right?
Rym: Like that's the one You know what one Frankenstein's and that way the whole town man's together, but not for the good reasons not for the good reason, right?
Scott: It's like when have you seen a horror movie end where it's like, yeah, actually Everyone gets on the same page realizes the bad guys are bad, right?
Rym: You know, yeah when the kids like don't invite her in and the mom it like listens to him and turns and it's like All right, wait up.
Rym: We got to figure out what's going on here, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: not only it's like does everyone believe you now, but everyone's gonna work together with you now, right?
Scott: Oh in marrow, it just has run away.
Rym: It's the guy who plays Tony in the bodega.
Rym: That's marrow from Jesus and marrow, which is just hilarious.
Rym: But the second he figures out the vampires are real He's like, oh shit and immediately calls them like yo, the vampires are real.
Rym: Yep, exactly The whole movie is filled with moments like that.
Rym: Nobody does anything stupid.
Rym: That is not plausible to a normal person mm-hmm, and they don't have the right level of Skepticism.
Rym: like the kids watch blade and suddenly are freaking out about vampires.
Rym: Yeah that tracks that.
Rym: that makes sense
Scott: But except they don't realize that the kids watch they studied the blade
Rym: after I Liked how Most of the vampires were like super stereotypical Like what we do in the shadows vampire vampires to like the fact that when the gang bangers come around the corner the vampires are Standing there.
Rym: They're just like.
Rym: what the fuck?
Rym: What is wrong with you?
Rym: Who are you?
Rym: What's going on here?
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: I did really appreciate the clever plot point where they managed to combine The gentrification storyline with the vampire storyline.
Scott: Yeah, the vampires were buying the real estate and So that they could enter without being invited because if they own the property then you don't have to invite them in.
Rym: it's their property like literally I'm the landlord now.
Scott: Yeah, so I was like.
Scott: that was just a really clever way.
Scott: It's like, you know, you wanted to tell these two stories.
Scott: one is a metaphor for the other but also Combining it with the actual vampire, you know mythos and mythology that way was extra clever and I think really, you know Even though it was only briefly mentioned It's it was kind of huge and really tied the whole thing together like oh that explains everything and it's really clever.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: But also the moment where I knew from the beginning that one rich guy was just they're familiar Like that was that was check out obvious bias the fact that when the kids confront him They're like yo the fuck you.
Rym: What do you think the endgame is to this?
Rym: and he's like, yeah, you're right like That was a cool moment that I did not expect.
Scott: That was another cool moment of you know.
Scott: adults like listening to the kids and common sense.
Scott: Right as opposed to in most horror movies people just you know, denying the truth acting irrationally and causing more trouble, right?
Scott: It's like, you know people said things straight up to other people and the people that heard it.
Scott: they heard it and they were like Oh, that's right.
Scott: It's like, you know, once the there was enough evidence to Support what was being said, you know people listen to reason.
Rym: the only beat we missed that we should have had was the girl who?
Rym: Already knew how to fight vampires.
Rym: We should have seen her take at least one vampire out like that was.
Rym: that was a moment that needed to happen.
Scott: She needed a moment exactly like the first person that believes the kid.
Scott: Well, the second person that believes the kids right is this girl who you know, totally believes them My grandma's Haitian.
Rym: I've been.
Rym: she's been preparing me for this shit my whole life Right.
Scott: It's like she knew everything.
Scott: She was ready to like.
Scott: it's like, you know, Van Helsing appears suddenly and What does she do though?
Rym: Right, all she ends up doing is leaving this the the Fight to go and collect the community and bring them back.
Scott: It's like she should have been the one you know to lay down some hammer right.
Rym: at least one hammer like one, right?
Scott: Yeah, she wasn't a mate.
Scott: shows the side character.
Scott: So you can't be like, you know having her, you know, take all the glory right from the main characters.
Rym: There was at least another sum.
Rym: When they they the two other scenes that are like one-to-one mapping with the Lost Boys.
Rym: The Lost Boys has a scene where the kids are like, all right, let's do the smart thing.
Rym: Let's go into their fucking nest during the day and kill him because they can't get us and it fails because of you know they're not actually ready for this.
Rym: that scene is almost the exact same scene from the Lost Boys and the scene where they kill him with where they kill a vampire with the The communion wafer is.
Rym: Also, there's a scene where they kill a vampire with a stereo.
Rym: that was staged very similarly in the Lost Boys.
Rym: There's a bunch of little mappings like that But the other beat from the only beach from the Lost Boys.
Rym: I expected that didn't happen.
Rym: I really thought there was going to be a scene at the very end where the priest comes in again like at the end after they beat all the vampires sees them all and Said something like man.
Rym: I moved to the Bronx to get away from all those fucking vampires Like.
Rym: I expected that because that has been a post climax scene in multiple vampire movies over the years Not just the Lost Boys, but other movies, too.
Rym: Mmm, you know at the end where the vampire with our grandpa's just like, you know I moved to San Dimas to get away from all those vampires.
Rym: Or no, what's the problem with San Dimas too many fucking vampires?
Rym: So it's not actually San Dimas.
Rym: It's just I've had Bill and Ted on the mind for reasons to yeah But yeah, what else?
Scott: Yeah, if you're looking for if you're looking for a fun Way to spend you know, uh your Halloween watching right your your your stay at home socially distanced internet Halloween party or you know, just your Halloween tradition and you just you know, you want to get that same feeling that you get from all your traditional You know fun Halloween party movies, you know Uh, and you just want to.
Scott: but you also just want to see something new right?
Scott: Not the same old over again.
Scott: This is Perfect, right just put it up there in that same pantheon where all the rest, you know.
Scott: And I think actually, you know, it's like, you know for years to come, right?
Scott: I see no reason why this shouldn't be considered along with the others like oh, it's Halloween.
Scott: We're traditional movie Are we gonna watch?
Scott: it's on the list with all the other ones.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: This definitely will be on that list in perpetuity.
Scott: Someone makes like top 10 movies to watch your Halloween party List.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Rym: music can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Marty green.
Rym: Yeah, just like a dude guy Graham fish.
Rym: You hold the key to my heart.
Rym: I Ain't trying to get arrested yet.
Rym: I just got here.
Rym: Clinton Walden J pants Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Chris mid give dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Shervin Von Harl and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: We will definitely on our next Tuesday show review Star Wars quadrants, but spoilers games great.
Rym: Like just get it.
Rym: It's good enough already We're having a lot of fun with it.
Rym: You should play it.
Rym: But for now I leave you with.
Rym: We've got a standing room only crowd and a beautiful night and getting ready to rock and roll army.
Scott: well Richard You know the Kalamazoo County Fair board told us the only time that the fair sells out or when the monster trucks roll into town.
Scott: And the best of the sport are here this evening.
Rym: and there's the best of the beast so far.
Rym: It is rowdy.
Rym: Rod Litzau USA won.
Rym: He's the best of the beast because he's the defending Renegades national champion.
Rym: He was our top qualifier tonight.
Rym: at eight point two nine seconds.
Rym: He's about to make his by run.
Rym: then it's gonna be John Breen and mad dog taking on Gary Wiggins Mopar magic the Jersey Outlaw forward of madman Mike wine against Jesse Bergy and the auto value claim for keeps Dennis Anderson and grave digger taking on the Ford of John Moore.
Rym: and
Scott: no problem We'll
Rym: have the equalizer the rookie dangerous David Morris going up against
Scott: Bennett Clark and the Clydesdale King crunch with
Rym: Scott Stevens one of the innovators in this sport taking on Bob Breen and wild hair Starvin Marvin Smith a stopper takes on John Kwasniewski and the Buffalo trimmer
Scott: Carolina Crusher
Rym: Gary Porter number one in the current national point standings against Dave Wysorek and nightlife
Scott: and the USA.
Rym: one has completed his by run.
Scott: now It's time for side-by-side racing up what I think lost him the race.
Rym: It was something by the name of a Dave Wysorek.
Scott: I told you why Sork in my opinions one of the best drivers in this sport.
Scott: get him a sponsor.
Rym: That kid will play big league ball with him.
Rym: Well, the red lights are on.
Rym: that means he's ready to rock and roll.
Rym: We're talking about Dennis Anderson and the grave digger against the board.
Rym: and a tough board John Moore and no problem.
Rym: And you can see the drive shaft has been fixed on the grave digger.
Scott: We broke the drive shaft the first round.
Scott: where we're gonna watch here?
Scott: It's a kamikaze on four wheels.
Scott: call the grave digger.
Scott: What's gonna happen more?
Scott: trying to pull him back in.
Scott: Anderson come down.
Scott: Clear all the car Richard.
Rym: we wanted about it.
Rym: He's the first one to clear the final jump 12 cars and he went over them all.
Rym: a good race by John Moore But not good enough.
Rym: and the grave digger moves on.