Rym: It's Thursday September 10th 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are reviewing the fantastic film Parasite.
Scott: Let's do this All right, so you may or may not know if you'd listen to the opening bits or whatever that since you know I can't go outside as much these days.
Scott: I've been biking inside and I set up a little streaming thing.
Scott: so is with.
Rym: I did find some stuff I can do because our bike is really cheap, but the sensor like the computer stuff.
Rym: I can just plug it into a better device Mmm, so I'm looking into that.
Scott: Yeah I actually Learned yesterday that I can.
Scott: actually there was a way to use my Apple watch as heart rate monitor to connect to the Zwift So I tried it.
Scott: It looked like it was working.
Scott: I don't know how accurate is.
Scott: It feels like it has a delay because if you look at the the graphs of like wattage verse heart rate Like what goes up in the heart rate goes up like a. what goes up?
Scott: it goes down then the heart rate goes up Just after.
Scott: yeah, it's like though.
Rym: so one thing you have to bear in mind is that heart rates like your heart doesn't react instantly and Like ramping up and slowing.
Scott: I don't know anything about her.
Scott: It's that's like the first time my whole life I've tracked heart rate while exercising.
Rym: so the one thing that you might find interesting that this is something you can watch for in the data regardless of that is The way to tell.
Rym: if your heart is getting like athlete conditioned is a very specific thing that happens.
Rym: And the thing is normal people.
Rym: when you exercise your heart rate goes up right like if you work harder.
Rym: it beats faster When you stop exercising or slow down, it doesn't just slow back down right away.
Rym: It actually takes it a while like it'll slow down very slowly.
Rym: Your body's like, I don't know if he's done yet.
Rym: Let's be ready.
Rym: Keep beating keep beating.
Scott: But if you actually train a lot and like get past the point of just being like a normal person Well, I don't think I don't think Zwift is gonna detect that because it stops tracking as soon as they push and exercise.
Rym: So when I do stuff I always leave my things tracking for like a minute or two after I'm done so I can see the drop Off.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know if it's anyway, I'll look at it.
Rym: But basically what is if your heart drops like right back to 60 like within 30 seconds of stopping biking.
Rym: That means you you basically have the heart of a pro athlete like you've done it.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think that's happening.
Rym: If you keep biking at the right year, that might happen.
Scott: It's not that it's not biking very hard.
Rym: Yeah, well, I guess you'd have to do intervals which I imagine you will never do.
Scott: I think it might be doing intervals.
Scott: I'm doing whatever the thing says to do right, but it's you know, you know, what intervals are.
Scott: It's you work hard, then you don't work hard.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's like work hard again.
Rym: run so hard It hurts for a few minutes.
Scott: then I don't do that.
Rym: slow down and jog for like five.
Scott: I mean it's basically like all right do this many watts and I'm like, ooh, that's a lot of watts It's more than just.
Scott: it's more than just chillin, right?
Scott: But then it's like, okay go back to just chillin All right, a lot of watts again, but I don't do so many.
Scott: it hurts Right because I have my policy of if it hurts don't do that.
Rym: I do spin training where I go to the point of cardiovascular pain on purpose.
Scott: I I do not.
Scott: I mean I'll be I'm not.
Scott: I'm like.
Scott: I don't find Breathing heavily to be uncomfortable or painful.
Scott: So it's like yeah, I am breathing heavily and my heart rate goes up But I am in no way in pain if I'm in pain of any kind.
Rym: I'm like, oh, yeah I guess it's because there's the difference between like Achy or like tired or exerting versus like ow, there's a pain something's wrong.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, if I just breathing heavily, it's like, okay.
Rym: No, if I breathe in it was like waiting.
Scott: It's like oh, what's the big deal?
Scott: That's not a problem.
Scott: I don't care, right?
Rym: So, okay, what do you say that like when you're doing a long bike now that you're good?
Scott: I only did it one time.
Rym: I'm curious because I have data now when I run long distances.
Rym: My heart sits at about 160 to 170 the whole time.
Scott: Aha, so I mean I think if I look at it from yesterday it was like Depending on the wattage, right?
Scott: So it was.
Scott: basically it only got up to one.
Scott: I think the highest was 180 for like a second or two, right?
Scott: It's like they're like little dots in the 180 area.
Scott: most of the time it was in the 150 160 zone Right like a little curve lump, right You know, but you could see it going up and down with the based on the wattage that was being demanded, right?
Rym: So the cool thing you can do is there's something called the RPE scales like this one to ten scale.
Rym: That's basically how do you feel and if you remember the number you would put on that scale?
Rym: Coupled with the heart rate you can figure out like basically how healthy your heart is like pretty directly.
Rym: It's a cool thing.
Scott: I always feel the same.
Scott: I pretty much have two feelings.
Scott: feeling is My feeling is a just chillin.
Scott: I guess three feelings just chillin up, right?
Scott: Okay, I'm not just chillin, but it doesn't hurt and then that's too much.
Scott: I'm not gonna do that.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So I guess three does the three fail.
Rym: one on that scale is hardly any exertion more like watching TV than walking.
Scott: There's definitely less than just chillin.
Rym: like a three is.
Rym: you could do this for hours.
Rym: It's easy to breathe and carry a conversation like a five or six you're breathing That's just.
Scott: that's just chillin.
Rym: Yeah, like a five breathing heavily, but you could still hold a conversation.
Scott: Seven I mean I can hold a conversation, but I have to like stop between words.
Rym: Yep, so they're like a four.
Rym: you could hold a conversation a six.
Rym: you have to like pause like you can have conversations But it's slightly challenging and like you have to say short.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: I don't think I have that That middle one there.
Scott: I pretty much have either just chillin I could do this for hours and then I have to pause there here.
Rym: a seven Borderline Uncomfortable short of breath can speak a sentence.
Rym: I know I don't do seven nine very hard to maintain can barely breathe can speak Maybe a few words at a time.
Scott: Yeah, I don't do maximum effort.
Rym: You literally could not push yourself further Even if your life were in danger, you are unable to speak even a single word.
Rym: You cannot maintain this for more than 30 seconds.
Scott: Yeah, I don't do any of those.
Rym: I've only experienced that twice in my life and that was in a doctor's office getting a heart test.
Scott: Because basically what happened?
Scott: they made me run until I said 10 and then they immediately stopped the treadmill and I was done when they asked for too much wattage, I just pedal really slowly like And I'm like, all right, we're moving the pedals they're moving.
Scott: No, so an interesting thing happened is Which is the thing that I had heard of before right, but apparently I guess that's the first time it happened to me.
Scott: It's not really.
Scott: it's not really a big deal, right?
Scott: But when I was when I was done, I smelled a weird smell.
Scott: that wasn't a BO smell.
Rym: Oh You got into keto.
Rym: It sounds like you're burning fat.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: So then I googled and it's like yeah if you smell like an ammonia smell and I'm like might be an ammonia smell Vaguely, I don't know.
Scott: All right They're like, yeah, that means you know, something something and they're like, yeah They're like, they're like drink more water and I'm like, I already drink the most water.
Scott: I can't possibly drink more water.
Rym: Yeah, you might have to hug fuel more.
Scott: I think that's like yeah, it's like eat more food or something.
Rym: I'm like, okay I actually read in something I always eat During the quarantine like I'm doing these crazy long runs like way more than I used to and I'm like really working out way more Than I ever did so normally.
Rym: what would happen is I do a long thing and at some point my body is like out of calories like whatever I've eaten is gone and fat starts getting burned and that causes like your Sweat to smell a certain way.
Rym: You'll like taste this acetone like flavor in your mouth.
Rym: Sometimes there's all sorts of things that happen.
Rym: But if you keep going and you don't have any more fat to burn then you smell this more like acrid Ammonia and other smells like this sour smells and that means that your body's actually starting to break down muscles.
Rym: You're making yourself weaker.
Scott: Yeah, that's not good.
Rym: Yeah, but I wasn't even working hard.
Scott: I was just chillin.
Rym: Yeah, well, I don't know.
Rym: Maybe maybe you're not eating enough compared to your activity levels.
Scott: now I'm not hungry.
Scott: Yeah, I'm eating what I'm hungry and I'm not hungry.
Rym: Yeah, there's a lot of stuff that could be.
Rym: I'd have to smell it, but there's no way I can't.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know whatever but that's just an interesting thing and it's like it's not some unknown thing like those info about on the internet some.
Scott: But yeah, if you if you smell weird after you exercise Google it.
Rym: Yep, so got any news.
Scott: Yeah, the sort of a little combo II news here right.
Scott: so the movie we've been all been waiting to see for a super long Time right from cartoon saloon the Irish animation studio the makers of the amazing films breadwinner Secret of Kells a Song of the sea.
Scott: right they were making the wolf walkers.
Scott: They were making the wolf walkers for a long time.
Scott: We've been following it very closely right it is actually coming out.
Scott: finally on Saturday two days from now the 12th.
Scott: Holy crap.
Scott: It's actually coming out.
Scott: It's for real right.
Scott: We were watching like previews of it and behind the scenes of it like we've been following this thing.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: So we've also known for a while that they made a deal with Apple like Apple iPhone Apple Right Steve Apple all right Tim Apple.
Scott: So it is going to be on Apple TV Plus which you can either get a free trial if you've got I guess some kind of Apple device or pay five bucks a month right?
Scott: So that's a one way to watch it.
Scott: It's going to be G kids has the license in the u.s.
Scott: Expected, but how you gonna go to a movie theater?
Scott: I guess you wait for G kids to make a DVD or go to a drive-in or risk your life to see it.
Scott: I wouldn't do that.
Scott: live in a different country where the movie theater is safer.
Scott: You can do that.
Scott: I'm sure it'll be distributed wherever you live.
Scott: if you're listening to this podcast And I was like damn how am I gonna watch this?
Scott: am I gonna pirate it?
Scott: am I gonna get a free Apple TV trial?
Scott: And try to rip it from Apple TV.
Scott: What am I gonna do?
Scott: all right?
Scott: Tom Moore the director of the film on Twitter was doing a little.
Scott: he said hey sending questions, so I asked and Tom said You'll be able to buy it on iTunes Which is not subscribing to Apple TV right something anyone can do right?
Scott: you know.
Scott: without owning Apple devices you can just install iTunes for Windows on your Windows PC and buy it and get a video file that you can then play.
Scott: So that's I guess it's superior option.
Rym: Yep Cuz like I most things that I want to see I tend to just buy them on like Amazon And I just have this library that slowly building of things.
Rym: I've bought sure.
Scott: if you think about it though, right It's like okay.
Scott: What am I gonna buy this movie?
Rym: $15 right probably $20 who knows I mean $15 would be like the cost of one ticket to go see it at a story of Kaufman.
Scott: that's true.
Scott: That's very true.
Rym: If I could go to the Astoria Kaufman theater today and see that movie I would pay the $15 like right now.
Scott: You would.
Scott: that's one way to look at it, right?
Scott: But another way to look at it is hey that Apple TV plus assuming you have an Apple device to use Apple TV.
Rym: Oh, I see where you're going with this.
Scott: It's only five bucks a month.
Scott: Yeah, so just get it for three without even without even a free trial, so it's like huh, you know It's the same kind of deal where you know people always come at Adobe Creative Cloud and these other subscription services Right you know as being like in principle.
Scott: They don't like it.
Scott: They want to own stuff right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I see where that principle comes from right.
Scott: But it's like listen if they take something down, and it's not available anymore Yarr, yeah, that's pirate.
Scott: It's like pirate it.
Scott: What's the big deal right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: you know it's nothing.
Scott: you're not gonna lose anything in the age of the Internet.
Scott: someone out there has got it for you right.
Scott: and The subscriptions despite being in principle not owning stuff Economically are if you're gonna go as legal route are way way better than buying things right.
Scott: It's like pay five bucks a month.
Scott: You can get Apple TV a free trial and then three months worth.
Scott: Well the caveat is if you feel like the cost of buying one movie You can see all that Apple TV plus Yep.
Rym: The caveat normally is that a lot of these things disappear from streaming services over time like I said.
Scott: But I said if that happens just pirate it.
Rym: Because one thing I've noticed over time is that I watch a lot of stuff on Netflix But it's usually like shows that are coming out now or that are out recently that are current.
Rym: But I don't think in like five years have I ever gone to Netflix and thought oh I would like to watch X movie type the name of that movie into the search and it was actually on Netflix to watch.
Scott: Not once.
Scott: oh yeah that almost never happens like it's.
Rym: it's like literally.
Rym: It's been five years since I've typed the name of movie into Netflix, and it was actually on Netflix.
Scott: No, no at this point in time the subscription services are for the.
Scott: that's why they're making content, right?
Scott: They're basically TV channels.
Scott: They just happen to be the bat probably the best TV channels because they don't have commercials.
Scott: And that's where the best content is these days right?
Scott: It's like what good contents on like NBC these days.
Scott: You know it's like.
Rym: well You know there all the good is a bunch of good NBC stuff.
Scott: But I I acquired a lot of that on shall we say a boat I'm just saying But like the best you know fictional Video entertainment media these days is mostly being run on these subscription services the Disney pluses the Hulu's The Netflix's the whatever.
Scott: but honestly
Rym: like one thing I know I've noticed looking at these services that I do pay for is that if I add up the Cost of all the
Scott: HBO Max's
Rym: yep I subscribe to a bunch of them and if I look at the cost of all of them combined It's still actually less than what basic cable would cost me.
Scott: right and it's better than basic.
Scott: So it's like.
Scott: you know on the one hand you could be mad about these kind of situations, but on the other hand It's like actually if you just give up on your principle your life will actually just be better.
Scott: Yeah, cuz you'll save you'll save money and get more.
Rym: in fact the pro way to go is to like stuff.
Scott: Just really care at everything.
Rym: I will buy things.
Rym: I really like adventure time.
Rym: I bought them all because I like having this archive to like go because I'll watch that show again I'll show it to people.
Rym: like in the old days We'd buy the DVD of an anime that we wanted to show to other people Regularly like cowboy bebop.
Rym: we kept showing to people.
Rym: so we had the DVDs But most stuff that we like we didn't really need to watch again.
Rym: We didn't plan on watching it again, so we didn't need to own it.
Rym: But anyway like people who you rotate through like I'm gonna watch a bunch of Netflix stuff.
Rym: you got Netflix for six months Then you cancel Netflix.
Scott: Yeah point is this weekend go out and watch yourself some wolf walker walk.
Scott: some will get it right.
Scott: You know the next GeekNights Wednesday is gonna be about that.
Scott: move 100% I can tell you right now excited about this movie Right.
Scott: so go and figure out some way that you're gonna be able to watch it.
Rym: So in some other news this is not news like the thing I'm about to talk about.
Rym: it is not new.
Rym: we all knew this.
Rym: This is more about some of the details of what it means.
Rym: you can read the article Why.
Rym: it's the way it is and it's a problem that even though we know it's coming Especially people who listen to this podcast a lot of you are gonna be in this boat and a lot of you are younger than Us.
Rym: so you're gonna even be in a worse boat.
Rym: possibly the argument that the articles about how it's Basically almost impossible for any millennial to actually retire at a reasonable age like there's just no way we did.
Scott: we know that.
Scott: That's yeah, that's been.
Rym: but it goes into a lot of the details of like what this means Why other generations could all retire how Millennials are like this like extra screwed for a bunch of weird reasons.
Rym: It's very like.
Rym: the details are odd in some ways because like tech workers are more likely to be able to retire than pretty much anyone Else in America who's a millennial, but that's because that sector is really hopping for reasons We talk about a lot on the show, but what I find interesting is that?
Rym: Almost everyone who talks about this talks about like you did like oh.
Rym: of course Millennials won't be able to retire But almost no one really actually tries to talk about what could we do about it like oh?
Rym: Do?
Scott: there's a very easy thing to do about it.
Scott: There's tons of things we can do about it.
Scott: That's that's no problem to solve at all.
Scott: that the problem is not Figuring out those solutions.
Scott: the problem is making those solutions happen by getting power to implement those solutions.
Rym: Almost all things all these systemic problems in America are pretty much tied to the fact that the people who Actually want to solve these problems do not have power and you need to acquire power by playing a very difficult and complicated game.
Scott: It the same you know same problem of everything right, but it's like yeah, we we know how to fix Social Security for Decades.
Rym: yeah the post office like was fixed working fine till we broke it on purpose.
Scott: right well We didn't break.
Scott: what else?
Scott: broke the royal?
Rym: we broke it on purpose.
Rym: sure the illegitimate president of the United States broke it on purpose More.
Rym: yeah as as much as they.
Rym: the crazy thing about the post office.
Rym: They've been attacking the post office for 40 years to try to destroy it and despite all of that It was still working fine until our current president decided to just find by one definition of fine right is like.
Scott: we saw you see other countries that have like Incredible post offices and ours was Maintaining right.
Rym: well ours was doing in.
Scott: ours was even when even when you know the evil people had less power The less evil people did not Transform the post office to make it ours Incredible like ours was.
Rym: our maintain thing was still better than the domestic mail delivery in a lot of other industrialized countries.
Rym: it actually was.
Scott: You know I've seen you know we were looking at.
Scott: you keep talking about Australia.
Scott: We just didn't you know Australian post office already eight years ago, right?
Scott: And that was better than any US post office if I've ever been in my whole life.
Rym: however the thing we mailed didn't actually arrive so That's a different story.
Rym: Saying I'd like to talk that up more to my poor hand Scott between you and me actually using the Australian post office We're batting 500 because I mailed something once from Australia, and it made it and we met.
Scott: I blame it.
Scott: I blame that more on my handwriting then Anything else,
Rym: but I guess what I'm really the thing that bothers me about these retirement conversations though like point I want to make because I don't want to dwell on this I picked this because I didn't have better news and I mostly want to talk about parasite is that every conversation about retirement in America How do we get Millennials to retire?
Rym: What do we do about old people who have money?
Rym: They all still assume that you should work until you're like 62 or 65 When I think we need to figure out a way to have people work less.
Rym: overall The whole point of working should be that you can enjoy a lot of the time in your life with the benefits of your labor.
Scott: Well, you know, I think there's just a clear divide and this you know It's it's somewhat of an.
Scott: it goes along with correlates with the age divide in society.
Scott: But I see plenty of people my age and even younger where you know their life is Their work right.
Scott: their work is their thing.
Rym: Oh, I'm in a weird place.
Rym: Most people I work with their career is Like the majority of their life Right, and it's like.
Scott: so those people it's like they don't want to not work, right?
Scott: They may even you know enjoy working less hours Yeah, or they may enjoy having more vacation day.
Rym: if I have money to retire to a meager lifestyle today I would quit my job and retire immediately.
Scott: Right, right exactly, but they want like.
Scott: their job is still like they're defining thing in their life, right?
Rym: And well, you can always tell when you meet people at a party You're like and someone's like.
Rym: there's always someone's like, oh, what do you do?
Rym: Right when people ask me that I'm like, I'm a gamer in a podcaster, right?
Scott: People ask me like, what do you do?
Scott: And I'm like too much.
Scott: It's like yeah, it's you know, it's like.
Scott: but most people you ask them What do you do regardless of age and they're gonna tell you their job unless they're unemployed and do something else.
Scott: Yep, right
Rym: So and I know that like the thing I want to point out in this article is it talks about and a lot of people Talking about retirement and Millennials are pointing out that Millennials can retire if they work longer which I think defeats the point of retirement entirely because hours you have when you're young are way more enjoyable than hours you have when you're old because things break down in our bodies.
Rym: like If I wait till I'm 80 to fly around the world, I'm not gonna be hiking a hundred miles through the Outback Most likely unless we get cyber bodies or something, but this article like I'm gonna read as passage here Working longer is a powerful lever.
Rym: if Social Security benefits are claimed at 70 instead of at 62 Then you can retire like way better.
Scott: You got to make it to 70.
Rym: Yeah How many people die before they can retire like you didn't a lot?
Rym: Yeah, you didn't even get to use that money you saved.
Rym: And this article even says quote.
Rym: in fact my research so shows that the vast majority of Millennials will be fine If they work to age Although and this is the ridiculous part.
Rym: Although that might sound old.
Rym: It's historically normal.
Rym: in another sense This is old person talking right here.
Rym: Retiring at 70 leaves the ratio of retirement to working years the same as when Social Security was originally introduced.
Rym: Talk about a terrible goalpost to base things on.
Rym: Social Security came out of the Great Depression So old people wouldn't starve in the streets.
Rym: if that's the bar you're setting what the fuck?
Scott: The bars is not.
Rym: the bar should be work for 10 years.
Rym: robots do the rest like that's the goal.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: The bar should be.
Scott: no one has to work ever.
Scott: robots do the rest.
Rym: But look we bug.
Rym: you see all those graphs.
Rym: as we build robots we build robots We automate things.
Rym: Scott and I our job is mostly to automate things like that's kind of in the end what we do.
Rym: So machines will do it and the more we automate things the more profits come out and the more work gets done.
Rym: But they don't let us work less hours.
Scott: No, we've been talking about this forever.
Rym: Yeah, cuz it's it's a primary It's a second.
Rym: It's the second biggest concern in my life after defeating fascism.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: you call dibs on this so you get to talk about this.
Scott: Alright, this is the one of the best things of the day in a while.
Scott: I wouldn't say that if I if I wasn't super confident in it.
Scott: so apparently right I learned something about ancient Rome.
Scott: I didn't know granted.
Scott: There's a lot about ancient Rome.
Scott: I don't know God that's inside joke from like 20 more than 20 years ago, so apparently in ancient Rome they had these coins And not the coins you think of the Roman coins with.
Scott: you know the Caesars head on one side right or both sides even right?
Scott: but these coins On one side of them had a Roman numeral usually from between 1 and 16 in Roman numerals and on the other side of the coin was a elaborate and explicit depiction of a sexual act of some kind.
Scott: and There are lots of these coins.
Scott: if you do some Roman archaeology you will find these coins.
Scott: No problem.
Scott: if you go to a museum and you go to the Roman section They probably have a ton of these coins.
Scott: They're not rare.
Scott: There's a lot of them right there.
Scott: Anyone who's dug up Roman ruins has found these coins.
Scott: probably they're all over the place.
Scott: They're not a secret or anything.
Scott: however in no like written record or Recorded record did Romans anywhere say what the hell these were for right?
Scott: It's like you read all the Roman writings, and you'll learn nothing about these coins.
Scott: like.
Scott: there's no talk of them.
Scott: There's no speak of them, but you find a ton of them.
Scott: It's like man.
Scott: We're finding these things everywhere, but we're not finding anyone saying what they were.
Scott: so we don't know for sure.
Scott: According to this Twitter person who definitely knows more about ancient Rome than I do Unless this is a fake thing like you know a Scottish military ration, but I don't That.
Scott: yeah, we don't know for sure what these are for.
Scott: right, but Common sense right and basic educated logic would give you this one most likely conclusion which is the conclusion I also thought of before reading it which is that There was some sort of Roman law that said yeah, you cannot use you know a depiction of.
Scott: you know The the Emperor right when you're paying for prostitution as an attempt to outlaw prostitution, right?
Scott: and so and so They set up a system whereby you would exchange your Caesar coins for sexy coins by sex with sexy coins Right and then the prostitutes would turn their sexy coins back into.
Scott: you know
Rym: Caesar just described arcade tokens
Scott: pretty much Right so there's a good chance that these are arcade tokens for brothels or Fake or their real thing or whatever regardless
Rym: what they could make or weaver tokens like oh, I owe you a hand job I'll pay you a hand job and three blowjobs for that goat.
Scott: Anyway, this is too good to not be thing of the day.
Scott: check it out especially the awesome Pictures of coins with sexy act.
Rym: what I appreciate about the coins the most is that the people in them just look like they're having fun Like there's.
Scott: oh, yeah, no, they're they are great.
Scott: They and they are doing all kinds of different sexy acts.
Scott: They're not doing the one where the guys like got the rope Yep, all kinds of good stuff going on in a sexy room.
Rym: Yeah This is good stuff.
Rym: So my thing is really simple.
Rym: So many, you know, I play the trumpet and because of kovat, you know, I'm stuck home a lot.
Rym: So one of things I've been doing for a while I'm playing my trumpet again cuz I was a semi pro like I almost went to school for trumpet.
Rym: I almost had a very different life.
Rym: I don't think I would be podcasting here and live in this life if I had actually pursued that But I was really good trumpet player, but I play a normal modern trumpet.
Rym: if you don't know Trumpets and more all horns.
Rym: those keys don't actually do a lot and 90% of the work to make a trumpet play a different note is all muscle and lips Like it's just it's.
Rym: it's more like exercise It's like a physical skill.
Rym: learning to play a trumpet is more about like learning to ski than it is about learning music.
Rym: so Old trumpets don't have any valves at all.
Rym: modern trumpets have valves because you can play more notes.
Rym: old trumpets were played entirely With those muscles and you could only play notes.
Rym: that were natural harmonics of however long the tube was of the trumpet you were holding.
Rym: on consequence if you don't remember high school physics of resonance in tubes is that and the harmonics is that.
Rym: Generally the higher pitch you have the more harmonics you have.
Rym: so in a trumpet with no buttons You you don't have that many notes.
Rym: if you're playing low like if you play a note It'll be like a C. But then if you use your lips to go one note up You don't get to a D. It goes all the way up to a fucking G. You can't play any notes in between because those aren't harmonics of that tube.
Rym: the valves change the length of the tube.
Rym: So a valve modern trumpet is actually just a whole bunch of different trumpets.
Rym: So you don't have to have 50 trouble 12 trumpets.
Rym: You just have one trumpet that you can turn your trumpet into whatever trumpet you need to make it easy to play a note at Any level.
Rym: but if you get way high up Fingering's don't mean shit.
Rym: You can play the same note with like five different fingerings and it's all in the lips.
Rym: This is a video of someone playing a moderately difficult piece.
Rym: I've actually played this piece before on a regular trumpet But it's someone playing a baroque trumpet that has no valves and you mean like the big long ones with the flag hanging off it.
Rym: Yeah, but well So some of those actually have valves and they just look fancy because they're nice and loud and look cool in a renaissance fair.
Rym: I've played.
Rym: I paid that.
Rym: I played those for money in high school at a renaissance fair.
Rym: They're real fun.
Rym: or the long ones?
Rym: Yeah, they have the flag on it, but they're actually just a broke trumpet.
Scott: Usually they're not as long as the ones you're thinking of But you know that you always see they're like cartoons and stuff, right?
Scott: It's like a whole whole - you're going that you're walking to a king and there's two lines of dudes all the way.
Scott: Yep, those they're like.
Scott: they're like trumpets on both sides.
Rym: Yeah So this video is someone playing one of those.
Rym: but I want you to watch it because it really shows how utterly Ridiculously physical playing a torn like this is.
Rym: because it is very strenuous to play high notes And because it's already strenuous to play something like a tuba, right?
Scott: It's like something old like that.
Scott: It's like damn.
Rym: but to play a high note is really strenuous.
Rym: and to make notes in a trumpet that doesn't have valves You have to play basically all high notes.
Rym: every note is a the equivalent of a modern very high note and this guy is fucking doing trills and like Really really fast melodies with no keys Faking it.
Rym: No, that's that's just what it's like to play broke trumpet.
Rym: They're hard as shit to play.
Scott: He's just.
Scott: he's just really good at.
Rym: he's just really good at it.
Rym: But if you watch you can kind of see that he's like he doesn't show it that much But you see him like sweating and exerting himself to play while he's just standing there.
Rym: Yeah, there's an aside.
Rym: I hate broke trumpets.
Rym: fuck them.
Rym: I think technology has advanced for a reason.
Rym: All right in the meta moment Stuck inside at some point.
Rym: We'll read the tale of Genji PAX Unplugged.
Rym: It's not happening.
Rym: PAX West not happening Basically, no cons are happening, but packs online is happening.
Scott: That's not happening.
Rym: That's not happenings We talked about two days ago, but packs online is happening like even happening really soon.
Scott: You can already go to the discord for packs online Which I guess is sort of the equivalent of hanging out in the hotel before the con.
Scott: It packs online is gonna start Saturday the 12th and run all the way through the 20th.
Scott: a whole lot of packs online gonna Go down.
Rym: Yep, check it out.
Rym: There's a discord server.
Rym: That's live now where you can like hang out.
Rym: talked about that Alright, yeah, but there's already people in there like hanging out.
Scott: Yeah, I said that.
Rym: Alright, it's like the lobby before packs.
Rym: I just said that.
Scott: yeah, I just said yeah, just repeating what I said.
Scott: Yeah, just repeating it.
Scott: But anyway, that's right.
Scott: That's the packs.
Scott: You're gonna get.
Scott: that's the packs you're gonna get.
Scott: So do it.
Scott: It's uh Yeah, I don't think it costs any money unless you want to buy merch.
Rym: I've been not super jazzed about a lot of online cons just cuz they're like they don't feel like they're gonna do it for me.
Rym: But honestly after the crunchyroll Expo and then after hanging out in this discord a little bit and like seeing what people are saying.
Rym: I Guess my hunger is so great for a con that it's almost doing it for me.
Scott: hmm, but yeah The the packs online is really trying as hard as anyone can try to really do the online con and replicate Packs as best as possible.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it's still far from the mark, but you know They're trying so and it's gonna.
Scott: it's actually a combination of awesome West.
Scott: So it's nine days 24/7 content.
Scott: Oh, it's store.
Rym: You can buy a Physical badge that they will mail to you and they give you a.
Scott: so they give you a packs online one and a packs awesome yep, and the West ones yeah, but the What was I saying?
Rym: I bought it.
Scott: the content is technically 24/7 for nine days.
Scott: But at times for example, our panel is up against no other panels, right at least so far.
Rym: I heard tell there's something that's going to appear in the main theater slot.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: That's possible.
Scott: There are.
Scott: There's lots of content from like sponsored adjacent groups like egx.
Scott: But if you look at the schedule online, you can see this alls content and West content and it's like separate.
Scott: It's like if you wake up early in the morning, you can watch packs alls content on these channels Right and PAX Australia people.
Scott: you can wake up at whatever time it is in Australia Yeah and see content in that u.s.
Scott: Times, right?
Scott: So when is our panel exactly?
Scott: 5 p.m.
Rym: Pacific Daylight Time on Friday the 8 Pacific time.
Scott: I thought it was New York time 5 p.m.
Rym: Pacific time.
Scott: It's like 7 p.m Oh I have to adjust my calendar then because I thought that the schedule got adjusted to New York time when I looked at it.
Rym: Maybe I'm looking at the pack schedule.
Rym: I don't know if it adjuster.
Rym: I'll go back to the static post I made.
Rym: Yep, does the pack site adjust to your what it thinks your time zone is?
Rym: But if you it's 2 p.m.
Rym: Pacific time because the official schedule is in Pacific time.
Scott: That's right 5 p.m 5 p.m.
Rym: Eastern New York time, but if you go to the pecs site It doesn't say the time zone on the site, but it looks like it's just in your time zone.
Scott: So what?
Scott: so it's 5 p.m.
Scott: On the 18th Friday the 18th New York time.
Scott: 5 p.m.
Scott: Friday the 18th.
Scott: There's a lot of other panels.
Scott: a surprising number of panels are from people We know.
Scott: I just want to point out just a couple just to you know, carry us over here, right?
Scott: You got a Sid Meier panel On Saturday, you got the keynote on 115 on Saturday.
Scott: of so you can go key on this Saturday the 12th after you watch Wolfwalkers You can watch the packs keynote at 115 New York time and within Sid Meier 730 p.m.
Scott: New York time.
Scott: you got Those Apple day.
Scott: you're gonna have an Apple keynote busting into your packs on Tuesday.
Scott: New iPhones presumably right.
Scott: you got a super art fight on Thursday the 17th at 11 p.m.
Scott: New York time.
Scott: You got our friend Matt doing a panel on Saturday the 19th at 8 45 p.m.
Scott: And the Omega thon finale is Sunday the 20th at 9 45 p.m So stay up late for that Omega thon finale.
Scott: The Omega thon is gonna be a little different this time.
Scott: I think they're not eliminating people.
Scott: They're just having way more competitions that I think one a day.
Scott: So nine total and I think everyone's gonna be in all of them and they're gonna use points or something to figure out who's who?
Scott: Wins or something.
Rym: pretty excited like I watch a megathon.
Rym: stuff at physical packs is like when it's convenient But I'll skip a lot if it's not convenient, but for an online one, I'll just watch them all.
Scott: Yeah, you could why not?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So yeah come to packs online.
Scott: Yes, the packs with all the pets The only packs we got.
Rym: so and honestly like go into the discord if you watch our panel while you're watching it because you're never Rare opportunity will be in that discord actually like answering questions.
Rym: Like we're gonna take questions.
Rym: We have a question.
Rym: We'll just answer it.
Rym: Maybe I mean I will.
Rym: you might not like my answer.
Rym: All right, oh and so, you know during that part like your audio was cutting out for me a little bit and then it fixed Itself, so I didn't hear everything you said.
Scott: Oh Only on discord though only on discord like.
Scott: obviously let me check the audition.
Rym: I assume your audition is fine because discord does go recording.
Scott: Yeah, so I don't know.
Rym: It's probably fine because discord does cut out every now and then during the livestream, but it doesn't affect you.
Scott: You didn't cut out at all.
Scott: So yeah All right.
Scott: It seems like.
Rym: it seems like it's all.
Scott: keep this audition open.
Scott: Keep my eye on it.
Rym: It seems like it's fine.
Rym: This is this has happened before and it's never shown up in the recording you have.
Scott: Okay, seems good.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Let's jump right into this.
Rym: so we uh We I would say we became aware of Korean cinema in college when someone told us to watch a movie called attack the gas station.
Rym: Like up to that point like we watched a lot of Chinese kung-fu movies We watched a lot of Japanese live-action stuff But we didn't really watch.
Rym: you know a lot about Korean films until we've watched Attack the gas station and we got weirdly obsessed with it because that film is a triumph.
Scott: Yeah, it's weird.
Scott: It's like I'm interested in you know media from all sorts of countries.
Scott: I don't care what country it is Right, and it's just that you know, it's like.
Scott: well It seems weird to be always focusing on the Asian East Asian countries Korea, Japan China, right?
Scott: Obviously, they're huge countries.
Scott: You know culturally right it.
Scott: Korea is not huge South right, but You know, we're always like focusing on their media.
Scott: right?
Scott: anime, right?
Scott: We're not talking too much about you know, Russian animation.
Scott: There's very few we talk about right And part of it has to do with just how much media they create.
Scott: but really just how accessible the media different countries create Is to us right?
Scott: It's like if suddenly I could access a whole bunch of Turkish media in English, right?
Scott: I might be into that right?
Scott: I just can't that they don't put it out, right?
Scott: So, you know Korea or you since they were already watching a lot of Japanese Chinese things, right?
Scott: You know, I was thinking of Korean stuff because it's right there geographically speaking.
Scott: And finally some of it became available right, you know, we were starting to see things like Korean DDR, right?
Scott: And then eventually kpop became a thing.
Scott: But yeah, so it's like we've been watching Korean movies for a while.
Scott: And then you know this guy you may have heard of him bong joon-ho comes on the scene and he directs quite a few Significant movies over the course of.
Scott: you know, since you know, the 2000s right you had the snowpiercer, right?
Scott: Which everyone knows.
Scott: yeah was a big deal.
Rym: I love that that movie is.
Rym: I think that movie is brilliant and I love it and I love how weird and dumb it is.
Scott: Yeah, you have oak jaw, which is uh, I don't know how many people know or have seen that movie but You know, maybe you should.
Scott: yeah It was kind of a big deal.
Scott: But yeah, so parasite came out.
Scott: So I went to see parasite in the theater with a friend like the tiny IFC theater because you know There was a lot of excitement going on about this movie, you know before it won the Oscar for Best Picture.
Scott: Hey, yeah And then it did win the Oscar for Best Picture deservedly.
Rym: so yeah, like I saw all these accolades I saw everyone talking about it But somehow I avoided knowing I'd like.
Rym: I pointedly tried to not know what it was about because I wanted to just go see it.
Rym: I lately doing this a lot with movies where if I can avoid seeing even a trailer I like to go into movies completely blind.
Scott: I don't believe in spoilers.
Scott: Tell me everything.
Scott: Anyway, the point is I went to see this movie.
Scott: Well, and then Rick I was like Rick because see this movie Yeah, even before it was literally officially the best movie.
Rym: Yeah, and you were you were like you wouldn't best move.
Rym: You wouldn't tell me anything about it.
Rym: All you said you just go.
Rym: What are you there?
Rym: So like what's in the basement?
Scott: And then I mean because at the one No, I don't care about Right.
Scott: Well, I don't care about being spoiled.
Scott: I'm not gonna guess be a jerk and spoil people.
Scott: They don't wanna.
Rym: but you know, I gotta say well, we won't spoil anything until we'll warn you.
Rym: we're gonna talk about this movie in a little more depth with spoilers after a point, but I Did not know like where this movie was gonna go and it started.
Rym: I followed it.
Rym: I saw what was going on like okay, I see where the movies going.
Rym: and then the thing happened and The movie changed radically and I was there.
Rym: then the movie was great.
Rym: And then anyway, but there's a big moment where the movie changes.
Scott: if you haven't seen this movie.
Scott: Come on What do you what are you waiting for?
Scott: Right go and see it right now You can go online and I think if you keep it's not at any streaming service where you live You could.
Scott: there's definitely like a legal way for you to just pay a flat rate Like I think I got an Amazon Prime video.
Scott: I paid money Yeah, and they gave me I could just watch the movie as many times I want.
Scott: now You can obviously get a DVD or Blu-ray.
Scott: You could pirate it.
Scott: There's a very easy movie to watch.
Scott: go watch it immediately like stop listening to this right now and go watch it.
Scott: Yep, what you know, but I guess what anyway is the like.
Rym: the acting is good The.
Rym: the cinematography is just beautiful like the movie is funny, but also dark It is tragic.
Rym: It is violent, but it is also heartwarming in some aspects.
Rym: There's a lot going on in this movie like most good movies.
Scott: It's got a little everything.
Scott: It's not one of those, you know, sort of like just a comedy just a whatever kind of move.
Rym: Yeah It's not just.
Rym: John Wick shoots people in the head for an hour and a half, which I love.
Rym: But that is not what I would consider the mark of a great movie for all time.
Scott: No, so The name parasite right?
Scott: It's called parasite because you know I mean it's about the sort of parasitic relationships people have in a capitalist society, right where it's like.
Scott: You know you need money to live right?
Scott: Well, where do you get money?
Scott: from someone else who has money, right?
Scott: So you need your sort of become much like a parasite on that person, right?
Scott: you have to you know latch on to them right, you know, whether it's your employer or You're a criminal and you're stealing from someone right, you know, there's capitalism.
Scott: You know people's relationships are all sort of parasitic in nature.
Scott: You're sucking at the metaphorical teat of something Right, it could be a government teat or who knows what right - right.
Scott: and so in this movie They're telling the story of a of a family of four right a mother father a daughter and a son.
Scott: The daughter and the son are like older.
Scott: They're not.
Scott: they're like, you know early 20s late teens sort of college.
Rym: Yeah, like college age.
Scott: Yes, Lee on college-age kids.
Scott: And this family is poor unemployed.
Scott: They live in like a basement.
Scott: It sucks.
Scott: Yeah, right and they are.
Rym: They're like lower middle class or like, you know upper lower middle class like they're that step below the Simpsons.
Scott: Yeah, they're.
Scott: they're not doing well, but they're not homeless, right?
Scott: It's like they have food, but it's it's not great, right?
Scott: So This family obviously is a is a is a parasitic.
Scott: they're the main characters.
Scott: they're a parasitic family, you know.
Scott: They're parasites on society and sort of like in order to live right there sort of like they live sort of like cockroaches, right?
Scott: You know try, you know scamming, you know con artist thing.
Scott: You know working odd jobs here and there right the folding pizza boxes to try to make money.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: and the movie like it does not.
Rym: it's not denigrating Like the movie really shows like they got their hustle.
Rym: Everyone's got their hustle.
Rym: Don't begrudge someone.
Scott: They're hustle.
Scott: They're hustling, right?
Rym: They're not survive.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: So what happens is they eventually find a hustle.
Scott: One of the son's friend, you know is tutoring this.
Rym: Oh, yeah tutoring.
Rym: He had his own hustle.
Scott: Yeah, he had his own hustle, but the son's friend is not poor right like they are And he has to leave.
Scott: he's gonna leave to study abroad and he is tutoring this high school girl And he's like, hey, you know, you're my friend.
Scott: I want you to tutor this high school girl.
Scott: Now I'm gonna refer you to get this job right tutoring to make some money.
Scott: because I trust you, right?
Scott: I don't trust my other college friends Right But anyway, so he goes and gets this job with the referral from his friend, right and he's sort of you know His parasitic way scams his way in there and the family of the daughter that he's tutoring is very wealthy.
Scott: They live in this fancy house made by a famous architect, right and the house itself becomes a character in the movie.
Scott: but the rest of the movie is now about this parasitic relationship of the wealthy family and The poor family.
Rym: like the poor family finally finds the perfect hustle.
Rym: Yeah, and they execute it.
Rym: they execute this hustle and then what happens after that?
Rym: it is a movie.
Rym: Yeah, the one thing I would say like that.
Rym: I think the fundamental question without talking about spoilers about this movie like the question to ask yourself as you watch Who is the parasite?
Rym: What is a parasite like for real?
Rym: It's hard to really talk about this movie unless you've seen it right now.
Scott: That's that's the number one thing I like about the movie is how there it's not a. you know The director himself said yeah that the real bad guy is capitalism, right?
Scott: Is that during different points of the movie your opinions on different characters how they're behaving goes Every which way right?
Scott: someone who looks someone who looks good is like at one point.
Scott: It's like It's like oh look, you know, I'm really sympathetic with this person right?
Scott: and the next second they're doing something They do something that's heinous, right?
Scott: You're like that awful person and it's like it's flips back and forth on all the people like sometimes scene to scene.
Scott: You know, there's also a gradual shift throughout the movie, right?
Scott: And it's like you see people doing bad actions that are on their own heinous But you can understand why they're doing them.
Scott: So maybe you're on their side.
Scott: you see someone doing something like nice and noble But you see why they're doing it and now you're against them, right and all these, you know It keeps flipping and flopping all over right and it's like no one in the movie is A hundred percent clearly good bad Like.
Scott: it's not about this direct conflict of these are the good guys the main characters.
Scott: These are the bad guys.
Scott: It's these are the people are gonna focus on more.
Scott: so the main characters.
Scott: but we're it's this intertwining relationships here between all the characters.
Scott: and To demonstrate to you that yeah, all you know, people are forced to do they're trying to be good Maybe they're not.
Scott: but all these things that people are forced to do and the situations they're in are because of Society, right?
Scott: It's sort of created this scenario of awfulness for everybody.
Scott: Yeah, watch it explode Fashion.
Rym: Yeah, I can't just like we're gonna spoil after this.
Rym: So if you haven't seen this movie go watch it like 100%.
Rym: This is one of the great movies of all time.
Scott: So I don't know about that.
Scott: It's up there.
Rym: I think about all the sudden all time.
Rym: I think this movie will be remembered like decades from now.
Rym: It'll still be spoken of in.
Rym: Oh, yeah, this will.
Scott: this will be a movie that sticks around that people like in 20 years where it's like, you know Movies you should see right the same way.
Scott: That's like, you know, we're still watching seven samurai, you know, it's like, all right.
Scott: Well 30 years from now people still be watching parasite for sure.
Scott: Yeah, so some other non Spoilery things about the movie, right?
Scott: There I watched some behind the scenes Ooh, I didn't watch that And some commentary stuff on YouTube.
Scott: so I highly recommend doing that after you see it and some of it was really fascinating about like how some of the thing I Remember most is they talked about the set where the poor family lives and how it's this street and they live at the end of the street and like a sub basement and They're like, they're like, yeah everything on this street.
Scott: We built up to that point and everything beyond that is CG All right.
Scott: And that I found was really fascinating.
Scott: I'm pretty sure the house the movie takes place in is a real house.
Scott: You could go to it if you wanted to but it's sort of you know, I guess it's not a very accessible place.
Scott: It's like up on it up on a hill and fenced off from the world, right?
Scott: It's because it's a fancy mansion type place.
Scott: Yeah There's really fascinating stuff to see there.
Scott: The other thing is so in the movie.
Scott: There's sort of this Sort of certain things that happen over and over again.
Scott: the son who I guess is the mainest main character maybe right?
Rym: Yeah I mean he he's the character who basically initiates the movie and also ends the movie.
Rym: Yes so and he has that and we should probably explain like You could you might want to look up what that Rocky is carrying around is because if you're especially if you're an American you might Have be familiar with this concept.
Scott: yeah, it's sort of like These stones that I don't fully understand the deal myself But like, you know, there's sort of like a thing like people have a hobby collected them.
Scott: There's sort of like philosopher Philosophy stones or something Rym's googling it right now.
Rym: So I googled it because I was vaguely familiar with it like you and I googled it after we watched the movie to see Seen them on display in some people's houses occasionally and I've seen people have lots of them before.
Rym: I've seen him like professors at RIT would have like like I'd seen like sitting on a shelf in their office.
Scott: Yeah, they're
Rym: basically just rocks to contemplate aesthetically Like
Scott: sort of like a bonsai tree, but it's a rock but you don't do anything to it cuz it's just a rock
Rym: yeah, whereas
Scott: you have to care for a bonsai tree and
Rym: There's like higher but there's like higher quality ones and lower quality ones and like people who I'm
Scott: sure there are care
Rym: about them.
Rym: Like think about all these different attributes.
Scott: Anyway early on in the movie right that college friend who's only in for one scene gives that rock to The family is like a gift which I thought was fascinating because you see this whole scene Like it's not really spoilers where this family is desperately poor.
Rym: and then their friend who's way better off Like the guy the kids friend gives him a gift that if you're that poor is absolutely worthless and at best is just a burden.
Rym: but yet he thinks it's a good gift to give.
Rym: like the movie like that sort of sets the tone for the movie of Hey, here's a gift that does not help you in any way Mm-hmm, but also, you know, the Sun says oh, it's so metaphorical right.
Scott: and then he repeats that line several times throughout the movie.
Scott: and Whenever the rock reappears in the movie, right it even if he doesn't say it It's like the rock is always doing something metaphorical.
Scott: It's weird.
Scott: It's weird how it's not weird.
Scott: It's The movie is Simultaneously full of metaphor and allegory but is not subtle, right?
Scott: It's sort of like it without it doesn't you know, it always shows rather than tell which is good But it shows in such an obvious beat you over the head showing way that you couldn't no one could miss it Which I mean snowpiercer was very similar.
Rym: I mean you've seen snowpiercer.
Rym: The movie is just oh Those are the people in steerage.
Rym: These are the people in coach.
Rym: Those are the first-class people.
Rym: This is a metaphor for society, right?
Scott: I think about the end of the Godfather.
Scott: spoilers right the end of the Godfather.
Scott: the first one Is a is is two different scenes.
Scott: right in one scene all these hitmen are going out and killing every other mafia boss Except the Godfather and in the other scene the Godfather is in church Right becoming the Godfather of like his I guess nephew or something niece or nephew.
Scott: I don't remember right.
Scott: and there the priest is like, you know Satan Do you renounce him?
Scott: and he's like yeah, I renounce Satan and then it shows his own hit man Like shooting a dude right in the eye, right?
Scott: It cuts between back and forth that kind of allegory that is not subtle.
Scott: is this whole movie?
Rym: Yep, right this movie like it it escalates quickly like ever as soon as you think okay See where this movie is going.
Rym: It will just escalate and escalate and escalate and escalate and then it's and it just ends, right?
Scott: And it's like every time you think that it's like, okay I see where this is going.
Scott: step one We go up the stairs to step two go up the stairs to step three.
Scott: It takes it up two more levels to wherever you think it's gonna be.
Scott: Yep, right.
Rym: Oh, it's raining outside.
Rym: Oh rains a platform.
Rym: Oh, right.
Scott: Oh Right, and they managed to bring back right.
Scott: You know Common thing in comedy sketches and movies right is like you introduce the thing Chekhov's gun and it comes back again later.
Rym: Right Chekhov's scholar stone.
Scott: Chekhov scholar stone right but also it's like so the scholar stone.
Scott: when you see it at the beginning of the movie You're like that's Chekhov's gun.
Scott: Yeah, I see that is I could tell right away the shot like guns in on it a couple times.
Rym: the kids like carrying it.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: and and it fires.
Scott: they fire that gun.
Scott: Trust me But it does a good job.
Scott: and that there are many other Chekhov's guns in the movie.
Scott: There's like a whole Chekhov's Arsenal right and the whole Chekhov's Arsenal.
Scott: It all gets fired every gun fires.
Scott: There's no There's no gun.
Scott: We're like they didn't fire that one.
Scott: It's like no they fire all the guns several times even.
Scott: but Some of those guns that are fired you did not recognize as guns when they first appeared.
Scott: But when they first appeared they appeared so prominently that when they do fire you remember Very clearly.
Scott: Oh, that was a Chekhov's gun.
Scott: It was so prominent when I first saw it spoil But I didn't know it was a gun when I first saw.
Rym: the one that was the starkest was the automatic lights in the house.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that was that's the least obvious one because when it when that gun fires I was just like motherfucker and that gun fires two or three times.
Rym: Yeah, it just keeps firing.
Rym: It's like a semi-auto in there.
Rym: Yep Alright super spoilers cuz I actually want to talk about like what this movie is about like for real.
Scott: But now you know what kind of movie it is, you know, what kind of feel it has.
Scott: Right, so, you know if you want to watch if you're still thinking about not watching it now, you know if you're super pro Capitalism you might get mad at this movie.
Rym: This movie is basically saying you are a bad person and it's not wrong.
Scott: No, it's not wrong.
Rym: Alright spoilers spoilers spoilers.
Rym: I Think the scene that hit me the hardest was the dad just saying don't make plans like that scene when they're in the shelter after the flood like that whole scene of them just walking through the rain and like everything's in misery and like if it's almost feels Like an apocalypse is happening.
Rym: and he's just like don't make plans like that's the secret.
Rym: and then like the next day Just happens like the apocalypse fades out and then the climax of the movie fades in.
Rym: basically That was the scene that got me the most.
Scott: hmm, I think the scene that I think in this is the the most Like.
Scott: it's most memorable for me is when they're all hiding under the table, right?
Rym: That was both funny and a little scary.
Scott: I like right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like because that scene goes on Law.
Scott: it's not.
Scott: it's not too long but it's way goes on.
Scott: they're under that table for an uncomfortably long amount of time Hiding right and trying to get out of there in a way, right?
Rym: And it's like without getting caught but also like whole time that seems going on long But the head injury like you're still thinking about that like that right gone away.
Rym: That's like resolved and the camera doesn't come back to it.
Scott: There is so much stuff going on at that time and it's like, you know You have scenes in movies where things get tense and they get more tense and they get more tense And usually there'll be some sort of you know relief right like, you know horror movie.
Scott: It's like the aliens come and the aliens come and someone dies you get away and now you're chilling and waiting for the tension to build Away does not solve any of their problems.
Scott: No, it's like here.
Scott: you just have the tension builds and they manage to find new ways and ways you didn't see coming to have it continue building and Twisting and turning.
Scott: it's like the screw just keeps getting tighter throughout the whole scene.
Scott: Oh now the family's coming home.
Scott: Yeah, now they're fighting over that while they're fighting over the cell phone.
Scott: then it's like.
Scott: it's like, you know It's like stuff just keeps happening.
Scott: They just keep throwing every time, you know, the current tension is about to become sort of dull and you know Okay, this is gonna.
Scott: they twist it again with a new a new thing to make that scene go harder.
Scott: I think that scene actually makes up.
Rym: I don't know time wise but it feels like it makes up like the bulk of the movie in a way because that's where like that whole scene not like Not up until they're hiding but like the head injury and the fight in the basement.
Rym: All of that is where it like they were like you could make the argument originally like alright There's this rich family this family.
Rym: Now.
Rym: There are parasites of the rich family.
Rym: Obviously, that's the facile allegory.
Rym: That's not what the right was going for.
Scott: It's like that part of the movie where they're.
Scott: you know in getting into the the rich house right takes up You know quite a bit of time Right, but then it's like that scene sort of like when they're all in the when the the rich family goes to camping Right and then the
Rym: old caretaker like comes back and knocks out the poor
Scott: family.
Scott: poor family's chillin in the house.
Scott: That is the moment where it takes you into like the next act.
Rym: That's also the heights like.
Rym: that is the height that family has ever achieved.
Rym: That is like the best night they have ever had in their lives, right?
Scott: And then the doorbell rings right exactly the doorbell rings.
Scott: things get completely off the rails.
Scott: They keep going off the rails like that whole night, you know in movie time, right?
Rym: But then that's like we're like it fades back in the next day and it's like the Sun is out.
Rym: Everything's quote normal.
Rym: everyone like acts like everything's fine and goes about.
Scott: their business depends who right?
Scott: It's like they go home in the flood, right?
Rym: But it's like I meant to wake up like after the flood.
Rym: when they go quote go to work in where they're fighting for clothing Yeah but that long scene like I when There.
Rym: so they're the parasite of the rich family facile allegory, whatever.
Rym: But then when they encounter people who are they are lower class than them who are more in more desperate states than them They start getting moral like we deserve to be where we are.
Rym: you you parasite get out, right?
Rym: Exactly what you're doing.
Rym: they're even like yeah You're lower middle class or you're like low class.
Scott: those be more than one Parasite sucking on the same thing.
Scott: and then those two parasites fight each other.
Rym: Because because the real parasite is the really really rich family that's the parasite that's the movie Yep, and that I think is really driven home and that's like that.
Scott: But even the really really rich family is only the way they are because the way society is Yeah, like they've introduced the wife as being like really like mentally ill and broken.
Rym: But then you see how isolating her life is.
Rym: the guy like he has like he doesn't understand how to interact with normal people Anymore because of the life he lives.
Rym: but there's also that scene at the penultimate scene where Like the rich German family is moving into the house and how the rich people in all capitalist countries are the same.
Rym: There's no difference.
Rym: It doesn't matter who lives in the house You'll everyone in this movie like fills the role of the place and station that they have achieved.
Rym: The rich families are all the same.
Rym: The poor families are all the same.
Rym: the desperate families are all the same in terms of the struggles and like what they end up Being and doing in this world.
Scott: The one thing that is starkly, you know, most of this is a universal tale of capitalism.
Scott: Yeah, right You know, but the one thing that is starkly different is how?
Scott: After you know the ultimate climax right with the stabbing and everything Right, the Sun is in the hospital right in the United States.
Scott: The Sun would not be in the house.
Scott: Yeah, because we do not have the universal health care that South Korea has.
Scott: right the Sun would be dead.
Scott: right and also the justice system in South Korea at the end comes into play and It would not have treated those people.
Scott: the United States justice system would not have treated those people the same way.
Scott: the group did Right, so not to say that theirs is necessarily perfect or better or worse Some ways better but the health care is definitely better.
Scott: Yes There is a stark difference there.
Scott: That way is not universally true for all capitalism Right, like if you think about the gym scene even like after the flow in America.
Rym: No, those people would all just been totally fucked right?
Scott: It's like, you know, it's like okay the whole poor neighborhood flooded.
Scott: Everyone went to sleep in a gymnasium and there was a pile of clothes to fight over in the morning, right?
Scott: It's like in the United States.
Scott: that would not happen, right?
Scott: I would just be stuck in your flooded house You have to pay for a hotel or sleep in your car or some of those people would just be dead.
Scott: Clothes is like yeah.
Scott: No, you don't go to walk about clothes.
Rym: check-offs toilet.
Rym: Yeah, check-offs toilet big time They they they zoom in on that toilet.
Rym: the toilets rate like and our friends our other Scott's house Like he has a toy.
Scott: It was kind of a. the effect that was.
Scott: the one thing is the effect of the toilet burping up water.
Scott: That was sort of that.
Scott: it was sort of a. it was sort of a fakie kind of fun house effect.
Rym: No, that's why I've seen that happen.
Rym: That's what that looks like for real.
Scott: Hey, Larry cartoon in a cartoon.
Rym: I'm saying that is literally what a Below the like sewer line toilet looks like if there's a flood for real in the real world.
Rym: All right, go look for videos of it.
Rym: It's terrifying.
Rym: You know that whole thing about the Pittsburgh toilet in the basement.
Rym: Yeah, that's to prevent that from happening upstairs anyway, but the Like the scene where they're first they're attacking and trying to get the other parasite out because you know the whole.
Rym: in Capitalism the lower classes are basically tricked or forced into fighting with each other over the scraps.
Rym: so of course the family that's slightly better off now than the earlier parasite like oh We're poor but at least we're not on the run from loan sharks like right.
Scott: Well, I think what what had happened is they had that the family right acts didn't realize that they were bumping out another parasite right now the you know much like they were faking it and Appearing to the rich family to be better off than they were.
Scott: right they were putting on airs of being you know More not wealthy, but you know morally respectable in one way right above their own class.
Scott: right their smell gave them away But so was that housekeeper right.
Scott: that housekeeper was also putting on airs and ended up fooling.
Scott: So that's why they didn't have any qualms about getting rid of her.
Scott: Right because they thought they were fooled.
Scott: also that that person was.
Scott: They were.
Rym: if you look at the situation She was in with her husband.
Rym: they need this help way more than this family does.
Rym: they're way more fucked.
Scott: Oh, yeah, absolutely.
Rym: But this family takes this moral superiority angle of you're that your parasites get out.
Rym: you're breaking the law.
Rym: We'll get rid of you.
Scott: It's like well you are too.
Rym: Yeah, well especially Because they're well like I'm actually.
Rym: I want to get back to the smell thing first because I found that scene really interesting the scene where you finally have the rich people by themselves and you basically have this scene where you have the poor dad Like hiding and he hears what the rich people actually say and think in their normal lives And how yep
Scott: before it up until
Rym: that bid and and just classist it is and like what they think of the people around them.
Scott: Yep up until that point, you know, the rich people are shown as you know, naive people who happen to be wealthy.
Scott: They don't do anything.
Scott: that's explicitly evil.
Scott: You don't see them exploiting anyone, you know directly Right, like they're paying their employees very well like that's like that everything seems right like the face like it's like yeah They're rich.
Scott: Yeah, they clearly don't understand the non-rich world, but you know, they're not like Actively, you know Reprehensible people right but you know and but every interaction you see with them is with you know Between them and others right between them and the you know, their employees
Rym: Yeah, but when there's no one else around right
Scott: and then it's not until that point you see them just talking to each other right and Not to someone in a different class and then they reveal their you know, their true their true nature, right?
Rym: And there's also the bit there's a little bit when they first displaced the housekeeper like they finally like secured their space and now they're the they're the.
Rym: they've made their parasite life.
Rym: they Really convinced themselves that that housekeeper will just find another job somewhere Because they don't want to face the consequences of the displacement They have caused.
Rym: yet then when they have to escape and they cause that horrific head injury And I remember when that happened.
Rym: The first thing I thought was wow, she has to go to hospital She's gonna die.
Rym: and I was really glad that this movie like yeah, that's exactly what happens Like she doesn't make it.
Scott: She's just tied up to a lot of people don't make it.
Scott: Yeah So another so related back though to the what the the rich people right so early in the movie There's a scene where you know The the husband the rich husband and wife are discussing the underwear that they found that was planted in the driver's car Right, which is how they got rid of the old driver and got the dad to replace him, right and You know, the the the wife is like, oh, you know She's like gasp at the mention of like drugs.
Scott: if you have to understand this South Korea even like, you know drugs That would be like legal here.
Scott: even over-the-counter would like get you a jail there, right?
Scott: They got way stricter laws.
Scott: It's actually a big problem.
Scott: It's like a negative thing a lot of times like drugs that you can get here which you should like especially a lot of psychiatric drugs.
Scott: Yes, psychiatric drugs, especially.
Scott: but you know even like you do some you think you get in trouble for doing weed in the US somewhere where there's if you're black and The cops hate you it's like, you know, if you're anyone and you got weed in South Korea, you are fucked, right?
Scott: You know, but anyway, so the mother the rich mother gasping about drugs like oh, oh, right.
Rym: But they're also like weirdly turned on by like ooh the lower class stuff, right?
Scott: But then later on in the movie, right?
Scott: When she's getting it on she's like, oh buy me drugs, right?
Rym: No, she's like role-playing the prostitute that they imagined like.
Scott: right exactly, you know It's like.
Scott: and the dad's like, you know, if you wore those panties I found in the car I'd be really turned on by that.
Scott: You know, it's like.
Rym: I think that is the unsexiest sex scene I've ever seen in any movie ever.
Scott: It's not supposed to be exactly supposed to be you know.
Scott: But yeah, there are.
Scott: but also it's just another illustration.
Scott: It adds on because you know.
Scott: at the same time you see, you know The the rich people speaking truly to each other, right?
Scott: They also draw that contrast by you know Showing you how they spoke when someone else is there versus when someone else is.
Rym: and then there's also a running theme with the lights And with a bunch of other things around each level of the society portrayed in this house Doesn't understand the true plight of the ones lower than them and assume they're way better off than they are.
Rym: And I think that's really shown the lights.
Rym: I love that.
Rym: just the allegory there of the the rich guy Appears to have just assumed his entire time that he's lived in this house that those lights are automatic like oh the light that's just a feature of the house and You learn that it's literally the crazy guy in the basement doing it out of his weird hero worship of the rich guy Mm-hmm, like the rich guy not understanding like the sausage-making that makes his life possible Like he has no idea what normal people are like at all.
Rym: he doesn't understand the things that are easy for him or just happen for him are happening because of the Dangerous and insane efforts of others who are far more exploited by society.
Scott: And then you see that paralleled in every interaction in the movie all the way down to the bottom Mm-hmm, but yeah, that's you know, that's also it seems is a lot of things like that which are like less.
Scott: They're not you know, rather than running throughout the movie.
Scott: There's sort of like, you know one-off Non-subtle allegories right of you know showing other aspects of.
Scott: you know The parasitic capitalist relationship.
Scott: and there's one where it's like yeah, you know, despite the rich people being the problem We're gonna show you this thing that happens in the real world Which is people who are really poor worshipping the really rich people, right?
Rym: Twitter stans like think Elon Musk is some kind of guy.
Scott: I was just gonna say.
Scott: it's like Elon Musk dick is sucked by so many people who should be just stabbing him.
Scott: Evil dude is an evil dude.
Scott: He's basically Lex Luthor, but even worse possibly, you know and real.
Scott: and yet people are like, you know Kicks it kissing his ass right.
Scott: you have no money and nothing, right?
Scott: It's like the same thing you are.
Scott: if you are that person then you are that dude in the basement in parasite You know singing the praises of the rich guy bang in your head against the light switches.
Scott: Yeah, that's you.
Scott: so Shut up with the Elon Musk.
Rym: Yep And there's a lot more we could say but we've gone on for a while.
Scott: You could do.
Scott: probably a whole series of you can make.
Rym: a podcast like.
Rym: this is one of those movies You could just you could spend hours writing essays on lit crit of all the directorial decisions.
Rym: Everything in this movie is done on purpose and the movie is just very well done.
Rym: So We'll keep the conversation going in the discord in the forum, I guess.
Scott: Oh The only other one thing I did want to mention though is the the house, right?
Scott: The not only is you know, the the house is sort of like a character in the movie, right?
Scott: It's made.
Scott: it was supposedly made by this famous architect who lived there previously and had the same housekeeper previously.
Scott: to the story I don't know the true story of the real house, even though it is a real house.
Rym: The parks house was a specially constructed set.
Rym: I just looked it up.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I thought it was a real house.
Rym: Ground-floor in the garden were on an empty outdoor a lot.
Rym: the basement and the first floor were on a set.
Rym: There was okay house.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: It was a fake house.
Scott: But the point is that this the shape of that house right is so important to the film Right in the way the different shots that they set up in the house, right?
Scott: You know like the upstairs scenes are sort of like in this other world right.
Scott: the basement scene, right?
Scott: That's another neck old right the basement is another world.
Scott: But the entrance to the basement and that narrow sort of doorway in the kitchen with the stairs, right?
Scott: So it's like, you know, you see Where someone ascends or descends those basement stairs, especially where the guy.
Scott: you can see the guy's eyes coming out from the basement.
Rym: That was actually a really creepy shot like what that's high.
Scott: and then you learn the story of how the kid got scared Right when he was young and had a seizure You know.
Scott: and then there's the main the main big room right with the glass going outwards, right?
Scott: and there's just so many shots in the movie that I think you know, obviously telling me it's a fake house makes more sense because You know you look at you know, I thought they just got lucky with the house and like filmed around it geniusly.
Scott: But it's like.
Scott: no they planned like.
Scott: oh, yeah, you know at this scene, right?
Scott: It's like they're inside talking looking out the glass.
Scott: the light comes in the windows, right?
Scott: You know the.
Scott: they set up the.
Scott: you know, the birthday party outside the walkie-talkie going in and out through the windows, right?
Scott: it's like the shape of the house is like, you know matches the the story of the movie while also The camera, you know the filming of the movie right is like designed around the shape of this house, right?
Scott: You know to create the scenes and the shots that they needed, right?
Scott: So it's really you know, kind of trying to think like other movies that did similar things Right where they had a. you know, it's almost it's not quite a one-room thing like a glass menagerie kind of deal But most of the action horror in that one area and I'm reading about.
Rym: they spent a lot of time Trying to make that set exactly perfect for these shots.
Rym: Yeah Like they thought a lot about the furniture in that room to set establish the idea that the family spends most of their time in That room when they're recreating because that room connects to the outside garden.
Scott: Yep I mean even though it's a wealthy clearly a wealthy house.
Scott: It's not actually that large right?
Scott: It's like bedrooms a giant Recreational room with glass a yard.
Scott: I'm not gonna lie.
Rym: That house looks amazing.
Scott: I'd love to live there.
Rym: I would do it.
Scott: an extra fancy kitchen a storage base.
Rym: Would you murder someone with a scholar stone to live there?
Scott: depends who.
Scott: But anyway, yeah, so the I just really appreciate what was the.
Rym: Oh Mirai is which is all Anime, I also said it like a special architect designed house.
Scott: Yeah, but that's about an architect.
Scott: true May you could see as Mirai is a prequel to parasite if the houses are a little bit similar Not completely though.
Scott: They didn't have a housekeeper in Mirai either.
Rym: Yeah, this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the patreon patreons for this particular episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Heidi, mythical Marty green.
Rym: You just like a dude guy chartavich and Graham Finch.
Rym: You hold the key to my heart.
Rym: I wanted highlight.
Rym: So the way patreon works the spreadsheet.
Rym: unless I export it into a bunch of stuff I have to hover over a tooltip to see any long names.
Rym: Well, the plane landed and when I came out Clinton Walton, Jay Vance, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Nicholas Brando Chris Midkiff, Dred Lilly Tenebrae, Chris Reimer, Finn, Shervin von Horl, and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names Yeah, I got nothing can't really go anywhere.
Rym: So for now, I'll just leave you with something from somewhere Darryl, I don't have time to talk right now.
Rym: Yeah, I know.
Rym: No, well cuz somebody went in and clicked the recoup base encryption hash key button.
Rym: What's that do?
Rym: Well, it pretty much means we have to reset everyone's password on every server and a whole enterprise.
Rym: So, uh You know who clicked it?
Rym: No, man.
Rym: I'm just helping with a sales meeting right now.
Rym: So well since you're logged into the box here and it's running under your username I just thought I'd ask you huh, and you know I can see from the squid log here that you did just do a search for recoup you'd encryption hash key.
Rym: So it seems like you might know.
Rym: all right inspector Darryl.
Rym: I clicked it.
Rym: It's right next to the apply button.
Rym: I mean Do you know how we fix it?
Scott: We ain't doing anything but you need to get busy resetting everybody's password and you can't do it remotely.
Scott: You're gonna have to come down here with a recovery CD and start going up and down the rows popping it in the box.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: every password?
Rym: It doesn't make.
Rym: it doesn't make sense that that one button has that effect on every password.
Rym: All right, listen, um Darryl, I they're trying to get in on the VPN.
Rym: so I got to deal with that.
Rym: I'm sure they'll understand, you know, I'm gonna get fired.
Rym: is what's gonna happen?
Rym: You can fix this stuff up anytime.
Rym: you fix the virus attack, you know, I mean you do that.
Scott: Yeah Hell yeah, you think I made it 30 years an ID.
Scott: All right.