Rym: It's Thursday, November 19th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: We are talking about hoodies and possibly jackets.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, we actually planned to do this show a couple weeks ago, but I had a thing come up and we bailed on the show.
Rym: But then, just a couple days ago, it got cold, so it's actually more topical now than it was two weeks ago.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Brr.
Rym: Yeah, it's, uh- It's cold.
Rym: Yeah, it was cold enough where I actually had to go around and, like, turn up the heat in all the different rooms.
Scott: All the heaters are now on, but I have the heaters set to, like, 68, which is, like, what's recommended or whatever, so they don't turn on that much.
Rym: Yeah, mine are in, because there's three zones and they're three independent units, but- We got three independent units, yeah.
Rym: The number that it shows, like, the number on that thermostat does not line up to a real temperature.
Rym: It's basically just relative.
Rym: Like, it is a temperature number, but because of where the sensors are, they're all, like, accurate to themselves.
Rym: Like, they're consistent, but they're not consistent among each other.
Rym: So, I have one set to, like, 74, one set to, like, 68, and one set to 70.
Scott: Well, I mean, it seems fine in here.
Scott: The apartment's well insulated.
Scott: When the sun shines in, it gets really warm, even if the heaters aren't on.
Scott: You know, it's like, you know, we're definitely not- it never gets so cold in here that, like, we're like, "Bird, turn up the heat," right?
Scott: You know, we just put on a hoodie or a blanket or whatever.
Rym: I mean, I'll admit, I like to be in shorts and t-shirt in my entire life, and I like my home to be that warm, which, thankfully, in New York, doesn't really cost anything.
Rym: Even if I turn the heat off, it's usually short and t-shirt weather inside of our apartment.
Scott: Okay, so, we had a hard time coming up with any news today, so let me geek-bite this thing, because whatever.
Rym: I got a similar thing, because there's no news, really, except the coup attempt and COVID and the hurricanes.
Scott: Alright, so, Mario, Super Mario, not the any other Mario that you might be thinking of, is 35 years old.
Rym: I'm just thinking of regular Giuseppe.
Scott: Yeah, so, one of the things they did is they released this Mario Brothers Game & Watch, right?
Scott: So, it's like, it's a Game & Watch, just like the old Game & Watches.
Scott: The only difference, obviously, is that the form factor is the same, but the battery is USB-C, rechargeable battery.
Rym: Yeah, not like what AAA's or whatever went in the original Game & Watch.
Scott: No, and the screen is vastly superior.
Scott: It is, you know, the right resolution to play Mario 1 on, right?
Scott: So, and it has Mario 1, Mario 2, and Ball, but when you play Ball, Ball is the, you know, the old Game & Watch ball game, right?
Scott: When you play Ball, Mario's head is on the guy, it's not Mr.
Scott: Game & Watch.
Scott: It's Mr.
Scott: Game & Watch's body with Mario's head.
Rym: Wait, wait, it's only Ball, so I can't play Flagman or Manhole or Octopus?
Scott: They are not on this, no.
Scott: The Mario 2 is the real Mario 2, it's not, you know, US Mario to Doki Doki Panic.
Scott: It's actual, you know, Mario 2.
Rym: The Lost Levels!
Scott: Yeah, supposedly Lost Levels.
Rym: Of course, depending on which Game & Watch, the originals took those little tiny dime-licking cells of varying types.
Scott: Well, people don't realize, it's like, why is it called Game & Watch?
Scott: 'Cause it's a game and it's also a timepiece, right?
Scott: And so is the case with this anniversary device.
Scott: So who is this for?
Scott: At 50 bucks, it's not for a lot of people.
Scott: It's for people who, A, want to keep it sealed in the box and never open it and have some kind of collector's thing, right?
Scott: I don't know how much of a collector's thing it's gonna be, 'cause I think it's readily available.
Rym: It's not sold out or anything.
Rym: Ah, it is sold out everywhere I checked.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: Well, I just ordered one, like...
Rym: Nintendo is officially out of stock.
Rym: I'm poking around to see if I can get one anywhere else.
Rym: Not that I'm gonna get one, but...
Scott: It just showed up.
Scott: I ordered it, like, you know, I didn't order it way in advance or anything.
Scott: I ordered it, like, you know, a few months ago.
Rym: I think it sold out post-release, but, like, not that quickly.
Scott: Anyway, it's for someone who does not have any sort of portable... It's like, if you have a phone, I guess it's like... I guess if you don't have any Game Boys or anything and you just want to play, like, Mario and that's it, it's, like, I don't know.
Scott: It's really not that great to play Mario on.
Scott: The controls are not the greatest, even though, I mean, the buttons themselves are great.
Scott: It's just the form factor of a rectangle is not pleasant to hold, right?
Scott: The screen is pretty impressive color-wise and brightness-wise for such a tiny device, especially at this resolution, you know, the resolution of an NES.
Scott: But the refresh rate is pretty good considering, but you can see ghosting, like, behind Mario a little bit.
Scott: It's not... I don't think it's 60 FPS on this screen.
Scott: So what I'm actually using it for is not to play Mario so much, but more, like, the watch part.
Scott: So if you try to use it as a watch or, like, a desk clock or a nightstand clock, it doesn't have any alarm feature.
Scott: It's just showing you the time and that's it.
Rym: I feel like this is the kind of thing you either put on your desk at work or, like, leave in a waiting room for people to poke at or on a coffee table for people to poke at.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: It's pretty good as a desk clock.
Scott: So the thing is, if you don't have it plugged into USB all the time, it'll just eventually... You'll see this surprisingly high resolution image of, like, Mario taking a nap and then it will turn off.
Scott: So you have to keep the USB-C plugged in at all times for the clock to keep going.
Scott: But if you do, it's actually a very nice clock because, like, basically Mario is, like, constantly doing stuff.
Scott: He, like, hits his head on the numbers to change them.
Scott: They're made out of bricks.
Scott: You can change the scenery.
Scott: Occasionally he'll, like, go into a water level or fight a Bowser just, like, randomly and do all sorts of cute stuff.
Scott: It's, like, stuff is happening, right?
Scott: So it's pretty, you know, it's not boring to have it there, you know?
Scott: It's, like, a really interesting timepiece.
Scott: I guess you could just write a piece of software that does this.
Scott: It's like a screensaver with a clock on it, kind of.
Rym: I guess I stand by.
Rym: This is something you put on your desk at work and every now and then you kind of fiddle with.
Rym: Or someone's, like, coming over to talk to you and they pick it up and fiddle with it.
Scott: Yeah, I think it also has great potential as if somebody is good at hardware hacking.
Scott: You could, you know, perhaps... I'm pretty sure it's just a ROM and whatever in there.
Scott: So you could easily, if you can get this to run any other program, suddenly it becomes very interesting.
Scott: So hardware hacky type people should be all over this if you can get one.
Rym: The pro move would be to steal someone else's, hack it to add creepypasta.
Rym: that'll happen occasionally on the clock screen, and then put it back.
Scott: Creepypasta does happen on the clock screen, normally.
Scott: So it's, like, you'll be, like, "What just happened?
Scott: What?".
Scott: And also the background behind Mario.
Scott: It's, like, during the day.
Scott: it's just the normal Mario background color.
Scott: But actually it's, like, it fades like it's the sun sets and then it rises in the morning.
Rym: Now I kind of want one, but they're sold out everywhere.
Scott: Alright, well, I got one.
Scott: I ordered it, like, less than a week ago and it showed up, like, the next day.
Scott: I think I ordered it last Friday and it showed up Saturday.
Rym: Oh, not too bad.
Rym: I guess it sold out.
Rym: I guess it came out, people were, like, "Oh, it
Rym: exists!"
Rym: and then it sold out.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, if I didn't get one, I'd have been, like,
Scott: "Whatev.".
Scott: Yeah, that's kind of how I feel.
Scott: It's, like,
Scott: "Whatev.".
Rym: I mean, looking at my desk right now, I have two different identical smartphones just sitting here.
Scott: Yeah, I just sort of bought it on a whim, like, "Alright, whatev," you know.
Rym: I've spent more money on dumber things before and this thing's actually pretty cool.
Scott: I've been using it as a clock for, like, a couple days now.
Scott: It's kind of nice, actually.
Scott: You don't want to turn the noise on.
Scott: You can control the sound and the brightness.
Scott: You don't want the sound on when it's in clock mode, at least not all the time, because it makes noises constantly, like tick, tick, tick, like doot, doot, doot.
Scott: It's annoying.
Scott: It's fine if you're just, like, pulling it out of your pocket to check the time, but it's not fine if you've got it on all the time, like on your desk.
Rym: So I bought something not on a whim.
Rym: I put myself on the mailing list for this a long time ago, and I finally, it chewed through the queue.
Rym: I'm sure this means that version two of this is going to come out, like, right after I get it, but whatever.
Rym: So I'm finally going to get a Valve Index because I'm kind of going, like, I'm diving deep into VR.
Rym: I'm not going to get into, like, the games I'm going to play with it or anything because that's more of a Tuesday thing.
Scott: All two of them.
Rym: There's more.
Rym: There's actually, Star Wars Squadrons is, don't buy VR just for Star Wars Squadrons, obviously, but Star Wars Squadrons is great in VR.
Rym: If you can name, like, four other VR games you want to play, then low-end, like mid-tier consumer VR, probably worth it for you.
Rym: But one, I want to develop in VR, and two, I want to try more esoteric and interesting experiences.
Rym: And I want to get away from the Facebook ecosystem because they basically said that all Oculus devices will be garbage within a couple of years.
Rym: We've talked about that before.
Rym: So I figured I got to plan to get off of Oculus before that all breaks because I'm never going to make a Facebook account.
Rym: So now I'm going to put the index, which I just got the notification that I'm allowed to buy it, so I bought it.
Rym: It hasn't shipped yet.
Rym: I think it'll arrive next weekend or maybe, like, Is it just they can't make enough to meet demand?
Rym: Yeah, they just can't make enough to meet demand.
Scott: I can't imagine demand is that high.
Scott: They must not be able to make that many.
Rym: Basically, what you do is if you try to buy it on Steam, it'll say, "Okay, here's the deal.
Rym: We'll put you in the queue.
Rym: It's just a stacked queue.
Rym: We just chew through the queue as fast as we
Rym: can.".
Rym: When your number comes up, we're not just going to charge you and ship it.
Rym: We're going to email you and give you a week to decide if you actually still want it.
Scott: Why don't they do this for pre-orders of everything in the world?
Rym: Why not?
Rym: Can you imagine?
Scott: They should do this for tickets to concerts.
Rym: They should do it for a 3080.
Rym: I should be able to just get in a queue for a 3080.
Rym: PS5s.
Rym: EVGA just emails me and they're like, "Yo, dog, you still want that 3080?
Rym: Click here and it's
Rym: yours.".
Scott: That's a little different because you have several manufacturers.
Scott: There isn't just one product.
Scott: But they could each do their pre-orders in this fashion and you could get on all the queues.
Scott: And then the first one you buy and the rest of them you say no.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: But it helps the scalpers because it's easier then to control.
Rym: one Steam account, one thing.
Rym: That's another reason why Valve can do this.
Scott: That's also true.
Rym: The problem is now I'm going to get this thing.
Rym: I can use it with my 1080.
Rym: It'll be fine.
Rym: It is way better than my Oculus Rift.
Rym: Everything about it is better.
Rym: It'll work better.
Rym: It'll work directly natively with Steam.
Rym: so I can just uninstall.
Scott: I guess you'll find out if it's better on paper.
Rym: No, I've used one before.
Rym: It is literally the best VR you can possibly get without going into non-consumer hardware.
Rym: The refresh rate, the max refresh rate is 144 which is pretty crazy for VR.
Rym: The resolution is nuts.
Rym: It is an experience.
Rym: It is a boutique, powerful... This is the max.
Rym: This is like the person who got one of the first 4K monitors for VR.
Rym: And it's only $1000.
Rym: It's actually not that bad.
Rym: So I'm going to rotate the Oculus Rift, the ancient OG one that I've got, into the living room.
Rym: But I won't be able to use it out there until I get the 3080 because I ain't buying another video card.
Rym: I want to take this 1080 and put it out there in a new HDPC.
Rym: And I can't get a 3080 because scalpers bought them all.
Rym: And it is literally scalpers.
Rym: I was poking around online and I could buy a 3080 right now if I was willing to pay double MSRP.
Rym: There's just tons of them.
Scott: Yeah, but it's not the same.
Scott: It's what happens when the supply is low.
Scott: It's not the scalpers fault.
Scott: Scalpers is doing what they do.
Rym: Oh yeah, I make that argument all the time.
Rym: When I yell at kids who are mad like, "What do you mean?
Rym: PAX hotels sold
Rym: out?"
Rym: Like, dude, there's only so many hotels in Boston.
Scott: There's only so many 3080s.
Scott: The fab is making them slowly.
Rym: But what's interesting is the scalper market has outpaced the consumer market.
Rym: There are 3080s just for sale that you could just buy right now.
Rym: Plenty of them.
Rym: I could go buy three or four if I wanted, but I have to pay the markup, which is about 100% right now.
Scott: This is the same as why all the sellers are just really dumb and are not responding to market pressure.
Scott: The same reason you have all these vacant storefronts in the city.
Scott: I guess now it makes sense to have people jacking up their rent.
Scott: They'd rather not sell it and set a high price than lower the price until it sells.
Rym: Now, the most efficient way to do this, like a 3080, the most efficient market for that could possibly exist for that would be to just they sell them and basically you put in a bid like an exchange limit order book.
Rym: And whoever's willing to pay the most gets the first one.
Scott: Well, this would be something, right?
Scott: So we already have eBay, right?
Scott: eBay exists, right?
Scott: What if instead of eBay, we did like collective eBay where everyone, people are either buyers or sellers.
Scott: People have 3080s and people have money, right?
Scott: If you're a buyer, you type in secretly the most amount, the highest amount you are willing to pay for a 3080.
Rym: Scott, that is literally how the equity stock market works.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And then everyone who's got a 3080 puts in the lowest price.
Scott: they'll sell their 3080 for.
Scott: And then it just swaps 3080s as much as possible.
Rym: And all you do is you take like a 0.1% commission to facilitate each transaction.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But no website that does that exists, but it totally could.
Scott: It could.
Rym: That's literally, nothing did that for stocks.
Rym: And then one day someone was like, you know what?
Rym: I'm going to make a stock exchange.
Rym: I'm going to write down everyone's orders on a piece of paper.
Scott: eBay sort of does it, but eBay does it like.
Scott: each seller has to intentionally go and set up a specific auction.
Rym: The key would be, because think about who you're selling this to.
Rym: You sell it to normal people.
Rym: Like I would go in there and type a number because I want a 3080.
Scott: I think the thing is I would also, I would also.
Rym: But you're also selling it to the scalpers.
Rym: You have to get the scalpers to agree to type in their numbers here and sell it to them as look dudes, put in your numbers here.
Rym: And you'll maximize how much you get from your scalping with the real market.
Scott: Well, also with the service that are provided to both peoples, right.
Scott: Is I would justify my fees and increased fees.
Scott: In fact, with escrow, right.
Scott: You send me the 3080, you send me the money.
Scott: I verify it's a legit 3080.
Scott: If it's not, I send the money back.
Rym: Guess what?
Rym: Stock exchanges and clearing houses do.
Scott: Did you verify that the shit's legit?
Rym: Yeah, that's exactly like.
Rym: basically you have, it's not always escrow, but there are systems that are very similar.
Rym: If I buy stock and you sell stock and we end up transacting with our stock on an exchange, the exchange guarantees that we're both going to actually deliver.
Rym: I'm skipping a lot of steps, but it's basically that.
Rym: I feel like something like that will exist someday because there's, even if we have communism, communism is not going to cover like complete luxury goods like a 3080.
Scott: Let's just make it and ignore and do what all the Silicon Valley companies do, which is ignore the fact that laws exist until it matters.
Rym: I can't actually imagine anything illegal about this.
Scott: There's no regulation we would have to follow.
Rym: No, it's not illegal to be a scalper.
Rym: You can just fucking scalp.
Scott: Alright, so let's just make this website.
Rym: I'll be the head that to the hopper.
Rym: It's in the hopper now.
Rym: Let's do it.
Rym: We'd start with the 3080s.
Rym: I got to go find a scalper to talk to and be like, hey, would you use this?
Rym: Alright, in some actual like news news, no one should have had to tell you this.
Rym: The news is not that you should do this because that should be obvious.
Rym: You should not travel for Thanksgiving.
Rym: Do not travel anywhere to visit people for Thanksgiving.
Rym: There is a global pandemic.
Rym: Good God, do not fly anywhere to see family.
Rym: Do not go on a road trip to see people who you're not already quarantining together with.
Rym: If you already close your bubble with someone, like you and another family, mutually exclude the rest of the world, but your kids play together, that's one thing.
Scott: There's a great graphic, guys.
Rym: If there's a person... It is hard to do GeekNights on Discord.
Scott: I saw this great graphic that was like the bubble you think you have and the bubble you actually have because it showed how, oh, here's a bunch of people and each person in the Venn diagram has a reasonable bubble of only like five people.
Scott: But all of those bubbles overlap with like one or two people and your actual bubble ends up being like 30 people.
Scott: So, especially on a holiday situation, if you haven't already... Holiday times, especially in the
Scott: U.S.,
Scott: it's like you're going to see the relatives you see less often.
Scott: It's like, no, just see the people.
Scott: If you're not seeing the people on a daily frequent basis already, don't go see them.
Rym: Especially because when you form a quarantine bubble as opposed to visiting someone for a one-off, most people I think who actually do that and take it seriously do have that conversation of like, all right, how often do you actually like bump into strangers and you both have to make sure you're at the same level of risk or one party in that group is going to be super screwed.
Rym: But like, Uncle Joe, how often do you talk to Uncle Joe?
Rym: You sure Uncle Joe isn't just like going to the bar at night?
Rym: Do you trust Uncle Joe?
Rym: Did Uncle Joe get drunk at the last four Thanksgivings?
Scott: Well, even not Uncle Joe, right?
Scott: It's like, okay, so you and your neighbor and your parents.
Scott: But like, anytime I walk outside, I walk past a doorman.
Rym: So that doorman is not in my bubble.
Scott: You're not getting sick from the doorman.
Rym: But I have a contact with that doorman on a regular basis.
Scott: You're not hanging with the doorman long enough to get sick.
Scott: No, but I'm walking past him.
Scott: That doesn't matter.
Scott: You're not going to get sick walking past somebody.
Scott: Not for two seconds, right?
Scott: So you got your neighbors, two people, and you got parents, two people, right?
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Well, your parents have you, right?
Scott: One person.
Scott: And they have their friends.
Scott: Their bubble is also a small little bubble.
Scott: But those friends are in your bubble that you never see, right?
Scott: And then those friends, right?
Scott: Your parents' friends go to see someone on Thanksgiving, right?
Scott: And now suddenly all the people that they saw on Thanksgiving and all the people that they previously saw are now in your little safe bubble to five people with just your parents and your neighbor, right?
Scott: Has now been, you know, gets contact with a whole crap ton of people because their parents' friends went to see someone on Thanksgiving.
Rym: Never mind the fact that if someone flies or travels a long distance, that just opens up a whole door.
Scott: That person's got to go into a one-person bubble.
Rym: Like, I am not going anywhere near an airplane until like 2022 probably.
Scott: Yeah, definitely not a boat.
Rym: But the news is the CDC in the U.S.
Rym: actually advised Americans to not travel for Thanksgiving.
Rym: And that is notable because up until this point, due to our current president and the Republican Party, they basically prevented federal agencies from telling anyone to not do anything.
Rym: And it is notable that a federal agency is actually giving people good advice again.
Rym: That is a very good sign about the long-term future of America.
Rym: But I don't think many people are going to take that advice, and I think there's going to be a big shit show about three weeks after Thanksgiving, to be honest.
Scott: Yeah, probably, but at least to just make sure it doesn't happen to -- you know, you can't control what the rest of the people in the ridiculous world we live in are going to do, right?
Scott: There's nothing -- you know, if it happens, it's like it sucks.
Scott: I don't want it to happen.
Scott: But what can we really do to stop it?
Scott: besides tell people good advice?
Scott: Not much, right?
Scott: Well, you know, what's important is just worry about your own people.
Scott: You know, it's like not because that's a good way to think about the world to be tribal and selfish, right?
Scott: You should care for all the people, but, you know, when it comes to action, you've got to accept that you can't do anything for the other people, even though you might want to, or there's little you can do.
Rym: Like, I was out walking the other night, and I walked past a bar or a restaurant that was open and had indoor dining, and there were a shit ton of people in there.
Rym: There's nothing I can do about those people.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: Just stay away from them.
Rym: Other than avoid them.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So last thing, I've been kind of, when I'm exercising, working my way through the original Unsolved Mysteries, because it's all just free on YouTube.
Scott: You can watch anything.
Scott: You have access to all the video, audio, book content in the history, you know, and you choose, of all the things, to watch some garbo TV show from the '80s, '90s.
Rym: I'm not watching every episode, and I'm skipping all the boring ones, but basically I'm watching all the, like, UFO bullshit ones that are, like, ghost nonsense, because they're actually, as an adult, I have not seen most of these since I was a kid.
Rym: They're actually really, really, really funny, if you're an adult, watching a lot of them.
Rym: I'm sure they are.
Rym: And people have been bugging me about this, because a lot of people know I'm watching Unsolved Mysteries again, and I have a lot of feelings about that show, that there is a new, like, a reboot of Unsolved Mysteries that's on Netflix.
Rym: But it's actually, I have not watched it yet, but a lot of people have been telling me that it is kind of, like, serious, like, it's more like a real documentary, and that they are earnestly presenting cases where they believe the public could help solve this crime, or bring someone to justice, or save somebody.
Rym: And it seems like it's actually, it might be kind of like the original show, where, for all the ghost nonsense, they actually did solve a lot of crimes, for real, with people calling in tips.
Scott: I also wonder, though, is, like, a lot of those, especially the crime ones, it's like, if you're not local to where that crime was, it's like, you can't, what are the odds?
Scott: you can help, right?
Scott: You're so... Unless you recognize a person who moved to your neighborhood recently.
Rym: A lot of them were that.
Rym: Someone was, like, on the lam after a murder, like, and the phone call was someone in a different state who, like, recognized the person under a different name coming to their golf club, or some crap like that.
Rym: But in this case, this news came by, just while I was looking for news today, because I didn't really want to talk about the coup attempt, or the global pandemic, or any of that nonsense too much.
Rym: And not only is the Netflix show apparently, like, legit like this, the new one, but they're actually even, like, right now, there are updates on cases they have covered in the new show, and they're asking the public for more information, and the police are following up.
Rym: Like, it seems to be making progress on some cases.
Rym: So I'm going to link to one of those.
Rym: Like, they're asking about all these people who went to some party.
Scott: These are, like, things that the police should be doing, and not, you know, harassing.
Rym: Oh yeah, it's almost like we need to completely re-envision what the concept of police is, because right now, if I call the police because someone stole my bike, they're not going to do shit.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: What do I have?
Scott: So I think I used them as a thing of the day before.
Scott: There is an amazing musical group from Korea, of course, known as Norazo.
Scott: They did a song that, I mean, they've done a lot of songs, but the first song I saw from them, I think, was the cider song.
Scott: In Korea, I think they refer to Sprite as cider, right?
Scott: C-I-D, whatever.
Scott: And then they also had the shower song, and today they have released the bread song.
Scott: The music video is kind of amazing, I think because of the restrictions due to the pandemic and such.
Scott: They want to release a music video, but you've got to get a whole crew together, right?
Scott: You've got to get a lot of people in one place to make a music video.
Scott: They don't want to do that.
Scott: It's a lot of work, especially when, you know, I don't think they're making as much money as some of the other major acts out there, right?
Scott: They're mostly making enough money to keep this going, though.
Scott: So the entire music video is green-screened with hilarious CG, and three costumes, and just a couple backup dancers, and that's it.
Scott: And it's just like, I think what we're going to be able to tell, looking back, video things-- Who knew production and who didn't when they didn't have all their staff?
Scott: Well, no, you're going to be able to look back and say, "Ah, you see?
Scott: This video is--.
Scott: We can tell this video is from 2020, because look at how they tried to reduce how many people were in it," right?
Scott: But yeah, hilarious, excellent video.
Rym: Well, wait until there's movies about the year 2020 or set during this whole pandemic.
Rym: Will everyone wear masks in the movie, or will they just not?
Rym: Because that would be weird in a movie if the movie wasn't about the pandemic.
Scott: Right, so if you like wacky comedy-type stuff, you know, the sort of ridiculous, eccentric, Eurobeat, high-energy ridiculousness, these are your people.
Rym: So this is just a really cute animation by a third-year CalArts student.
Rym: I just tumbled onto it the other day.
Rym: It's actually a YouTube video from 2013.
Scott: From what year?
Scott: Does it have a year on it?
Scott: Oh, old, okay.
Rym: It's old, but I've just never seen it until recently.
Rym: It's called Moon Goddess.
Rym: It's the story of Aphrodite.
Rym: You know the story where dude accidentally sees her naked and she turns him into a deer?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Well, this is a take on that, but dude Aphrodite is just there, or Artemis, Artemis, Artemis is just there being cool, and horny dude shows up being annoying, and Artemis turns horny dude into a deer, and it's cute and funny after that.
Scott: Yeah, I did watch this.
Scott: Yeah, I remember.
Rym: Yep, I liked it.
Rym: And the meta moment.
Rym: We are, I haven't read any more Tales of Genji.
Rym: I have not gotten past the point where I read two previously yet.
Scott: I also have not.
Rym: It's a game of chicken on which one of us gets to a new page first, thus triggering the apocalypse.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: New code of conduct, there's conventions, the MagFest virtual convention was announced, so I assume we're going to be taking part in that in some fashion.
Scott: Oh, I hadn't thought of that, but I guess that will happen.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, stay tuned.
Rym: There's going to be a VR Gaylord.
Scott: I was thinking about it.
Scott: I was just like, oh, I guess I'll go to that.
Scott: It's like, oh wait, no, I probably have to do a panel edit.
Rym: Yeah, we're going to have to set up all our ridiculous nonsense and do a panel again.
Scott: No.
Rym: Hey, at least we put all the hard work in, we know how to do it, and we've gotten through the growing pains of, let me tell you, it is really fucking hard to record a panel the style of how Rym and Scott normally do panels when we're not in the same room.
Rym: I cannot stress enough.
Scott: I guess the cold is going to make outside not an option.
Rym: I know.
Rym: We never even got to the point of doing outside as much as we wanted to because it was also a pain in the ass.
Rym: So we're going to have to go through this one more time.
Rym: I feel like I want to try to structure the kinds of panels we do to be more conducive to this environment.
Rym: I don't know what that means or what that looks like, but we'll figure something out.
Rym: Otherwise, there's a lot of post-processing and a lot of false starts and a lot of talking over each other that I got to edit out.
Rym: So it's perfect time to talk about this.
Rym: It is now officially hoodie weather, though it's rapidly approaching full winter coat weather.
Rym: But it's still at the point where if I go outside, all I got to put on is a hoodie.
Rym: It's not that cold yet.
Rym: And we've done a lot of shows on clothes over the years.
Rym: Clothes and Food are two of our go-to.
Rym: what are we going to do on Thursday, look around the room, think about a food we've eaten recently and do a whole show on it.
Rym: But hoodies, actually, I think a lot about hoodies.
Rym: I own a lot of hoodies now.
Rym: I got a lot to say about hoodies, I think.
Rym: And we'll get into jackets if we run out of steam on hoodies somehow.
Scott: I don't think we'll run out of steam on hoodies.
Scott: There's a lot to say about hoodies.
Rym: There is a lot to say about hoodies.
Scott: I was watching some videos on YouTube even before we decided on this episode about the history of hoodies, and it was going way back to monks.
Scott: You think about a monk wearing a cloak with a hood.
Scott: And it's showing basically the history of hooded garments, which are basically all hoodies.
Scott: They're just different manufacturing methods, different materials and such over time.
Scott: And what we think of today is the champion hoodie made out of cotton jersey.
Rym: We think of hoodies, they're usually a pullover or a zip-up.
Rym: They got a hood, they got two pockets to the side.
Scott: It's a newer garment.
Scott: It's not that old on its own, but the hood in general, the hooded jacket of some kind, goes way further back.
Scott: And they're all related.
Scott: They're all the same thing.
Scott: And if you're a fashion historian, I guess there's a such thing as that.
Scott: There's probably tons of history about every kind of garment.
Scott: But the hoodie in particular is just really fascinating in what it means culturally, practically, the different scenarios in which you wear it, places you've seen it that are significant.
Scott: And the signals that it sends and how that's changed over time.
Scott: The types of people who would wear it.
Rym: Scrolling through this Wikipedia, it shows a picture from the 70s of people wearing actually modern looking hoodies.
Rym: But that's on the front page of this Wikipedia article.
Rym: Because the 70s, they weren't that common yet.
Rym: At least not the way they were later.
Rym: But you also see the UK, they have a whole section on bars banning them, getting into the cultural aspects of hoodies.
Rym: We went from a time- Oh great, a picture of the Unabomber.
Rym: Here we go.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: So you've got Unabomber wearing a hoodie.
Scott: That's iconic.
Scott: You've seen, what's the movie, Hot Fuzz, right?
Scott: The bad kids in town are like the hoodies.
Scott: It's sort of like wearing a hoodie is sinister.
Scott: It was associated with gang violence.
Rym: It was associated with trying to hide your identity when you needed to, across multiple cultural contexts.
Scott: The hood has so many uses, right?
Scott: Comfort, warmth.
Rym: Like if it's actually cold, a hood on a proper winter jacket is crucial.
Scott: So it went from that, but you've also got like, at least say Silicon Valley CEOs wearing t-shirt and hoodie, as opposed to suit, which all CEOs would wear previously.
Rym: Now it's funny, because when I think about my own life, I never wore hoodies, really, until a few packs is in when I bought that Pax hoodie.
Rym: I never liked hoodies, because in fact, I never liked long-sleeved garments of any kind, and I tried to avoid wearing them at all costs for much of my life.
Rym: Like I never, as a kid, like up until high school, like after high school, never wore sweaters, like ever, except if you and my mom bought me and kind of pushed me into wearing.
Scott: Well, sweaters are a little bit different.
Scott: I avoided sweaters in my youth, because the ones I had were like the itchy wool kind.
Rym: Oh yeah, I had a few of those.
Rym: My mom actually made me get all these Abercrombie ones that were pretty fashionable, but I had kid brain, but my idea of fashion was kid brain fashion, so I didn't like all the fashionable things.
Scott: But I eventually came back to sweaters when I got ones that weren't itchy.
Rym: Yeah, but even not itchy.
Rym: My whole life, I hate wearing long sleeves, and only in my like late adulthood do I tolerate wearing long sleeves, except in like extreme temperatures.
Scott: You can cut your sleeves off a hoodie if you want.
Scott: No one's stopping you.
Rym: Yeah, good.
Rym: But in high school, middle school, like whenever I needed something warm, like the kind of weather today where I'd like put on a hoodie, in those times, I was one of those kids who would put on a flannel button-down shirt that I did not actually button, and that was what served as my warming garment.
Rym: I was a flannel kid.
Scott: See, the hoodie, I feel like it's, you know, it's not quite a jacket, and it's not quite a shirt.
Scott: It's like, you know, putting on just a plain sweatshirt, you could, right?
Scott: But the plain sweatshirt is more of like either a lounge wear, an athletic wear, maybe you're going outside to like rake the leaves or something, you know?
Scott: It's sort of like, eh, you know, right?
Scott: Whereas the hoodie is like, I need to be warmer than I am now, right?
Scott: I'm not necessarily like going out.
Scott: If I'm going out, right, I'm going to put on a jacket, because I'm going out.
Rym: Outdoors.
Rym: Well, it depends on the weather.
Rym: I generally also avoid, I don't have light jackets.
Rym: I have full jacket, and I have like nothing.
Scott: Sure, but it's like you can put on the jacket, go outside, when you get at your destination, you take off the jacket, put it on a coat rack.
Rym: True, but you keep the hoodie with you.
Scott: Right, then you would, when you leave, right?
Scott: So the jacket is just for keeping you warm during that outside transitionary period.
Scott: The hoodie, it's like the hoodie is making you warmer, but you don't take it off.
Scott: It's an indoor/outdoor, right?
Rym: Well, you know where the change was for me?
Scott: I'll even put a jacket on over the hoodie, right?
Scott: It's like, okay, it's a little bit cold inside, but it's like too cold inside to just wear a shirt only, but it's really too cold outside to not wear a jacket.
Scott: You just described MagFest.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like hoodie, then jacket.
Scott: So it's like I get where I'm going, I take off a jacket, but it's still cold.
Scott: It's a little bit cold inside.
Scott: I got the hoodie.
Rym: But it was really like it was conventions that got me to start wearing hoodies, primarily because the way I use a hoodie is it is the versatile garment for the variety of conditions I'll run into, primarily at conventions, like tabletop's.
Rym: really cold for some reason, but when I walk out of the main area, it's really warm.
Rym: I can take the hoodie off and like tie it around my waist.
Rym: That's also fashionable.
Rym: If it's really cold, I can pull the hood up and put my hands in the pockets.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I've always had it like, you know, wherever my office is where I'm working, I always have like a hoodie on the chair at work or a hoodie on the chair at home.
Scott: And it's sort of like, okay, you know, the place that you are frequently, you've just got this hoodie at the ready.
Scott: In case you're cold or whatever, you can just put it on.
Scott: Maybe you just need to, you're going to go out, but you're going out quickly.
Scott: Well, the hoodie's right here.
Scott: Grab, go out quickly and then come back in, you know, or maybe it's going to rain, but you're not sure it's going to rain.
Scott: And maybe it's not, if it does rain, it's not going to be like umbrella raincoat rain and you're not going to be out that long.
Scott: You just don't want your head to get that wet.
Scott: So you just need the hoodie hood.
Scott: You don't need any other kind of, you know, hood action.
Scott: Maybe it's not that cold.
Scott: You don't need a big heavy jacket, but it's going to be windy.
Scott: You want to keep your ears warm.
Scott: You don't want to wear a hat.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The thing is though, the hoodie hoods tend not to be windbreakers.
Rym: And if I, if I'm worried about wind, I have a lot of specialized sports jackets and sports gear to cover that sort of thing.
Rym: And I'll use those windows again.
Scott: The wind is that severe that you need a specialized gear.
Rym: But if it's not that severe, I would just never put anything up on my head in the first place.
Rym: Like I almost never pull the hood up on a hoodie like ever.
Scott: No, I use the hood a lot.
Rym: Well, I guess I have a lot of hair.
Rym: I basically have a built in hoodie.
Rym: The one thing I hate though, my whole life I have hated pullovers.
Rym: Like I do, I cannot stand a pullover hoodie because the whole point of me wearing a hoodie is that I can take it off and put it on really quickly without like messing up my hair or like any hassle.
Rym: Like I can keep it on zip most of the time.
Rym: I only zip it up if I'm cold.
Rym: If it's a pullover, there's a little more hassle to take it out or put it off.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I don't have hair to worry about, at least not right now, but I still do prefer the zip hoodie to the pullover hoodie.
Rym: People in the chat are really talking about their hoodie preferences, but people are talking about these button up hoodies, which I don't think I've ever seen in my life.
Scott: Button up hoodie is kind of weird.
Scott: It's like, it's even harder to put on.
Rym: I mean, I refuse to wear a button fly.
Rym: I remember those got popular for a little bit.
Rym: I was like, no, that just delays me peeing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, no, the pullover hoodie is just sort of like, uh, like.
Scott: I don't understand why they still make it when the zipper exists.
Scott: Is it cheaper?
Scott: Is like wind going to come in the zipper area?
Rym: It's warmer, but the problem for me is if I want something that's like warm, warm, where the zipper is going to matter, I'm wearing a jacket at that point.
Rym: And if you're really cold, you get a jacket where you've got the special zippers that are insulated.
Rym: Like all my ski jackets are like that and all my sports jackets are like that.
Rym: But I also focus on hoodies as a fashion thing.
Rym: Like I mostly wear them, like I said, in conventions because they're versatile, but also because every hoodie I own is definitely social currency.
Rym: They're all either like packs, hoodies, or like from, from some property or like I've got a glitch wave hoodie that I really like.
Rym: Like they're definitely primarily fashion accessory.
Scott: I mean, that is an interesting thing in, in 2020, you know, or at least more recently, right.
Scott: Is it's like, you know, say when like Rocky wore a hoodie, it's like, that wasn't like a fashion item that was like a workout clothing.
Rym: Like I'd always imagine hoodies as being black or gray, maybe red, like all one color, cotton, cheap.
Rym: But now when I think of hoodie, I think of like my like line of fancy hoodies that are hanging over there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like the hoodie now.
Scott: is it's like, it's, it's utilitarian and fashionable at the same time.
Scott: You know, it's, it, you know, you can, you can show off like your, your sweet hoodie.
Scott: Let me, Champion, the company, I guess it was originally called something else at the time they invented the hoodie, but it became Champion, which I don't know who owns it now.
Scott: Wikipedia will probably tell you.
Scott: But the brand still exists.
Scott: And that was the brand that invented the hoodie.
Scott: The hoodies they make now are like super nice, fancy fashion hoodies.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're not like, I mean, I guess you could wear one and go rake the leaves, but you probably wouldn't because it's a lot of money.
Rym: I went through this like the cheapest rapid transition, like about 2019 where I had like, I only owned one hoodie.
Rym: It was that original PEX one that I got and it wore the fuck out because I wore it a lot.
Rym: And I started to like have to get a new hoodie, wear it out, get a new hoodie, wear it out.
Rym: And I changed to a strategy now of own a bunch of hoodies and rotate through them.
Rym: So no one of them wears out particularly quickly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So a Champion, the default pullover Champion hoodie, the reverse weave hoodie is like 60 bucks.
Scott: But if you scroll down immediately, right past the first row of boring old hoodies, you see just tons of tons of fancy hoodies that are all fashiony.
Scott: We got Mario hoodie, Toad hoodie, Mario hoodie.
Rym: I really like hoodies that have a striking, even if they're playing on the outside, the inside of the hood.
Scott: Here's some with iridescent logos on them.
Scott: Here's one with a giant C for Champion on the front.
Scott: Here's some camo hoodies.
Scott: Here's one with a different color hood.
Scott: It's like a white hoodie, but the hood itself is like turquoise and it's kind of fluffy, right?
Scott: I like the materials, right?
Scott: So we think of, at least in terms of the Champion hoodie, right?
Scott: You're thinking of like, you know, that sort of cotton jersey sweatshirt, sweat pant material.
Rym: I only have one hoodie like that and I only use it for like ski lodge stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Hoodies today, it's like.
Scott: you got fleece lined hoodies and that's like not, that's tame.
Scott: You've got like velour kind of hoodies, all kinds of, you know, fancy materials, different textures, some really smooth hoodies, right?
Scott: You got hoodies with like, you know, fancy sport tech type, you know, wools and things, right?
Scott: You know, it's all the same shape basically, but different thicknesses, right?
Scott: Here's one with a mesh pocket on the front with a zipper.
Scott: It's obviously not utilitarian pocket, right?
Rym: You know, actually I realized one benefit of the pullover hoodie is usually the two pockets combined for added warmth.
Scott: Yes, usually you have the kangaroo pocket on the pullover hoodie.
Scott: So if you're into the kangaroo pocket, the zipper isn't going to.
Rym: I'm not a fan of that.
Rym: What I like, I only have one hoodie that has this.
Rym: It's that original Pax Prime hoodie, the blue one, the one that peeled up like we all have.
Rym: The thing about that one is in the right pocket, there's a little like sub pocket that is exactly the right size to wedge a cell phone into.
Rym: And I actually love that feature and use it a lot.
Rym: And I've never found another hoodie that has that little tiny sub pocket that is exactly the right size for a cell phone.
Scott: Well, the pocket on the hoodie is another great thing, right?
Scott: Because, you know, you think about it.
Scott: It's like, OK, you get pants pocket, right?
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: And you got your.
Scott: normally if a shirt has a pocket, it's like a dorky pocket, you know, protector pocket, right?
Scott: The hoodie gives you pockets in a place that a coat gives you pockets.
Scott: But now you can have those pockets indoors like those.
Scott: If you had if you're wearing a hoodie, those are now the primary, most accessible, most useful, you know, easily grabable pockets.
Rym: Now, I wouldn't put anything like super important, like I'm not putting my keys in those pockets because I feel like they'd fall out if I wasn't careful.
Scott: It depends on the hoodie.
Rym: Somebody said like the pockets have like a little bit, a stitch at the bottom and they're angled the right way to where stuff won't fall out, kind of like bike jerseys.
Rym: But I've seen some hoodies where if you like look the wrong way or bend slightly, everything just falls out of the pockets.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But also, if you are maybe wearing clothing that does not have any pockets.
Scott: You know, say maybe you're wearing, you know, some maybe like some like tights for some exercise, like some yoga situation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like those don't have pockets on them usually.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Or, you know, maybe you're wearing like a skirt and it doesn't have pockets or a dress with no pockets.
Scott: You know, you could pop a hoodie on over to the top pockets.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's a you know, and it's such a. the hoodie is such a, you know, gender neutral garment.
Scott: It's pretty much anyone can wear one at any age.
Scott: Right.
Scott: At any time in almost any situation.
Scott: A hoodie can be appropriate.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You could even see someone like wearing a fancy gown at a ball.
Scott: But meanwhile, on their chair at their table where the assigned seating is, they got a hoodie over the back of the chair.
Scott: That doesn't seem strange at all.
Rym: That's perfectly normal.
Rym: You know, my day job is in capital markets.
Rym: And just because of the nature of my work, sometimes I'm wearing like a blazer and sometimes I'm wearing nice jeans, a T-shirt of some kind and a hoodie.
Rym: And that is just totally accepted and expected.
Rym: So the fanciest hoodie I own in terms of like the quality, it's weird that this is the one.
Rym: Like it is just so much higher quality than any other hoodie I've ever owned is of all things that Penny Arcade, remember Automata?
Scott: Oh, that one.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And they made that special like black on black on black hoodie.
Rym: That hoodie ended up just being like such high quality.
Rym: Like that is the best hoodie I own by far.
Scott: So, you know, early, I guess early in my life, most of the hoodies I got, I would buy, you know, before buying clothes online and going to fancy stores.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There was like, you know, the local clothing store that was in Connecticut.
Scott: Where you just buy clothes at.
Scott: I think it was called like Bob's something.
Scott: It wasn't related to the discount furniture, whatever.
Scott: I don't think it was like a huge chain.
Scott: But, you know, imagine like a Kohl's basically.
Scott: Same kind of place.
Scott: Only clothes, mostly clothes.
Rym: Yeah, it was Midwest.
Rym: So we were mostly national chains.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: OK.
Scott: But I mean, it was still a chain.
Scott: It just, you know, but you'd go in there and if I wanted a hoodie, I would get the one.
Scott: I would get a Rangers hoodie or a Mets hoodie or, you know, a sports team related hoodie.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And who knew who was made by.
Scott: And I didn't care about clothing quality then.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, and those are the hoodies I had.
Scott: Just whatever.
Scott: I think maybe I did have the actual champion hoodie at one point.
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: You know, but hoodies are actually kind of like expensive.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Compared to like, say, a shirt.
Scott: It's like, you know, if some artist you like is like making merch, it's like you want to buy their T-shirt.
Scott: It's like, oh, OK, 20 bucks, maybe 25, 35 if it's extra fancy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're making a hoodie.
Scott: It's like, yeah, it's 67.
Scott: It's a lot of money suddenly.
Scott: But then, you know, I started buying hoodies later with stuff I cared about on them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like pecs hoodies.
Scott: But they were making these pecs hoodies on.
Scott: basically the way that works is, you know, some artist is just buying stock hoodies from some company, Gildan or American Apparel or Hanes or who knows who.
Scott: Right.
Scott: For someone of those, you know, major clothing companies just buying blank hoodies and screen printing on them.
Scott: And the hoodie that they choose is not always going to be the best hoodie.
Rym: The pecs hoodies have definitely gotten worse and worse quality as time has gone on.
Rym: Like, I'm glad they're buying.
Scott: They're basically buying in bulk the cheapest blank hoodie they can get and then putting, you know, pexifying.
Rym: Like, I'm very glad I own the first like pecs blue hoodie, like the good one.
Rym: And that first pex east hoodie, because those are way higher quality than the hoodies I've seen.
Scott: They are higher quality, but the quality overall compared to all hoodies in the world is still not that high.
Scott: True.
Scott: So the biggest thing that wears out on the hoodies, the problems I've had with them personally is, A, the hood, the inside of the hood can get kind of there even if you wash it.
Scott: Especially if the lining is thin or if the color is bright and your head oils get on there.
Scott: It's like you just can't wash them out no matter what.
Scott: And especially I got a bald head.
Scott: So it's even worse if you're putting I guess room is not putting the hood on.
Rym: So I never put the hood on.
Rym: So my hoods are all like immaculate.
Scott: The dark colored hoodie obviously has less problem with that sort of thing.
Scott: And then the other thing is that thin material, right, can wear because you're wearing a hoodie a lot.
Scott: Like you might wear the hoodie every day or frequently.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So what ends up happening is it just gets worn out because you're wearing it more.
Scott: And the areas that it gets worn out are elbows.
Scott: If you're putting your elbows on tables a lot, especially which I do, I'm doing it right now.
Scott: And also the pockets, if you've got stuff in the pockets sagging them down, rubbing on the inside of them.
Scott: And so I've had hoodies with like a hole in the pocket or a hoodie where the elbow is... Like all my PAX hoodies, you look at the elbow and it looks like someone just rubbed them a whole bunch.
Rym: Well that's especially because when you're wearing a PAX hoodie at PAXs, because we go to a lot of PAXs, half the time you're sitting there with your elbows down on a table playing a tabletop game.
Scott: But I do it also just every single day.
Scott: That same hoodie I wear at PAX, I bring to work.
Scott: And then I wear at work all day.
Scott: But yeah, they wear out.
Scott: So recently I went online and I was searching through hoodies to find like... I didn't care what was on the hoodie.
Scott: I was okay with plain color.
Scott: I just wanted to find the strongest, most comfortable, highest quality hoodie that was available.
Rym: I think that's the Automata Penny Arcade hoodie.
Scott: No, you haven't seen this hoodie that I got.
Scott: So I don't know if this one is the best one.
Scott: Because basically what I did is I went and I read a whole ton of hoodie reviews and watched hoodie reviews on YouTube.
Scott: And I learned a lot about all the different available hoodies to choose from.
Scott: And I chose one, and that one that I chose was so great.
Scott: So I have nothing to compare it against.
Scott: There may be a greater one that I simply, because I just chose one based on other people's advice, I chose wisely.
Scott: Or it could be that no, actually this isn't the best hoodie.
Scott: There is a better one.
Scott: I just didn't discover it.
Scott: But it's so much better than any hoodie that I've owned.
Scott: And you can tell immediately out of the box, out of the bag, that it's so great.
Scott: So it's made by this company I've never heard of before called American Giant.
Scott: The hoodie is almost too thick.
Scott: It's super warm when you put it on.
Scott: It's like, whoa, I had to take it off because I'm too warm.
Scott: They had a medium weight one, but they sold out.
Scott: So I kind of want to get one of those.
Scott: The elbows are actually reinforced, right?
Scott: So the material for the sleeve, it's got a full sleeve, but then there's an extra piece of material that comes on top of the sleeve, right?
Scott: It's like an extra, extra layer that goes from the front half of the forearm, like the bottom half of the forearm, all the way to covering the elbow.
Scott: So it's like double reinforced there.
Scott: And the zipper is way strong.
Scott: The hood, right?
Scott: So I look on the Pax hood, for example, the Pax hoodie, and it's two layers on the Pax hoodie.
Scott: There's the cotton jersey, and then there's like this thin lining on the inside, right?
Scott: This hoodie, the American Giant one, whatever, the hood is two layers of cotton jersey.
Scott: It's just like a double thick hood, right?
Scott: It's ridiculously solid and heavy, and the size and shape of the hood varies a lot, actually.
Scott: I watched a lot of hoodie reviews, and they were like, "This hood covers my whole head.
Scott: This one doesn't.
Scott: This one's super huge.
Scott: Look, you can't even see my
Scott: face.".
Scott: There was so much variance in the hood shape.
Scott: You know, this hood keeps falling down.
Scott: I can't see with this one, but the hood shape was just excellent.
Scott: So yeah, I think if you... The problem is it's just really hard to get sort of the two-in-one deal, right?
Scott: There's nobody out there who's taking an expensive, ultra-high quality garment and then also putting their cool webcomic art on it, right?
Scott: The webcomic artist that wants to sell hoodies, they're going to sell $50 hoodies, not $150 hoodies.
Rym: Because most people buying a hoodie for the intellectual property that is associated with it are doing it solely for that purpose.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: It is social currency.
Scott: I don't know how much market there is for, you know.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: But yeah, it's the nicest hoodie I've ever had, probably.
Scott: And people I saw who had it and reviewed it said it lasted them many, many years and was still new.
Scott: And holding it, even though it's only a week old or whatever, I can see how that could be the case, and I hope it is.
Scott: So we'll find out.
Rym: Yeah, the hoodie I got, and it's sad because I got it literally.
Rym: I ordered it right before PAX East, went to PAX East, I got this hoodie, and I can't fucking go anywhere.
Rym: So no one's seen me wear it, really, except the burger joint downstairs.
Rym: But I got this super glitch wave hoodie.
Rym: It's like a slim fitting hoodie.
Rym: I've seen a lot more slim fits these days.
Rym: And it's my favorite hoodie.
Rym: And I was actually weirdly looking forward to wearing it at a PAX, and I can't.
Rym: Because I'm kind of done wearing the PAX hoodie to the PAX.
Rym: That's starting to feel more and more like I'm wearing the shirt of the band to the band's concert.
Rym: Like I want to signal some other thing that I'm interested in when I'm at a PAX, because you know I'm a PAX person.
Scott: I'm at the PAX.
Scott: Alright, well.
Rym: I think that killed enough time.
Scott: Okay, but yeah, hoodies.
Scott: Essential garment of, you know, the times.
Rym: I feel like hoodies are going to be very iconic of the late 2010s and 2020s, like in terms of fashion.
Scott: Yeah, there's so many other, you know, every kind of clothing, right?
Scott: You can go on and on about if you knew more about it than we did.
Scott: But my guess would be if you're going to pick one particular clothing item, right, that really symbolizes, you know, the time that we have lived in, like the hoodie is way up there, right?
Scott: It's certainly not like the jean.
Scott: The jean was for a previous era.
Scott: Not that we don't wear them, but I think it's more symbolic of a time before us.
Rym: And I think the types of jeans people wear, like the fashion of jeans, has actually moved around a lot over the last couple of decades.
Scott: It's like the baseball hat is strong, but it's not the baseball hat, you know?
Rym: Yeah, I haven't seen a lot of other types of hats.
Rym: People are really wearing berets a lot in the US.
Scott: It could be the sneaker.
Scott: The sneaker is really strong, right?
Rym: True.
Scott: The hoodie and the sneaker are pretty close.
Rym: But that's really dependent.
Rym: I think there's more cultural bounds to the fancy sneakers than there is to a fancy hoodie.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't have to be fancy.
Scott: I'm just saying, like, all hoodie versus all sneaker, right?
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: I guess I could make a GeekNights hoodie high quality with the new logos and everything.
Rym: Like, that could be classy.
Scott: Yeah, you know, but how high quality are we going to make it?
Rym: Yep, I can make it mid quality without doing any work because I do have that Amazon account, but high quality would take some effort.
Scott: Just so people are aware, let's see, the hoodie that I bought is the American Giant Classic Full Zip.
Scott: It costs $112.
Rym: Yeah, so would you buy a $120 GeekNights hoodie?
Rym: Otherwise, you're not going to get a high quality hoodie.
Scott: I mean, if this hoodie does end up lasting for many, many years more than other hoodies have lasted, then that's actually kind of like a bargain, right?
Scott: Because if you think of regular hoodies, $60, this is the cost of two hoodies.
Scott: If it lasts as long as, you know, two shitty hoodies, you're saving, right?
Rym: Someone in the chat said something about Root hoodies.
Scott: Like the board game?
Rym: That's what I was assuming.
Rym: Maybe it's just a brand because I don't see any Root.
Scott: There is a company that I think called Roots that makes hoodies.
Rym: I think it's Roots makes good hoodies, not.
Rym: there are Roots hoodies.
Scott: Yes, there is a clothing company called Roots.
Scott: If you go to roots.com.
Scott: The thing I don't like about the Roots ones actually, I did look at those, is that they prominently put the Roots logo like right on the front of pretty much all of their clothing.
Scott: And I like to have clothing where the logo is not on there, right?
Scott: You go to Uniqlo and it's like very few clothes at Uniqlo have a Uniqlo logo on the clothes.
Scott: You buy a red shirt there, it's a red shirt.
Scott: But if you buy a Roots hoodie, it says Roots on the front.
Scott: Odds are it says Roots on the front.
Rym: Yeah, I don't want that.
Rym: That just reeks of Abercrombie and Fitch.
Scott: Well, I think the one I hate the most is Superdry because Superdry clothes, actually the aesthetic of those clothes, I like a lot.
Scott: It's not my favorite, but I do like it a lot.
Scott: The only thing I'm not a fan of is the puffy jacket.
Rym: I've never liked puffy jacket.
Scott: Yeah, every single item of clothing in the Superdry store says Superdry on it.
Scott: And it's like if you had just taken your logo off of that clothing, I would have paid probably more than what you're charging to buy it.
Scott: Because the shape looks pretty good.
Scott: But no, it says Superdry and I'm like get that shit out of here.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Heike McNichol, Marty Grenier, Link E.G, Graham Finch, you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: And I yelled at the cabbie, "Yo, home smell, smell ya
Rym: later!".
Rym: Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Chris Minkiff, Dre, Lily Tenebrae, JustLikeADudeGuy, Chris Reimer, Finn, Shervin Von Horl, and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: So I'm not going to inflict more Neil Cicierega on you, but instead, I've got something else that's kind of fun.
Rym: Hopefully you recognize it.
Scott: It's all skeletons, isn't it?
Rym: Yeah, let's go.
Rym: Right, but why is it all skeletons?
Scott: What did we do?
Scott: We did have a lot of xylophones on the last record.
Scott: Right, that we did, six or seven.
Scott: Why'd we put so many goddamn xylophones on the song?
Scott: I had been listening to a lot of Tom Waits, and he's got those marimbas.
Scott: Under Your Thumb, Rolling Stones.
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: It's a cool sound.
Scott: It's woody, it's haunting, it's underutilized in rock music.
Scott: We really should have splurged on the full-sized marimba and not gotten that dinky xylophone.
Scott: We should have.
Rym: We totally should have.
Rym: Now look what's happened to us.
Scott: This is karma.
Rym: If we just run, are they going to chase us?
Rym: They're skeletons, Mike.
Rym: They're unpredictable.
Rym: Stand on the Earth, or else we'll lose.