Rym: It's Wednesday, April 28th, 2021.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we are reviewing the anime, The Great Pretender.
Scott: Let's do this!
Rym: So, uh, the other night, you know, we did a GeekNights and didn't really feel like cooking.
Rym: and GeekNights took us a little- we went long.
Scott: Like it- I usually don't cook if there's a GeekNights, right?
Scott: I cook on the nights so there's no GeekNights.
Rym: But, uh, the show went a little long so it was a little later and we didn't really feel like cooking.
Rym: so we were like, "Why don't we just order a
Rym: pizza?".
Rym: So, we dicked around for like a half hour, ordered a pizza, uh, assuming, you know, it'll be here in about an hour, I can live with that and go about our business.
Scott: And it was- it was delayed, I'm guessing.
Rym: Uh, so, an hour goes by and I think, "Alright, the pizza should be here
Rym: soon.".
Rym: Then another 25 minutes goes by and I think,
Rym: "Ha!"
Rym: and I go to the Grubhub website.
Scott: You didn't- one hour I call.
Rym: I'm like, you know- If I call it one hour it- The pizza place we order from usually says 60 to 70 minutes.
Rym: It takes them a while.
Rym: It happens.
Rym: So, uh, and I'm not, like, I'm not gonna, like, I'm not gonna, like, pressure them or be weird about it.
Scott: No, no, no, I'm just, like, my- just the other day we actually- there's a place, the Arepa place, we can get brunch from there.
Scott: Ooh.
Scott: But it- you can't order the brunch until, like, 11 or 12 and then it takes a while, right?
Scott: So, uh, it's kind of annoying, like, you can't- you can wake up and order from the diner immediately and get pancakes right away or bagels right away.
Scott: But you can't get Arepa brunch right away.
Scott: It has to be, like, an early afternoon dinner.
Scott: So, even knowing that, I was, like, okay, I'm fine with that, right?
Scott: We'll just, you know, we woke up late.
Scott: I'm, like, okay, we'll wake up late.
Scott: Let's just order the Arepa brunch and wait an hour.
Scott: And I, you know, I ordered it and then, like, an hour later it still wasn't there.
Scott: So, I'm, like, I called them and my call was just, like, hey, I ordered this an hour ago.
Scott: I just want to check and see, make sure you're all good.
Scott: And they're, like, yeah, we're all good.
Scott: And then 10, 15 minutes later it showed up.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So, at this point- It's about 9 o'clock at night because, you know, we ordered a little late.
Rym: So, whatever.
Rym: That's not that late a dinner for a New Yorker.
Rym: But it's getting there.
Scott: You can order a pizza at 9 and it will show up.
Rym: And I roll over to my computer and I just open, like, I come back to it and I open the tab where I ordered it and GrubHub has that little status.
Rym: And it says, "Your order has been
Rym: canceled.".
Scott: Uh-oh.
Rym: The pizza place just had a problem and shut down.
Rym: It wasn't making pizzas.
Rym: I happen to have my phone on.
Rym: Do Not Disturb because I didn't want it to be buzzing during gig nights and I didn't uncheck that.
Rym: Usually I'm sitting at my computer fucking around and I would have noticed.
Rym: So, this comedy of errors happens.
Rym: Now it's, like, 9.20.
Rym: I'm so hungry.
Rym: I feel like I'm going to pass out.
Rym: We don't have anything to cook and it's too late to order most of the kinds of food we would order.
Scott: You can order another pizza.
Scott: It'll just take another while.
Rym: Yeah, but a lot of the pizza places during COVID, they stopped taking orders around 9.30.
Scott: Oh, I don't know.
Scott: I didn't hear about that.
Rym: That's just in our neighborhood for some reason.
Rym: Not all of them, but the shitty places.
Rym: we'll deliver later.
Rym: So, I sorted by, like, what will get us food quickest and I skipped past all the fast food crap.
Rym: And you know what was right there saying 30 minutes we'll have your food?
Scott: Chinese food?
Rym: La Casa Enrique.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: A Michelin star place that we can't go to because there's always, like, a multi-hour wait and they won't take reservations.
Rym: They have delivery now.
Rym: So, we ordered some tacos.
Scott: How much did it cost?
Rym: It cost, like, $14.
Rym: So, about $7 a taco.
Rym: So, it was pricey.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: Those tacos showed up in, like, 25 minutes and saved me.
Scott: Yeah, all right.
Scott: Yeah, there was also the time I ordered bagel and accidentally didn't click delivery and it was pickup.
Scott: And I realized way later I had to leave the house and go pick up the bagels in an emergency.
Scott: And there was also a time where bagels didn't show up and I had to go to the place because when I called them on the phone, it went to their voicemail box.
Rym: There was also the time at PAX where I was skeptical, but you were like, "Let's order delivery
Rym: breakfast."
Rym: And it showed up and it was fine.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: I just didn't expect that to work outside of New York City, let alone in, like, the weird convention center part of a town.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, today I want to get my second shoddy.
Rym: Oh, mine's this weekend.
Scott: Yeah, I did this morning.
Scott: And since the weather is so nice, it could be warmer.
Scott: It could be warmer, but it's warm enough.
Scott: It's warm enough.
Scott: I had to wear a light jacket on the way there because it was still early.
Scott: But on the way back, I just put that light jacket in the Citi Bike basket, right?
Rym: Ah, the Citi Bike.
Rym: I just re-signed up for Citi Bike.
Rym: I had it for a while, way back when I first started.
Scott: Well, let's talk about this, right?
Scott: So, Citi Bike is still, you know, just fine.
Scott: There was no issue with that.
Scott: The issue was that I have Citi Bike for free from my work.
Scott: They give me a code, and I go to the website with the code, and it renews my annual subscription for zero dollars, right?
Scott: With the code.
Rym: Not bad.
Scott: I suppose if I gave the code out and it was used too much, they would be trouble, but no one's done that.
Scott: So, I checked the website, and I haven't used it in a long time, obviously, but I renewed it in August 2020.
Scott: So, it should still be active.
Scott: It's an annual dealie.
Scott: Makes sense.
Scott: So, I go out there, and I, you know, first, before I even get to the dock, I'm opening the Citi Bike app, because I haven't opened it in a while.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and it's gone.
Rym: You've got to have, like, the Lyft app or whatever.
Scott: So, well, there is a Citi Bike app, but yeah, you're exactly right.
Scott: I had to make, like, you know, all I wanted to do was find, because I assumed I was just going to use my key, get the bike, and go, but before I left, I wanted to know where the closest dock, Citi Bike dock to my dock tour was.
Scott: So, I knew where I was going.
Scott: Was I going to go on 53rd, you know, which street I was going to go down.
Scott: And I had to make the Lyft account, and then I had to do all this stuff, and I'm standing next to the Citi Bike dock doing all this shit on the phone.
Scott: I didn't realize I had to do with the accounts, right?
Scott: But eventually it worked, and then I go to, you know, put my key in, and it goes, like, red light, and I'm like, "What the
Scott: fuck?".
Scott: And I get a text message that's like, "You don't have a payment method attached to your
Scott: account.".
Scott: And I'm like, "My account is fully paid annual paid
Scott: nonsense.".
Rym: Ah, yeah, annual accounts require a payment method now, partly because of the e-bikes.
Scott: Well, that's true, but I had Apple Pay.
Scott: When I did all that account stuff in advance, I did Apple Pay, so it had a payment information, and my Apple Pay information.
Scott: So, eventually, I'm just like, "Well, I have to go get, I can't just stay here and figure this out," right?
Scott: So, I used the app to try to unlock the bike, which, you know, I used the QR code, where you take a picture of the QR code on the bike, and it unlocked.
Scott: It totally worked, and then when I got to there, the end of the ride, it fucking charged me money, because my annual account was not somehow transferred.
Scott: So, while I'm waiting at the doctor in the 15-minute waiting period after getting the shot, I send an email to City Bike, and I'm like, "I have an annual thing, you just charged me money, and I'm probably gonna get charged money on the way home.
Scott: I want that money back, and I want you to reinstate the annualness of my
Scott: account.".
Scott: That's a pain.
Scott: Yeah, sort that shit out.
Scott: And then, of course, I paid money for a City Bike ride home.
Scott: What was interesting, though, yeah, the e-bikes, almost every City Bike.
Scott: I saw, actually, whether other people were riding it or whether it was in a dock, were the e-variety.
Rym: I'd say about half of the bikes on the dock outside of our apartment are e-bikes on any given day.
Scott: I think I saw very few people riding the non-e ones.
Scott: I'm like the only person on a non-e one.
Rym: Reporting, like articles talking about City Bike, like local New York City stuff, talking about how most people exclusively use the e-bikes and don't want to have the regular bike.
Scott: Sure, why not, but I didn't want to pay.
Rym: Yeah, even if you have an annual plan, you still gotta pay per minute if you have an e-bike.
Scott: Yeah, if the e-one didn't cost anything extra, I would probably just be like, "Okay, I'll take whatever's
Scott: there.".
Scott: On the way home, right, when I went back to get the bike that I left, it wasn't there.
Scott: The dock had only e-bikes.
Scott: I had to walk to a different Manhattan dock to find a non-e bike.
Scott: But yeah, I still had to pay because the freaking thing didn't recognize my account, so they better fix that shit.
Rym: Yeah, it's funny because I was like, "Oh, I should re-sign up for City Bike,".
Rym: because I know they changed all the crap, so I signed up for it again.
Rym: And despite the fact that I closed my old account completely in 2014, so I made a new account because I tried to log into my old account and it clearly didn't work.
Rym: I wondered if I could re-sign up, so I just made a brand new account.
Rym: And it just seemed normal.
Rym: And then a couple days later, I got an email that was like, "Oh yeah, we found your old account and we linked them
Rym: up.".
Rym: And all my old shit is now in there.
Scott: Yeah, when I tried to do it, it's like, "Do you have an
Scott: account?".
Scott: I said, "I already have an account," because I thought I did.
Scott: I didn't realize this whole Lyft account thing was happening, so I said, "Yes, I already have an
Scott: account.".
Scott: And I typed in my email address and they emailed me and were like, "No, you don't have an
Scott: I'm like, "Okay, fine.
Scott: Make a new
Scott: account.".
Scott: And I made a new account.
Scott: And then when I finished making a new account, it was like, "Here's your ride history," because it was the same email address.
Rym: It's funny because then I can see June 3rd, 2014, the last time I used a City Bike, and I canceled it then because it wasn't useful at the time anymore.
Rym: Mostly because most of our friends didn't have it, so anytime we were out in a group and City Bike would be the easy way to get to Kips Bay or something, only a few of us had it.
Rym: So I ended up walking with all the slow people anyway, so I canceled it.
Scott: I mean, obviously I have it because it's free for me.
Scott: Theoretically, it's supposed to be.
Scott: Because I use it when I want to bike somewhere and don't want to bring my actual bike and worry about it getting stolen.
Rym: But also, since then, it expanded into a lot of Queens and a lot of places.
Rym: You know where I use it mostly?
Rym: Bike down to Vernon Jackson, go to a restaurant, bike to the E-Train once I ride the subway again, that kind of thing.
Rym: So, yeah.
Rym: You'll see how we do after our shots.
Rym: I'll be curious to see if you have any second shot side effects.
Scott: The first shot, my left arm hurt.
Scott: The second shot, at least so far, it's been how many hours now?
Scott: Six hours?
Scott: I feel better than I did after the first shot.
Scott: My arm doesn't even bother me.
Scott: I feel completely normal in every way.
Rym: I'm getting Moderna, so we'll see how that goes.
Scott: I got the other one.
Rym: Pfizer seems like it's better for the person getting the shot in terms of things like side effects, but it's really hard to distribute.
Rym: Moderna is a more practical vaccine for the public.
Scott: The best vaccine is the one that you can get.
Rym: Right now, that is 100% true.
Scott: The vaccine that you can get and get quickly is the best one.
Scott: Don't go sitting there and being like holding out for one or the other or not going to canceling an appointment because you don't like which one they have there.
Scott: Do not do.
Scott: Just get whatever fucking appointment you can get.
Rym: The thing is, there's a million appointments in New York City now.
Rym: You can walk into a bunch of places.
Scott: Wherever it is that you are, whatever the situation is, if you don't have one yet, get one as soon as you can.
Scott: And whichever one they have, that's just take it.
Scott: Don't worry about which kind it is.
Scott: That's the best one is the one you can get.
Rym: So let's get into some anime, animation news, etc.
Rym: There is huge news that happened right after we did like a Wednesday episode and we ended up not doing another Wednesday episode until now.
Rym: We had to remember if we had talked about this, I don't think we did.
Scott: No, I don't think we did.
Rym: Yeah, the whole Macross, Robotech, Harmony Gold thing appears to be resolved.
Scott: I don't know about permanently resolved.
Scott: It is resolved for now.
Rym: Such that Robotech can be released and continue to do its thing, but the real Macross can also be released.
Scott: Well, you could have already watched.
Scott: The real Macross is on Amazon.
Scott: You could watch it.
Scott: But there were issues with some other Macross things.
Rym: Think of it more as like the Macross universe, I'm making quote marks here, versus the Robotech universe.
Scott: Okay, so if you don't know, this is a long saga.
Scott: I'm sure most anime nerds know that there were these three shows in Japan, three different anime that only had barely anything to do with each other.
Scott: Well, not zero to do with each other, but not that much.
Scott: There was Macross, legendary, amazing robot show, which was Super Dimension Fortress Macross.
Scott: Then there was the Southern Cross show, and Southern Cross was actually called Super Dimension Century Southern Cross.
Scott: So there was some relation with the Super Dimension thing, but the shows had nothing to do with each other.
Scott: They were like different characters, different plots.
Rym: There wasn't a protoculture.
Scott: Right, they were just completely unrelated stories, characters.
Scott: They both involved mechs, I guess, right?
Scott: Southern Cross is not really that great.
Rym: I've actually never seen it, full disclosure.
Scott: You don't need to see it.
Rym: Good.
Scott: And then there was another show called Genesis Climber Mospita, which I've never seen, but I heard is at least better than Southern Cross.
Scott: I don't know, right?
Scott: But it's a show with motorcycles and stuff, and I guess it has some merits.
Scott: It might be worth seeing, I don't know.
Scott: But the point is, none of those two other shows are Macross, which is a legendary A+ show.
Scott: So someone wanted to bring those shows to the United States, which they recognized that those shows were amazing, especially Macross mostly.
Scott: In order to do so, they mangled it, rewrote it, edited it, combined it to get more episodes.
Scott: They combined all three shows together into a thing called Robotech.
Scott: It was basically a travesty.
Scott: But it did expose the U.S.
Scott: audience to Macross at least.
Rym: It was extremely popular in America and in Europe.
Scott: There were some positive side effects, and there were arguments to be made.
Scott: it was necessary at the time, but overall there is no reason for it to exist now, and it's not as good as just watching the three original shows separately in their original form.
Scott: So, over time, various things happened, but the big deal was this intellectual property thing.
Scott: Because Macross, mostly the main, you know, the first show, was made by Studio Neue.
Scott: I don't know how to pronounce it properly.
Scott: N-E-U-E.
Scott: Yeah, Neue.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I've heard Neue.
Scott: And there was also involvement with another Japanese company, Big West.
Scott: It's like an advertising company.
Scott: And another company, which is a company you actually know.
Scott: Harmony Gold?
Scott: No, not Harmony Gold.
Scott: Tatsunoko Productions.
Rym: Yes, yes, yes.
Scott: So, those three companies in Japan basically got together to make Macross.
Scott: Tatsunoko, on its own, without consulting Big West or Studio Neue, licensed Macross and other stuff to this company in the U.S Harmony Gold, which is like this very strange company.
Scott: It's like such a Hollywood story.
Scott: It's like a real estate company, but they also do some Hollywood stuff.
Scott: They actually made like a movie recently.
Scott: It's like a rich dude, but he's not like billionaire rich, but he's still mega real estate Hollywood rich.
Scott: You know, it's like a family-run business, right?
Scott: And somehow they got this deal, and there were several lawsuits.
Scott: And when the lawsuits, you know, also involved things like Transformers, because obviously, you know, in the Transformers G1, you had what's-his-name, Firebird, whatever, the guy who's basically the same exact robot as a Valkyrie.
Scott: And there were lawsuits about that.
Scott: And they decided, I guess, and after all these lawsuits, that Harmony Gold still had like the rights to like this limited set of character and designs.
Rym: We'll link to an article, because it's actually not only is it shockingly complex, but also...
Scott: Very complex.
Rym: We also like don't know the full details of what happened, because a lot of this was still resolved behind closed doors.
Scott: I don't think anyone knows.
Rym: But basically, the gist of it was Harmony Gold tried to renew the Macross trademark with Tatsunoko in like the late 90s.
Rym: Big West sued, saying that it and not Tatsunoko had rights to that.
Rym: Later, like a decade later or five or six years later, Japanese courts ruled that Tatsunoko had the rights to Macross, including sequel rights.
Rym: But there was some complication that Big West owned the franchise, which included the 41 original designs.
Rym: So it was basically fighting over the ownership mostly of merchandising and like the right to the franchise and brand of this stuff, as opposed to the individual show.
Rym: Like imagine if one company had like Scott had the rights to Mickey Mouse as a property for merchandising, but I had the rights to the first 20 things that had Mickey Mouse in it.
Rym: But then some other company owned the rest of Mickey Mouse.
Rym: It's one of those situations.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then you've got a TV show that has Mickey Mouse and Goofy, who's owned by a different person in it.
Rym: And then Scott licensed some of the toy stuff to the US, but then I licensed my own stuff to the US.
Scott: And that show that has all these different things in.
Scott: it is called FUBAR, and someone else owns the trademark to FUBAR.
Scott: The title, right?
Scott: It's like Robotech is its own.
Scott: You could own the rights to Robotech conceivably, that trademark, and not own the rights to like the Valkyrie robot.
Scott: So what does this actually mean?
Scott: So basically what it's meant is that for the longest time, Macross stuff, which is really what we want.
Scott: We want Macross stuff, right?
Scott: Everywhere for everybody who was a fan of Macross and has been hard to get right.
Scott: Hard to produce, hard to distribute, because there's just been legal kerfuffles involved.
Scott: If anyone tried to do it right, you tried to license it.
Scott: You'd have to fight with all these people and get, you just don't want to touch it with a hundred foot pole.
Scott: So for the most part, there has been very limited distribution of any Macross related thing outside of Japan, you know, for a very long time.
Scott: We've had like the Macross box set that I bought for a fortune.
Rym: I remember that.
Rym: I remember how excited we all were about that at RIT.
Scott: And you could, you could watch Macross, I think on Amazon prime video.
Scott: And it's like, that's pretty much it, right?
Scott: It's like, you can't, none of this stuff is, is very limited availability.
Scott: So what we wanted, what nerds wanted is for basically harmony gold to just lose everything, you know, get this big West garbage out of here, right?
Scott: Just studio new, right?
Scott: So, you know, you know, the original, the people who really should just have it, she should just own everything, right?
Scott: They, they made it, they should own everything.
Scott: Let them do whatever they're going to do.
Scott: Combine everything together.
Scott: All good.
Scott: And Robotech and Dynafire.
Scott: That's not what happened.
Scott: What's happened is since the lawsuits has ended, basically they just keep renewing agreements with harmony gold, right?
Rym: Big West and studio new, I have acknowledged that harmony gold has a legitimate license to Macross.
Rym: Like it is legitimate.
Rym: Harmony gold, I think can release the Robotech movie in Japan.
Rym: now, I guess there's an upcoming Robotech movie that we haven't talked about yet.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: So yeah, so what's happened is now after these like renewals that sort of just sort of kept a sort of steady state for a while, all the parties involved got together and just made some sort of agreement that we only know part of.
Scott: And it's a good news, bad news, right?
Scott: The good news is that now the doors are unlocked.
Scott: All these people are going to cooperate with each other under some contract terms.
Scott: And as long as those terms aren't broken, they won't sue each other again.
Rym: They will allow for the immediate international distribution of quote most Macross television, sequels and films.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So all the Macross stuff that we haven't been able to get is now just going to be let out, hopefully over time, you know, they've already made websites and stuff for some things.
Scott: We're going to get Macross stuff.
Rym: Big West and Harmony Gold have also agreed formally to, quote, cooperate on international distribution of any future Macross and Robotech projects post 2021.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the bad news is that the bad companies are still in, they still got their hand in the pot, right?
Scott: We were thinking we would just wait for their rights to expire, right?
Scott: Why are you doing this, right?
Scott: Just get them out of there.
Scott: But, you know, so good news, bad news, but still huge news either way.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So in some other news, that's also pretty big.
Rym: WarnerMedia, basically Adult Swim, HBO Max animation, like a whole bunch of crap is basically all going to be under one division now with one person as the programming head for it.
Rym: Basically, you can read this article, but it's going to basically make a large, powerful and well-funded studio and distribution network to make adult animation.
Scott: Yeah, because, you know, previously you had situations with like Cartoon Network Studios, Adult Swim, you had all these like different divisions, right?
Scott: Which like little animation companies producing each one was producing like different stuff, right?
Scott: You know, it's like, you know, if you looked at like just Cartoon Network, right?
Scott: The Powerpuff Girls or whatever, I don't even know what cartoons they got now.
Scott: If you go back to how old I am, right?
Scott: You know, your Powerpuff Girls and your Dexter's Labs were made over here, right?
Scott: And then your, what was on Adult Swim back in the day, your Sea Labs, I guess, and all your Birdmans, right?
Scott: Those were made over there.
Scott: The Space Ghosts were made over there.
Rym: Now remember, this includes the entity, you know, people were talking about HBO Max because they picked up the Adventure Time stuff.
Rym: They are the most credible place for Venture Brothers to land if it continues, like, so the person they put in charge of it also, she, I don't know a lot about Susana Makos, but from looking at her pedigree here, she seems like the right person too.
Rym: Because she was overseeing things like Bob's Burgers, Bordertown, stuff that seems to be pretty popular.
Scott: So an industry person who knows.
Rym: Someone who seems to know the deal with like adult animation, adult meaning for adults, not adult as in porn.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So yeah, so all of these, you know, tiny places now that we're all animating separately are now at least combined, if not physically, all under one company in one place with one organization, right?
Scott: One boss.
Scott: So there'll be reorganization, realignment, and I guess it's, you know, again, good news, bad news, right?
Rym: On one hand, these consolidations are going to lead to the world where Disney literally owns everything down the road, which is a problem.
Rym: But in the short term, this will mean there's some legitimate serious competition for what Netflix is doing with adult oriented animation, which is good.
Rym: So in the short term, I think we'll have more funding for good animation and more diversity in animation that's not purely aimed at kids.
Scott: I don't know if you have diversity when you have consolidation, right?
Scott: I think diversity will actually be lacking.
Scott: What I think you'll have more of is just like power and quality of, you know, of unified vision.
Rym: That's why the short term part of that was a load bearing part of that statement, because what this means is now there's an entity with similar amounts of funding and power and a variety of different intellectual properties to compete with the other places where that exists today.
Rym: Netflix is not going to just dominate the space as they seem to be trying to do for some time.
Scott: Yeah, but having many small companies is where the diversity would have been.
Scott: Yeah, there's less of them.
Rym: Now, remember WarnerMedia also like back in 2019, they had already done a bigger organization that included Elation, Crunchyroll, Rooster Teeth, VRV, Cartoon Network, Adult Swim, and Boomerang.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So all those things, all those things are also part of this.
Rym: So the long term trend is still not great, but I think in the short term, I feel like HBO Max might have a slight edge in terms of what type of animation they'll be able to make compared to what Netflix is doing.
Scott: I'm definitely right now, if you look at what HBO Max is doing, including the recent announcement on animation related, that there will be some NHL games on HBO Max.
Scott: I could definitely see, like, you know, plus you got the Adventure Times on there, all this other stuff, I could definitely see.
Scott: once I'm done watching stuff on Netflix, I'm probably going to switch to HBO Max next.
Rym: Watch out though, Castlevania is going to drop imminently.
Scott: Yeah, I said when I finish watching stuff on Netflix.
Rym: How long do I keep watching stuff on Netflix?
Scott: I don't keep watching stuff.
Rym: There's going to be more Dragon Prince, like a lot more.
Scott: Yeah, you know, I can always switch back once I finish watching stuff.
Scott: I don't like to have more than one at a time.
Scott: Pick one, watch everything you can on that one, pay for one at a time.
Scott: And it's sort of just, you know, why pay for two months?
Rym: I pay for a few, but not that many.
Rym: But the thing, one thing I've noticed is that some people complain that, oh, now it's just like the TV days where I have to pay like some crazy amount for cable to get everything.
Rym: Despite paying for like three different services, it's still way cheaper than what cable costs.
Rym: Like, good lord.
Scott: To add, to get cable service and not just like the basic cable that has almost no channels, but the real cable service that has, you know, HBO, for example.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And hockey, for example.
Scott: Would cost like 50 to $100 a month.
Scott: What's Netflix cost?
Scott: 20 something?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, okay, so I can do like three Netflixes.
Scott: I can do, I can do Netflix, HBO Max and Hulu.
Scott: And there were the best plans and still be paying less than cable.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or Apple TV Plus or whatever the hell, you know, whichever one you want.
Rym: Right now we're rocking the Disney Plus, the Netflix and the C roll.
Scott: Oh, D plus.
Scott: That's the other one.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But I'm just doing, I got Netflix and C roll right now.
Scott: And I'll, the Netflix is the, is the, is the, uh, the shuffle slot.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So in some other news, uh, really brief, just go check this out.
Rym: So cells at work.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Manga, anime, like.
Scott: I think we've watched a few, I watched a few episodes.
Scott: I respect it, but I just, you know, I just don't feel like watching the whole thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It didn't drag me in, like say decadence of the great pretender did where I wanted to watch it all the way to the end and like actively tried to watch it all the way to the end.
Rym: But, uh, they did something kind of cool.
Rym: They made a little like after chapter.
Rym: that's basically about the coronavirus vaccine and how it works.
Rym: And the Ministry of Health, Labor and Welfare in Japan has basically released this to the world for free.
Scott: Okay, cool.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's a neat little thing.
Scott: I wish they would get their own vaccination situation in order, right?
Scott: They seem to, there's a lot of issues going on over in Japan.
Rym: Over in Japan, over in the entire world, except the United States.
Rym: Yes, but Japan has fucked it up nearly the most.
Rym: We're also the ones with the most vaccines due to, well, basically billionaires and bad stuff that we have no control over.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: We, you know, it's like, yeah, our country is, is all these vaccines because it's evil and I happen to live here.
Scott: I would rather it not be evil, but I am here.
Scott: So what am I going to do?
Scott: Not get back?
Scott: No, I'm going to take right shots.
Scott: I think Japan's COVID situation has the added problem of the Olympic situation, right?
Scott: Which no one else.
Scott: And there's a lot of hypocrisies surrounding, you know, both of those things in combination.
Rym: That is true.
Rym: So getting back to Netflix, Netflix is going to be streaming the Sailor Moon eternal anime films like soon.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So what, right.
Scott: So what happened here, if you don't realize these aren't like standalone movies for the Sailor Moon anniversary, they did Sailor Moon Crystal, remember?
Scott: And there were some seasons of Sailor Moon Crystal.
Scott: So in lieu of a final season of Sailor Moon Crystal, they instead made two movies that are the final season of Sailor Moon Crystal.
Scott: So those two movies will be on Netflix.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I don't know if I care about them that much because honestly, if you haven't seen all of Sailor Moon Crystal, there's no point because those two movies are the final season.
Rym: But also Sailor Moon Crystal.
Rym: I remember when we reviewed it, when it came out and it was awful, mostly because they released it with like, not just like not quite finished animation, but like just missing animation.
Rym: Like characters wouldn't have faces.
Scott: Well, usually that's like, you know, the TV, that happens a lot with anime.
Scott: The TV release is busted.
Scott: It was just particularly egregious.
Rym: I feel like they really rushed it to get something out like around the anniversary.
Scott: Well, I think because unlike other anime, the Sailor Moon anniversary was like, it's now, this is the anniversary.
Scott: It's happening.
Scott: You need to do it now.
Scott: So then they rushed it.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But even when they fixed it, I honestly don't find it to be that compelling.
Rym: It just feels almost...
Scott: I'll just watch Old Sailor Moon.
Scott: I don't need to watch.
Rym: Like Old Sailor Moon honestly just feels like it has a lot more heart and life, even though it deviates significantly from the manga and Crystal is truer to the manga.
Rym: And honestly, the manga is great because it's more like Marvel space bullshit than it is like what you expect it to be.
Rym: But I don't know.
Rym: There's just, it's, the show just feels really sterile and bland compared to the original cartoon.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: It's still going to be on Netflix.
Rym: I know we've been talking about Adventure Time, like the next episode of the four post Adventure Time things on HBO Max.
Rym: We had assumed and the whole world had assumed, like all the press, not just us, that the Peppermint Butler goes to wizard school was going to be coming next.
Scott: The one that I want to see the most.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And out of nowhere, the one we thought was the last one, Finn and Jake Together Again, that's actually coming next and it's coming on May 20th.
Rym: And so many people had misunderstood the order that it looks like people involved in the project actually had to issue some sort of statement.
Rym: They basically said the order we typed the names in that release had no bearing on the order they were going to be released.
Rym: And there was definitely a read between the lines of, "Seriously, you're
Rym: nerds.".
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, the first two were in that order, first of all.
Scott: And second of all, they said that I think the order they're being aired is the order we delivered them in.
Scott: Which I guess, okay, does that mean you did it, you delivered them in that order on purpose?
Scott: Or that, you know, they're all, you made them all individually, so you didn't really care which one.
Rym: I feel like they will be individual and stand alone, which will be fine.
Scott: So far the two we've seen are stand alone.
Scott: You could watch them in either order and you could have fooled anybody saying the second one came out first.
Rym: I feel like nerds will debate the correct viewing order forever, but I always go by the order in any media.
Scott: There's no correct viewing order because they're unrelated to each other and they're not even in the same part of the timeline.
Scott: It's like, it doesn't matter.
Scott: As long as you watch them after you watch the entire TV series, it doesn't matter.
Rym: But I usually go with whatever order something was actually released to the public in is generally where you're going to watch it in.
Scott: Sure, it's not a big deal.
Scott: Just see the whole TV series first, then watch these, at least so far the first two in any order, and you're good.
Scott: Let's not do a GeekNights episode, though, until...
Rym: Until we've seen the last two.
Scott: We don't want to do four episodes and four things.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day!
Rym: This made the rounds before.
Rym: It makes the rounds every year or two, like around the Oscars.
Rym: If you've never seen what it looks like to actually make a live stream or television event or anything, like not a sport, but something more complex than a sport.
Scott: Even a sport is complex.
Rym: Sports are complex, but they're complex in this different way.
Rym: Sports tend to have a pipeline that is very repeatable compared to an event like the Oscars where it only happens once a year.
Rym: So the pipeline for that only gets dusted off once a year.
Rym: So there's a little bit of a distinction there, but...
Scott: And it's less of a predictable... You do have the whole thing scripted.
Scott: It's like you know that so-and-so is going to... Someone's going to come and read a thing, and then open a card, and then someone... There is sort of a pattern.
Scott: But you've got sometimes performances, and there's special presentations, and then you've got...
Rym: Someone trips, someone goes long, there's commercial breaks.
Scott: Actually, the ratings for the Oscars this year I think I read were super low, relatively speaking.
Rym: I could see that.
Scott: Which is good, but it still has high ratings relative to television in general.
Rym: Like watching the NHL, they have low-key fuck-ups in their streams and their television broadcasts pretty much all the time because it doesn't matter that much.
Rym: But imagine if there was only one hockey game a year, and they messed that up.
Rym: So what this is is a video from actually a longer time ago than you might think.
Rym: You can figure out the date based on what actors are shown, but this is what it looked like behind the scenes to actually make this live stream happen.
Rym: And the thing I want to point out is that the technology is different now, and a lot of this is easier, but the process of what they're doing, why and how, is basically unchanged to this day.
Scott: There's many, many cameras, and even though you may be able to switch between them easier with big displays and touch screens and who knows what kind of stuff they got set up in the production crate or whatever.
Scott: But you still have to have a human deciding which camera to go to with which timing.
Rym: And how do you manage that on the fly with a bunch of people?
Rym: You've got 400 camera operators, let's say.
Scott: All those cameras are being operated by people who need to know where to aim, how much to zoom in, what to look at, right?
Rym: And this is just a video showing exactly how they do it, and literally it's not that different today.
Rym: They don't do the snap thing anymore.
Rym: Often the person making those calls will be actively just using the dashboard or telling someone else to use the dashboard.
Rym: But otherwise, it's pretty much the same, at least from what I've seen.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: Ah, so a listener in our Discord, where you should come to submit things of the day, why not, right?
Scott: Informed me that the great Keiichi Arawi, who is known for creating Nichijou, City, Helvetica Standard, right?
Scott: Has a YouTube channel, and on that YouTube channel they made this little animation, this animation which requires no knowledge of the Japanese language to understand.
Scott: And it is an excellent little animation worth the few minutes it takes to watch, and there are other things on the YouTube channel as well.
Scott: But I mostly want to highlight this one video, which is really fun.
Scott: This video is great.
Scott: And very much in the Keiichi Arawi style, if you appreciate that style.
Rym: It gave me this desperate urge to go watch Nichijou again, but I'm actually not sure where I can watch it right now.
Scott: That's a good question, I could watch some Nichijou.
Scott: I don't think it's on Crunchyroll.
Scott: It's gotta be somewhere.
Scott: Yeah, I'll figure that out later.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: But yeah, check out this YouTube channel.
Scott: Thank you to our only listener, Jay Vance.
Scott: I guess you've seen this thing of the day already, so you only get one thing of the day this episode.
Scott: That's a shame.
Rym: And I got a little mini thing I'll just link to.
Rym: If any of you were at ConnectiCon 2009, it was a pretty interesting ConnectiCon, a convention in Hartford, Connecticut.
Rym: Because the previous year, we'd gone to this con and we kinda crapped on it for not being that well run.
Rym: And the con did what most fan cons do, they said, "Put up or shut up.
Rym: If you want it to be better, volunteer.
Rym: We need
Rym: help.".
Rym: And we, being weirdos, were like, "Alright, give us a panel
Rym: room.".
Rym: And they said,
Rym: "No.".
Rym: And we eventually tricked them into giving us a panel room.
Scott: I think we were like, "Let us run your panels,".
Scott: and instead they gave us one room.
Rym: Well first we said, "Let us take over your whole panels department," and they were like,
Rym: "No.".
Rym: And they were like, "Fine, give us one panel room,".
Rym: and they said,
Rym: "No.".
Rym: But then they came back to us because they didn't have enough content, and they gave us a panel room.
Rym: And that led to us running all the content on that floor of that con for like nine years after that.
Rym: But the funniest thing was, that year at the con, our panel room, the one that me and Scott ran with our friends, had more content in it than literally every other room in the convention combined.
Scott: Right, if you looked at these schedules for the other panel rooms, it's like they had a panel and then like a huge gap in the schedule that was as big as a panel.
Scott: They'd be like an hour panel, and then an hour gap, or an hour 90 minute gap, and then another panel.
Scott: And there were many, many rooms, and those rooms had like two or three events a day.
Scott: And you see, when you looked at the schedule, there was then panel five, which was our panel room, that was just, we didn't put gaps at all, we just blocked it solid.
Rym: We were like, "There's a hole, fill it with
Rym: something.".
Scott: We just filled, we just got as much panels as we could and filled this one room.
Rym: And they opened the big con book, and there's just like this really sparse schedule.
Rym: And then right in the middle, panel room five was like packed from 8am to midnight, every single day, with just like great sounding panels.
Rym: And I gotta say, that was a nightmare.
Rym: That was more work than I've ever done in a weekend in my entire life, to make that happen.
Rym: But it was fun, so if you want to look, I found that schedule that we put together.
Rym: Like I found the Google Doc randomly when I was looking for something unrelated.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: In the meta moment!
Scott: We are on the internet, and every possible place, most places that you can imagine on the internet that we would be, we are there.
Scott: Whether you, you know, we already mentioned your discords, right?
Scott: We got your good old web forum, our podcast, I don't know where you're listening to it now, but it's available on Spotify, Apple, even Amazon Music, Amazon Podcast, who the hell uses that?
Scott: Google Podcast.
Scott: It's on freaking everything.
Scott: It's on, Rym's even got a Patreon, you shouldn't give money though.
Rym: We have a number of t-shirts and also some other things on Amazon.
Rym: if you look for the GeekNights brand.
Scott: You don't need those either.
Rym: There's more stuff coming with our much better logos.
Scott: If for some reason you're hearing this, and for some reason enjoy and want more, think about what websites you like to use, and look for GeekNights there.
Scott: We even have a subreddit that nobody's in.
Rym: People joke about asking us for an OnlyFans, but no one has seriously asked us for one.
Scott: Right, you know, we're not on OnlyFans yet.
Scott: But it's, yeah, you can go on OnlyFans, you don't have to make porn, you can just have it if you want to.
Scott: No one's making you get naked.
Scott: Stay tuned, our Discord.
Scott: It's like, I don't even mind getting naked if you really want to see.
Scott: I mean, the reason I wear clothes is mostly because it's courtesy to others.
Scott: I'm like, you don't want to see this.
Scott: Also, self-protection.
Scott: If you do, I don't care.
Rym: The only reason I wear pants other than the law is avoiding sunburns.
Scott: That's a good point.
Rym: But otherwise, in our Discord, once the Discord stage feature lets us at least show a slide or some video, we're probably going to start also streaming the show live in the Discord, which I think could be possibly much more interactive than what we do with the stream now.
Rym: So stay tuned on that.
Rym: We're kind of waiting because it's a pain to stream to YouTube and that, because we can't do video on that, so TBD on how to get that all going.
Scott: Well, I think what we could do is we could, I don't know, we'll figure it out.
Rym: Yeah, I sketched out a pipeline that would work.
Rym: It's a little bit annoying and complicated, though.
Rym: That's the problem.
Rym: Compared to what we do now, which we've kind of got a rhythm going.
Rym: Well.
Rym: Anyway, otherwise, let's just get right into it.
Rym: Because The Great Pretender, it's not an A anime.
Rym: This is not Cowboy Peep-Pop.
Rym: Like, do not get us wrong at all.
Rym: But it's one of the rare anime that in recent history, I watched the first bit and I felt compelled to watch it all the way to the end.
Rym: I think this is DecaDance or something.
Scott: I did watch it all the way to the end.
Scott: I wasn't like super compelled to watch it all the way to the end because it wasn't like one sitting.
Scott: We're like, no, I'm not going to watch it.
Rym: No, no, we pointedly were like one episode a night, maybe two if there's a big interesting cliffhanger.
Scott: But on the one hand, I didn't have to control myself and force myself to stop, right?
Scott: But on the other hand, when the next day came around, I immediately went to the next episode.
Rym: That's the sign of a B+ anime, like Scrap Princess.
Rym: I want to watch the next episode, but watching Evangelion, I am compelled to watch the next episode.
Scott: Right, like it's hard to just turn it off.
Rym: I have to be like, no, I've got to go to bed.
Rym: I remember that weekend at RIT, we pulled out Cowboy Bebop to show someone who'd never seen it the first four episodes.
Rym: And then instead of just going about our weekend, we watched the rest of it like that night and the next morning.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So The Great Pretender is an anime on Netflix and it's broken up into two seasons in each season.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I got some stuff going on.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Each season is broken up into cases of varying lengths.
Scott: There's four cases in total.
Scott: So season one is three cases.
Scott: The first case is longer.
Scott: The second and third cases are shorter.
Scott: And season two is just case four.
Scott: So there's four segments of the story with some time gaps in between of some sorts.
Rym: And what it really ends up being is the first season, these three arcs set up all the characters.
Rym: And that's it.
Scott: It's over.
Scott: There is no more Great Pretender.
Rym: And that's something I appreciate.
Rym: I really like shows that were made knowing how they're going to end.
Rym: Or, at least in the case of Paranoid Agent, it was going to end after that many episodes regardless if they knew how it was going to end.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: So I can watch it as a unit and not think about, "Oh, well, it was season nine with the Hakage arc or
Rym: whatever.".
Rym: I can't deal with shows like that anymore.
Rym: But the first season is basically these three arcs sort of set up all these characters and all this world and bit by bit reveal things.
Rym: And then the fourth season is like, "Alright, here's what the deal was.
Rym: Here's what was going
Rym: on.".
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So the biggest question I have, and I think this is, it's such, you know, you can't see this show and ignore this, is that the show is called The Great Pretender.
Scott: And the closing music and the closer of this song is The Great Pretender by Freddie Mercury.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that wasn't free, right?
Scott: Netflix paid for a sync license to get that song on there, right?
Scott: For every single episode, that's the closing song, right?
Scott: A real frickin' song.
Scott: Normally when this happens, why could they pay the money for Freddie Mercury on the closing and on fucking Evangelion, a show that is better than The Great Pretender, not to say The Great Pretender is bad.
Scott: They couldn't pay for fucking Fly Me to the Moon.
Scott: What the fuck?
Scott: My suspicion- There is no excuse.
Scott: There's no excuse.
Scott: It's like, you know, it'd be one thing.
Scott: if like, yeah, they just had some chintzy, you know, but it's like you're paying for a big closing music here.
Scott: It's like, what?
Scott: People aren't watching it for the closing music.
Scott: You know, it's like, why would you ever pay money for it?
Scott: But if you do pay money for it, that means you must think there's value in having the good, correct closing music.
Scott: What, if they didn't get that song, were they going to change the name of the show to something else?
Rym: Normally, there have been a number of anime that had a like big song like that in their opener or closing.
Rym: Like, what, Speedgrapher, Eden of the East with that Oasis song.
Rym: But when that happened, usually they'd have such a limited license that that opener would only be for like the first time it was aired on TV.
Rym: And then there was some terrible song that replaced it once they actually released DVDs like that would usually happen.
Rym: I suspect the only reason they paid for a real license was that Netflix made it.
Rym: So they were willing to throw money in it based on the creative vision of the creators.
Rym: But Ava, that's just a show they've got.
Rym: They don't care.
Rym: People are going to watch Ava with or without it.
Rym: There was no creative vision they cared about.
Scott: I think they also, yeah, which is BS.
Scott: But also I think as people will, you know, they make, especially in anime.
Scott: specifically, they'll license a show, they'll buy a license for just the Japanese territory or the US territory.
Scott: Because guess what?
Scott: The US sync license doesn't cost more, right?
Rym: So there's a reason why a lot of bad music ends up in anime in America.
Rym: Like, remember the Dominion Tank Police soundtrack in the dub?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Think about the.
Scott: think about the population of a place like Luxembourg.
Scott: They don't even talk about Luxembourg.
Scott: They talk about Benelux.
Scott: Because it's that's, you know, if you're going to license something, you're not going to license in such a small place, right?
Scott: You're going to license it in all of, you know, Belgium, Netherlands.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But if you want to license a song, The Great Pretender, right?
Scott: Let's say you're making a TV show in Benelux.
Scott: You know, you have to pay a certain amount of money.
Scott: And they know the population of Benelux and how popular, even if your show was a mega hit, how many people will see it.
Scott: And they charge appropriately.
Scott: If you want to license the same exact song for a similar TV show in the United States, they know the population and wealth of the United States, right?
Scott: They know how many people are going to be hearing that song versus if it was a Beneluxian TV show, it costs more.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that's a lot of the issue here.
Scott: But regardless, no, Netflix, I'm pretty sure is a worldwide license for The Great Pretender, which was couldn't have been free.
Rym: They named the show The Great Pretender.
Rym: The themes that are some of the themes that are addressed in that song are directly applicable to the plot of the show.
Scott: Like, did they license the song first and then make the show?
Rym: Actually, so I have an interview I'll link to with the writer and the director, and they were asked specifically, "When did you get the idea to use the Freddie Mercury song as the ending theme, make the visuals focus on his
Rym: cats?".
Rym: And the answer is very short and perfect.
Rym: This is the director, I think.
Rym: "When I was in my teens, I listened to Queen and became a big fan of Freddie Mercury, something that probably any fan wonders about.
Rym: But I honed my craft while thinking if he were alive, I wonder what kind of videos would delight him.
Rym: Also, I loved the music video of the song, The Great Pretender, so I made an homage to
Rym: it.".
Rym: But also, it doesn't address this in the interview, but if you watch the show to the end, it's very clear that the lyrics to that song are directly relevant to the overall, for real, plot of the show.
Scott: Alright, so the plot of the show.
Rym: The plot of the show is pretty good.
Scott: If you've ever seen the movie The Sting, go watch The Sting right the fuck now.
Scott: Isn't it what, Robert Redford, right?
Scott: Yeah, Robert Redford.
Scott: Okay, yeah.
Scott: Amazing, amazing movie.
Rym: When we lived in Beacon, you discovered that I had never actually seen it, and you made me watch it.
Rym: Like, I remember.
Scott: Well, it's such a Rym movie.
Scott: I was like, "How have you not seen
Scott: this?".
Rym: No, you literally were like, "We're watching it tonight, and we watched
Rym: it.".
Rym: And the whole time, you're like, "This is a Rym movie.
Rym: This is a Rym
Rym: movie.".
Scott: This is the most Rym-est movie.
Scott: The Sting is a movie about con men, right?
Scott: They trick, basically, this, you know, but they're con men doing good, right?
Scott: They're conning this rich, evil guy, but they basically set up, spoilers, right, an entire bookies, right?
Scott: And they fill it with actors who are all pretending to bet on horses.
Rym: Like, you know how Penn & Teller, their magic relies on someone going through such a ridiculous effort that no one would believe they would do it?
Rym: It's a con job like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, they set up an entire fake bookies for horse betting, off-track betting, OTB.
Scott: They're not near the horses, because then, obviously, the whole thing wouldn't work.
Rym: And they run something called the wire scam.
Scott: Yeah, TV didn't exist yet.
Scott: So, obviously, right?
Scott: So, it allows this scam to exist at the time, in the movie, at least.
Scott: And the only person who isn't an actor in, obviously, everyone's an actor because it's a movie, but the only person who isn't a con man or a con artist is this one rich dude.
Scott: And they fool him into, you know, betting on these horses, and that make him think he's winning a lot of money, and then they get him to bet the farm on this other horse, and it loses, and they keep all his money, and they basically scam this rich dude.
Rym: The movie's great, but the point is, the kind of scam they run in that movie, and also, the vibe around the why of the scam, the great pretender is clearly riffing on this directly.
Rym: In fact, the writer said, "Why I made this movie?
Rym: I always liked films about con games like The
Rym: Sting.".
Scott: Yeah, probably maybe the best con movie there is that I know of, at least.
Rym: And also, the writer of the show, Ryota Kosawa, is known almost entirely for live action stuff, not for anime.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: So yeah, in this show, what you have is basically people running cons against each of the episodes, the four acts of the show.
Scott: Each of them are targeting a different rich, wealthy, evil person with some sort of con that is a big, elaborate con in order to take all their money and hurt them because they're bad people who deserve to be stolen.
Scott: But they're not evil, killing people.
Scott: They're con artists.
Scott: They're still criminals, but they're basically using their criminal skills to take a whole bunch of money away from evil, rich people that the police aren't doing anything about.
Scott: They do it four times.
Rym: And not spoil anything.
Rym: I guess we'll talk a little bit toward the end of this, just about the very end of the show, because I think there's some things we both want to say about it.
Rym: that will be spoilers.
Rym: And I think you should just watch the show.
Rym: It's one of the better anime to come out in a long time.
Rym: But each of the heists sort of reveals why one of the members of this gang is a confidence artist, why they're doing what they're doing.
Rym: And the stakes just slowly escalate and the consequences slowly escalate and the ramifications slowly escalate.
Rym: And then at the end, it all sort of comes together and you find out the original why.
Rym: But the fun part is that the scams, the show takes great lengths to make them as plausible as they can be.
Rym: It has a little artistic license for just as anime, but like the very beginning, it starts with this just kid in Japan running some low rent con job.
Rym: But it's a 100% legit con you could literally do for real today.
Rym: It would probably work.
Rym: Like all the cons are actually very well thought out and the writing on what the cons are is good and free.
Rym: It's grounded up to a point, but it always sort of gets a little over the top.
Rym: It edges into Lupin territory toward the end of every arc, but it doesn't go like full Lupin.
Rym: That's how I describe it without like spoiling stuff.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't go into like really supernatural territory or anything ridiculous like that.
Scott: But it's, you know, or people doing things that are like absolutely impossible for humans to do kind of, but it does get a little ridiculous.
Scott: The ridiculousness sort of comes towards the end of the cons for the climaxes, right?
Scott: It's like up until then, everything is sort of running in a normal fashion, even if it's an elaborate one.
Scott: It's just like, okay, yeah, no one's that clever.
Scott: This would never happen.
Scott: But if there was a character that was that clever and there was a cons within cons within cons, then yes, this is okay.
Scott: And it's sort of fun to have those cons within cons within cons unfold because certain characters are operating at different levels of the con.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And then you can sort of see like someone thinks they're conning someone, but actually they're being conned into conning someone as part of a larger con.
Scott: And then they discover it and you discover it together at the same time.
Scott: And it's sort of you're zooming out and, you know, it's not like a terrible secret of space.
Scott: where it's like.
Scott: we're telling you there's a terrible secret of space, but we're not telling you the answers.
Scott: You're always asking questions.
Scott: It's that you're watching a thing and then suddenly there are answers you didn't even have questions for.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: I think your analogy was right.
Rym: It's like the show, like the camera is just slowly zooming further and further out.
Rym: And bit by bit, things come into frame.
Rym: You're like, wait, what the fuck is going on over there?
Scott: It's like you see a puppet and you think it's real and then you zoom out.
Scott: It's like, oh, there was a puppet master.
Scott: And then you zoom out and the puppet master was also a puppet.
Scott: Daddy three puppets.
Rym: But what I also appreciated was the way it starts.
Rym: Like in the first episode, it's not really a spoiler.
Rym: It's the first episode.
Rym: But the show I thought was going to be a lot less good than it was because in the first episode it starts with this like really pedestrian con and the guy doesn't work out and it just feels really predictable.
Rym: But then when Ed and Murrah, like the main character, sort of slides in and you see what the real con was, I didn't expect that and it was clever.
Rym: And then the show just escalates from there.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So let's talk about, there's a few details in the show I want to touch on.
Scott: So the first detail is the background art, right?
Rym: That background art is fucking amazing.
Scott: I don't know the name of the art style or the artist who drew that way.
Rym: It's like abstract and hyper saturated and colorful.
Scott: It's a style you've seen before.
Scott: It's like you could imagine that even though the show takes each of the different episode, the, what's it called?
Scott: The arcs or whatever.
Scott: The arcs, right?
Scott: Take place in different geographies.
Scott: One of them's in Singapore, one of them's in the UK, I think, or France.
Rym: I guess it's a spoiler to say where the last one is.
Scott: Yeah, but all four of them are in different locations.
Scott: The first one is in California, but they all feel like a painting that you would see hanging in like a motel in California in your hotel room, right?
Scott: And it's like a style.
Scott: I've seen that style before, but I'm not, I don't know enough about art history or what to Google for to figure out the name of that style or the artist who came up with that style.
Scott: But I've seen that style.
Scott: It's a style I like, you don't see it that often.
Scott: And they, every single background, whether it's like a shot where the background is taking up most of the frame or just like a regular old talking headshot.
Scott: It's like almost always the background is a painting in that style, right?
Scott: With quite a bit of effort put into it.
Scott: And it's really, you know, it sort of maintains, no matter what's happening in the show, that sort of, you know, sort of visual like anchor point, right?
Scott: Of stylistically.
Rym: And it subtly really sets the mood for the scenes and sets the mood for how apart from non-con men these characters are.
Rym: And also it really like pegs them to the place they're in.
Rym: Like the Singapore arc is like specifically and directly set in a very specific part of Singapore.
Rym: The LA one is like a real place.
Rym: Like they scouted locations.
Rym: They made it very, very true to the spirit of those places, but highly stylized.
Scott: It's not one of those ones where it's like, you know, it's New York, but no, it's not.
Scott: It's not New York.
Scott: It's like, oh yeah, that's...
Rym: It has that history of like where you've been and I've been there more than I've realized, but it really captures what Singapore feels like if you're there and you're well off and like in the kind of places that they're at.
Rym: Not like daily life, but like this larger than life experience.
Rym: The other thing I would say is that the soundtrack, I feel like it is like directly trying to pay some homage to Cowboy Bebop, like straight up.
Scott: It's not the kind of soundtrack that I would put on, right?
Scott: Like I would play, but it's, while you're watching it, it's a lot of fun.
Rym: It's one of those, it fits, but it's not a score that's particularly memorable other than of course the closer, but that's not a score.
Rym: That's a soundtrack and it's just a Freddie Mercury song.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We already know that song.
Scott: Another thing I want to point out is that, you know, you have this main character who is a Japanese guy, right?
Scott: And his name is Edamura and people, a lot of the characters make fun of him and call him Edamame, right?
Scott: Which is, you know, the green peas.
Rym: Because the show is very specifically like he is a Japanese character out in the world among mostly non-Japanese people and people make fun of him for it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's like a cultural sensitivity aspect to it, especially since even though these characters are traveling all around the world, right?
Scott: You're watching this show either in Japanese with English subtitles or with an English dub.
Scott: And so the characters will be mostly speaking in the language that you wonder that you choose for your audio track.
Scott: But it's sort of assumed that like while they're in France, right?
Scott: It's like, okay, that character doesn't speak French, but all these other ones do.
Scott: And it's like, you know, sometimes they'll actually speak French with subtitles.
Rym: I love that.
Rym: I almost feel like it was a gag on them.
Rym: They made the voice actors speak English and French a bunch in this show as well.
Scott: But then there'll be times where like, okay, I watched the Japanese English subtitles.
Scott: There are scenes where characters are talking in Japanese, but it's just assumed they're actually talking in English because you're in California right now.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because they'll make comments like your accent, you know, everyone, you know, your English accent is kind of no good, even though the character didn't speak in English at all just then.
Scott: So there's this sort of this and all the it's clearly it's very clear which characters are like, that's a French character, right?
Scott: That's a Middle Eastern character.
Rym: But they play it up and like there's in the first few episodes, there are long scenes of all the characters like speaking in English, even in the Japanese soundtrack or the Japanese audio.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They're all con artists.
Scott: So they all they're all fluent in many languages and can even, you know, hide their accents or not have accents in various languages to some degree.
Scott: But it's clear.
Scott: the main character's Japanese accent, you know, doesn't, you know, he has it when he speaks in English where like one of the other characters, you know, is French.
Scott: But if they speak English, you wouldn't know that they're French because they're so good.
Scott: They're a con artist.
Scott: They've learned to speak without an accent.
Scott: and how many different languages, you know.
Rym: Another thing I could say is that I like the like, for example, the first arc, which is kind of set in
Rym: L.A.,
Rym: it definitely has a big get shorty vibe, like the way that who that director is, who's also in the mob and like what's going on.
Rym: And there's a scene that is clearly an homage to that scene in The Untouchables where Al Capone beats the shit out of a guy with a baseball bat.
Rym: But we're watching.
Rym: I'm thinking, oh, they're going to do the Al Capone thing.
Rym: But the director guy, who is the mob boss guy, is such a basic piece of shit that he basically is like, I'm doing the Capone thing.
Rym: And then he does the Capone thing like that.
Rym: Like it's almost like he's almost you'll have to see it to see what I mean.
Rym: Like that guy is such a doofus.
Scott: Yep, yep, yep.
Rym: In terms of like we're not going to spoil anything about the end, but I'd say the end is pretty satisfying with a possible off note.
Rym: I see what they were going for.
Rym: There's sort of a post ending, very short scene that might radically change how you interpret the show.
Scott: Hmm, that's true.
Scott: But yeah, I think it's not just the post scene, but also the ending.
Scott: On the one hand, the ending does sort of tie up and explain everything with like the most zoomed out biggest explanation, right?
Rym: Like at the end of the show, it's almost like I had a checklist of they better not just ignore the child trafficking that was happening in that arc.
Rym: And like every box got checked.
Scott: Yeah, they just took everything that they had and just like wrapped it up.
Scott: But I think the ending was it felt at least whether it was rushed or not.
Scott: production wise, it's the pace of it is rushed.
Scott: It's like the things that happen at the end happened so quickly.
Scott: It's like, you know, this and then this and then this and then this.
Scott: It's like they're just like cramming that ending full of everything.
Rym: I felt like they could have either cut a little bit of that out or had like a few more episodes to make that all come together.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And the other thing is that it becomes because of that rapid pace of the ending, it's a little like confusing and messy, right?
Rym: But at the same time, that almost works.
Scott: You get the information about how a thing was wrapped up and all the facts and all the questions are answered.
Scott: But it's like you could have spent a little more time showing those answers in a more emotionally impactful fashion, right?
Rym: Though at least I can say that one thing that did do is that when we were watching it and the sort of final arc, like the con that's happening gets revealed and some people walk out a door after the floor thing happens.
Rym: I'm being very vague here on purpose.
Rym: We were both just sitting here thinking, what the fuck?
Rym: Does this show get weird now?
Rym: Is this supernatural or magic or nonsense?
Rym: Because we almost got conned.
Rym: Like we were conned ourselves.
Rym: And then as the camera zooms out and it's like, oh, oh, like you have this moment of I get it.
Rym: I get what they did.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And I feel like that was done well, but it could have been done slightly better.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like I was saying before, how it's a show that's giving you answers without, you know, asking, you know, giving you the question.
Rym: That's the first time I gave you a question.
Rym: I was literally like, what the fuck just happened?
Scott: But it's sort of in that way.
Scott: It's conning you, right?
Scott: It's like you're rather than you knowing there's a terrible secret of space and just not knowing what it is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, I know there's a mystery out there.
Scott: It's like, it's like, no, there is no mystery.
Scott: This is the truth.
Scott: This is what's happening.
Scott: We're showing you everything.
Scott: Look, we're showing you that they're con men and that they're pulling a con.
Scott: You see the whole con, right?
Scott: You see everything, but you're being, you yourself are being conned, right?
Scott: As the larger con is revealed to you and characters simultaneously.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that's what I think gives it a little different structure.
Rym: Another thing, something actually I did appreciate around like the way the show progressed too, is that the characters were pretty complex and many of them had significant changes like over the course of the show for as short as it was.
Rym: But also I didn't know where the show was going until the final arc because there are a lot of moments where the show looks like it's about to take a very dark turn and it doesn't necessarily reassure you of, no, it's not actually going to go too far down that road.
Rym: It almost feels like it's at any moment it could get real dark.
Rym: Like there's a moment where a character kind of out of nowhere pulls a knife and you don't see it coming and an episode ends.
Rym: And I like, I give it a 50/50 shot that the show is about to take a really dark swerve.
Scott: Right?
Scott: It's like there are dark things that happen in the show for real, right?
Scott: And the characters, while they're always, you know, when they're not conning someone and acting, right, to con people.
Scott: They are always, all of them, even if they all have dark pasts to varying degrees, they all act in sort of a jovial having a good time joking around manner with each other.
Rym: Well, you know how to sum that up?
Rym: There's a meta message in this show.
Scott: Teasing each other, right?
Rym: The meta message of this show is it's all fun and games until it isn't.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then at the same time though, they always will, even though they're almost always just joking around with each other, they'll always stop and say like, no, we're not teammates, right?
Scott: You could just, yeah, you could just die.
Scott: We're doing dangerous shit.
Scott: And they absolutely, and they absolutely are, right?
Scott: So, and they're also reminding you, the viewers.
Scott: So then when dangerous shit happens, sometimes it's real and sometimes it's a con and you can't tell until later when it's revealed whether that was, you know, a fake or real dangerous things that happened.
Rym: Which is because some con movies or con like confidence shows, they tend to portray thieves who don't suffer consequences and also seem to feel like they are immune to consequences.
Rym: Like it's always assumed everything's going to work, but the show definitely edges into talking about how that is a fiction and how real cod art is doing these kinds of things.
Rym: Like they are moments from death, basically constantly with what they're actually doing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And there's, there's plenty of scenes where while they're executing a con, right?
Scott: There's, they're building tension showing you like how close they are to messing it up.
Scott: Like, Oh, security, you know, they were trying to do something.
Scott: A security guard, you know, is coming back, right?
Scott: He's going off the plan and they had to, they have to think fast and come up with, do something else.
Scott: Right?
Scott: What are they going to do?
Scott: Are they going to mess up?
Scott: Are they, you know, they were trying to escape.
Scott: They didn't escape.
Scott: Uh, you know, all these different things happen.
Scott: They, they, they wanted to convince someone of something.
Scott: They failed to convince them.
Scott: Well, now what do they do?
Scott: And it's like, you can't tell if sometimes because there are cons within cons, if the failure to convince was part of the plan or they've just successfully adapted to the plan or if the plan has failed and now they don't know what to do and they got to find a way to work it out later.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Do they have the, all these layers planned out in advance or not?
Scott: You're always, you don't really know because it's not like they sat you down and told you what the whole con was going to be before they executed it.
Scott: You're just watching this execution, not knowing who planned what at what level.
Rym: Which is extra fun because for the first three arcs, Edamura, our main character, he is in just as much in the dark as you, the viewer are.
Scott: I think in all the four arcs, you basically know what Edamura knows.
Scott: Well, the fourth arc is interesting.
Rym: It would always be a spoiler to make my argument about this, but I think the fourth arc is where that's the only time he knows what is going on.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: He knows more in that one for sure.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Cause that the final.
Scott: Sometimes I guess in that one, sometimes he knows more than you.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I guess in the final one, one way to put it is the first three arcs are almost training and the fourth arc is he does the thing.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Scott: Pretty much.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But yeah, I think we'll talk a little bit about spoilers.
Rym: So the last thing I'll just say is this show, like this is an anime, if you like anime, watch it.
Rym: Like this is a fine anime.
Rym: It's one of the better ones to come out in a long time.
Scott: It's just on Netflix.
Scott: I wouldn't subscribe to Netflix to watch this show, but if you have Netflix and you like animation, why wouldn't you watch this show?
Scott: It doesn't take that long.
Rym: This is the kind of show, if we showed the first four episodes at like an RIT anime club, like the people would be cheering.
Rym: It's the kind of show that like people would show up to the marathon, but like it's not a cowboy bebop, but it's a B plus.
Rym: I think it could have been like a full on a minus if the ending had been a little bit tighter.
Rym: Didn't really hit a, but it did do.
Rym: a lot of the things that good shows do like the closing, like the closing animation, what's happening on screen with the cats and like the lyrics of the song together are allegory for what happens in the show.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: That's one of the things we always talk about.
Rym: Anime where you can figure out things in the show from the openers and closers tend to be better shows.
Rym: So spoilers, we're going to spoil stuff.
Rym: If you haven't watched the show, stop listening because we're going to spoil stuff in a show.
Scott: Or if you're like me and you don't believe in that spoilers ruin spoil things and that's something that can be spoiled isn't, you know, worth watching at all.
Rym: But from this point, not only are we going to spoil things, but we're going to assume you've seen it and not explain what we're talking about.
Rym: Like we're going to talk about it like you have seen it with us.
Scott: Just out of common courtesy, we're just letting you know that's your choice.
Rym: Last chance spoilers.
Rym: My favorite thing at the end, like of all the things that happened in the end, I think the part I enjoyed the most, I was very happy that his wife was a hundred percent in on it the whole time.
Rym: That would have felt like a sour note if he had been hiding this life from her.
Rym: The fact that she knew and approved of it and was basically just like trying to set her son up to like survive and deal with it.
Scott: I just thought that's why she kept, well, she didn't want to, the thing is like, she didn't tell her son cause he told her not to, but she would just, but like she, you know, she didn't, you know, hate the dad even though, you know, supposedly.
Rym: I always got an undercurrent that she liked what he was doing and was probably even involved in some things when she was younger.
Rym: And then they might've changed that because they had Edamura.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: But they don't, they don't go into so much detail on that, but they, the way they reveal that all those scenes I think were just very emotional and touching.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The thing that really got me was that you have the, right from the early parts of the show, you see the dad was a, you know, this good lawyer who, you know, got arrested for child trafficking.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you know, from that point on, I just assumed, you know, like I didn't have questions about that.
Scott: Like where is dad?
Scott: I didn't think that was going to come up.
Rym: Around the third arc I started wondering like, what was really the deal with his dad?
Rym: Cause that was definitely going to be the fourth arc.
Scott: Well, cause I saw, well, yeah, but I basically, you know, from arc one, two, and most of three, I was just like, dad's in jail.
Scott: I had no questions about dad.
Scott: He was just a bad guy.
Scott: That's what happened.
Scott: I did not think for one second, the dad was like a part of the plot of the show.
Scott: I thought it was just like, he was part of the OG gang.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's just, it's just like, that's the backstory of Edamura.
Scott: His dad was a guy who went to jail.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I didn't question where's dad now.
Scott: She's in a jail.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And the show, it did that thing I love where an episode just starts or like a long scene just starts in the past and you see like a history when you see the original gang.
Rym: And then the moment when she was like, all right, let's do one more score.
Rym: That is the same as saying I'm going in for a closer look.
Rym: That is the same as saying we're going to die.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: That's a, that's old cliche of like, okay, we've done all these, you know, we've climbed 10 mountains.
Rym: It's like, all right guys, one more and then we're retiring.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: This is my last day before retirement.
Scott: It's like, well, you're going to die on this day, aren't you?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But it did also bring up this interesting meta point about how everyone other than her had a reason, like a life and a reason to do cons, like to support that life in some way.
Rym: Except her, she was the one who was conning because she loved it.
Rym: Like that was the con, the con was the end and the means.
Scott: And she just having a good time.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like, you know, where other people might've had a good time as a side effect of, you know, But they had a real life to get back to.
Rym: And there were consequences for them, like that.
Rym: she didn't seem to care about as much.
Scott: No, no, not at all.
Rym: I, I feel like they tried to make the very end where, you know, she comes back as being ambiguous, the way she reacts when she sees the, there's two ways to read it.
Rym: Either if she survived, like simply, or she orchestrated that on purpose to get Laurent out of that life.
Rym: So she could keep criming without him, like having a problem.
Scott: Or, you know, there's also the, you know, and she realized everything worked out.
Scott: It's like, okay, if she's still alive, is she a, because they sort of made it ambiguous, right?
Scott: Does she a still not remember anything, which she really doesn't remember anything.
Scott: That's a possibility.
Scott: B she's a con artist.
Scott: She's pretending not to remember anything.
Rym: And if she's pretending then was that just, she survived and that's how she survived.
Rym: Or did she plan this thing failing all along?
Rym: Was she the mastermind of freeing Laurent from this life and from his affection to her?
Rym: And the, the, the way, like the intonation of the way she said the final line of the show when she saw that, that jewel really, I think they made that ambiguous specifically on purpose.
Rym: And I don't know, it's a, it's not a bad moment, but I think the show would have been fine if it didn't have that last little scene.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I think, you know, it was really- The interpretation of the show is cleaner without that.
Scott: I think up until that point, you had all these different scenarios where people were fake dying.
Rym: They almost overused that.
Rym: They basically gave Edinburgh PTSD.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They, they overuse quite a few things, you know, along those lines, but especially the fake dying.
Scott: And it's like, okay, you fake died and then, okay, you did it once.
Scott: And then it's like, oh, you fake it.
Scott: Then it's like, you believe it the next time.
Scott: Cause like you've already used the fake dying, right?
Scott: And it's like, no, they just keep using the fake dying.
Scott: Like nobody fucking died at all.
Scott: They just fake deaths like a hundred times.
Scott: And it's like, uh, after you've done it that many times.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: The guy who got his testicles crushed by that baseball bat, he might not have survived.
Rym: We don't know.
Rym: We don't see him again.
Scott: But none of this, there are several times significant characters die and they're not really dead.
Scott: It's like, they just kept doing that over and over.
Scott: And it's, it's like they, they did it enough times that before the end of the show, like sometime in the middle of that last arc, I basically was like, well, I guess no one dies in this show.
Scott: And I was right.
Scott: And it's like, you used it too many times.
Scott: If you would have used it maybe two less times, you would have been better off.
Scott: Um, you know, like actually kill someone.
Scott: Come on.
Rym: But I guess one thing I did appreciate that's, that's adjacent to that is that the actual cons were really simple.
Rym: Like while there's all this accretion amount around it, the con was literally just a very simple, all right, now this guy has given us the money and we're gone.
Rym: It's over.
Scott: And also, even though the, the big, big con, right, it's like, yeah, they planned this big, big con, but like they weren't, they clearly weren't planning the details of each thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So like, especially with the art guy, it's like, they weren't, it's like, you know, the fact that they accidentally sold him an expensive thing was an act, right?
Rym: Arguably, Lawrence, it was implied that he might've set that up, but they don't actually reveal.
Scott: Oh, that he might've just put that painting there?
Rym: Yeah, I think that was heavily implied because remember he got him, he got him to stay there.
Rym: Uh, like it fits with everything else Lauren was doing the whole time.
Rym: One of my favorite scenes with Lauren is when he just imagined himself murdering that triad guy.
Rym: That, that was a, that whole scene was one of the tensest scenes in the show where he's playing Ma Zhang with the mob bosses.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Uh, they're also, I guess the fun, you know, one thing that show had, uh, is fun side characters, right?
Rym: And they were very, the, the seductress and the old man are my two favorite characters in the show by far.
Scott: Well, also the mechanic guy.
Rym: Oh yeah, he was fun, but I don't know, the seductress and the old man together, like you could have a spinoff show of those two and it would be great.
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: They were the, the fun side character action and like they're there the whole time.
Scott: Um, like they're there from the beginning to the end and they show up rather, you know, I think they did a good balance compared to other shows, which either don't use their fun side characters enough and you're disappointed or overusing them to where it's like, yeah, those are just like, you know, side characters.
Scott: You shouldn't be having them all over the place.
Rym: They use them the right amount.
Scott: The right amount, I think.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Which, which made me like them a lot.
Scott: So that was, that was good.
Scott: Um, the bringing back of characters from the previous acts.
Rym: That was the primary sour note I had from the show.
Scott: It was a little, it was a little meh.
Scott: That sort of made sense.
Rym: Especially cause he wasn't evil.
Rym: He was just a playboy.
Scott: He wasn't a bad guy.
Scott: Right.
Rym: He was, he did some bad things, but he wasn't like actively aggressively bad like his shitty brother.
Scott: But this bringing back the, the villains from the first three arcs in the fourth arc, just for that brief moment.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And portraying them that way was like, uh, no, that doesn't work.
Scott: You should have just been done with them.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Just leave them be the whole, I thought you got revenge on them.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And also your gang is doing crime for all these other reasons.
Rym: They're just like selling meth to kids.
Rym: Like what?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Why do you do it?
Scott: Right?
Scott: Those are actual criminals.
Scott: They're bad guys.
Scott: That's why you conned them in the first place.
Scott: What the hell are you just doing?
Rym: For a brief moment, I had hoped that they were all actually being conned and they were going to be like abandoned on a boat or like something was going to happen to them, but no, no consequences for them.
Rym: That just got ignored.
Rym: That was honestly my only real sour note because while the fake deaths was a little bit overdone, it sort of made sense as con artists using the tools they have that work.
Rym: And they did play pretty well how Edamura was deeply traumatized by that.
Rym: And they all tried to brush it off.
Rym: And I thought it was interesting how Abby of all people was like, you guys are really underestimating Edamura and how much you fucked him up.
Scott: Well, especially I think the thing is that Edamura wasn't as much pre fucked up as the other people were.
Scott: The other people had more serious traumatic events in their past already.
Scott: Well, also they were older, I guess some of them.
Scott: And I guess the younger one, Abby, it's like her past was at war, the most serious darkest past of everybody.
Rym: Just that moment when she's pushing the guy's wheelchair, then she stops and you just hear the knife and she's like, tell me, did you pilot bombers during the Iraq war?
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But her, uh, Edamura's past is.
Scott: my mom got sick and died and my dad went to jail, which is a traumatic past indeed.
Scott: I'm not want to downplay that at all, but compared to my family was bombed while I was a child.
Rym: Or the love of my life was murdered in front of me by the triad and I had to pretend I didn't know her to survive.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: That is not, uh, you know, everyone else had more serious trauma than, uh, Edamura did.
Scott: So, you know, exposing him to this hard, uh, life, right?
Scott: The hard parts of, uh, artistry was, you know, you know, he had to deal with things suddenly like, uh, the child trafficking that was going on.
Rym: The fact that, the fact that it did a time skip that it's like, all right, you're working for the mob now, and then it just fast forwards and he's just actually working for the mob.
Rym: They did that one with the cigarette.
Rym: There's that moment where he's like, he's faking smoking to fit in.
Scott: The cigarette was symbolic of him, you know, actually, you know.
Rym: That's one of my favorite moments is just when Abby's like, you actually smoke now?
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: It's like, you're supposed to be acting, not actually, you know.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Like it almost shows like that there's a slippery slope there.
Rym: It's very easy for someone, even if they're conning for all the right reasons and doing crime for all the right reasons, it's very easy to just get a little bit deeper and a little bit deeper and compromise a little more and compromise a little more.
Rym: And eventually you're running the auctions for child trafficking.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, he started out as the only, you know, everyone else was sort of like, yeah, we don't like child trafficking, but we're, we're doing the con.
Scott: So we have to just go along with it where he was like, no, I want to, you know, let's just, let's free these children right away.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Where, you know, and then he ended up being the one that got, you know, more in with it, running the auction.
Scott: But think about what that con was.
Rym: Give him such deep trauma that he turns to this mob boss as a surrogate mother and joins the world of crime for real in order to run a longer con.
Rym: Like that is fucked up.
Rym: But the show very clearly is like, yes, this is fucked up.
Rym: what is happening here.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: That's that's enough of this.
Rym: This show.
Rym: Go watch it.
Rym: If you got to the end here and you didn't watch it, go watch it.
Rym: It's great.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon Patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi McNichol, Alan Joyce, Link Ege, Drew Dremel, Larry Sternberg, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walden, Crane Patek, Old Man, Save Desk, Peacock, Mind, Snack, Finn, Graham Finch, JustLikeADudeGuy, Kahashia, 85, Renfro, New Zealand, ReviewMan, Bill34, Cowards, Ryan Perrin, Sam, Erickson, Sheriff of Mount Horrell, Taylor Braun.
Rym: You hold the key to my heart and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: Alright, so now, I leave you with... what am I gonna use?
Rym: I actually don't decide... full disclosure, I don't actually decide what the final stinger audio is gonna be until usually an hour or two after I record the thing I'm recording right now.
Rym: So, whatever you hear after I stop talking, I don't know what that's gonna be yet at this moment.
Rym: I will know later.
Rym: So, armed with that knowledge, I leave you with... So, I grab what's going on, and I say, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Rym: I say hey.
Rym: I wanna story now.
Rym: And he tries.
Rym: Oh, my doctor, I try.
Rym: I try all the time in this institution.
Rym: And he prays.
Rym: Oh, my doctor, I pray.
Rym: I pray for sake of faith.
Rym: [MUSIC].