Rym: It's Monday March 15th 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are talking about cable management.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: so uh today I actually did a a very in your late 30s adult char because I've worked at a lot of places and I've accumulated like I've rolled a lot of them over but not all of them.
Rym: just because I was lazy and it didn't matter that Retirement retirement.
Rym: I've accumulated five Separate retirement accounts with five different entities that were at the first had money in them.
Scott: The first two jobs I had.
Scott: I didn't even realize I had such accounts.
Scott: That was what happened with my first real job I when I quit even my cut even my co-op when I was at RIT.
Scott: It wasn't a 401k they hit there was like a profit-sharing thing.
Scott: I didn't even know It wasn't much money.
Rym: IBM didn't have anything like that.
Rym: third They had a little profit-sharing thing, but it was basically like I got 500 bucks when I left You know something along those.
Scott: All right, but I never liked these paperwork just kept coming for it.
Scott: I was like what the hell is this?
Scott: I finally figured out.
Scott: it was like oh, it's money I have.
Rym: Okay So what you know what you want triggered me to do this was I got that paperwork again like for I had a 403.
Scott: I don't get any paperwork anymore from anybody I don't.
Rym: I don't accept.
Rym: I had this 403b from Montefiore Medical Center back when I worked for the hospital and It's like a. it's like a magic 401k for nonprofits.
Rym: It was pretty good.
Rym: It had like almost no money in it because they didn't pay me shit But it was making its returns.
Rym: But I ever like every month they'd send me a paper statement and the system was so out of date I couldn't get a digital.
Rym: so I was ignored it.
Rym: and then recently it changed.
Rym: like a couple years ago I got paperwork that said oh, it's changing to a different company.
Rym: And then I started getting paperwork from that different company.
Scott: Yeah that happens occasionally.
Rym: in the last month the Paperwork now said that it was coming changing to a third company and it moved to a third company.
Rym: and this third company was finally One that had a website and a portal that worked and was modern.
Rym: I logged in and immediately rolled it over into my betterment.
Scott: It's just like yeah yeah, I just After it was so with a third job I had that paid real money not counting like, you know high school jobs.
Scott: Yeah, right They they had a real 401k that I contributed to and got matched and all the normal stuff.
Scott: And then I so when I once I had that I rolled everything over and then every time I changed jobs After 90 days, I would always roll over.
Scott: so I have all the money in one Place and when I got this job a few years ago, I rolled it over.
Scott: I haven't had to do a big combo.
Scott: But the other thing is they've all been 401k rolloverable.
Scott: I haven't had other like three B's or IRA.
Rym: so I have a bunch of mine.
Rym: were That got like turned into IRAs because of nonsense didn't really matter Mmm, but basically I've never had to mix and match right?
Scott: It's always been the same kind directly rolling over at hundred percent of the money from the other.
Rym: so I went there.
Rym: I basically spent a while like Figuring out the account numbers for all these things and doing all the rollovers and it's at least it's easier now.
Scott: Every time I did it even just a few years ago.
Scott: I had to like get the HR person at my company involved.
Scott: I couldn't just
Rym: oh, you know hard the reason I didn't roll over that one from a pipeline so long ago because after I quit I thought okay, I'll deal with that like in a few more like after I get situated and then the company went under
Scott: And
Rym: It was hard to like contact a person to deal with anything.
Rym: and that was back.
Rym: All these investment firms had like portals that worked.
Rym: Yeah, like.
Rym: there was a time when like kind of like we did that ecommerce show where a lot of old ecommerce sites would be Like oh now that you've chosen the thing you want to buy here's how to mail us a check.
Scott: Yeah, the other thing is I you know, the previous one in the current one We're both fidelity which made moving the money easier Whatever.
Scott: but you know when I log into fidelity this two accounts listed there and the old one.
Scott: for some reason They didn't take all the money.
Scott: It was like some.
Scott: it was like 35 cents or something Like they didn't.
Scott: they didn't get a hundred percent of the money out of there.
Scott: So we kept reporting on it and I was like eventually I called them and I was like look I got like 35 cents.
Scott: Can you just like do something about that?
Rym: I got so actually.
Scott: so what they did is they changed it.
Scott: So now it's a zero.
Scott: it says zero.
Scott: now I guess they just took the 35 cents and ran away with it or whatever, but I don't care
Rym: you're when you're like 70 We're gonna be in the retirement home playing Pendragon and you're gonna open The equivalent of how letters get delivered in that distant future and it's gonna be like, yeah Here's the dollar 80 that you
Scott: are earned.
Scott: But the point is the 35 cents is gone.
Scott: I don't know where it went But when I log in it still shows both accounts and it's like can you just get get rid of that one?
Scott: It's like it's it's done right?
Rym: It's like close it You know, what sucks about working in enterprise software is that I know why a lot of times you just can't get rid of that.
Rym: There's the same reason.
Rym: my steam login still includes part of my social security number.
Scott: Yeah, anyway,
Rym: yeah Anyway, but I actually that reminded me of a related thing where I had a bank account That I didn't think had any money in it that I forgot about
Scott: Money that I
Rym: haven't been to in forever and I eventually got a letter from the government That was one of those.
Rym: Hey, the government has determined that you are the custodian of this unclaimed money Mm-hmm.
Rym: There was.
Rym: there was like 400 bucks in there.
Scott: It happens.
Rym: Yeah problem is back.
Rym: Well, I remember when I had that there is a in what.
Rym: I could really use that money back when I had that account if I It was there.
Scott: if you live in the United States, there's usually a website for your state.
Scott: I know New York has one.
Scott: I think the comptroller runs the website.
Scott: I'm not sure but basically you type your info into this.
Scott: totally legit not You know, make sure you find an actual legit one and not a fake one.
Scott: but I know for sure that New York has a website where you type in your info and they find if there is Unclaimed money in New York that actually belongs to you.
Scott: It's like in this database, but you just you just can't get it unless you look it up.
Scott: So it never hurts.
Scott: there wasn't any money in there for me But it never hurts to go.
Scott: everyone should go and take a look.
Scott: You know if such a thing exists where you live and if you are in it Because there might be money that belongs to you that for some reason the government is just holding and waiting for you to come And claim yeah, it takes you what five minutes to check, you know, google it.
Scott: It's not not a joke at all I'm totally serious.
Rym: so in some news One thing that has caused problems for technologists and humans for basically all of our adult lives And this has been around for a long time.
Rym: Can you experience it this weekend daylight saving time?
Rym: Yep, there's no s on the end because remember I I was for many years a professional time nerd like my job.
Scott: I don't think the s matters that much.
Rym: There's no fucking s there.
Rym: Don't say it with an s. It's not daylight savings time It's daylight saving time.
Rym: as in we are going to save daylight during this time.
Scott: Anyway, daylight savings time mean the same thing It's the time in which there is daylight.
Rym: save the time in which there are daylight savings.
Scott: There will be.
Scott: there will be savings of daylight during this time.
Rym: Yeah, but that's one not the text of the bill that caused it to come into being nor is it the actual name of the program.
Scott: The point is that matters is that this is it sucks ass.
Rym: is the point?
Scott: This is closer to the correct position, right?
Scott: You know a lot of people are complaining about losing an hour or whatever and some people hate sunlight or complaining about sunlight.
Rym: But the point is well the first half of those people the I do.
Rym: Time is arbitrary.
Rym: for the second job Pound sand.
Rym: we won and we're gonna win right.
Scott: the point is you want the clocks to stay Right in a position such that there is more daylight hours When you're not fucking working when the typical typical fucking sleeping is home and awake.
Rym: Exactly maximize the amount of time where the average person in America is home awake.
Scott: I don't or anywhere.
Scott: Yeah anywhere they live.
Rym: Well, cuz most places just don't bother with anything like this at all.
Rym: It's very much like an American and European thing.
Scott: The point is you're still choosing the hours, right?
Scott: You know when you know even regardless of where clocks are right?
Scott: It's like, you know, you could live in like Island X. who knows what time zone it's in right?
Scott: Is your live on Island X?
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: when at what time on the clock do people on Island X?
Scott: Wake up.
Scott: What time do they start working?
Scott: What time do they stop working, right?
Scott: It's like it doesn't matter if you shift your clocks around, right?
Scott: It's the times, you know that you like you could have a whole country or a whole society where people wake up at Midnight, you know the equivalent of midnight when the earth is on the exact opposite side of the Sun isn't the exact opposite side of the earth, right?
Scott: And then you could all just just you could just decide that and that's how people there operate.
Rym: Yeah now daylight saving time.
Rym: I think we've talked about this like ignites a lot But basically it exists solely because of the combination of it made sense in an ancient agrarian American time Coupled with the fact that our government can't ever change anything.
Rym: Yep, except the clocks apparently.
Rym: but and the thing is most known for for the last 40 years is Fucking up a bunch of IT stuff between two and four times a year.
Scott: Well, not I mean you've got you have your shit together now.
Scott: You would think that there are so many outages and weird problems around daylight saving time Around the world four times a year.
Scott: I think it's.
Scott: I think it's been you know close to like, you know, maybe 15 years since I've had a database that wasn't full of just everything in UTC and that's it.
Rym: So honestly, it's not databases and like data quality issues It's usually like DevOps like real-time systems monitoring type stuff that messes up these days Mmm like that.
Rym: That's what I see.
Rym: But anyway, there is Possibly literally the only thing that any American Republican in our government has ever supported in.
Rym: that is actually a good idea.
Rym: There is a bipartisan bill in the Senate Democrats and Republicans Trying to do exactly what Scott and I have always wanted.
Rym: now that we've lost The hour in quotes and sprung forward into the correct time the better time.
Rym: the bill says let's just fucking stay here Forever and never go back.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: That's what we should do.
Scott: But also that bill I think has come up many many times.
Scott: so it's not really news that it's up again.
Rym: Well, it's interesting that it's not like you could.
Scott: you could say you could.
Scott: we could have said that same news for I think Probably every year.
Rym: Well, what's interesting is it's not clear why this bill never actually passes.
Rym: No one disagrees with this except because it's not.
Scott: it's not a high priority and If it actually came close to passing they'd start to report on it and people hate change So they'd get mad and sit goes sign style.
Scott: So yeah, if you're a representative, it's like, you know, how hard do you want to?
Scott: Push on this, you know It's like just to start a big bunch of nonsense and it'll be a huge news.
Scott: and more, you know When you're dealing with like something is actually important like, you know climate change or people dying Why would you waste your time on this?
Scott: Yeah, you know, you just toss the paper out there and then it's like that's it.
Rym: Yeah, there is.
Rym: there is evidence though that it would actually improve public health for reasons that are probably too much for the show.
Scott: There's a lot of things that are improved public health.
Rym: Yeah, but this one costs us nothing and just makes the world a better place.
Scott: Government requires someone to do work to push something through and everyone's working on something more important.
Scott: Yeah or not working at all.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, uh, we'll see if maybe for once this might be the last time this comes up because there has been increased interest in removing This as best I can tell the people who are most against changing it in America are.
Scott: I hate to stereotype as old people But it seems like older voters are against it just because they're against stuff Right, but also I think I see a lot of people who are They want to make the standard time permanent because they hate the Sun.
Rym: Yeah, they want it to be dark earlier for like reasons that are in baffling and inscrutable to me.
Rym: Yeah a lot of it's People who get up early.
Scott: if you meet anyone who's like let's make standard time permanent get your garlic I so I can.
Rym: I do know the per a person who is against doing what we wanted who wanted to just stay in regular time Forever standard time.
Rym: their argument was that they get up early and punish all the people who don't also get up early.
Rym: Force people to get up earlier.
Scott: I Mean if I had the extent of the art if I was the boss of a company, you know And I didn't have to interact with other companies too much.
Scott: I would just be like, yeah We're gonna set our.
Scott: we don't care what the fucking clock say.
Scott: we we can start our work at any time We want right, you know and avoid commuting traffic, you know make everyone's life better.
Scott: You could make dentist appointments without having to take off work.
Scott: Yeah kinds of good stuff.
Rym: Anyway, so in some other news Twitter at a weird outage recently.
Rym: They had one outage only in Russia because the Russian government messed something up when they're trying to censor stuff.
Rym: But they had an outage like yesterday.
Rym: I think it happened on Sunday and like a little bit over the weekend Twitter accidentally started temporarily banning anyone who tweeted the word Memphis.
Scott: It's true.
Scott: They fixed it pretty quickly, but I assume this is some sort of you know Mistake some human error or some AI kind of error that must have detected some yeah You know pattern of bad tweets that had that word and then you know honed in on that word and started.
Scott: Maybe some bots were using that word a lot.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it looks it's interesting because smile mildly interesting.
Rym: it seems like what's been happening.
Rym: because if you notice the Twitter lately has been grappling with the fact that people can pretty easily manipulate where specific words into appearing in the trending tweets and A lot of people have been manipulating that lately.
Rym: So I'm pretty sure Twitter tried to put in place some sort of anti gaming system on that but they made it generic.
Rym: So it caught pretty much any.
Rym: there's you know, the thing we always talk about there's literally.
Scott: no There's not gonna.
Scott: Twitter's not gonna explain it to us.
Rym: It's like, you know, but there's literally no difference between a lot of people being interested something in something and a DOS.
Rym: They're the same thing.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: so I Feel like the real story here is that Twitter keeps trying to do these kinds of changes to clamp down on behavior that Embarrasses them or goes against their monetization instead of applying it toward the thing They should apply it toward which is harassment racism, etc.
Scott: Yeah, of course What else is new?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So you got any other tech news?
Scott: Yes, here's the news.
Scott: This is a little bit old like last month or so.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's not really about this particular incident because who gives a crap about that?
Scott: it's about the broader Concept right?
Scott: is that somebody made a browser extension an add-on right for Chrome Firefox, whatever.
Scott: And when you have a browser add-on And Firefox at least usually these things nowadays are used to be that they would just have you know Full control of your browser basically.
Scott: Yeah nowadays they'll at.
Scott: you'll have to grant the the Permission to your add-ons to do specific things, right?
Scott: But if you want to like your ad blocker you have to give it a shit ton of permissions to actually block ads.
Scott: You don't really have a choice there.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's got to be able to see the contents of the page exactly, so when you Like live your whole life in this browser.
Scott: if you know the add-ons that you choose to you know The browser software itself you have to trust But you have to trust the add-ons you add to the browser written by some who knows who on.
Scott: you know Whatever.
Scott: you just take some code put it in your browser.
Scott: Yeah, if that code is anything untrustworthy in it Like it could just ruin you.
Scott: You know, it's.
Scott: there's only so many protections that the browser has to limit the power of like any add-ons whatsoever.
Scott: You can like look at the web pages your you know.
Scott: You go to bank calm and it can just look and see how much your money.
Rym: Also web browsers are a high-value target for all the reasons Scott just described like if you cover If you can control someone's web browser you can have it do things.
Scott: you can have it make web requests and do all kinds of Net stuff.
Scott: and you know, you're just like running JavaScript on someone's computer.
Scott: It's like thanks Use your computer to run JavaScript.
Scott: mine coins do whatever bullshit, right?
Scott: So what happened was is there was an extension that was popular And it was perfectly good.
Scott: There's nothing wrong with it.
Scott: But then the person who made that extension just like sold it to someone else.
Rym: that's happened and Multiple times like you might block you block got to change hands at right and that's why we use you block origin now.
Scott: Don't use regular you block anyway.
Scott: But yeah, that's they sold it to someone else and the someone else just put in some malware's.
Scott: And that's that it's like.
Scott: and it's like a lot of times people trust something just cuz it's on like github.
Scott: It's like ah, it's open source on github.
Scott: Therefore.
Scott: Someone must have looked at ya.
Rym: I remember the old days people would be like, oh go to SourceForge and get the thing.
Rym: It's like, okay This is something dot exe.
Rym: just because it happens to be on SourceForge does not mean it.
Scott: Mozilla and I think Chrome in their add-on stores.
Scott: They do have programs where some of the add-ons are Validated like they like.
Scott: they went and they checked and they said like Firefox will go Mozilla will go and say yeah We looked at this add-on and it's legit we you can trust it.
Scott: At least if you trust Mozilla then you can trust this add-on and other ones are labeled as like someone uploaded this And we didn't look at it.
Scott: We're just Redistributing it on the add-on store.
Scott: because that's you know, whatever I think a lot of if it's.
Scott: if it's a shady add-on, please click this report button so we can block it.
Rym: Right, but in the meantime You know Well two things all your own risk most Malware will not let on that you're infected with malware so you won't know to report anything.
Rym: and To a lot of people seem to think that oh, it's open source Like it's on some sort of repo and it's open source.
Rym: Someone would have noticed if it was malware.
Rym: Guess what?
Rym: Not many people spend their time going through like chrome tab Suspender extensions to look at the source code and see if anything he's going.
Scott: you go to install an extension.
Scott: You see it's open source.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: are you gonna put through the effort or do you have the ability to look at it?
Scott: Investigate it and determine whether it's malware or not.
Rym: Yeah, I can read code.
Scott: Why do you assume that anyone has done that even one time?
Scott: if you're not willing to do it that one time yeah.
Rym: So I trust this extension because a bunch of my friends use it.
Rym: They must be smart and they all trust it cuz they know people.
Rym: but at no point did anyone actually look and see that it's Forwarding all your traffic to some dodgy IP address in Russia.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: If anyone wants to do a good deed pick one of your extensions That's a less popular one, right?
Scott: you know something like you block origin.
Scott: you probably don't have to do this right, but find another one that you use and maybe Read the code of it and make sure it's legit and then let everyone know if it's trustworthy or report it if it's not.
Scott: and but Yeah, just be aware of Which add-ons you have in your browsers?
Scott: That's the news there.
Scott: Okay other news tiny news, right?
Scott: We all know that companies all have these little home pod things.
Scott: I guess Apple is the only one that's actually called a home pod.
Scott: the Amazon ones like Alexa and the.
Rym: I don't know What's up with the Google cuz Google changed its branding around this stuff a bunch of times and I don't know anymore.
Scott: The Amazon one seems to be the winning one.
Scott: Yeah, I mean not that I would get one But I'm just saying like it's it's.
Rym: I have an old drop cam and I think that like moved into the Google ecosystem But it just won't work anymore and I didn't bother to try to figure it out.
Scott: Point is these things?
Scott: I'm not.
Scott: I was really surprised that they became popular because I feel like if you've got a big house in the suburbs One little speaker right is like, okay Maybe you put it in the living room or the kitchen like this main area of the house But it's like don't you kind of want to cover the whole house with it?
Scott: It's like you have to get more of them.
Scott: It doesn't seem too useful if it's not everywhere, right?
Scott: And also if you've got that much room, you've got room for like an actual sound system.
Scott: Why do you want to have sound coming in this one little guy, even though there are pretty impressive for being one little guy I mean that little.
Rym: Good.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, they're not.
Scott: they're pretty impressive for being one little guy, but it's still.
Scott: it's like even in my house.
Scott: I have two Like sound systems with speakers in this little.
Rym: so my grandparents they had a pretty like swinger house that they built themselves And the house was wired with a really fancy intercom system.
Rym: so basically every room had stereo speakers in it and you could use the intercoms like ping other rooms and talk to people and there was a central system that Could connect the whole thing up to the radio the hi-fi system or the CB radio.
Rym: that was integrated into the house.
Scott: Yep I've seen those.
Scott: But anyway, the point is that Apple they came out with their home pod mini like their last.
Scott: Was it one or two keynotes ago late last year?
Scott: They're basically just like the home pod mini was interesting because usually you have like iPod iPod nano Right and the smaller one is better in a lot of ways.
Scott: But it's also worse in some ways.
Scott: right the iPod nano did not have the storage or the battery life of the big iPod.
Scott: Yeah, it was.
Scott: it was lesser in some ways.
Scott: The home pod mini definitely seemed to me when they announced it.
Scott: Like isn't it just better than the home pod in every way?
Scott: like in what way?
Rym: So reading is a regular home.
Rym: the home pod mini cost $99 a third the price of the home pod and offers notably lower sound quality.
Rym: Oh Okay speakers physically smaller speakers are just worse.
Rym: It's true.
Rym: We'll stop that's true.
Scott: But in terms of any other kind of features besides the sound quality, I guess It was just worse.
Scott: I mean just better.
Scott: So they've just canceled the regular home pod and it's like yeah, no one bought those things to begin with.
Scott: I don't think anyone bought the mini one either.
Scott: I guess maybe a rich person would put these in like Sense, I feel like someone who's rich enough.
Rym: They're getting a bespoke system like integrated into the house.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I really like.
Scott: these are popular.
Scott: people have them but it's like like yeah if I was you maybe if you're a person with a one-room or two-room apartment and you don't care about sound quality and you're You're not really.
Scott: You know I wanted to just works Listening person and you actually talk to Siri or Alexa or whoever out loud Yeah for doing whatever it is that you do with that then maybe that's for you.
Scott: But like I never understood who the hell these are for who wants these it seemed like it's something companies wanted to sell right and in the same way that You know SUVs or something car companies wanted to sell and they made people want them, right?
Scott: So the companies I think have done and you know, they've done a clearly an amazing job of making people want SUVs.
Scott: I think they've done an okay job of making people want these But there's only so much you can do Right in.
Rym: that's a fascinating because my whole career because I'm a product manager like that kind of decision.
Rym: I Have always focused on what is a problem that I can solve for people out there where they would be willing to pay me for That solution.
Rym: I have never in my life Actually tried to say I have a thing that's easy to make.
Rym: I want to get people to buy this thing like that.
Rym: I've never tried that.
Rym: I've never even like gone down that path Mm-hmm.
Scott: But yeah, the point is I don't know who these are for.
Scott: It's not unsurprising to me.
Rym: Yeah I was really rich like stupid rich and I wanted like a sound system in my giant sprawling house.
Rym: I would have fancy speakers mounted into like the ceilings of every room Wired to a central system that is generic and can take literally any input in.
Scott: Right, but like I just don't know who you know, you're we're only thinking you're only thing about like the stereo feature, right?
Scott: He's have the that you talk to it, right?
Rym: Well the all the other aspects of it.
Rym: I see the place people seem to put these the most in my Experiences like pre kovid when I'd like be in someone's apartment or house is they always put them in the kitchen And they use them while they're like hooking and doing kitchen these stuff.
Scott: Yeah, you can use it for a timer but you can just.
Scott: I see a lot of people use Siri for a timer.
Scott: They just use their phone or their watch.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, if you have a home pod you have an iPhone I watch.
Scott: Maybe right.
Scott: I'll definitely have an iPhone.
Rym: No question if they were smart enough to.
Rym: so why do you need real-time respond to me?
Rym: With more advanced queries like Siri, how how long should I cook?
Scott: but that the same Siri that's on the home Pod is in the iPad and the iPhone.
Scott: It's the same Siri.
Scott: Why wait from camera.
Scott: It's like what's the home pod for?
Rym: Well, cuz my phone won't listen to me unless I touch it and turn it on.
Rym: I Have to keep turning it.
Scott: You can make it not do that.
Scott: You can.
Scott: I don't want it.
Scott: I don't want it to listen when I'm walking this thing.
Rym: That's what this thing does and it can't play loud music by itself while I'm cooking and there's a bunch of banging going on in the kitchen.
Scott: That's because you've never had an Apple phone or Apple iPad even even then.
Rym: and I find surprising.
Rym: Audio, well that event fan is going.
Rym: compared to one of these things.
Rym: There's no subwoofer in your eyes.
Scott: if the vent fan is going even my real stereo with with 5.1 sound it needs to be cranked to a dangerous level.
Scott: So I don't I just turn off audio when the fan is on.
Rym: So in some other news, this is a tariff like this article.
Rym: the thing that happened is terrifying to me and It honestly like I already like LG has not really been on my doesn't doesn't terrify me.
Rym: It doesn't terrify me in the sense that I'm not vulnerable to this.
Rym: I would never buy an LG TV.
Scott: Of course not or an LG monitor or an LG anything, but I got an LG monitor.
Scott: It's fine.
Scott: It doesn't have ads on it.
Rym: Yeah, I Think it's gonna be fine one day one day.
Scott: I think it's not connected to the internet.
Scott: It's good.
Rym: Well, this one wasn't connected to the internet either.
Rym: That's the problem.
Scott: Well, yes and no.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: so basically the the.
Rym: you can read the article to see the details because this kind of thing is Happening in the low end of the TV market and has for some time.
Rym: This is a trend in all industries.
Rym: same thing happened with like I don't know e-readers.
Rym: cheap e-readers would like show ads on their home screen that you couldn't turn off like.
Rym: that was the thing.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But the margins on TVs are pretty low and it turns out most consumers unless you're rich and buying like an upper high-end thing.
Scott: Price only rich P only rich people.
Scott: and you know tech people who know about tech and snobs Actually care about things like contrast ratio, right?
Scott: most people just say I Want to I got a flat TV and I get the biggest one I can afford or the fits on my wall or whatever.
Rym: And how big is it?
Rym: How many dollars is it?
Rym: That's it.
Scott: Yeah, then they don't give a shit about anything else.
Scott: It's only you know people who care of like oh, how's the color reproduction?
Scott: Those the only people care about what anything else.
Scott: so I know it's funny Best buy and buying a TV off the rack.
Rym: I got some training.
Rym: I'm like setting price points and like market research on prices like pricing as a topic and It basically the the thing that came up.
Rym: in the training.
Rym: we were talking about how people actually make decisions based on data.
Rym: The fascinating part was people like you and me who actually care at all about the specifications of any ultra rare Significant insignificant you might even pay attention to.
Rym: the advice is just pretend those people don't exist or cater exclusively to them.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: We don't exist in the market.
Rym: Same reason why I like shitty.
Rym: airlines are all shitty in the same ways because the only decision that matters is the number of dollars for the ticket at the time you buy the ticket, so The problem is
Scott: because of
Rym: that and because of market pressures and margins and everything This kind of thing is now rising higher and higher into the stack into like the middle of the road options.
Rym: Basically Fancy o LED TVs not just the bottom of the barrel ones, but like an actual LED TV from LG Has.
Rym: they have embedded ads that will play in the menus built into the TV?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, it's in the smart TV portion, right?
Scott: So if you're not using the smart It's not like it's gonna go on top of like a movie or watch.
Scott: Yeah But when you open up the menus to do smart TV shut shit like use the Netflix app built into the TV Right.
Scott: Yeah, press the menu button.
Scott: this menu comes up and it shows you all these apps built into the TV.
Scott: You know Netflix Apple TV plus HBO max or whatever and you're going to choose one.
Scott: Well, there's a whole area on the screen for them to show ads.
Scott: the L because it's the.
Scott: you're in the LG OS.
Scott: to some It's usually Android powered most of the time Although I've heard that at least one of them is like still web OS.
Scott: it doesn't matter what OS they're using Right is this?
Scott: there's a little computer about as powerful as a phone a shitty phone built into the TV that's doing this stuff and This is why I never get a smart TV, right?
Scott: Yeah, TV should be a monitor only it should do nothing.
Rym: It's all it is.
Scott: That really does a Video signal I send into it does.
Scott: there are still companies making monitors and there actually is a trend lately of monitor companies Making very large monitors.
Scott: Yeah, right They're selling them as monitors like by this 55 inch gaming monitor.
Scott: and it's like that's a television.
Scott: Yeah, but look at it like that.
Rym: But it is called going after the Rym and Scott and for other people demographic right there.
Scott: But it's like Alienware has like a 55 inch or I think or something like that.
Scott: But the point is it doesn't have smart TV bullshit in it as a monitor.
Rym: So where this ad cropped up was when this person went into the TV to update some stuff.
Rym: the ad just played.
Rym: There's no way to turn it off.
Rym: And this is a $1,400 TV.
Scott: Yeah, I mean don't use I. this is the advice We've always said and will continue to say do not buy a smart TV if you have no choice.
Scott: But to buy a smart TV.
Scott: Do not use any of the smart things in the TV.
Rym: never let it connect to the internet.
Scott: even never Connect the TV directly to the internet.
Scott: disable the Wi-Fi in the TV.
Scott: Do not let it connect to your Wi-Fi.
Scott: do not put an ethernet cable into the TV, right?
Scott: Do not let it touch your home network in any way shape or form.
Scott: only use the TV for it's you know, not smart functionality of other devices sending video signals to it probably with HDMI because it's 2021 and you know plug your switch into it.
Scott: plug your HTPC into it and if you really aren't gonna have an HTPC and you got a Roku or an Apple TV or something use those.
Scott: Those are more trustworthy than the shit that's in the TV.
Scott: Right?
Scott: an Apple TV is 10,000 times better as much as it's not good.
Scott: Yeah, then whatever is in any TV, even the best TV in the world use that instead And that's it.
Rym: Yep, and just we need to agree.
Rym: like this kind of like a non-consensual Advertising creeping a higher and higher higher into the stack needs to be nipped in the bud because this is all they're gonna.
Scott: It's not just it's not even just advertising right?
Scott: It's it's you know, all the other The Internet of shit coupled with the non.
Rym: HTPCs tend to not have the full functionality of a web browser going to the site where the content is and Have their own ulterior motives for monetization and often their own algorithms to drive What kind of content get gets pushed at you?
Scott: That's.
Scott: the other thing is that you know, you'd be just.
Scott: it's just tons and tons of reasons We've talked about in the past.
Scott: but do not if you can at all, right which you probably can Do not you get smart TV?
Scott: And if you have a smart TV don't use the smart parts Yep at all.
Rym: ever under any circumstance and since LG is breaking ground in putting these ads How pretty high up in the stack my advice is never buy an LG device again, at least not a TV.
Scott: Yeah, I would not buy, you know, if a company has a TV that has ads in it I'm not going to buy a TV for that company.
Rym: Yeah I would like really I would like to see legislation to make it difficult or impossible to embed ads in devices directly like this like there should be some sort of regulation around this because really What this is gonna turn into have a really good regulation.
Rym: people and very technologically savvy People can avoid this shit and everyone else is stuck with it.
Scott: I have a really easy regulation, you know, because it's already been.
Scott: you know, I'm not a lawyer or a constitutional scholar or anything But I am aware Correct me if I'm wrong the while speech is very strongly protected.
Scott: United States Commercial speech is not.
Scott: it is illegal to have cigarette ads on TV.
Scott: Yeah, it used to be illegal to not have prescription drug ads on TV.
Scott: You know, you can't even have cigarette ad billboards or magazines anymore, right?
Rym: They're like banned like Congress.
Rym: kind of ad.
Rym: full stop.
Scott: Congress has the power to write regulate commercial speech.
Scott: full stop you could.
Scott: they could write a law that says Advertising is illegal.
Scott: any company that advertises the CEO goes to prison for their life.
Scott: That's the whole law.
Scott: the end vote.
Scott: vote on that law.
Scott: vote.
Scott: Yes, there are no more ads anywhere ever.
Scott: or the CEOs in prison.
Scott: Either one of those is fantastic I'm not even joking.
Scott: Just do that.
Rym: but anyway things Of the day.
Rym: so check this out.
Rym: This is actually a really simple video.
Rym: It's smarter every day, but I don't think I've ever actually linked to them or if I ever was a long long time ago.
Rym: But they did a really really simple video and I want this is my thing of the day to prove a point This is just a video on how to use the snatch block and like how a block and tackle works.
Rym: But it's not like.
Rym: the high school physics demonstration of this is why pulleys are magic.
Rym: It's actually much more focused on the practical aspects of pulleys.
Scott: Because okay a lot like we've done a pulley thing of the day in the past.
Rym: Uh, not definitely not done this.
Scott: I've definitely watched a whole bunch of videos in my life where it's like someone lifts a real heavy thing with a rope because they Got like seven pulleys in line.
Rym: Yeah, this is not that though.
Rym: This is more like Practically like how do you how do you as a person in your day-to-day life?
Rym: Quickly and effectively deploy pulleys to solve real problems?
Scott: I'm a bicycle effectively kinda.
Rym: Yeah, and I you know as much as I'm very like a lot of us especially like they kind of nerd to listen to a podcast and cares About embedded ads in their smart TV garage your garage door.
Rym: Yep They're.
Rym: uh, this is more like if you have to make a pulley or like deal with a pulley quickly or solve a problem Like I don't know you ran your car into a ditch.
Rym: How do you get the car out of a ditch?
Rym: there's a difference between you call for having this abstract knowledge of how technology works like how to use a winch and having an intuitive and internalized understanding of how to apply Very simple and effective technology to quickly solve problems people are able to do.
Rym: the latter tend to Survive things better and be more effective in their day-to-day lives.
Rym: That's an observation I've had.
Scott: I'm gonna try to focus use a pulley Directly think about it.
Rym: I had to use a pulley Was actually in like a for real right like solving a realm with the pulley.
Rym: was we got a Jeep stuck in a ditch?
Rym: But Basically, all right.
Rym: All right, Scott.
Rym: You got a Jeep.
Rym: It's got a winch on the front.
Scott: I don't have a Jeep and I never will.
Rym: let's say you do because you're driving off into the wilderness to find the last.
Rym: That's some crazy billionaire hid in the wilderness and you know where it is.
Rym: I'll come up and tell me to tell you're in a Jeep and you get the Jeep stuck in a ditch.
Rym: How do you get the Jeep out of it there?
Scott: I'll leave it there and walk.
Rym: All right.
Rym: It is you cannot make it out of the wilderness without driving.
Scott: I'll call for help on my phone.
Rym: your phone is dead because you're in the middle of the wilderness.
Scott: use a helicopter There's.
Rym: you only have a Jeep walk You'll do okay you starve to death before you make it to the edge of the wilderness.
Scott: why I deserve it for deepen.
Rym: Anyway, there's a naive way to use a winch and a Very smart way to use a winch and this is the kind of practical knowledge that people who do real physical work No But a lot of nerds as much as they think oh I know about a nuclear weapons work and I know how a gun works.
Rym: I know a pulleys work.
Rym: There are the practical application of those simple like how to practically apply a lever Not actually that obvious or intuitive to most people and they tend to fuck it up no matter how smart they are.
Scott: All right, so I don't know if I've mentioned it on the show before I probably have.
Scott: there's a thing called Pico 8.
Scott: I think we may have talked about this when we talked about Gamer X at some point because there were some really good Pico 8 games at gamer X when we went in New York.
Rym: God that was a long time ago.
Scott: Pico 8 is a fantasy game console.
Scott: It doesn't actually exist, right?
Scott: They just came up with right this game and there's actually some competitors or not necessarily competitors.
Scott: but there's a few of these right where?
Scott: What if a game console existed that had this chip in it?
Scott: Right, so they just make an emulator for a chip that never existed, right?
Scott: And it's like you just made a console and now people can make games for that console.
Scott: So Pico 8 is one of those that makes games with a particular aesthetic.
Scott: But you know and there's been a lot of really high-quality Pico 8 games I've seen in my time Especially on itch.io and but I've discovered this recently because everyone is tweeting about it I think it had maybe a big release or something.
Scott: I don't know But What this is is Pico CAD.
Scott: It is itself a Pico 8 application.
Scott: So you need to run it on a Pico 8 and it will any or on.
Scott: you know in your browser You can run the Pico 8 emulator, right?
Scott: It's just.
Scott: it's just free.
Scott: and then It lets you make a 3d model and sort of color it and texture it as really simple Pixley 3d model that looks like it's from something even less than like a PlayStation 1.
Scott: We're talking like Virtua racing from Sega, but maybe with like better color and textures on it And you can't make your model too complex or obviously you start to run out.
Scott: You know hit the limitation the artificial limitations of the Pico 8 console.
Scott: that doesn't exist.
Scott: but you can make 3d models of like a particular and awesome aesthetic using Pico CAD and then you can use those tiny models in Perhaps some other Pico software you're gonna use.
Scott: it just exports to like totally normal files.
Scott: You can load them into like, you know, whatever.
Rym: well It looks like the most recent update is exporting to OBS and MTL.
Rym: so you can import them into like blender and unity.
Scott: Yeah, you get unity.
Scott: Yep, you can.
Scott: just you can make stuff in Pico CAD and then import it into your actual Outside software.
Scott: Yeah, and perhaps I don't know if you can do vice-versa.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: This is just looks really cute and easy.
Scott: Yeah, this is is.
Scott: quite imagine if there was like, you know It's almost like a Mario Paint situation, right?
Scott: Where it's like, ah, you can use your Super Nintendo to make Super Nintendo sprites.
Scott: So you can use your Pico 8, you know, you're in quotes your Pico 8 To make Pico 8 models, right?
Rym: Has anyone made a physical Pico 8?
Scott: I Mean generally.
Scott: you can just take like a Raspberry Pi put it into a box and run Pico 8 on it, right?
Scott: So and then you can put Pico 8 ROMs right onto cartridges.
Scott: I'm sure someone's done that There's.
Scott: there are some competitors.
Scott: I forget what they're called because I think Pico 8 itself technically isn't like the open source Like it doesn't cost any money, but I don't think it's open source.
Scott: I'm not sure there's another one.
Scott: I think that is fully open source.
Scott: That's a little different but not bad.
Scott: I Look it up.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Yep, but that's it in the meta moment.
Rym: We're still stuck at home, but we are reading the tail.
Scott: I am reading the tail, but I am progressing.
Rym: Hanzo is done.
Rym: We're back to Genji.
Rym: Here we go.
Scott: Yeah, the first novel that has ever existed the first You know literature written by a human that that is in the format known as novel Is the tale of Genji and We are reading that book.
Rym: my advice to you so far if you're picking this book up either because you were finally reading it Or because you're a new listener you just you waited until we started reading it before you dove in.
Rym: my advice is if You read like a page or two and you're a little bit confused like you don't know exactly who one of the characters is my advice is to just keep going and You'll kind of figure it out later anyway.
Scott: So it won't matter that like if you don't at the beginning of each chapter at least in the edition.
Rym: Oh, yeah It gives you a list of all the characters that are in that scene.
Scott: right because you know in there trying to keep with the you know, like I guess more and it's not ancient but you know, The traditional older style Japanese that this is written people are referred to obliquely, right?
Scott: Yes in that old style of language.
Scott: People are not always referred to in a clear fashion.
Scott: It would be like if I wrote a Whole something in English and I kept using pronouns all the time, right?
Scott: Something or or using other ways to refer to a person like, you know, ah the gamer I just said the gamer every time right and it's like.
Scott: well, you know it but it's in a room full of gamers.
Scott: Which person are they talking about?
Scott: And that's the way there.
Scott: so in trying to keep with that old style language the translation right Uses pronouns and other ways of referring to someone all the time instead of just saying their name often enough Right that you can tell who the hell it is.
Scott: So you have to figure that out?
Rym: But seriously just steamroll through.
Rym: as long as you understand what happened in each scene it all slots together like pretty easily like You'll kind of just get into a groove with it.
Scott: Yep So that's that tale again.
Rym: G any other meta things whatsoever Mean there's light at the end of the tunnel on the vaccines to the point to where at some point this year There's a chance.
Rym: Scott and I can record something together again, but there's a non-zero chance, but it's.
Scott: uh, you know There's even.
Scott: there's even a non-zero convention chance, but it's it's way low.
Rym: Yep It gets higher toward the like later in the year like November December definitely But we're talking.
Scott: we're talking like lottery tickets here.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So, uh, yeah a lot of projects are on hold until post-covid just because like we've said before It is such a pain in the ass to record a panel In this environment that we have only done it when absolutely forced to.
Scott: yeah.
Scott: All right, so cable management.
Scott: I'm pretty sure we did a show on this and you deleted it.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: We did a show in The best I could find September 28th 2017. we did a show on Desks but I poked at it and we seem to almost entirely talk about the form factor of desks themselves.
Rym: And I'm pretty sure I talked a little bit about like rack cable management back in like 2006 but that was back when shows didn't really have topics necessarily.
Rym: Yeah, like we did a show once called games were reviewed like seven tabletop games in a row.
Scott: All right, the point is when it comes to cable management right at least for an everyday or even a technological person.
Scott: I really see four four categories right that come to mind in my life, right?
Rym: Yep Well, how do you deal with his telepathic powers?
Rym: How do you deal with his telekinetic powers?
Rym: Right my current toad line cable or is he from the future?
Scott: right the four instances.
Scott: I have to manage cables, right are Inside of a computer.
Scott: you're building a computer this cables in it.
Scott: Right, you're outside your computer around your desk.
Scott: You've got your monitors your computer and your mouse your keyboard.
Scott: You gotta wire everything together.
Scott: this case to Case three that you're in a data center and there's mostly networking cables, but also power cables and other cables that need Yeah, which if I did professionally for many years, I managed data centers and also like personally pulled cables.
Rym: I can talk about that at length.
Scott: and then the fourth one would be of a home a home theater and you're cabling.
Scott: You know, you got cables going from the TV to your HD PC to your game consoles to your power outlets talk.
Scott: Alright, there is some other ones that I have not had to do personally.
Rym: Like we're not talking about like power met cable management in a house.
Rym: Like that's just home, right?
Scott: You might work at a phone company.
Scott: You know, we're not talking about telcos either like you might be in like the the You know stage business theaters you might or concerts and wiring up those sorts of things.
Scott: Or your DJ.
Scott: you got a wire that stuff.
Scott: but most any you know Serious electronic system of any kind.
Scott: we still depend on wires in 2021 to some degree.
Scott: Not everything is wireless.
Scott: So you have to you know, take you know physical, you know lengths of.
Scott: you know Some sort of metal in sort of some sort of shielded sheath of some kind with connectors at the end To connect one thing to another thing.
Scott: and when it's only one thing to another thing, it's easy.
Scott: You just boop boop done, right?
Scott: But often you will have several things that need to be connected to several other things in the proximity to each other.
Scott: And if you just connect everything boop boop one at a time.
Scott: It will work and it will also be a mess.
Rym: you get a desk that looks like what my desk looked like in the early days of GeekNights right, so I you got to do some sort of trickery, right?
Scott: It's not easy to connect all these wires in such a way that they are a neatly organized Clean and you know pleasing to the eye or perhaps the the you know, the god tier invisible
Rym: Like I'll admit someone like think something that bothers me viscerally whenever I see it even though I would never like to say something.
Rym: if I was in someone's house.
Rym: if there's a really nice TV hanging on the wall and Three or four different cables just coming down the wall at three or four random angles coming to its mentor Well, well that might mean that's my TV, but they're all.
Scott: yeah My mind that my TV doesn't have a pyramid but they're all just sort of going straight down because it's like that's better than the Inverted pyramid in my mind not by much but it is better.
Scott: But I guess mostly just cuz.
Scott: I've got you know I've got the power cable and I've got like three HDMI cables coming out and then I've got for the Wii I've got this component cable.
Rym: Yeah I've already decided how I'm gonna handle that.
Rym: I cuz I am gonna hire your guy to mount my TV on the wall.
Rym: after kovin I'm gonna actually mount a cable channel inside of the wall and Have a port at the bottom or he maybe even in the other room for I'd like to do that.
Scott: But I don't.
Scott: this isn't?
Scott: I don't?
Rym: I rent I don't own Already cut multiple holes in my walls to run cables.
Rym: You know, I'll do.
Rym: when I move out one I might just leave them cuz there's no way the building would notice Like you know through.
Rym: oh there's an extra faceplate that looks just like all the faceplates that were there when I moved in over a Decade ago.
Rym: that has some ethernet in it.
Rym: Where does that go?
Scott: I mean if If I wasn't renting I would absolutely do that or two.
Rym: if it was a problem All I'll do is just put plaster over it and leave the cables in the wall and just move out.
Rym: Yeah, but if I was yeah, yeah, but well, I think let's go.
Rym: but I think we'll go inside out.
Rym: We'll start with inside the computer to work our way out.
Rym: but the parameter what we're only talking about semi permanent cable installation because Permanent installation is like I am wiring a house fully and permanently.
Rym: like these cables will never move Like that's when you're zip tying cables directly together and like permanently sticking them somewhere gluing them whatever putting them inside of something you can't get them out of but and temporary like if I set up a computer in the living room to do.
Rym: like all the cables I laid to record that panel are Recorded for packs online.
Rym: I just let them lay everywhere because as soon as I was done recording I rolled them all up and put them away.
Rym: like don't manage those just let it be.
Rym: Yep, exactly inside the computer Counts as semi-permanent because you want it to be nice in there But you don't want to like permanently mount them all somehow.
Rym: because what if you add a new hard drive to your computer?
Rym: What if something breaks or changes?
Rym: like yeah, there's a lot of reasons.
Rym: You might have to go inside your computer and move one of those cables You also you also want to keep them nice to.
Scott: so don't restrict or mess up the airflow in the computer.
Rym: it's funny.
Rym: in the old days this actually like you kids are lucky.
Rym: computer cable management is Orders of magnitude easier than it used to be.
Rym: we used to have these fat ribbon cables.
Rym: They were like two inches wide Yep, and you couldn't even make them smaller.
Rym: if you tried to like bundle them together You get signal interference and like your hard drive would get slower or not work.
Scott: Yep, they used to sell some.
Scott: that would be like, you know That would be sort of do the inverted pyramid on both ends.
Scott: Yeah, we're like the middle was wrapped tight around itself.
Rym: Yeah, but those were kind of expensive and sometimes had problems and those came late to the scene later.
Rym: One
Scott: thing that's nice and one thing that's nice nowadays is you might be you know most of the cabling inside of a computer at least, you know in these times is You know If you can make a computer with only m2 drives which I think most people can get away with and maybe have a NAS Then you don't need any of that.
Scott: You can just not have hard drives in your computer that are require any cables and you've just taken away So much of the wires in the computer Like in the old days.
Rym: you had to plug so much crap in like oh you got a CD drive.
Rym: I plug the PETA cable in parallel ATA Plug in the magic cable that made audio come out of it.
Scott: Yeah, if you've only got m2 Drives in your computer.
Scott: The only cables you need are basically from the power supply to everything.
Scott: and Is that it?
Rym: The stuff that's on the front of your case into the headers on the motherboard Right.
Scott: Yeah, but there's the magic.
Rym: the thing that changed for all of you isn't just that all this old fuddy-duddy stuff disappeared Like you'll never have to worry about a ribbon cable again in your lives but also cases got way better like computer cases used to just be like No one no one even thought about the user experience of one of these things.
Rym: like you would have to unscrew the entire thing to Like move a hard drive like literally take the whole case apart.
Rym: back in the day Motherboard went straight into the back like there was no room behind the motherboard.
Rym: nowadays Honestly, you know my cable management strategy is buy a nice case.
Rym: it has channels behind the motherboard but inside the case.
Rym: Yeah, cram everything back there.
Rym: Don't really care if it's ugly cuz no one can see it and it's not in the way.
Scott: Yep, that's what I do too.
Scott: It's I do.
Rym: there are channels back there with little like Like Multiple sets of channel like it's so fancy channels.
Scott: But basically yeah the way the case is.
Scott: they know what you're gonna be putting in there.
Scott: They know the power supply goes here and such and nowadays power supplies of modular cables.
Scott: You don't need to like.
Scott: I used to have all these just cables sitting in the computer because the power supply just had like a big Crazy number of wires come.
Rym: I cut them off one of one of my power supplies.
Scott: It could be a little dangerous.
Scott: You got to tie them up, right?
Rym: No, I cut it.
Rym: I cut them off and then I terminated the ends.
Scott: Yeah, you got terminate or something.
Rym: Yeah, but it is leave the bear cow.
Rym: You gotta hang it out.
Scott: There's.
Scott: uh, you know now they're modular power supplies.
Scott: You only put the few the cables you need and no extras, right?
Scott: Yeah, then you take those.
Scott: they go There's a hole.
Scott: there'll be a hole near the near the power supply where those cables can go directly behind the motherboard.
Scott: Right because the motherboards aren't mounted on a plate.
Scott: then they can go up or sideways or wherever they need to go And then there'll be holes near the places they need to pop out and then directly attached to whatever they need to attach to you.
Scott: So it's like ah, there's where the motherboard has its ATX power connector and there's a hole right next to it.
Scott: So the power supply cable goes behind where no one can see.
Scott: it pops out in the front connects And then once you've connected everything on that back plate behind the motherboard are like little ties.
Scott: So you can sort of bundle the cables together into little groups, you know, so they're not just you know a mess.
Scott: But even if they are a mess doesn't matter.
Scott: This is fun.
Rym: Yep In fact, you can even leave a few extra cables back there and tuck the ends out of the way And then you buy a new hard drive.
Rym: Just pull those little ends out plug them in.
Rym: good to go.
Scott: Yeah, even if you do have you know SATA cables still like I do it's like yeah, you can route them generally with the same kind of method.
Scott: You know depends on your case.
Scott: Yeah But just just try to hide as much as you can then your case will look pretty nice.
Rym: Cool thing is a lot of modern no one can see.
Rym: behind the motherboard we'll have a whole separate section in the bottom for basically just the power supply and Usually if you do have giant old spin and hard disks, they usually put racks down there for those too.
Rym: So they're just completely invisible.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yep What the listener pointed out the fans fans in the early days when all they just need power.
Rym: It used to be easy cases.
Rym: Just didn't have fans usually Mmm, then there's beard fans.
Rym: There's nothing to plug them into.
Rym: You'd have to like your motherboard.
Scott: your motherboard has spots for the power to go and if it's a fan that needs power supply power You do the same thing.
Scott: no higher goes back and then it pops out near the fan.
Scott: and
Rym: the cool thing is most nice cases will come with fans like Already in all the right spots and usually even have cables running through the channels to the place That's likely near where you're gonna have to plug them into the motherboard like standardization happened of all the things that the ATX specification didn't specify.
Rym: Kind of naturally and you'll always be able to take advantage of that unless you buy a super shitty off-brand case.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So the next kind of cable routing let's go to the the TV area, right?
Scott: So as room was saying, you know If you've got a situation where the TV itself like mine has like four HDMI cables going into it gives you got to switch it to Nintendo switches and an HD PC and all this stuff, right?
Scott: If your TV's on a table of some kind it's not too big a deal, right?
Scott: You can just do sort of normal cable routing right, you know tie things up nicely with cable.
Rym: Yeah all my cables are tied up with cable ties sitting behind the like Entertainment center shelf where unless you really go back there and look like you're not gonna see him Every single cable I have.
Scott: I went on the internet a few years ago and I bought a package of like a hundred You know hook and loop for a velcro cable ties and what I did is basically every single cable I owned Except for the ones inside a computer, but even some of the ones in the computer But mostly the outside computer ones USB cables HDMI cables power K all those sort, right?
Scott: I any time I came across a cable that did not have a cable tie on it I put a cable tie on it and that cable tie could be used.
Scott: if the cable is put away I'm not using it right now.
Scott: I could bundle it up with that little cable tie and if I am using it I can bundle up the slack on the cable with a little cable tie or Combine it with other cables because they all have cable ties, right?
Scott: They can grab on to each other to form a nice cable channel.
Scott: That is nice and clean instead of a spread out You know indecipherable mess.
Scott: So that's step one.
Scott: But if your TV's up on the wall Elevated Rym was correct.
Scott: It looks fugly as mine does where the cables are just coming down the wall.
Rym: My best advice is mount as much as you can on the back of the TV.
Rym: I see a lot of people do this like they'll mount the TV on the wall But they'll also stick stuff like the power like anything they need to make the TV work or even a tiny HDPC in some cases an Apple.
Scott: an Apple TV can hang on the back of a television really easily.
Scott: It's tiny.
Scott: my HDPC is too big for that.
Scott: Yeah But it would be possible for me if I really wanted to to mount the HDPC on the wall behind the TV.
Scott: it could happen.
Scott: right now You're thinking wait a minute you put more stuff on the wall more stuff on the TV.
Scott: those cables still need to go down Right somewhere.
Scott: well no not really because what happens is the HDMI cables are now all in one place, right?
Scott: They're going from the devices on the wall into the television.
Scott: They're all up there already hiding behind the TV.
Scott: The power cables need to go somewhere.
Scott: well what you do is you take your power strip, and you put that up there.
Rym: Oh now You just got to get one cable to that TV.
Scott: now the only cable that has to come down from the TV is the Power cable from the power strip and you can hide it in a channel or hide it in the wall Or something else like that.
Scott: if you can't do that you can do a rims doing which is where The cables go into the wall or into a plate that's on the wall Right and then you have sort of down near the floor.
Scott: you have some sort of exit where the cables come out.
Scott: Yeah, and then that stuff is where you connect to everything else in a hidden fashion.
Rym: I like the plates.
Rym: I like the idea of you have plates where like you could like they literally have like HDMI and DisplayPort and USB like ports on them.
Scott: right yeah up on high on the wall HDMI hole you know and on the low on the wall is an HDMI hole.
Scott: inside the wall is an HDMI cable as long as You never have to upgrade that HDMI cable to a newer standard yeah, and even if you do It's only a minor pain in the ass I guess.
Rym: but another way to go that actually is a lot easier for people is You might have what one of those two might have the whole like the proper like plug just coming out of the wall usually the One that's the most visible, but on the other end of it usually hidden behind the TV you get a face plate That's basically just an open hole with some stuff to make it easy for cables to like kind of hang there easily And just jam the cables into the wall through that big hole because no one will see the hole
Scott: exactly.
Scott: But yeah, you just want to find.
Scott: it's really about that gap.
Scott: You know that's where the unseemliness is between the TV and the you know because your power outlets are gonna be near the floor.
Scott: I guess if you make your own house isn't that you put the power outlets up near the TV And get really fancy right if your TVs on certain kinds of arms for mounting right.
Scott: so my Arm doesn't have this too much as a little bit bit But my monitor arms.
Scott: in the arm of my monitors There is a channel for cables to go.
Scott: so basically all the cables from the monitor get bundled up.
Scott: They go into this channel, and then they exit at the.
Scott: you know where the mom where the the arm clamps right onto the back Of my desk.
Scott: they exit there.
Scott: So you really you know don't have them just like flopping all over the place.
Scott: It's pretty nice, and you know TVs can do a similar thing.
Scott: find You know some sort of channel or pipe or race way or something to for cables to go?
Rym: Yeah, when in doubt if you're on it's all.
Scott: it's about aesthetics right?
Scott: the cables themselves are ugly.
Scott: You just trying to hide them yep Them in like a tube.
Rym: But as a matter they're actually if you're willing to put up with cutting them to the right length yourself And you're okay with them smelling bad for like a week.
Rym: go on Amazon and buy like the cheapest cable channels.
Rym: They usually stick to your wall with like adhesive tape.
Rym: they look fine They just work and they really clean everything up.
Rym: Just get like some black or white ones and just plan them in advance like.
Rym: the only other thing you really got to think about Is plan what you're gonna do before you start sticking stuff in places and how long?
Scott: Lengths right you're gonna need.
Scott: as soon as when you try to organize things into channels that takes because you're not taking a direct route From point A to point B You're routing your go.
Rym: cables need to be longer than you might realize.
Scott: You need more length than you realize.
Scott: you have to consider the maximum lengths possible for certain kinds of cables when you're doing this right.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not any granted.
Scott: You know there's the advertised Specified lengths for different cable standards, and I have never.
Scott: I've seen many cables exceed those specs And I've never seen one not work.
Rym: I've seen higher end like later USB.
Rym: that's too long has trouble, but like USB 2 you can make a USB 2 cable Scarily.
Scott: I've seen Ethernet so long.
Scott: it shouldn't have worked, but it worked.
Rym: But the thing I got to do is I'm actually gonna mount the dock for the switch on the wall, I think You can do that right next to the TV.
Scott: Yeah, there are other solutions to get creative for things like that.
Scott: you know cuz the the switch itself the bottom of it is just USB-c.
Scott: yeah, so you could do is you could have like you know you could get some third-party switch dock.
Scott: That's like the one I have.
Scott: that's like just like a little adapter kind of guy.
Scott: You can hide that and just have a USB-c cable like off in the corner somewhere So you don't even have a switch dock.
Rym: or I mean the pro move is I would like to route a few cables like through The ceiling.
Rym: I don't have any place to do this in this apartment.
Rym: obviously like I can't dig it as much as I'm saying I'll dig Into my walls.
Rym: I'm not digging into my floor But I would love to run like some USB and a couple other cables From that wall under the floor to like behind the couch.
Rym: So if I'm sitting there I could plug something like say I needed to use a wired controller for some reason.
Rym: just plug it in right there that yep That is like S-tier.
Scott: Yeah, if you want to get something from the TV to the couch right the best thing to do is called a raceway.
Scott: You've probably seen it.
Scott: It's basically like a little rubber guy.
Scott: That's you know.
Scott: and the point of these is actually more of a safety issue.
Scott: if you're setting up something temporary You'll just use like duct tape to cover cables because people could trip over them when they're running around on the floor, right?
Scott: but if you have a more permanent situation where this?
Scott: you know, maybe you're in a conference room in an office and The Kate the conference tables in the middle of the room.
Scott: all the cables on the conference table go into the middle down Inside the table.
Scott: So the table is clean, but then they have to come out the bottom of the table and they're all together.
Scott: But they need to get to the wall and the wall is far away from the table.
Scott: So you have this thing.
Scott: It's a raceway Is what it's called and it's basically just like a little rubber Thing with holes in it and all the cables can go into it on one side and out on the other.
Scott: But when you plop it on the floor, the bottom of it is flat.
Scott: So it lies flat on the floor and the top of it is rounded.
Scott: So if you have like a chair with wheels or a wheelchair Or any sort of thing that needs to you know, move around a person's foot You won't trip over it because it's just a rounded thing on the ground.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: like in our own the old house and beacon to get a cable where we needed because we we tried to run it through The walls but like the interior walls were insulated for some reason like that house was weird but We'd literally just crammed the cables into the corner of the room like kind of into the car where the carpet met the wall.
Rym: I just jammed it under there.
Rym: that actually works pretty well, especially in older houses that have carpet.
Scott: Yeah, or you can go up and over doorways or and unless it's a power cable You can just like run it under your computer the TV or around the desk, right?
Scott: That's the main situation with the desk Computer.
Scott: is it gonna be on the floor or is it gonna be up on the desk, right if it's down on the floor?
Scott: Your challenge is the cables that go from up to down right again up, you know Same as the TV situation right from your monitor to the bottom.
Scott: My advice is one if you had hands to the bottom However, you're gonna make those transitions, right?
Rym: Yeah, if you can do it get a power strip mounted on your side of the desk go into the other side of the desk.
Scott: So like for example on the right side of my desk, I've got like there's a scanner way over there But my computer is way on the left side of my test.
Scott: So I got like an extra long USB cable and need some sort of horizontal path for it to go without just sort of draping.
Scott: so they do make desks that have like channels in the back for things to go horizontally and what you can do then with those is take all the cables that are on the desk and send them into the channel and then Underneath the desk everything exits the horizontal channel where the computer is and goes straight
Rym: down.
Scott: Yep And that's a good way to go.
Rym: Now the the cheat mode is if you have a big enough space is you can just buy those.
Scott: I Can't hear him at all.
Rym: Oh you finally noticed It's got finally noticed that he couldn't hear that he was not hearing my audio.
Scott: Yeah, I finally noticed why I couldn't hear your audio.
Rym: Oh, you can hear me again.
Scott: Yeah, I I was trying to.
Scott: I Was trying to turn on the hockey game - I didn't want the hockey audio to interfere with the podcast.
Rym: Yeah, I can't earning because of the way I capture your voice.
Rym: I can't actually turn on the blab seal.
Rym: Yeah, I Had to.
Rym: I turned off my own headphones Realized I started to talk about cable channels and raceways and stuff and you just didn't?
Rym: you just kept talking.
Rym: So I was like, okay, I'll figure it out.
Scott: Yeah, I figured it out.
Scott: I turned off my own headphones.
Rym: But one thing you can buy if you got like an older desk that doesn't support any of this stuff as long as you have Space for it.
Rym: You can buy these like wire cages that you stick on the back of your desk and just cram everything into these wire cages.
Rym: the other pro tip is Get a power strip that you can mount and my like if you have it one of those desks that has like a top part In the bottom part.
Rym: seriously mount a power strip in the top part like behind where your monitor is gonna go if you have like because then you can Plug your monitor and anything else on your desk like speakers that needs power Into something also on top of the desk without having more cables going down
Scott: The power strip.
Scott: that is not on the floor again same as with the TV situation as a pro move It keeps the power cables from going right from high to low.
Scott: They could just you know, bring and then weigh the power, you know anything that combines Cables right.
Scott: you want to bring the Combining part as close to the things as you can and then just the one cable that comes out of the power strip is the one That makes the long run that where you know is unsightly.
Scott: but it's like it's not unsightly.
Scott: It's just one cable.
Scott: No big deal.
Rym: Yeah The other thing I found is that a cheap way even if you don't make a nice clean aesthetic do something to get your cables off the floor, even if they're still a mess.
Rym: that'll save you a Surprising amount of hassle.
Rym: as the years go on like more than you realize Cables that are touching the ground will accumulate dust and grime that is not actually that easy to get rid of Unless you crawl under there and like wipe them down periodically.
Scott: It's also hard to like vacuum like you ever.
Scott: take your vacuum and you go down there.
Scott: It's just cables.
Rym: You know vacuum are you trying to sweep and you know and they're touching the ground.
Rym: you might like sweep a cable out from under Your desk.
Rym: Oh fuck.
Rym: What was that even plugged into?
Scott: Yeah, so my cable game right now on my my desk is kind of good.
Scott: it's like the best I've had it but it's not perfect right because I've got some.
Scott: I got some speaker cables going up to the Ceiling way above to a high shelf and they're not hidden at all.
Scott: They're just you know, they're they're tied together, but it's still not that great.
Rym: I've got a horizontal while on my desk.
Scott: I've hidden everything but once you go underneath the desk, it's hideous, right?
Rym: So Emily's all that in a way, you know, she did under the desk.
Rym: She put her computer back Like straight behind where her feet are and turned it sideways.
Rym: So the glass and all the bling is pointing out and all the cables are just behind the computer where no one can see them.
Scott: No, maybe but yeah I think I'm gonna basically make a little plan.
Scott: figure out everything every wire like a little piece of paper.
Scott: Right the length I need for each one maybe buy some accessories, right and then yeah the play.
Rym: I guess that's the advice for all of this.
Rym: make a plan like literally sit down with a piece of paper.
Rym: Look at your desk.
Rym: Didn't like write down all the things that need to be plugged in and what they need to be plugged into and draw?
Rym: Where are these cables gonna run?
Rym: how do I want this to look like?
Rym: the more you plan in advance the more you can get the right tools to do the Job, and even if you do something kind of inelegant and hackish You'll at least have a plan going in and it'll turn out way better.
Scott: Yeah, and if you go online look at examples of what other people have done There isn't like one best way.
Scott: But there are people who have like setups where like you don't see any wires at all.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of those people are doing stuff like wireless mouse keyboard and you know.
Rym: So a lot of those people live in not New York, so they have a slightly bigger area to work with than I do.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: They have less constraints and whatnot or they can modify their walls.
Scott: Yes like that, but You can.
Scott: you can go really and get pretty fancy and learn from what other people have done with fancy setups.
Scott: and you know It's just like it's nice to not have wires everywhere.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: It just you know, just I even if you just personally you're just like I don't care.
Scott: It's like I don't understand that.
Scott: It's like it just feels better to have things be clean.
Scott: Yep
Rym: and then when I add something to my setup or change something it's like everything's a lot more modular and easy to work with which Scales up to and we won't talk about this very long because we've got on plenty of time Serious cable management which you can have a full-time job doing and it'll pay pretty well
Scott: right in in the data center.
Rym: that matter.
Rym: it's basically all the concerns like even aesthetics.
Rym: aesthetics actually matter to a degree in that kind of environment, but The key the real reason you organize the more serious professional stuff Is that you need to be able to very quickly fix something that went wrong add something remove something change something understand something and You might know where all the stupid cables on your computer go.
Rym: But if someone else comes over to your desk to try to deal with it like something breaks How well are they gonna do if your cables aren't organized?
Rym: now?
Rym: Imagine if that desk is a bunch of servers that are doing something important.
Scott: Yeah, it's like no one has to understand right how my TV is set up right and it's like only I do
Rym: like if I was on a long business trip and Emily had to like Use my computer to recable everything to make GeekNights happen like worst case scenario Unplug everything figure it out plug it all back in like, okay fine.
Scott: Yeah, it's not that many but if you're in a data center It's like you have to know every.
Scott: you know Some whoever's working there has to be able to tell what the hell's going on Even though they weren't involved in setting it up at all.
Rym: I don't think I ever touched what the things I used to set up when this was my job.
Rym: I would never touch again.
Rym: other people I never met would touch them if there was a problem.
Rym: So I had to make sure it was perfect.
Rym: and my advice to you professionally.
Rym: there is honestly one Learn from whoever you're working with.
Rym: if you work in a data center It'll be obvious immediately if they're doing a good job or a bad job with this.
Rym: if they're going doing a good job Figure out who made it a good job and learn from them and do whatever they're doing.
Rym: Like don't don't try to reinvent the wheel that the things you might think are an obvious good idea are not for reasons that you Won't know right away if they're doing a bad job.
Rym: You have to make a very important decision.
Rym: Do you care or not?
Rym: Because if you don't care don't touch it because as soon as you touch it or talk about it You're gonna be asked to fix it.
Rym: and that gets to my final piece of advice.
Rym: If I was tasked with setting up a new rack like a like, you know a standard computer rack fully loaded.
Rym: So there's like I don't know 20 40 units.
Rym: So say there's four switches and 20 computers and some other bullshit in there.
Rym: I would budget for myself if I was cabling that up and doing nice cable management for full working days Eight hours times four to do those cables, right?
Rym: Mmm, it takes a long time to do it, right and However long you think it's gonna take unless you have been doing it a long time just triple whatever you think and that's the estimate You should go with those four days
Scott: because are including the time it takes to plan it out, right?
Scott: It could be a situation usually where it's been planned out and you're just making many racks that are all the same.
Scott: Yeah, I'll take four days right but the the planning part, right?
Scott: It's like okay the rack will have this and this and this and this and the wires go here.
Rym: that will tell you some amount Of time and especially it depends on like yeah Are you just adding like rack?
Rym: 11 to a rat like they're just adding ten more computers of the same kind at the end of a row.
Rym: or is it like this is a bespoke rack or like you're doing your own thing or Did someone do a bad job and you've been asked to fix it.
Rym: that task is almost impossible.
Scott: Also, the one last thing about data centers, is that like, you know, there's messy data center obviously, right?
Scott: And then there's you look at one that looks really nice.
Scott: You know, you got all these networking cables.
Scott: They're going into a nice these channels in between the racks Right, and then they come out the bottom and then they're routed through the floorboards and they're you know standard good job data center.
Scott: It seems like every couple of years.
Scott: I'll see a picture of some data center that is doing something That's just like new and incredible and different with your cable man.
Rym: Well, cuz they're so much has changed.
Rym: like.
Scott: there are so many new developments in this area.
Rym: Yeah, like.
Rym: you'll have a whole row of racks that are all direct DC power.
Rym: There's no AC power fucking anywhere, right?
Scott: It's like and you know, that's not even that new.
Scott: so If you are in an existing data center, you only have to get it up to the good level.
Scott: That's all that you know, it's like.
Scott: is that how much better is that better level?
Scott: But if you're making a new data center Right from nothing you should go and find out the best and the fanciest one and then make sure the whole place Follows the same, you know stuff.
Scott: even if you're doing different things in different areas Consistency is key.
Rym: if you're like literally down to the level of This kind of tat like this kind of networking will be on green wires and this other kind will be on blue wires.
Rym: Like the more standards and like consistency you can make the better.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce Lately gee dry lily tennant gray tennant brain Chris Reimer Clinton Walton Graham Finch just like a dude guy.
Rym: Now go through the last year or so of podcasts and make Rym sing rain from New Zealand.
Rym: review mad bull.
Rym: 34 cowards Ryan Perrin Shervin von Horrell Taylor Braun you hold the key to my heart and a bunch of people who do not want me to Say their names.
Rym: the Rangers lost in overtime and now I leave you with Humid a great crime against the Galactic Federation On their watch.
Rym: a rebel fleet escaped and then they held hands.
Rym: What is your punishment?
Rym: Wait a sec.
Rym: Wait.
Rym: Wait, what did he?
Rym: What did this guy just say?
Rym: They let the rebel fleet escape and they held hands.
Rym: Sir they held hands.
Rym: these two held hands Immediately, what are you gonna do to dude?
Rym: Wait, dude, like you're gonna execute people for holding hands.
Scott: Yeah, what What kind of Empire is this man?
Rym: That's so stupid.
Scott: That's so so so stupid.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I don't like that one.
Scott: Can we get rid of it?
Rym: Sure, I I don't see why not.
Rym: You guys want me to get rid of that?
Rym: Yes, all right three two strike that down Done hold.
Rym: Yeah now you guys can hold.