Rym: It's Monday, May 10th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: We are talking about remote controls.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Got a little, uh, got an envelope.
Rym: I only check the mail, like, once every week, give or take, during COVID.
Rym: Like, I just don't go down there that often.
Rym: Uh, I got a jury summons.
Scott: Uh-oh.
Rym: At least I'm vaccinated now, by the time it'll come up, because I really didn't want to go to a courtroom if I wasn't vaccinated.
Scott: Well, that's how that goes.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But I got it basically right after I got my second shot.
Rym: Here it is.
Scott: As long as it's not in a faraway Long Island court.
Rym: Well, it's in any court in Queens, and I'm a standby phone juror.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: So, starting on Friday, I got to call that number, go to that website, and every day, I'll find out if I get to skip work or not, basically.
Scott: It seems you're a recurring theme on GeekNights.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I'm confident I will not serve.
Rym: Partly because, I mean, I've been kicked out every time I've ever been called up, and some of the default questions they ask usually just automatically exclude me.
Rym: Like, has a member of your direct family ever been a victim of a serious crime, or is any member of your family a member, like an emergency responder?
Scott: Well, it depends.
Scott: What if it's a civil court?
Scott: I was at a civil court when I, you know, last time.
Rym: One or two times ago, the question where they were like, "Nah, you're done," was, "Would you believe the testimony of a police officer over that of someone, like a private
Rym: citizen?".
Rym: And they did not like my answer to that one.
Scott: Anyway, so in technology, personal news, right, you know that I'm someone who has had, let's see, I have iPhone 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, and now I have 12.
Scott: I skipped all 8, 9, 10.
Scott: I skipped four iPhones.
Scott: So, I'm on my sixth iPhone, and the only phone, I see people with broken phones all over the place, and I'm always looking down on them, like, you know, "So clumsy, why aren't you taking care of your
Scott: phone?".
Scott: I never put my phone in a case, ever.
Rym: Oh, I see where this is going.
Scott: iPhone 3G I had in a case a little bit, but then I was like, "Fuck this," and I'd give up on phone cases, right?
Rym: Yeah, I still don't do cases, like, ever for phones.
Scott: Right.
Scott: What's the point?
Scott: You know, it's like they put so much effort into making the phone all strong, and then you put some ugly-ass plastic shield on it, it's like, okay.
Scott: It's like a tablecloth, right?
Scott: It's for old ladies.
Scott: The whole point is I bought a nice table to see the nice table.
Rym: Now you gotta cover the couch in plastic so it never gets stamped.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: You know, I don't believe in that.
Scott: And so far, that has been perfectly fine for me.
Scott: I have never, the only time an iPhone screen of mine ever broke was when the iPhone 5 screen broke, because it was in my bag, and I fell off my bike.
Scott: So it's like, not much I could do about that one.
Rym: I remember when your iPod mini broke.
Scott: Oh, well, that was already, I guess, a dead device at the time already, because I already had an iPod Nano.
Rym: Well, yeah, you say dead.
Rym: It worked, but you kept saying how invincible it was, and you were like, look.
Scott: It did see, it was very invincible, although I did have it in, like, a rubbery thing.
Scott: True.
Rym: You had it in a case.
Rym: But I just remember, you were like, it's invincible, and you dropped it onto a carpeted floor from a very low height, very gently, and when you picked it up, the screen was shattered.
Scott: No, I stepped on it a few times.
Scott: You did.
Rym: You poked at it with your foot.
Rym: You did not step on it.
Rym: You, like, gently tapped it with your foot.
Scott: It was not broken until I stepped on it.
Rym: Gently tapping.
Scott: It wasn't broken just from the dropping.
Rym: I think it was the combination of the carpet and the slight touch with a toe.
Scott: Maybe, but anyway, it was, I never imagined, right, having all these phones and not broken them, except for when I fell off my bike, right, that my Apple Watch screen could break.
Scott: I'd never seen someone walking around with a broken Apple Watch.
Scott: It's like, it just didn't conceive, I had no idea that that was even a possibility, right?
Scott: Like, how would that happen?
Scott: So the other, you know, just the other day I finished, I'm using it as like, you know, a heart rate monitor when I ride my bike to nowhere in the morning.
Scott: Then I go and take a shower, and I take it off before I go in the shower, and I just drop it from, like, wrist height.
Scott: It lands on the bathroom floor, and sure enough, the screen on the Apple Watch breaks, and I'm just like, what the fuck?
Scott: I didn't even know that could happen.
Scott: The thing's pretty old already.
Rym: I broke a watch in a mountain biking accident once as a kid.
Rym: I just, like, smashed it on a tree.
Scott: Yeah, so the thing still works, right?
Scott: Everything about it works.
Scott: The screen still displays.
Scott: The only problem is that with the screen shattered, obviously pieces of glass chip off of it.
Scott: That's not great.
Scott: Obviously, waterproofness is gone entirely.
Scott: I'm not here.
Scott: But only the top right of the screen is still sensitive to touch.
Scott: The rest of it is sort of not, so you can't, like, use it.
Rym: That's what happened when my old, god, this was an ancient, ancient Android device.
Rym: But I was traveling, and there was a tiny crack on the screen that had been there forever.
Rym: that, like, had been there for over a year, but the phone was fine.
Rym: But I guess air pressure flying something, one day, like, the crack just expanded a little bit.
Rym: Suddenly, like, on its own, like, it made a noise, and then the entire touchscreen didn't work anymore, except for a tiny part of the top right of the screen.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, the thing is that I don't have a lot of great options here, right?
Scott: So my ideal would be, like, hey, this is an iPhone iWatch 3, the LTE one.
Scott: And apparently, they still sell the iWatch 3, but they only sell the Wi-Fi one, Apple at least, right?
Scott: And apparently, that one, you shouldn't buy it, because they didn't tell, I don't know if this was public information, at least I didn't learn it until recently, but the LTE version, whether you use the LTE or not, has more memory than the Wi-Fi only one.
Scott: And the Wi-Fi only one has so little memory that you have to, if you want to update the watchOS, you have to erase the whole watch, then update the iOS, then reinstall all your apps, right?
Scott: The LTE one has enough memory that you don't have to do that, which is why, when I read the article, I was like, this is full of shit, I can just update my watch just fine, this person doesn't know what they're talking about, and then at the end, they're like, actually, the LTE one is just fine, and I'm like, oh.
Scott: So you can't buy the iWatch 3 LTE unless you buy, like, a used one on eBay.
Scott: So I can't just replace my watch.
Rym: Alright, just get, like, one of the newest iWatches.
Scott: You could do that, I would do that, in fact, but they come out with new Apple watches every September, and it is currently May.
Scott: If it was, like, October, I'd be like, oh, perfect, right?
Scott: I'll just buy the new one.
Rym: You could just not have a watch until September.
Scott: That's an option as well.
Rym: I mean, how much are you going to be going out in the foreseeable future?
Rym: Like, you can just Strava with the phone.
Scott: You can use it for a lot of stuff, just in the house, though, right?
Scott: Like, timing, cooking things, controlling Spotify.
Rym: For whatever reason, I don't use my watch for any of that stuff in the house.
Scott: Yeah, because your watch doesn't do any of that stuff.
Rym: It does do all that stuff, I just don't bother, I just do it on my phone.
Scott: Well, the Apple Watch does all that stuff.
Rym: Like, if I want to change the volume on the Windows or Futs with anything, I just open whatever app on my phone and do it.
Scott: Apple Watch is faster and easier to do all those things.
Rym: I don't wear a watch if I'm home.
Rym: I don't even know where my smartwatch is because I took it off at the start of COVID, and I'd never put it back on.
Scott: Well, maybe if it was more useful and powerful, we would wear it all the time.
Scott: Regardless.
Rym: I'm saying, in my house, I don't want to wear a watch.
Rym: The whole point of the watch is I don't have to get my phone out of my pocket when I'm, like, out and about in the world.
Scott: Yeah, I don't have to get my phone out of my pocket, even in the house.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, so there's not a lot of great options.
Scott: To repair it, Apple wants, like, $100 less than the cost of buying, like, a cheapy Apple Watch, right?
Scott: It's, like, $100 more than a used one.
Scott: Every option is, like, either wasteful or economically bad.
Scott: So, we'll see.
Scott: I'm basically going to send it into the Apple repair place, which doesn't commit you to paying money.
Scott: You get, like, a quote eventually.
Scott: They gave you a pre-quote.
Scott: The pre-quote was high.
Rym: I feel like the quote you get back is going to be equal to or greater than the pre-quote.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: But at least for free, I can find out.
Rym: I would bet you money.
Rym: that is the case.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Scott: For free, I can send it in to get the quote and then decide from there.
Scott: But, you know, I just want to point out that for a company that is at the last few keynotes has been doing so much bragging about their environmentally friendliness, right?
Scott: And, you know, also is really bad about the right to repair and is fighting it everywhere and doesn't want third-party repair services to exist.
Scott: And meanwhile, the third-party repair service for, like, an iPhone screen is significantly cheaper than the Apple one, but the Apple Watch repair service from a third party was not that much cheaper than the Apple repair quote.
Scott: I think it was, like, $180 versus, like, $220 or something.
Scott: It was a $40 difference.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Regardless, they, you know, they should be like, hey, if you want to be better for the environment, here's a perfectly good watch that just happened to get dropped on the floor.
Scott: If you would make your repair cost cheaper and make battery replacement cheaper, that would be really helpful.
Scott: You know, in a time when chips are in, you know, high demand, low supply, probably a good idea to keep existing chips operating.
Scott: There's nothing wrong with them.
Rym: Well, I think part of the issue is that a tightly packed, embedded device that's waterproof and has touch screens on it, it's very hard to make that easily repairable.
Scott: Well, you should, you know, you're the one making it.
Scott: Make it better.
Scott: Make it easier to repair.
Rym: There might not be a better that's better enough to matter to make that cost cheaper.
Scott: Well, and I also found out, I didn't realize this, but, you know, it's something I guess wouldn't have mattered to me until now that I realized that the screen can break.
Scott: If you buy, the Apple Watch actually comes in three different materials.
Scott: I don't know, maybe four.
Scott: I don't know if they still have the ceramic choice available, but they have aluminum, the cheapy one, stainless steel, and then titanium, right?
Scott: If you get stainless steel or titanium, which are hundreds of dollars more than aluminum, you get a different, the screen is made of a different, better glass.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Maybe that's not a problem.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So of course I have the cheapy aluminum, which I'd never, why would I, you know, but now I might consider, you know, if I end up getting a new one, maybe I will pay more.
Scott: It's like, normally I would just been like, fuck that aluminum.
Scott: But now it's like, well, maybe the stainless steel one.
Rym: So in some actual news, the whole Apple fight with everybody, like there's a bunch of Apple lawsuits and fights going on right now.
Rym: We've talked about several of them.
Scott: It's mostly the Apple.
Scott: epic is going to keep feeding us news for the next few months.
Rym: That's the big one.
Rym: Like the second biggest one is probably the lawsuit over purchasing things on iTunes.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But the Apple and Epic game store one is.
Rym: it covers so many areas and it's so big that no matter how it falls, the precedent that this case sets is going to be a big deal.
Rym: Pretty much no matter what happens, like there's no way for like the entire industry, not just the games industry, but the, the concept of an app store to come out of this unscathed and unchanged.
Rym: So there's a bunch of recent developments that are actually interesting enough to where we probably should talk about them because Apple is making a lot of interesting points in court.
Rym: And because this is all public, like you can go read what's happening in this court case.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, they're trying to appeal to the, to the judge, right?
Scott: With this one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, or I don't know if there's a jury or not, but basically what happened was is they're like, look, you know, that epic store on the epic store.
Scott: You can buy, you can download the itch IO store, right?
Scott: And in the itch IO store, there's porn games.
Scott: It's like, of course there is.
Rym: So I can download something called a web browser in the Apple store and in that web browser, there is in fact a lot of pornography.
Scott: There is in fact, it's just out there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Um, but yeah, it's like that's, Apple is using that as like a point they're trying to make.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that is, I think one of Apple's, you know, for as good as Apple is on a lot of issues, notably privacy, right?
Scott: Being like the one issue they're good on, they've been really bad about this issue right now.
Scott: Of course we always say, and I still agree with this wholly that it's like, yeah, you're a private, the own thing, right?
Scott: You don't have to respect freedom of speech.
Scott: You can choose, right?
Scott: What, you know, you want to have on your platform.
Scott: If Apple doesn't want to have porn on the Apple store, that's up to them.
Scott: They don't, they don't have to, right?
Scott: They can make whatever rules that they want.
Rym: And you know, uh, the invisible hand of the market and consumer preferences and et cetera will decide if that was a good idea or not.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: Uh, capitalism.
Scott: Nice.
Scott: But, uh, I just disagree.
Scott: I think their rules are bad rules, right?
Rym: Well, Apple in particular has done a lot of just sort of semi-random arbitrary things over the years, mostly under the guise of maintaining a wholesome, uh, reputation.
Rym: Uh, like I remember for a while back, despite the fact that cannabis is legal in a whole bunch of states, Apple blocked and removed pretty much all the apps that cannabis nerds used to configure their fancy vaporizing devices.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I know some of it might have to do with, you know, Apple has their little ad thing.
Scott: Like you can use the official Apple ad thing when you make an app.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Uh, and then, you know, the Apple wants to keep all the apps advertiser friendly, right?
Scott: Um, you know, and advertisers, you know, again, the, you know, the problem stems with them not wanting to, it's like, why don't you want your Coca-Cola ad next to some porn?
Scott: What's the wrong with that?
Scott: What's your problem?
Rym: Yeah, of course.
Rym: Turn that around.
Rym: What about people who don't want their ad next to some right wing nut shop?
Scott: That's right.
Rym: The real problem there is that ad networks are fundamentally, it's impossible to make one that's ethical and that has reasonable rules because ad networks dissenter, like they separate who is buying an ad from where the ad is placed and they commodify the ads.
Rym: They make them fungible and that makes a market that's very murky and prune to abuse and disagreement.
Rym: It's not like I say, I want my ad to appear on this app, which is how things used to work in the old days.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Scott: Anyway, uh, but yeah, this is, you know, bringing up all the usual arguments you have, you know, of, you know, hey, you should be like, what's wrong with fricking sex?
Scott: Right.
Scott: What do you have against my completely not offensive, just sexually explicit game?
Scott: What's wrong with that?
Rym: And it's not clear what's wrong with it, according to Apple, because they seem to have brought this up in court just to disgust everyone and try to like win over the judge and like make a big deal about how offensive all this itch.io stuff is.
Scott: Yeah, well, Epic, you know, did, I think, an okay job of explaining what itch.io actually is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which is like, hey, it's actually an amazing platform that supports indie developers.
Scott: It's very developer friendly, gives developers a great cut.
Scott: But itch.io, you know, with their little bundle for racial justice, gave more money than Apple or anyone did.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, social justice things over the...
Rym: Also, there's a big conflation in this kind of conversation where a lot of people, especially old crappy people, will argue that things are offensive or sexual when in fact they're just LGBT content.
Scott: Well, I think that's the thing that's happened a lot.
Scott: is that, you know, LGBT stuff, you know, is, you know, LGBT is an identity that is around sexuality.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So LGBT content is, you know, not always sexually explicit, but is, you know, always it's sexual content by nature.
Rym: Well, you also get the situation where straight sexual content is much more tolerated on larger platforms than sexual content that is LGBT is tolerated.
Scott: So there's a huge confluence of all these factors.
Scott: Historically, you'd have like a movie, right, and the movie with like, you know, a dude kissing, you know, a lady, right, it's two straight people kissing, would be like PG.
Scott: But if it was two dudes kissing and if you made this movie in like 1980 and it had two dudes kissing, that would have been like rated R or some shit.
Rym: RPS said this in terms of the whole topic.
Rym: Apple in court, I'm quoting the article, made it sound like the excellent indie focused store is an evil demon app that sells games "so offensive they couldn't possibly speak about them in
Rym: court.".
Scott: Well, there are, in fact, some, many games that are sold on itch.io, some of which are horrific and some of which are not horrific, but would be horrific to a non-internet person, which I presume a judge is likely to be.
Scott: You know, so you tell someone about, you know, some game that's actually not offensive and doesn't contain anything bad.
Scott: It's just like a really sexy game that's, you know, very gay or furry or something.
Scott: And that might freak out some judge.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like, but yeah, there is also stuff like, you know, they did.
Scott: I think they found like the most explicit thing they could find, like sister lust or something.
Scott: I tried to search on itch.io for a sister lust and I couldn't find, I couldn't figure out which thing they were talking about, but there was definitely some stuff there that, you know, well, this is like, hey, if you don't want it, don't buy it.
Scott: You got parental controls on your phone, you know, what the hell?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And also, like, don't put it in your app store, like directly, like, sure.
Rym: But if there's another app store, you can't use your monopoly powers to keep that app store away, even if that app store itself has a different policy from you.
Rym: We do need a diverse ecosystem of places to be able to.
Scott: And this is still getting away from the core issue, which is like, hey, you know, people have to use the Apple App Store, they have to use the Apple payment thing, right?
Scott: That's the issue.
Scott: It's like, it doesn't matter what the content is.
Scott: It's like, you know, you're making everyone use your payment.
Scott: You can't just, you can't just use their credit card and give the money directly to someone else.
Scott: You're taking a 30% cut of everyone's money, no matter what they do.
Scott: It's like, well, they might do porn.
Scott: Oh, OK.
Scott: And so you don't want to collect the money for them doing porn?
Scott: I know.
Scott: OK, well, then let them collect all the money for their part.
Rym: But it almost seems like they're bringing this up just to try to turn the tide of public and legal opinion against the Epic Games Store's argument.
Scott: It's typical lawyer, you know, typical lawyer strategy, right?
Scott: What you do in a courtroom.
Scott: In related news, Steam, which has went from being anti-porn to less anti-porn.
Rym: But still, Steam has the same problem.
Rym: Apple does.
Rym: Their rules are not transparent and are applied semi-randomly.
Rym: Two identical games could be released.
Rym: One will be banned.
Rym: One's OK.
Rym: And no one can explain why.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So Steam is allowing, you know, since the news a while ago, right, some more sexual content that some would consider pornography, which is good.
Scott: You know, you can block it and whatever.
Scott: It's perfectly fine.
Scott: There's plenty of it in the Steam store if you want it.
Scott: But there are rules around exactly what is and isn't allowed.
Scott: Because they're not just a free-for-all on Steam, right?
Scott: They have this line, but the line is very blurry.
Scott: And there's a recent case where these people have made these VR porn games/experiences in which they have scanned in the bodies of actual porn actors.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And replicated them in VR.
Scott: So it's not like a video of a real person, but it's like sort of like Mortal Kombat 2, right?
Scott: It's like mocap and you got they scan the person's body.
Scott: So it's exactly the 3D model matches the actual real person, probably with some touching up.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: And Valve rejected those with somewhat vague messages.
Rym: As they do.
Rym: Valve is super vague about anything related to this.
Rym: Like, no one can figure out what their rules actually are.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like if you've got rules, right, and you want to draw a line, it's like, OK, but you need to, you know, be explicit, explicit about where your line is.
Scott: The developers, you know, someone who works on a game and is going to sell it, right, you know, and there they announce like, oh, I'm going to release my game on Steam.
Scott: They got to know well in advance, 100 percent certainty whether their game will or will not be allowed on Steam.
Rym: Especially when there's so few marketplaces to sell these things at scale.
Rym: Thus, every marketplace that's large enough has a pseudo monopoly by itself.
Scott: Even if you look at the Switch eShop, there's plenty of, you know, sort of games in there these days.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like, you know, it's like you can have a line.
Scott: You know, I said I totally believe that, you know, any private, you know, platform has an absolute right to decide what they are and aren't going to allow.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, A, I might disagree that they're allowing or disallowing the right things.
Scott: And B, you need to make it clear to users and, you know, anyone you interact with what your rules are.
Scott: You can't have something vague because that's just being a dick.
Rym: You can't get away with being a dick, the game.
Rym: You can't get away with it because these vague rules, if you're going to ban something, you should almost be required if you're a big enough platform.
Scott: Absolutely.
Rym: To explicitly state why in detail and your rules will get more and more complex as time goes on.
Rym: You can't get away with doing what our legal system has done for so long with porn of saying, you know, we'll know it when we see it because that is right for abuse.
Scott: If you can't cite your rule and write a rule explicit enough to explain to me why it's banned, you should be legally required to accept it.
Rym: At least if a platform is big enough.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If your mastery of the English language is not strong enough to carve out a rule that fits, then you're going to have to make your rule broader or less broad.
Scott: And if I can find examples of things on your platform that are on the wrong side of the rules, you need to be forced to either adjust your rules or remove or allow.
Scott: People should be able to challenge, right?
Scott: Even if it's not my game, like if I see a game on Steam that I think breaks Steam rules, I should be able to challenge that and be like, hey, you're selling a game that breaks your own rules, even though it has nothing to do with me.
Rym: The logical conclusion of all this is it leads to a situation a lot like why certain restaurants appear in airports and special protected places.
Rym: Because you almost get to a point to where the experts who know how to navigate the arbitrary, capricious, and sometimes entirely random rules of a platform like Steam can themselves be the ones who sneak the content in that other people can't get very similar content in.
Rym: So you almost have a market for people who can navigate the Byzantine system.
Rym: And that is definitely a dark pattern on any platform where it occurs.
Scott: Steam, get your rules in order, and also if anyone wants, you know, the VR porn apparently is getting way better these days.
Rym: So in actually similar news, there was a story, this was back in February, I just didn't get a chance to talk about it, but Facebook has a system that will reject ads that might be offensive or break one of their own rules for advertising, which, as you can guess, are similarly arbitrary.
Rym: But Facebook's automated system to flag advertisements as being allowed or not has generally disallowed any ads about accessible clothing and accessible fashion.
Rym: Like fashion for people in wheelchairs.
Rym: It has been a specific problem where companies that sell jeans that are designed for someone who's sitting in a wheelchair, the same products, the ad would be put up on Facebook, the ad with the woman standing is totally okay, the ad with the woman wearing the same clothes in a wheelchair gets rejected by the system.
Rym: And the system, because it's machine learning driven, doesn't say specifically what the problem is.
Rym: And these companies who try to make these kinds of products are stuck just trying to navigate these arbitrary and random "rules" that no one will help them with.
Rym: These inexplicable systems, systems that cannot explain the decisions they make, are dangerous to society.
Scott: I agree.
Rym: Granted.
Rym: Arguably, how many humans can actually explain to a suitable degree why they've made a particular decision?
Scott: I ask that question of lots of people a lot of the time.
Scott: I'm constantly asking.
Scott: Someone will say, "I like
Scott: this."
Scott: And I'll say, "Why do you like
Scott: that?".
Scott: People don't know.
Scott: People don't know themselves.
Scott: I'm not saying I know myself, but I'm always at least attempting and introspecting.
Scott: Why did I do that?
Scott: Why do I like this and not that?
Scott: Why didn't I do that the other day?
Scott: I'm always meta thinking about everything, but meta thinking about myself, whether I'm successful or not is another story, but at least attempting.
Scott: If you ask me a question like, "Why do you like
Scott: that?"
Scott: I can at least try to answer it.
Scott: Whereas I find a lot of other people, you ask them a question like that, like, "Why did you do
Scott: that?"
Scott: "Why do you like that and not
Scott: that?".
Scott: All those sort of self-introspective questions.
Scott: I find a lot of people just have a hard time answering them or they just can't even give an answer.
Scott: I just do like that commercial.
Rym: So is it not then possibly hypocritical to say that humans should be making those decisions if arguably humans are not more explicable than some machine learning system?
Scott: I think that whether you have a machine learning system or an algorithm or a person making a decision, I think it doesn't matter.
Scott: I think you just have to provide an explanation of a decision.
Scott: If you can explain the decision, it doesn't matter how you arrived at it, but if you can't provide the reasoning behind it, then even if it was a good decision, you couldn't provide reasoning, so get bent.
Rym: I would also argue that even though we can't really explain humans, because granted, if human decision-making were truly explicable, maybe we've proven we don't have free will and all sorts of other weird consequences happen.
Scott: I mean, even if you're wrong about why you decided.
Rym: Well, at least being wrong, you can then be challenged on the specific merits of an individual case.
Scott: Right, at least tell me what your thought process was, even if it was a wrong thought process.
Rym: That's actually kind of how the law works.
Rym: That's why we have this concept of precedent generally, because it's the idea that, all right, here's a hundred similar problems and the decisions that were made for those hundred problems.
Rym: Now we're looking at a new problem.
Rym: Can we inform how we should deal with this problem by how it was done before, or should we change the rules for some arbitrary reason?
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you have a machine learning thing that is making that sort of decision that affects real people in that way, you should have to keep the complete logs of every single decision it made, and then at least you can show me, like, why did the machine learning qualify this as rejected?
Scott: What was its path it took through its code to arrive at that?
Scott: Present that to me as proof somehow.
Rym: So, oh, god, Meat Lust.
Rym: Meat Lust is not a porn game, don't worry, but we, uh...
Scott: When I was searching for the Sisterly Lust, I'd randomly on itch.io found a game in the search results called Meat Lust, and it looks just like a real simple Quake-ish kind of thing.
Rym: Quake Half-Life, it looks Half-Life 1-esque.
Scott: I don't know if this is good, I just saw a page on itch for it when searching for something else for the show.
Scott: Alright, so one last tiny news here.
Scott: So, I don't know how many people used Windows way back in the day, or were even alive then, but Windows and icons are a thing.
Scott: Back in the Windows 3.1 in 95 days, changing your icons was actually a big thing, because, like, you didn't even have a start menu, even in Windows 3.1, you didn't really have the start menu.
Scott: And you would use, like, desktop icons a lot, and you would customize them, and, you know, I remember I had, like... In college, I would, like, you know, I had to do 10 of desktop once, I had Asumanga.io desktop once, right?
Scott: You'd change your icons and your Winamp skins, all that sort of stuff that people don't do anymore these days.
Scott: People just change their phone wallpaper, and then you can't change your phone icons too much.
Scott: But anyway, changing Windows icons was a thing, now people seem like they don't bother.
Scott: But it's, all that feature is still there.
Scott: It's the same feature it's been since Windows 3.1.
Scott: Windows allows you to embed icons, you can have them just sitting around as their own file, like ICO files, or I don't know if you can use pings or JPEGs these days, but... You can just have ICO files lying around, but also, .exe files and .dll files can just sort of, I don't know exactly the format, because I don't do Windows, you know, local, you know, native app programming.
Scott: But you can just have icons, like, bundled, you can have a .dll, it has a bunch of code libraries, and also a pile of icons just, like, in there.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And then when you go in Windows, if you right-click on, like, a shortcut, and you go to an .exe or something, like, change icon, you can browse to any icon file .exe or .dll on your whole computer, and if there's icons there, you can choose to use that icon instead of the one that is chosen for itself.
Scott: Obviously, if an .exe has an icon in it, or icons, whichever one is, like, the primary one is sort of, like, the default, right, for that app, that's why the Photoshop icon is, you know, the Photoshop logo and such.
Scott: But yeah, so, Windows, since Windows 95, right, you've had this sort of .dll, the Shell32 .dll that has had all these icons in it, the ones that you know and love, the ones that looks like a document, the one that looks like a folder, the one that looks like a computer, the globe with the sort of ring around it, you know, the microchip, the printer, all these same icons are in there, and they're still used in various places around the system.
Scott: To this day, those icons haven't been changed.
Scott: They're the same Windows 95 icons.
Scott: Maybe the resolution increased, but the actual art of the icon has not changed since 26 years.
Scott: It's a long time.
Rym: I think the article mentions since Bill Clinton was in his first term.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, the news is that in an upcoming Windows version, you know, if you're using one of those Windows 10, like, early release program things, whatever, you probably have these icons already.
Scott: But yeah, coming in some time, perhaps, like, October-ish, later this year, the Windows Update, the big Windows Update, will change those icons that have been unchanged to something slightly newer.
Scott: There'll still be some floppy disks in there and some outdated stuff, but some other outdated stuff will be gone.
Scott: So, that will be interesting.
Rym: It's interesting how one of the biggest changes is all the things that were kind of at this three-quarter angle are now facing the user directly.
Rym: Like, I feel like that's a specific stylistic change they've made.
Scott: Well, that was a stylistic change that they made already, I think, in Windows with a bunch of other things, and now they're just sort of bringing it in line, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Go to the article.
Rym: You can see the examples of, like, a bunch of them and exactly what the previous one was, what the new one is.
Rym: You'll see what we mean.
Scott: Yeah, but that's still, it's, like, a huge kind of thing that, like, these symbols that have been, like, set in stone for 26 years will just be changed, right?
Scott: And the fact that you can just change them, like, it's, like, we have symbols out in public, like, say, let's, you know, when you're driving, they'll be, like, interstate signs.
Scott: Like, Garden State Parkway has that circle, right?
Scott: It's, like, the logo of the Garden State Parkway.
Scott: It's, like, you really can't change that easily.
Scott: You know how much stuff you would have to do to change that if they decided they wanted New Jersey?
Rym: Of course, I would argue it's also almost moot because, one, no one who uses Windows changes the icon of anything anymore.
Scott: I'm just saying, but those icons still show up in places.
Rym: True, but, two, no one uses Windows anymore except at work or if they're a professional.
Scott: Right, but to change a symbol, like, a publicly known symbol like these icons are, right, in most places in society, in the physical world, is basically impossible.
Scott: It's, like, you're stuck with whatever they picked in 1950-something, right?
Scott: Whatever your country was made.
Scott: But these icons, because they're software, they can actually be changed.
Rym: Well, I mean, think about it.
Rym: To this day, we have fast-forward and rewind.
Rym: Like, that won't change.
Rym: That'll never change.
Scott: Yeah, you know.
Rym: And last, we'll talk about this briefly, but we'll see how this all progresses.
Rym: If you didn't notice, there was actually a significant cyber attack in the U.S.
Rym: against a gas pipeline to the point that it is shut down.
Rym: And the President declared a local regional state of emergency because we can't actually distribute petroleum distillates.
Rym: Fuel prices are slowly rising, but kind of like the canal situation in the Suez, the longer this thing is down, the worse it could get as time goes on.
Rym: Because as much as we want to get away from a fossil fuel society, especially in the Northeast, a lot of things like heating and water stuff are driven by gas.
Rym: Like, not even just cars.
Scott: Yeah, so there's a bunch of things.
Scott: It's like, okay, great, we shut down this pipeline.
Scott: If it shuts down forever, it seems great.
Scott: But then you think about it.
Scott: Well, short term, we're in the summer now, but as soon as it becomes winter, if it's not fixed, a lot of people will just be fucking cold and they could die.
Scott: People will die.
Rym: Or like a lot of food still gets delivered with trucks that need regular old gas in their tanks.
Rym: Like, we don't have fully electric fleets everywhere delivering random bread to your house.
Rym: But the attack appears to be from Russia, but also appears to be a pretty simplistic, uh, it's just a ransomware attack that just happened to hit the infrastructure.
Rym: Like, it's not clear if this was targeted or not.
Rym: It's just a normal-ass, like, typical ransomware.
Scott: Yeah, the typical pattern these days, and I actually linked in our forum a story about a typical security thing that happened quite along these lines, I'm guessing, at a research institute, like a thing in Europe somewhere.
Scott: And basically what happened in that situation, not the pipeline situation, is that there was a student and they wanted, there was some visualization software that they use in the lab and they didn't own it.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So they wanted to, they wanted to get their own copy.
Scott: And then they saw that it was hundreds of dollars a month.
Scott: So they pirated it.
Scott: And of course, the pirated software they got was actually, you know, bad.
Scott: Because it's the year of our Lord 2021.
Rym: All pirated software is full of malware.
Rym: You don't have a hookup.
Rym: You don't know better and you can't tell.
Scott: And then not, now the Windows Defender blocked it, but then the student, I guess, had the wrong permissions and was able to disable the Windows Defender and install it anyway.
Scott: And then it was a ransomware and they lost like a week's worth of data to the ransomware.
Scott: And basically, but the thing that happened was after the ransomware activated.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it didn't, it didn't actually like do anything right away.
Scott: But instead, usually the pattern is most likely that someone is out there trying to like distribute, you know, these, these, you know, attacks.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And when they catch someone, they don't, you know, attack them themselves.
Scott: They sell, they're like, Hey, I've got SSH access to this server.
Scott: You know, anyone out there want to pay me money and I will give you the access and you can do what you want to do.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, Hey, I've hacked into this oil pipeline.
Scott: Who wants to attack it?
Scott: Anybody?
Scott: How much will you pay?
Scott: You know, a hundred dollars, a thousand dollars, a million dollars.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Who wants it?
Scott: And then they take their money.
Scott: And then the other person, well, they obviously were willing to pay money.
Scott: They want to do damage and they do the damage.
Scott: Or they're hoping they can get more of right ransoming than they can buy, you know, or who knows.
Rym: Now, the fascinating part is we don't know yet exactly how they got into this.
Rym: Like, read the articles, like go.
Scott: Probably a poorly secured Windows computer and someone doing something foolish.
Rym: Well, it seems like this is probably the same thing that happened when that water system got hacked.
Rym: Someone had a team viewer or a Microsoft remote desktop because they're working from home during covid.
Rym: And there wasn't a good way to do that.
Rym: So the the people who run this thing just hacked something together.
Rym: And there's a lot of easily guessable or easily compromised remote desktop ways to get to otherwise completely unsecure systems that never had remote access capabilities.
Scott: The computers that control a pipeline should be air gats, period.
Rym: Remember the movie Mission Impossible, where they had to break into a building to get to the sensitive computer because it was not connected to the Internet?
Rym: That's real.
Rym: And that needs to happen.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Every computer that controls essential infrastructure that is of national security importance should have no connection to the Internet and should be never allowed to connect to the Internet ever under any circumstance.
Rym: And if you need to give someone remote access to do a job, that has to be an extremely hardened, special means of access.
Scott: No, there's a real easy way to do it, actually.
Scott: Let's say there's an oil expert.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they need to remote access to the computers at the oil place.
Scott: Well, you just and they can't get there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: For some reason, they're at a wedding.
Scott: You just have another person.
Rym: Well, the situation here is this is no one who is going to these places because of Covid.
Scott: Obviously, you need to have one person there.
Scott: And then even if it's just a person who doesn't even know anything about the oil pipeline, they just know that they just know how to use a mouse and a keyboard and to read the screen English.
Scott: They can call the oil expert on the phone, take pictures of the screen with their phone and like, tell me what to click on, dude.
Scott: You know, there are.
Rym: there are ways to make secure remote access to certain kinds of systems.
Rym: But you'd probably even then want that secure remote access to go to a system that itself is, even if not fully air gapped, at least has some sort of gap between the production systems that do the thing.
Scott: You could even have them on a network.
Scott: That's just not the Internet.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Their own separate network.
Scott: You could network together like I guess it would make it a higher profile target itself.
Scott: But if you network, say, like two oil pipelines together, as long as one of the two oil pipelines has a person added, they can handle both of them.
Rym: That's how a lot of very secure things are in the world is?
Rym: there are private circuits that connect data centers or cages within data centers directly.
Scott: As long as there's no Internet access, that's not too bad.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It's like, you know, it's better than a team viewer with a default password that's easily guessed that connects to a like Windows box that doesn't even have a password on it.
Scott: The point is, is that never pirate software in the year 2021 because it's just a security problem.
Scott: And yeah.
Scott: And also that, you know, the situations like this.
Scott: Both of these situations are security problems caused by people not willing to spend money.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You weren't willing to spend the money to hire someone to actually go to the oil pipe.
Scott: But you weren't willing to buy your student the expensive software license, the software license, the company that makes the software was overcharging for hundreds of dollars a month for some, you know, visualizations.
Scott: Well, so I remember an RIT as an example, though.
Rym: While the software I needed to do a bunch of my labs was expensive software, the school provided it in labs.
Rym: The only reason I pirated that software is that I did not want to have to go to the lab.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like.
Scott: there's, you know, there's the level of, yes, security best practices were not being followed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, but if they were being followed, that would have created a huge hassle and problems.
Scott: The student wouldn't have had the software to do their work.
Scott: The person, you know, at the oil pipeline would have had to gone in and risk their life or something.
Rym: But maybe an oil pipeline is important enough to where you should spend the money to secure it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If people not spending, if you spend the money right to provide people with what they need, then you not only help people, but you also, you know, shore up your security.
Scott: If people are have food, you ever heard the term food security?
Scott: You're going to have less people doing crimes.
Scott: You're helping out security of like the grocery store by giving out free food.
Scott: Right.
Scott: To people who are hungry.
Scott: You think you're hurting the grocery store by giving out free food.
Scott: It's like because you're competing with the grocery store.
Scott: It's like, no, you know, less starving people means people aren't robbing the grocery store.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Or you've got someone who has a very sensitive security job.
Rym: Make sure they're not struggling and poor because the poorer and more struggling they are, the more temptation there is to game the system in some way.
Rym: They're more compromise-able by the nature of society and the nature of humans.
Rym: Just got to have a hustle and you got to survive.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So I think, you know, the lack of support for the, you know, the small, the laborer, right, is definitely hurting the, you know, the wealthy person in terms of causing them security problems.
Scott: Right.
Scott: By not paying people.
Scott: So we're going to see more and more of that.
Scott: Not that we haven't seen a ton of it already.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: I found this randomly, like literally randomly, I think because I was watching a lot of DMX videos and independently I'd been watching a lot of music theory videos, a few of which had been focused on David Bowie.
Rym: And I saw a video that was titled DMX Meets David Bowie.
Rym: And it was about four minutes long.
Rym: And it looked and felt like it was going to be a mashup, like some sort of song.
Scott: That's what I'm imagining it's going to be.
Rym: That's what I expected.
Scott: So I clicked on it.
Scott: You're saying it's not a mashup?
Rym: So it ends up having a mashup song at the end.
Rym: It's actually a comedy skit that is David Bowie being woken up in his house by DMX, who wants to hang out and play video games and board games.
Rym: And both of them, it's like they use a bunch of interview audio from David Bowie being interviewed and a bunch of DMX singing audio and they cut together dialogue.
Rym: And it's like a whole episode of a sitcom where David Bowie and DMX are friends and play games together.
Scott: Well, rest in peace to those two legends.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: And at the end, it turns it like it's actually legitimately funny.
Rym: It surprised me at how funny and simultaneously wholesome it is.
Rym: Like what it is is like really wholesome.
Rym: And then at the end, they sing a duet together and it's actually pretty touching.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I was just surprised at how good this thing was.
Scott: I got a very Rym thing of the day.
Scott: This is ThemeParkBrochures.net.
Rym: Oh, but why would I want anything but Cedar Point or...
Scott: They got that on there.
Scott: Of course they got that on there.
Scott: So this website has two things, basically.
Scott: It's very, it seems like it's early days.
Scott: I don't know how long the site has been around, but it doesn't have, it has a lot of content, enough to be interesting, but they're looking for more.
Scott: So if you've ever been on vacation, at least in the United States, I don't know about other countries, if you're in a vacation place, like a tourist town and you're in like a hotel, even in New York City, you'll see these.
Scott: You go into a hotel and in the front of the hotel, there'll be like this little stand or at a rest stop on the highway.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: A highway rest stop or diner off of a freeway.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: It'll be in the foyer of the diner.
Scott: It's a little wooden stand and it'll be full of tri-fold brochures that are just advertisements for all the things in the area.
Rym: Like, "Hey, the world's biggest pile of dung is over here.
Rym: Two miles that way.
Rym: Exit
Rym: 44.".
Scott: So pretty much every theme park in the United States has a brochure of this nature and distributes it to all the nearby wooden stands, rest stops.
Scott: And the bigger a theme park you are, the wider you distribute your little brochure.
Scott: They also, every theme park, even today with advent of phones, they're needed less, but they still exist as maps.
Scott: Even Disney World, especially big complex place like that, but even small places, people need a map.
Scott: They need to know where that roller coaster is, where the water slide is, where the toilet is.
Scott: And the maps were typically, I think even still, like these little cute hand-drawn things.
Scott: Little miniature representations.
Scott: They're really fun.
Scott: They give you that sort of same feeling as like video game map, RPG map.
Scott: Which place do you want to go to?
Scott: And I think I feel a lot of that same fun if I'm at an amusement park with a map that I feel when I'm playing an RPG or a video game or reading a fantasy novel.
Rym: Yeah, you're looking at the map and you're like, "Ooh, the Mystic Cave is up in the top left of the park.
Rym: Let's go over and see what the Mystic Cave
Rym: is.".
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: You're real disappointed when you see one, you get there, it's closed, stuff like that.
Scott: I really do think, so this website obviously is an archive of brochures and maps from theme parks in the United States and perhaps elsewhere.
Scott: I don't know if they have any elsewheres.
Rym: Over a long period of time- There's definitely some Canada, because I see Canada Wonderland here.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: They've got enough to be interesting.
Scott: They got old enough to be interesting, but you could probably easily find some in your possession that you could upload to them.
Rym: Oh, I definitely could.
Rym: It is far from complete.
Rym: Cedar Point is pretty underrepresented here.
Scott: Yeah, they have some Cedar Points on them.
Rym: A few, but way fewer than I would have expected.
Scott: But yeah, you got to imagine you could get one from every single year for most of these places.
Scott: They're updating them somewhat frequently or every time they add a ride or update an attraction, they're changing their map or something.
Rym: That's good stuff.
Scott: But yeah, I think this is really useful because A, fun for people who like theme parks, but also B, the maps would be useful.
Scott: You could just take one of these maps and play an RPG.
Scott: There is an RPG.
Scott: Isn't there a tabletop RPG that has kids on bikes or something?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, you know what you could do?
Rym: You could make an RPG.
Rym: There's the idea.
Rym: But the RPG is get one of those brochures.
Rym: Everyone has to go to a diner, like you're on a road trip, get a bunch of those brochures, and the game is designed to be run solely from the content in those brochures.
Scott: Something like that.
Scott: But yeah, you could just take a map- Aw shit!
Rym: Terror on Church Street.
Rym: This is, in fact, the brochure I remember.
Scott: You could take the map from any theme park and just sort of translate it to a fantasy world, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, instead of calling, you know, the something something is a roller coaster, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, the Batman roller coaster.
Scott: It's like, no, no, no.
Scott: There's actually, that's a Batman over there.
Scott: It's like, you know, what's that?
Scott: Well, that's the roundup.
Scott: What's the, what's the roundup?
Scott: It's actually, you know, it's not, you know, it's a ride that spins and goes up and down, but you know, just imagine what the roundup would be in fantasy world, right?
Scott: And suddenly you've got yourself an RPG map, you know?
Scott: So yeah.
Rym: It's good stuff.
Rym: In the meta moment, uh, we're still stuck inside.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: That's what I got.
Scott: Still slowly- There is gonna be a PAX East Online, which is basically, all the online PAXes, all online conventions are basically world PAXes.
Scott: The only thing geographical about the PAX East Online is that the time zone of the schedule will be East-ish.
Scott: Whereas the previous PAX Online has a West and Australian timed schedule.
Scott: But you can watch everything post-PAC.
Scott: You don't need to watch them live, right?
Scott: So, and the panel submissions for PAX East Online are up.
Rym: I've literally got that open in a tab because we got to decide what panel or panels we want to do.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So that's a, I guess that's a thing.
Rym: I think I want to try to do a new panel or at least something like radically different from what we've done recently.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Yeah, we'll do something.
Rym: I'm not doing that game economy loop one though.
Rym: I'm still doing primary research.
Rym: That's gonna take a while.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Um, yeah, I don't know.
Scott: Is there any other- The Book Club book is the first novel ever written by human beings, The Tale of Genji.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's starting to get warm enough to where soon I can sit outside and read when I'm idle, which means I'm gonna probably power through the book.
Rym: I'll bet- I don't know, I'm thinking about when- I feel like it's sometime toward the end of June I might be done with the book.
Rym: If it's warm enough for me to hang out in a park and just read.
Scott: Well, I hope so.
Scott: I'm making somewhat progress, but I got distracted by some other things lately.
Scott: Anything else going on?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: If you're somehow listening to this, I don't know how it's possible and you don't know who we are, you don't know anything else.
Scott: We have an internet presence on every single platform.
Scott: that matters basically, that you know of.
Scott: All the major ones.
Scott: At least all the major English ones.
Scott: So come and wherever it is that you like to be on the internet, whatever site it is or app it is that you use, we're there in some fashion.
Scott: Come find us.
Scott: A lot of the podcast platforms are adding more features.
Scott: Spotify, I think, as I read today, they're adding the ability to link to a specific time in a podcast, which YouTube does for videos.
Scott: We're also on YouTube, by the way.
Rym: Yeah, we're live streaming to YouTube right now.
Scott: So yeah, you know, just come find us wherever the place you like to be is.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Let's get right into it.
Rym: So, remote controls.
Rym: I don't know how much we have to say, but I think there's something to say here because it's another one of those...
Scott: We're running out of Monday ideas.
Scott: Send your Monday ideas to...
Rym: But it's another one of those things where they did not exist or were rare when we were young.
Rym: They proliferate...
Scott: The first several televisions I had were not remote controlled.
Scott: You had to get up and physically turn a dial on the television in order to set the channel.
Rym: Often multiple dials like switch to UHF.
Scott: We had a UHF, we had two dials, the VHF dial, but the VHF dial had one channel, which was UHF.
Scott: And if you switch to that, then the UHF dial would matter.
Rym: And then you could go to the high channel, like channel 56 or whatever.
Rym: And then we actually had a third thing that we had to control physically.
Rym: What it did is it rotated the antenna on our roof.
Rym: Our antenna was directional.
Scott: We just had ears on the television that we would just adjust.
Rym: Oh wow, we had a gigantic color roof antenna that was wired to the whole house, and there was a control box that was physical.
Rym: And you could rotate it to the geographic direction you wanted it to point, like the coordinates, and it would slowly tick as it rotated on the roof.
Rym: And there were a few channels where we had a little cheat sheet next to it, where if you wanted to watch that channel, you want to rotate it to point at the source, so the quality would be better.
Rym: And channel 9 from Canada, we couldn't see it all, so we pointed it at channel 9.
Scott: We had a roof antenna, but we didn't have to point it.
Scott: I think also part of that is because we were in such an area between New York and Connecticut.
Scott: We basically just had all the New York and Connecticut stations were just really strong, so we didn't need to mess around.
Rym: We mostly had to point it if we wanted the central time zone stuff, which we could kind of get.
Rym: We also had to point it if we wanted the Canadian stuff.
Scott: Anyway, that's not remote control really.
Rym: Because it was a thing that even when we had a TV, a color TV, that had a remote control, that 1974 color RCA that you knew and loved.
Rym: And even when we had a remote, we still had to get up and go over to the TV anytime we wanted to move that stupid antenna.
Rym: So we still had to physically go fuck with the TV on a semi-regular basis, despite having our remote control.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Just anecdotally, right?
Scott: So even at the time when we had all the TVs in the house, all the frequently used living room, bedroom type ones were color and gray.
Scott: They were still CRTs, but they were better, right?
Scott: In the kitchen for the longest time in the kitchen, we had the tiny black and white TV with its own little antennas.
Scott: Because the only thing that TV ever watched was ABC World News Tonight and Jeopardy.
Rym: That black and white TV was If You Want to Watch TV in the Kitchen.
Rym: And then later, because you could see it from the kitchen, you couldn't see the real TV from the kitchen.
Rym: But then later, that was the TV the Atari 7800 was plugged into, because the NES was plugged into the big TV.
Scott: Anyway, so remote controls weren't exist.
Scott: So when we finally got remote controls, it was like, "Oh yes, I don't have to get it from the
Scott: couch.".
Scott: It was such a huge deal.
Scott: I don't think people realize how big a deal that was, right?
Rym: It's like you'd be watching something.
Scott: The amount of luxury that you had, right, to be able to just turn the channel without getting up and to go through them quickly, right?
Scott: It's just like, yeah, and you'll adjust the volume.
Rym: It changed how people, like.
Rym: it's a simple technology that I don't think you, like you have to understand how much it changed how people interacted with TV.
Rym: Which was the primary source of pop culture entertainment for almost everyone in America at the time.
Scott: So, channel surfing was not a thing before the remote control.
Scott: You would be on a channel and you like, you wouldn't want, because you were lazy and didn't want to change the channel, you would sit through commercials more likely.
Scott: As soon as you had remote control, it's like, "Don't got to sit through that shit anymore.
Scott: Click, click,
Scott: click.".
Rym: I remember advertisers, like.
Rym: there was a moderate, short-lived public discourse about how the remote control would end television because people would just change the channel anytime an ad came on.
Scott: We did.
Rym: We did change the channel every time an ad came on.
Rym: Somehow TV survived, but also you get the situation where there used to be huge inertia between a show that ended leading an audience into the show that came on next on that channel.
Rym: Once the remote came, that effect actually persisted to a significant degree, but it wasn't nearly as powerful.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: So, remote controls, I think, for consumers at least, started for television, and the way most of them work and still work is with infrared.
Scott: There's basically a little infrared light bulb in the remote control, and every button on the remote, you push it and it blinks the infrared light bulb.
Rym: It's a really simple signal.
Scott: Yeah, with a specific pattern for each button, and on the TV, there's basically an infrared sensor, right?
Scott: Sort of like the same one that's in a Game Boy Color on the front, right?
Scott: And it detects when infrared light blinks at it in a certain pattern, and then the TV behaves according to whatever, so if it received the blinking pattern, sort of like a Morse code you could think of it as, right?
Scott: For volume up, the TV turns its volume up.
Scott: If it received the signal from volume down, it goes down, right?
Scott: The problem was that every TV decided on different signals for the different buttons.
Scott: Different TVs had different buttons on their remotes, right?
Scott: So then you had VCRs getting in the picture, right?
Rym: Sometimes you'd have a TV that would detect the wrong signals, like if you had two TVs in your house, one of them would partially fuck with the other TV, but not in a reliable way.
Rym: If they were next to each other, right?
Scott: If you had line of sight to both TVs from where you were sitting.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We had a giant mirror in our kitchen, or in our dining room/kitchen area, and another giant mirror opposite it in a different room in the living room, and you could basically work the remote from almost anywhere in the house because of that.
Scott: Yeah, that'll do it.
Scott: I mean, infrared light is just light.
Scott: You can't see it because you have stupid shitty human eyeballs.
Scott: If you put on night vision goggles, you can see it.
Scott: It's just a light bulb blinking.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: In fact, I remember as a kid...
Scott: We could have used actual light bulbs to do this.
Scott: We didn't need to use infrared ones, but infrared ones were just better.
Rym: When I was a kid, I learned it was infrared.
Scott: You don't bother people by blinking.
Rym: We had this simple thermometer that was like a strip of almost film strip.
Rym: You hold it up to your forehead, and it would turn colors, and it was basically like a very simple thermometer.
Rym: But if you just held it in front of a remote control, and hit the power button and a bunch of buttons, it would basically show a fever.
Rym: So, you could point the remote control at this thing, make it show a fever, then hold it on your head, and then show your parents that you had a fever in school.
Rym: That worked exactly zero times because my parents figured out exactly what I was doing.
Scott: Well, they can just touch your head and be like, "This makes no
Scott: sense.".
Rym: Yeah, they were like, "Eh, let's use the real thermometer.
Rym: Huh.
Rym: No fever.
Rym: Huh.".
Rym: And you have the remote control in your bed for some reason.
Rym: That's where it went.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah, losing the remote became a thing.
Scott: But this technology for remote controlling the TV was somewhat actually slowly, but at least from my perspective, applied to other things.
Scott: I have a remote control fan over here.
Scott: Remote control lights in your house are still not common.
Rym: Bit by bit, there was a boom of a lot of things started to have their own remote controls that were all proprietary.
Rym: But then bit by bit, there was just too much proliferation.
Rym: People didn't care that much.
Scott: I guess it doesn't make sense to have a remote control.
Scott: It's like you really need a microwave for the remote control, right?
Rym: Only if I could somehow have the microwave go get the food and put it in itself.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like you could remote control basically any electronic device, but you need a good reason to do that.
Scott: You've got car remote door openers.
Scott: Those are not infrared because your car might be far away from where you are and not have line of sight to it.
Rym: But the thing about remote controls is that all these early remote controls had zero security whatsoever because it didn't seem like it mattered.
Rym: Someone can change the channel on your television, okay?
Rym: That's what it's for.
Rym: You can occasionally prank people by changing the channel through their window.
Rym: if you knew what kind of TV they had and you had a remote that would work.
Rym: But garage door openers became a big problem because I remember in the 80s and early 90s, a lot of them used a very small number of codes.
Rym: And it was very common for one person to have a garage door opener that would open like three other random garages in the neighborhood.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you open up, I guess, I don't know how the newer ones work, but like just any garage door opener or remote car door opener, unlocker thing, you open them up.
Scott: And basically what you'll see is there's going to be a little set of dip switches, right?
Scott: And you know, there'll be, I don't know how many, right?
Scott: But you only, if you have like, you got to think, right?
Scott: They're all binary.
Scott: So if you got like eight switches, that's like, you know, what, two to the eighth or whatever, eight, I don't forget the binary, two to the eighth or eight squared, I don't know.
Scott: My math is bad right now in binary, but you got, there's a lot of possible combinations, right?
Rym: So the odds of you conflicting- Don't you just want a factorial?
Rym: I guess it depends on the symmetry.
Scott: It's just binary, right?
Scott: It's like, if you've got eight, eight bits is how many possible combinations, right?
Rym: Of course, the real problem was they were, you, all these early remote controls used fixed codes.
Rym: They use like, this is the signal that will open this garage door all the time.
Scott: The idea was that you would ship them with, you know, a different, you know, you'd key in a different one at the factory on to each one.
Scott: So the, you know, two people buy one from the same hardware store, they won't get the same code.
Scott: But I remember the one my grandparents had, because we didn't have a garage, but the one my grandparents had, the actual dip switches were exposed.
Scott: So if you could find someone in the neighborhood, you obviously had to remember your little, your dip switch configuration or else you wouldn't be able to open your own garage door.
Scott: But I guess if you had the key, you could get into the garage and re-figure it out, right?
Scott: But you could go around the neighborhood and flick the switches and try to open up other people's garage doors if they had the same garage door opener.
Rym: I guess it's just interesting that even in these early days, there was proto, like not internet of things, but it was suddenly we have remote access to things to control them.
Rym: And nobody put even the barest thought into security at first.
Scott: They put the barest thought, they figured that that would be good enough.
Scott: What are the odds that two people are going to pick the same code and have the same garage door opener in the same place?
Rym: Yeah, but what they didn't think about is a nefarious actor who would just, like you could pretty easily try a lot of combinations.
Scott: What are the odds that two people have the same garage door opener in the same neighborhood with the same evil, right?
Rym: Yeah, except in my, in practice, like in my own life, it happened constantly everywhere I ever lived due to the density of houses.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well also people wouldn't, you know, in those days it would have been very much more difficult to say it would be easy to do this now, but to just make a computerized radio that attempts to open every possible garage door opener brand with every possible code.
Scott: So you just go up to any garage, they have this actually, the TV be gone, right?
Scott: That thing?
Scott: It's like you just push it and aim it at a TV in like a bar and it tries to tell it to turn off using every infrared pattern for every major television brand and you wait a while, eventually it'll turn that TV off.
Scott: Sooner or later it'll find the right code to get that TV to turn itself off.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And there's really no way to see, like there's no point in securing something like that.
Rym: Like put a piece of tape over it and don't use the remote if you actually care about like the security of controlling that TV.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So, you know, garage door opener, it's like you would need like a radio on whatever frequency it is, right?
Scott: Some whatever megahertz, right?
Scott: That's broadcasting every possible signal to get garage doors to open in a sequence really fast.
Scott: As fast as you can, right?
Scott: Because you can't do it super fast.
Scott: You have to do one after the other, right?
Scott: Because if you mix them together, well, they just interfere with each other.
Rym: Right.
Rym: But I guess the other interesting thing that happened with like remote controls, especially on TVs, is that it opened up a secondary market that previously hadn't existed.
Rym: Like for third parties to, one, people would like buy and sell old remotes, like have an extra remote could be useful if you lost yours or you broke it or something.
Rym: But two, people started making generic remote controls, universal remote controls, and configurable remote controls.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, because it's like even though the patterns were different on every device, right?
Scott: People, A, had two problems they wanted to solve, right?
Scott: Problem one, my remote is lost or broken.
Scott: I can't get the original one.
Scott: Maybe it's not even possible to get it anymore.
Scott: I'll just buy this remote that works with any possible TV.
Scott: And it has in it programmed all the patterns for all the TVs.
Scott: because the person who made this remote collected a bunch of remotes and wrote down all the signals, right?
Rym: It's easy to figure out.
Rym: You hit a button, see what signal comes out, hit another button, see what signal comes out.
Rym: Like that's it.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: You're like, okay, volume up on the Samsung TV is two and volume down is three.
Scott: On the Magnavox TV, up is four and down is five, right?
Scott: So you just need to put all that in the memory of one little circuit on your remote and people type in a number.
Scott: In the book, you would say type in this number for this TV brand and poof, there you go.
Scott: The remote is now doing what your original remote would do.
Scott: But also, people had VCRs and cable boxes back in the day and those had their own remotes.
Scott: You'd have three remotes and it was a pain in the ass.
Scott: But theoretically, if you set everything up right, there was a way to do it where you could have the cable box or usually the VCR remote would be like the best one.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The VCR remote was the one that had all the buttons you needed to control the other devices eventually.
Scott: So if you wired it up wisely and everything worked together and cleverly, you could make it such to where the VCR remote would, via the VCR, control the other devices.
Scott: You would turn the VCR on, the TV and the cable box would then turn on on their own because they were plugged into the VCR or into each other and then into the VCR.
Scott: And then you would change channels on the VCR.
Scott: The TV would be stuck on channel 3 but the cable would go into the VCR which would then go to the TV.
Scott: And so when you change channels on the VCR, the TV channel would be changing because the VCR is converting it to channel 3.
Scott: And then if you played a movie on the VCR, it's like alright, you're playing a movie now.
Scott: Just ignore whatever the cable box is doing.
Scott: You could just use that VCR remote for everything if you did it right and almost no one did it right.
Rym: Yep, we had our system set up very tightly in my house but we watched a lot of TV and that was very important to us.
Rym: so we spent a lot of time making everything work.
Scott: But yeah, so what you'd end up doing is you'd get this universal remote that would instead be able to control all the different devices and switch between them.
Scott: You'd push a button on it for VCR and now this one remote is the VCR remote and it's more convenient than having three things on your lap.
Scott: You have one thing and you just have to push buttons on it to transform it into the different remotes.
Rym: I remember as a kid, in that era, the only people who had a system that was overcomplicated and didn't work were the people who also had a fancy surround system.
Scott: Yeah, it's hard to get, people who didn't think about it and didn't understand wouldn't set it up the way it was intended and make things difficult for themselves.
Scott: If you knew how it worked and you thought about it, you would somehow use your receiver for your surround system as the central control for your whole everything.
Scott: The problem was that if you did that, it meant that every time you watch TV, you're using surround sound and some people, like in my house, you wouldn't always want the surround sound on, it's loud.
Scott: In my apartment, I always have it on, but it's not that loud.
Scott: Back in the day, that was loud.
Scott: It would wake up the whole house.
Rym: So I just learned something fascinating.
Rym: I did not realize this was ever used in consumer technology, but apparently in the early 80s it was common.
Rym: A lot of remote controls in that era, when we were growing up, were not IR.
Rym: They were ultrasonic.
Scott: Interesting.
Rym: And they were extremely prone to failure and extremely prone to false signals.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: For all the reasons you can imagine.
Scott: I think it was in fact a few really old TVs that had like a wired remote that was like...
Rym: Oh, I had one of those.
Rym: My first VCR had a wired remote to the VCR.
Scott: Mmm.
Rym: Plug it into a slot and it was a wire.
Rym: It was like 10 feet long.
Scott: It seems ancient when you think about it, but how is it different from a gamepad?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Wireless controllers on video game consoles?
Rym: Not common and didn't work well for a long time.
Scott: The first ones that were really wireless were what?
Scott: Like Xbox?
Rym: Well, I mean Atari had a wireless controller.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, so did NES.
Scott: But it's like they were Garbo, right?
Scott: The first ones that were any good were Xbox 360, I want to say.
Rym: Yeah, the first ones that were good, that just worked?
Scott: PS2 wasn't wireless.
Scott: I guess PS3 was?
Scott: Right?
Scott: I want to say PS3, Xbox 360 was like... and Wii.
Scott: Wiimotes.
Scott: Because GameCube remotes were not... well, there was the GameCube Air one.
Scott: That was one of the first ones also.
Rym: But it's interesting how the change in both controllers becoming wireless and TVs becoming larger and higher resolution changed how people interact with TVs as well when they're playing games.
Rym: Because when we were young, even young as late as like the Super Nintendo or the N64 or the PlayStation 1, you'd have to sit really close to your TV to play anything because the cords were not long on those controllers.
Scott: You'd also be changing cartridges and stuff.
Rym: Yep, there was no remote control for that.
Scott: If you had a wireless NES remote and you wanted to change games, you're getting up to swap the cartridge or the disc on your GameCube even if it wave-birded, right?
Scott: So it wasn't the fact of digital games just opening on the menu and changing games like on the Xbox 360 or the PS3, right?
Scott: Now the wireless controller made way more sense because you didn't have to get up ever, right?
Scott: Basically.
Rym: And now you're at the point where like a Nintendo Switch and its dock, any of the controllers, if they're first party, are also sort of a remote control and you can turn on the Switch from the controller wherever you are and that will, if your TV isn't too ancient, automatically turn on the TV and set it to whatever HDMI input.
Scott: Yeah, if you've got everything configured that way, then sure, it totally works.
Rym: Yeah, that should just be automatic on any current setup.
Scott: You know, you might have a setup where you don't want to do that.
Scott: Maybe you've got some other in-between device, something going on.
Scott: But yeah, I think for most people, that's what you would want to do.
Rym: The other thing I learned, because we were just talking about how it changed the way people interacted with media because they could change channels, like channel surfing became a thing.
Rym: Apparently in 1952, a product was sold that was a wireless remote called the Blaboff in the United States and its sole purpose, it was just a mute button.
Rym: And it was marketed.
Rym: as any time the ad read happens, the Blaboff will make sure you don't have to hear it.
Rym: So there is some very Rym or Scott-like personality has been thinking about how to use this technology for good from the very beginning.
Scott: Well, I mean, you've also got to think one of the best things about remote controls is just what they've done for accessibility, right?
Scott: There's a famous old TV commercial, the clapper, right?
Scott: And it was always sort of like a joke, like clap on, clap off the clapper.
Scott: But the clapper lets you turn your lights.
Scott: It was basically what you would do with this thing.
Scott: is you plug it into your power outlet and then you would plug your lights into the clapper, right?
Scott: It basically just went into your power outlet between whatever device.
Rym: Really simplistic, this thing, how it works.
Scott: If it hears clapping noises, right?
Scott: Sometimes erroneously, sometimes not sensitive enough, it wasn't perfect, but it would just cut power or allow power to go back on.
Scott: So you could turn your lights on and off from bed, right?
Scott: Or turn your TV on and off just by clapping, even if it wasn't a remote control TV or usually your lights.
Scott: And what this was, you know, for normal people seems kind of seemed a little bit silly, but you know, it's like, okay, it's not too bad, right?
Scott: It's like I turn the lights on when I entered the bedroom with the switch that's right near the door, I get in bed, then I clap and I turn the lights off because the switch is all the way over there.
Scott: Now I don't have to make a trip in the dark to my bed, right?
Scott: From the door.
Rym: It illustrates that concept that good user experience design often automatically becomes good or at least acceptable accessibility design.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, what if you are a senior person or a person who has a hard time walking or, you know, someone who could trip and fall in the dark and severely hurt themselves, right?
Scott: This silly thing suddenly becomes like this, you know, life saving, changing type device, you know, some, you know, if you have a hard time getting up, right.
Scott: It's like you want to change to control the channel on the TV and it's a dial.
Scott: It's like you're going to, you know, an old an old person who can barely walk like a walker.
Scott: Imagine them getting up to walk over to the TV, turn a dial, then go sit down again every time.
Scott: It's like, you know, versus remote control.
Scott: It's like that's that's life saving.
Rym: The clapper also, as an aside, in terms of usability, very pointedly notice that remote controls for lights have never been common or popular for a lot of reasons.
Rym: The main reason is you would have to carry that remote control with you everywhere.
Scott: You know, and you probably tried to do.
Scott: the people have tried this home automation where, like, you have an app on your phone that does it and you wire all the lights in your house and like the same kind of system.
Scott: But those only seem to be popular amongst, you know, like wealthy or very techie type people.
Rym: They also, they do the Internet of shit problem where they're not secure and they cause problems.
Rym: The difference between a remote control and that and like an app on a phone is that remote controls are direct and do not leave the boundaries of your house.
Rym: They're air gap.
Rym: They're not hackable in any meaningful sense.
Scott: But as soon as you discussed with the garage door.
Scott: Yeah, true.
Rym: But that was just extremely poor design there.
Rym: But like think about a phone app.
Rym: It is possible there are phone apps.
Rym: Like if you had a phone or a smart device that has an I.R.
Rym: receiver and sender, there were phone apps for those devices or software that would literally make them be a remote control.
Rym: And with Bluetooth, another thing is it would be possible to have a phone app that is a remote control, but it directly connects to devices without using some cloud service or the Internet.
Rym: It's not accessible anywhere else.
Scott: Or even just stays on the LAN in your house and doesn't go to a cloud service.
Rym: But these things tend to always use cloud services because of, well, mostly bad reasons.
Scott: People's LANs are, you know, if you make it work on LAN only, everyone's house network is so messed up.
Scott: You would have so many customer support issues.
Scott: And then you'd have to help people with networking in their house, like actual networking stuff.
Scott: You would never survive.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But I guess the moral of this is that even something as prosaic and simple as the television remote control, which went any remote control like it came in.
Rym: But even though television went specifically like zoom in on something so specific, it's really important to think about how surprising the changes were that happened around it because of it.
Rym: Like it changed the way people interact with media.
Rym: It changed the way people interact with their devices in fairly profound and far reaching ways, despite how relatively simple and obvious all of that seems in retrospect.
Scott: I think with the biggest development that's recent is that the remote controls, which used to have shit tons of buttons on them and sometimes still do, have had way less buttons on them because all of our televisions now have software in them.
Scott: So there'll be like a fancy user interface on the television screen.
Scott: And so the only buttons you need are like to navigate that interface up, down, left, right, OK, back.
Rym: That's actually something that bothers me a lot about current TVs.
Rym: The remote controls usually have a million buttons on them.
Scott: Like look at the.
Scott: look at the Apple TV remote.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It doesn't have a lot of controls on it because you're at the Apple TV interfaces was taking care of the complexity as opposed to lots of buttons.
Rym: But now you have the situation where the user experience of the TV itself and how it portrays those menus can become a problem, especially now because you have a remote control where the only buttons you're actually using are the arrows and the enter and the back.
Rym: And yet they still tend to have a lot of other buttons that often aren't that useful because they don't actually do anything for most users, which makes them confusing.
Rym: And a lot of non-technical people just give up and just have broken AV systems.
Scott: Well, I think, you know, there are some things we've seen that remote control has been added to recently, like thermostats, relatively recent remote control thermostats.
Scott: And, you know, it's like I think there still is room for other things to have remote control added to them or have remote control complexity increased for a car.
Scott: Remote control is getting better all the time.
Scott: Now you got like it turns the heat on.
Scott: It starts the remote starter.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, you know, we're going to have pretty.
Scott: I don't think we have self-driving car.
Scott: We talked about that a lot.
Scott: I think we will have within our lifetimes, maybe next five, 10 years, basically remote valet where you the car parks itself and then comes back.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It doesn't drive all around town and take it all the way destination.
Scott: But it's like you can go to a parking lot, pull up to the store, push the park button.
Scott: It can navigate a parking lot and park itself.
Scott: And then when you come out of the store, like on your way to the door, push a button and the car will be there for you at the door.
Scott: I think we can have that within some reasonable amount of years kind of thing going on.
Scott: But if you can think of things to where adding remote control to them, they currently don't have remote control makes sense and improves people's lives, especially if it helps, you know, accessibility.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which remote control has, you know, high potential to do.
Scott: You could make a real big difference, right?
Scott: Because it's even after decades, it is still has a lot of potential.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: There.
Rym: So we could kill the Monday.
Rym: I got Monday ideas set of our way.
Rym: GeekNights at FrontRowCrew.com.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi McNichol, Alan Joyce, Link Eiji, Dredd, Lily Tenebrae, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Crane Paddock, Old Man Save, Des, Peacock, Mimesnack, JustLikeADudeGuy, Kashyaya, 85, Rebecca Dunn, Revue, MadBull34, Cowards, Ryan Perrin, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Harel, Taylor Braun, YouHoldTheKeyToMyHeart, and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say they're not.
Rym: We have a good idea for a Monday show, but Scott's gotta finish something first because we're enacting our no shit talk policy.
Rym: You could always flood us with suggestions that we should just do tech news roundups more frequently because I think those are actually more engaging shows.
Rym: I don't think we really want us to do another like "here's how keyboards work" type of show because there's just YouTube channels that do that kind of crap.
Rym: But anyway, for now, I leave you with... (Singing in Japanese).