Rym: It's Wednesday, February 17th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we're talking about upcoming animation that we may want to watch.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So, you know, we have an official-ish GeekNights Discord where you could come and talk to the other listener.
Scott: And today there was, you know, a discussion that started with evil people who are now thankfully deceased, but it managed to wind its way around to Denethor.
Rym: Ah, Denethor.
Scott: And someone incorrectly referred to Denethor as a king, and I had to correct them and point out that he was only a steward of Gondor and not the king.
Scott: That's why it's called "Return of the King" because the king comes back.
Rym: There's a certain kind of person for whom that is an extremely important distinction.
Scott: The most important.
Scott: But, as even though I am such a person who knows a fact, right, like that, I actually did not know, though always wondered, how the hell did it end up that way?
Scott: How did, you know, it's like, yeah, I know Isildur was killed, the ring fell on the lake, Gollum got it, Isildur was the king at the time, right?
Scott: But it's like, why didn't just, Isildur had children, why didn't they just become the king?
Rym: I can come up with plausible historical things, but yeah, I never actually thought about that because it was presented as a steward now.
Scott: I've thought about it often, I thought about it often, and not until today did I bother to actually fucking look it up.
Scott: And you know what, it's actually not as complicated as I thought it was, it's actually pretty straightforward.
Rym: Where his kids too young?
Scott: You don't know.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: One of his children, basically, there's Gondor, right, and then Aragorn, we knew that he came from the north, the mysterious north, right?
Scott: In the north is another kingdom, Arnor, right?
Scott: It's another kingdom of men, right?
Scott: That's why there were so many kings of men, right?
Scott: Like Rohan is also men, right?
Scott: And apparently, Isildur was the king of Arnor and Gondor.
Scott: He was a king of two places.
Scott: And after he died, his child became king of only Arnor.
Scott: They were just sort of like, they just sort of gave up on Gondor.
Scott: All his children just in the north, and they basically, they just didn't rule over, they technically were the kings of Gondor by birthright, but they just didn't bother.
Scott: They're just like, you know what, we're just gonna rule over Arnor and ignore Gondor.
Rym: This is already very, I've been learning a lot about how that kind of thing works thanks to Crusader Kings 3.
Scott: Yeah, so the steward of Gondor at the time just sort of ran the show even though they knew they weren't king, but they had to do the king's work of managing shit, right?
Scott: You know, government work.
Scott: And Denethor was the son of the son of the son of the first steward, whatever, right?
Scott: And then, you know, Aragorn comes out of the north.
Scott: He was king of Arnor already, right?
Scott: He's the king of Arnor.
Scott: He comes down, you know, and then he goes and he picks up the sword from the elves, and the elves are like, oh, you're the king of Arnor, actually came down from the north.
Scott: Okay, you want to be king of both places again.
Scott: No one's gonna stop you.
Scott: Except the bad guys.
Scott: The end.
Scott: And that's the story.
Rym: I will just never forget seeing the scene where Denethor comes to a conclusion.
Scott: That was how the conversation started, because we needed the gif for that scene.
Rym: Yeah, we did need that gif.
Rym: I look up that gif kind of often, because I will never forget the moment when the movie is serious, serious, serious, serious.
Rym: And that scene, just the way it was framed and the way they, the entire, like, there was a moment of silence and then multiple people just started laughing out loud in the theater.
Rym: I think it was that he yells and runs way longer than you would expect him to.
Scott: Especially for a person on fire.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Like, I can't imagine looking at layouts of that castle, how he made it that far to actually jump off the edge while on fire the entire time.
Scott: Well, you know, the wiki that I was reading happened to also mention that Denethor was actually stronger than he, you know, you think, right?
Scott: Because you think about it, right, Saruman, right, was like a super strong wizard dude.
Scott: Like, damn, right?
Scott: But basically he was just directly corrupted by the Palantir, right?
Scott: Denethor was actually a good person and was pretty way stronger actually.
Rym: Until he sort of went crazy-ish.
Scott: Well, he didn't really, he didn't give in to Sauron, right?
Scott: He was, he was, he's still like anti-bad guy, right?
Scott: It's just, he basically, you know, became so depressed.
Scott: He's like, no, we can't win, right?
Scott: He wasn't like, you know, teaming up with the bad guys.
Scott: He was just so, just so full of despair.
Scott: He's like, well, we can't win this, right?
Scott: And that was, so he wasn't, he wasn't weak, right?
Rym: Yeah, I see Gandalf reading the same wiki.
Rym: Gandalf described him as proud and subtle, a man of far greater lineage and power.
Scott: And the reason, the reason he's messed up in the movie is because by the time you see him in the movie, he's already been so messed up, right?
Scott: From, you know, contact with the evil.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway, so yeah, in some news, we won't really talk about it today because it's kind of still coming out and I've only seen tricklings of it.
Rym: But the Nintendo Direct is happening right now and there's usually good- Okay, do you want us to just end it?
Scott: It ended.
Scott: then I came and started the show.
Rym: Ah, that explains it.
Scott: I told you that.
Scott: I told you that before we started the show.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: I'm scrolling through Twitter because I didn't see a good roundup of everything.
Scott: I'll give you the roundup.
Scott: Ready?
Scott: Here it is.
Scott: I don't care about new controllers.
Scott: It depends on what, yeah, depending on what you care about, but the big Nintendo things is Mario Golf, which would be great if we were in college, but maybe, right?
Scott: There's gonna be a Skyward Sword HD remake, but I have it on Wii, so I don't feel like I need to buy that.
Rym: I never played it, and I did see that one because apparently they're gonna have two modes.
Rym: A mode with the motion controls and a mode where it's only buttons.
Scott: It's the kind of game where you play it once, you beat it, and you're done.
Scott: It's not bad like, say, Zelda Train game, but it's not, you know, it's not a top tier Zelda.
Rym: Yeah, Zelda Train and Twilight Princess were the only two Zeldas I ever started playing and just didn't bother finishing.
Scott: Splatoon 3 next year, 2022, was their highlight.
Scott: Some Xenoblades characters in Smash with a really cute intro they had during the direct.
Scott: Here's something I don't really care too much about Ninja Gaiden 3D games, but what they're doing is something I like a lot, which is instead of doing an HD remake, which they could easily do, they're just gonna sell a bundle of all three together.
Scott: And if I was gonna, if I was gonna play those games, like that actually is like, oh, you know, I might buy that, you know, not like Square Enix or like buy Final Fantasy 6, you know, remake whatever on its own for a pile of money.
Scott: It's like, no, how about you do this?
Scott: How about you sell Final Fantasy 1 through 10 or whatever in a bundle, right?
Scott: For 40 bucks or 30, right?
Scott: It's like, I will probably buy that maybe.
Rym: I would probably buy that.
Scott: Maybe, right?
Scott: It's like, so I kind of like that, that was in there.
Scott: Capcom's doing a thing.
Scott: There's a new Monster Hunter or something.
Scott: You know, there's a new, people like that, I played that first, was it?
Scott: No More Heroes, right?
Rym: I saw the triangle game.
Rym: a lot of people are buzzing about.
Scott: Yeah, that's a Square Enix game, which is the same series as Octopath Traveler, except it's more of a tactics battle kind of situation.
Scott: There should be a demo of it.
Scott: you can play today for free on your Switch.
Rym: I'm gonna check out that demo before I say anything about it, because that kind of game can go in a lot of different directions and most of them are bad.
Scott: I actually like the Octopath Traveler demo, but I wasn't about to pay money for a JRPG that I knew I wouldn't finish.
Scott: The demo was enough for me.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure there's something I'm forgetting because it was kind of long.
Rym: Yeah, we'll probably talk about bits in more detail on Tuesday.
Scott: You know, depending on who you are and what you care about, there'll be some things in it that you cared about and some things that you didn't, because they rattled off a whole mess of games.
Rym: In my feed, just people I follow on Twitter, if I don't look at it, all anyone was talking about was, "Oh my god, there'll be some Animal Crossing Mario
Rym: stuff.".
Scott: They already announced that before, that's not new news.
Scott: But that's still whatever we're talking about.
Scott: They re-announced it, yes.
Scott: I think the one thing that was new in that news is that they said you could put a warp pipe on your island so that way you can get around your island faster.
Rym: Ooh, I like that.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Scott: That was good.
Rym: So, in some news, there's been a lot of chatter about Airwig and the Witch, the Studio Ghibli movie, that it looks bad, probably is bad, I haven't watched it yet, so I'll reserve judgement.
Rym: But if you watch the trailer for it, the animation looks terrible.
Scott: Like, absolutely terrible.
Scott: I've actually only seen still images and I knew it was a thing and I knew it existed, but I don't even know, is it out yet or is it coming soon still?
Scott: If it's coming soon, it's coming very soon.
Rym: It's coming, yeah, there's reviews out already.
Scott: So it must be, is it out now?
Rym: I'm not 100% sure, because I wasn't really excited to see it, to be honest.
Scott: Yeah, I wasn't that hyped for it either.
Scott: Even though we usually say you should watch all, oh no, release date, December 30th, 2020, so it's been out.
Rym: So the reviews so far have been, like, scathing is not even close to describing.
Rym: I'm going to quote some of these reviews, I'm just flipping through right now.
Rym: Erig and the Witch, Studio Ghibli's first computer-generated feature is an unholy eyesore.
Rym: If nothing else, Goro Miyazaki's feature makes an effective argument for the magic of hand-drawn animation.
Scott: Maybe that's what hand-drawn animation needed, was bad CG, right?
Scott: It's like, there's plenty of good CG, we just talked about that Lupin movie, not the last Wednesday show or the one before that.
Rym: Yup, which looked amazing.
Scott: Right, it's like, you know, CG isn't necessarily a bad thing, but maybe that's what they need to get more money into.
Scott: the hand-drawn stuff, is examples of bad CG.
Rym: Oh, here's another quote for you.
Rym: While Erig and the Witch is far from the ugliest film of its kind, there's something uniquely perverse about seeing Ghibli's signature aesthetic suffocated inside of a plastic coffin.
Rym: Like, the lighting looks bad, the animation is stiff, like, it looks like a student film from five-plus years ago.
Scott: I wonder what the backstory is.
Rym: Aha, that's the thing that no one's talking about.
Rym: I've seen fucking nobody talk about what I'm about to talk about.
Scott: How did it end up this way?
Scott: Was the budget way low?
Rym: So, the budget was basically zero.
Rym: This was a made-for-TV movie with a tiny crew that, in Japan at least, was basically talked about as a proof of concept.
Rym: Like, Ghibli put this together with a tiny team to explore 3D animation and do something.
Rym: This is not a full-feature theatrical release like everyone in America is talking about it as.
Rym: So, everyone's comparing this to, like, all the other Ghibli films.
Rym: You know how many people worked on this thing?
Rym: Like, so, it took a while to dig around because Ghibli won't talk about the budget or anything.
Rym: Like, I had to dig around for this.
Rym: There are a grand total of, there are fewer people in the entire staff for producing this film than were in the sound department for the Lupin movie.
Scott: Apparently, according to Wikipedia, right, which has citations if you trust them, it says that basically what happened is Goro said that his father, I'm reading from Wikipedia directly, Goro said that his father told him to go with it and Toshio Suzuki encouraged him, but after that he was left on his own and made the anime with young staff and didn't consult with the old guys at all.
Scott: He also said that he is the only one at the studio who knows the method of creating CG animation.
Scott: So, basically, it was like they had some resources of Studio Ghibli, but just the young inexperienced people on their own doing it, right?
Rym: Not even just the young inexperienced people.
Scott: And it was their first go at it, right?
Scott: You know, it wasn't like they brought in people from the outside who had knowledge or experience in this area.
Scott: So, here's something for you.
Rym: I want you to guess.
Rym: How many animators worked on this film?
Scott: Animators?
Rym: And people who are credited as an animator.
Scott: I mean, to make an 82 minute animation and actually deliver it, you need a lot, but I'm guessing it was way too, it's not, it's either way too many or way too few.
Rym: There is one animator credited.
Scott: Well, that's just not gonna cut it, right?
Scott: There is a character.
Scott: I wasn't gonna say one.
Scott: I was gonna say like ten.
Rym: The animation department consists of one character designer, one CG supervisor, one animator, and one animation director.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: Oh, and they credit a fifth person, but that's just the original character concepts.
Scott: So, they didn't outsource anything?
Rym: The production crew for this was tiny.
Rym: The budget, as far as anyone can surmise, do it like the journalist who tried to figure this out, was tiny.
Rym: And it was basically treated as like a made for TV movie that, and even by that standard, it's not good, but people in America are really...
Scott: Listen, if you get yourself and a few friends together, right, and you slap together 82 minute long movie...
Rym: Like, my hat is off to you.
Scott: And you put that shit on YouTube, that's pretty good.
Rym: If that was how this was framed to me before I saw that teaser trailer, I would have been a lot more sympathetic to it.
Rym: The problem is...
Scott: I think it also, you know, the Studio Ghibli brand, right, when you start this movie, does it show a blue screen with a Totoro on it?
Scott: 'Cause that's like, that's the problem, right?
Rym: It's
Scott: like, I've never made a shoe in my life, but if I were to, you know, design a shoe and then I was able to legitimately slap a Nike logo on the side of it, and someone put the shoe on and broke their foot, and then the shoe fell apart, right?
Scott: They would have a complaint.
Rym: Yup, but that's kind of the thing that I don't see everyone talking about.
Rym: Everyone's just trashing this movie, and pretty legitimately, it's not good, from any account, but they're also trashing it by comparing it to, like, Princess Mononoke.
Scott: That's 'cause they put the same Studio Ghibli logo on it.
Scott: They should have done that.
Scott: They should have put some other brand on there.
Rym: I don't know where the breakdown is, but at least in the US, like, this is being marketed as the next Ghibli movie.
Scott: It is technically a Ghibli movie.
Rym: So,
Scott: uh, maybe you shouldn't, you know, this is why, when you look at, like, other companies, right, like, especially, you know, publishers in the book world, they have imprints where it's like, yeah, all those ten different brands are actually one company, but they keep all those brands alive because, you know, marketing reasons, right?
Scott: You know, that they don't want to be, like, imagine if, you know, like, Penguin Books, they have Penguin Classics, right?
Scott: Imagine if every book they published, even, like, some, you know, sleazy, new, like, pulp sci-fi thing, they're like, Penguin Classics, you know, and it's, like, something like that, right, 'cause they only have one brand.
Scott: That's what Studio Ghibli's done here.
Scott: They only got one brand, and they slapped it on everything, and then it's like, well, maybe you should have made a different brand.
Rym: Is whether or not this was a situation of this just being marketed outside of Japan, like, in the wrong way, like, for whatever reason, the decision was made to treat this as a Ghibli movie.
Scott: Try to make, try to, I mean, you can, you can make, you're not gonna make, it's, it's basically, if you just ignore it, right, you won't make any money, you won't lose any money, you won't make any money, though.
Scott: So, if you wanna, like, hey, here's a thing, we can legitimately put a Ghibli logo on this, and say that, and some people will give us money based on that alone, and nothing else, regardless of how good it is, why would we not do that?
Scott: We will make money.
Rym: Yep, but you might poison your brand, or cause these, uh, reviews to come out about this thing.
Scott: There are already Ghibli movies that are not good, it is not a perfect run, like, uh, some other people who have had a perfect run, so, therefore, uh, you know.
Rym: Is it that, or is this some sort of, like, power struggle or passive aggressive thing within the studio, like, did they set Goro up to fail?
Scott: I don't know, maybe, who knows.
Rym: Yeah, it's just, it's, it annoys, the thing I'm annoyed about the most is that everyone who's reviewing it and talking about it does not at any point talk about the size of the production.
Rym: At all.
Rym: I don't know if they just didn't, like, think to look.
Scott: I mean, people, when people, people judge a thing, you just gotta judge the end product, right?
Scott: I do agree with that.
Scott: You're applying a different standard of quality, right?
Scott: It's good or it's bad, it's like, even if it has excuses and reasons it was good or bad that are perfectly legitimate, it doesn't make it good.
Rym: Well, that's it, I'm not saying that the reviews should treat it better, I'm saying the reviews should include this information.
Scott: Yeah, the job of the person is to say, look, um, you know, don't, you should or shouldn't watch this, you shouldn't.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Of course, I don't know, maybe they could all be, I don't think they're wrong, I'm guessing, I haven't seen it, it could be good and they could all be bad reviewers who are wrong about things.
Rym: If you watch the teaser trailer, it does just look amateurish, like, it looks like Toy Story but bad.
Scott: I'm not saying it's likely, I'm saying it's possible.
Rym: Yeah, but, like, by contrast, in the US, the budget for a movie is usually, like, very prominently featured in reviews of the movie, like, that's always a point that's brought up.
Rym: As far as I can tell, Japanese studios, like, Ghibli in particular, they don't talk about their budgets.
Scott: I think the reason that that's a thing in the US, I think there's, like, laws or other, some sort of regulations.
Scott: and just the way Hollywood specifically works is that that information ends up being public.
Scott: and I, the thing is, that's something I talk about a lot when I talk other industries, especially, like, Apple, Nintendo, right, whatever.
Rym: Even my industry, like, I don't have to tell you what the budget is for something I'm working on.
Scott: Right, they're so secretive and I'm always, like, why are you so secretive?
Scott: And it's, like, one of the examples I can always bring up is, like, look, the movie industry is not as much less secretive.
Scott: They just tell, you just know way in advance who's being cast for what, what's been optioned, who's budgeted for this, you can read all that stuff, it's all just out there, right?
Scott: And it doesn't seem to hurt the movie industry, even though you know movies are coming way in advance, it just hypes them up more.
Scott: It's, like, Apple, if you tell us what's going to be an iPhone 15 in three years, it's just going to hype people up more, right?
Scott: And if that makes people say, well, if, you know, people will start saying stuff like, well, you know what, if that's what's an iPhone 15, that's the one to get, right?
Scott: Because 16 looks meh and 14 is meh, 15's the sweet spot, then just don't bother to make iPhone 14 and 16, just make the 15 after you can see what people's response is to that, right?
Scott: It only helps you to be less secretive, I don't think that the, you know, and I really want to be, like, I really, really want to interview anyone who has or does work at a secretive place, you know, and get them to explain, you know, I'm not asking you to tell me secrets, I want to know your reasons for, like, Tim Apple, tell me why you're so secretive, how does it benefit you, show me proof that it benefits you, right, to be secretive, you're not just doing it because you can.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: I mean, the real answer is we just got to nationalize more stuff and have a lot more government regulation on everything, of course.
Scott: Sure, sure, yeah, but anyway.
Rym: Yeah, so you got some news?
Scott: Do I have a news, what was it again?
Rym: We just talked about this, Crunchyroll.
Scott: Alright, yeah, so, you know, we talked about Crunchyroll and Funimation merging a while ago, right, under Sony or whatever.
Rym: Yeah, the great consolidation of the anime distribution industry.
Scott: So I thought that at that, you know, you know, at what point are we going to see the complete merging, one of them disappearing, folding into the other, everyone gets an account on the other thing, something like that, right?
Scott: But until then, they're actually, surprisingly worse, are still new shows being added to both services, Funimation and Crunchyroll separately, and they just announced a bunch of new shows to go on Crunchyroll.
Scott: And a lot of them are shows that you can completely ignore and should not watch.
Scott: For example, there was one that I recognized from the olden days of anime, they said, "Oh yeah, Stelvia is coming to
Scott: Crunchyroll.".
Scott: And the only thing I remember about Stelvia is that I've seen the DVD cover at Media Play and at the Anime Club way back in the early 2000s, and I was like, "Well, that looks like garbage and I'm never going to watch
Scott: it.".
Rym: I didn't say it was garbage, my thinking was, "That looks like...".
Scott: I said, "It looks like
Scott: garbage.".
Rym: I thought, "That looks like an anime,
Rym: period.".
Rym: It was Stelvia, like, Arise of Mind, Scryde, were just all these shows that I'd see, and I'd hear people talking about it in the club, but I just had no desire to ever even look at them.
Scott: It came out in 2003, so I'm correct.
Scott: But yeah, you don't need to watch that unless you really got nothing to do.
Scott: But there were two robot shows that I was surprised to see on Crunchyroll, and I'm going to watch one of them.
Scott: So there's the original, uh, Voltus 5, which is like a super old-school classic robot anime that I, you know, the kind of thing you'd never think you would see, you know, released.
Rym: Yeah, like the robot literally looks like a toy with his fist out if you've never seen it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So I'm really surprised to see that, uh, and I'm going to maybe probably watch some.
Scott: I don't know if I'll watch every episode of it, but I'm going to watch some.
Scott: And then, Tetsujin 28, the oldest robot show, but actually not the oldest version of it.
Scott: It was a later remake of Tetsujin 28.
Scott: I don't know what year this one's from.
Rym: Well, kind of like how the original Astro Boy, watch a few episodes to, like, get the deal, but honestly, the '80s Astro Boy is the one to watch for real.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: But yeah, I don't know which one this is.
Scott: It must be, oh, it might be the series.
Rym: This is the 2004.
Rym: Oh, 2004?
Scott: Okay, it's not the 2000, because there was apparently another one from 2013 to 2016.
Rym: Yeah, what I'll say about Tetsujin 28, I've seen a couple episodes, like, I don't know a lot about it, honestly, but- Gigantor.
Scott: Gigantor is the same thing.
Rym: Yeah, if you watch, like, I don't know, Big O or Giant Robo, and you want to know, like, where some of those inspirations came from, there is a straight line back to Tetsujin 28.
Scott: Tetsujin 28 was, like, the first robot show.
Scott: Like, the first one.
Scott: And, you know, the kid is remote controlling the robot with, like, a little remote control and such.
Scott: And it's, you know, it's actually pretty good.
Scott: There's a lot of good going on there.
Scott: that's what caused people to be so inspired and create an entire, you know, genre of robot animes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, this isn't the original, original one, but it is, you know, the same storyline remade for the umpth time or whatever.
Scott: So, you know, I'll probably, I'll give it a look.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So, one really brief thing, but we'll skip talking about this in more depth until the main bit, because it's very relevant to that, but Bell, Memorial Hosted as upcoming new movie, a teaser trailer dropped today.
Scott: Yeah, we actually talked about it, and then the teaser dropped, like- That's beautiful.
Rym: I'm getting summer wars crossed with Beauty and the Beast vibes from this in a big way.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So, yeah, we'll talk about that more in the main bit.
Scott: It looks- It was such a coincidence that I mentioned the movie.
Scott: I was like, "What was that movie he's working
Scott: on?".
Scott: "Oh, right,
Scott: Bell.".
Scott: And then, like, minutes later, a trailer for it drops.
Scott: And I'm just like, "What the fuck?
Scott: Did I speak that into
Scott: existence?".
Rym: Like- There's probably only, like, 30 or 40 frames of animation from it that you could even see in this teaser trailer.
Rym: It does not give you much to go on.
Scott: It gives me enough to go on.
Scott: Oh, I've got enough to go on, if this was not going to- I'm going to be first in line to see that movie.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So, in some more industry news, I feel like on all four days of GeekNights, we've had a lot of news recently about big consolidations in industries, because there's a lot of reasons why that's happening right now.
Rym: But another thing that's happening is, not consolidations, but a lot of big companies are shutting down parts of themselves, either that they had spun off or that they had acquired.
Rym: So, Disney just shut down Blue Sky Studios, like, in the middle of a movie that they're almost done with.
Scott: Yeah, so I don't know if people know this, but Blue Sky is the CG animation studio that brought you- Yeah, all the Ice Age movies.
Scott: And the studio was actually located in, I think, Connecticut?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So, it's like almost all the animation stuff is going on, obviously, California area, right?
Scott: So, this was sort of like the last animation place that was in, not California, in the United States.
Scott: At least, big one.
Scott: There's obviously small ones all over the place.
Scott: You know, probably in New York City, there's still probably a few here and there, right?
Scott: But not big ones.
Scott: The big ones that are making the big movies, they're all in California.
Scott: And so, that was kind of meh because, you know, usually when a place is closed down, as opposed to consolidate, you know, they usually see on Twitter, "Oh, jobs.
Scott: Let's find jobs for these people," right?
Scott: Because they lost their job through no fault of their own.
Scott: They're not bad at their job.
Scott: They're not canceled people, right?
Scott: You know, they're all quality animators.
Scott: But here's the problem.
Scott: They live in these cars, right?
Scott: I guess you can get remote work easily these days, I guess.
Scott: At least for now.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, if you live, if the job you have is somehow tied to the place you are, right?
Scott: And the thing is with animation, there's no, you know, reason that all the animation places should be located together other than that makes all the people in the industry live in that place so that they can, you know, all switch between the companies.
Rym: But it also makes it easier if you're doing that stuff to have a pool of people to hire.
Rym: Like, there's a reason why so many companies like Amazon want to be in New York City because they know there's a guaranteed critical mass of any possible profession.
Rym: There'll be 10 people coming to your door with resumes.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: So when a place is in, you have a business in a different kind of place, not an atypical geography.
Scott: Like, I know there's like video game studios that are occasionally, they seem to actually be spread out a bit, right?
Scott: They're not all centralized in one location.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: There's like four or five nexuses of a lot of game studios, like Prague of all places.
Rym: There's a lot of video game studios in Prague.
Scott: And then Carolina's got some, I think, right?
Scott: You know, but it's like, if you have a business, you'll, if you bring your business to like a small town or a small, a smaller city, right?
Scott: Say like a Rochester or a, an Ohio city or something like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, and it's like, you can sort of help that town a lot.
Scott: You boost their economy by building a company there by creating jobs there and such.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then if you're shut down though, it's like, it's like a double, it's like twice the pain, right?
Scott: Cause not only is that place now hurt, but those people, there's nowhere for them to work cause they're living in some small town, smaller city that you started in and not living in New York City or LA where they could just get another job.
Scott: No problem.
Scott: Um, so it's extra, it's extra sad and damaging on that level.
Scott: In addition to the normal level of, you know, this art producing thing is now shut and art, the art fountain is spreading out less art.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Even worse here in this particular case.
Rym: So like blue sky did really good stuff like the peanuts movie, which do you know, whether you, whether you liked it or not, right.
Scott: Well, you know, I didn't like, I'm not an ice age fan.
Rym: Did you ever see the peanuts movie?
Scott: Uh, which one?
Rym: The new one, the two, like from like 2015 dive nuts.
Rym: No, it's, it's a real good movie.
Rym: Like surprisingly good.
Rym: It's also beautiful.
Rym: It's in a unique style.
Scott: Well, isn't all the peanut stuff on Apple TV plus now.
Rym: I don't actually know.
Rym: I saw it on a plane.
Scott: I think Apple TV plus now has all the peanuts licensed stuff and I have an Apple TV plus free trial for a whole year cause I got an iPhone.
Rym: Well, Disney is absorbing all of blue skies, characters, and IP, all the stuff that they like directly own.
Scott: What's not clear is what's happening.
Scott: Disney doesn't own peanuts.
Rym: The other stuff, because one of the things, if you're listening to GeekNights, you've probably heard of Nimona.
Rym: You might know that blue sky was making the Nimona movie, which apparently was turning out fantastic.
Rym: Like this was a for real movie.
Rym: that was, it only had like 10 months left in production, according to this article.
Rym: And apparently when, with the change with Disney shutting them down, Disney's not absorbing that movie to finish it.
Rym: They're just canceling the entire thing.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Mouse guard movie got shut down.
Rym: Mouse guard movies suffered that same fate.
Rym: This is, we talk about this a lot.
Rym: A movie does not exist until it is in a theater or published because studios, there are entire ass movies that get made and then just burned.
Rym: Like that just happens.
Scott: I look forward to the people who were there, right?
Scott: Indirectly or directly releasing the materials they did produce via leaks or their resumes.
Scott: when they're applying for other jobs, their portfolios will contain things from the Nimona movie and we can see them that way.
Rym: It's a shame because I'm adjacent to like Emily.
Rym: We know a bunch of people who like work there and the best I can tell is that the Nimona movie was like an A plus movie and it was arguably, might've been the first like full on theatrical movie that was just based on a web comic.
Scott: Um, tough call maybe?
Rym: That Megatokio movie never happened.
Scott: No, good question.
Scott: But yeah, there have been more, um, there have been movies made based on, you know, indie comics or less than mainstream comics.
Rym: Well like Scott Pilgrim, the movie was made and it was based on that very short comic run.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: But a web comic like with a capital w like what we think of as web comics.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I think is, I think these days I don't really put web comic in a different category than just like, you know, it's like you happen to put your comic, you know, on a website, but it's like, I don't see that as any different than a comic, you know, that's like, okay, some independent individual creator wrote and drew a thing and published it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they happen to, whether you happen to put it in a book first and sell it to the comic book store or happen to like Scott Pilgrim or, you know, you get a deal with someone like, you know, one of the smaller publishers, um, and you get it out that way or you put it on a website.
Scott: I don't really see them.
Scott: Those as different categories.
Scott: Right.
Rym: There was a time when it was very distinct, but that was large because it was an error when there wasn't much else on the internet at the time.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: You know, I mean, it's, it's, it's not, I don't think it's ever coming back, but like I think of just, I think of just Cucumber Quest, right?
Scott: It's like, yeah, is it a web comic?
Scott: It came out on the website.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But also it's a book.
Scott: It's like, is it, it's a comic.
Scott: Was it, you know, which, whether you published it, which way doesn't change what, like you make it a different category than Penny Arcade.
Rym: What I feel like this movie might've done though.
Scott: It's not a different medium.
Scott: It's a different genre, obviously.
Rym: The reason it hadn't actually been able to come out is I think it would have opened the door to more movie studios looking to dig through back catalogs of web content to look for stuff that they can fund and make movies with.
Rym: Like it would have opened the door to another content mine.
Scott: Only if it was successful.
Rym: Yes, of course.
Rym: Only if it was successful.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, I think that's sort of the thing is, you know, you had your scout pilgrim.
Scott: It didn't make that much money, even though it's sort of a fantastic movie that became kind of a, it's kind of a thing, right?
Scott: But it didn't make a, it didn't make a fortune necessarily.
Scott: Um, so it's like, if someone comes out and is like, Hey, I made a movie based on some, you know, indie comic, I found it, you know, tea calf, right?
Scott: And it's a big hit.
Scott: Then you're going to see movie execs go in a tea calf to buy to things.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, but until then you're going to, this is, this is as far as it's gone.
Scott: right now is basically mouse guard movie being made canceled.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So, uh, what did I have here?
Rym: Right.
Rym: Uh, Shogi is a game that I, I appreciate.
Rym: Like it's, you know, some people, people talk about it as Japanese chess.
Rym: Like it's a chess like game.
Rym: If you've never played chess like game or Shogi, it's like the Duke.
Rym: But, uh, a difficulty that both chess and Shogi share is that if you look at the board and no one has taught you the game, fuck, if you're going to figure out what to do, like why would you know that the horse moves forward to and left or right one?
Rym: Like who's got, there's no way to figure that out from the looking at it.
Rym: Someone has to explain it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You need a rule book or an explanation and they need to memorize the way each piece moves and associate those movement patterns with those symbols, which, you know, it doesn't take that long.
Scott: I was able to do it.
Rym: But it's a barrier to entry.
Scott: I almost never play chess, but I could tell, I could teach you how to play at any time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, so it's not complicated, but it is yes.
Scott: A barrier to entry.
Rym: Because like I, when I was a kid, I was fascinated by chess cause like all the adults were playing it.
Rym: So I wanted to play, but I couldn't even poke at it until I memorized all these pieces.
Rym: So what I had was this not like checkers.
Scott: You don't got to know nothing.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: I use a little chess set that was like a fellow looking pieces and they just had arrows that showed how the piece I was moving moved.
Rym: So I could dive right into the game.
Scott: The Duke, each piece tells you how it moves on it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So this is a Kickstarter for a shogi set.
Rym: And the person who is pushing this, who like had the idea is a Monica.
Scott: Is it a Japanese person?
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It's a new Kickstarter.
Scott: I was going to say, I was hoping it was a Japanese person.
Scott: So it's not a cultural issue.
Rym: So Monica Kitau is pretty famous globally because she is an one.
Rym: She's a Nida.
Rym: Like she's a, she is like near the top, like the equivalent of a chess master.
Rym: Oh, she, her big thing is let's get more people, especially girls to play shogi globally.
Rym: Like let's advocate, let's get people to enjoy this game.
Scott: Yeah, that sounds good.
Rym: So basically she contacted this person.
Rym: There's a whole, you'd read the Kickstarter to see all the details to basically ask them if they could create a language neutral, easy to learn version of shogi to make it easy for people who have never played it before to jump right in and experience the mechanics of the game to fall in love with them.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: This is something, you know, I've played shogi maybe once or twice and I had like a little paper guide that told me how each piece moved because each piece has like a kanji written on it.
Scott: And I would look on the guide, say, oh, that piece moves like this, that piece moves like that.
Rym: Then the pieces can upgrade and then they move differently like the Duke.
Scott: And it, you know, I didn't do that.
Scott: well, but it's like, okay, it's a game I can see, you know, it's not bad.
Scott: Um, but it's like, I didn't get into it.
Scott: And, but it's like, you know, whether you're a child who, you know, like a Rym child looking at a chess set or even just an adult who doesn't know Japanese kanji, or even if you do know kanji, I don't know if that's necessarily going to help you know how each piece moves.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I could make a chess set where it says it's just the word king is written on the king piece.
Scott: I don't think that that helps you know how it moves.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: Like kings are slow and queens are just a moving field artillery.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Uh, but yeah, that's, uh, that's fantastic.
Scott: Uh, I don't know why there has to, this has to exist.
Scott: I can't believe it doesn't exist already.
Scott: It seems so obvious.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And the cool thing is this isn't just, I have seen shogi sets and chess sets that have like diagrams and things on the pieces.
Rym: This one goes further and the Kickstarter actually talks about why it was designed the way it was to make it completely language neutral to facilitate learning the game.
Rym: But also remember shogi has like the board, there's like a neutral zone and then the defensive zone and the attacking zone, but none of that's written on the board.
Rym: You have to just know the board itself is different to make it clear where the neutral zone is.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: It's little things like that.
Rym: It's just, it's really cleverly designed.
Rym: I'm backing it.
Rym: Uh, and it also includes three by three and four by four little boards with like slightly different rules to do like young child learning or like quick learning or kind of like how go players learn on small boards and then level up to bigger boards.
Scott: Ooh, I guess, you know, chess, I've never seen like smaller chess than regular chess.
Rym: The only smaller chess I've ever seen are chess problems, which you've got to be a particular kind of person to enjoy chess problems.
Rym: I actually enjoy chess problems more than I enjoy chess.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The only smaller chesses I've seen is like just regular old chess except the pieces are rethemed to be cute.
Scott: Like I think I've seen like a Simpsons chess set of that nature.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So yeah, I think of the day.
Scott: So I'll never forget.
Scott: when we went to see in New York, we went to see Will Wright talk this in the SimCity creator.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: And in the middle of his talk, we've told the story before, but in the middle of his talk, he just stopped and just was like, all right, time for the Russian space minute.
Scott: And he told us a story of the Russian space program of the Soviet space program.
Scott: And then he's like, all right, that's over.
Scott: And he went picked up right where he left off.
Rym: And the story was great.
Rym: It involved a pistol, wolves and teeth getting knocked down.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It was a horrific story.
Rym: It was horrific, but no one died.
Scott: But it was incredible.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, so here is something that's very GeekNights.
Scott: You know, we often think, you know, government secrets.
Scott: We're always thinking about US government secrets, right?
Scott: I guess occasionally UK government secrets, right?
Scott: But you don't often think about like, what secrets does the French government have?
Scott: You know, what secrets does the, I don't know, the Brazilian government have?
Scott: I'd really love to know what the Brazilian CIA equivalent has in their secret vault.
Scott: What kind of hidden knowledge.
Scott: And maybe that's just because it probably largely because of, you know, US centrism.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But even so, I, you know, I think people are, you know, when you think about government secrets, you're thinking about US government secrets.
Scott: They're the ones who know about the aliens.
Scott: It's not the Norwegian government that's hiding the secret alien info.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I just, I watched recently an old Unsolved Mysteries and one of the big ones was the Belgian government is covering up the UFOs.
Scott: Nice.
Scott: That would be awesome.
Scott: I'd love to see.
Scott: Anyway, but here we have, you know, in the US more recently, you know, not more recently, but over time that things become declassified, right?
Scott: And we find out about them and it's pretty cool.
Scott: Even in, apparently, Russia, classified things can get declassified.
Scott: And here are documents of declassified Russian space program things, not just rockets, but also space weapons.
Scott: These are things that the Soviet space program was actually working on or made.
Scott: And now it's declassified and released.
Scott: And here it is for your perusal, real stuff.
Rym: Fighting orbital laser station.
Rym: Here we go.
Scott: Probably not made up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Definitely worth a look.
Scott: Fake or real.
Scott: The spiral.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The aesthetic is A+ no matter what.
Rym: Especially the ones where there's a photo of the prototype or the actual thing in some cases.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So that's my thing of the day.
Rym: That's pretty good stuff.
Scott: Declassified Russian space program biz.
Rym: In the meta moment, GeekNights book club book that I'm feeling inklings toward reading the tale of game.
Scott: Same.
Scott: Because it's getting cold.
Scott: We've said that for a few weeks now.
Rym: Yeah, but I finished those two nonfiction books I kept saying I was working on.
Rym: And I had this sudden urge to read some science fiction.
Rym: And I thought that I said, Whoa, it's time to read fiction again.
Scott: But not, but not, not the first fiction.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, I'm going to go read the first fiction.
Scott: The first fiction ever.
Scott: Because the book club book is the tale of Genji.
Scott: Literally the first novel ever written by humans in the history of humans.
Scott: Period.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Undisputed.
Scott: No one's like arguing with that either.
Scott: It's like it's the first novel.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's older writings like, you know, the Iliad or the Odyssey, but those weren't novels.
Scott: So they don't, they're not the first novel.
Scott: They were poems.
Scott: Deal with it.
Rym: Otherwise stay tuned for whatever stuff we get up to online.
Rym: Follow us on all the internet places.
Rym: Check out our discord, check out these live streams and stay tuned.
Rym: A lot of the big projects that we keep deferring will probably get undiffered at some point in a post COVID world.
Rym: But it's just too much of a pain in the ass to record video separately right now.
Rym: So yeah, we'll get right into it.
Rym: We, uh, there's a lot, we haven't watched any new anime.
Rym: Scott's not watching the animated shows that I'm watching.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: You really should catch up on DuckTales.
Scott: I'm going to wait.
Scott: It's DuckTales is go.
Scott: So that's one of the things I want to talk about.
Scott: This is going to be over soon.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And as soon as that show is over, I'm probably going to go watch all of it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And I'm watching a lot of disenchantment.
Rym: I think there is going to be a season four so I can talk about it in the context of this episode, but take it away.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So yeah.
Scott: Uh, I said, Hey, you know, there's nothing that we've both seen to talk about and we can't think of any general topics to talk about.
Scott: Let's talk about what's coming that we haven't seen.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, early in the year we could, when we did, you know, wrap up of the previous decade, we could have easily copped out and gotten four easy episodes of like predict the next year, you know, forward, right.
Scott: The next year, the next decade in tech games.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So this is sort of that.
Scott: This is, Hey, let's look at the animations that have been announced.
Scott: We know are coming and we are interested in seeing and talk about what they are and why we're interested in seeing them.
Scott: And that way you can know what sort of, basically all of these things are going to have GeekNights episodes coming up in the near ish future the next year or year and a half, maybe two year.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Uh, so yeah, let's talk about some DuckTales.
Scott: We did an episode on the DuckTales, the new show, uh, when it first came out, we watched like the first few episodes.
Scott: And it's on D plus, I think.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I, uh, I've seen the first two seasons.
Rym: The third season is not on the D plus yet.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: However many seasons there are.
Scott: the ending of the show is going to be like a month from now.
Scott: on March 15th, they're going to put out the final final ending part.
Scott: I don't, I think it might, I heard it might be a little longer than a normal thought.
Scott: Maybe like it's going to be a big end.
Scott: It's going to be a big ending like the end.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I'm going to wait for that.
Scott: And then I'm probably just going to go back and just go right through the whole thing and all in one go.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: A few episodes, a few episodes a day till it's done.
Rym: Season two is pretty great.
Rym: The show, like you saw season, like you saw some of it, right?
Rym: Like the first couple of three episodes, maybe.
Rym: So you know how it was like funny, but, and like really like true to the ducks, but also like a little bit dangerous, a little bit dark, the darkness, like on the edges of the things they show on screen only increases as the show goes on.
Scott: Any sort of a gravity falls fashion?
Rym: In some cases, it actually gets a little darker than that.
Rym: Like in the second season, I would say in nearly every episode, at least one thing happens where the characters, like it happens and the characters react to it appropriately because it's a, it's a serious thing that happened.
Rym: But the implication of the thing that those characters just recognized is far more horrifying than like the show got into because something interrupts them and they move on.
Rym: The implications of what happens in every episode get increasingly terrifying as the show goes on.
Rym: I don't want to spoil anything, but there's a moment where a character dies and it's a, it's a whole thing.
Rym: Whoa.
Scott: All right, well let's focus on the things that are completely not out yet, right?
Scott: So we already talked about Earwig, right?
Scott: And how it's probably meh.
Scott: But Miyazaki still is working on some mysterious movie that'll be out when it's out, who knows when.
Scott: And you know, I'm not too sure.
Scott: Like is it, is it going to be like, you can never believe him when he says it's the final one.
Scott: He's cried wolf too many times.
Rym: No, like I get the impression the dude literally wants to die in the middle of his masterpiece.
Scott: Yeah, I think he doesn't want to, you know, he still smokes like a chimney as far as I'm aware, right?
Scott: So it's like, uh, I don't know how he's even still alive.
Rym: It must be the monkey, monkey spa.
Rym: You will live to make your greatest work.
Scott: Yeah, maybe.
Scott: But yeah, it's the title of it though.
Scott: How do you live?
Scott: really?
Scott: is the kind of title you give to like, you know, something like that.
Scott: Like a, like a grand philosophical thesis to end your overall, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, that's the kind of title you give to something that's like your last work.
Rym: I already felt like the wind rise.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know what the Japanese, I don't know what the Japanese title would be of how do you live.
Scott: I don't know if it's a direct translation or not, but, um, but yeah, you know, it's got the, it's like, I'm definitely going to see it whenever it comes.
Scott: If it comes, if he doesn't make it and it and finish it, will it be finished?
Scott: I'm going to lean towards.
Scott: No.
Scott: Um, if he does finish it, does he make something else?
Scott: I lean towards.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: But yeah, it's like, who knows?
Scott: Like, you know, I guess there's nothing to know about it.
Scott: It's just, you can't not mention that as the greatest looming coming animation that's in the world.
Scott: Right?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Um, so let's talk about something.
Scott: We can talk a lot more about.
Rym: I didn't realize he announced this back in 2017.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: When he announced that he came out of retirement because I realized we, you still haven't seen the wind rises.
Scott: You said I somehow I haven't seen, I've seen most, but not all.
Scott: That is one of the ones I haven't seen.
Scott: Did you see princess Kaguya?
Scott: Cause I remember I, we, I went to see that and you didn't.
Rym: That's the only one I haven't seen.
Scott: See this, you know, you haven't seen them all.
Scott: It's just 90% of them.
Rym: The wind rises is I, I feel like he wanted that one to be his last film.
Rym: considering the subject matter.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I know the subject matter and it definitely feels like a, you know.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So science Saru of course is working on something because they're just, they're just going at 11 all the time.
Scott: The, the, the Inu-O.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So we saw a little bit of work for this during Annecy.
Scott: There was like some preview stuff about it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it wasn't anything more than like some, you know, there, there wasn't much to go on.
Scott: Um, but regardless, obviously it's exciting just based on who's making it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Science Saru, bat in a thousand.
Rym: Everything they've made is just solid gold.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it's like, you know, even though, um, uh, it was, oh, isn't this the story of, uh, It's the child born horrific and they cover whatever his deformities are with a mask?
Rym: and he did.
Scott: I was thinking of, um, the, the, uh, Tezuka one where the guy has like no body parts and he gets his body parts back.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: It's not that.
Scott: It's not that one.
Scott: It's a different one.
Scott: Uh, but it's sorta, I guess in that same category.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, anyway, but yeah, that's, uh, you know, that's what that is.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I'm looking, I'm looking forward to it.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Here's something we can talk a lot about.
Scott: that's coming, right?
Scott: So since, right.
Scott: I remember when we were still going to Otakon, it must've been the late two thousands, right?
Scott: Eight or nine or something like that.
Scott: And the first evangelical movie, not the, um, you know, I guess the first evangelical movie was some technically like, you know, death and rebirth.
Scott: They're one of the end of evangelical.
Scott: One of those are technically movies, right?
Scott: But you know, the remake movies, right?
Scott: 1.0 to one, whatever they're all called, right?
Rym: You cannot do whatever you cannot finish this remake.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All of those, that whole series, even one, I have not watched even one second of them.
Scott: All I know is that the remakes of evangelical, the animation has, I guess, been updated with newer techniques and technologies.
Scott: Uh, there's that, there's that new character pilot who's purple, right?
Rym: Like that, the fact that they added that character instead of just doing the expansion of the characters that were originally intended for the original anime was what gave me pause to even like watch them in the first place.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There were other students in that classroom, uh, in the original TV series that would have piloted, you know, anyway.
Scott: Uh, but yeah, so my plan from that, even at Otakon, I had the opportunity to watch like the U S premiere.
Scott: I was right outside the room.
Scott: I could have just walked into the room and watched it for $0, right?
Scott: Money I already paid to get there.
Scott: I chose not to.
Scott: I said, you know what?
Scott: This is 1.0.
Scott: Uh, there's been this pattern where they've released 1.0 and then they updated it a little bit to be like 1.0 V2.
Scott: It's like, and then they did two and then they did two and then they updated that one.
Rym: Never forget when we watched Sailor Moon Crystal, they didn't even have the faces finished on the fucking characters when it first aired.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like they're like each of these movies has been released and then had a second like director's cut.
Scott: ish updated release afterwards.
Rym: Yo dog, I'm downloading Evangelion 4.4 dash one beta.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So the w the final one, supposedly they say that it's done.
Scott: I think we talked about that in a news item and that one is called 3.0 plus 1.0.
Scott: So it's not called 4.0.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's called 3.0 plus 1.0.
Scott: Um, but you know, there's going to be a 3.0 plus 1.0 director's cut, right?
Scott: And when that comes out, right, I believe I actually probably foolishly believe that the second updated release of this soon to be released movie will be the final one in the series.
Scott: And then at that point I will watch all in a row, the only the director's cut ones, all four of them, one, two, three, four, and I'm going to be a bit bam, bam, bam, bam.
Scott: And then we could probably get four GeekNights episodes out of that.
Scott: We'll probably do a whole two months.
Rym: Cause you know how much we love the original Evangelion.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, even though not everyone else loves it all, but we do.
Rym: Our point we made repeatedly is you don't have to love it, but you got to respect what it was.
Rym: There's a reason why people like us keep talking about it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the that's going to happen.
Scott: So the news, the most recent news I've heard is that the, the 3.0 plus 1.0, which I'm is not out yet.
Scott: And I'm not going to watch till it has a director's cut is apparently like over like two and a half hours long.
Rym: It's like, I mean, it says runtime theatrical edition of the whole thing, 556 minutes.
Scott: Oh, for all of them combined.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Uncut edition, 309 minutes, but it's ongoing.
Scott: So how, how many, what's the combined minutes of the 26 episode TV series?
Rym: 24 times 26 comparable.
Scott: It's like 624.
Scott: It's almost as long as watching the whole TV series.
Rym: We watched that the whole weekend.
Scott: It is no surprise that they can fit the same amount of material in there, especially since they don't need like recappy kind of stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Cause it's movies.
Scott: Um, yeah, I am, I am actually have been looking forward to watching all those for like a decade, good or bad.
Scott: I'm just not doing it.
Scott: And like, like same with DuckTales, not doing it.
Rym: I have to just because I enjoy the, like what Evangelion was and I want to see if they add more to it.
Rym: Like if there's more to take away from this compared to the original.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I'll probably, I imagine I'll still come out of it thinking that the original is the original and this is just some other deal, but you know, it's still interesting to see how they do differently.
Scott: What they thought needed changing, what they, you know, if there's any, you know, it could, they could reveal information that is true of the original right in this remake, even though it's a different timeline situation.
Rym: Well, the manga kind of did that.
Rym: One thing is if you are seeking to engage more with what the original anime did, like if you want to just to go deeper on those themes, you can, you can't really go much better than the manga.
Rym: The Evangelion manga is fucking fantastic.
Rym: I didn't even read it all because it was coming out so slowly.
Rym: I read a bunch of it and I had like, it's near the top of my queue to read that entire manga start to finish.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So let's talk about the thing we talked about in the news, which is Belle, the new Hosoda movie, right?
Scott: So Mamoru Hosoda, right?
Scott: Summer Wars, Boy and the Beast, right?
Scott: You know, Wolf Children.
Rym: Batting a thousand.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not, not all of these movies are like S tier, but there are, none of them are bad.
Rym: They're all A at least.
Scott: Yeah, they're all like pretty good.
Rym: I think Summer Wars might be S tier.
Scott: Summer Wars was just- Summer Wars is I think S tier.
Rym: Like what a chef kiss.
Scott: That's definitely my favorite of them for sure.
Rym: What I'm excited about with Belle is that it's diving, it's going deep into that same kind of world where everyone is online and like the Uber MMO slash social network to rule them all.
Scott: Something like that.
Scott: The only thing we know about this, right, is what the imagery that we've seen in this trailer and the preview image, which is also part of the trailer.
Scott: And it's like, it just looks, it gives you some, you know, Hosoda vibes from Summer Wars.
Scott: It also gives me some Satoshi Kon like Paprika kind of vibes.
Scott: And it's just like, you know, like this, like, you know, creating some sort of stunning fantastical world, right?
Scott: Oh, yes.
Scott: Mirai was also a Hosoda movie, right?
Scott: I think you can just watch Mirai on Netflix now.
Scott: Mirai was great.
Scott: It's on some of the streaming service.
Scott: I don't know which ones.
Rym: But this one, the Japanese title of this one is The Dragon and the Freckled Princess.
Scott: Ooh, interesting.
Rym: It's definitely, if you look at the teaser, there's big Beauty and the Beast vibes.
Scott: There is definitely some sort of fantasy element mixed in with this sort of, you know, somewhat vaguely utopian cyberspace.
Rym: Like the main character meets this, like, dragon person online.
Rym: as far, like, as best we can see.
Rym: There's something about, like, the studio said something to the effect of the show is about interspecies communication.
Rym: And we don't know anything else about it.
Scott: No, no, it gives me a little bit of, you know, just the vibes I get from what we've seen is a little bit of Laputa.
Scott: But not Laputa in the sense of, oh, people uncovering some, you know, lost thing.
Scott: But, like, that lost civilization in the sky at its height, right?
Scott: And you're seeing what's happening there, which is what I always want to see.
Scott: I always ask for that.
Scott: Don't give me the story of the ruined kingdom, right?
Scott: Show me the kingdom when it was the best awesome kingdom.
Rym: But then that story is likely going to be, and it falls into ruin.
Scott: No, how about the awesome kingdom becomes awesomer?
Rym: From one frame, there's definitely a sea of people basically adding the dragon, telling them that they don't have any reason to exist.
Rym: It looks like it's fairly existential, and from what little we've seen, the animation just looks beautiful.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: Let's see, I am still... So, does a Disney movie come in, like, imminently, Raya and the Last Dragon?
Scott: Okay, I haven't heard about that until you mentioned it earlier today, so tell me about it.
Rym: So it looks like a standard, like, Disney movie, but the thing that looks really cool about it is, it looks like it's about a woman who, like, meets a dragon who might be the last dragon, like, Dragonheart style.
Rym: But the dragon's character design...
Scott: The story I've heard before.
Rym: Looks really fun.
Rym: Like, the dragon looks a lot more like a dragon from, like, a My Little Pony type world, but 3DCG.
Scott: Is it going to be, like, Aladdin Genie kind of dragon?
Scott: That kind of character?
Rym: No, it's more like the dragon, she is just not that good at being a dragon and trying not to get killed by people.
Scott: So a combination of, uh, Dragonheart and how to train your dragon?
Rym: Uh, yeah, I get both of those vibes combined.
Scott: So much dragon action.
Rym: There's a lot of dragon action right now.
Scott: There's not a lot you knew you could do with dragons.
Scott: You gotta be pretty good to...
Rym: Well, I mean, we had Wolf, like, Hot Wolfman was the theme for a while now.
Rym: And now we're edging into dragon action.
Rym: We got the dragon in the belly and the dragon in this.
Scott: We really need someone to go, we've seen, there's owls, right?
Scott: There's that whole series of movies, I haven't watched any of them.
Scott: Like, the Kahool or whatever it's called.
Rym: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Scott: The only reason I know those exist is because I've seen them train.
Rym: The owl thing.
Rym: You've gotta watch the owl house.
Scott: Yeah, what I'm saying is, like, we have owl things, we have dragon things, we have wolf things, right?
Scott: We need some other animal action, right?
Scott: We have some insect things, there's like ants and bugs, and there's some fish things, we got Nemo.
Scott: But there are so many animals in the world.
Rym: Chicken run, we had a lot of farm animal stuff over the years.
Scott: Alright, we got dogs and cats are covered, right?
Scott: Let's see, we got Bambi, kind of animal...
Rym: Horses and ponies have had their day.
Scott: Birds, is there like a bird thing?
Scott: Ducks, duck tails!
Scott: That's a duck thing, yeah, okay.
Rym: There's been a duck tail.
Scott: Has every animal been turned into a thing?
Scott: And I just keep thinking there must be, there's a jellyfish, the jellyfish show.
Rym: Princess jellyfish.
Scott: There's a penguin thing, but there's no... Princess jellyfish is not about jellyfish.
Rym: It's about aliens.
Rym: that, yeah, anyway.
Scott: I'm talking about, yeah, I'm talking about literal, something about literal jellyfish.
Scott: The same way that, you know, Bambi is about deer.
Scott: Make a story about jellyfish.
Rym: Yeah, they're adjacent in Ponyo.
Rym: Arguably because of what Ponyo's about.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Alright, fine, there's no animals left to go on.
Rym: Oh, the listener came through.
Rym: Capybaras deserve feature films.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: I want to see a slice of life anime that is just Capybaras chilling and solving problems for their community.
Scott: This is actually a pretty good, like, almost Jackbox game where it's like, name an animal, then you gotta name an artwork in which that animal appears.
Rym: Then you do the chain, and the next person has to name a different animal that's in that artwork, and then the next person has to name a different artwork that has that next animal.
Scott: Ooh.
Scott: That's a real good chain game.
Scott: Alright, so I'll start with, like, uh, you know, uh...
Rym: Come on, sorry, Babe!
Scott: Well, Babe has a pig in it.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: And Babe also has, I guess there must be a cow in there somewhere, it's a farm, right?
Rym: Are you 100% sure?
Scott: No.
Scott: I haven't seen Babe in 100, since it came out.
Scott: I saw it one time.
Scott: We need a mechanic, we can challenge the person.
Scott: I mean, also, in my brain, right, it's like, uh, you know, Babe and Charlotte's Web occupy a lot of the same space.
Scott: Obviously, the final scene with, like, some pig written on the web is from Charlotte's Web.
Scott: But the entire rest of the story in both of those is merged, other than the ending and the presence of the spider.
Scott: The spider parts are clearly in the Charlotte's Web zone, but all the rest of the parts of both of those things are combined into one brain space.
Scott: So, alright, there's probably
Rym: a ton of things we didn't even talk about, but there's also all the things that are just continuing that we've watched some of, that we want to watch more of, and I think I realized, I tried to stack rank, and it was actually hard to stack rank for myself, of all the things, all the animation I'm watching that is currently paused, which one I want most.
Scott: It's gotta be Adventure Time movies, right, because we're doing GeekNights episodes on those, I'm watching those immediately if they appear.
Scott: But I had, like, what else?
Rym: What am I looking forward to more?
Rym: The next Adventure Time, which is Peppermint Butler going to wizard school, which puts it way up there.
Scott: Nothing can, what can possibly beat that, unless the Ghibli movie gets released tomorrow.
Rym: For me, personally, Castle Vassal.
Scott: I like the Castle Vassal a lot, but I don't think it beats Peppermint Butler going to wizard school.
Rym: I think this might be a Roman Scott epic, because for me, Castlevania, like, digs back to the first anime I ever saw.
Scott: You are, yeah, you are a vampire person.
Rym: Yeah, Vampire Hunter D was, like, is probably the reason I live here today.
Rym: Like, it set me on the course that put me in front of this microphone.
Scott: Listen, there is no question that the day that Castlevania season drops on Netflix, I will watch all of it, right?
Scott: There is no question whatsoever, right, and this is someone who puts everything in the queue, right?
Rym: That is true.
Scott: That is true, right?
Scott: But at the same time, there is no question that if the Peppermint Butler drops, right, I'll be watching that on the same day.
Scott: Right, that I can pirate it, or if I somehow happen to have an HBO, I might have an HBO Max subscription even, or who knows.
Scott: But if they were to drop on the same day, and I finish my work, and it's time to go watch, I'm going to watch Pee Butt first.
Rym: Fuck, I realized I would too, but only because Pee Butt is just one thing, and then I can binge on all of Castlevania uninterrupted, because there's a whole ass season of that coming.
Scott: If they drop on a Saturday morning, and I have all fucking day.
Rym: They're all getting watched.
Scott: I'm watching Pee Butt first, and then I'm watching Cast... Right?
Scott: That's what's going down.
Rym: But right up there is season two of Beastars.
Scott: Oh, season two of Beastars is up there.
Scott: I don't know if I would watch that immediately, but I would watch it quickly.
Rym: I would watch it immediately, but like the first episode, but then I'd do the thing of just watching an episode a week to try to like drag it out.
Scott: Okay, there are some other things that if, just Dragon Prince, which I haven't even watched all the Dragon Prince.
Rym: Dragon Prince is the only thing of the things we haven't talked about yet that's higher on my list than Dragon Prince is more of the Owl House.
Scott: Yeah, I haven't watched any Owl House.
Scott: It's in the queue.
Rym: Take Gravity Falls and make it just better and darker.
Scott: Owl House is in the queue.
Rym: And funnier.
Scott: I like what's going on there with the owl, but you know.
Rym: Yeah, and I know I probably misrepresent how much Hootie features in the Owl House.
Scott: Hootie is a kid's side character.
Scott: I'm aware that Hootie is a bit side character because I can see from the screenshots and gifs that Hootie is attached to a door and therefore would only appear in the show when the show is in that house or the Owl House.
Rym: Pretty much, and I feel like that is very-.
Scott: The rest of the time, I imagine a lot of the show takes place not at the, you know, I guess, what's the word?
Rym: The Owl House.
Rym: It's called the Owl House.
Rym: The house is called the Owl House.
Scott: What's the word for when some eponymous Owl House, that's the word?
Rym: Nominative determinism for the eponymous Owl House.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: But I'm actually real excited about Dragon Prince, not just because there's more of it, because I really like it, but because they committed.
Rym: It wasn't just announced, oh, they're going to make another season.
Scott: A pile of seasons.
Rym: They're going to make all the seasons, as in the original creative vision of what Dragon Prince was supposed to be will complete.
Rym: So I don't have to worry about season nonsense.
Rym: The whole story is going to get told.
Rym: And honestly, where it ended was a real interesting point.
Rym: Like, it escalated rapidly, and if there's going to be this many more seasons, this is like the big epic fantasy that I'm here for.
Scott: Some other things I just want to mention, right?
Scott: So One Punch Man had a second season.
Scott: I've only seen the first, but the manga keeps going, so you have to imagine at some point something that popular is going to get- They're not just going to stop.
Scott: They could, I guess.
Scott: There have been other anime series, like Hajime no Ippo, they didn't animate the whole manga.
Scott: They just sort of animated a bunch of it and stopped, and that was it.
Scott: But if they make more One Punch Man, I'm looking forward to that.
Scott: I don't think any has been announced.
Scott: Similar thing with the Yo-Yo Pedal, right?
Scott: Yo-Yo Pedal, they animated a whole bunch of the manga, and then they just stopped.
Scott: I don't know if they're waiting for more manga, or if they're just not going to make any more of an anime, and you just got to read the manga to get the rest of the story.
Scott: But if there was more Yo-Yo Pedal anime, I would watch that also.
Scott: It just hasn't come, or it won't come, who knows.
Rym: So one thing I'm actually- I don't think you've really watched much of it, but Disenchanted, that Matt Groening show, that the reviews- The Fantasy Futurama.
Scott: that's on Netflix.
Rym: Yeah, the reviews across the board.
Scott: I know it exists.
Rym: It's okay.
Rym: It's alright.
Rym: It's not great.
Rym: It's not bad.
Rym: But I'm watching it now, partly because we got through the queue of all the other animation we wanted to watch.
Rym: And the thing I want to say about it is that I'm actually really looking forward to a fourth season.
Rym: I don't even know for sure if there will be a fourth season.
Rym: Uh-oh.
Scott: I assume there will, because I- So I'm assuming, I guess, the third season you just watched did not end it.
Rym: So we're not- we're near- we have like two more episodes to go in the third season, and it- Oh, so it could end.
Rym: You know, so here's the thing.
Rym: You know those episodes in Evangelion, like near the end, where like the pacing gets really weird?
Rym: Like the show just really slows down and zooms in?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Disenchanted kind of did that, like near the end of the third season.
Rym: Like there's a couple episodes where like the pacing gets really, really atypical and odd and slow.
Rym: And it feels like it's doing something.
Rym: Like it feels like the show's going to try to be more than it appeared to be.
Rym: And I'm intrigued by this.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: It's also like pretty funny.
Rym: Like it's a slow burn funny.
Rym: Like it feels very like, okay, it's just Futurama humor.
Rym: But as it goes on, it kind of builds on itself, and King Zog just gets funnier and funnier and funnier, and I cannot get over that character.
Scott: Okay, well I can't think of any more.
Scott: There's no- I'm sure there's plenty of other animation in the world that is being made now announced and unannounced that I'm very interested in and simply unaware of.
Scott: Like Studio Trigger's probably working on something.
Rym: Oh, the listener comes through.
Rym: Supposedly there are six intended seasons for Disenchanted.
Scott: Very nice.
Rym: There's just no date yet for season four.
Scott: Yeah, Makoto Shinkai's probably working on something again, even though he just released something, right?
Scott: You know, there's stuff coming.
Scott: We just don't know about it yet, or whatever.
Scott: Or I just personally don't know about it yet, even though it might be public.
Scott: So if you know of other animations' works from anywhere in the world that you're looking forward to, you should let us know so we don't miss them.
Rym: We'll put them in the hopper, because for like five years now we've just been living in this golden age of amazing animation.
Rym: And it doesn't seem like that train is slowing down at all.
Scott: Uh, thankfully not.
Scott: So, I'm gonna go eat dinner.
Rym: I smell some food in there.
Rym: I'm like salivating right now.
Scott: Okay, bye.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Link EG, Graham Finch, you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: Now go through the last year or so of podcasts and make Rym, Sink, Clinton, Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan, Perrin, Review, Mad Bull, 34, Cowards, Dread, Lily, Tenebrae, just like a dude guy.
Rym: Chris Reimer, Finn, Shervin, Vothole, and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: You might have noticed a while ago that the Patreon for some reason was 18 plus.
Rym: Patreon did that on their own, and when I asked them why, they could not tell me why and they undid it.
Rym: So, we'll see what that was all about, but the Patreon should be more visible just out in the wild now.
Rym: Otherwise, I'll just leave you with... That school wants you to drink the water.
Rym: It's bad water.
Scott: Don't drink the water.
Rym: See?
Scott: That means good, right?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Jake?
Scott: Why are you making stupid face?
Rym: Who's Jake?
Rym: Dang it, I knew that water was junk.
Rym: If you awaken from this illusion and you understand that black implies white, self implies other, life implies death, or shall I say, death implies life, you can feel yourself.
Rym: Not as a stranger in the world.
Rym: Not as something here on... Jake!
Rym: Get out of that water right now!