Scott:
Rym: It's Monday, May 24th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we are talking about video cameras.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, I did actually, you know, I'm fully vaccinated.
Rym: Like, I'm way past the two weeks after my second shot.
Rym: So, uh, I went back into my office once today.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: I've not gotten even to Manhattan's except for to get vaccinated and to go to the dentist once.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: I mean, so even now, having done this, I can count on one hand the number of buildings I have been inside since the weekend after PAX East last year.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Pretty much, yeah.
Rym: This one CVS this one time on a bike ride, uh, because I wasn't even going to grocery stores because, you know, delivery.
Scott: Oh, right.
Scott: I went to the grocery store.
Rym: But still, that counts as one building.
Scott: Oh, I went to two.
Scott: Actually, there are a few grocery stores.
Rym: Oh.
Scott: Family Market.
Scott: We got a Family Market over here.
Rym: Yup, but now it's at the point...
Scott: There were some takeout.
Scott: There were some times.
Scott: I got takeout and I went in, got the takeout, and walked out.
Rym: I was weirdly able to avoid that for almost the entire quarantine because all the places that did pick up had outdoor pickup places.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: It's not a big deal to walk in and grab something off a table and walk out.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: No, we had... Both of our households were pretty prudent and also lucky in that we didn't have the free... Because, you know, statistically, low odds aren't zero odds, so if you do everything right, you could just get fucked.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: But we pulled out.
Rym: okay.
Rym: so far, so my observations going to Manhattan is one.
Rym: There is still, like, nobody in Manhattan.
Rym: Like, it is just a ghost town.
Rym: Like, there's almost no traffic.
Rym: There's no one on the street.
Scott: When I went to the dentist and when I went for the vaccine, there was less people, right?
Scott: So the vaccine was, what, six to eight weeks ago when I went?
Scott: And it's like, yeah, Times Square.
Scott: It's like, there were, you know, there was a hot dog vendor and, like, no one buying hot dogs.
Scott: I think I saw one blob of tourists, right?
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Stuff is still closed, though, so why would tourists be there, right?
Scott: It's like, the Broadway is like, "Oh, we're going to open September.
Scott: It's way far.
Scott: It's months
Scott: away.".
Rym: Yeah, but New York's not an amusement park, even as much as tourists think it is.
Rym: Like, if you just show up here, it doesn't dedicate you.
Scott: Let's come to New York on vacation, guys.
Scott: What are we going to do?
Scott: Stay in a hotel?
Scott: Buy a hot dog?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: What else is open?
Scott: The gift shop was open.
Scott: You could buy an island of New York.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: You can do all the things that are only fun to people who live here.
Scott: Get vaccinated.
Scott: That's what you can do.
Rym: Like, what do I do in New York?
Rym: Go hang out in our amazing parks.
Scott: Don't fly here to do that.
Scott: Yeah, the park wasn't open until recently, so that's not the street.
Scott: That's the park.
Scott: So I'm sure if you go to the park, there's plenty of people.
Rym: Dude, pretty much everything is closed, like, permanently closed.
Rym: Like, there's so much empty real estate that it was surprising.
Scott: Well, there was before, and now there's more.
Rym: Yeah, there's so much is empty, and all the places, with one exception, that I have ever, like, eaten lunch at on purpose more than once near my office are gone and replaced with more generic chains.
Rym: Like, all the Maison Caillé's are all gone and replaced by the shitty version of Le Pen-Quotidien.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So, like, there weren't a lot of lunch places.
Rym: The category market is still open and just fine.
Rym: Like, they're just totally normal.
Rym: And also, at least, everyone's still wearing masks, except when they're, like, alone outside.
Rym: Like, every store still has their mask signs up.
Rym: People are still being pretty cautious in New York compared to other places.
Scott: Yeah, it seems like, you know, my office, I only know what's going on there because of, you know, Slack messages, right?
Scott: But it seems like there's more people there than there were.
Scott: They had, like, a very regimented system, and it seems like very few people were participating in it previously.
Scott: And now it feels, I think, that basically what they, I can't, I don't know exactly what system they have now, but it feels like, based on what I'm seeing, is that, yeah, it's like people who want to go back there are just sort of back there now, you know.
Rym: Yeah, we're at a, like, no one wants to go back.
Rym: Like, I know a few people who, like, wanted to go back to the office full time, and that is not the majority opinion.
Scott: Even if I go back there, basically no one on my team of people is there, right?
Scott: So what am I gaining by going there?
Rym: Oh, no, I was only there performatively because, you know, like, I'm a highly visible, like, pretty senior manager, but seriously, almost all my engineering teams aren't even in the US.
Rym: Like, they're in places where they can't even get the vaccine.
Rym: Even if there was no COVID, they're all remote.
Rym: Like, almost no one I need to talk to is physically in the same building as me.
Scott: They do keep sending out messages lately of, like, all the food that's in the office.
Rym: Yeah, we're getting a lot of that too.
Rym: They're like, "Hey, we added...".
Scott: In the New York City channel, it's always like, "Free food on 14, guys.
Scott: Come
Scott: on.".
Scott: And it's like, it's sort of like, "Oh, come back to the office and get free
Scott: food.".
Rym: Yeah, you're not tricking me.
Rym: You gave me free food all the time when I was in the office, and I didn't even eat it then.
Rym: You think I'm gonna eat it now?
Scott: My thought is, you know, if I do go back there, I'll be sure to only go back on the days when the food is...
Rym: Nah, Taco Tuesday.
Rym: My plan is to go back in one day a week, and...
Scott: Well, isn't that because you're required to?
Rym: Yeah, well, so it's one of those, I am not officially yet required to.
Rym: However, as a highly visible person, I am expected to show up semi-regularly, and it's all kind of a statistics game and whatever.
Scott: Just don't.
Scott: Just be like, "Fuck you.
Scott: Make
Scott: me.".
Rym: Yeah, I'll go out one day a week.
Rym: It was novel enough, but I will say, I was way less productive in the office than I would have been at home because, you know what my day was?
Rym: A million meetings with people who are at home using the shittier work computer with the shittier headphones and the shittier webcam.
Scott: I don't know if I'm more, you know, it's like, am I more or less productive in the, you know, maybe in the office, maybe actually more productive because I don't have the good screen next to the bad screen.
Rym: Yeah, but at work, it's not...
Scott: If I'm more productive, that's a problem.
Scott: Also, the time, you know, even if I am more productive in the office somehow, and I want to be more productive, what about the time I'm losing going to and from the office, just riding a train?
Scott: Well,
Rym: the thing is, I think, so I think the entirety of the tech and even to a broader set like capital markets sector, like the technology enabled stuff in New York, I think there's going to be a huge exodus of people who are asked to come back into the office, but moved away and are just going to quit and try to find a job.
Scott: People on my team moved away.
Scott: Oh, I know a lot of people.
Scott: Everyone's got different backgrounds on their video chats.
Rym: A lot
Scott: of people moved
Rym: and a lot of people also, I know I've run into a lot of people who had the long commute for a long time, like people who unlike us just stayed upstate, like that's just their life doing an hour commute and they didn't think much of it previously.
Rym: Like they'd resigned themselves to having that long commute, but now they had a year of not doing that commute and they realized how soul sucking it is and they can't go back to it.
Rym: But they also can't afford to buy a place in the city.
Scott: Aren't they right?
Scott: If they're Bloomberg, shouldn't they be getting paid a fortune?
Rym: It depends on what the job is.
Rym: And also, part of the reason why I feel like I'm being paid a fortune is that I am a dink.
Rym: I don't have any responsibilities.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Most of the people I know who worry about that kind of thing have multiple kids and possibly own a house.
Scott: Well, who told you do that?
Rym: Yeah, I'm pretty happy with my, if I work from home, my commute is 45 seconds because I just kind of roll out of bed and go to my first meeting and then I brush my teeth.
Scott: Whether I commute or even on Saturday, I go to the same chair.
Rym: But even if I go to the office, it's a 12-minute commute, maybe?
Rym: But the other thing, I took a city bike there because you have to get COVID tests before you even go into the building.
Rym: So I didn't want to deal with having to stash my bike and go out and I just took a city bike.
Rym: And they only had e-bikes at the city bike station, Darros.
Rym: All e-bikes.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot more.
Scott: I had to pay $1.30 to get one.
Scott: Oh, you paid?
Scott: Oh, when I used my...
Rym: E-bikes aren't free.
Scott: Last time I city biked, I actually had to walk to a different dock to get a non-e-bike.
Rym: There was literally, the dock was completely full and it was all but one where e-bikes, the non-e-bike, was broken.
Scott: Yeah, just go to the next dock.
Rym: The next dock is like five minutes away.
Rym: I have to walk to it.
Scott: Okay, well then pay money.
Rym: I paid the $1.30 and the e-bikes are alright.
Rym: But I did learn something I didn't think about because these are e-bikes that are designed to make people not hurt themselves.
Rym: And they're designed to not drive unless you're pedaling.
Rym: It makes sense.
Rym: So what I discovered is I was going down the Queensboro Bridge and I was like,
Rym: "Yeah.".
Rym: So it seems to figure out if I'm pedaling, if I'm pushing against.
Rym: the gearing above a certain threshold is when the power assist kicks in and it seems to increase if I push harder.
Rym: So I pedaled as hard as I could on a downhill to see what would happen.
Scott: To just crash into the wall and die?
Rym: I was able to get pretty fast for a city bike.
Scott: You don't say.
Rym: I got about 40 miles an hour, which is way slower than I can go on my real bike.
Rym: But I did not think I would get a city bike up to 40 miles an hour.
Scott: You didn't.
Scott: The motor did.
Rym: I got it there with the motor's help.
Scott: The motor was doing most of the work.
Rym: The fastest I've ever gone on a bike.
Scott: this was exactly 51 miles an hour.
Rym: And that was on a mountain bike in the mountains of Tennessee when I was in middle school.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: That was a bad idea.
Scott: You don't say.
Rym: Basically we were driving on a family trip.
Rym: We'll get into the news.
Rym: And we're on the mountains and we're going to take this exit that goes down a really, really long downhill ramp to this parking lot thing.
Rym: And my parents were like, "Hey, you guys want to bike down
Rym: that?".
Rym: And we're like, "Fuck yeah!
Rym: We just got on our bikes and just went
Rym: down.".
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It was awesome.
Rym: Anyway, got any tech news?
Scott: I do have a tech news, so check this out.
Scott: Where was it again?
Scott: There it is.
Rym: Free node?
Scott: Oh, do you want to do the free node one first?
Scott: Okay, so if people don't know, free node is a very old IRC network.
Scott: And what free node is, is an IRC network specifically for the open source community.
Scott: So all the major open source projects out there, even I guess until recently, and maybe even still today if they're not aware of what's going on.
Scott: Usually if you start an open source project and you have a community of people who are actually like developers, and you also need maybe to provide support to users because you're like a real project.
Scott: You're not just something one guy made and slept on on GitHub.
Scott: You generally will start a free node channel, an IRC channel on the free node network.
Scott: And then people will know that generally, "Oh, this is a somewhat major open source project.
Scott: I need help with
Scott: it.".
Scott: Or, "I'm getting more involved with
Scott: it."
Scott: And they'll know that there's going to be a free node channel for it.
Scott: And they go there and they join the channel and there's the other developers and that's what you use.
Scott: You didn't have like a Discord for your open source project.
Scott: You don't need more than one channel.
Scott: You just need the one channel.
Scott: What else is there to talk about?
Scott: It's just the project.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: So what happened was it's one of those situations that we're seeing, I guess, of this pattern of free node is sort of like a foundation.
Scott: I don't even know what its technical organization is or was, but it's one of those sort of like non-profiting groups.
Scott: I don't know if it's actually a 401(c)(3) nonprofit, but it's a foundation or something like that, some sort of organization that is not for profit.
Scott: It's just, you know, maybe it has a board or something.
Scott: I don't fucking know.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think about IRC much, nor have I for about 15 years.
Scott: But it's basically just benevolently administered for the sake of the people and the community.
Scott: It's not trying to make money.
Scott: It's not trying to do anything.
Scott: It's just, you know, doing, you know, taking some donations and paying people the bare minimum to keep this thing up, updated, stable, running, you know, and so forth.
Scott: You know, volunteers doing, you know, just whatever you got to do to keep the lights on, you know, this rock of the community of open source software.
Scott: So what happened recently was this thing I've seen happen before where some sort of profiting organization somehow ends up taking control via means or another, right?
Scott: I think in this case, I heard some stories like there was a profiting group that was helping with like conferences on the side, you know, but somehow the contract wording and they ended up grabbing more ownership legally speaking or some business like that, right?
Rym: I skimmed this article and couldn't quite make out exactly what went down without deeper reading that I didn't care to do.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But this has happened a few times.
Scott: .org was almost taken over by a for profit entity, but that was stopped, thankfully.
Scott: But there have been some other incidents.
Scott: I just can't think of any right now.
Scott: This definitely isn't the first.
Scott: Regardless, you know, there's been a lot of hearsay from different people.
Scott: I saw one person write a story about how, you know, because they were worried about the state of free node, they opened, they moved, they had like a bot channel and they moved.
Scott: They started, they relaunched the bot channel on a different IRC network.
Scott: And in the free node channel, they mentioned that they had moved in the subject line of the IRC channel.
Scott: And then they found, and then later on, some, one of the admins of free node who is with the new owners, you know, sort of reset the channel and kick them out and reset the subject.
Scott: But that's just a story.
Scott: I guess I could have gone logged into IRC to check and verify, but you know, whatever.
Scott: But one thing that I saw that basically gave a lot of credence to all of these rumblings that basically free node is dead.
Scott: Everyone moved to this other IRC network now.
Scott: I forget the name of the new IRC network people are moving to, but is on the GitHub for free node.
Scott: And like the code of conduct area, right?
Scott: You can see, I saw it on GitHub.
Scott: There was basically this, you know, commit that was removing the language in the code of conduct that said like, you know, don't be racist, domophobic, transphobic, et cetera, et cetera.
Scott: And that language just got removed.
Scott: And there was a comment that was like, oh, so it's okay to just say racist shit on free node?
Scott: No.
Scott: The comment was along those lines.
Scott: So, yeah, whoever took over free node, someone took it over somehow.
Scott: And now all those open source, you know, people are probably going to slowly figure out what's going on and move off of free node.
Scott: Looks like they're moving to LiberaChat.
Scott: Yes, that's the one.
Scott: LiberaChat is now the new is the new free node, apparently.
Scott: So, yeah, it had a long, long life.
Scott: I don't know what they hope to gain from owning it, like they're messing with it.
Scott: Like, well, I don't understand.
Scott: with these kind of people who are smart enough to run IRC servers aren't going to pay for them when they can run their own and when discord exists and when slack.
Scott: And it's like, what were you hoping to do here?
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Rym: More of the power play was people who had a weird personal, like anti progressive agenda.
Rym: I don't know what to see that every now and then.
Rym: Like, look at the point of doubling down on supporting who shall not be named.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you need to go to the IRC channel to get support for an open source thing, go to the Libera, whatever, and not the free node.
Rym: I would argue, because actually is the lead into my news a little bit, but I would argue that the culture of go to the IRC to get support is a big part of why a lot of people don't use open source software.
Scott: Well, it's usually you're going there not just to get, you know, run of the mill support.
Scott: You're going there for like the deep, the deep support.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, you're even like.
Rym: I have a lot of men who basically the IRC is one of those things that like really old people talk about sometimes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You go there because like you're involved in developing the project and you need something like you need to actually have a conversation that you can't even do on like the pull request comments or anything.
Scott: You really need to.
Rym: And it's interesting because on one hand, I feel like most newer projects and things that aren't tied to old open source culture would probably just make a discord.
Scott: But, well, usually you can get almost everything.
Scott: these days you can just handle with your GitHub issues and those sorts of things.
Scott: You don't really need the chat room, basically, but you the chat room is more for the developers themselves, right?
Scott: Because like at my work, we need a chat room amongst us developers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Our GitHub issues aren't enough for your JIRA isn't enough for whatever you're using.
Rym: Like the JIRA is add this thing or do this thing, but you got to decide what's the architecture.
Scott: The IRC is basically the actual developers need to have a chat room for themselves and then it's just open.
Scott: If you really need to go, you can actually talk to them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's what it is.
Scott: It's not for the everyday.
Scott: get help.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So we'll see.
Rym: I mean, I don't know how much impact this news would even have.
Rym: Like how many people care, think about this at all, would even notice?
Scott: There's a lot of people on Freenode.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But like how many?
Scott: The open source, a large amount of the open source community is on there.
Rym: Oh, let's see.
Rym: Freenode has, according to Wikipedia, has an average of like 80,000 users globally.
Scott: No, that's about right.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: That rounds down to basically zero.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: You could have said 800,000 or 8 million.
Scott: You would have been like, eh, it rounds down.
Rym: No, if it was 800,000 or 8 million, I would have been a very different average number of servers, 32.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Oh, well, the Wikipedia already got updated in May 2021.
Rym: Freenode underwent what staff described as a hostile takeover.
Rym: 30 staff resigned.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Only a handful of those staff are involved in the Libro chat project.
Rym: Looks like everyone else just bailed completely.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They're just like, eh, fuck this.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We'll see how that all goes.
Rym: So Audacity is basically the most used open source audio editing and recording software?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, if you want to be able to just talk and record your talking, the software that's available to you for zero dollars free legally, there aren't a lot of great choices.
Scott: You know, like, I guess if you're, you know, if you got like your iPhone, there's like the audio recording app and Windows, I think there's some kind of recording app, right?
Scott: I guess GarageBand isn't really great for talking.
Scott: It's more for music focused.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I guess you could talk into it, but not the greatest.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you know, you go beyond that.
Scott: It's like, well, what are you using?
Scott: It costs money.
Scott: Adobe Audition, right?
Rym: Or CoolEdit, which I, well, I pirated, then I pirated a different way and I got a legit license long after that software was gone.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And, you know, so despite the fact that the user interface looking like it's ancient Garbo, Audacity is that program.
Scott: It's totally free.
Scott: It runs.
Scott: It works.
Scott: You can plug a microphone into a computer, push the record button and talk and it will record your voice and save it and make an MP3 and do everything.
Scott: And so it's what a lot of people use and they don't need anything more than that.
Scott: So it's, you know, it's a long running, popular project.
Rym: In the old days, we actually used it to record GeekNights.
Rym: We didn't edit or master GeekNights in it because it really doesn't, it's GIMP levels of quality for all that stuff.
Rym: But for the recording, we'd recorded Audacity and then I ran a script in a bunch of open source crap that I won't even mention because you shouldn't use it because it's garbage.
Rym: But that's what we used to use.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But, you know, the thing is, it's really old.
Scott: It's been around a long time.
Scott: It's improved a lot over the years, but it's improved.
Scott: In some ways it's improved and in some ways it's still the same old Garbo.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But what would you pay for?
Rym: One of the two problems I guess I've always had with Audacity is that even when I first tried it, on one it definitely does not at any point have anyone who's even sniffed the concept of UX and their life involved in it.
Rym: Nope.
Scott: None whatsoever.
Rym: But two, it's informed very heavily by the kinds of things that the loudest and most vocal users of Audacity try to do, which are often weird things that if they knew anything about audio they would not be doing in the first place.
Rym: So you end up with an interface that very prominently centers features that people shouldn't be touching regularly and hides or doesn't even have the things that someone who actually knows audio would literally want to do every time they open the application.
Scott: It's not meant for pros, right?
Scott: It's meant for just the average person who wants to record their voice and do a little bit of cut and paste and some of those other things that aren't so easy to do in the sound recording app on your iPhone.
Scott: It's something between that and Audition.
Scott: They don't need any of those other features Audition has.
Scott: that makes it worth paying for.
Scott: So, anyway, Audition got acquired also by a company.
Rym: Yeah, Audition was cool at it.
Rym: Adobe bought it and then actually made it way better eventually.
Rym: Like, Audition...
Scott: Oh, yeah, right.
Scott: No, I'm saying Audition.
Scott: What's the one where I... Audacity.
Scott: They almost start with Aud, right?
Rym: Well, I didn't want to mention Ardour.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, Audacity got acquired by this some sort of group of some kind and they don't seem to be bad like the people who took over Freenode are bad.
Scott: And they're actually, there are people now who are, they are being paid full time employees to work on Audacity to improve it, right?
Scott: So, they're actually going to work on like its user interface and its other things.
Scott: You're going to see probably in the coming time period, years, who knows?
Scott: Audacity get more, better, faster than it has in the past.
Rym: Yep, I would hope so.
Rym: Because the GIMP never got better.
Rym: But Audacity I think is way more broadly used than the GIMP is.
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: So, Audacity looks like they tried to add some telemetry data collection to Audacity that you could opt in or out of.
Rym: Like, what do people do?
Rym: Like, what do people click on?
Rym: What are they trying to do?
Scott: So this is, you'll see this a lot in like almost all your apps, like, you know, send us anonymous usage data, checkbox, yes, no.
Scott: And what that is, is like it just records you in some, in maybe small or large ways with some amount of detail.
Scott: Like what you use the app for, what features you use, what you don't use, but crash reports, all these sorts of things.
Scott: And usually most apps that have this have it on by default and you have to turn it off.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So if you have, you know, you might think it doesn't matter, but actually that kind of matters a lot, especially for less popular apps.
Scott: That data they get really will inform the decisions they make during development.
Scott: If you turn it off for like, you know, your Apple apps or something, it's like, you know, okay, in some small way that might matter for your privacy or who knows.
Scott: But they have so many people who have it on that your data is just, you know, lost in the sea.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And that's the kind of data that can tell them like, hey, this button that's prominently featured actually is not used by anyone or it's used by this one jerk.
Scott: Hey, we notice a pattern.
Scott: This crash keeps happening and all the people who have that crash have this exact GPU.
Scott: Then we need to get one of those GPUs to test with because clearly there's some, you know, right, something going on.
Rym: Now, what's fascinating is best I can tell.
Rym: the developers had planned to ship Audacity with the telemetry in it, but disabled by default.
Rym: So you could opt in.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Yes, they were doing it.
Scott: They're not.
Scott: They're being a good.
Scott: whoever is the new caretaker is doing it seems to be doing good.
Scott: They're like, listen, it's off by default.
Scott: Just only turn it on if you want to write to help us make Audacity better.
Scott: It's really anonymous.
Rym: The user base of Audacity flipped the fuck out about this to the point.
Scott: Well, the hardcore vocal user base of Audacity that was like involved in, you know, the Audacity community space.
Rym: The ones I mentioned earlier who do weird, bad things with Audacity.
Scott: The ones who are in the IRC and in the forums or whatever kind of slacks or channels that they have.
Rym: Like, I'm pretty sure these are the same.
Scott: Most of the Audacity users are people just making podcasts who are not involved in the Audacity community.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But remember how I mentioned those are like the loudest users.
Rym: These are the same people who get mad that Audacity has the ability to update itself, like the kind of person who wants to install an old version of the application and keep using it forever.
Rym: Like, it's a weird subset of the usage of Audacity.
Rym: And I don't know for sure, but I strongly suspect those people are a big part of why Audacity still has a really bad UX.
Rym: But anyway, those people flipped out to the point that Audacity now will not include any telemetry, opted or otherwise.
Rym: Just nothing.
Rym: They're just getting rid of this whole idea.
Scott: Alright, so the people who took over are trying to be such do-gooders and trying to ingratiate themselves with the community so much that they bowed and will not make Audacity as better as they could.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But it looks like those people were also mad about the auto-updater.
Rym: So Audacity will also now let you disable checking for updates and downloading new versions.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Go right ahead.
Scott: if you want to disable new versions.
Scott: Be my guest.
Rym: It's just like desktop open source software never really has a good design.
Rym: This is a topic for another day, but the projects tend to only take feedback from people who will also write patches and contribute code.
Scott: Well, not even that.
Scott: You don't even have to write patches or contribute code.
Scott: You just have to be active in the community of the thing.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But... Most of the users are not in the community of the software.
Rym: Well, that's it.
Rym: I use a web browser.
Rym: I'm not in the Chrome community.
Rym: I'm not like every day just chatting with other people.
Scott: Most of the Chrome, sometimes you have a piece of software where, you know, especially something like, you know, that's a developer tool, right?
Scott: And most of the people in the community are developers who are using that tool.
Scott: It's like a library or something.
Scott: But something like Chrome, almost all the users of Chrome are not in the Chrome community.
Scott: They just download, install, and use Chrome to browse the web, right?
Scott: So they have to consider, and they do, that's why they have telemetry, so that they can consider what the actual users are doing with Chrome, right?
Scott: And Audacity, it's like, seems to be, you know, not learning that understanding that like 99.99% of your users have not commented, right?
Scott: You're allowing .001% of the users, the ones who care so much about Audacity that they hang out in the Audacity community, to run the show and impact.
Scott: the 99.99% of Audacity users who simply go to the Audacity website, download, install it, and never interact with any of the community whatsoever.
Rym: And I guess that's the broader point is that I feel like a lot of desktop open source software, especially if it's in the free open source software subset, like the people who also have ideological reasons for being involved, tend to greatly amplify a very small number of voices from a very narrow perspective in just all the decisions they make.
Scott: Well, if you're in the 99.99% of the GeekNights community that just listens and never comments or forums or does anything, you're letting the .001% of the, you know, people who are weirdos who come and talk to us, you know, mess with our minds and influence what kind of GeekNights sausage is made.
Scott: So get on in here.
Rym: So in some other news, it's a minor thing.
Rym: Well, it's a small thing.
Rym: It's a minor news.
Rym: It's not allowed to say about it, but it's a good thing.
Rym: Spotify is adding a bunch of accessibility improvements on their iOS and Android apps around podcasts.
Rym: But the one in particular that I want to highlight is automatic podcast transcription.
Rym: Which is a moderately big deal because one, it's hard to do.
Rym: Two, most podcasts are amateurs who don't make money.
Rym: And if they actually like, even if they want to do transcriptions, they can't afford it.
Rym: Like, look at us, when we were doing, when we were poor and doing GeekNights.
Scott: We have a lot of money.
Scott: We could, we could afford it once in a while, but we could, I guess if we did way less podcasts, we could afford all the episodes.
Rym: But we were doing four hours of content a week for many years.
Scott: To do our archive would be prohibitive, right?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It was a little bit prohibitive.
Rym: I was paying for Spanish subtitle translations for some of our panels a while back and professional transcriptions.
Rym: And it ended up adding to all, adding up to a lot of money.
Scott: And it covers, it's hard, it's hard time consuming work that someone deserves to be paid for.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's one thing to say, yeah, if you're a big company, you know, you know, a TV network, you have no excuse.
Scott: You better fucking translate that shit to every language known to humanity.
Rym: But if you're just like a hobbyist, not even making money off your thing.
Scott: It's like you want to make it accessible, but it's making it accessible is not accessible to someone who has no money.
Rym: That's part of why we started live streaming the podcast on YouTube.
Rym: It's not just because like there's 20 ish people who watch it on a regular basis, but also because it does make a pretty good transcription that is there for anyone who needs that.
Rym: But the fact that this is going to be embedded into the apps for podcasts specifically, kind of a big deal.
Rym: It really will open up the accessibility of podcasts to people who are hearing disabled in some way.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: What I don't like, though, and you see this with Apple launching their subscription podcast today, right, on iTunes or whatever, or the podcast app, I guess.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Whatever is that the podcast used to be and they still mostly are technically on the bottom level, this open thing, right?
Scott: It's just someone's putting out this publicly accessible text file, you know, available on the Internet via HTTP within RSS format or Adam format that lists all where all the MP3 URLs in a big list.
Scott: Right.
Scott: With the names of the episodes next to each MP3 URL.
Scott: And then you can write software or by hand, you know, subscribe and keep an eye on that file and get all the new episodes.
Scott: And, you know, when, you know, we're available on all the platforms, we will always take our feed and just put it into any software that'll parse it.
Rym: It'll just work.
Scott: We will always have that raw feed available for you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But other people, you know, their podcasts, you know, especially these sign up with like some, you know, they don't make a website for themselves.
Scott: They just sign up with like a podcast, you know, hosting site and they're on Spotify and all these, you know, they're getting onto these closed places.
Scott: And now, you know, maybe can't get the podcast so easily the old fashioned way.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Especially because there's always this ebb and flow in podcasting in particular of trying to make money versus trying to expand audience.
Rym: And it's not like most people are like GeekNights where even if we didn't make any money at all, we just afford to run this because it's fun to make.
Rym: But this cycle right now is moving back into everyone's trying to monetize podcasts heavily.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I'm not liking the closed podcast ecosystem is all I'm saying.
Rym: Well, it's starting.
Rym: It's interesting because streaming like video game streamers and Twitch streamers in particular versus podcasters are starting to diverge in their strategies for monetization.
Rym: I don't think either one is going to work out in the long run, but I'm at least glad to see that there's some diversity in how they're doing it.
Rym: Because as much as I don't like closed ecosystems, I much prefer someone pays a content creator dollars to get content.
Rym: Rather than all these other like, well, we'll set up a complicated system of redistributing money from like advertising sales and aggregate and all these like indirect methods.
Scott: What about?
Scott: people have no money, though, and then now they can't, people have no money, can't get any content.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But people who have no money could never get content until relatively recently when we started making free content by monetizing those people via advertising.
Scott: You mean for the past 50 years since someone pirated a cassette tape?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But I'm saying like all the broadcast TV only existed because the people watching were the actual product.
Rym: And that just created over time an increasingly toxic ecosystem.
Rym: Really, we just need some form of communism, but I digress.
Rym: Anyway, at least these subtitles would be pretty cool.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: Galaxy upcycling.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So long ago, you can see the story and I fix it to get all the details.
Scott: But long ago, Samsung Galaxy unveiled this plan to do this upcycling program.
Scott: The idea would be that like, hey, you got these old Samsung Galaxy phones.
Scott: We know you bought a new phone, right?
Scott: That old phone isn't really good enough to be your phone anymore because you can afford a new one.
Scott: There's a newer version of Android.
Scott: That one's running an old version.
Scott: You don't want to use it as your phone anymore.
Scott: We get you, right?
Scott: But, you know, maybe the screen's broken, but that is still a useful electronic device.
Scott: Somebody could use it in, you know, if they could only run any software they wanted on it instead of the phone software.
Scott: That is like a full computer, basically.
Rym: I mean, you know, I was just cleaning out a bunch of my closet space.
Rym: I have four perfectly functional old Android phones.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That's still a perfectly functioning computer, right?
Scott: And even though it might not be able to be good enough to be used as like your phone, because you live in New York and you have a lot of money, it could be used as a lot of things, right?
Scott: It could be the computer in some other device.
Scott: You know, who knows what, right?
Scott: So the idea was that they were going to be like, hey, you know, give us back all these old phones and we'll find companies that like have product ideas.
Scott: And those companies will just use old phones and the boards, chips, batteries, screens, whatever parts from those old phones in brand new devices, right?
Scott: And that will be totally, that's way better than fucking recycling or, you know, pretty much anything, right?
Scott: It's like, that's like the absolute best thing you can do in terms of environment, you know, environmental niceness when it comes to semiconductors, right?
Scott: It's like, just find a new use for it.
Scott: You know, you bought it, oh, you bought a brand new gaming computer.
Scott: Well, take your old gaming computer, which isn't good enough to run games anymore, and we'll use it as a computer in a dentist office.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Like look at how many people, like there was a lot, just take an old laptop, that's an HDPC.
Rym: It's great.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, you know, just find, keep finding a way to make use of it, right?
Scott: So the thing is, is that because Samsung basically said, and they stopped talking about it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It kind of just petered out to nothing and just disappeared.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And I fix it every time they try to talk to them about it, they just eventually stopped responding, right?
Scott: And it's like, oh, what happened?
Scott: Well, basically what happened is that like for-profit companies do, they decided it wouldn't be worth it or wouldn't make enough money, you know, to be worth it.
Scott: And they didn't do it.
Scott: And it's, you know, it seems to have disappeared or has surfaced in only the most, you know, bare, you know, minimal way.
Scott: that is not sufficient.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's kind of sad because it's like, hey, I think they're wrong.
Scott: I think it would make them a bunch of money.
Scott: And because what would happen is the idea is that you just, they just need to release a thing, some sort of, you know, app or something that would allow anyone to, with an old enough phone, right?
Scott: Sort of just remove the OS and unlock it to allow anything to be installed on it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Probably someone would just install Linux on it.
Scott: I imagine.
Rym: Because otherwise, if you want to just reuse an old Android phone, you probably have some like old, un-updateable, insecure version of Android.
Scott: And the Android is of Linux kernel.
Scott: So, you know, you just need to have the right drivers in that kernel and you're good to go.
Scott: You can run any software on it now then use its peripherals as long as, you know, if you have drivers for the different parts of it, you're good to go.
Scott: That's not too much work from Samsung, I imagine, right?
Scott: Not too much maintenance, but apparently it's, they think they wouldn't make enough money to pay for even that small token effort.
Scott: But actually, I think they're dead wrong.
Scott: If you did that, suddenly there would be a hot market for those old phones.
Scott: You know, whether they were used or new, right?
Scott: Maybe ones they couldn't sell, right?
Scott: It's like you had your overstock, right?
Rym: I mean, it's not just a computer.
Rym: It's a computer with an embedded touchscreen, embedded battery, and between one and three cameras.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And then, not only that, but people I think would be more likely, you know, especially if they were, you know, cool, to buy that phone knowing that when it was done with its life, that it would then be able to be unlocked at some point in the future when they upgraded to a new phone, that the old one would be useful as a generic computing device and wouldn't just sit in a drawer as an emergency backup like my old iPhone is, right?
Scott: I don't know if it would get me to switch, but if I had to suddenly buy a phone now and wasn't already an iPhone person, if that existed, that would really make me, you know, right?
Rym: Also, I wish it was easy.
Rym: Like, I have so many old Android phones just lying around.
Rym: And I always had this idea of, "Oh, why don't I leave them in the house to be like, just, I don't know, even a conversation piece or like a web browser for anyone who happens to be
Rym: over?".
Rym: Because back then, not everyone we knew even had a smartphone or a smartphone that was good.
Rym: Used them as remote controls, set them up as security cameras.
Rym: I got all these cool ideas, but it was just too much.
Scott: All sorts of things you could do with one.
Rym: But it's just too much for me to ask.
Rym: Like, I booted one of the old ones up to see what was on it.
Rym: It's proprietary, locked down, and also doesn't really work anymore because it's so old.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Scott: So, it's just a really disappointing story that Samsung didn't go through with it.
Scott: I'm in favor of a law force.
Scott: I'm going to do it.
Scott: The end.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day!
Rym: So, you know, I like me a mashup.
Rym: And, uh, YouTube has also figured out that I like a mashup.
Rym: But it also knows that I like very particular kinds of mashups.
Rym: And it's starting to recommend to me relatively obscure ones that are great.
Rym: So, I submit to you a very well-made M&M Lose Yourself, but it's Mr.
Rym: Blue Sky by Electric Light Orchestra.
Rym: It is surprisingly well done, and I legitimately like this as a song.
Scott: There's a lot of those on YouTube.
Scott: You know, DJs, they find two songs that are far apart from each other, but have the same BPM or close to it, and they just go to town, right?
Rym: Yep, but there's this unquantifiable aspect.
Rym: I'm trying to think more about this now that I'm seeing a pattern of which ones of those I like and which ones I just find just tiresome to listen to.
Rym: And there's a very delicate line, and I'm trying to, like, articulate exactly what it is that makes one of these good for me.
Rym: I have not figured that out yet.
Rym: Neil Cicierega, like, tapped it straight to my soul, and this is one of the few I found that also triggers that impulse in me.
Scott: You gotta be in the right mouth mood.
Rym: Yeah, my mouth felt this one.
Rym: I lost myself.
Rym: Mom's spaghetti.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: So, let's go back in time, right?
Scott: It's 1980-something, and you want to make an NES game, right?
Scott: So, today it's really easy to make an NES game.
Scott: You get your emulator, right?
Scott: You just get your compiler.
Scott: There's even tools to, like, there's NES Maker kind of things out there.
Scott: There's a Game Boy one, actually, on itch.io.
Scott: you can get.
Scott: I forget what it's called.
Scott: Well, you can just make games really easily, and you just push File, Save, and it makes a ROM.
Scott: You load it in your emulator, and you play it.
Scott: You put it on your flash card.
Scott: You put it in your device.
Scott: You play it.
Scott: Super easy to develop, relatively speaking, games for old consoles.
Scott: What if you want to do it in the year 1980-something?
Scott: It's a lot harder, right?
Scott: Even if you have, like, the NES dev kit.
Scott: What, you think the NES dev kit was easy to use in 1980-something?
Rym: Yeah, you know what a big step was in the NES "dev kit" of that day?
Rym: Drawing your pixel art on graph paper, and then using specialized tools to input that data into a computer.
Scott: You didn't have fucking Visual Studio Code, right, in 1980-something.
Scott: So, how the fuck did you do it?
Scott: Well, one way you could have done it was the way this person does it in this video.
Scott: They've got an Apple IIe, and they set that shit up.
Scott: It's not even as good as my Apple IIgs, Apple IIe.
Scott: And they found a card on eBay that is an EEPROM writer.
Scott: So, what they can do is they can write a program on the Apple II, which sucks ass to do, and then compile it, assemble it, and burn it to an EEPROM.
Scott: And then they put the EEPROM over, they got a separate device that was, you know, that was from back in the day, that lets them copy the EEPROMs, right, and they got physical chips.
Scott: You put the chip in the card in the Apple II, you burn it, right?
Scott: You take it out, you put it in the other thing, you copy it, and then you put the chips into this NES cartridge that has two holes to put chips into, and you slap that into an NES, and now you can play the game.
Scott: And in the video, he goes through the whole process of, you know, making an NES game the way you might have had to make it in 1980-something if you had an Apple computer, or pretty much any computer.
Scott: Like, what computer would you have then?
Scott: that was better than that?
Scott: It's like, that's the best computer you could have had in those days, right?
Scott: What are you gonna have?
Scott: You know, so, programming was a pain in the ass then, is the reason we don't do it that way anymore.
Rym: You know, it's funny, there's a video just, like it just made the rounds.
Rym: Captain D is back, and he did a long dive into how they made Flight of the Navigator.
Scott: I did see the link to that, I didn't watch.
Rym: It's 45 minutes long, it's way in-depth and way good.
Rym: But I am glad that we live in an era where creator tools are much more accessible and easier to use.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, how to make Flight of the Navigator using Adobe Premiere and After Effects.
Scott: Oh, it will take you like a day.
Rym: Like, imagine trying to make something like a podcast or a radio show in the 70s compared to now.
Rym: Forget even, like, syndication, just recording it and editing it.
Rym: Old audio editing sucked.
Rym: Tapes sucked.
Rym: I hated tapes.
Rym: I never want to see a tape again in my life.
Scott: You have to cut film with a scissor.
Rym: Alright, in the meta moment, we're still mostly stuck at home, but there's a little bit of light at the end of the tunnel.
Rym: We're out doing stuff every now and then, bit by bit.
Scott: The book club book is still Genji Monogatari, The Tale of Genji, the first novel ever written by human beings.
Scott: The author of Murasaki Shikibu.
Scott: I read like three chapters yesterday, so we're moving along.
Rym: I think in June we're going to do an episode on it.
Scott: There's like 50-something chapters in total, I think, right?
Scott: So that's a significant portion.
Rym: I think July is the latest.
Rym: we will do an episode on it.
Scott: Yeah, so just in case anyone, you know, over the past year for some reason decided you're finally going to go for it, right?
Scott: We're reading like the unabridged translation.
Scott: Who's the person that translated it?
Scott: so you know it's the right one?
Rym: I'm looking to see.
Rym: You didn't actually say in the posting.
Rym: I was hoping it was there.
Scott: Oh.
Scott: But yeah, we'll say it next episode.
Rym: And of course, we have to read the best possible unabridged translation, and you didn't say what that translation was.
Rym: And there's a tiny image that is not big enough for me to read.
Rym: Wait, wait, I can click on "Purchase the
Rym: Book.".
Rym: "Tale of Genji Penguin Classics Deluxe
Rym: Edition.".
Rym: Uh, "Royale Tyler" is the translator.
Scott: That's the one.
Scott: The "Royale Tyler" translation is like, I did research when we chose this, that's like the one, right?
Rym: Oh yeah, there's a quote here.
Rym: "The world's first novel in a translation that is 'likely to be the definitive
Rym: edition.'".
Scott: Yes, that's, I'd say accurate.
Rym: Alright, so yeah, June to July, around then, we'll do the show on it.
Rym: So you can start reading it now, and you'll probably finish it around when we finish it.
Rym: My only advice to you, I've said this before, don't stress about it like it's like middle school or high school, and try to like get every nuance of what's going on.
Rym: Just read it for entertainment, and if you're not 100% sure like exactly what happened, just keep powering and it usually becomes pretty clear later, and you don't have to sweat it that much.
Scott: I think one thing that people might not realize is that, you know, even if you were to get the original text of this book, right?
Scott: Even modern Japanese people couldn't read it, because it's like written in ancient Japanese, right?
Scott: So, you know, it would be like if you tried to read old English, right?
Scott: It's like, you can't.
Rym: Yeah, old English is not like, "I went to ye old
Rym: pub!".
Rym: It's like this German sounding nightmare.
Scott: Right, it's like.
Scott: it's not, it's not the same.
Scott: So, and it wasn't even translated into modern Japanese until like way later.
Scott: And it wasn't translated into English that we can understand until even later than that.
Scott: So, and that's why it's got its, you know, quirks, but we'll get there.
Rym: Yeah, otherwise follow us in all the places.
Rym: Stay tuned for what will likely be between one and three PAX Online panels.
Rym: And we'll see if any conventions happen toward the end of this year or not.
Rym: We're just kind of waiting to see how things go.
Rym: I think the con that has the best chance, not saying like this is certain or anything, the con that has the best chance of us being added in person that is soonest is probably PAX Unplugged in November.
Scott: Yeah, it's like PAX West seems like it has a non-zero chance of happening.
Scott: But it's getting too close to when it would happen to plan it.
Scott: Right, would I go to it?
Rym: Or could it be planned quickly enough?
Rym: Like there's a long lead time to get the game industry to show up to something.
Scott: If it did happen, would I like to go to it?
Scott: If it was safe, sure, right?
Scott: But can we make it happen?
Rym: Yup, there's a lot of things that could get in the way of it that are not, like it might be that COVID, it could be pretty safe to go by September, but that it was too late to know it would be safe in time to plan it.
Rym: That's the kind of thing we can't control right now.
Scott: Or too expensive, right?
Scott: Or who knows?
Rym: Yup, so we'll see.
Rym: My main rule is I'm not going to any con that requires masks or social distancing because if they require those things, it's still not safe.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: If they don't require those things, that does not necessarily mean it is safe.
Rym: It's got to also be safe.
Rym: Looking at you, AnimeCon, I'm not going to name that happened like two months ago.
Scott: Right, it has to be so safe that reasonable, intelligent, good people have to be like, "You know what?
Scott: It's as safe as it was in 2018.
Scott: We don't need to worry about this pandemic, right?
Scott: We can just have our convention like we used to.
Scott: It can't be, "Oh, the pandemic's still going on, but fuck
Scott: masks.".
Scott: It's like, "No, no,
Scott: no.".
Rym: Yup, so we'll see.
Rym: And maybe we'll record some stuff.
Rym: At some point, Scott and I can be together in the same room, which makes it a lot easier.
Scott: Yeah, that seems like it will be safer sooner.
Rym: Yeah, we're going to edge into outdoor meetings of friends and then figure out what to do from there.
Rym: We're going to take it slow, and I advise you, not that we are experts, to just take it slow.
Rym: Step by step.
Rym: Don't just dive into licking door handles again.
Rym: Save that for 2022.
Scott: And this is another one.
Rym: I think the earliest PAX you should lick doorknobs again.
Rym: is PAX Unplugged, maybe.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: All right, so video cameras.
Scott: Somehow we haven't done a show on any sort of camera anything.
Scott: I searched.
Scott: If anyone sees that we have and Rym deleted them or something, let me know.
Scott: But I searched our archive.
Scott: I didn't find any photo or video episodes, which seems really wrong.
Scott: I feel like we've definitely done some.
Rym: But we're going to focus just on video cameras, primarily post film.
Rym: We don't want to talk about Super 8 camcorders.
Rym: Those are cool, but one, that's a different show, and two.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, you know, back in the day, there were film cameras.
Scott: You had a big roll of film, spun it through really fast, you know, expose and those would be a little spinner.
Scott: So each was in perfect synchronization with the frames going through.
Scott: And it would expose, you know, frames at some rate, usually 24 times a second.
Scott: The light would come through the hole, hit the film.
Scott: You take a lot of pictures real fast, and then you needed to develop it.
Scott: And then you needed a projector to watch it.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But there were basically two main types of video recording or not even recording in many cases, devices.
Rym: You either recorded on film and then you had to project it to play it back into anything.
Rym: Or you had a digital like a digital or analog modern electronic video camera.
Rym: I'm choosing a lot of vague words because there is a variety of technology that was involved in this.
Rym: But the key thing, you know, early video cameras could not record.
Rym: They could only capture and immediately broadcast somewhere.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: People don't think about this too much.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like, you know, you look at, say, old movies.
Scott: Like a movie from the 50s.
Scott: Right.
Scott: What's a movie from the 50s?
Scott: What, Seven Samurai or something?
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, Alfred Hitchcock, something like that.
Scott: And then look at TV from the 50s.
Scott: It's complete garbage, basically.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And why is the TV from the 50s garbage?
Scott: The TV from the 50s wasn't on fucking film.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They didn't develop the television program on film and then play it back.
Scott: Like, you know, that's not how it was done.
Scott: They had a TV camera.
Scott: Right.
Scott: An enormous monstrosity.
Scott: That basically was kind of like a radio, but for vision.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The same way, you know, it was like instead of having a microphone that then would go to an antenna and broadcast radio signals.
Scott: The television camera in those days would basically see, and I'm not explaining in detail how it works, but, you know, and then broadcast radio signals live.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Of whatever it was seeing.
Scott: And your antenna would pick it up and you watched it live on television.
Scott: the same way you listen to radio live.
Rym: Like early television didn't have the concept of reruns.
Rym: It was a one time broadcast and it's gone.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And if there was a recording.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The recording would be similar to recording the radio.
Scott: There's an analog signal going out the antenna to play back the TV program.
Scott: You need to play back that same analog radio signal.
Scott: You could record it to a magnetic analog tape.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, a big reel to reel magnetic tape is what you could record it.
Rym: But that tape was storing analog signals.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It wasn't storing, you know, like film, actual images.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was storing, you know, just an analog recording and then you could play it back to broadcast again.
Rym: Meaning it was limited to whatever standard and NTSC came way later than some of that early stuff.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, you know, those early video cameras were, eh.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And to really drive this home.
Scott: Film was the king of quality for even, probably even very close to today.
Rym: That's why some TV shows.
Scott: Arguably still today.
Rym: Like some old TV shows, even things from like the 90s, look great if you get a remastered version because they were actually originally recorded on film.
Rym: So they could just re-scan that film to a higher quality modern digital format.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You watch some fucking Snow White.
Scott: It's like, yeah, it was on film.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But then you had some shows that were recorded with TV cameras, meaning NTSC is literally the best quality signal you ever got.
Rym: There's no master film anywhere.
Rym: There's nothing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that was true up until like, you know, maybe you watched like in the 80s or 90s.
Rym: Star Trek Voyager would like, there was no film there.
Rym: That's why Voyager looks like shit compared to TNG that was recorded earlier.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like Voyager was not filmed on film like it was a movie.
Scott: It was a TV program.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was recorded to tapes, you know.
Scott: Better than VHS tapes, but still just tapes.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, yeah, we got past all that.
Rym: And what we really want to focus on is the era of not really camcorders, but video cameras that were accessible to people, even if it was just professionals who are not only at mega studios and news broadcasts, like the super big iron studio stuff, because that could be a whole show on its own that we're also not that versed in because it's all arcade dead technology.
Scott: Fun note, though, you can go like on eBay and other places and buy old studio TV equipment that was pre, you know, digital era.
Scott: And some of it is useless, but some of it like this lens is like a lens from an old TV camera.
Scott: You know, it's like, hey, yeah, nothing wrong with that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You can slap that on something newer.
Rym: I mean, that old VHS camcorder I had, like, of course, had a shit sensor and all.
Rym: it had a lot of problems, but it had a really good lens in it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, you know, some of that old stuff has all been thrown out and is going for cheap because people don't need it anymore.
Scott: They've got newer, better stuff.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But like one last point isn't necessarily bad to really drive home.
Scott: Like how much cycle it.
Rym: A lot of old TV.
Rym: If there's indoor scenes on a set, they were recorded using a TV camera like did like video camera.
Rym: And if there were outdoors or on location, they use film because the NTSC or TV cameras were too big and hard wired to be brought anywhere.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Depending on the year.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Eventually you had the, you know, the sort of like news broadcast truck stuff.
Scott: Where, you know, you get that big the van with the dish on the roof.
Scott: They still have those.
Scott: Obviously they're much.
Scott: they're much different now.
Rym: Also, that's a mostly just digital pipeline.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, you know, you used to have 80s, 90s, you know, even 70s, you know, they had the camera.
Scott: that is like big ass thing they put over their shoulder.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You get the camera guy with the person with the microphone doing the news report on the street.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You know, nowadays, most people use a running.
Rym: Actually, the camcorder I got is one of the most popular ones for like local news run and gun.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So in terms of like people having digital video cameras outside of this professional settings, like digital ones that recorded to a file of some kind.
Rym: Those are actually pretty new.
Rym: And ones that were good are scarily new.
Rym: Like they're a recent thing.
Rym: During the run of GeekNights, there were not good digital cameras that were affordable for normal people for video.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, you had the ones that recorded to VHS or Betamax.
Scott: Right.
Scott: All kinds of different tapes, like little tape that goes inside the big tape.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And those are basically just shittier versions of the TV ones that you would use.
Scott: And then the first ones, video cameras that were digital, that's like, I don't even know what the first consumer one was, but like they would record and these crappy codex like AA, like what was it called?
Scott: Like ABC or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Rym: AVCHD.
Rym: Is that what you're thinking of?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The encoding chips that would translate the raw signal from the digital camera sensor to a video file, they had to be able to do it fast enough at whatever frame rate there was.
Rym: And it's not like nowadays, like you would stream on OBS.
Rym: Look at how many resources encoding live video uses, even today.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you have some device that has to be small enough and someone's holding it.
Scott: It's a camera.
Scott: It's got a sensor, right?
Scott: It's got a lens.
Scott: It's got all this focusing, all this stuff going on.
Scott: And it needs, it's got a battery and it needs to be able to take all the video data that's coming in from the sensor, right?
Scott: Without overheating the sensor or anything.
Scott: And write to a file, right?
Scott: The frame, the full, however resolution it is 24 times a second, 30 times a second.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then if it fails, you don't want the file to just, or if it runs out of battery, you don't want the file to be broken.
Scott: You need that person wants all the video that they recorded.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It would be upsetting if like you recorded until the battery died and then your file was, you recorded actually nothing.
Scott: Um, so yeah, there were five, there were file formats that were like, you know, basically highly compressed, lost, very lossy, like you'd like, there was this early era, you could buy these cameras that were like record at 720 P 60.
Rym: Like, yeah, cool.
Rym: Uh, but each individual frame, like what that video looked like, uh, I think the industry term for what it looked like was dog shit.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You, it would throw away a lot of the color data.
Rym: It's like early MP3s, like those 64 Kbps MP3s you'd listen to.
Rym: It was like that for video, right?
Scott: It's like we had higher quality video files.
Scott: Your computer could play them back, right?
Scott: Cause playing back is actually less CPU intensive than recording.
Scott: But you know, it's like you could have, you could, we could even encode them, no problem, but we do have to be able to encode them in real time.
Scott: If you're recording at 30 frames a second, you need to write to the hard drive 30, all 30 frames right within a second or you start buffering.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You start piling up.
Scott: It's like, okay, well there's more frames coming in that we're holding in Ram that we haven't written to the hard drive yet.
Scott: And if that Ram fills up, well now you can't record anything.
Rym: Also Ram eats power and cameras are usually portable and not plugged into anything.
Rym: So the more buffer space you have, the less battery you have and the less you could even record in the first place.
Scott: So there were all kinds of cameras for quite a while that could record video digitally that consumers could buy, but the quality was really low.
Scott: Even if that same camera could like record really great photos, you know, at a high resolution sensor or something.
Rym: And it was this confluence of the storage.
Scott: The storage wasn't fast enough.
Scott: The encoder wasn't fast enough.
Scott: The power wasn't high enough.
Scott: The quality was bad.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I think we did.
Rym: We had, we did a show on Codex back in like 2006.
Rym: We'll see how that was like.
Rym: Cause that's actually the era when the camera I'm about to talk about came out.
Rym: But in those days, like so many things have changed, but if you had to boil it down, one batteries got more powerful, like battery technology got better.
Scott: The lithium ion batteries became way better.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Two portable general purpose computing got better.
Rym: It wasn't that dedicated chips got better to do this for most purposes.
Rym: It was that general purpose chips became power, like economical enough and also economical economical enough to embed in these devices to be able to see.
Scott: people don't think that when you buy a digital camera, you're not thinking about the CPU in a digital camera cause they don't really advertise what CPU is in there.
Scott: But guess what?
Scott: There's CPU's in there.
Scott: There's video encoding chips in there, right?
Scott: And they're way more powerful on the newer cameras than they are on the older ones.
Scott: And it matters a lot.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And then you also had the problem of Codex.
Rym: The way you encode video have evolved a lot since then.
Rym: Like early Codex had huge problems with editability.
Rym: There used to be this big problem.
Rym: We ran into it where even if you had a fancy digital camera that could record video, good fucking luck.
Rym: Doing anything other than playing that video back, try to import it into video editing software.
Rym: Not that there was even that much worthwhile video editing software for consumers in the year of our Lord 2006, but usually wouldn't even work.
Rym: Like we had a flip camera.
Rym: I spent a lot of money on this thing for GeekNights.
Rym: This thing was handheld.
Rym: It could record a couple hours of 720p video.
Rym: It was one of the earlier adopters of H.264 and AAC audio, like MP4 file formats.
Rym: And the video it outputted was so... I'm trying to think how to describe this without getting too jargony.
Rym: It would slew so much and the timing was so off.
Rym: Like it encoded badly.
Rym: It made a barely formed, probably actually incorrect file.
Rym: And if you try to import that file into video editing software, you get a ton of artifacts and frame drops and ugly broken frames.
Rym: Sometimes things would just crash on you.
Rym: Like video was not very interoperable back then.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: And the other thing is the storage.
Scott: Video takes up a lot of space.
Scott: You're taking 24, 30 photos a second, even if you're compressing them and they're low resolution.
Scott: That's going to fill up your storage real fast.
Scott: You know, so, you know, nowadays you can get 128, 256, you know, and even the ultra pro storage on like, you know, pro video cameras.
Scott: these days, they're just slapping SSDs right into the video camera directly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But back in the day, what do you have?
Scott: a compact flash card of, you know, one, you know, a few megabytes on an SD card.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not like today where an SD card holds.
Scott: it holds a crap ton.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, gigabytes and SD cards then were slow.
Scott: So even if it could hold all the video, you you had to be able to write 30, 24 to 30 frames per second to it.
Scott: Otherwise, again, buffering, you're you're filling up your RAM with with frames that haven't yet been written to the SD card.
Scott: The SD card, whatever your storage is, needs to be fast enough that you can slam the frames onto it as fast as, you know, they're coming in the thing.
Rym: So before you say, oh, just use an SSD.
Rym: Those didn't exist in a consumer form.
Rym: Like my first SSD was 16 gigabytes and I paid like 400 bucks for it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And I was glad to pay such a cheap price for an SSD.
Scott: So the Sony I remember the Sony camcorder we bought in the late 2000s had like an actual just it had like a laptop hard drive.
Rym: Spinning magnetic disk was just in it.
Scott: It had a two and a half inch laptop hard drive.
Scott: You couldn't take it out or anything, but like that was a fact.
Scott: You could tell that was what was in there.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You could even feel it spin up when you started like it might have been 64 or 128 gigs.
Scott: I don't remember exactly how big maybe only 32.
Scott: I remember exactly how big it was.
Rym: I gave the main gig nice camcorder that we've recorded most of our panels with, which was generate one generation better than the camera you're describing.
Rym: I think it had a 32 gigabyte laptop drive.
Rym: I gave it to the cold guy.
Scott: This camera wasn't HD.
Scott: It was just SD, you know, three, you know, three to aspect ratio.
Scott: Right.
Scott: TV aspect ratio.
Rym: But even worse, you want to get video off of that thing.
Rym: All right.
Rym: One, it's going to be highly compressed because it can't record.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You plugged it in with a USB cable to a computer, USB to and you waited.
Rym: It took a while to get a file.
Scott: I think it did have an SD slot.
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: I know you could definitely take still photos to the SD.
Rym: I don't remember if you could record video to the one I had one generation newer than yours could record to the SD slots.
Rym: But back then, you were lucky to have like a one gigabyte SD card.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: This is only, you know, 10 less than 20 years ago.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And even then DSLRs at the time, just still photo digital cameras.
Scott: They didn't have SD cards.
Rym: They had compact flash cards in those those days for a lot of reasons, partly because back then, compact flash was faster for writing.
Scott: Yeah, but compact flash wasn't going to hold up for video.
Scott: No, I don't think I've ever.
Scott: I don't think I've ever seen a video.
Scott: There might be one, but I've never seen a video camera.
Scott: that's a compact flash.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I'm just thinking back to all the cameras I've owned.
Rym: But so the era we live in now is so great for video.
Rym: You have so many options.
Scott: Your phone is amazing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I don't understand how hard it was to record a GeekNights panel in the year like 2008 and like how much shit we went through to have those early videos up.
Rym: That was a nightmare.
Rym: Nowadays, we both have to like 4K cameras on our phones and our pockets.
Rym: I have a pile of cameras.
Scott: I'm not even the old go.
Scott: I have a GoPro five.
Scott: I think the current GoPro is like, what, nine or something?
Rym: I got it right in front of me.
Rym: This it doesn't say it's a GoPro is the GoPro.
Scott: So that they're at least on eight.
Scott: Right.
Scott: My GoPro five can do 4K 60.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I think this one can do 4K.
Scott: Oh, no, there is.
Scott: There is a GoPro nine now.
Rym: What?
Rym: That must have just come out because I just bought.
Rym: No, I didn't just buy the aid.
Rym: It's COVID fucked up my sense of time.
Scott: Never mind.
Scott: There's a GoPro nine now, but yeah, my GoPro five can do 4K 60.
Scott: So there's four newer GoPros.
Scott: It's gotten four increments better.
Scott: So yeah, we're at the point where it's like, yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: The old cameras have, you know, video, digital video cameras for consumers have gotten way better in a short amount of time, but it's still a long enough amount of time.
Scott: You can buy something five, six, seven years old, just not 10, 15 years old.
Scott: And it will be amazing and cheap.
Scott: And that's and the new stuff will just fucking blow your mind if you can afford it.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So where are we now?
Rym: There's basically there's four.
Rym: I'd say there's four like rough ways to go, depending on what kind of video you want to get.
Rym: One way is seriously, just your phone.
Rym: It's probably fine.
Scott: Like phone, 90 percent of people, the phone camera is better than if you're.
Scott: it's like the phone camera is going to be better than anything unless you spend a ton of money and learn a lot about video.
Scott: So why, Bob, unless you're super serious, don't bother.
Scott: Just use your phone.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: That's the other thing.
Scott: I'm famous on TikTok with just your phone.
Scott: You don't need anything else.
Rym: The second sort of thread are the hyper portable, durable GoPro and GoPro adjacent type cameras, which are used for a variety of purposes.
Scott: Mostly those are used.
Scott: They're not.
Scott: that GoPro isn't that much better than a phone.
Scott: Honestly, the advantage of the GoPro is really that it's you know, you don't want to strap your phone to the front of your bicycle or bring it in the ocean or put it on the front of your snowboard or whatever else.
Scott: Surfing, which is what a GoPro was originally made for.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because you'll fucking break it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But also, my GoPro can just take SD cards like my phone really can't.
Rym: Well, my phone can actually, but that's because I have a weird phone.
Rym: Most phones don't.
Scott: My phone can.
Scott: I have a dongle.
Scott: That's how iPhones do.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You're not going to have a dongle plugged into it while it's strapped to your chest.
Scott: No, you record to it and then you transfer it to the SD card.
Scott: afterwards is how it works.
Rym: I want to record one long video.
Rym: But anyway, if you're doing like a lot of people are doing it, but pay for a phone with more space inside.
Rym: Yeah, it won't be enough.
Scott: The iPhones come with like a terabyte.
Scott: You can get big ones.
Rym: Yeah, I could fill it anyway.
Rym: I guess the other.
Rym: But the GoPro type cameras, a big use of them is people who want to live stream or make like a mini studio of some kind in an apartment or a house.
Rym: You can just buy like three or four of those things and use them as a big multi camera set up.
Rym: They're pretty fucking good.
Rym: Not that expensive.
Rym: Really easy to use.
Rym: The third the third and fourth way to go.
Rym: really it's four factor.
Rym: like DSLRs like photo cameras tend to be fantastic video cameras because they tend to have way bigger and better sensors than a lot of even professional video cameras have.
Scott: So people don't realize this, right?
Scott: So the first, you know, digital camera DSLR basically that was also a video camera was like the Nikon D 90 I guess something like D something and it came out like 2008.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So now it just seems like normal that you're using like a digital photo camera to make video.
Scott: It's a dual purpose thing.
Scott: But that is not that old development.
Scott: Only 13 years old.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, like my DX one can not output video on its HDMI port.
Scott: And that original Nikon, I think it could only do like 720 P 30 and didn't do a great job of it.
Scott: So since then, now, of course, you know, you can get four K sometimes even more than that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And because a digital still camera.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: You know, the DSLRs with the lenses and everything or now now that have mirrors, now they're just, you know, digital lens, mirrorless cameras.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like the one I have, you know, they're meant for still photos primarily.
Scott: The sensors are big, right?
Scott: Usually a video camera.
Scott: The sensor is tiny, like a one inch sensor or smaller.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That giant fancy camcorder you probably saw when I was tweeting about a thing that we were working on the other day.
Rym: That sensor is tiny compared to the sensor in even like my Lumix GX one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Your phone sensor is even smaller than that.
Scott: And look at the phone sensor can do.
Scott: But when you get a bigger sensor.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like having bigger film.
Scott: The quality goes up.
Scott: You can get less.
Scott: You can get a shallower depth of field is really one of the big advantages.
Scott: You can open your lens up really big and sort of get that separation.
Scott: You know, that blurry bokeh background that the photo people are all excited about.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That your iPhone, your iPhone just fakes it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: A lot of people are starting to fake that even with fancy cameras.
Rym: Sometimes it's easier to get a a deeper depth of field and then just do whatever effect you wanted in post.
Rym: But.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Why not.
Scott: But yeah.
Scott: Bigger sensor means higher quality mostly.
Rym: Better low light performance.
Scott: Oh.
Scott: Low light performance is huge.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, you take photo in the dark.
Scott: If your sensor is big enough.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You can capture more photons with it.
Scott: You can capture more photons with a bigger net.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You get a tiny sensor.
Scott: You can't get that many photons with it.
Scott: It's too small.
Scott: How many of the photons in the room are hitting it?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Less.
Scott: If you had a big sheet of paper, how many photons in the room are hitting it?
Scott: Way more.
Scott: So, yeah.
Scott: So that's.
Scott: But the thing is the ability.
Scott: The fact that those can now record video.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They have powerful enough CPUs and fast enough storage in them that they can now record video from that big sensor.
Scott: The quality is just like wow.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Unbelievable.
Scott: The problem is that because of the form factor.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're still.
Scott: primarily were designed originally for stills photos.
Rym: So like they're not comfortable to hold if you're doing like if you're like doing camera work like video work.
Rym: They also don't have things like XLR inputs.
Rym: They don't have like.
Scott: You can add them.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You can add them with all these accessories.
Rym: But then you get one of these monsters with a million things plugged into it.
Rym: They have these.
Rym: They lack all these features, but they have an amazing camera.
Rym: So if you just plug like you're like you just record video with it or just plug an HDMI cable into it and plug that into your capture device.
Rym: That'll be a better camera than even most professional camcorders you might look at.
Rym: And you already own it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean the people these days.
Scott: what they tend to do is get all these accessories and attach like handles and rigs and cages and all sorts of things to the.
Scott: you know their mirrorless or you know camera to sort of make it good for videoing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And yeah it's it's amazing if you do that.
Scott: And you also get the side benefit of.
Scott: you have an amazing stills camera that you can change the lenses on and it's like the best camera you've ever had.
Scott: You're good.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And especially if you were doing something where you're like sticking the camera on a tripod and not touching it or like mounting it on the wall and pointing it at something.
Rym: It doesn't matter that it's not like all those things a camcorder does are not going to help you.
Rym: You're just wasting money or you're getting a worse sensor and not using any of those features.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And you know like I said phones are so good these days.
Scott: there's no reason to buy a standalone camera unless it's significantly better than a phone and you know how to use it so well that you're going to be able to make it better than your phone.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Now camcorders are in this weird space because if you go to the camcorder route instead of a DSLR there is a place like a really good place for the point and shoot equivalent because those things are pretty cheap like a few hundred bucks.
Rym: They tend to have pretty good sensors.
Rym: And they will record video very easily and very accessibly and you don't have to know that much.
Rym: And you also have to worry about things like a lot of phones.
Rym: if you try to record video for too long can start to overheat.
Rym: They're not really designed to record video for hours on end in a way that these camcorders are.
Scott: Nowadays they are.
Scott: The newer iPhones like you can make movies with them.
Scott: They even show you in the ads people making real movies with iPhones.
Scott: I've seen movies made with iPhones.
Scott: You know they're totally legit.
Scott: You know the only thing you really miss out on using an iPhone is like lenses and even then people have like tiny ones.
Scott: they stick on the front.
Scott: they actually kind of work.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But like a three hundred dollar like HD camcorder is really really really easy to use.
Rym: We'll get some pretty great.
Scott: I think the only advantage of that really is that is I don't think that's better than an iPhone these days.
Scott: But however it's cheaper than an iPhone.
Scott: Right.
Scott: An iPhone is eight hundred dollars.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that's the play.
Scott: That's why that still exists.
Scott: is because you know OK yeah your phone can be better if you buy a new phone.
Rym: But there's one other thing that these all have significant optical zoom.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That's also true.
Rym: Like phones are doing mostly ninety nine percent of the time.
Rym: all digital zoom unless you're nuts.
Rym: That does not get to the nuts part.
Scott: But you're not taking sports photos with your iPhone because you need the big zoom.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You're not taking wildlife photos of the iPhone unless you get really close to the wildlife because you want the big zoom.
Scott: Sometimes you need the big zoom and the phones don't have that.
Rym: And then the full on camcorders like what I use.
Rym: they mostly are built to be very rugged very durable and they have like a lot of convenience features for the kind of workflow of oh shit I got to get a video of that right now or I got to record something strange.
Rym: Like there's like little things like I can hit a button and pick what neutral density filter I want and it'll just do it on.
Scott: it's all built in it as I love.
Scott: my little street camera can do that.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: A lot of things.
Rym: a lot of video cameras can't do that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: No but yeah you're right.
Scott: The big professional camcorders the purpose they have is the sensors usually aren't as good as the the.
Rym: the sensor on mine is pretty small.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The they come with a lens that's usually a really pretty good lens with a wide zoom range right.
Scott: So you don't have to worry about switching lenses but you then again you can't switch lenses.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But the advantage they have is all these other things they have built in are things you would have to accessorize and intentionally swap in and out on.
Scott: you know if you were doing the sort of you know DSLR route right.
Scott: If you had some Sony you know A7 whatever and you would have to apply so many accessories to that thing.
Rym: That it turns into a giant camera that's less durable and like safe to use.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Like you're more likely to bump it into something and snap a piece off.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So features for example that a big semi pro or pro camcorder would have that you know you would have to accessorize would be something like a network cable.
Scott: You can just plug them right into the internet.
Scott: direct direct direct RTMP streaming just in it just streams just on its own.
Scott: If you want to add streaming to like you know my if I add streaming to my Panasonic GH5 you can't do that you.
Scott: the Wi-Fi isn't strong.
Scott: that it has is not strong enough to stream.
Scott: You have to plug the HDMI output into a capture card of some kind and then get that into a network cable somehow.
Rym: Things like redundant recording like stick four SD cards into it and it'll record the same video in one codec to two of them and in a lower resolution to the other two.
Rym: like that kind of nonsense.
Rym: Relay recording.
Scott: I can record to two SD cards at once.
Scott: I can't record two different codecs at once.
Rym: I can do two different codecs on mine.
Rym: What I what I've often done is one SD card is getting full like the maximum like maximum whatever and the other one is getting like a 1080p 30 basically mixed down that I could edit on my phone or tablet.
Scott: If I wanted to pretty quickly you know multiple microphone inputs right.
Scott: it's like my.
Scott: you know a little GH5 guy.
Scott: he's got one microphone input and you can get this accessory to add two XLR inputs.
Scott: Some of those camcorders it's like they got room for several XLR inputs.
Scott: You can get your your shotgun mic on the top.
Scott: You can get the microphone that like the news reporter is going to hold in your hand.
Scott: You can get all those hooked up directly to the camera.
Scott: No accessories necessary.
Scott: It's got like a full mixer on there for all of them.
Rym: Yeah you can even redirect the output like you can do clever stuff.
Rym: In fact one thing I've often done is had just the shotgun mic on pointed it at two different audio inputs on the camera and recorded one with a high gain and one with a low gain in case I run into clipping.
Rym: Like all these little like quality of life features that you probably don't need unless you're doing certain kinds of professional video but make it really easy to pick up the camera and deal with whatever shot you're trying to get right the fuck now.
Scott: Yeah it's just like you know.
Scott: it's like this.
Scott: it's an integration of all the pot like the most common accessories into one device.
Scott: Yeah but then they're sacrificing some of the camera bits.
Scott: but it's like you're doing video.
Scott: it's like what you know camera bits you need.
Rym: Like here's the compromise.
Rym: I have a Leica Dykemar 20x optical zoom lens in this thing.
Rym: It's a pretty good lens.
Rym: I can do a wide angle.
Rym: I can do macro.
Rym: There's like.
Rym: there's a lot of elements in there and optical stabilization I can turn on or turn off but it also only has a one inch sensor.
Scott: I mean you know you think historically speaking right.
Scott: even with film right when you're taking a still photo people are going to look at that one image for a long time right?
Scott: or you're going to use that you're going to print that image out right like on a poster or a billboard or something big maybe right or at least a magazine.
Scott: And you know you really just need the quality of that one image to be unbelievable which is why back in the day you'd still photos.
Scott: they would use like you know sheet film you take like a five inch.
Scott: you know photo right for some landscape or something right on just one giant piece of film right as big as a whole piece of paper.
Scott: just enormous right.
Scott: You know nowadays medium format is considered big which is.
Scott: but you think about it's called medium format.
Scott: There's there's a large format too.
Scott: It's enormous.
Scott: But even back in the day it's like films on film.
Scott: right old days it was the 35 millimeter film right spinning real fast.
Scott: you know there wasn't enough light to record on a giant piece of film.
Scott: Imagine giant.
Scott: you know large format film going through fast even 70 millimeter is ridiculous for for a movie.
Scott: And I think it's the biggest you're ever going to see right.
Scott: It's like you know.
Scott: So even though you have a camera that is you know a stills format shaped camera it's got this big sensor.
Scott: If I record 4k video on my Panasonic GH5 it doesn't use the whole sensor it's using a 4k shaped piece of the sensor.
Scott: And the rest a lot of the sensors being ignored because for video you don't need as much.
Scott: you're only looking at each image for a smaller amount of time.
Scott: And guess what that smaller image is still 4k still unbelievable.
Scott: That's how unbelievable the quality is.
Scott: just.
Scott: it's not about the video being low quality is about the stills being high quality.
Rym: Yeah it's what do you optimize for?
Rym: like a camcorder can get away with a like a lens that has a different performance profile because it needs to be more versatile but it doesn't need to be necessarily as high quality as what you would use in a still camera for like a zoom shot.
Rym: I just need a lens that goes from like 24 millimeter to 480.
Scott: So what the pros are using these days from what I can see is basically these video cameras like the best possible ones like the you know the reds and the RE ones and all that stuff.
Scott: And basically what they are is just sensor in a box right.
Scott: It's like if you ever watch like slow mo guys or whatever the slow mo cameras it looks a lot like that.
Scott: It's just a box and on one end of the box is a sensor and a hole to attach whatever freaking lens.
Scott: you can find some ridiculous cinema lens some you know anthropomorphic lens any kind of lens you can.
Rym: I think you mean anamorphic.
Scott: Anamorphic yeah or anthropomorphic you don't know.
Scott: both kinds whatever you know you're filming.
Scott: who knows right.
Scott: It's just some lens mount with a big sensor and a basically a computer and everything else is outputs.
Scott: you attach the storage separately.
Scott: you attach the monitor separately right doesn't even have a screen on it.
Scott: you just everything attaches separately.
Scott: It's just a sensor in a box.
Scott: you power it up you attach everything else to it.
Scott: you put it on a crane you put it on a dolly whatever you're doing at your.
Scott: you know film TV studio whatever and that's how they're doing.
Scott: And that's you know for a studio.
Scott: that's very practical right.
Scott: It's like it's its own piece.
Scott: if it breaks you don't have to replace everything else.
Scott: you know we can get a bunch of them right.
Scott: We can attach whatever we have to them to suit our needs specifically.
Scott: We're not locked into any choices here.
Scott: We have the money we can afford it right.
Scott: But for a normal person that's completely impractical right.
Scott: It's like you have to go and buy like the whole universe a rat to surround this box.
Scott: Yeah it's just a sensor and a hole.
Rym: And that is why I own a camcorder specifically like a professional one is because the kind of video I make most often is I just want it to work.
Rym: It's going to be a possibly interesting situation.
Rym: this camera's in and I want to just hit a bunch of buttons and make it work as quick as possible with the minimum effort minimum stress minimum risk of damaging anything.
Scott: So final recommendation.
Scott: Almost every single person should just use their phone.
Scott: Like 99.9% of people use your phone.
Scott: If you don't if you're not a professional at photo or video you're not.
Scott: even if you bought something expensive you probably wouldn't be able to do better than you can do with your phone.
Scott: So if you have the knowledge and the money and it's a hobby or you're into it you're a youtuber for real or something your twitch streamer for real you're big into it.
Scott: you're actually doing it.
Scott: you're not just thinking about doing it.
Scott: you're actually already doing it frequently.
Scott: Right you've proven that you're.
Scott: this is a thing it's for real for you.
Scott: now you're.
Scott: it's now your deal.
Scott: it's worth spending money on to you right.
Scott: The question is do you ever take are you into stills photos or not right?
Scott: if you're in distills photos go buy some mirrorless camera and whatever lenses and guess what.
Scott: it's also the best video camera you don't need to buy.
Rym: Or honestly if you record a lot of video then don't get a DSLR.
Rym: don't even get a still camera.
Rym: use your phone for still cameras and if you're recording a lot of video for some reason get one of those really small like hand cameras like hand camcorders like a Panasonic or a Sony.
Rym: They're not that expensive.
Rym: they'll do everything you want.
Rym: they'll look great.
Scott: Right you're going to save so much money right?
Scott: if you're not doing the stills photos it's like you're saving in.
Scott: you know your phone isn't good enough.
Scott: maybe got an old phone or you can't afford the newest phone that you know.
Scott: you can get a 4k.
Scott: you know one of those right?
Scott: or GoPro.
Scott: it's like that might be better than the phone you have.
Scott: I don't know a phone you have and it'll be cheaper for sure.
Scott: Yeah and then if you are just like a video only person but you are deep in the video zone and the video you are doing is more of the TV style video right the TV style video then you can go for the sort of prosumer camcorder right but if you're doing more of the movie video.
Scott: Right where you're sort of setting up your shots taking your time then you want to go back to the sort of mirrorless you know area right because you can change out the lenses you can get higher quality right you know put cine lenses on there anamorphic lenses on there
Rym: like my camcorder unless there's something wrong with the shot.
Rym: I'm using a lot of its automation because I'm trying to capture the events more so than trying to set a mood.
Scott: Right we're using it for recording a GeekNights panel.
Scott: if you need to make a movie like we you know we had a screenplay and we had seen I would not use my camcorder isn't?
Scott: the camcorder is not helping with that right.
Rym: So that type of camcorder there are better versions of that with bigger sensors that are used for film like if you need someone to run along with the camera and all that.
Rym: but those are pretty specialized equipment.
Rym: they cost a lot more than the camcorder I'm talking about.
Scott: If you're making a movie you really need to switch lenses out right.
Scott: yeah I'm doing still photos.
Scott: you need to switch lenses if you be general.
Scott: all-purpose lens is really just for.
Scott: I'm recording events right that are not.
Scott: you know.
Scott: visually it's.
Scott: it's not about the the.
Scott: you know the the camera angle or the lighting or the.
Scott: you know the scene right it's.
Scott: here's a recording of our panel.
Scott: Or you know some some documentary you know reporting type.
Scott: you know just here's what's happening stuff nothing artistic in nature.
Scott: about the filming itself.
Scott: you know the events that you might be recording might have value but it's you know it's not like your choices as the camera operator that are adding the artistic value to the the video record.
Rym: We went out a little long.
Rym: I think we can end pretty much there but this overlaps heavily with something we talked about in the last Thursday episode of GeekNights around.
Rym: that like the momentum to get started to do a thing and like trying to overproduce it or over plan it makes it less like you'll do it in the first place.
Rym: that's probably the most important thing.
Rym: what do you want to?
Rym: why are you trying to get some video and then think about how much are you willing to deal with before you can actually make the video.
Scott: Do as much as you can with with just whatever you have.
Scott: right you got a phone.
Scott: okay go and make.
Scott: do you want to do a video?
Scott: do as much of it as you can with your phone and if you can get it done why are you buying anything else?
Scott: just try to get it done.
Scott: and if you only buy something new if you're saying look.
Scott: I'm trying to do this thing I've been trying to do with my phone.
Scott: I researched how to do it with the phone.
Scott: I tried to figure it out and what I found is that yeah I can't.
Scott: I wanted to zoom in.
Scott: I wanted to take a photo of birds and I can't do that with my phone.
Scott: it's like well yeah because you need a fast zoom big zoom lens to do that.
Scott: their birds are flying.
Scott: they're going fast.
Rym: Remember those videos we do of walk around the expo holiday con.
Rym: do you know how much of a pain in the ass those were to record without a camcorder?
Scott: you could you could do that just with a phone.
Rym: nowadays we need to excel our inputs into that phone.
Scott: May that's I guess that would be the problem.
Rym: yeah I would wear a Marantz on me like on my waist.
Rym: Scott would wear another Marantz.
Rym: And then we had the camera and we deal with it in post.
Scott: Until you find something that you cannot do with what you have don't buy anything new.
Scott: but that's the state of what's available.
Scott: if you do end up in that situation with your video recording.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi McNicholallen, Joyce Link, EG Dredd, Lily Tannenberry, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walden, JustLikeADudeGuy, Kashiya85, Program Threat, Open Speed, UnderTakeLawAdoption, Pierce Absorb, Rebecca Dunn, ReviewMedBowl34Cowers, Ryan Perrin, Sam Erickson, Shervin von Horl, Taylor Braun, YouHoldTheKeyToMyHeart, and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: And now, tonight, I leave you with...
Scott: What do you mean, what videos?
Scott: You said people enjoyed the videos, what?
Scott: Yeah, you know when we'd hang out and we'd pretend to be characters and act out scenes and... Dude, you were videotaping that?
Scott: You saw the camera and the tripod, didn't you?
Scott: I thought that was just surveying equipment.
Scott: So you thought we were just hanging out and I was just surveying land on the side as like a hobby?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You never really explained what that stuff was.
Scott: I mean, but you'd hold it and you'd get shots and stuff.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You didn't tell me what I was doing.
Scott: You thought you were surveying the land.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: When you held the camera.
Scott: Well, you weren't.
Scott: We were making videos.
Scott: Oh.
Scott: And people really liked them.
Scott: Huh.
Rym: But even then, that doesn't explain how you didn't see the videos, because I sent you an email every time we made a video.
Rym: Those might have gone to my spam folder.
Scott: Why would my emails go to your spam?
Rym: You keep sending me like Roblox stuff, so I just kind of marked everything you send me as spam.
Scott: Well, you snooze, you lose, because I sent you a Chipotle coupon last year.
Scott: Oh.
Rym: Shoot.
Scott: You could have had a free burrito.
Rym: Dang it.