Rym: It's Monday, April 26th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight It's a tech news round.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Okay, so recently we did a show about like what something like wiring cable management or something like that.
Scott: But you know and we talked about different places to manage your cables data center house, etc.
Scott: Yep So, you know, of course after we do that, you know, I should have done this before we had that show but I went and I rewired my desk because the situation with my desk up until since I moved was basically Let's take all the wires and they'll be behind the desk.
Scott: But if you look under my desk, it was a disaster because they're all hanging and going every which way all over the place Right, but if you're above the desk, it looked kind of nice above the desk, right?
Scott: The only thing that didn't look nice was that I got this big shelf up on the wall above the desk and There's two speakers up there and I have the amp down here and so the speaker wire like running up the wall Right behind my little frame, you know, it was kind of fugly, right?
Scott: So what I did is I went and I bought a little Speedway like a little plastic Speedway Like.
Rym: they cost super cheap.
Rym: You'll just buy a giant pack of them and you won't be able to use them all.
Scott: Right, and it was it's a Speedway design to hold like one wire.
Scott: It is actually way smaller than I thought it was gonna be which is nice because it's way less conspicuous.
Scott: And basically all you do with this thing is it comes with some cheap sort of two-sided tape And you just stick it to the wall and run your cable through it.
Scott: It's so easy.
Scott: And now that cable is hidden and even though the Speedway is so cheap It looks way way nicer like significantly.
Scott: So so that was a bonus.
Scott: The second thing I did is I moved my desktop from the left side, right?
Scott: So it was on the left side of my desk because that was closer to the router and the NAS and such right To get the network cable to reach.
Scott: I moved it to the right side because that's closer to the power outlets and the UPS.
Rym: Oh, I get a longer network cable Right.
Scott: So I also got a switch.
Scott: so the network cable now, right?
Scott: switch before Right, so just to add some more ports anyway right because the router was full and I wanted to get my work laptop connected by wire instead of Wi-Fi to stop which did by The way I we talked about.
Scott: did we talk about the annoying noise on the show before?
Rym: did we talk about it on the show?
Rym: Or did we just talk about that in our real lives?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: but the point is there was a situation I'm using some software where a lot of packets a small packets were sent very quickly and when that happened to go to my work Laptop you would hear my router making noise and I'm pretty sure it was the radio.
Scott: and I'm now 100% sure it was the radio Because as soon as I plug the work laptop in with a cable to the switch that noise is gone.
Scott: So yes They've said a lot of small packets quickly over the Wi-Fi.
Scott: the router will make noise That you can hear if you have good ears, so that's solved.
Scott: But yeah, the only wires that go horizontally now all the way across the desk from the left Are the NAS power cable because I want to send that to the UPS.
Scott: All the other power cables that are over there can just go to the wall.
Scott: And then the red one.
Scott: now one network cable from the router going horizontal Everything else.
Scott: now what I did is I flipped my desk over and I drilled And I attached two cheapo metal cages to the bottom of the desk.
Rym: Ah the cage.
Scott: So now there's two metal cages under there and all the cables and all the power adapters and amplifier Which was previously on my desk, right?
Scott: Because the only thing I actually need to access with my hands is the little audio interface thing the scarlet whatever, right?
Scott: I don't actually need to access the amplifier.
Scott: I can just shove that underneath.
Scott: So that's down in the cage.
Rym: My annoying part is my audio input device needs a USB-C cable That's below like it has can't be longer than the spec or it'll run into sequence.
Rym: It'll run into synchronization problems possibly.
Rym: So I have the maximum length USB-C cable I can use and the only place I can put that thing where it's convenient is Behind my monitor instead of up top where I used to put the old one.
Rym: It's a minor annoy.
Scott: Yes for me.
Scott: So now the underneath my desk looks way cleaner with all those cables just in this cage thing.
Scott: So the cage thing itself is a mess just cables.
Scott: I just threw them in there.
Scott: Yeah, whatever but it's still a lot of less stuff on my desk a lot more stuff.
Scott: as you look under my desk It's like big and open now and it's like the wall.
Scott: you see the white wall there.
Scott: It's really great.
Scott: I have the.
Scott: it was super inexpensive right to do this like very very.
Scott: I bought the cheapest crappiest stuff.
Scott: My desk is very expensive and I screwed in these the cheapest possible metal cages to the bottom of it.
Scott: It was actually kind of a little bit difficult.
Scott: I'm glad I bought a new power drill to do it because the wood was so solid.
Rym: Oh, yeah I got some crap.
Rym: Oh I can't desk so I could just drive.
Rym: actually drilled a lot of things into it over the years.
Scott: It actually said do not.
Scott: the cages I bought were like do not mount this on a crap.
Scott: Oh IKEA desk.
Scott: It will just destroy At least with the included screws that it came with.
Scott: Yeah, if you've got it, if you have a big old wire mess, right?
Scott: I suggest go on the internet and buy the cheapest wiring.
Scott: There's so many options available.
Scott: It was way worth it.
Scott: And now I my desk is super nice every day.
Scott: I also bought a USB hub to put on my desk Which is super great as well, I have like 10 USB ports on my desk now like just right up front in the middle.
Scott: So I'm not like reaching down to the desktop to use the ports on that or the back of the monitor or anything like that.
Scott: They're just right there.
Scott: And I was also because I have this hub.
Scott: I was able to take various USB devices that used to have permanent homes on my desk and sort of stowed them away and it's Like well if I need to use them I'll take them out and plug them in and then put them back because I got a hub right here.
Scott: It's so accessible.
Scott: So that's great.
Scott: what I was surprisingly unable to find one thing is that I wanted to get you know This is a USB 3 hub.
Scott: It's not a USB C hub.
Scott: I wanted a USB C hub because a lot of more things are USB C. now.
Scott: all the USB C hubs I found were Designed for like.
Scott: you have a MacBook or you have an iPad.
Rym: It's got one USB C and you want to turn it into a bunch of other stuff, right?
Scott: I want something that turns one USB C into several USB C's at least four Right, maybe six something like that.
Scott: the one I have now turns one USB 3 into 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 USB 3's and three that are just power only.
Scott: Right, so it's pretty great.
Scott: The USB C ones were like it turns one USB C into an SD reader and one more USB C and maybe HDMI or display port or like some other.
Scott: you know, it's like that kind of thing Wasn't?
Rym: I think it's one USB C becomes five USB C because the technology of USB C Usually things that are gonna plug into USB C you're gonna take advantage of the special things USB C does.
Rym: that from what I've read are difficult to do in a hub the way that I sound like old USB Like I remember in the old days a USB hub divided the bandwidth by however many ports you had.
Scott: Yeah USB one or two Yeah, yeah Yeah, so I couldn't get a USB C hub.
Scott: that struck my fancy, but the USB 3 hub is still great.
Scott: I still have a lot of.
Rym: here's one that makes see for and it's only 20 bucks Five.
Scott: it's got me that link Dobe brand.
Scott: I'll check it out and see if it's legit.
Scott: cuz I want that.
Rym: I just type USB C hub and Amazon is one of the first things that popped up.
Scott: I'd search for that and I didn't see anything like that USB C hub for port high-speed data transfers Compatible with laptops.
Scott: I did that search and I didn't find any such thing.
Scott: But anyway.
Scott: So There you go.
Scott: That's that's the opening bit.
Scott: desk rewiring is good idea Yep.
Rym: So, uh Well pretty much just skip through the news and get right into the main bit after thing of the day since it's a tech news Round-up day.
Rym: We're just gonna talk about news the whole time Managed to last not a year.
Scott: you managed to last a year and a month since the last tech news roundup.
Rym: Good you had a few vague ideas for a different topic, but you weren't super into those.
Rym: So I figured we just do the tech news roundup next month next Monday show.
Scott: Now you realize you can't do one next, you know in 11 months you have to do it in.
Scott: now the date new date is April.
Rym: Pay ahead on principle instead of interest on your student loan exactly.
Rym: So things Of the day, this is a really short thing.
Rym: It tickled my fancy Partly because of the line of work I do.
Rym: but I sometimes enjoy when someone can make something that is horrific Like utterly horrific, but which technically 100% conforms to whatever specification it is ostensibly made for.
Rym: like I like that kind of toy project.
Rym: That's just the kind of thing.
Rym: I enjoy.
Rym: so Parker meek has written a song.
Rym: Parker is titled this song jingle bells - oh, I've seen this.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It's uh, it's pretty fun.
Rym: it is.
Rym: it's playing around with the Rules of how music notation works at least like Italian style music notation.
Rym: Nothing here is wrong.
Rym: This is perfectly valid notation.
Rym: It is just shall we say?
Rym: unorthodox notation and also this song other than the snare solo at the end is terrible.
Rym: I Mean, you know, you wouldn't want to listen to this song But if you're gonna listen to it You have to actually look at it'll play to show you the sheet music as it plays to fully appreciate what's going on here.
Scott: If you don't know how to read sheet music I mean You should at least know.
Scott: you don't need to read be able to read all that element Like.
Rym: I feel like everyone learns how to read Italian style sheet music in elementary school.
Scott: I learned like the basics.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Rym: yeah, you don't need to know much to understand this.
Rym: What's the time signature?
Rym: What's a key signature?
Rym: That's.
Rym: what's the tempo?
Rym: That's pretty much it.
Scott: You only even need to know like, you know whole note half note quarter note, right?
Scott: It's like.
Rym: well, there's some 16th notes and 32nd notes and glissandos here.
Rym: Yeah, anyway Over for a time signature at one point.
Scott: So my thing of the day.
Scott: I just mentioned how.
Scott: you know, I got a new little 12-volt power drill to.
Scott: you know, attach those things to my the bottom my desk is.
Scott: my existing power drills were Grandpa's drill from which is a super heavy unwieldy black and Decker monstrosity from who knows when it really sucks to use has to be plugged into the wall and a Battery powered power screwdriver from at least the 90s if not older.
Scott: That is so weak.
Scott: You're better off just using your hands and putting it in manual mode.
Scott: so We're gonna get rid of both of those things because the new power drill I got is way good.
Scott: But the new power drill I got advertises that it has a brushless motor, which is something I've heard Frequently, right?
Scott: They always talk about like oh, it's got a brushless motor.
Scott: It's way better, right and I always knew that like Yeah, there's a brushed motor and a brushless motor.
Scott: They're both, you know, DC motors.
Scott: They turn they rotate, you know The brushless one is better.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: that's why they advertise get the brushless one, right?
Scott: It's it's better in some way.
Scott: But and I knew the general principles of how a motor worked.
Scott: just any generic motor right, you know Electromagnet, right north-south it gets pushed in a circle, right?
Rym: I know how it's right Except that the mode of motors are basically AC.
Scott: Yes But did I if you told me hey Scott, what's the difference actually between a brushless and a brushed motor?
Scott: like I literally imagined like brushes like Brushes you would clean up your dust with like, you know, like that kind of brush, right?
Scott: And obviously, you know, but that made no sense.
Scott: It's like a brush in a motor.
Scott: What the fuck does that do?
Scott: Is it to like reduce friction?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Why would there be a brush in there?
Scott: So I went and I googled for what the difference was and I don't need to explain the difference because you can google as Well, and that's not what the show is about.
Scott: But what I found was something that was thing of the day worthy and that is this website Which is a brushless motor simulator.
Scott: You can control with this website pretty much almost every aspect of a brushless motor.
Scott: Right, how many volts are going into it?
Scott: It's everything right and see how it will respond.
Scott: You know how much torque it'll put out how many RPMs you can get all that kind of stuff.
Scott: So after you read about the difference between brushed motors and brushless motors, you can come here to test your your knowledge.
Rym: It's really easy to make a motor that doesn't do anything.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: And if you ever happen to be in a situation where like maybe you're writing some software It's like control of brushless motor in you know, some piece of hardware This will really help you out in terms of figuring out like what you know You should do to make the motor go forwards backwards stop, etc.
Rym: Yeah, usually a lot of those things like you'll have some abstraction software.
Rym: You can just tell it like I want to beat this RPM or this direction.
Scott: Yeah, sure.
Scott: But if you're writing that abstract, it's true true.
Scott: Or maybe just making something that's just an electronic device straight up.
Rym: Thanks, Dayton.
Rym: the whole time I was futzing with it till I got it to actually rotate Same direction at a consistent.
Scott: Yeah, it's surprising.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if you're just fiddling randomly.
Scott: It's surprisingly difficult to make it spin that.
Scott: arguably you need to know what's happened.
Scott: You need to know what's happening to make it go.
Rym: most of the foundational changes in human Technological evolution have been someone discovering that if you just fiddle with it randomly, it won't do anything.
Scott: Yep Yeah, it's good good stuff to know.
Scott: also I just want to just mention right I've one thing I forgot when time are rewiring my desk.
Scott: I got one of these little arch the cheapest possible arm to hold the microphone on.
Scott: Oh, yeah as we discussed previously.
Scott: So now it's no longer on a little stand on my desk.
Scott: It's now on this arm.
Scott: not really much difference.
Scott: The main difference is that now when I put my hands towards my keyboard There isn't some microphone stand in the way, which is pretty nice.
Scott: Not bad than that.
Scott: It's basically the same.
Rym: I have to remount my arm because it's a little bit too far away.
Rym: I've got it like stuck in a straight line between where it's mounted in my face.
Scott: Okay, but it's the cheapest possible arm like literally 20 bucks.
Scott: that cheapest.
Rym: Yeah, the better arms are mostly not actually better.
Rym: in my experience.
Scott: if this breaks like when will this break?
Scott: I don't know, but I'll just buy another $20.
Rym: I think I've had to break in the history of GeekNights and I spent about 10 bucks on each one.
Rym: So Considering that a nicer arm costs like $90.
Rym: I'm still I'm still profiting.
Rym: Yeah, this is fine in the meta moment.
Rym: Uh, it's warm out started reading.
Rym: tell again G again.
Rym: Watch out.
Rym: Oh Otherwise, we got no car.
Scott: I do that tonight because I have nothing to do tonight after I'm gonna play some games tonight.
Scott: No, I'll play a game.
Scott: what game?
Rym: Oh Roo doesn't come out yet.
Rym: That's when's.
Rym: that's tomorrow tomorrow, huh?
Rym: Tomorrow I got bleeds in the dark.
Rym: Well, nope I don't think I can play your wall I'm playing blades in the dark Considering I think we're about to make a deal with some sort of demon to make our boat powerful.
Rym: Anyway, so sort of vagabond to get a crossbow Just dive right into it.
Rym: It's the tech news roundup.
Rym: So I've semi randomized the order of all these newses.
Scott: Apple news first, right?
Rym: Yeah, let's do the Apple news first cuz that's sort of like the obvious news that's going on right now.
Scott: You know, I mean so the Apple news is like a week or two ago.
Scott: Apple news has always seen to happen on Tuesdays right after a GeekNights, right?
Scott: It's like we'll do a GeekNights Monday and then there'll be an Apple keynote the next day.
Scott: So what did Apple announce at the keynote that happened after we did a podcast?
Scott: The biggest thing they announced was the air tags, right which is a rumored for years I feel like at least two years and now is real like things that do these kinds of things in the past Like it's not a new.
Scott: Well, okay, so there is a popular product called tile and it does work rather well and I'm talking about tile.
Rym: I remember seeing some things that didn't.
Scott: your tile is the one that works right that everyone.
Scott: You know If you wanted one of these before you would get the tile one and so basically the idea is that you get some sort of electronic doodad.
Scott: You attach it to something that you don't want to lose and then if you lose that thing You can now digitally locate that thing because it has a doodad attached to it.
Scott: So you put one on your keys and now you can't lose your keys.
Scott: You can use your phone to find your keys.
Scott: Just the same way you can use your phone to find your Apple watch your Apple watch to find your phone or your Apple phone To find your iPad.
Scott: right with the find my system.
Rym: Yeah, put it on the car of someone you're stalking.
Scott: so the air tags are surprisingly a Inexpensive the 30 bucks each and you can buy a four-pack for a hundred which is what I did, right?
Scott: - yeah, Apple's gonna you know strong arm you on the accessories, right?
Scott: The air tag itself doesn't attach to anything.
Scott: You need to get something else to attach it to something.
Scott: So they're charging $30 for like a thing that turns an air tag into a keychain.
Scott: Wait, the third parties will be up on Amazon with like 10 packs of keychain right for like $5, right?
Scott: Just hold your horses on the go to some tech conference.
Rym: People will be giving away things to put air tags into Exactly.
Scott: You could even just attach it to something with tape.
Scott: I guess if you wanted to or you know, make your own right with your 3d printer or something, right?
Scott: the surprisingly even more.
Scott: the air tag takes a Perfectly standard coin cell CR.
Scott: I think 2032 battery which is a very common kind.
Scott: I have a whole bunch.
Rym: Apple didn't put a proprietary non replaceable battery in there.
Scott: No You're just a user replaceable coin cell battery that will last a year and that year estimate is Based on you like looking for your lost keys daily.
Scott: So if you basically don't lose your keys and don't try to find your air tag that often it that coin cell is gonna last a long time.
Scott: So yeah, you can get four of these for a hundred bucks and you can put them on your luggage, right?
Scott: That seems like a good thing to put.
Rym: a lot of people want to put them in their wallet Like put them on the things you lose the most.
Scott: I could see people putting what making wallets that have a spot for the air tag like inside somewhere.
Scott: I could see myself putting one in like the seat of my bike for when my bike I want to figure out where to hide it on the bicycle Like I'm gonna maybe try to mount it on the bottom of the rear rack or something like.
Rym: try to find a hiding place If you put it on your bike, that's not gonna help you get your bike back most likely.
Scott: Uh, you know, maybe maybe not who knows right it could.
Scott: it might.
Rym: Unless someone parks that bike outside you could just steal it back.
Rym: You're probably not getting back with an air tag.
Scott: this, you know, it's better than nothing, right?
Scott: It's and for 30 bucks that is worth it right if you it's like someone stole my bike.
Scott: I lost a $30 thing, you know, that might have given me a good chance of getting it back.
Scott: I say 50/50.
Scott: I'd say that's worth it.
Scott: You know, it depends on your bike and your $30, right?
Scott: But you know, yeah.
Scott: So yeah, these are I say pretty good if they were rumored for a long time there and they seem okay, right?
Scott: Yeah, next news the iMac.
Scott: They so the I met the new iMac is Shockingly thin.
Scott: it.
Scott: basically what they did is they took a MacBook the One and they took the keyboard off and the touchpad off and they stood it up and they put a big old monitor.
Scott: Well, I guess a my book has a monitor but a bigger monitor and they just stood it up there.
Scott: That's actually, you know, if you don't need to take it anywhere, that's pretty nice.
Scott: You get a bigger nicer monitor.
Scott: Yeah, you're getting the same m1 chip in all the other Mac devices.
Scott: You get your external keyboard and mouse and they make an iMac that has visa mount instead of a stand So you can put it on an arm and that's pretty nice.
Scott: so if you're a Mac user and you want a Mac on your desktop and you You know get the bigger screen.
Scott: It seems like a good good choice, I guess right.
Rym: it comes in nice colors They look slick and really if you're not playing games, you don't need to GPU.
Rym: probably fine.
Scott: It's it's not for me, but it's for someone.
Scott: so the next one is Apple.
Scott: the new iPad Pro right has an m1 in it and also Not only that even bigger news that people still seem to care about as much about 5g thunderbolt and an XDR display.
Scott: Right the XDR display, right?
Scott: That Means the.
Scott: the big iPad Pro which is the one I have only mine is few years old already has the same screen as like the super amazo Met ridiculously overpriced screen that sells.
Rym: people are saying like the contrast ratio Which is a little bit of a like.
Rym: that's a number that you should take with a grain of salt.
Rym: They're saying that the contrast ratio of this thing is a million to one.
Scott: Well, so the trick that everyone's doing these days is local dimming, right.
Scott: So for example the LG monitor I have here in front of me This 4k monitor has local dimming which and you can sort of see it in action.
Scott: And what happens is for example, if I put a black screen on the monitor except for my mouse cursor Which is white and I move the mouse cursor left and right you'll see that the monitor is dark Except wherever the mouse cursor is There'll be a noticeable vertical band where the LEDs are like turning on and the other LEDs in the back are off right and You know, so it's like okay you've made.
Scott: you've sort of achieved contrast like directly around the mouse cursor isn't really the great contrast because It's your.
Scott: you're illuminating this entire vertical band, but at least the rest of the monitor is dark, which is better than nothing, right?
Scott: It's better than having the whole monitor lit up.
Scott: It also saves power Although some power is spent on the processing of figuring out which LEDs to turn.
Rym: I mean, I think that's still a transitionary technology because event like OLED or the equivalent where each pixel is its own brightness Yeah, I don't know why Apple hasn't made it.
Scott: I guess they just can't make it work.
Scott: You think they would.
Rym: oh LED TVs even now ain't that cheap?
Scott: Yeah, of course, they're really.
Rym: they're pretty low resolution.
Rym: They're like if like 4k but gigantic.
Rym: so they're big.
Rym: I don't know how small LEDs can get right now.
Rym: That's true.
Scott: You make a retina one as an iPad.
Scott: I don't actually don't know about the current state-of-the-art of like small LEDs at all But what Apple has done is they taken that to the next level.
Scott: They don't have like this, you know.
Rym: Think we lost Scott.
Scott: I don't know what happened.
Scott: My my phone just started playing music randomly.
Scott: I didn't touch anything interesting.
Scott: Yeah, I want to see about that.
Scott: Oh, maybe I bumped my why I bumped my watch.
Scott: Yeah That's what happened.
Scott: okay, so What Apple has done with the XDR display is instead of just like these vertical bands?
Scott: They actually have lots they crammed as many little backlight illuminating LEDs as they could in a grid, right and those are like Individually.
Scott: not only are there so many of them, but they they can sort of you know, increase or decrease their own brightness level Individually, so if you did you looked at an XDR display.
Scott: if you had the black screen with the white mouse cursor It would pretty much only be bright where the mouse cursor was and that was it.
Scott: Yeah, so the the iPad Pro the 13-inch one the big one does that which is like An incredible screen.
Scott: like I kind of want that iPad, but the iPad Pro I have is still just fine.
Scott: So I'll probably get.
Scott: but it's exciting to know that whenever this iPad Pro does die two three four years from now Whatever the one I replace it with is gonna be like ridiculously good right without m2 or m3 in it or something.
Rym: It's like the upgrade is not super straightforward because also the new iPad Pro requires a different keyboard.
Scott: Yeah, so you if you like me bought the an expensive keyboard To attach to your iPad Pro.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: Your pencil your expensive Apple pencil will work with the new iPad Pro, but the keyboard will not fit.
Scott: You need to buy a new expensive keyboard Yeah Which is more expensive than my actual mechanical key.
Rym: because the new iPad Pro is thicker like significantly thicker than the old one.
Scott: It's really thicker because they crammed all those LED backlights into yeah as a whole extra layer in there.
Scott: But I'd say that's worth it, right?
Scott: It's not enough thickness that it's not worth it.
Rym: Yeah, and 5g which is sort of expected.
Rym: but That puts people an interesting situation where someone who
Scott: I always get the Wi-Fi only one But yeah if you do get the 5g one
Rym: Because then you've got a device that basically has unlimited bandwidth and all these features and depending what you're up to That could be the only device you really use.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the thing is, you know, there's two things that you know come from this.
Scott: It's like hey Apple now has the same exact processor in the Not the iPhone the iPad Pro The iMac the MacBook Right the Mac Mini all have the same exact CPU.
Scott: That's m1.
Scott: all of them, right?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: There might be slight differences.
Scott: I don't know if they've changed it, but they're calling them all m1.
Scott: I assume it's the same exact chip, you know, the differences are surrounding it You.
Scott: why aren't you Cowards putting a OS X on the iPad Pro, right?
Scott: They let you run iOS apps on Macs.
Scott: Don't let you run OS X apps on an iPad that has an m1 same chip.
Scott: No reason it couldn't.
Scott: And they still don't have Xcode on the iPad Pro.
Scott: Right, which is the?
Scott: you can't make an iPad app on an iPad.
Scott: that is still I've been saying this for years horseshit.
Rym: When I see about all I'll fix that like in general the old the people who I see using iPad pros where they actually use Like the real kit like all the extra capabilities it provides seems to be mostly Photographers and to a lesser extent video.
Scott: That's what I use it for.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I use it for.
Scott: Yeah, it seems like that is that might be which is why that improved screen is really good.
Scott: Yeah Right, that would be like it's still.
Scott: even with a brand new monitor The iPad Pro is the best screen in the whole house because almost everyone else I know like who has an iPad Pro and mine's an old iPad Pro.
Scott: It's old and it's still the best screen in the whole house.
Rym: But other than you and a few other people like everyone else I know who has one of these things doesn't do anything on it that a non Pro iPad could do.
Scott: if you are not doing any pro things photo video editing Anything of that nature do not buy an iPad Pro.
Scott: get the regular iPad.
Scott: It's just a regular iPad that is still phenomenally powerful.
Scott: That will is like the new iPad like the thing to do.
Scott: I've had air.
Scott: It's like it's a way.
Scott: good You don't need the iPad Pro if you're not doing pro stuff plus.
Scott: it costs a lot.
Scott: It's a thousand dollars.
Scott: It's like it's right if you you're getting the iPad Pro because you don't have a laptop right you're.
Scott: Your laptop is gone.
Scott: You're right.
Rym: Yeah I feel like you either have a laptop and a really shitty cheap tablet or you have an iPad Pro and no laptop.
Scott: You also if you have the iPad Pro, you're not buying the big phone.
Scott: You're getting the mini phone, right?
Scott: Well, no reason to have the pro iPhone based on the data.
Rym: No one's buying the small phone.
Rym: So Apple launch, you know iPhone 12 12 mini a little bit the fancy purple color but there's a lot of The last small iPhone.
Scott: if it's the last small iPhone if they announce in September October when they announce new iPhones as usual On schedule if the iPhone 13 does not have a mini variant I will be buying an iPhone 12 mini to put in the closet.
Scott: maybe two who knows.
Scott: yeah stash away Just in case because there's a bit alone is going to be good until it's considering the fact that my iPhone 7 is still good The iPhone 12 at MIDI is going to be good until 6g is out and 5g is like being faded away.
Rym: So yeah, but there's a lot of chatter in the industry generally about how basically Nobody wants small cell phones anymore at all.
Rym: Like nobody does there is no demographic of people Except like weird tech nerds like us who want small phones and any of you know any amount that matters.
Rym: So I think Sony might literally have the only small smartphones that are left that are like toys.
Scott: Yeah, we've talked about it many times.
Scott: Is that for most people like phone is their only thing or maybe they have a tablet just to be convenient At home?
Rym: part of what disrupted this I think is people have dedicated streaming devices instead of Htps, which later on we'll talk about how that is often still a mistake.
Rym: but anyway, yeah, so they have that.
Rym: most people just have their cell phone and If they're a kid, they probably have the Chromebook their school gave them.
Rym: Yeah, I forget I don't think we actually talked about some of the show, but it's a mini news.
Scott: Chrome OS it's an older news, but it checks out.
Rym: Yeah, it's literally the number two Operating system desktop computers like desktop consumer desktop operating consumer desktop laptop operating.
Rym: Yep, Windows is far and away the champion for you know, cuz people like to play games and run software But include servers Linux is the champion.
Rym: Yeah, but for consumer laptops and desktops It's Windows.
Rym: and then the next one down is Chrome OS almost entirely because of the school situation.
Rym: And then Mac OS is just an increasingly shrinking space.
Scott: Yep, pretty much
Rym: But it's interesting that I think what that means is that most kids like young people today like whoever like the kids younger than zennials They pretty much have a phone and a Chromebook They don't like to use because the school makes them use it and that is it and that is all they will ever want.
Scott: That's all the Chromebook doesn't do anything that they need.
Rym: personal, you know, yeah used for also depending on the school They go to.
Rym: either they like it's super locked down and the school doesn't let them do anything with it.
Rym: Chromebook by default is locked down it can only do so many things and also they probably are afraid to do anything interesting on it because they assume the school's spying on Them.
Rym: and they're probably right depending on the school.
Rym: So, uh, I'm not saying anything good or bad about that, but I think that trend is just the state of the world.
Rym: It's.
Rym: I think it's underestimated how that might shift consumer usage of things down the road because There's been a lot of speculation that larger phones are being driven by people wanting better battery life.
Rym: But so partially it may be partially true, but at the same time smaller phones Usually not iPhones, but all the other like Android phones They usually have a lower resolution screen and have comfortable or an oftentimes better battery lives than their larger equivalents.
Scott: Yep, that's it's definitely a thing.
Scott: where in Android there are you know, whatever smaller phone is available is also a weaker phone.
Scott: It's like they're not putting the highest end chips the highest end specs in the smaller phone.
Scott: It's like people, you know, if you want the most powerful best top-of-the-line phone It's only a big phone.
Scott: even Apple where the iPhone mini is really strong.
Scott: Yeah, that the better the max iPhone the bigger one does have better specs in addition to being bigger.
Scott: You can't get the pro max iPhone in the mini size.
Scott: Don't have that.
Scott: so but as we're even it even is someone who does want small Isn't with?
Scott: there are people who want might want smaller but aren't willing to sacrifice the battery life and the horsepower Which is interesting because most phone users don't use any of that horsepower.
Rym: like cell phone gaming does not push the boundaries.
Rym: that much For most.
Scott: well, I think also if the cell phone is your primary computing device and that's what you've got Then a big one makes more sense.
Scott: Yeah, I give I. if I only had the iPhone I didn't have the iPad or a desktop or anything.
Scott: I sure as hell I'd buy the giant iPad iPhone Pro.
Rym: so if I had no device and I could only have one I would probably get a tablet and with with cell capabilities and Literally not have a phone at all.
Scott: That might be a good choice.
Rym: Also, that's probably what I would do Just thinking about my life the big.
Scott: the biggest problem with that though.
Scott: Is that It's like that makes perfect sense until I have to like go somewhere right?
Scott: Go to a concert and bring my tablet Ride a bike with my credit.
Rym: I see so many people at conventions like holding up their stupid tablet to like get a video in a concert.
Scott: so because they were Convention makes a little more sense.
Scott: You have a lot of sitting in line time and you know, you may have a bag with you.
Rym: Yeah But I have.
Rym: I've encountered that a surprising number of times in my life.
Rym: someone like Holding on to a giant tablet trying to take pictures like out in the wild in situations where it really isn't appropriate.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but I think the screen size seems to be the primary reason because if that's their primary device What are kids doing on these things?
Rym: They're mostly watching movies and watching TV and watching shows.
Rym: that seems to be killing your battery.
Scott: That's why my battery doesn't go down.
Scott: I don't do that.
Rym: that kills the battery.
Rym: It also uses bandwidth etc.
Rym: It seems like all these factors together Lead me to believe that the screen size is the primary thing they care about because if the thing that's draining the battery is watching A bunch of movies.
Rym: They probably don't want a tiny screen to watch those movies on.
Scott: You know, I watch plenty of stuff on my iPhone 3G on the train.
Scott: I would watch anime.
Rym: I mean I watch stuff on my Sony Xperia and it's totally fine.
Scott: But yeah, I mean I don't watch a lot these days on my phone because I use the other devices.
Scott: But I have watched whole things on my iPhone 3G.
Scott: No problem Anyway, so one last Apple news that wasn't announced that their keynote is someone suing Apple.
Scott: and basically the story here.
Scott: I'm not gonna get into all the details.
Scott: You can read them.
Scott: It's you know legal stuff and whatnot, right, but somebody bought a bunch of stuff on iTunes Apple Store, etc.
Scott: Right, and it's when you go to buy stuff.
Scott: Sometimes it says get sometimes it says rent.
Scott: Sometimes it says buy, you know, depending on what you you know, like.
Scott: sometimes you like, you know get so you can download something.
Scott: But it's like there's gonna be in-app purchases.
Scott: It's not a whole all free, right?
Scott: But you can download it and at least run it for free.
Scott: you just you know There might be limited functionality until you pay for example, but if something says buy that you means buy, right?
Scott: So it's like if there's a game and the app stores is five bucks.
Scott: you pay five bucks.
Scott: You now have the game right.
Scott: there still might be more in-app purchases, but you you have the only game now.
Scott: He bites a music on iTunes or a movie.
Scott: Yeah, you download that movie and you can watch it, right?
Scott: Someone bought a bunch of stuff on iTunes a whole lot actually and then their account was shut Right for whatever reason.
Scott: I guess they broke Terms of Service or something and Apple decided to close their account.
Scott: Maybe they were doing something?
Scott: shit, you know, who knows?
Scott: And now all this stuff that they bought is gone and LA.
Scott: so they're suing Apple and they're saying hey Yeah, the Terms of Service says, you know, you can shut my account at any time.
Scott: and Apple says yeah Of course people it's common sense.
Scott: Everyone knows that if your account is shut you lose access to everything, but they're saying no No, no, it says buy I bought that you should at very.
Scott: they're saying that like at minimum sure you close my account.
Scott: You should not be able to take away the things I bought.
Scott: I should be allowed to log in and watch those movies listen to the songs play those apps that I bought and Even if you deny me from doing anything else making further purchases, you know, whatever, you know, that's okay.
Scott: But I bought those things.
Scott: So therefore I should have those things and I think apples in the wrong here.
Rym: I think this complain it now they I don't know why their account was shot.
Rym: It might have been bad stuff.
Rym: Like we don't know.
Rym: but yeah at least in terms of what this means If you buy something like if I buy a movie on Amazon I should have the legal right to watch that movie even if I don't have an Amazon account anymore.
Rym: However, they make it happen.
Rym: They should be forced to accommodate me and
Scott: I think I talked about how when you buy an app in the App Store Even if you know the app Goes away and you can't no one else can buy it You can still go it's like the purchased section of the of your account and find it and download it again.
Scott: Yeah, and how you couldn't?
Scott: we talked about that in relation to the Sony stores Not going down even though they might have gone down.
Rym: Well like I bought a bunch of random shows over the years just on Amazon and I pointedly chose to buy them instead of like get A rental or whatever and I can still just watch him because I have an account.
Rym: But I think this should also apply to if I buy something like that.
Rym: Amazon can't.
Rym: even if they stop selling that thing They have to give me access to it forever.
Scott: Exactly, and this is where it gets like the streaming services.
Scott: It's obvious like hey, you know you you're paying for Netflix.
Scott: This show is no longer on Netflix.
Scott: You can't watch it anymore.
Scott: It's like yeah, I'm paying for access to the service whatever the current state of it is.
Scott: Yeah, but if you were to buy something on Netflix doesn't sell things, but let's say they did Amazon you can.
Rym: there's Amazon streaming stuff that as long as you have an account like it's just for you to watch.
Scott: Let's say Amazon has a determinator for sale for five bucks.
Scott: You can pay five bucks and you now own Quotes the Terminator digitally on Amazon Prime video, whatever.
Scott: You can watch it all you want.
Scott: You own it.
Scott: You're not renting it.
Scott: Suddenly their agreement with determinators studio whatever studio owns the rights to Terminator.
Scott: I don't know who You know runs out.
Scott: and now they Terminator is no longer on Amazon Prime.
Scott: if I bought it I There should be right.
Scott: I should be Still able to download it and watch it as much as I want.
Scott: I bought it.
Scott: Yeah, now these companies should have.
Rym: they should be able to just not sell things like that like they could make different terms or whatever They really want to but don't use the word by use a different word which is sort of what the lawsuits about.
Rym: also I would try to grab services that did.
Rym: let me buy things and frankly I think the law should be.
Rym: the laws and regulations around this should be such that if you buy something The company has to provide access to it in perpetuity.
Rym: if the company fails to write access Then you should be able to get redress in terms of either the thing in an unencrypted
Scott: money back
Rym: Uncontrolled format like they have to give you the movie file now, or they are you have the legal right to pirate it
Scott: Or something like
Rym: that.
Scott: right just give me five bucks back.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: But yeah, it'd be interesting to see a conflict here, right?
Scott: It's like let's say Amazon makes a deal to distribute a movie and then they say buy the movie I buy it and then it's like okay The court says they have to provide it to me forever because I bought it But then they're their agreement with whoever they got the movie from runs out and they're not allowed to give it to me anymore.
Scott: So now they're basically wronged on both sides.
Rym: So it seems like Amazon already handles this when you buy stuff.
Rym: I definitely have bought things on Amazon like movies and TV shows that are not on Amazon anymore But I can still watch them when I'm logged into my account.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Well, that's good You know, but it's not a guarantee that that'll be the case and also The case.
Rym: I would sue Amazon personally, right?
Scott: Of course, but it's like, you know Something could happen to your account.
Scott: Maybe they accuse you of writing fake reviews or something and shut you down.
Scott: You lose all your movies, you know, who knows.
Rym: but I think Apple is squarely in the wrong.
Rym: and the saddest part is Apple like their lawyers really pulled some like Spurious arguments to try to get this case dismissed and the ruling was not that Apple is wrong.
Rym: The ruling was that Apple's motions to dismiss were not.
Scott: Yes, the case is going through.
Scott: they're gonna get sued Getting sued now.
Rym: Apple basically tried to argue that it's ridiculous that someone would think buying something means that they bought it.
Rym: Yes, that's basically what they argued.
Rym: Yep So there is actually some gigantic science and technology news like this Should in a just world overshadow any other news on earth right now.
Rym: This is bigger than COVID vaccines.
Rym: This is like.
Rym: this is big.
Rym: a year-long trial in Burkina Faso has concluded on a malaria vaccine And this malaria vaccine is Shockingly effective like 77% effective.
Rym: That's a lot.
Scott: malaria all the malaria in the world.
Rym: if we could vaccinate everyone and we could decrease malaria by 77% that would change the world more than like any medical advancement that's ever happened in the US in the past like 40 or 50 years.
Scott: So if you find a hundred people who had malaria and you said listen, I know a hundred of you have malaria But actually in the future only 25 of you are gonna have malaria and the rest of you won't.
Scott: the rest of you will Just live normal.
Rym: It's actually better than that not to get into it.
Rym: But you know because I learned all.
Rym: I learned a lot about but I'm not qualified to speak about The you know when we talk about the efficacy numbers of these vaccines like all the COVID vaccines 77% effective does not mean that the remaining 30 ish percent of people get it.
Rym: It's actually way better than that, but I don't of course That's the worst case.
Scott: in that worst case, it's still incredible.
Rym: Yeah But like I think especially a lot of Americans are people who live in industrialized countries.
Rym: Don't really without my personalized the horrific scourge that malaria is around the world and like it is still a huge problem.
Rym: It has not gone away.
Rym: It is in fact worse than it was in the past in many cases.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: You don't want it But this is huge news.
Rym: that like ate a vaccine deployed in the parts of the world that experienced malaria and high rates could actually like a fundamentally transformed society in those places in a Relatively short span of time as so many days all are killed or wounded or have long-term chronic issues from malaria.
Scott: So not only will that basically save like the people who live in malaria places, right?
Scott: But people who don't live in malaria places can now would be able to get the vaccine and then go there, right?
Scott: Places like this place is like I won't go.
Scott: It's like oh no, there's malaria there ain't going there.
Rym: I mean, I've been to places where malaria and yellow fever endemic.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like I'm not gonna go there on purpose.
Scott: It's some at least.
Scott: it's definitely just waiting people from going to places suddenly, you know, if you get malaria out Suddenly a lot of places turn way.
Scott: good, you know, you just you know, especially, you know, you think about it's like, you know In America, we have shitty health care, right?
Scott: how much like one medical incident can like ruin a whole family, right?
Scott: It's like oh, you know Someone got sick.
Scott: now our whole light all of our several people's lives are up ended taking care of this person because we don't have Universal health care.
Scott: It's a bunch of bullshit.
Scott: And then that you know add that up across an entire society an entire country multiple countries continents Right of how much damage is done.
Scott: if you could eliminate just like this one disease even 70 something percent How many of those families aren't gonna have just this fucked up thing that ruins their whole life of several people, right?
Scott: Not just the person who got it and got sick or died But all the people around them now won't have that and can now go about their lives, you know doing what they were doing before.
Scott: Right, it's like, you know and the net effect of that and the entire world is just you know, incredible.
Scott: So I hope this is legit and I deploy it which I'll get there.
Rym: we and there's a bunch of other.
Rym: Let's deploy vaccines from Larry like all these MR Like all the MNR mRNA research for the kovat vaccines has led to like there is a vaccine for multiple sclerosis That's being tested now.
Scott: We might be even know that was a virus.
Rym: It's not your food.
Rym: You can.
Rym: Vaccines can be made in novel and interesting ways now using this technology.
Rym: that opened up something.
Rym: We don't fully comprehend yet We might be on the cusp of radical transformation of how we treat disease just globally The end of disease.
Scott: that can be great.
Rym: Yeah, the problem is right now.
Scott: That is you know, that is a thing.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: It's like we keep going a universal health care universal health care, right?
Scott: And it's like if we just end a disease That wouldn't be such a big deal in right?
Scott: It's like for for.
Rym: well Let's just invite that to disease caused by pathogens and autoimmune disorders because when you get it amounts of mental health.
Rym: That is a different kind.
Scott: It's not gonna say a vaccine won't stop you from breaking your leg.
Rym: Also, yeah, well, there's a lot of other things.
Rym: but if there were no more infectious agents and there wasn't a huge let's say But also even then the cost of universal health care would be so much lower, you know, well unless you know Things like maintaining bodies maintaining mental health also Psychological.
Rym: there's a lot going on there.
Scott: It would still be lower than it is.
Rym: Hmm, right I mean I hope one day there's a cure for aging like.
Rym: I really consider aging beyond like 30 years Just be a disease.
Scott: Yeah, there are though, right?
Scott: It's like people talk about.
Scott: you see like it comes to the environment.
Scott: There's a lot of people looking for some sort of like technological escape hatch Like hey We won't have to stop burning fuel if we can just invent something that'll clean all the carbon out of the air like this pipe dream and that's very
Rym: Gorillas will freeze to death over the winter,
Scott: right?
Scott: It's a very unrealistic dream right to be able to do that.
Scott: It's not impossible, but it's like you can't be aiming as that as your way out, right?
Scott: It's like that's not gonna be the way we'll be dead before you figure that out, right?
Scott: But in terms of infectious disease, it's like, you know, I'm not saying that we should Give up on other options in saying.
Scott: Oh, we haven't a technological escape hatch now But this is a really promising technological escape hatch that we shouldn't just you know Brush off the way we brush off people with fantasies about sucking all the carbon out of the well Especially
Rym: because vaccines are interesting in that almost everything we can do to treat infectious disease relies on our immune system to do the heavy lifting.
Rym: because remember like to put it simplistically your body is filled with a semi-autonomous army that literally defends you from all this shit and most of the treatments we have for infectious disease involve Augmenting or assisting that system in some way are like most drugs don't do anything directly like the antibiotics will kill bacteria.
Rym: But most treatments for diseases just buy your body time to do its thing or train your body to do its thing in a particular way.
Rym: So those autonomous kill BOTS are going to be the neck of one of the biggest frontiers of medicine to come Like I think humans are barely if real.
Rym: So, uh pursuant to that Bill Gates is a horrible person because he actually argued recently that the u.s Should not open up the patents on all these COVID vaccines and all this type of research.
Scott: Strange it like the guy who's been known for like his.
Scott: number one thing is charity to fight malaria and diseases, especially malaria.
Scott: Yeah is like hey, let's not Let's not share vaccines.
Rym: It's like what the yeah, there's a Scope of this show.
Rym: but suffice it to say there should not be billionaires.
Rym: Bill Gates's money should be seized.
Rym: But also there's a weird problem right now where the u.s.
Rym: Actually has a surplus of vaccines.
Rym: But due to the former guy, I just like I like the fact I don't have to say his name anymore But the former president of the United States Specifically engineered the contracts with these companies to make the vaccines to prevent the export of those vaccines.
Scott: Means the US companies are evil and have no interest in going back on that housing it.
Rym: I feel like the right answer is to nationalize every major pharmaceutical.
Scott: yes, good answer, but Anyway, the go-go Moderna people.
Scott: I saw an art.
Scott: I saw in my headlines today.
Scott: I saw two headlines next to each other from two different news sources.
Scott: One of them said Moderna agrees to temporarily not enforce its IP rights until the end of the.
Rym: yeah The word temporarily is a load-bearing word.
Scott: So basically there.
Scott: so that headline basically says hey If you make COVID vaccine and give it out, we promise not we we're still holding the rights.
Scott: We own this.
Scott: but if you make it and give it out before the pandemic is over We won't.
Scott: we probably semi pinky swear with ourselves that we won't that we won't sue you.
Scott: But at whatever arbitrary point we declare the pandemic over of course people are still gonna want Vaccines because to prevent, you know, you have a new baby.
Scott: It needs a COVID vaccine.
Scott: Well, you're right.
Scott: It's like you don't want it, you know, right?
Scott: Or hey the pandemics over here someone hasn't been vaccinated.
Scott: they want to be vaccinated now, right?
Scott: Yeah We're gonna then start suing you and make you stop so that will then you know be the only ones making it afterwards.
Scott: And then the next headline I saw was like yeah, Moderna's full of shit And I was like those two headlines next to each other.
Rym: it's like Yeah, the one thing I hope before we go on to all the other news here that Something unique happened with these vaccines.
Rym: because irrespective of the intellectual property problems at least in the United States a Whole bunch of people experience what universal health care is like.
Rym: like you just show up.
Rym: They give you a shot They don't ask for any paperwork.
Rym: It just works Mm-hmm.
Rym: Yeah, that's you know, that's literally what universal health care is like.
Rym: imagine if you could do that when you got hurt.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I got a band-aid.
Scott: walk into somewhere get a band-aid.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So in some other news, let's skip ahead here.
Rym: So yet another car company has said that they're going to stop selling combustion engines by some arbitrary date.
Rym: That's far too out in the future.
Rym: It's 2040 which is earlier than some companies have said But it's still not enough.
Rym: We actually have a bunch of news.
Rym: is that we'll get to around cars.
Scott: But yeah, I saw a headline that was like yeah, you know, they're talking big about electric cars.
Scott: But if you look at the numbers Detroit is going all-in on SUVs for quite a while.
Scott: Yeah, right making more and more of them, you know.
Rym: Well, cuz there's two problems going on here.
Rym: on one hand We've put the moral hazard on the side of the consumer in that the consumer has to choose which car to buy.
Rym: Maybe can't afford a car that is more efficient.
Rym: Like there's a lot of problems there, but the electric cars are more expensive, but also Consumer preferences where I do want to put the moral hazard on those people.
Rym: people are buying Gigantic cars that are just.
Scott: they've been made.
Scott: they've been made to want those cars by the car companies.
Scott: They didn't want them originally Yeah, but it was.
Rym: but where is the line of?
Rym: advertising made them buy that cuz one could Not be tricked by advertising.
Scott: and yes If you look at the number no because we we have an example for this.
Scott: we got rid of tobacco advertising and it fucking work Yeah, which proved right.
Scott: so we should ban car advertising and alcohol advertising as well and pharmaceutical advertising.
Scott: Yep Well That tobacco advertising was bad, right but it's constitutional.
Rym: the problem with this type of news of like Honda in this case They're gonna stop selling combustion engines.
Rym: fine the problem is electric cars pretty much pollute the same amount because Most of the local pollution that comes from cars is from the tires which are not regulated at all.
Rym: Electric cars in the local environment pretty much just as bad as combustion engines.
Scott: look at look at a photo of a traffic jam And just be like okay all the cars are electric.
Scott: now It's like okay.
Scott: I guess there's a little bit less pollution in this area.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We have a better Came from somewhere.
Rym: we have a better Collecting and distributing the energy to run those cars like electric car.
Rym: if you ignore the tire problem Electric cars are at least better than the alternative because we can generate Electricity and transmit it with overall less harm Assuming our electric grid moves away from things like coal which is yet another problem.
Scott: You're replacing the you know, the gas refinery with some lithium battery factory, you know You know replacing the oil rig and the ocean with a lithium mine.
Rym: But that arguably if we move to certain kinds of nuclear power that ends up being mostly a wash or likely slightly better.
Rym: And it's different kinds of pollution contributing less to global warming.
Rym: However Local pollution doesn't go down because electric cars generate more particulate pollution from the tire degradation Which there's no good way to solve right now.
Rym: and that kind of pollution Well, it doesn't contribute as much to things like global warming.
Rym: That's the kind of pollution that causes things like health problems in the people who live in the places where cars are.
Scott: It also, you know maintains car supremacy Which doesn't help.
Scott: you're locally.
Scott: it still maintains all your public space is still taken up by roads.
Rym: It doesn't change the induced demand problem of cars and car infrastructure.
Scott: Anyway, anyway cars are not the answer.
Rym: So here's the news.
Rym: It's kind of nuts.
Rym: So there was this post office scandal in the UK.
Scott: Like I haven't gone deep into the story I saw the headlines but didn't read the details.
Rym: So basically there was some software It looks like was made by Fujitsu and it was used to manage the finances of post offices.
Rym: in the early 2000s Apparently a bunch of people 42 people who worked for the post office were convicted of stealing money Based on data from the software like the accounting caught them stealing.
Rym: some of them went to jail.
Rym: There was they like 42 people had their lives basically ruined because recently Judges in a court of appeal have ruled that all those convictions are invalid Because it was just due to software glitches in this.
Rym: in this system Some of them lost their homes.
Rym: Some of them couldn't get insurance.
Rym: Some of them are now dead and can't even be compensated.
Rym: Basically this software set a bunch of people to jail for nothing.
Scott: Yeah, whoever made that software should go Get swapped low.
Rym: So, you know we were talking about this before the show.
Rym: there's an image that's been making the rounds on the internet that is like a 100% apt to a lot of the problems in the industrialized world today that basically said Computers should never be allowed to make management decisions because computers can never be held accountable for their decisions.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: That slide that was what from a presentation in the late 70s.
Rym: Yeah, it was an old thing.
Rym: I guess we're just incapable of learning lessons You don't say but this kind of story is Extra nuts because I cannot imagine Like I haven't.
Rym: I've gone through all the details.
Rym: I don't even know enough about like European or in this case.
Rym: I think British law.
Rym: How could someone even be convicted when the no money was actually missing?
Rym: like yes Like where's the word?
Scott: the money go?
Scott: look at my bank account.
Scott: There's no money there.
Rym: Yeah, like I feel like for all the problems of the American judicial system This particular case feels like it would have been difficult to.
Rym: it would have been difficult for this to happen in the?
Rym: u.s due to the way our structure like the system of course is coupled with the fact that generally America's doesn't have a good track record of even being able to prosecute technologically advanced crimes.
Scott: Yeah, I feel like you know, we think about you know, the the sci-fi cliche, you know minority report or V for Vendetta, right?
Scott: Yeah, by the way is from the country in question here, right?
Scott: And you know you this like surveillance society, right?
Scott: Which I guess this is part of right.
Scott: they had this accounting software was Surveilling the activities of all these employees and then the evidence from that surveillance was used to convict them Even though it wasn't just you know surveillance cameras, which we usually think of And you know, we think of China as like using it intentionally and knowingly right?
Scott: It's like you sort of how we characterize them.
Scott: It's like yes, they're they're doing 1884 on purpose, right?
Scott: Whereas we sort of characterize, you know, the UK as doing it, right?
Scott: They've had cameras all over the place, you know before anyone else right?
Scott: I'll feel it feels like before anyone else.
Scott: But it's like it always sort of felt like they weren't doing it in the sort of on Purpose big brothery way, but instead, you know doing it in sort of a not heeding the warnings kind of way.
Scott: And I think that that characterization is probably in part racist, right?
Scott: It's like they're doing it just as much on purpose as China.
Scott: is what?
Scott: what really is the difference between?
Scott: You know going, you know, I mean there is a difference, you know, the UK isn't currently to my knowledge Committing a genocide.
Scott: They did all the genocides in the past.
Scott: Where's China's genociding right now?
Scott: But how much difference is there really between China and the UK, right?
Rym: How do you get to a point to where you have some software that Fujitsu wrote?
Rym: That's so buggy that it just means like it reports just wrong numbers and then an entire legal system just sends prosecutors.
Rym: they successfully prosecuted 736 people based on data from this for jitsu software.
Scott: This is why we probably Believe, you know at the time they believed that there was widespread, you know Whoever was there believed there was this widespread crime happening.
Scott: and just like people are led to believe that there's like things like widespread voter Fraud.
Rym: Yeah, but it's fascinating that you can have this happen when there literally wasn't any crime.
Rym: There was no evidence of crime Software but people believe that there is widespread.
Scott: In this case though the government believed the conspiracy instead of the people or maybe the people and the government believed it and then bad Things happen
Rym: and it doesn't get a broader for
Scott: slightly lucky that you know We were able to at least you know, we had a government that part parts of it believed in parts of it didn't write.
Rym: so now we've been talking about this topic on GeekNights for over 16 years.
Rym: the simple fact that Globally no government and no judicial system is capable of interacting with even the most basic of digital crime.
Rym: Yes, like.
Rym: they just can't in any way deal with it.
Rym: Like either they can't prosecute people who clearly did a crime or they just prosecute random people who didn't commit a crime Like it's just all over the place Mm-hmm In some let's see skipping ahead.
Rym: So there's a bunch of news.
Rym: you probably saw Elon Musk's stupid tunnel, which is clearly like unsafe and pathetic.
Rym: I guess you didn't.
Rym: Scott didn't even notice that it was in the news because there was like a tour of it and they were Like driving cars.
Scott: Yeah, I thought I mean I did see.
Scott: I thought it was just yeah.
Scott: Elon Musk announces another evil scheme and shows off, you know an evil villain presentation yet again.
Scott: I didn't think it actually happened Until Rym mentioned that it actually.
Scott: yeah, he actually did dig the tunnel.
Rym: They drove.
Rym: so they drove that they drove a car through the tunnel and just to summarize you can go read This was dunked on appropriately by people who know better.
Rym: one the tunnels so narrow You probably couldn't even get out of the car if it had a problem.
Rym: Two the cars can't self-drive through it as far as anyone is said.
Rym: Three if if anything happens in the tunnel, basically everyone in the tunnel dies Like there's no way to get an emergency vehicle in there.
Scott: I don't understand what the deal is.
Rym: It's just I mean we have like just a tunnel that's shittier than like any of the tunnels from a hundred years ago under Manhattan.
Scott: It's like we have tunnels.
Scott: tunnels are not a new invention.
Scott: We have them.
Scott: We know how to build them.
Rym: It's the tech bros who keep saying we can solve the housing crisis by making cheaper to build houses.
Rym: like House building is literally the least difficult part.
Scott: We have empty houses.
Scott: There's more empty houses than there are homeless.
Scott: Yeah, like digging the tunnel.
Scott: Just buy them the houses give the houses to the people.
Scott: It's not a matter of building the house.
Scott: Just give them the house.
Scott: That's already there.
Rym: Same thing with like Elon Musk and his stupid hyperloop.
Rym: digging tunnels is actually one of the things humans are super fucking good at.
Rym: We can dig tunnels.
Scott: We have civil engineers.
Rym: Yeah, you know digging the tunnel is not the reason why we don't have enough tunnels.
Rym: There is one reason why our governments don't build mass transit.
Scott: Yeah, come why don't you just come and take whatever money you spent on that tunnel and give it to us and we'll repair our Tunnel to New Jersey.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Not that I want to go to New Jersey or I want to have New Jersey coming here But yeah, probably fix that tunnel.
Rym: granted if the Republicans in New Jersey hadn't blocked it our seven train The subway would have gone to New Jersey.
Rym: Instead it doesn't and now there's no way to make it go there Yep.
Rym: Well a minor aside I know we've talked about how you can't get video cards because of these stupid coins and NFTs which are all just scams.
Rym: but This these shortages are starting to expand and this is gonna get way worse before it gets better.
Rym: Silicone is getting under short supply.
Rym: chips are getting in short supply.
Rym: We're getting to the point to where multiple car manufacturers have said they're cutting down production of cars Solely because they can't get like the basic chips They need to make these cars and it seems to be solely due to the demand from cryptocurrency.
Rym: bullshit.
Rym: Yep I mean Disrupting hospital supplies like this is gonna be a problem.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, this is yet another argument and just in you know in you know, we learned in school, right?
Scott: It's like, uh, you know communism the USSR.
Scott: They couldn't manage, you know their own economy, you know by hand Capitalism is not doing much better Right.
Scott: Yeah capitalism.
Scott: It's like, okay.
Scott: Well, we'll let the market decide Instead of making the useful shit We actually need because it made that you're making.
Scott: that other shit makes numbers go up by scams.
Rym: Market decided.
Rym: the best analogy for cryptocurrency at this point is remember in Captain Planet where there'd be a villain who had a machine that Basically just pumped out pollution and generated money.
Rym: That is basically what cryptocurrencies are Pretty much.
Rym: Yeah, like it's a machine that just makes it doesn't even generate money.
Scott: It just vacuums up money from suckers From suckers and blows them into the wallet of the evil versus and it burns down rainforests in the process.
Scott: yeah, pretty much.
Rym: but like I Think these shortages are just going to get worse and worse and worse for possibly years to come.
Rym: like I Don't think you're gonna be able to build computers soon.
Rym: the way this is going like I don't know I've heard.
Scott: I've heard some people say it'll last six more months.
Scott: I've heard some people say it'll last into next year.
Scott: Well, here's the problem.
Scott: It's gonna have to be hard to prognosticate because there are is.
Scott: that's why no one agrees.
Rym: There are legitimate companies who are investing in this shit now Partly because it makes such high returns that that risk is acceptable to them Mmm, which is adding further legitimization which gets even more suckers to think it's gonna be a longer play.
Rym: So, I don't know when it's gonna crash.
Rym: I Think it's gonna last longer than people expect.
Rym: I think the crash is gonna be way worse than people expect.
Scott: Yeah, the higher you go the farther you fall.
Rym: Yep Anyway, and some others stay down here.
Scott: Trust me.
Scott: It's safer.
Rym: This is super fun.
Rym: So signal which there are some problems with the signal company that I don't want to get into right now.
Rym: Like they're doing some cryptocurrency now.
Scott: I couldn't understand the know than whatever nonsense was going on with them.
Rym: Yeah, but one thing about signal is that it is one of the few Properly end-to-end encrypted networks out there and if you like it like I use it for actually secure communication Like.
Rym: that's how I would endorse it.
Rym: however, uh signal Did something really cool recently and basically fucked up another company Celebrite who basically exists to hack into like iPhones, right?
Scott: So for example there, you know, if you are in the United States mostly but also other countries, right and you commit some crime And let's pretend everything's hunky-dory you committed a crime.
Scott: they get a warrant, right?
Scott: Yeah, you know.
Rym: they come in and take our iPhone that probably has the all the crime information on it exactly.
Scott: They seize your phone.
Scott: They seize your computers.
Scott: They seize all your digital things legally, right?
Scott: You you know, they have warrants.
Scott: They're gonna investigate them.
Scott: You know the FBI is common right and They need to collect.
Scott: basically what they do is they scan all the storage on all of your devices.
Scott: that's what they're interested in and to and they're looking at all your files and To see if there's evidence to relate to the crimes you committed.
Scott: they can find things like the web browser history.
Scott: You know your documents, you know, whatever right whatever is on your computer your child porn that you shouldn't have because you're right But you're.
Scott: this is for criminals, right?
Scott: So what they do is they can't just you know, open up windows and start browsing.
Scott: who knows?
Scott: first of all a Well, maybe then someone could say you made that file you put that child porn there.
Rym: right computer forensics is a difficult Like it's like any other forensics.
Rym: It's method you try to use.
Scott: You try to log in and maybe I have you know my iPhone.
Scott: if you try to log in and fail ten times It'll erase itself, right?
Scott: You can't just go about it normal way.
Rym: think about the old story that no one actually had but everyone dreamed about of the Computer where you hit a button and thermite destroys all your hard drives from the 90s exactly exactly.
Scott: So You need to.
Scott: if you're gonna collect evidence and submit it in court You need to do it in a court legally approved way which is with certain software that has been approved and you know checked out by the government.
Scott: and One of the most pretty much the most popular was a thing called celebrate which is the company makes this thing.
Scott: I think it's an Israeli company and they have software that can help.
Scott: law enforcement would buy the software right.
Scott: take devices from people and You know extract the the storage the data from the storage devices in a way that is admissible in court legally.
Scott: and so what signal did?
Scott: is they said hey the celebrate thing itself is You know for being a computer security company that made it isn't so secure is it?
Scott: and they basically put a file On the storage device for celebrate to find.
Scott: and when celebrate found that file Celebrate itself was then, you know exploited.
Rym: that is some ghost in the shell fun nonsense right there.
Scott: So you could make your computer such that if sella, you know celebrate is insecure.
Scott: therefore if you celebrate Comes and tries to read all the data off your hard drive Your hard drive base is a booby trap that catches only celebrate and messes it up if it tries to read your hard drive Signal.
Scott: the engineers there created a proof of concept for this that totally worked and that's and they announced it.
Rym: Like you go read all this and watch their videos because they also say they found some Apple copyright violations in celebrate software.
Scott: I believe it.
Rym: They found some MSI installers like digitally signed by Apple and some other nonsense in there.
Rym: The the story is pretty in-depth and you can go as deep into this as you want.
Rym: But I think this is just fascinating because in the end like my opinion on this is that Encryption is necessary.
Rym: Backdoors in encryption are unethical and if a police organization or a government Even if they have a legitimate interest in this information the theoretical They're trying to hack into the terrorist cell phone to figure out where they put the bomb Even in that case.
Rym: I don't think any technology company should in any way be required To make it easy or possible to compromise the security of their devices.
Scott: Yeah, if it mean if it happens to be possible, you know on purpose it was never secure in the first place Exactly, but if it's brief you made a really secure device, you should be a allowed to.
Scott: let's say let's forget about computers, right?
Scott: Let's say I actually make a lock and that lock is truly a Indestructible.
Scott: it's made of adamantium wolverines adamantium.
Scott: You can't break it and be.
Scott: it's such a good lock.
Scott: Even lock picking lawyer can't open it.
Scott: best lock in the universe unpickable.
Scott: Obviously, that's impossible.
Scott: Let's just pretend right that that lock exists and it's.
Scott: it's locking a safe and the whole safe is made of adamantium There's.
Scott: no you can't.
Rym: there was an episode of the old Superman live-action show that was about this.
Scott: actually Yeah, even if you nuke it you won't open, right?
Scott: The only way to open it is legit way to open it, which is a combination that the criminal knows, right?
Scott: It's like well tough shit.
Scott: It's like too bad That's you're not opening it.
Rym: Yeah Legitimate interest.
Rym: do actual Investigatory work like get a warrant tap the wiretap key loggers Like there's a lot of traditional ways.
Scott: find some other evidence.
Scott: if you can't get that evidence find some other evidence.
Scott: Yeah, I think this lazy way out of demanding someone, you know open they're safe for you if they don't want to write.
Scott: All right, one thing I got it.
Scott: we got to talk about this.
Scott: one news, yep So the Linux kernel, you know, it's an open source project.
Rym: Oh, yeah this one contribute.
Scott: So somebody sent in some patches and the Linux kernel.
Scott: people looked at those patches and we're like what the fuck is this nonsense?
Scott: And then somebody linked to this published academic paper from the University of Minnesota where what they were researching?
Scott: They were researching the idea that hey, what could you?
Scott: Submit patches to an open source project Right and get them accepted and merged.
Scott: but they also contained, you know security holes right, but the people who were accepting the patches didn't notice.
Scott: and Then you come along later and now exploit the security vulnerability that you got injected into the open source project.
Scott: Yeah, because the open source project didn't notice because you were.
Scott: so the patch you sent was so clever, right?
Scott: They're researching like that.
Scott: Could this be done?
Scott: Can you do it?
Scott: Etc.
Scott: And there's a whole paper they published about, you know doing this.
Scott: So they saw this suspicious patch come in and they noticed that it was from someone at University of Minnesota.
Scott: and Then someone linked to that paper and suddenly the whole kernel is like what are you guys?
Scott: You know what the fuck you doing here trying to see right?
Scott: It's like they were trying to research whether you could sneak stuff in and lo and behold they couldn't sneak one past They couldn't get it in there.
Scott: So the response of the Linux kernel people, you know, Greg Crowe Hartman mostly was hey Not only are we not accepting your patches the University of Minnesota is no longer allowed to send us any patches We'll just block you right?
Scott: We don't care what you send us.
Scott: we're not accepting it because you can't be trusted and we're gonna go back through the whole Linux kernel and find anything you ever submitted and We're gonna check it all out and we're gonna remove Most if not all of anything you've ever contributed because you can't be trusted.
Rym: and I find it hard to fault their response.
Scott: and they sent them a list and they said if you want to if you want to Undo your band.
Scott: He has a list of things that you can do to undo your band, right and the University of Minnesota The people there they sent an open letter on the kernel mailing list and they said we're sorry we fucked up.
Scott: we've learned, you know, basically right that sort of letter yeah, and Greg's response to that was We sent you a list of things you can do to get on band.
Scott: You haven't done the things on the list.
Scott: I don't really give a shit.
Scott: what you write in your own letter.
Scott: Go fuck yourself do the things on the list or get the fuck out of my face in in so many words much fewer words Than I used.
Rym: I'm pretty cool with this letter.
Rym: honestly on one hand like all open source Software has to be vigilant for this kind of thing because clearly other people are gonna try to do this all the time.
Scott: Yeah, and actually try to put you have a widely, you know, if you have a project that's not used widely then who's gonna bother Just and try to submit you a pull request.
Scott: That's got some shady biz in it.
Scott: Why would they?
Scott: that's barely gonna affect anything but Unless you yourself are using it and you're a high-value target on your own, but if you have a popular open source project Yeah, you got to be on the lookout.
Scott: every single patch has to be you know security reviewed in some way To look out for any sort of intent unintentional shady biz or intentional shady biz.
Scott: And if you get word right in the community that for example University of Minnesota is submitting shady patches If you're running an open source project, it's public contributions.
Scott: search your commit history for anything of at umn.edu.
Scott: I think that's the that might not be the right one.
Scott: Just check it.
Rym: Yeah, and If you see any Inspect those patches real closely or revert them, but I guess I don't fault the university for doing this kind of research.
Rym: I also don't fault the open source community for deciding to take punitive measures against them.
Rym: It seems like it was a rational like appropriate escalation in this case.
Scott: I Think if you do I think they went there about the research right like the wrong way, right?
Rym: Research is a debate we could have here.
Scott: It's like it's one thing to be like, yes, this is something that should be researched, right?
Scott: You know are you know, what percentage of open source people do have their eyes open and don't is something information We should know right?
Scott: we should raise people's awareness about this.
Scott: So the open source project maintainers are on the lookout But you shouldn't actually get actual security holes into the Linux kernel that is on all these computers around the world.
Rym: Well, I wasn't wasn't clear.
Rym: the article I read is if there were vulnerabilities in the specific patches they put forth They think they're you know, regardless.
Rym: Also, here's another thing.
Rym: I don't think there's no cry.
Rym: I mean, it's open source software.
Rym: I could submit anything Sure, unless I exploit that.
Scott: but if you're being all you're being underhanded, right?
Scott: You're lying about what you're submitting, right?
Rym: You know, yeah, but arguably it's not.
Scott: it's not illegal to lie It's not illegal to lie, but it's morally wrong.
Rym: But what if the patchy got in and then then the university was able to say look the Linux kernel is easily compromised and we Just compromised it.
Rym: Here's what we submitted.
Rym: Please back it out.
Rym: This is a global crisis now.
Scott: They didn't do that.
Scott: Yeah, and also you should.
Scott: you know you you could.
Scott: what you could have done is you could have you know Submitted it seen what the comments were before it got merged and then you would stop it before they merged it.
Scott: You'd be like, hey, I actually don't merge that.
Rym: Well, I would say the motive issues of the researchers are irrelevant.
Scott: They've been doing this for years.
Scott: This isn't a new thing, right?
Scott: They're going back.
Rym: I'm saying what the researchers did is irrelevant.
Scott: Let those all those patches sit in there for all these years.
Rym: And the reason I say that is that an open source system is obligated to protect itself and it has done just that Like.
Rym: here is the.
Rym: you know, we always talk about how.
Rym: there's no difference between being popular and being denial-of-service.
Rym: So in this case There's no difference between a hacker trying to fuck with you and some researchers at a university.
Rym: in both cases Your response should be the same.
Rym: It is a threat and you neutralize the threat.
Scott: Yeah, they neutralized it.
Rym: So Let's see still we've got on pretty long So I think I'll blow through a few things really quickly and then that'll be gone more round up.
Scott: All right, what you get?
Rym: so a back on cars being shitty.
Rym: a Tesla crashed Burned for four hours.
Rym: The fire department was unable to put the fire out and it killed two people in, Texas.
Rym: Upon investigating this charred Ruin of death they discovered that there was no one in the driver's seat.
Rym: the two people who were in the car had told this Tesla to drive and had climbed into the backseat and Then the car killed them.
Scott: Well a how is a car street-legal if you can't put the fire out.
Rym: Uh, yeah, that's a big problem with electric cars.
Scott: actually and be Obviously, why was the car able to continue driving when no one is?
Rym: obviously because Tesla doesn't actually want to enforce the rule that says there has to be a driver sitting in the seat ready to take over at any time.
Scott: because If they did that why you would want?
Scott: you want news stories about your car crashing and sitting on fire.
Scott: Well, I think
Rym: they know that none of the people I was about to use a pejorative term for these people who are buying Tesla's that are self-driving would actually buy them if They couldn't just tell the car to drive because it turns out that self-driving software is not nearly as versatile as they want it to be.
Rym: They probably wouldn't buy the car if they couldn't disable the safety checks.
Scott: I guess at least it will only kill people who buy Tesla's Oh and Crash into somebody else.
Scott: That's why it shouldn't be street-legal.
Rym: That's why yep I self-driving car technology is far more advanced than people realize in some regards for like freeway driving Limited types of environments like truck cars or certain certain parking situations automatic parking.
Rym: One could argue that it should be mandated for all those situations but the problem is Even if it is actually better in those circumstances Let's forget all the circumstances where it's obviously not better and we could mandate that every car has it.
Rym: Humans will still misuse that technology and not actually pay attention.
Scott: We have technology as good as it is.
Scott: It's still nowhere near good enough.
Scott: It's like light years ahead of human driving in certain situations But it's light years behind where it needs to be to just drive you and you can take a nap.
Rym: I mean there is the problem where we accept the fact that a lot of humans are worse at driving than even like the shitty Tesla self-driving.
Rym: they shouldn't be allowed to drive they shouldn't but in practice they are because our entire society is built around these guys.
Scott: Yes What you really care about this whole topic?
Scott: There's another podcast called the war on cars.
Scott: read listen to that podcast instead.
Rym: But it is just very telling that Tesla for all its advanced technology could Trivially detect if there is no one in the front seat.
Rym: and yet it does.
Scott: Yeah even even like a super old like The last car that I was in right had a passenger side airbag and there's a light that would tell you whether the passenger side Airbag was enabled or disabled.
Scott: I don't know why they had a light for that, but they did.
Rym: dude and me I Drove a car Important and I rented.
Rym: I rented a super fancy car because they didn't have anything else So they gave me the fancy card.
Rym: I paid nothing for it.
Rym: Jokes on you.
Rym: I dropped it off in like Leroy, New York.
Rym: Good luck getting someone to rent it there.
Rym: the point is thousand dollars a day But this car had stuff in it where while I was driving It would play tones if it detected that I was not sufficiently paying attention to the road.
Rym: It was looking at my eyes the whole time.
Scott: But that point is this car is older.
Scott: car would simply Know by the weight of whatever was sitting in the passenger seat whether that airbag should be enabled or disabled.
Scott: Why doesn't the Tesla?
Scott: I mean, yeah, it can be fooled by someone putting like a bag of rocks in the driver's seat.
Rym: Yeah But make it make it at least hard to.
Scott: they don't have that and not only do they not have the industry standard very easy Weight sensor.
Scott: that would.
Scott: it could just do it, right?
Scott: At least it's one more thing.
Scott: Someone has to do to get the car to drive without a person behind the wheel But they refuse to put it in.
Scott: it's like fucking.
Scott: why Why not?
Scott: The car is already expensive.
Scott: Just put the thing in the weight sensor and the driver's seat So it won't enable if there's no one sitting there.
Rym: Come on Yep but like if these are the fancy technologically advanced cars.
Rym: Technology already exists to determine if a human being is paying attention to the road and they're not doing that doing basically nothing.
Rym: I think Tesla the company should be directly culpable for basically murder in this case.
Rym: I Now the humans who died are also culpable for actively Circumventing the safety measures, but yeah, we're lucky that they didn't hurt anyone else and only got themselves those two people.
Rym: And Tesla the company is also culpable.
Scott: Yes You know and who knows like the burning batteries the you know, the firefighters might have gotten.
Scott: I had to breathe some shit in.
Rym: Firefighters have been saying that electric cars aren't ready for a long time and they have yet to be proven wrong in my mind.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Rym: There's a lot of not to get into it.
Rym: There's a lot of.
Rym: you know, I grew up My dad was a fireman so like I know how to use the jaws of life.
Rym: jaws of life could kill you if you use them on an electric car and Don't know where you're not allowed to cut.
Rym: some of those wires are in non obvious places with a lot of voltage Yep.
Rym: so Well, this is one more big thing.
Rym: There's so many big things recently to talk about.
Rym: Roku is currently warning its YouTube TV customers that YouTube TV could just stop working anytime because Google is a monopoly.
Rym: YouTube is now fighting back saying oh, we're not acting in good faith or in bad faith.
Rym: You're acting in bad faith.
Rym: This is there's a big fight going on between Google and Roku right now.
Scott: They're probably both bad in this situation.
Scott: who knows who's on the right side of things?
Scott: But the point is is that do not get dedicated streaming device.
Rym: Always live in arbitrary TVs smart TVs.
Scott: they're always limited to whichever app.
Scott: some businesses agree that will let you use the HTPC is the only way you need to get a real computer.
Scott: Even if you don't want to play games, you can just get a Mac Mini Otherwise PC and it will do everything.
Scott: because every no one has their service not available on Windows.
Scott: right Netflix YouTube TV just straight-up youtube.com Hulu HBO max everything is on just plain old Microsoft.
Rym: Yeah, I do nothing.
Rym: It can't do I worryingly do believe especially considering the computers are not a thing for most people anymore.
Rym: There will come a time when some of these services only have an app and there is no other way to access their content.
Scott: It is possible that that will have.
Rym: I think the death of the desktop PC and the death of the laptop for Non-professional users is going to lead us to that very bad place down the road, but I don't even Right, but even like everyone's phone, right?
Scott: Cuz some people have iPhones some people enter.
Scott: the common factor is still the web.
Scott: Everyone's got a web app right the web browser.
Scott: So all these things, you know, you they work on the web.
Scott: So as long as that's remain as long as the web remains the thing then we're okay.
Scott: Yeah, but I remember way back with a web browser to connect to your TV.
Rym: We were trying to watch YouTube videos at a friend's house and they had an app on their streaming device and we found that there Were a lot of YouTube videos mostly ones that had a copyright thing where they were not taken down.
Rym: But like the monetization was weird Where they just wouldn't show up.
Scott: if you search for those videos and the streaming ad you went to your phone and you found the Video, but you couldn't find it when using the yup.
Rym: I've run into that many times in my life.
Scott: that specific thing with YouTube Specifically, yep To use a real device for your TV.
Scott: Don't use any of these roku's or anything.
Rym: speaking of those roku's and anything you might have seen this a little while ago, but there this is a insider like announcement about some venue technology that Warner Brothers Sony Paramount Visio CBS Universal seemed to have developed together and it is a Set-top streaming device, you know.
Rym: The thing we just said you shouldn't use.
Rym: but it's killer app is that you can give exclusive special content through it Because it has cameras facing the audience and you have to buy a ticket for every individual human who is in the room watching that thing.
Rym: This is obviously dystopian bullshit.
Rym: yeah, it's also not clear if this will actually get made and released to the public because patents on things like this have definitely Come about before.
Rym: but in practice no one actually made devices that did this ridiculous nonsense.
Rym: But this is just one of those.
Rym: I got further along than a lot of those other ones.
Scott: No, it's just one of those ideas that people have that make you know executives all horny.
Rym: Well, because the customer is not you the person trying to watch content in your exactly.
Scott: You don't want this.
Rym: the customer is like a company that wants to be able to sell pay-per-view.
Rym: where they get to they get a cut.
Scott: Yeah, are you telling a movie executive?
Scott: hey, you know, we can make a technology where you know If someone shows a movie in their house and there's ten people sitting there will can charge them ten times as much.
Scott: They're like, oh, yes do that.
Scott: They just want they're just a greedy guy.
Rym: You know what they're mad about.
Rym: Remember way back there was that disastrous round a Rousey fight.
Rym: one friend of ours paid for the PPV And we all watched it like 30 of us on the HTPC.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: Um, so that's you know, they're they're excited for that, you know Someone came up with this idea and sold it to them.
Scott: It got money from them.
Scott: that person now doesn't even care if this thing really comes to be or works.
Scott: They're just like hey, I got rich people to give me money because I had an idea that makes them excited.
Scott: Right, but ideas that make normal people excited don't get funding and you know They have to actually make it all the way to market first right to get a pile of money.
Scott: Yeah, because that's how our capitalism works.
Scott: So yeah I'm not too worried about this becoming real.
Scott: and if you look at the history things like divics the DVDs that Disintegrated after you watched them one time or whatever.
Scott: Yeah, those did not work out very well.
Rym: divics not to be confused with divics Exactly.
Rym: I don't think I don't think anyone younger than us has ever even heard of the original divics because it died its rightful death.
Scott: Good, but yeah, they made DVDs and a special DVD players.
Scott: We could watch the movie once and the idea was that like hey, we'll sell people DVDs for cheap But then they can only watch it once and then we will sell more.
Scott: right is like an idea that made movie executives really excited.
Scott: No consumer wanted that ever.
Scott: they actually did sell them in circuit city and they were complete bullshit and they failed.
Rym: Everyone I knew who got one got it to hack it in some fashion.
Scott: Yeah, and this is this is the same kind of idea.
Scott: where it's like if someone actually makes this it will just fail miserably.
Scott: The one Avenue I could see this maybe coming to fruition is not in the home because who?
Scott: no one's gonna buy it, right?
Scott: is The pay-per-views that happen in bars and such?
Scott: where right now bars have to buy like these licenses Like special pay-per-view things when they want to show like a boxing match or a Super Bowl or whatever They're in their bar, right?
Scott: And there's already an existing system around that.
Scott: but if somebody had the ability To count how many people were in the bar and send that information to some home base, right?
Scott: I mean obviously they're already bars and other places that are pirating those that's not going to change Obviously, but the places that are doing it legitimately and are currently buying into the system could be forced to Have some sort of technology not hack it right.
Scott: someone comes to inspect it or who knows what right and then They could get charged more if the bar is more crowded during the Super Bowl than if one person come Yeah,
Rym: which could
Scott: like actually be advantageous to the bar instead of paying the flat fee based on like their?
Rym: well I'm pretty sure whatever.
Scott: the only one person came to my bar for the fight.
Scott: I'm not paying you Right, whatever.
Rym: the end of charging the bars would magically be the same or slightly more than what they're paying with The current rates is what I would.
Scott: probably it wouldn't be too.
Scott: probably it would not be.
Rym: I just took a class on how to do pricing in the like the current modern world and Yeah, it would cost.
Rym: the same is what I would suspect.
Scott: but it could also give the the bars perhaps more features, right?
Scott: Like hey, you got a bar.
Rym: We're gonna let you show a movie that came out fucking but we're gonna collect the Demographic information to the people who watched it in your bar and spy on you with surveillance cap.
Scott: exactly you charge a cover fee.
Scott: We'll count the number of people in your bar and we're gonna take half your cover and we'll know you're not lying about the cover.
Rym: Now we know the gender race Economic income.
Rym: you can figure out someone so she know what everyone drank the u.s We're gonna change.
Scott: we're gonna see what people are drinking and change the beer ads.
Scott: live cuz we're even up.
Rym: It's still dystopian like don't get us wrong.
Scott: But I think that has a more possible chance of happening than the in-home count people.
Rym: Yeah, so last last news.
Rym: This is another big one.
Rym: This is wild type because I'm hungry.
Scott: I'm hungry, too.
Rym: It's a food related one.
Rym: This company has been made sell cultivated salmon Like the salmon I would use in sushi on like a nigiri Mm-hmm, and apparently it is pretty much indistinguishable from a real fish but grown entirely in a lab and Should be able to be scaled up to produce sushi grade fish entirely in a lab with no cruelty.
Rym: It's basically chicken knobs for fancy salmon.
Scott: Well, is it?
Scott: what color is it?
Scott: It's pink Is it so?
Scott: I read a thing recently that talked about how salmon in the ocean right or wherever you get them?
Scott: are Pink because of what they eat which is common for a lot of animals.
Scott: their color changes based on their diet.
Scott: Yeah, you know.
Scott: and that the farm salmon the ones where they're just you know Farming salmon and like wherever they farm them right are actually gray because they feed them different food.
Scott: You know They're not feeding them the natural whatever.
Scott: and then they dye them pink because who's gonna buy a dark gray salmon?
Rym: I mean if it tastes the same like it tastes exactly the fucking same.
Scott: I would buy it but People would go into the grocery stores.
Scott: a gray sand, you know what.
Rym: there's a sort of aside.
Rym: the fundamental thing You always have to think about when you talk about the public or public policy is that I never matters.
Rym: People is a very different demographic from I or you or they Exactly.
Scott: So they die.
Scott: farm salmon pink to make it, you know That people will buy it if you grow the salmon in a lab.
Scott: just sell cultivate salmon flesh cells, right?
Scott: They just start growing.
Scott: You know if they're pink Does that mean that you're feeding them the thing that makes them pink?
Scott: are they dying it?
Rym: or the article doesn't talk about how?
Rym: They get the pink color, but it does talk like it talks about the actual flavor Like people have eaten this in trial.
Scott: I taste just like salmon.
Rym: Yeah, they said it tastes like very clean salmon.
Rym: In fact That's good.
Rym: Like it's a little less fishy, but it no mercury and such.
Rym: Yeah I Really look forward because eventually there's an endgame for humans where we literally don't eat meat that came from things with nervous systems again and just think about it if we get what.
Scott: first of all We got to upgrade to get the lab-grown tuna because I would be unbelievable, right?
Scott: But then - it's like you go get some sushi, right?
Scott: And it's like all the sushi great salmon.
Scott: We had to fly this fish across the world.
Scott: It was all fished yesterday.
Scott: It cost a lot of money.
Scott: It sucks for fishermen, right?
Scott: But that's a dangerous dirty job.
Scott: Yep That maybe no one should have to do even though it's a lucrative job, but regardless it's like hey We just got a fuck ton of salmon.
Scott: We just grew it and we got shit loads of it.
Scott: Oh you want to eat a little tiny sushi?
Scott: No, here you go.
Scott: We're gonna fill the whole fucking boat full of sushi.
Scott: It's so cheap, right?
Scott: It's like let's go everybody, right?
Scott: It's like we need to be like, oh, here's your little sushi.
Scott: It's like oh, no.
Scott: No, here's the big boy.
Scott: It's like no more hunger.
Scott: for right Let's say you come in instead of $14 for a little tray.
Scott: It's like $14 of sushi.
Scott: Holy shit here Here's the whole fucking fish.
Rym: I even I look forward to like make up a new fish and then like that is a new type of.
Scott: I am really looking forward to invent new animal New flake, you know, it's like, you know, yeah invent new flavors by cooking with new ingredients, but like just invent ingredients Don't exist.
Scott: I feel like this - yeah, like this is uh, this is the Scott fish.
Rym: It tastes great It's you know, but like hints of honey on one end like things like seafood like scallops fish like this.
Rym: They seem more suited to lab growing because like the way the texture is like this seems easier to true true.
Rym: and on the other end Bulk cheap meat like fake beef in bulk is also something we can make it.
Rym: Well, it isn't quite as good as like quote real beef for like a fancy burger or a fancy steak.
Scott: If you McDonald's it you won't fucking know the difference We got.
Rym: we got fake meat white castles the other day that has the heme proteins in it.
Rym: They fucking taste better than they taste more like meat than the actual meat.
Rym: white castles like for real.
Scott: So listen, I won't say it tastes more like chicken, but I've been eating the the Gardein fake chicken Tenders, you know once in a while.
Scott: not not like eating them like constantly, right, but I basically don't eat chicken nuggets.
Scott: I was like dinosaur meat.
Scott: Yeah, they don't taste you know, like Chicken right entirely but they taste better that the thing that they taste like.
Scott: I prefer Rather eat those than eat chicken nuggets.
Rym: Well, especially considering that meat production is one of these single biggest contributing factors to climate change and deforestation in the world The there is an eventual point where we literally as humans do not kill animals for meat and we throw chicky knobs like this in Labs and I really look forward to that day.
Scott: Apparently you can present it as dystopian, but I don't see it that way.
Scott: I see it as hey look you need to eat protein to eat.
Scott: Let's get the protein in the best way that we can get it and let's make it as delicious as we can make it.
Scott: make it using my most efficient energy source is possible because Agriculture limit their imagination.
Rym: the agriculture that sustains the meat industry.
Rym: Itself is a huge contributor of carbon and also requires a lot of oil.
Rym: the way we do it today We've talked about that God like a decade ago on GeekNights, maybe more.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And at that point I'm looking at this picture of the salmon.
Rym: I gotta eat some food.
Rym: Oh my god, so I think I'm eating.
Rym: tech news roundup.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi McNichol Alan Joyce link eg dread lily tennant break Chris Reimer Clinton Walton crane paddock old man safe desk peacock mind snack Finn Graham Finch just like a dude guy.
Rym: kashaya 85 Ren from New Zealand.
Rym: review mad bull 34 cowards Ryan parents Sam Erickson Shervin about oral Taylor Braun you hold the key to my heart and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: So now you want to have a tech news roundup till at least April of next year.
Rym: So for now, I'll leave you with.