Rym: It's Monday, August 23rd, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We're talking about Apple see Sam and privacy, you know, one of the biggest stories in the last few weeks.
Scott: We could actually done the main bit on computer sleeping.
Rym: Oh We should save that for another one Because I already set all this up.
Rym: Write it down.
Rym: I will write it down.
Rym: All right Let's do this.
Rym: So we went down to a private beach house with some friends to get away for a week And then we didn't have to race.
Rym: like it was easy to get home before the hurricane.
Rym: but that tropical storm escalated pretty quickly and Actually hit New York and if there's some I say fun flooding because the flooding in New York was not like super bad.
Rym: in the end We actually got pretty lucky and the storm petered out and hit other places worse.
Scott: It was just a whole bunch of rain.
Rym: Yep It was enough rain though to where I thought.
Rym: you know, it would be cool like what I've done in the past.
Rym: I'll go out for a run during the tropical storm or the hurricane like it won't be.
Rym: that sounds like a bad idea But okay, I mean unless the winds super bad like that's fine.
Rym: If it's warm like what I'm wet.
Rym: who cares?
Scott: Yeah, but it's not as bad of an idea as the people who go like surfing when the hurricane is coming, right?
Rym: But that is the best surfing Yeah, but it's also the deadliest Yeah, you do taking your life in your own hands in that case like like the one who's always in your own hands.
Scott: Sometimes it's in someone else's hands Sure, but it's still in your own hands, even when it's in someone else's hands, but so we get home.
Rym: I think maybe I'll go run.
Rym: I got on the balcony and it is raining Hard enough to or even I am like, yeah, I'm just not gonna go outside at all.
Rym: You know, it's not gonna work out.
Scott: No surprise.
Rym: I've biked home in similar rain, but that's different from doing like an hour-long run Mm-hmm.
Rym: So yeah, there is.
Rym: we missed a week of shows because I was out of town.
Rym: we came back for a brief One show week and we went out of town again.
Rym: we're finally back and with pretty much on a regular schedule for the foreseeable future and of course a ton of Honestly really important big deal.
Rym: tech news happened the one time.
Rym: We're not around to talk about it.
Scott: It happened.
Scott: I think before we left We just didn't have a Monday show between then exactly between the last Monday show we did.
Rym: and now on three Major stories happened and I'm not allowed to call for a tech news roundup.
Scott: I'm sure more stories It's more major stories than that happened.
Rym: But oh, yeah a bunch happened.
Rym: But these three were the biggest three that we got something to say.
Rym: Yep So instead of doing a normal main bit, well, basically the news we have the most to say about became the main bit.
Rym: We'll see how that goes.
Rym: So first things first, we'll dive right into it.
Rym: Only fans Basically pulled a tumbler Right.
Scott: So only fans.
Scott: I'm sure you know what this website is, but just in case you didn't it's a social network type site Where you pay to follow someone and most of the people that you're going to be paying to follow our porn stars or sex workers and That you know, it was.
Scott: it was a site that a lot of people used.
Scott: There's a lot of competition for it now that I've seen some people using.
Scott: but yeah It was it's a thing.
Scott: It was a thing and it's soon gonna not be a thing.
Rym: Yep, and Effectively with a bunch of caveats and a lot more complexity than we really want to get into.
Rym: they're banning Pornographic content the likes of which the most people who use only fans use it for that is what they seek out.
Rym: That is why that platform grew.
Rym: That's why it was there.
Rym: That was the primary reason people use it.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of.
Scott: I saw a lot of jokes on Twitter that were the equivalent of like.
Scott: oh in the news today orchard stop Selling apples.
Rym: It's help.
Rym: What's interesting is only fans.
Scott: McDonald's stop selling burgers.
Rym: the company acted like.
Rym: they were surprised that this announcement was met with people just dropping their platform Like they were.
Rym: they seemed surprised at the huge amount of vitriol anger and basically the fact that their business is done now Like they're just destroyed Mm-hmm.
Scott: But yeah, so I Mean, it's really surprised me and that usually the pattern of a Silicon Valley business is to start out completely ignoring laws Regulations rules of any kind.
Scott: right the way, you know You see uber continuing to do uber way of trying to change the rules.
Scott: In fact, they went far above and beyond.
Scott: That's another news that their rule change was ruled unconstitutional in the California court.
Scott: But usually you see a crunchyroll style pattern, right?
Scott: It's like start out with just a pirate anime website and then become legitimate anime website and then eventually they're bought into Funimation slash Sony and it doesn't matter anymore that they were once committing crimes, right?
Scott: So and many many Silicon Valley businesses operate this way.
Scott: just you know.
Scott: They start off that.
Scott: you know You can't afford you if you try to start any business even a small normal little business like say a restaurant And you try to follow every single fucking rule right right out of the gate from day one.
Scott: You know paying every tax getting every inspection, you know everything.
Scott: you're the costs to start the business.
Scott: We'll just ruin the business.
Rym: Yep, pretty much every convention you've ever been to started running like directly illegally.
Rym: Yeah, every day Even packs.
Scott: I can think of very few businesses that start just doing everything completely by the book 100% kosher and succeeding and going far.
Scott: It just doesn't happen that often right?
Scott: so?
Scott: and but in Silicon Valley It's to a greater extreme of the illegalness, right?
Scott: Just blatant disregard for all laws to get your business off the ground.
Scott: just straight capitalist extortion Exploitation not extortion and then whatnot.
Scott: So that's what only fans did just you know, ignoring all the porn laws, right?
Scott: They couldn't afford to actually Verify.
Scott: every single person is a man.
Scott: you imagine if every single person who went to only fans and said new account Right point my webcam at myself get naked Make money, right?
Scott: That's like a 10-minute process or at least it was You know very quick process.
Scott: if only fans actually verified and checked on every single person who was either a customer or a service provider On their site the cost and time required to do that what they would have been impossible to surmount They just go under
Rym: yeah, but what I what's interesting is that it appears pornhub had a similar problem.
Rym: You might remember last year where their payment processor went after them.
Rym: But they actually changed their policies to comply with the payment processor rules.
Rym: And if you have it, I'm if you're unaware pornhub is still around and doing fine.
Scott: Yeah, well, I mean because they're doing.
Scott: I don't know how well they're doing but they removed a lot of the porn on their site.
Scott: They basically don't let people just upload, you know, look at something like YouTube, right and you know Pornhub's doing a better job moderating its content than YouTube is.
Scott: Well, I mean pornhub but used to just allow people to upload whatever the hell horn be.
Rym: So what pornhub now it's like?
Scott: yeah, no almost no one can upload anything.
Rym: So what pornhub did to comply with those rules was pretty simple.
Rym: They only allow like verify ID users to post videos and No one can download videos directly from the site.
Rym: Like obviously there's an analog hole and everything.
Rym: analog hole for the analog hole but you can't actually download the videos.
Rym: and there's a couple other minor changes they made around moderation and that seemed to Get them around the new rules.
Rym: It's unclear to me Why I mean, there's so many things going on in the story.
Rym: But if we just focus on OnlyFans what I don't understand is if OnlyFans has such a user base and is so big Why could they not now that they're established do what pornhub did?
Scott: I don't know that's.
Scott: you think that would just be the common sense thing to do because the narrative of why this happened.
Rym: Someone who knows more about this than us could probably do an entire like YouTube series just on this space.
Rym: But essentially there is a long history of politicians Conservative interests and a variety of industries not just banking Generally just trying to keep porn out of the public discourse and the legacy of that and the damage of that All not just porn but also sex work is clearly a factor here.
Rym: that legacy continues.
Rym: There are very conservative forces in these spaces, but there's a bunch of other factors at play.
Rym: For example Pornographic content is one of the primary causes of chargebacks, charge disputes, lawsuits, escrow problems, extortion, money laundering, like all the things that even if you are the kind of payment Processor or bank who literally doesn't care about the content and all you care about is handling transactions for a fee It costs so much money to deal with that kind of nonsense that even if you think porn is fine as a business You're probably better off not allowing it so you don't have to deal with that space and all the problems that come up within it.
Scott: Yeah, well, I think also it's that you know, we see by you know, designating pornography even you know Legal consenting adult pornography as sort of like this special thing, right?
Scott: Yeah, you know, it's.
Scott: it's you have to go to a sex shop.
Scott: It's not just you know, you want to get a pornographic book.
Scott: It's not at.
Scott: you know Barnes and Noble borders doesn't exist anymore.
Scott: All right, you get it at the special shop I remember going to a Walden books.
Rym: You want to go you want to buy a book for a pseudo-girlfriend I had in like sixth grade because she was really into Danielle Steele and I went to buy it and the Walden books wouldn't Sell it to me because I was a sixth grader and they both share pornographic.
Scott: Right, but that wasn't poor.
Scott: but the point it was according to Walden books Whatever, but you can't buy a sex toy at Walmart.
Scott: For example, they don't sell dildos unless you're brave.
Scott: Sure depends what you want to use But you can't buy.
Scott: you know, it's like they just don't have those there.
Scott: and if that wasn't the case Right, if you just had porn as an accepted societal thing then porn would just be mixed in with other stuff.
Scott: You would write then it's like a payment processor isn't gonna cut off Walmart because there's a porn section at the Walmart.
Scott: But it's when there's an entire business and it's like the entire business is porn only Then it's very easy for the payment processor to cut it off.
Rym: Yep So I suspect in this case and again, we have no insider knowledge what OnlyFans was attempting to do this is just my personal guess is They started with porn They they ran into the problems I just described and eventually their payment processor was like look buddies enough is enough.
Rym: even pornhub follows these rules and rather than Continue to double down on trying to be in that space They tried to pivot to all the other kinds of things such a platform could do like Fitness instructors and tutoring and all that other stuff and just back away from the whole space.
Rym: Of course this led to a lot of backlash But also I don't know how much money there is in the rest of that.
Scott: Compared to it would be one thing if you if you intend, you know Put that up as your as your front and everybody knows wink wink The front and then the facade fell down and it's fitness instructors right in that facade now, right?
Scott: That's the wrong way to do it.
Scott: But I mean there is clearly I think it is a good core idea to have a somehow Some sort of site where people upload content and then people pay to access that content.
Scott: It's called patreon.
Rym: it exists Similarly had to deal with a lot of these issues back in 2017 and they're successfully navigated.
Rym: But as you note even to this day There's all that.
Rym: many of you we listen to GeekNights are probably aware of a lot of pornography on patreon But it's not easy to search for that patreon pornography via patreon for a reason.
Scott: Yeah, you know Twitter is supposedly gonna try to do their super follow, which is effectively the same thing which is like yeah, if you pay you to follow me, you'll see more tweets that only people who pay to follow me see.
Scott: and Twitter does have a lot of porn on it.
Scott: Twitter is mostly okay with as long as you know, it's within certain lines.
Scott: So we'll see how that goes.
Scott: So I
Rym: found an article on xbiz that see
Scott: and also Facebook speaking of which right a lot of people correctly pointed out Facebook basically has more child porn another garbage on it than like any of these other platforms
Rym: with a possible Exception when we get to the main bit that Apple might have had more at least for a maybe.
Scott: but the point is Nobody's either.
Scott: the payment processors weren't cutting off Facebook.
Scott: right payments for ads and such?
Rym: Yeah, well for ads but there were.
Rym: I get the impression there were things that happen behind the scenes in these other websites as well.
Rym: I what I did learn Mastercard, I actually found the rules They're listed on this website I'll link to.
Rym: that are at stake here for the MasterCard part of the payment processing lifecycle that are affecting only fans.
Rym: So it's only.
Rym: it's not that many bullet points.
Rym: It's pretty straightforward.
Rym: One that one section.
Rym: This is the section that applies to what they call tube sites.
Rym: So pornhub x-video only lands anything you like.
Rym: Yeah anything that's live streams or direct interaction and stuff like that One.
Rym: you must enter a written contractual agreement with any individual contributing content that includes their consent their identity and their age.
Rym: That seems reasonable.
Rym: all Depicted in the content must in themselves give independent verifiable consent For the content to be distributed and downloaded.
Scott: You know if I can't if I sign an agreement and get an account and suddenly I invite someone over to be in a video It's like whoa, we got to know who that is.
Rym: Yeah, never mind.
Rym: a big part of the problem in this space is non-consensual pornography Where someone surreptitiously films say an encounter with a one-night stand and then that is the porn they publish.
Rym: That is a huge growing problem.
Rym: Wrench porns all kinds only verified users can upload content.
Rym: the big one I think is all content must be reviewed prior to publication or Real time if it's live streams and no content can violate the Mastercard brand Bram policies.
Rym: I'll get to that in a minute.
Rym: I dug into what that is a little more business risk assessment and mitigation policies Which is mostly around Mastercard saying these are the things that you cannot let happen with your payments because they are literally illegal.
Rym: The website must have a complaint process for reporting and removing material.
Rym: They must have policies to make sure the website cannot be used for human trafficking effectively.
Rym: They must provide monthly reports of flag content and what was taken down and No search terms or marketing partners or anything in their ecosystem can give the illusion that child porn is there.
Rym: They can't hit at child porn.
Scott: if someone searches for child porn.
Scott: It's got to say zero results.
Scott: Sorry, bro.
Scott: And that if someone searches for like, you know hot teens, it's got to be like no.
Rym: So as best I can tell with the caveat that this is like a couple days of research.
Rym: Those are the rules that OnlyFans is unwilling or unable to comply with.
Scott: Well, then that's it.
Scott: I think the real-time moderation one might be the hardest one for them Which is definitely the most expensive because you need so like you just need to pay people to sit there and watch it all day And that's not a job.
Scott: That's so.
Rym: what are those brand policies on Mastercard?
Rym: Well, that's a lot more complicated, but it seems to come into having controls to prevent directly like explicitly illegal activity from being paid for like if I buy a hitman or illegal drugs or illegal tobacco Coerce transactions, which is a euphemism for Blackmail or like literally just going up to an ATM and forcing someone to buy something or take money bribes.
Rym: Yeah, child trafficking Cryptocurrencies are covered by that.
Rym: buying and selling cryptocurrencies is heavily restricted by Mastercard.
Rym: similarly for all the reasons you can expect illegal gambling and There's a slightly more nebulous class of what they call offensive adult pornography but as far as I can tell it mostly applies to Explicitly illegal pornography or pornography that doesn't comply with those other rules that we were talking about.
Scott: Yeah, they're not they're talk they're not talking about, you know, just somebody's, you know, freaky kink or you're talking about.
Scott: You know really stuff that you know is shouldn't be.
Rym: So this is a really complicated space and it is a little bit too much of a simplification To say that Mastercard is directly anti porn or trying to censor Though that there that is definitely a factor considering the history of this industry and this space and these.
Scott: well Just you know the law right requiring certain things and as part of the problem is that you know a lot of the laws that are you know, well-meaning in an attempt to prevent or hinder job child porn and also Other crimes like, you know extortion bribery Etc.
Scott: black male right that the laws are not, you know, very sharp and delicate instruments.
Scott: They are blunt hammer and cause.
Scott: you know They cause a great deal of collateral damage mostly to consensual adult sex workers.
Scott: Because we have all these things in place, you know, not just because of companies But also because of the laws that make those company do do things right.
Scott: As a result, it's like yeah We're not.
Scott: we're gonna try to stop these things and as a result the thing that we don't want to stop is also stops.
Rym: Yep, so it's not just conservative agitation.
Rym: There's a lot more going on here.
Rym: There's a lot of Self-interested I don't want to deal with the sector.
Rym: that is extremely dangerous to deal with based on it like real kind.
Scott: Oh, yeah, of course also capitalism right because in socialism you would just have You know government sex workers.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, no no that that gets into another dicey territory.
Rym: I think a better way to look at it is in a you know, truly socialist society that was constructed.
Rym: Well Nobody would be doing sex work unless they wanted to Exactly.
Rym: That's a better way to put it.
Rym: government sex workers gets into a far more terrifying consequence of poorly written laws and This is a. this is a an argument that would need to be addressed by better laws.
Rym: But imagine if sex work were completely legal and regulated Arguably under existing laws.
Rym: someone could be forced to do it if they found a job in that sector and we're currently collecting unemployment Or risk losing their unemployment.
Rym: That doesn't feel right.
Rym: Does it?
Scott: No, it doesn't.
Rym: Yep This is why this is such a complicated space.
Rym: So only fans really shit the bed and fucked up here because they as from everything I can tell they could have taken steps to comply with these rules and other sites like Pornhub have indeed Complyed with these steps and continue to take payments.
Rym: so only fans pivoted away from the demographic and the people that made them a success and I kind of hope they go out of business because they really should have had those people's back.
Rym: their platform only got to the scale it got to because of those people.
Rym: if you're Gonna if you're gonna go into that industry You'd better be there for the people you're working with.
Rym: at least the people who invested in it are gonna get burned Yep, because I don't think OnlyFans is gonna survive on people paying to get a hockey player to chat with them like an old Call the hotline to talk to Corey Haim thing from the 80s?
Scott: Yeah Pretty sure.
Scott: the hotline just talked to a recording, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah There has been at the phone that eat that I saw.
Rym: I watched a YouTube video a while ago talking about like that whole or like Preteen 900 number ecosystem from the 80s.
Rym: What a weird world that was the late 80s.
Rym: But there's a ton more here that we do not have time or expertise to get into.
Rym: but I'm gonna link to a whole bunch Resources if you want to learn more about that space.
Rym: and if you think to yourself Why don't I just make a website?
Rym: that does it right?
Rym: Good luck.
Rym: And if you think why don't I just make a payment processor and a bank?
Rym: I thought about that.
Rym: We were talking about that a lot.
Scott: Good luck.
Rym: in my Professional opinion it is possibly possible to do it without committing a felony and I Don't think I think of it like this, right?
Scott: There's this big, you know, there's this big field of lava, right?
Scott: And there's yes, you can cross this lava field.
Scott: There is clearly some stepping stones.
Rym: Few other people in metal boats like making their way around the lava.
Rym: They're out there, but there's not many touching.
Scott: touching the lava means federal prison Right.
Scott: and the other side is is you know what we want, right?
Scott: Which is you know consensual adult sex workers get paid as they deserve to be Right and can sexual adult customers are able to pay them as they you know, should right.
Scott: and yet to cross that Someone's got to cross the fire the lava with the stepping stones without touching the lava.
Scott: Someone else is doing it.
Scott: Not me.
Rym: I'm not touching the lava Ah, so before we go to the next news the list is not gonna risk it Oh, but also it's not just that.
Rym: even if you're looking to lava You see boats flipping over and sinking in the lava constantly big ones.
Scott: The only fans one is like on fire.
Rym: Yep, the Titanic has flipped over and is sinking on fire and you're sitting there and your little dinghy thinking I gotta get me some of that.
Scott: I'm gonna be the one who makes it across.
Scott: all these big guys didn't make it but I'm the one who's gonna make it.
Rym: Yep, so but possibly possible is what I would say, but the listener it just asked.
Rym: What about cryptocurrency one?
Rym: Cryptocurrency needs to be banned for a bunch of other reasons like so many reasons I can't get into but to The infrastructure bill that the US government is about to pass includes and this is a whole topic for another day Includes language that allows the federal government to regulate cryptocurrencies and guess what those regulations will will effectively do.
Rym: They'll require the same kinds of things that MasterCard is requiring of porn sites Verifying the identities verifying where the money came from and what is being used for all the things that all the other banks do Which literally remove all the quote good aspects unquote of cryptocurrency that libertarian shitbags like to talk about.
Scott: The failure of cryptocurrency to be used as a currency even if you forget about its environmental damage Even if you forget about all the other nonsense and whatnot, right is that it's not being used as a currency.
Scott: No one will accept it for anything.
Scott: You can't pay your rent with it.
Scott: You can't buy groceries with it.
Scott: So at some point it needs to be converted to dollars and at the point it could be converted to dollars.
Scott: The government can get you and in fact, they don't even need to get to that point.
Scott: They've seized plenty of bitcoins from plenty of people before they converted to dollars or after I know when it was still in Bitcoin form.
Scott: So it actually provides none and almost nobody Right is actually using any cryptocurrency in the dis in the purely distributed way that you know.
Scott: The one benefit of it is like oh, you know, you can just anonymously transfer it between point A and point B. Yeah, that's if you with your computer with your wallet on your computer Directly interact with the blockchain from your computer with no one.
Scott: in between 99.99% of cryptocurrency transactions people are using some cloud service middleman to hold their wallet for them and that's Effectively no different than using Chase Bank.
Scott: So that's how you're getting caught and no one does it the real way.
Scott: So they've just thrown out the Bennett who the one paper on paper, but not in reality benefit of cryptocurrency.
Scott: It's just all bullshit.
Scott: see our episode on cryptocurrency.
Rym: So in some other big news and this really escalated in the weeks while we were gone.
Rym: So I was I was only barely following.
Scott: I saw it escalating but it's continued to escalate.
Rym: So now we got to talk about yeah And and the one thing I'll say before we get into this is that I am shocked this did not happen sooner.
Scott: Like I don't know why this took so long to have.
Rym: I know it's kind of like way back when I was a kid.
Rym: I was like, why doesn't someone just make a virus that instead of fucking up your computer Just like steals money or spies on you or something.
Rym: Like why don't you buy this?
Rym: Why isn't someone making money with this?
Rym: Why are they just making viruses that they did eventually?
Rym: Yep so Effectively, there is a there is a culture in twitch which not to stray from the point and definitely not to blame the victims.
Rym: But I think this culture is a broken and toxic result of how twitch makes money in the first place.
Scott: I think this see our ancient talk about.
Scott: you know, the game makes the community In this case the user interface.
Scott: If you consider twitch to be a game right all the rules of twitch and the way the software works Causes the community that is on there in my understanding.
Rym: So So basically the the culture at stake here.
Rym: Is that on twitch?
Rym: People will raid other channels and by raid which is usually a positive thing.
Scott: It's like I'm done streaming There's still 20 there's still a bunch of people watching me.
Scott: right I will raid which you know Even though it's it's a negative term.
Scott: It sounds like a bad thing.
Scott: It's actually in twitch terms a good thing.
Scott: I will send them to this other person that I like and Even if they keep watching me, they'll just be sent to this other person.
Scott: They'll probably watch them for at least a little bit and if they like them, maybe they'll stay there, right?
Scott: But if not, then they'll go somewhere else on their own.
Scott: No one can force them to watch this other channel But it's still.
Scott: it's giving that other person like a boost of attention And you the most.
Scott: it's usually a very good thing when a very popular streamer Right will raid a very small channel.
Rym: Well, it's good.
Rym: like twitch users and content creators perceive it as being good.
Rym: But I've seen a lot of evidence that those audiences don't actually stick around.
Scott: they primarily But for the most part they don't stick around.
Scott: but you know You just get one or two people can be a bit, you know a big deal for somebody It can.
Rym: but a big part of rating too is people will do raid campaigns to help someone they like Get twitch partner verified or whatever like get their account above the line so they can model.
Scott: So you'll you'll often see a community of streamers that are all friends with each other and they basically raid each other in like a circle And that sort of merges their communities together.
Scott: Yeah So that like you get the same viewers will follow all of them and watch whoever is online at a given time and they'll stagger Their stream schedules and make like a little.
Scott: you know a little thing You know, so it's a good functionality.
Scott: the term raid isn't helpful, but you know.
Rym: Yep, so but the problem there is that someone's account will get just barely above the line.
Rym: They get partner status.
Rym: They feel like they made it but those people mostly don't stick around.
Rym: now weeks later Their account falls way below the line and they're making basically no money and they're not any better off.
Scott: Well, you know, I'm just saying it's a there's a there's a.
Rym: there is a just due to the sheer number of streams.
Rym: It's not a strictly zero-sum game, but an individual person can only watch so many minutes of twitch per day.
Rym: so there is a zero sum of how many eyeballs you can get on your twitch stream.
Rym: and For a lot of smaller creators the cert the raid ecosystem is a turn of the same people Through a set of channels and it doesn't make anything sustainable.
Scott: But that's not.
Scott: it is a key.
Scott: It is a cute.
Scott: It is a cute sometimes helpful feature.
Rym: Oh, yeah uses but I have long-term concerns about it.
Rym: but What started happening and it appears that this is the work of a very small number of people who have written bots and built Infrastructure to make this happen.
Rym: They've written code.
Rym: then it appears even that the primary person or the smaller people involved with it are joining people's channels and even doing things like warning them they're about to run the racism bot or Asking for feedback on the racism bot posting change logs on.
Rym: hey, this is version 2.1 of the bot.
Rym: I hope you enjoy it before the Nazi stuff starts coming out.
Rym: The bot will basically cause huge numbers of random automatically generated Twitter account or twitch accounts to join your channel and Just start spouting extremely racist nonsense Like since your content you can imagine
Scott: and since twitch puts moderation on the shoulders of the streamers and their moderators and not on Themselves
Rym: yet also gives them almost no tools to actually money
Scott: gives.
Scott: it gives them tools, but it gives them very weak tools.
Rym: Oh, those tools are unusable garbage.
Rym: I've actually been working on a spec and like what those tools we need to look like and it does give.
Scott: it does provide Apis to let people build better tools, which you usually would use.
Scott: but even those tools are weak sauce.
Scott: So in the absence of strong enough tools and the absence of twitch not doing anything on their own.
Scott: really You know if this happens to you, the only recourse you really have as a streamer right is You can just turn your stream chat into sub only mode.
Scott: because yeah, go ahead subscribe to me with all those boss five bucks each I'll take it.
Scott: It's like You know, you don't really have a lot of things you can do about it.
Scott: Or you could put your chat it's like slow mode I guess and then try to ban them one at a time.
Scott: That's really a pain in the ass.
Scott: You don't want to be doing that.
Scott: You want to be playing the video game You're playing right?
Scott: You don't be clicking.
Scott: ban on a hundreds and hundreds of chats in there.
Scott: I guess you could turn off chat completely.
Rym: I don't even know if that's an option on but again the raid culture and the culture of twitch is that No streamer wants to make their stream subs only they want it to be open to anyone.
Scott: So you'd only usually streamers like don't want.
Scott: yeah You don't want to be sub only because that's gonna be a turn-off for you know, people who just come across your channel.
Scott: They're not gonna want to stay if they can't chat anything.
Scott: They're just stuck watching you.
Scott: I guess watching you isn't entertaining enough.
Scott: for some reason They need to.
Scott: they need to spam emojis to feel like they belong like.
Rym: that is such a part of that culture that I Understand it, but I all but I don't enjoy it.
Rym: I like.
Rym: obviously I'm old I don't care anymore, but also That culture is start is.
Rym: I don't want to blame the victims here But the culture of how twitch is used is making this problem worse rather than better.
Scott: Yeah, it's like the only time I ever chat on twitch is If you know what
Rym: if it's a small stream and I'm like chatting with like a small
Scott: small stream And I'm legitimately talking to the person who's streaming, you know, like I actually have something to say to them.
Rym: Well, like what are we doing?
Rym: the live stream on gig now?
Rym: It's like I'm usually chatting and text in the live chat while we're doing the show.
Scott: Scott can't even see that right but if our chat if we were super popular and our chat became a stream of emojis that was just provided that would I mean I Would just turn it off at that point was devoid of content.
Scott: Well, we might as well just turn it off then it doesn't.
Scott: It's doing nothing.
Scott: Yeah Right, so it's like I don't know.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: But yeah, the twitch chat itself is separate from this raid bot problem.
Scott: Yep, but the raid bot problem has been going on and it's mostly Targeting.
Scott: right Yes, yes, but also LGBTQ people right they're going after Targeting white dude.
Rym: No, they're going after us to say that primarily and almost exclusively Underrepresented and oppressed minorities.
Scott: Yeah and and posting, you know insult, you know slurs right in there in their bots, right.
Scott: so The question is a right Twitch?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like what the hell are you doing about this?
Scott: Why is it so easy to make a twitch account that you can just make a zillion of them once someone does this?
Scott: It should be really easy to identify.
Scott: Shouldn't all of those accounts just be perma banned Right instantly?
Rym: if I someone is of twitch and if someone is programmatically creating so many new accounts as they get banned?
Scott: Yeah, there's like, you know, it's quit.
Scott: and Twitter if you try to do API stuff It's like you have an API key.
Scott: They just turn your key off.
Scott: great.
Scott: You can't make any more API commands.
Scott: Yeah, and all right.
Rym: What else you gonna do like The one it's twitch needs to take an extreme action And instead they're making the slowest most miltoast actions possible.
Scott: Like if I and twitch has the resources of Amazon.
Rym: Yeah if I were the product manager for twitch like overall like the head of product the first thing I would do is literally Ban like I would halt for a couple weeks all new account creation.
Rym: May have a team dedicated to banning all the accounts that are doing this big forensic analysis Like I like I would treat this as an existential crisis for the company.
Rym: Yeah, which is saying like oh, well, we have tools.
Rym: We're gonna make more tools.
Rym: Those tools do not work at all.
Rym: We don't have time to get into all the examples if you want to see the one.
Scott: just one example, right?
Scott: There are many many many examples, but the one example in a tweet I saw going.
Rym: I know which one you're about to talk about.
Rym: I think I have it.
Scott: Someone was like, hey, what if I post the word?
Scott: I want to post the word jogger, right?
Scott: Obviously they were referencing another word that has two G's in it, right?
Scott: But like hey, what if I want to post the word jogger in somebody's chat?
Scott: It's like well, okay.
Scott: So they go in and they type in their block list the word joggers that it cannot.
Scott: so anyone who types It is automatically that that message is automatically blocked, right?
Scott: Okay So but the problem is is you can type any Unicode character you want into twitch and there's several Characters in Unicode that look like J several that look like Oh several that look like G Several that look like E and several that look like are right in Cyrillic and several other alphabets that are available in the Unicode character Space.
Scott: so the actual number of ways you could type the word jogger that would be recognizable in English right to an English speaker is many many many many and You can't type them all in right.
Scott: and twitch doesn't automatically block all the variations To block all of them.
Scott: You would have to do it with an automated, you know API calls right to your own twitch account to add all the variations of just one word.
Scott: and that would take you Even if you did all that and wrote the code to do it or someone provided a tool to do it with a limit on API calls that you can make to twitch would take you like several several many days Just to add one word to your block list if you wanted to block all
Rym: possible.
Scott: Yeah visual variations of it.
Rym: now Look at twitch.
Rym: How do you solve this one?
Rym: Really simplistic machine learning models can handle that like an exit.
Scott: We already have For decades.
Scott: It's called a spam filter.
Scott: We use it on email.
Scott: Yeah, right if somebody just
Rym: apply
Scott: a basic email spam filter technology to twitch chats Right if the kinds of twitch chats that are getting blocked consider that mark as spam and if you see an account that is Getting a lot of their chats marked as spam Automatically ban it
Rym: from.
Rym: so this gets back to that that original conversation.
Rym: because the twitch culture likes an extremely spammy chat and likes raids.
Rym: The the fact that the creators are unwilling to entertain solutions that end either of those things, right?
Scott: It's like you could just make for example, you could make all of twitch just all of twitch no chat No chat.
Scott: Why is chat have to be a thing?
Scott: I'm just streaming.
Scott: Why do I have to have a chat if I don't want to let people run their own discord or their own chat or something?
Scott: That's a people on twitch would not like that.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Well, you could make all chats sub only by default.
Scott: Well, that should actually encourage people to pay because you every chat is just always sub only all the time.
Scott: There is no public chat.
Scott: It's sub only chat.
Scott: You want to talk to me pay five bucks or use your prime sub right for the month.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: Streamers don't like that either because even though that might get some people more people to sub It would really hurt their engagement with people who have not subbed yet and getting them to sub right because they can't chat.
Rym: Yeah, but a lot of marginalized creators reach an audience of other marginalized people who couldn't afford.
Rym: you don't have $5.
Rym: Yeah, exactly.
Rym: So they don't want.
Rym: it's kind of like with the problems with Twitter.
Rym: as I always said the only ways To stop the mass abuse that happens on Twitter in an open platform.
Rym: There's really only two fundamental ways you can go.
Rym: you either make some sort of cost However small to create an account You.
Rym: well, I guess there's three ways you have a verifiable identity required to create an account or you accept verifiable identities.
Scott: Actually don't you know, they make it so that you can.
Scott: they make it easier to block someone right because you've have But they don't prevent the behavior There's.
Scott: there have been a studies that show that like yeah, most of the people on Twitter saying awful things Just have their real identities right there.
Rym: Because if we're willing to actually follow through and like go after those people with on available bands But they're not.
Rym: the third way to go is to do what we did with email.
Rym: They all and I say this a lot because younger people do not appreciate this.
Rym: The only reason email exists today and works at all is because as a society we collectively agreed that 99.99999% of all emails are vile spam and we're willing to let Lots of legitimate emails get blocked rather than see a single spam.
Scott: Yeah The email system is like you could.
Scott: no one can stop you from making an email server and just start sending emails to other email Servers, you know, there's absolutely nothing in the world that can stop you.
Rym: But what?
Rym: no one?
Rym: all your emails if you do that at all because no one will none you.
Scott: Yep, no one will get your emails right there neat.
Scott: You need to pass a rigorous sort of thing before any other email server will say, okay I will allow you to email but if twitch was like you must pass a very rigorous trial before we will allow a streamer to See your chats.
Scott: No one would pass that trial.
Scott: They want to get users So they had to lower their barrier to entry.
Scott: right.
Scott: that fundamental conflict is.
Scott: what's belying our entire all of our social networks Is that the networks want to lower the barrier to entry to get more users, but lowering the barrier to entry let's in shit
Rym: yep, and I think with twitch in particular There are no good ways to deal with this without harming some aspect of the twitch community Culture and interaction space that people enjoy though.
Scott: Well not harming.
Rym: not harming by some definitions way that drastically Drastically altered in a way that a huge percentage of twitch users would dislike.
Scott: and yeah, probably.
Rym: but I think the Avenue of least pain and harm would be for twitch to provide one provide actual effective moderation tools which all platforms are avoiding like something so simple as building block chains and shared block lists into the platform directly.
Scott: Twitter Blockchain like Bitcoin blockchain as like everyone that I've everyone that I've blocked and everyone that you've blocked are now blocked on both of us.
Rym: automatically then marginalized creators could band together and share a gigantic block list that would automatically update and Honestly solve a huge percentage of this problem that Twitter.
Scott: But why do they even have to do that?
Scott: The moderation should come from the platform itself.
Rym: No Band that.
Scott: if someone's banned from all these channels, why aren't they just banned from all of twitch forever?
Scott: Yeah, right It's if the hundred people block some shithead on Twitter.
Scott: Why is their Twitter account still allowed to continue existing up?
Rym: Why are Republican politicians who say literal lies about kovat still allowed to tweet like it's the same exactly?
Scott: The platform is should be responsible for the mud not you know.
Scott: The user shouldn't have to sit there right there and moderate and to do all this stuff.
Scott: It's you know, it's not their job.
Scott: they're there to watch streams or to stream.
Scott: They shouldn't have to be responsible for keeping racists and bots out of their chat.
Scott: Why is that their job?
Rym: yep, so twitch bears 100% of the blame for allowing this to happen because There are simple things twitch could have done or could still do that would not solve this but would have drastically Reduce this or even prevented the scale that is now occurring.
Rym: This is only gonna get worse and I have no confidence that twitch is gonna do anything Substantial to address it in the first anyway future.
Scott: But anyway on September 1st The all of these people who are you know, not happy about twitch not doing anything about this, you know racist raid problem Yeah are going to basically do a one-day twitch, you know One day twitch, I guess boycott right?
Scott: No streaming.
Scott: Yeah, no watching twitch.
Scott: don't cross the picket line Alright, so in September 1st, don't go to twitch.com.
Scott: Don't do any twitch anything.
Scott: Don't even watch like a VOD Right don't watch a clip.
Scott: don't do anything on September 1st.
Scott: No twitch streaming or watching whatsoever things Of the day.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: So you go to the hardware store, right and such a simple thing You see like a big old piece of plywood right like a big flat piece of wood Right and every time in my life.
Scott: I saw such a piece of wood You know, I thought to myself for a second like man That obviously didn't come from a tree.
Rym: That was eight feet wide Right Where pieces of wood that big did in fact come?
Rym: from?
Rym: a tree that pig.
Scott: Sure, that time is not now.
Scott: Nope And you know, how did that?
Scott: how did that piece of wood come to be right?
Scott: Was it you know a particle board?
Scott: I understand right?
Scott: You can just get like wood chips and like compress them together.
Scott: You know with glue or something right up a particle board sucks.
Scott: It sucks ass but plywood doesn't suck is right And it's just sort of like.
Scott: hey, how did that fuck?
Scott: did they make that right?
Scott: What you know what was going on at the lumber mill that produced that eight feet wide piece of wood?
Scott: well Finally somehow I remembered to google that And on YouTube I found a video and the answer to the question of hey How did just some fucking logs that are about the size of like telephone poles end up as you know?
Scott: Ultra wide pieces of wood?
Scott: the answer is about at the three-minute mark a very ingenious device.
Scott: That was so simple and so obvious.
Scott: Why did I not just think of imagine that on my own?
Scott: but no at the three around the three-minute mark?
Scott: I saw the machine and I said, oh, that's how they fucking do it.
Scott: God damn it.
Scott: Yeah Why did I think of that?
Rym: So I find as I older I increasingly enjoy learning how very simple things that you don't think about are done.
Scott: Yeah, but also this video shows everything from literal tree with bark on it up to delivering.
Rym: Oh, yeah barkers like the first part of the video.
Scott: Yeah, it shows you everything from tree all the way to piece of wood that's on its way to the hardware store already packaged.
Scott: so it's pretty fascinating.
Scott: all the other steps and Things that go on in the the lumber mill of you know, a modern lumber mill.
Scott: so Check it out.
Rym: So check this out.
Rym: This is if this were something that was for sale It's it's in the same category as that the game and watch that you got the Nintendo one.
Rym: if this was for sale I would just buy it.
Rym: Supposedly instructions for making one are coming soon from the creator and I think I'm gonna make one.
Rym: It's this tiny little TV and it is 3d printed to look exactly like the TV from The Simpsons the original one.
Rym: Okay, it's got two little.
Rym: and then what?
Scott: you take a little LCD screen and stick it in there.
Rym: So It has a tiny little computer in it a 640 bar for a Raspberry Pi a Raspberry Pi.
Rym: Yeah It has d card on it And basically it has of one of the dot the knob on the bottom with the volume slider.
Rym: It has the speaker in it and the knob on the top.
Rym: if you turn it on It'll start playing a random Simpsons episode from the first 11 seasons and if you try it could be it could play anything.
Scott: But they chose to put the first 11.
Rym: Oh, yes, but I'm saying they The the.
Rym: what I like about this device is this is the exact kind of neat social currency Slash desk toy that I love.
Rym: it's like an advanced form of that game and watch just flick the little switch and a tiny TV Is just playing a random episode from the good run of The Simpsons.
Scott: turn it off.
Scott: Nothing stops you from putting in any essay later in there or anything else that you know.
Rym: But I like the idea that it just plays The Simpsons and I really love the fact that when this when this person made it They literally just compressed 11 seasons of The Simpsons and just stuck them on there.
Rym: And that's the only.
Scott: don't really have to compress them.
Scott: You could just put full-on, you know, mp4 H.264 videos in 1080p.
Rym: Well, they fit they have they fit 11.
Rym: So 11 seasons times the number of episodes a season of Roughly 640 by 480 video though.
Scott: It's probably I feel like you could fit the entire run of The Simpsons Just everything on a micro SD card.
Scott: Oh probably but I guess since you're since it's an art piece You probably only want the 4 by 3, you know episodes.
Scott: You don't want the 16 by 9 one.
Rym: and also because there's an art piece.
Rym: You probably only want the first 11 seasons.
Scott: Let's be clear about that As your screen is also probably not 16 by 9, you know what I would say, I think it's neat Good idea in the meta moment.
Rym: We will not be at PAX West 2021. in case you were wondering I feel like we have to announce that a few times because Most of the people who see us at cons don't bother going to our website and seem to watch our YouTube channel more than listen To the podcast itself, but we will not be there.
Rym: It is too soon for me to cram myself into a building with tens of thousands of nerds indoors.
Rym: So we're not gonna be the first packs in the u.s.
Rym: We've skipped since our first packs in 2008.
Rym: It's weird that there will be a packs that I am NOT at.
Rym: I even went to the first two PAX Australia's.
Scott: So that's right Cuz even if I went and you know the even if I was you know We're willing to take the risk of getting a horrible disease, which I'm not Or giving it to someone else, which I'm not.
Scott: It feels like because of the horrible disease the packs itself will be greatly diminished and not worth paying the money to fly across the entire country to go to.
Scott: so if I lived in Seattle, there might be some amount of consideration.
Scott: probably still wouldn't go but Chances of going would be higher.
Rym: Yep, so we will not be there.
Rym: our panel from the last PAX East online Can't packs Atari game design.
Rym: It's just on YouTube.
Rym: You can just watch it slides everything.
Rym: It's all there.
Rym: We're still reading the tale of Genji powered red.
Scott: I read a bunch of the beach.
Rym: Yeah, I think by the end of September we can do this show October at the latest.
Scott: You said August last?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, then the end of August is in a week.
Rym: Yep Well, I'll be I'll be more.
Rym: I'll be past the halfway point in the next week at the rate.
Rym: I'm going.
Rym: but Some notes, you know, cuz I've said the same thing about the book a few times along the way.
Rym: So to be a little more specific There were more ghost murders than I expected in the tale of Genji.
Scott: ghosts It's also.
Scott: there's also, you know more Hamlet style goes coming to talk.
Rym: Yep, ghosts played more of a factor than I expected from the tale of Genji and I'm here for that.
Rym: I also Did not expect on a modern reading like again.
Rym: as you get further into the book and you think back to Who's sick when and what they complain about being sick with it's clear that half the characters in this fucking book literally have malaria Mmm, like specifically malaria or
Scott: be just be well, yeah, I mean there are people who have malaria, but there's also Just because it's such an old time before modern medicine people are sick a lot.
Scott: So it's true to you know, it's true to life in that sense.
Rym: So we'll get right into it.
Rym: We're gonna talk about the Apple thing.
Rym: that has honestly.
Rym: interestingly I have a very mixed and ambivalent opinion on this.
Rym: but the people in technology spaces that I know professionally or that I follow drastically out Like I know some I know of some.
Rym: these are some people I know and I've talked to about this and they're also People I just follow because I respect like Lawrence Lessig.
Rym: I respect like there's people I respect Yeah, they're.
Rym: all of them are pretty much 50/50 on this issue.
Rym: half of them are Demanding that Apple not do this extremely afraid of the negative consequences and the other half of them are basically arguing It's not really that much different from what everyone else is doing and we don't really care that much.
Rym: So This is authority issue.
Scott: I'm pretty much seeing only outrage from everyone except me.
Rym: I've seen a number of privacy advocates argue that it's not a big deal Mostly citing the fact that pretty much every other platform already does this.
Scott: So let's explain what's going on.
Scott: Yeah, so first of all, so what Apple is doing is they're doing three things, right?
Scott: The second and I'm gonna do them in a different date they explain them in this page on their website Apple comm slash child - safety and I'll talk about the two not so exciting ones first and then the big deal one last even though on the website the big deal.
Scott: So the first one is there.
Scott: it's called Apple calls it communication safety in messages And basically what it is is if you are a child and you have an iPhone that's hooked up to your parents iPhone But the parental protections and everything in which case your parents can already just unlock your phone and see everything is going on in There anyway, right?
Scott: Your entire Apple stuff is beholden to your parents.
Scott: if that is the case So It's not really a change from that.
Scott: But what the system they have added does is it allows the parents to you know?
Scott: Enable a thing where it'll be enabled by default and I guess you could disable it if you really want to but basically use machine Learning to see if the child has received or sent a photo that very likely has nakedness in it.
Scott: Right which?
Scott: and if a child is getting it is either a child looking at porn They shouldn't be or a child sending child porn of themselves usually, right?
Scott: Yeah, which shouldn't be and all it does is it will blur it to.
Scott: you know Make it so the child can't doesn't see it immediately.
Scott: So someone sends a dick pic to your kid.
Scott: They don't just immediately see the dick or your dick pic to someone.
Scott: They know they'll get a blurry image and like a warning like are you sure you want to see this?
Scott: Which I think is a feature that you just enable for everybody like hey, someone sent you a photo.
Scott: That's probably a dick.
Scott: Are you sure you want to see it?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: No, why is that for kids only?
Scott: That's just me.
Scott: for everybody if they want to enable that that should be enabled by default.
Scott: Regardless, it'll tell the parent like hey your kid You know got a message that might be naked.
Scott: Letting you know right and I don't really see the problem.
Scott: I don't see this as a problem It's just a helpful thing.
Scott: That's not any different because parents already effectively have complete control of their children's phones.
Scott: that they're paying that the adults are paying for.
Rym: So one avenue.
Rym: I see that these the chatter I saw on that was primarily around young under 18 still under their parents control children who have conservative religious parents who don't approve of their sexuality or lifestyle.
Rym: and Yep, this was one of the few truly encrypted avenues they would have to communicate with people.
Scott: Well a as I said that I completely agree with what you just said.
Scott: But the parents already had complete control of the phones because that their kids phone is not the parent It's the parents phone that the kid is using.
Scott: with the parental controls The parents could already just I assume just unlock the kids phone and see whatever.
Rym: I think in that case we need to.
Rym: we need more of the old awareness Awareness campaigns that used to happen in the 90s among nerds Around how to do encryption when you don't trust the devices and how to do encryption.
Rym: Yes, now that is difficult and that will require some work.
Rym: like you can almost make a nonprofit around teaching Especially marginalized kids how to use encryption that is platform agnostic.
Rym: So I think there are effective ways around that for kids who need it, right?
Scott: But also Apple has informed everyone of this.
Scott: This isn't a secret.
Scott: So there I don't know if a kid is in that situation and afraid of their parents finding out their Sexuality because their parents are pieces of shit.
Scott: You're just not going to be sending any of that stuff on your iMessage now.
Scott: You'll find another way to send it if you're gonna send it at all.
Scott: Because you know about this.
Scott: Apple told you that it's there.
Scott: It's not like surprise.
Scott: We told you we told your parents that you're gay.
Scott: It's you know.
Scott: so It could be.
Scott: it could cause a problem for somebody.
Scott: I guess it was unaware or something But I don't.
Scott: I'm not too worried about that You know given that everyone knows.
Scott: they just announced it to the world.
Scott: All right, the second thing Really?
Scott: Not a big deal at all barely even worth mentioning.
Scott: is that if you go to Siri or search on your phone?
Scott: If you try to search for see Sam, which I guess is the new term for instead of saying child porn You're supposed to say see Sam.
Rym: So it's the child sexual abuse material.
Rym: It usually refers to Databases.
Rym: governments maintain there's a the whole this to get a whole thing on this.
Rym: but basically law enforcement agencies maintain Databases of all the child porn that's ever been uncovered Partly to help study it to identify victims to find victims who have not been helped yet like traffic kids and Also to be able to identify it when someone else is found to be distributing it.
Scott: There's a lot of reasons why these databases exist Sure, but child sexual abuse material is just like the phrase that you know, they're using instead of saying out for it.
Scott: So there are databases that because I guess they like that term better because it's more specific, right?
Scott: It's.
Rym: but it's also more generic and that it covers all the different Ways like all the kinds of material that could be abusive in this manner Sure, but anyway if you try to search for a child sexual abuse material On your iPhone or as Siri about it, right?
Scott: It is now going to give you better help in in those regards.
Scott: So that's I guess only positive, right?
Scott: So the big thing that Apple's doing right is the see Sam detection.
Scott: So first of all, let's talk about how it works.
Scott: The way it works is this you have some photos on your phone And not only do you have photos on your phone?
Scott: You have enabled iCloud photo.
Scott: You're not right.
Scott: So that's probably by default on most iPhones, but you could disable it if you wanted to but you have iCloud photo enabled.
Scott: What they're gonna do is on your phone.
Scott: It's going to take hashes of all your photos.
Scott: It's not going to share your photos with Apple.
Scott: No one will see the picture of your birthday cake, right?
Scott: They're just gonna see a number and they'll have.
Scott: no I there'll be no mathematical way to figure out what fucking photo that number came from.
Scott: just like no way.
Scott: it's impossible mathematically impossible, but They have a database of child porn, right?
Scott: Because the government has it and what they'll do is they'll see huh?
Scott: Did any of the numbers on any of your photos match any of this?
Scott: see Sam, right?
Scott: That's not so try not to say child porn now because they told me not to right.
Scott: We have these numbers from photos of see Sam and we have the numbers from your photos.
Scott: if there's any matches It is mathematically Extremely likely that you have that shit on your phone.
Scott: It would be almost impossible For you to have a photo.
Scott: not absolutely impossible But almost impossible for you to have a photo on your phone and have the hash produced from that photo match.
Scott: One of the hash is in that database.
Scott: Right and even if there is some kind of match, right?
Scott: They've set up this whole system to where like yeah Apple's computers are doing this part.
Scott: someone else's computers are doing this part.
Scott: humans are looking at this part Right.
Scott: for it to actually reach the point at which you're in trouble because of this It would have to be like, you know almost guaranteed that like yeah, you got that shit on your phone.
Scott: what's wrong with you?
Scott: So I'm really confident there aren't gonna be false positives.
Scott: So what are people worried about?
Scott: Well, people are worried not at This technology here itself, right?
Scott: What's actually happening?
Scott: They are worried about these slippery slope, right?
Scott: Cuz once this system is in place For example just to make something up Apple could take an image of I don't know
Rym: leaked Apple product design, let's say
Scott: Sure, right an iPhone 13 and then they could be like well now, you know We add the hash we add that number of this photo of the iPhone 15 to our database and if anyone out there has a photo of an iPhone 15 on their iPhone Well, we know that they're a leaker, right?
Scott: They could add, you know, they could apply this to things besides photos.
Scott: Right because it's happening locally on your phone where decrypted things could be.
Scott: So your decrypted iMessages right.
Scott: Apple doesn't see your iMessages when they're in transit but if they could look at your iMessages and They could be like, yeah, what's the hash of the message that says, you know I hate the president right event?
Scott: or if anyone has a text message as I hate the president, right?
Scott: They could detect that specifically right without you know, because they've got.
Scott: they don't have the messages.
Scott: They're not seeing your messages but they have hash representations of all your messages so they can sort.
Rym: what they can do is they can just Take messages and search for them specifically take a new message generate the hash for that message and see if anyone sent that message.
Scott: Yeah, did anyone say this?
Scott: Oh, we caught you, right?
Rym: So well, so this actually gets a little bit worse in in the US in particular And I've seen a few security researchers make this point about the US federal government and gag orders national security letters.
Rym: the US government could in theory and Has done this in the past with other platforms and technologies say I have a technology platform with end-to-end encryption and I do not have a Mechanism to decrypt that information like built-in.
Rym: the government cannot force me to build new technology Like.
Rym: that is not something they can do with an NSA letter or an NSA.
Rym: They can't be like you are hereby order to build this technology for us like that That they would have to make a government contract to do that.
Rym: Why?
Scott: Pay it do and you have to agree to do it.
Rym: But if Apple?
Rym: if it is no now that Apple has this specific capability It is eminently plausible.
Rym: the US federal government could issue a national security letter with a gag order to Apple saying add these hashes to Your list and inform us if anything hits.
Rym: we will not tell you what the hashes are for and you under penalty of law Cannot inform anyone that you have added these hashes, right?
Scott: They could fight it in court.
Rym: But oh, they can fight that in a secretly a special secret court.
Scott: Yes, guess what?
Scott: probably are there?
Scott: probably are many such fights happening in secret courts all the time that we don't know anything about.
Rym: guess What you know.
Rym: why you don't find out about those.
Scott: Nobody ever wins their cases because they're all you wouldn't find out even if they did win because it happened in secret court.
Rym: Yep, but the specific danger is that by having the capability they've opened themselves up to the government issuing a directive like that in a Way that if they don't have the capability the government can't force them to build it.
Rym: That seems to be Primary Concern among the people I see who are the maddest about this.
Scott: Sure, it is a true.
Scott: That is a true concern.
Scott: Yes So but yeah, that is pretty much like the only concern, right?
Scott: It's like if Apple you know, cuz it's really a slippery slope thing, right?
Scott: It's like you're building this system But all of the negatives that everyone comes up with whether they're plausible ones like the one you just said right or any others They're all ifs.
Scott: it's like every single negative that anyone has come up with.
Rym: that's true.
Rym: But is it is a?
Scott: is a?
Scott: this negative could happen?
Rym: There's one important danger of the other thing I brought up though in that There's no way to ever know if the if have.
Scott: there is no way to know.
Rym: that is We could find out if they happen.
Rym: That's the one.
Scott: if there's literally no way to know There's also no evidence that the thing did happen.
Rym: But again there but there is evidence that the thing has happened on every other platform.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: so you think in that it did not have capabilities like this.
Scott: It's Apple does, you know, right and that is a good point in Apple's favor right.
Scott: Apple has always Said hey, look, we're not here.
Scott: You know, we're the most privacy conscious of all your options, right?
Scott: We're here to sell you the product for a large amount of money.
Scott: You aren't the product right.
Scott: the prod, you know, like you are with all those people who give you stuff for free like Google.
Scott: Right, it's like everyone else is already doing this.
Scott: Right, if they some of them might be telling you they do it Some of them might not be telling you they do it.
Scott: Some of them might be doing it way worse than like Google doesn't we know?
Rym: Google does it?
Rym: they publish information about?
Rym: Statistics of like things how many things they take down and how many violations?
Rym: Looks like Google in the Latin.
Rym: in 2020 Google disabled almost a hundred thousand accounts because CSAM material was identified mm-hmm, so 210,000 URLs were de-indexed because they included CSAM material.
Rym: I think the difference is.
Rym: the difference is and again I have not audited the specifics of how every different company implements this stuff.
Rym: The difference is that all these other platforms are Inspecting unencrypted content that they have access to.
Rym: is that a store that they have encrypted on behalf of a user?
Rym: This is the first time an end-to-end encrypted thing itself is Inspecting Personal content not shared content and not content.
Scott: I don't think the iCloud photos are truly end-to-end encrypted.
Scott: the way I message or like, you know in such is I'm not actually a hundred percent sure myself because I don't have an app.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's just You know, I don't think it's.
Scott: it's fully end-to-end encrypted.
Scott: there's a point at which Apple can see your your photos.
Rym: So there's a fascinating article on the Washington Post that I did.
Rym: it was it was published today.
Rym: Oh No, it's published a couple days ago.
Rym: I just saw it today.
Rym: but it's some researchers who built a very similar system to do almost the exact same thing and Effectively.
Rym: how they canceled it because it was.
Rym: they decided it was too dangerous based on what they discovered.
Rym: building such a platform Too easily abused you get I'm gonna leave easily abused.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yep, because like I said, I have a complex and Somewhat ambivalent opinion on this in that on one hand I would argue that if you truly truly care about Powerful end-to-end encryption where you need to protect yourself from state-sponsored actors which includes the US government because the US government is the primary entity that could issue a Security letter and leverage this technology from al-fizan's you need to be doing what we talked about the beginning of the show and have Actual end-to-end encryption that is platform agnostic that you yourself are managing using their own technology,
Scott: right?
Scott: You should be using your own platforms Like right your own hardware your own software.
Scott: if you're using anything Right run by some other provider at all Even if they're promising or verifying, you know giving you some sort of encryption like iMessages.
Scott: It's like you can't bet.
Scott: you can't trust that.
Scott: Right, if you really need the privacy run your own Linux server in your house.
Scott: get make your own phone Get some entropy like from your local environment.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know use Wi-Fi only you can't be going over Verizon t-mobile or anything like that Right.
Scott: It's like you can't?
Scott: it's just you know, it's just how it is.
Scott: As soon as you use someone else's service, that's it.
Scott: You gave them everything the end.
Scott: So That's one thing.
Scott: The second thing is Apple's getting a ton of flack for this which is partially because a They've decided to tell everyone not only that they're doing it But all the details of how they're doing it and because of their privacy conscious, you know message they've had for so long.
Scott: It's a bigger contradiction I think the latter Google to do it.
Scott: the latter is a bigger key because but if you look at what they're doing They're sticking to their privacy conscious, you know ideas and they're doing it in a better More privacy sensitive way than anyone else is doing it.
Rym: They are Except for.
Rym: obviously the only concern I have is the avenue where the government could force them secretly to leverage this technology.
Scott: But already it's been that way for Google Dropbox Microsoft Facebook.
Scott: That's already been that way for all of them who already have had these systems up.
Scott: Yeah in a far worse implementation.
Rym: What it means for me as a just like a person using technology is that This platform is now the same as all of those platforms.
Rym: It is not different or special.
Scott: It is not different.
Scott: It is slightly.
Scott: it is still Better.
Scott: it is not, you know, it is still Not private.
Scott: So but it is better than the other option.
Rym: What's also interesting is that Apple a gap between them has decreased.
Rym: Apple has been doing this for iCloud mail Since 2019.
Rym: Yep, no one cared because all the platforms that do this primarily are doing it on communication and Like storage but like storage that's shared or unencrypted.
Rym: I guess they're like.
Rym: this case is a slightly different twist because of Apple's Privacy message as you described.
Rym: that message cause the dissonance.
Scott: No Apple has also simply just told everyone.
Scott: Hey, if you just disable iCloud photo, which is a single button press and just keep your photos on your phone only This won't happen to you.
Scott: So there's they given you a way around it.
Scott: They just told you how to undo it.
Rym: I would do things I would personally Yeah, like I might switch to Apple when the next iPhones come out if the the error of the small phone But he just died.
Rym: I might just be fucked.
Scott: So we'll find out.
Rym: we're gonna find out.
Rym: I uh, I was salivating over that Supposedly leaked iPod or iPhone nano that they never made.
Scott: Yeah, never made.
Rym: back in the days of like in the tin 2010 I mean my iPod was still one of the best pieces of technology I ever owned in my life.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much if they made an iPhone nano like I would pay thousands of dollars for an iPhone I would have bought if they had made it in 2011.
Scott: I would have bought it and stuck with it forever if they made one today.
Rym: I would pay laptop prices in 2011.
Scott: I want I was specifically said I wanted an iPhone nano in 2010 2011.
Scott: They never made it.
Rym: But and if my threat because remember though They're only the avenue that I personally have the most concern about is the national security letter thing.
Rym: If the threat you are trying to protect yourself against is the US government You have got to you've got to use platform agnostic encryption.
Rym: Anyway, yeah there are iPhone.
Rym: I'm not fussed about this and this will not factor into my decision to use or not use Apple products.
Scott: Yeah as a more general point right is that almost as I said almost all the concerns Right are slippery slope concerns, right?
Scott: They're saying You know because the system as it is if we take Apple's word for it and we assume that there is or have not been Any national security letters adding other things to this?
Scott: Right if we just look at what it is and assume that we will not go over the slope in good faith, right?
Scott: We're not going down the slope.
Scott: This is only a positive thing.
Scott: This is gonna stop shit tons of CSAM.
Scott: Yeah, it's gonna catch all sorts of child predators.
Scott: This is a huge benefit.
Scott: No, it's like no one's focusing on that at all Right.
Scott: It's like if you don't go down the slippery slope, this is great.
Rym: However, the same argument is made by people who say we should abolish and end encryption Absolutely and require that's like.
Scott: there is a huge difference between that and this.
Scott: and the huge difference Is that if you abolish end-to-end encryption, right you were actually creating a Security problem, right?
Rym: Yeah, but you don't y'all to see for him.
Scott: Well, but you would also cause lots and lots of collateral damage.
Scott: That wouldn't be a slippery slope.
Scott: It would be a reality right of where.
Scott: yeah, if there's no end-to-end encryption, then that means I can't make a bank transaction Safely, right?
Scott: It's like you.
Scott: it's like already a built-in consequence here.
Scott: It's like they don't have to add more hashes.
Rym: So I did see one other.
Scott: It's not again.
Scott: It's not a guaranteed thing that any collateral damage will happen.
Rym: I found a story about a crypto audit project and a number of researchers pointed out that they were testing that had the neural hash Mechanism that Apple's using and they found lots of collisions very quickly.
Scott: Well, what they were doing was intentionally.
Scott: I looked at some of that.
Rym: Yeah some Definitely.
Rym: There's a lot of caveats on.
Rym: they were somewhat synthetic examples.
Scott: Well, not only that I saw someone who's like hey All of these images will make a hash collision.
Scott: a hundred percent of those images were Clearly like.
Scott: I didn't actually click through to the site because I had guessed what they were doing, but I saw a thumbnail of the site they had taken see Sam imagery and Just modified it to like make it blurry or whatever and it's like yeah Glad I didn't click through to you, but
Rym: also those are the collisions that you that would be a feature of the platform.
Scott: Exactly the point I you know, just like the more general point, right?
Scott: Is it not only with this but with a lot of things in our in technologically in the world?
Scott: There are slippery slopes that like yeah if you build, you know And I think we get this a lot because we've seen so many Twilight Zone episodes We've seen slippery slopes just ramp down to the bottom instantly.
Scott: in the real world We have seen slippery slopes in reality, you know nuclear power to nuclear bomb, right?
Scott: That's real That's not some made-up thing.
Scott: Right?
Rym: Well, no, actually that's not true because we went from nuclear bomb to nuclear power.
Rym: I Guess technically we didn't have nuclear power generation until long after we had nuclear bombs.
Rym: In fact, you get the bomb is arguably easier to make than a effective nuclear.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, I digress there have been real slippery slopes that have.
Scott: we have gone down in real life, right and We've just read, you know, so many UM play gods sci-fis.
Scott: right that you know, people are so worried about slippery slopes, but if We can there are many situations such as this where we can build the technology And as long as we don't go down the slippery slope We can gain a huge benefit.
Scott: right.
Scott: The negatives are further down the slope at the top of the slope.
Scott: if we hold Just hold and keep the snowball way at the top of the hill and don't go down the hill There's a huge benefits to be gained.
Scott: if we're so afraid of the bottom of the hill That we stay at the very tippy top and don't take the only one step down and stop there after one step We're actually sort of you know That's also a negative in that you can consider the positives that we would get one step down in this case lots and lots of CSAM dissemination just going to go getting off scotch-free not getting caught right.
Scott: all this child abuse just running rampant Right is like.
Scott: that's also a negative right?
Scott: So we need to figure out a way that we can Recognize the true and real dangers of going down the slope more than one step because they are super real right Recognize the damage of not going down the slope at all and find a way to go down the slope.
Scott: one step only.
Scott: fucking.
Scott: stay there Right.
Scott: make our society better right and not arguing against step one.
Scott: Be you know by pointing at step two as soon as someone goes to step two, yeah yell at them all you want.
Rym: Well, there's the step one, but while I agree with you in principle in this case We literally cannot know if step two ever happened because of the way u.s.
Rym: Law works.
Scott: the way to solve this problem is only in that specific case, right?
Rym: Primary concern of almost everyone.
Rym: I see it was credible in this space.
Scott: I can't imagine that becoming a huge a huge thing right?
Scott: has?
Scott: Have people been getting caught?
Scott: if that if that case is always true Right that the government is sending hashes to tell them to insert into the database to catch people doing other things besides legitimate See Sam.
Scott: then how come other people on the other platforms where these systems have been in place for a long time There should?
Scott: we should have been seeing people who have been getting busted for other non see Sam related crime.
Rym: You wouldn't because anything like that that's done under a gag order.
Rym: You're never gonna find out Someone.
Scott: if a human being goes to like is arrested you're right.
Rym: It's like no, you know, you know, but you would not know in the general public They have that sealed evidence.
Rym: in most cases that's never revealed to the public.
Scott: There aren't people being disappeared right or whatever.
Rym: How would you know?
Scott: How have you seen anyone you know getting?
Rym: all I all I know is stats.
Rym: I saw on Leaks attempting to show how many national security letters and gag orders get sent and it's a lot just generally across all technology.
Rym: But I'm saying the solution to this is to change the structure.
Rym: The US government should be much more limited in where and how gag orders are used and we need a lot more oversight over that Whole process.
Rym: that's the actual fundamental problem.
Rym: that's making this issue, right?
Scott: But the fact that we even know the system exists Right that Apple told us about it is a reason to have some measure of good faith in the system.
Scott: They could have just done this and never told anyone a fucking thing.
Scott: They could have implemented this whole system and never told anyone it existed that we would never even know about it.
Scott: You wouldn't know this was happening and you would just feel right as rain.
Scott: the fact that Apple told us that this existed and how?
Scott: It works when they didn't have to Right.
Scott: They didn't have to tell us is a reason to have good faith in the system unless this is like the the sort of You know double think strategy of the government, right?
Scott: Right, that's Right.
Scott: is a reason to believe that yeah It's gonna right until this until they say it's also a reason to believe that if things went to step two That someone would say something, you know, not necessarily Someone officially saying something but some sort of whistleblower.
Rym: I feel much more simple if this figures into your threat profiles enough to where you have a. Specifically you are already the kind of person who needs to be using platform agnostic encryption, right?
Scott: And yeah, I'm not gonna.
Scott: I'm not gonna get mad about this the way other people are getting mad about it until You know something actually happens, right?
Scott: I'm seeing this currently as a net positive of catching lots.
Rym: I mean when I need to communicate in a way that I know is verifiably secure.
Rym: I use Platform agnostic and an encrypted services.
Scott: Hmm I mean it.
Scott: you could just Seriously, if you don't want to set up fancy encryption if you just make a fucking Linux computer and two people SSH to it Yeah, and you'd write you edit a text file.
Scott: It's like the government ain't gonna find it even if the text file is unencrypted.
Rym: Well, so did you?
Rym: there was a thing.
Rym: a bunch of government people who were being investigated for corruption and other things got caught with this a Common way.
Rym: for a long time people would communicate anonymously and avoid government regulation and oversight and even avoid cops.
Rym: is Someone would log into a random email account write an email and not send?
Rym: just leave it as a draft.
Rym: Someone else logs into that same email account looks in the draft read the draft edits it But they never actually send the email anywhere.
Rym: smart there's a lot of well that that it's not staying inography, but that's a whole class of Security through obscurity communication mechanisms that are way out of scope for the show.
Rym: And I think we talked about it in like 2007 on GeekNights.
Rym: Anyway, I'm hungry and I think this was a plenty long show.
Rym: you see what happens.
Rym: we skip a couple weeks of shows.
Rym: It's all bottled up.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So, uh, see you on Wednesday when?
Rym: We do the show on.
Scott: I watched all four even movies.
Rym: Oh, I haven't watched them yet But I watched beat.
Scott: I watched Beast are season two.
Rym: Oh, I finished Beast our season two.
Rym: I was.
Rym: uh, all I will say is I was Surprised by exactly one thing and that thing was very surprising and it involved the number four.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't think that.
Rym: I thought I didn't think that was literally going to happen.
Rym: Okay, and then just literally happened and the show just moved on like yep that happened that that surprised me a little bit.
Rym: Okay, we can always review Beast our season two if we got nothing else.
Rym: Hmm or be.
Rym: I guess there's gonna be a third season coming to like wrap everything up.
Scott: Yeah, Ava movies would be better.
Scott: Beast our season two is Movies by Wednesday cuz I'm only four of them.
Rym: Yeah, you don't even need to watch tomorrow It's 730 p.m.
Rym: On a watch them all in two days.
Rym: Yeah, so, let's see tomorrow one day into the next day.
Rym: I'm working also the first.
Rym: you've already seen the dark literally all night.
Scott: You don't realize you've already seen the first one.
Scott: You could just watch the last one minute of the first one.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I figure oh wait, there's two there's another seat There's a scene in the middle of the first one That's less than like 30 seconds long and the end of the first one like literally the last less than minute.
Rym: Oh shit, like that matters like the Ava does.
Scott: yeah, but you can you can just watch those two scenes and otherwise I'm still not gonna.
Rym: I'm not gonna have watched four ish movies by Wednesday when we got to do a show.
Rym: cuz I have I Remember my entire tomorrow is taken up in the evening playing blades in the dark until like midnight.
Scott: If you just stay there Ava, so if you start watching them Oh, yeah, I know the danger.
Scott: You might watch him all today.
Rym: the reason Ava the cowboy bebop DVDs.
Rym: These things are under lock and key for a reason.
Rym: You can't see a screen playing certain things.
Rym: You're gonna be trapped for it.
Rym: Star Wars cannot be displayed on any screen.
Scott: The the first movie is ninety nine point ninety nine percent a compilation of the first six episodes of the TV series.
Scott: But starting with episode the second movie It's almost nothing like in fact that yet while being almost nothing like it It's all basically the same thing.
Rym: also You know what?
Rym: The problem is I realized that can't.
Rym: I can't make that Simpsons TV because it would turn into the day killers and our IT.
Rym: I'll leave you all with this.
Rym: We had a bunch of VHS tapes from my family where we would do ad blocking by someone would record shows and then we'd all Watch the shows without the ads later.
Rym: So that was a chore like taking out the garbage.
Rym: So I had these VHS tapes that were in like the lowest quality mode So like eight hours of tape and it was just back-to-back Simpsons episodes with no openers closers or commercials.
Rym: and if anyone put that in the VCR we were just trapped.
Rym: I can't get that little TV.
Rym: You'll see me sitting at my decks with two 4k monitors and I'll be staring at a tiny little screen playing like episode 36 of The Simpsons in 320 by 200.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night and The patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights now that we're back are Heidi McNichol Alan Joyce linky G dread.
Rym: Lily Tenerbrae Chris Romer Clinton Walton Dex Finn just like a dude guy.
Rym: Shoshaya high 85 Rebecca Dunn review bad bull 34 cowards.
Rym: It's coming.
Rym: Ryan Baron Sam Erickson Sherman one oral Taylor Braun under program law odd-do Pierce ab threat open seat, right You hold the key to my heart and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: I paused the patreon for the previous month because we missed so many shows, but we're back doing our normal thing.
Rym: We'll pretty much be on a normal schedule.
Rym: on the next Monday show We're talking about sleeping for computers and on the next Wednesday show We are very likely going to talk about all of the new Ava movies since they're all out and we've well by then We'll have seen them.
Rym: But anyway for right now now that we're back.
Rym: I leave you.
Rym: Where is locked if we can't get to bro?
Rym: Wait, I see him and it looks like he's wrestling someone.
Rym: What's he doing with his favorite bro, what other weapon does he have?
Rym: he needs his hands free.
Rym: Oh He's got him on his knees, it's just a matter of time now.
Rym: process toying with him.
Rym: Pretzel better rocks.
Scott: gotta teach me that one Fade of space may have got his helmet knocked off.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: He's hideous.
Scott: Must have been four boys on base phrase again.
Rym: Hey, that's not a phantom spaceman.
Rym: That's it Oh Right phantom spaceman.