Rym: It's Thursday April 22nd 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are talking about pets.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: so, uh the Rangers according to I typed Rangers odds of playoffs into Google really low because After the gate the game maybe one four in a row.
Scott: the Bruins also won four in a row suiting catch up to them Lose some games that were the elders fell back But then they just beat the shit out of us to create a bigger gap.
Scott: So now not only and the Bruins won again, so it's like not only the gap got bigger Yeah, and we haven't caught up to anybody.
Scott: even worse.
Rym: I looked at the schedule because some teams got better or worse at different parts of the season But the Bruins actually have a pretty easy schedule for the rest of the year.
Rym: the way things are going right now Games remain.
Scott: it's the grab is the most important thing.
Scott: the games remaining against Buffalo.
Scott: Yeah, the grab is the stat.
Rym: then of course we uh, we notably lost a buffalo earlier.
Scott: So One time.
Scott: Yeah, that was yeah.
Rym: Yeah, so if that doesn't happen again, cuz that could be a problem Oh, it was OT loss wasn't OT law.
Rym: So we got that point but I did Check because the odds were a lot higher before the game.
Rym: We just lost and then they dropped on the on the tee.
Rym: on the TV They said they have a seven point five percent chance of winning based on some bookie.
Rym: So making it into the playoffs.
Rym: So according to Google as of right now Based on games that happened in the intervening period from the last time we checked that their odds have risen to a sparkling 8.1 percent chance.
Rym: Yeah, so either roll a natural 20 or roll a 19 and then get lucky like that's.
Rym: that's the odds of the Rangers making the playoffs.
Scott: Not good odds not great.
Rym: Ah, that's fine.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: Well, just you know, we weren't expected to make the play.
Rym: There won't be hockey and it'll be warmer and then we'll continue.
Rym: we'll finish reading the tale of Genji instead of watching hockey.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: I I did turn off that game the other night And I was just like fart noise.
Rym: nice, you know what I did.
Rym: instead I played kid Icarus on the NES.
Rym: Okay, I'm fighting.
Rym: actually I made it pretty far.
Rym: I'm way better at that game than I was as a kid I can only get.
Scott: I've only ever like playing honestly without passwords or anything, you know I've only ever gotten past like the first vertical level.
Rym: I've gotten to the to the end of the first dungeon and beaten it legit on a real NES as a kid.
Rym: But I really couldn't get beyond that without codes.
Rym: I am using save states now, but I'm not doing any other cheating Like I'm just figuring the game out Dave states.
Scott: Oh, you're already just I'm doing the biggest possible cheating, but no other - yeah It means it's the best.
Rym: most perfect realization of me is what is me is playing this game.
Scott: Yeah, I've got a. I've got a motor in my bicycle that's hidden but no other cheating.
Scott: that's the only cheating I'm doing.
Rym: thing is what I will say playing kid Icarus without that is an exercise in misery.
Rym: Fuck that game.
Rym: playing it just with save states is actually Way better and more fun than I expected.
Rym: because I hated that game so much I never tried this before on an emulator to actually like try to beat kid Icarus.
Rym: So anyway in some news and this is actually moderately big news that I wish the u.s would emulate France This month has voted to ban any flights Where there is a train that could do the same route that is active and available to the public it within a certain amount of time Just straight up.
Rym: So right now currently it's going to ban five routes, which might not sound like a lot.
Rym: but to analogize this for you us ians Despite the fact that there's like a two ish hour Amtrak to Boston or DC from New York City like it's a real short Amtrak a Terrifying number of flights go between New York City Boston and DC on a daily basis.
Scott: I mean, it's like that, you know, the train is a little bit slower than the plane, but no TSA Don't.
Rym: yeah, there's no takes to get to the airport.
Scott: Right, exactly the you know, the train has some advantages and it's sort of evens out for those For those trips a little bit But also that they evens out for those trips in America where Amtrak sucks in France.
Rym: The trains are pretty good.
Scott: Yeah If that if that was a bullet train that went from New York to Boston the the plane would make no sense What?
Scott: so the worst part is it would carry less people in less time.
Rym: It actually kind of is a bullet train.
Rym: What one thing people always forget?
Rym: I think we've talked about psychicness before the Acela.
Rym: like the fast train Everyone makes fun of in America the Amtrak because it's so slow That train is actually a bullet train and can go very very fast.
Scott: However, technically it's like yeah sure what you know some semantic meaning.
Rym: Well, the word bullet does go that fast for short segments.
Rym: The sole reason though that route in America is so slow is because they have to redo all the tracks that have really tight turns.
Rym: Right, they can't compare.
Rym: it does.
Scott: when I when I say bullet train I mean the real bullet trains not in the Semantic, you know, no true Scotsman sense but in the sense that on the other side of the world there are trains that go 400 500 kilometers an hour and the Accela isn't even close.
Scott: Right, if you put the Accela next to that in a race, it would look like a snail.
Rym: They also serve different purposes.
Rym: Those super fast trains actually cover much longer distances and The Shinkansen in Japan.
Scott: It depends what those aren't the fastest.
Scott: They're not.
Scott: they are not the fastest but they are still several times faster than the Accela and Japan as a country is about the size of California.
Scott: ish Yeah, right.
Scott: so you could think of the.
Scott: it is making a trip from like, you know, LA to San Diego Which isn't too different from I'd say a Boston New York trip, right?
Rym: The point is simply this those trains that trip would be shockingly short even with our existing technology.
Rym: The sole barrier to that is the tracks themselves That NIMBYs won't allow anyone to upgrade and no government entity is willing to fund.
Rym: But even now with the current shitty Accela, I still think the US should ban flights between New York and Boston.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I'm 100% agreement.
Scott: So
Rym: in Paris, like this is a big step of Paris to a Bordeaux to Lyon to Nantes to Rennes and to Marseille are just banned and It seems like the evidence is this will have a world impacting Decrease in carbon dioxide emissions like it is a sea like it's not like enough to change our trajectory But it's like a measurable noticeable amount of reduction by not having those flights.
Rym: Mmm, and actually the rule is pretty good too.
Rym: The rule is if there if there's a train route that is 2.5 hours or less.
Rym: That is the trigger that will ban flights.
Scott: So the Accela time from New York to Boston is about three hours and change.
Rym: Yeah, the last I read if they fix the tracks, it would be a little under two hours.
Scott: So it'd be like seven.
Scott: it takes you.
Scott: if you leave at 7 p.m.
Scott: Today you'll get there at 1048 p.m.
Scott: Right?
Scott: If the Shinkansen can go 320 kilometer running at speeds and actually runs at speeds of 320 kilometers an hour.
Scott: Yeah, and it from New York to Boston is 346 kilometers, it would probably get there in an hour and change.
Scott: Yeah, so even the Accela with fixed tracks, right is Well, the Accela with fixed tracks is almost an hour slower.
Scott: Well, actually the Accela could go in, which is not fastest train on earth.
Scott: So if you had the fastest train on earth, you'd probably be at least an hour.
Rym: Pretty sure.
Rym: the fastest trains on earth are those two Chinese bullet trains.
Scott: So twice as fast as the best the Accela could do under ideal conditions Right.
Rym: It looks like the Accela could go on those routes something like 220 230 kilometers an hour with relatively minor improvements to the tracks that they can't even do.
Rym: Point is it's still a laughably, you know not as Until Biden didn't actually want to invest in trains at all in the last century.
Rym: Anyway, yep operating speed 240 kilometers an hour is a baseline operating speed.
Rym: Looks like they picked that number because that's the number that was reasonable to expect all the tracks to be upgraded to in.
Rym: the u.s Couldn't even hit that But I encourage this.
Rym: I hope the u.s Does something similar someday and I hope we do whatever we need to do to at least connect the Northeast Corridor via Amtrak.
Scott: So yeah, I mean there should there definitely should just be.
Scott: you know The original point right is that if there are several options several options to achieve the same thing and one of them is just Measurably more damaging.
Scott: Yeah, you should absolutely just make that decision.
Rym: for people Like it's like having a bus or a train like those two options Make sense because they're comparable.
Rym: like there's there are slightly different use cases.
Rym: one could be the budget option.
Rym: There's a lot of stuff going on But planes for that kind of route is just objectively more harmful and benefits almost no one.
Scott: The same thing is like plastic bag at the grocery store, right that the paper bag is just better?
Scott: Yep, right.
Scott: Don't put the moral and take the pass on the consumer.
Rym: That's the lesson.
Rym: never put the moral hazard choice on the consumer Because that's not fair.
Rym: We all live in a society.
Rym: So you got any news.
Scott: Do I have any news Katie coop?
Scott: No, that's not a news.
Scott: That's that's my thing of the day for next Wednesday.
Rym: Oh for next Wednesday.
Rym: Okay I got some more news that I.
Scott: it's not even what's not even Wednesday.
Rym: I just figured you wanted to talk about it.
Rym: I did And then you sent me another link that was like.
Scott: and then I said I said I said I said I said, what did I say?
Scott: Wait, I'll use that on a Wednesday Thing of today for today something else.
Rym: I didn't notice that part.
Scott: Wait, I'll use that on a Wednesday.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right There we go.
Rym: So I got some news.
Rym: This is actually a big deal.
Rym: So New York City, I'll summarize this because you can go read Wikipedia if you care about all the details.
Rym: there basically are two gigantic tunnels that get all the water New York City needs into the city and they are so old and So necessary that I want to say since 1917 and 1936 for those two tunnels neither one has been inspected at any point Because there's no way to
Scott: inspect it.
Scott: You got to turn the water off exact because otherwise you go into the tunnel you drown.
Scott: Yeah, so tunnel number one waters in there moving.
Scott: how fast right?
Scott: Death.
Rym: if you go in there and you might think well turn one off leave the other one on turning one.
Scott: Oh, no, it's not water.
Rym: turning one off would literally start killing New Yorkers Like there's not enough water.
Scott: You can't just have one.
Scott: how I get a shit.
Rym: So tell us number one and two Thankfully just seem to still be trucking but we have no idea how hot like how they're doing So.
Rym: the city has been trying for a little over 50 years To build tunnel number three.
Scott: This is like even mind these these tunnels right are Just to give you a perspective right?
Scott: So the water comes from upstate New York like many Harmon type places.
Scott: There are many there are many reservoirs and we have the Catskill aqueduct is like the biggest longest.
Scott: It's like the longest man-made tunnel is I don't know.
Scott: It's this humongous aqueduct right that gets the water to the city right.
Scott: that system Once it's in the city There's like this place that you know.
Scott: I've seen it on.
Scott: I seen a picture one time of like Where the water comes from the aqueduct and enters the New York water system and that's where these other tunnels come into play the tunnel One and two.
Scott: Yeah, it's a tunnel one and two doesn't?
Scott: outside isn't like, you know up in New York's, you know somewhere north Right, that's actually that's the Catskill aqueduct and other things that feed in or whatever.
Rym: Yeah, the system that gets water to New York is both very complicated but also surprisingly simple in terms of how it operates.
Scott: It's just as if it's complicated and simple hard and easy.
Scott: Yeah and expensive.
Rym: That's how I would describe most major infrastructure like.
Rym: the principles involved are fairly simple.
Rym: Like a lot of these things are designed so that they're slightly downhill For like miles and miles and miles and miles and miles to the point that you don't need pumps water will just go.
Rym: but To design that system to actually get the water from all the places and get it to the right place in the right quantities Figuring out that exact angle and figuring out exactly how to put it all together and how to deal with exceptions That is very complicated.
Scott: Also the further away you get from the start of the tunnel the deeper you got to dig.
Rym: Like well the tunnel number three, I think it's gonna be six hundred feet underground.
Scott: That's far.
Rym: that is very far especially because this area is a lot of like bedrock kind of ground.
Rym: Just it's way.
Scott: it's way lower than subways like not even close.
Scott: It's it's way down there.
Rym: So work has begun on the final phase of tunnel number three.
Rym: tunnel Number three actually is as far as I've read it started supplying water to Manhattan But it is not linked to the rest of the New York City system yet.
Rym: And the final segment is in Long Island City.
Rym: That's the last part they have to dig.
Scott: Yeah, so what's interesting about these these tunnels right is that you know, yeah, you have to be able to access them somehow.
Scott: So there's these shafts, right?
Scott: It's like a various spots along the tunnel, right?
Rym: There's a vertical Jeopardy question or jeopardy answer.
Rym: What are places river really would like to break into if he wouldn't be around Along that's along the tunnel right at various spots.
Scott: every so often There is some vertical hole like a straight down hole that there where you could go from the surface of the earth Open it up and go downstairs elevator.
Scott: I don't know what.
Scott: they got in there And go down to where the tunnel is.
Scott: Obviously, they're all fucking locked.
Rym: because yeah In fact, the city has actually started.
Rym: they've.
Rym: there were a lot more photos and press access to the sites where they were building tunnel Number three.
Rym: they have actually started scrubbing all those images off the internet wherever they find them and they have control over them.
Rym: They've banned press access.
Rym: They've shut down archives.
Rym: They're basically There's a lot of secrecy now around the exact details of where tunnel number three is Well, I mean for security reasons and also for you know picky me out, of course Yeah, people who are going there and die.
Scott: Yeah, it's a super dangerous place to work.
Scott: You know the people working there's are you know, risking their lives just to dig the thing, right?
Scott: So they don't want anyone unnecessarily you would.
Scott: you would never be fat if you went in there and died.
Scott: You would never be found.
Rym: I bet it's probably mafia bodies in the tunnel But like these stores always fascinating because any any piece of information you learn even reading this article I'm gonna link to You'll notice something.
Rym: and if you wonder about that you could go down a rabbit hole that would consume the rest of your night.
Rym: Like for example tunnel number three first began delivering water to Manhattan in 1998. and Why those?
Rym: why the end is there?
Rym: I'm not sure but that links to another article that There's a whole bunch of nonsense going on.
Scott: The point is is that once tunnel three is done and fully operational then they're going to shut down Temporarily tunnel number one, which will be by humans in over a hundred years.
Scott: There will be enough capacity to turn the water off on the other tunnels at least enough to go in there Yeah, and hopefully not die when going in there and clean it fix it, etc.
Scott: Which will probably take many many years.
Rym: and then now there is a danger Because apparently we New York City partly due to climate change has started to hit already.
Rym: It's bumping up against the maximum throughput of tunnels one and two combined.
Rym: So we got to do the maintenance on one and two before we get to the point where we now can't turn off any of them Again, which is probably coming.
Rym: The last interesting thing is so work began on the last two shafts there.
Rym: It's like a 14 mile one and I think an 11 mile one.
Rym: The final end of this looks like it's going to be in Mm-hmm, and then they have to build even more tunnels to connect it to even more parts of the city that are not as important.
Rym: I think in 2026 is when they can plan shutting down to the number one temporarily.
Scott: Yeah, you know SimCity 2000 when they added the water system really under you know You could just drag pipes and just like diggity diggity instantly.
Scott: It's like they while the game is paused They really did not accurately simulate.
Rym: This feels more like you haven't played hearts of iron with us yet when we did some live games.
Rym: It's like all right.
Rym: I want to make a new ship.
Rym: I want to another destroyer in my fleet and you click a bunch of buttons and then it'll.
Rym: you'll look at the game and the Game says like yeah, it's October 4th 1937 that's next destroyer will be done in 1941 and that's as fast as it's gonna be there.
Rym: and Four hours later, you'll get a notification like hey that one ship you asked for is done in some other news.
Rym: This is interesting because we talked about this on GeekNights and you but I think we even linked to the documentary of course but as you know the the character Apu on The Simpsons is problematic for a bunch of reasons and There's been a lot of conversation around that.
Rym: We're not qualified to talk.
Rym: wasn't there a whole documentary Fantastic documentary and one of the points in it was that Hank Azaria in the documentary like Basically seemed to disagree didn't want to engage was defensive and the documentary kind of focused on that.
Rym: rightly The news which just happened.
Rym: this looks like it's breaking.
Rym: as of like 7 a.m Today or at least very recently in the last few days Hank Azaria actually turned around and issued not a press release saying like I apologize But he was doing some interview thing and he talked about this topic and how the documentary actually forced him to see things.
Rym: He changed his like.
Rym: he realized he's wrong.
Rym: He up.
Rym: He like openly and it appears very earnestly apologized and I'm not gonna like.
Rym: this does not excuse anything that happened in the past.
Rym: That is not even a not something we could even like discuss because we're two white dudes doing a podcast.
Scott: I mean, it's not.
Scott: how can we I can't you know, accept someone's apology because I'm not the harmed person?
Rym: Yeah, right but I think this article is worth reading because it is also from the perspective of an Indian American talking about Like this apology and it links to the apology and it's.
Rym: it's something I honestly didn't expect to happen.
Rym: I expected that that documentary like we all watched it and that Hank Azaria We're just never saying anything about this again and everyone just try to avoid being in any way tied to that controversy and instead kind of out of nowhere.
Rym: he like Apologized and there was at least a step forward in that conversation.
Scott: Yeah, if anyone doesn't know he's like he's the voice actor.
Scott: He voices like half the characters on the show.
Scott: Yep He's also a real actor.
Scott: He's been a lot of movies.
Rym: But yeah, I know what you mean.
Scott: voice actors are real actors, right but you know, they're like you people.
Scott: I think people don't realize like you'll be watching a movie like I Think he was in Heat, right?
Scott: He's never.
Scott: I've never think he's ever been like the main character.
Scott: He might have been in certain things I don't know about but it's like you'll see him in like he'll be in a movie and you won't realize it's like that's fucking Chief Wiggum Because he's not using that voice.
Scott: He's using whatever voice is appropriate for the movies and you know, which is not you know, it's not like.
Scott: You know the the bender Jake guy who sounds the same.
Scott: What's his name?
Rym: Why do I always forget that dude's name?
Scott: If you told me the name, I'd be like.
Scott: if you said the name first I'd be like, oh that I know that is I literally forget this dude's the Joe DiMaggio.
Rym: Yeah, exactly Literally every time I just forget that dude's name, but anyway, it's not like.
Scott: you know Joe when he's voicing a character like you can tell it's him, right but His area like you can't.
Scott: he does different voice every time.
Rym: yep It's interesting how over time that voice became in my brain the voice of Jake and like if I ever watched a few drama.
Rym: It's just like oh that's Jake's voice and it feels weird.
Rym: instead of looking at Jake and saying oh that's bender's voice.
Rym: That feels weird.
Rym: But yeah, just I was.
Rym: I was surprised that there was a further note in this story.
Rym: Like I didn't think anything would ever come of this story again, at least from the white dude.
Rym: So yeah read this and form your own opinion.
Rym: I'm not gonna Really comment on that further.
Rym: So do you have any news?
Scott: There's nothing.
Scott: there's nothing really happening.
Rym: I Mean, there's a lot happening.
Rym: It's just stuff that we're not qualified to comment on or really don't want to center our voices on here.
Rym: I'll go to FARC.
Rym: It's going on a FARC right now.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: Uh Something about the yellow pages.
Rym: all these headlines are all hard.
Scott: No, no.
Scott: No, I'm at Google News.
Scott: No No, those are our Monday newses.
Scott: No, no, no.
Rym: Tech company razor announces plastic free single-use toilet bamboo toilet paper, which raises more questions than it answers.
Rym: Yes An RV exploded somewhere.
Rym: All right, that's sad Uh, I got a bunch of phone calls today from an alarm company telling me that a temperature sensor was continuing to get hotter and Hotter at some middle school in New Jersey.
Rym: They have not called back recently.
Rym: So I'm assuming that that school did not burn down and that they've realized they were calling the wrong number all day things Of the day, so check this out.
Rym: I'm gonna link to a Twitter thread from a fantastic Twitter account in Kuna Bula which mostly talks about Historic writing historic texts.
Rym: can a form tablets that kind of thing like Dead Sea Scrolls stuff like really good history.
Scott: Yeah form isn't it?
Scott: CUNY form can.
Rym: a form is how I've heard most professors pronounce it.
Scott: I mean, I don't know the end.
Scott: I don't know the answer.
Scott: I'm just asking.
Rym: Yeah, I'm good but most professors pronounce it.
Rym: that way in my experience could also be wrong because as you all may remember if you listen to gig nights a Long time in my middle school and in my high school multiple teachers pronounce the name Goethe as goeth and I was too stupid to realize they were wrong.
Scott: I Didn't know you were so adamant about saying Heracles.
Scott: all the time I am adamant because I.
Rym: that's something I care about.
Rym: I'm weirdly mad about.
Rym: I still don't know why I'm so mad about that.
Rym: Anyway, so I'll link to the Twitter thread because the thing that is the thing that day is amazing But this Twitter thread does a really good job of Framing a particular aspect of why this thing is so amazing.
Rym: if you've never heard of it.
Rym: This is the trippytaka coriana.
Rym: If I describe this without explaining like without just telling you what it is.
Rym: It's basically possibly the most complete and error-free transmission and storage of about two gigabytes of data from in the course of human history.
Rym: this is two gigabytes of data that has been maintained error-free since long before the year 1200 and The story behind how it was made and what it is is just amazing.
Rym: Basically it is.
Rym: if I had to summarize it is a collection of the Buddhist scriptures carved into 481258 wooden printing blocks.
Rym: Those printing blocks are stored in a special building that was built in the 13th century with the idea it was designed to be a permanent archive of this information.
Rym: it tended to last forever and It does continue to exist.
Rym: It's the same building It's the same wood blocks and the cool thing about it is the design was such that the wooden blocks are the authoritative source of truth.
Rym: They spent like 13 years carving these blocks with the characters not only so that they could then say this is the official Unedited version of this text where there couldn't be a disagreement about it or a way to forge one.
Rym: It's it's intricately catalogued and stored in a way to where it's persisted to this day.
Rym: But what they would do is take those blocks out and use those blocks to print Books and the books were what people had access to the monks who ran or run this site.
Rym: to this day They just maintained the blocks themselves.
Scott: Mmm, I can't believe.
Scott: this thing is basically like a wonder of the world that like no one I've never heard of it It wasn't designated as a UNESCO heritage site until like 1995.
Scott: UNESCO is an interesting thing.
Scott: I always think about UNESCO.
Scott: It's like it feels like every country in the world except the United States.
Scott: Maybe like.
Scott: do we not like, you know, like sighs.
Scott: do we like not sign up with them or something?
Scott: And every other country in the world UNESCO like dictates like this is a cultural heritage site.
Scott: This is an important thing.
Rym: I mean we do that too, but we're like.
Scott: are there any?
Scott: are there any UNESCO cultural heritage sites in New?
Scott: York City?
Rym: What was that Eddie is a bit long ago where it was like oh this mall was built in.
Scott: Yeah in the United States like, you know, we we dictate our own things.
Scott: We're like, ah, this is a national monument, right?
Scott: We don't know.
Scott: when there's no international people like saying ah This is an important thing even even things in the United States in our territory that are older than our very I don't know.
Rym: I do.
Rym: I probably do not know how many UNESCO World Heritage sites there are in the u.s.
Scott: I don't know that.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: yeah, I just know that like that's I just know that UNESCO is an organization and and you know picking You know designating cultural heritage sites is one of their functions.
Scott: That's what I know.
Rym: But think about this.
Rym: most of you probably never heard of this.
Rym: so yeah in the year like 1000 they made this thing.
Rym: in the year like 1200 something.
Rym: it got burned down by the Mongols and then the nation State of the place at the time decided you know what we're gonna rebuild this thing.
Rym: We're gonna make it even better.
Rym: and that data is That data has made it further than a lot of data.
Rym: I have generated in the last 10 years, right?
Scott: So it's in Korea.
Scott: so think about all the shit that has happened in Korea including obviously Korean War yeah between 1200 something.
Scott: and today Yep, and nobody went there and messed it up even though a lot of people wanted to take it.
Rym: That really sets this up.
Rym: the production of the Tripitaka Coriana was an enormous national commitment of money and manpower Perhaps comparable to the u.s.
Rym: Mission to the moon in the 60s Mm-hmm and this Twitter thread really frames it like the Transmission of data over the centuries like libraries do this.
Rym: But this Twitter thread makes a good point about how that is usually serendipitous like the intention of a library Especially like in the United States is not necessarily to preserve an unedited have access.
Scott: Yeah, it's to spread access.
Rym: Yeah, but this was this was the kind of thing that you see in sci-fi.
Rym: This was an archive that is intended to stand the test of time and last forever And it's doing a pretty fucking good job of lasting forever.
Scott: Yeah, all right well That's it's a really high quality thing of the day not as good as my thing of the day.
Rym: So the day is real good, so is it okay?
Scott: So there are these things in the United States, and I imagine no other country though I guess I could be wrong about that, but this feels like a very United States white people thing and that is Pig calling Contests which is you know you go to the country fair, and there's a microphone and you go to the microphone And you call a pig like here piggy piggy piggy.
Scott: you know come on You know what it's you.
Scott: what would you what noises would you make using you just your body and a mic and you know in?
Scott: order to Convince a pig to come to you and move in your general direction right.
Scott: and then I assume There's some sort of judging scoring system that I know nothing about and a winner is chosen.
Scott: Maybe they get a ribbon.
Scott: Maybe you get a prize.
Scott: Maybe some bacon.
Scott: I don't know what your prize is for winning the pig calling contest money.
Scott: I don't know But obviously they're really hilarious to watch.
Scott: you know people making pig noises People jumping up and down people taking it seriously people taking it not so seriously.
Scott: Etc.
Rym: I participated.
Rym: I learned how to do Pig calling as part of a 4-h thing with my Cub Scout pack when I was a little kid.
Scott: We did not do that.
Rym: Okay, but I got good.
Scott: In this video somebody has taken Video footage from some pig calling contests and edit it together.
Scott: on the right side of the screen and on the left side of the screen is a person with an electric guitar and Effectively They are playing the electric guitar With quite a bit of distortion along with the edited pig calling noises to create a somewhat good heavy metal song.
Scott: because What's how far away is pig calling from heavy metal vocalists?
Rym: Little more so reeling and a little less growling but otherwise No, I'm just saying Excellent excellent mashup here.
Rym: In the meta moment my reading of the tale of Genji did not accelerate as expected because I thought I could sit outside and read.
Rym: It got cold again.
Rym: So I think it'll accelerate soon.
Rym: give us another week or two.
Rym: It's weirdly extra cold for some reason now, and hopefully it will be warm again soon.
Scott: Gig night they gave us the super cold winter with all the snow and I was inside.
Scott: it had to go outside and now it's Like ah, okay.
Scott: We're almost ready to go outside still cold.
Rym: Yeah, like it was so warm.
Rym: I went for a bike ride.
Rym: I'm home.
Scott: Like I said the upside of the climate change is that it's global warming.
Scott: It's like if you're gonna kill us all and raise the sea level at least in the meantime.
Scott: if that's somehow Unavoidable because obviously I would like to avoid that.
Scott: but if it's unavoidable at least make it 90 degrees every day While I'm done.
Rym: Well, you're talking about how New York City is a humid subtropical climate and has been for about five.
Scott: Then why is it fucking 40 degrees?
Scott: Because it's spring at the end of April.
Rym: At least in the old days we wouldn't have that like couple weeks of it being weirdly warm before we had the cold snap again.
Rym: It would just be cold and still be cold right now.
Rym: There weren't many years where I was outside running and it was like 75 degrees and sunny on April 22nd in the fast.
Scott: Just make it warm.
Rym: Well, let's get in there.
Rym: Stay tuned.
Rym: I think it'll be warm this weekend.
Rym: Maybe I'll go bike up on that South County Trailway.
Scott: It's gonna rain.
Rym: I only on Sunday last I checked.
Rym: I'm gonna check right now.
Rym: Let's see 10-day forecast for Queens.
Rym: So no Saturday 69 degrees.
Rym: No rain.
Scott: What's the low?
Scott: you and your high one the lowest 50 is gonna be 69 degrees for like two seconds.
Rym: Now the low is 53 and that's mostly at night.
Rym: It's gonna be mostly warm all day.
Rym: It looks like This one.
Scott: I says says it's gonna be 52 at like 8 in the morning.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not gonna be up biking.
Rym: then I'll be biking at like 10.
Scott: You can't get very far if you're not up at 8 in the morning.
Rym: I got a lot more daylight now than I used to have at the end of the season last year.
Scott: sunset 746 yeah, that's fine.
Rym: I can bike in the dark.
Rym: I got lights.
Scott: sunrise 6 a.m Good.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: You got a skit.
Rym: I only get up that early if I'm like hiking mountain climbing or skiing or something.
Rym: I'm not getting up that early for a bike ride.
Scott: It's a good strategy actually to get up that early for the bike ride because by the time you have escaped the car area The you know that there's no traffic at 6 a.m Really true Zone
Rym: because usually I go to the west side because I like that route and I go up to Cortland up to Cortland Park to Get to the trail way, but it is much faster and more direct to just go over Randall's Island into the Bronx.
Scott: That's the way I go.
Rym: But those routes have a lot of cars and a lot of people parked in the bike lanes.
Scott: They're not really.
Rym: I've run into a lot of.
Rym: in fact, I have a video of all the cars blocking the bike lanes.
Scott: Yeah, it's not a bad.
Rym: I get a time-lapse almost every time I do that ride.
Rym: Anyway, so, uh, that's the meta moment.
Rym: like can find our stuff.
Rym: We're uh We're not doing any cons anytime soon.
Rym: Like there won't be any guns anytime soon.
Rym: Don't go to cons that happen anytime soon.
Scott: Obviously, if you live in New Zealand, you can go to a car.
Rym: Oh, yeah, if you live in New Zealand, you can go to a car packs off maybe some other Other countries, but that's toward the end of the year.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I can't say if you should go to that or not.
Rym: Yeah, it looks like it's scheduled at least and they're still talking about increasing the capacity.
Rym: Australia is doing better than us.
Rym: we can say that.
Scott: Okay It's hard not to be.
Rym: yeah All right, so we'll get right into it.
Rym: Oh, we didn't have a lot of Thursday shows queued up.
Rym: Uh, so we're gonna talk about pets which is something yet is very near and dear to me.
Scott: I've had a lot more pets than Scott at least but yes somehow in 15 16 years of GeekNights We haven't done a topic so basic as pets something that comes up just every day.
Rym: just review the Simpsons.
Scott: Sure, you know just saying I mean we did talk about Simpsons in the past at some point just not as the main bit Directly as itself, you know, it was incorporated into some other shows.
Scott: right that happens a lot.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, it's like said something so basic and fundamental to everyday life.
Scott: We have not done a show on it.
Scott: It's really hard to think of those things as they're hiding in plain sight.
Scott: It's like what should I do a show on?
Scott: and you could almost imagine a Simpson scene where someone's like hmm.
Scott: What should I?
Scott: something something and there's a giant something something walking around?
Rym: Well, you know why?
Rym: Well, I'm through the the process now like we used to have different processes We used to plan a lot more for a Thursday episode is well both bit during kovid.
Rym: we'll both be in our respective computer rooms and we'll have a discord conversation of what should we do the show on.
Rym: and Usually this now involves both of us looking around the room and typing nouns That we see that we don't think we've ever talked about that class of noun before.
Rym: Usually I'm not out of the room.
Scott: It's not likely to be a show.
Rym: Yep, but Usually only to find out that.
Rym: oh, yeah We actually did a show on that in 2006 and then we did it again in 2012 and here we are in 2021.
Scott: But yeah, somehow we've never done a single pet show ever.
Rym: So at least so easy if you think of other ideas along these lines something that is so simple and it's not Especially things that are not science technology gaming Anime animation comics manga something that is not one of those things.
Scott: Yeah, tell us cuz we need a Thursday ideas.
Rym: Yep So what's interesting is in my life partly like my family my entire family pretty much is very Like animal centric like we just always were even my extended family for the most part like not just like my direct family.
Rym: So I basically lived surrounded by pets ranging from standard cats and dogs to exotics to Straight up like deer and raccoons at times.
Rym: so I've interacted with a lot of animals and it was actually a a weird not a homesickness cuz I was jazzed to be in college, but There was a very weird time in my life when I was at between RIT and the living in Beacon where I didn't have a pet and That like gap was very like prominent in my just feelings.
Rym: and when we moved to New York City I have a pet again and I think that there that one period where I didn't have pets will hopefully be one of the only periods in my life That is of any significant length of time where there are not pets in my home.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not the.
Scott: I mean, I'm not the exact opposite like never had a pet but I've not had Many pet right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: what did I you know when I was very very young like?
Scott: I can't even remember so young, right?
Scott: My parents had a cat that was named Sherlock, right and my memory of this cat is not the cat itself I don't.
Scott: I couldn't even pick it out of a row of cats in a lineup, right?
Scott: Though I guess it was orange maybe but I think there's a photo of it somewhere.
Scott: But when I was young I remember the furniture my parents had in their bedroom Had all these like lines on it like all around the base of the furniture all the furniture Right and it wasn't until later that I realized Right that basically that cat was an evil demon cat.
Scott: My parents were afraid was gonna kill me when I was in baby form.
Scott: That scratched the shit up basically everything and you could tell how high the cat could reach because all the furniture was scratched Like this horizontal.
Scott: it looked like, you know Like you go to the beach and you see the line where low tide is high tide reaches It's low cats.
Rym: what it was like, it's low Exactly.
Scott: So I think that you know, my parents they had you know a dog or you know different pets in their lives, but We didn't get.
Scott: the only pet I had when I was a kid was I had some fish and then I didn't have fish.
Scott: and then when I left to go to college they got dusty the dog and Then that's pretty much it in the Reuben family his pets go.
Rym: That's it was a good dog.
Rym: I enjoyed my times hanging out with dusty though as I as he got older and dusty would definitely bark at me a lot more than he used to.
Scott: Well dusty, uh, you know, I couldn't get him to bite you.
Scott: but you know, yeah I did my best he'd bonk his head against me and then run away or go chase a Paper towel, I mean when you know, we haven't dusty.
Scott: Yeah when dusty was a was like a baby dog.
Scott: He would like eat paper towel, you know, yip a hole way too much.
Scott: But then when he got older he sat on the couch and watch TV like a Reuben.
Rym: Yeah, we What that?
Rym: the only like common pet we never had like the really common pet was probably cats.
Rym: not because no one like cats.
Rym: We just ended up.
Rym: our family never had cats Not even because anyone was allergic to them or anything and I at least when I was a kid was not allergic to cats.
Rym: I am now as an adult like Frighteningly allergic to cats like to a degree that is like comical in an 80s movie.
Rym: the character Who's only beat is they are allergic to cats allergic?
Rym: But yeah, let's see we had So new.
Rym: so when I was born my parents already had a bunch of dogs like just three bunch of dogs in the house And I have a lot of very like kid memory of those dogs like mascot and Libby Springer spandrels, and then we rescued dogs.
Rym: We got Brock it.
Rym: then we adopted different dogs.
Rym: We just had dogs in the house for my entire life.
Rym: We had fish The first pets that we like me and my little brother would like to have to take care of and there were our pets instead Of just the family pets hamsters.
Rym: we had figgy.
Rym: Hamsters don't live that long.
Rym: Then we had figgy the second and we had figgy the third.
Rym: then we had a fourth one.
Rym: We just called figgy again.
Rym: There was I want to say we had a fifth figgy and We just as kids.
Rym: figgy was such a good name for a hamster that we apparently Ademantly refused to ever name a hamster anything but figgy.
Scott: That was just a hamsters at once.
Rym: just two figgies now only ever had one hamster at a time.
Rym: You know hamsters do not like to be around other hamsters for the most part.
Scott: How do they make more hamsters?
Rym: They're around them long enough to make more hamsters.
Rym: Okay, interesting We had gerbils at one point that we got from a nun.
Scott: I still know the difference between a gerbil and a hamster.
Scott: Isn't it the same fucking thing there?
Rym: They're completely different animals.
Rym: They're not even remotely close to each other.
Rym: okay, a hamster imagine like a tiny little bear a Gerbil imagine like our.
Rym: take a rat and a squirrel mash them together and make them bitey.
Rym: They're cute Not super like human focused smart compared to a lot of other small animals like that.
Rym: Honestly, I don't think gerbils make good pets for like most people I think they should be treated more like an exotic pet.
Rym: hamsters are much easier for people to deal with.
Rym: I think Gerbils require special cages or you can literally drive them insane for reasons I don't really want to get into but we got these gerbils found.
Scott: I always found those interesting the hamster and the gerbil because I've never seen them out in the wild ever.
Rym: Oh, I've seen wild.
Rym: I've never seen a wild gerbil in person.
Rym: I've seen wild hamsters in a zoo before.
Rym: I've never encountered an actual wild hamster on my own in the wild.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I don't know like I'm talking like out in the wild.
Scott: It's like where did these animals come from?
Scott: I'm sure I can all different place.
Scott: Like I've only ever seen them as pets in a cage in someone's house, you know?
Scott: Oh, yeah, I know I've seen guinea pigs in the wild.
Rym: Yeah, yeah But I think The like not actually not.
Scott: I haven't personally seen them in the wild but I've seen in the wild on you know video.
Rym: at one Point we had we had a little mouse who was our pet.
Rym: we rescued him from a tragic pet shop that the owner.
Rym: and when we were kids because one thing my mom did one of her Jobs was basically rescuing animals from abusers and dangerous situations and like doing animal welfare stuff.
Rym: and there was this one moment where a Owner of a pet store basically just gave up and just left just like abandoned a pet store full of animals to die.
Rym: So my mom was part of like that rescue effort and we adopted a little mouse From that among some other animals that we helped foster.
Rym: I forget I'm actually trying to.
Rym: I'm old enough to not be able to fully piece together chronologies from my youth But I think that's the same time.
Rym: We got our second love bird.
Rym: I think frisbee also came from that pet store if I recall correctly.
Rym: But I think that class of like small animal that is Reasonably durable and doesn't require super specialized knowledge to take care of and only lives a couple of years is probably like.
Rym: I think there's something good for Children to be able to experience that and also honestly to experience that loss and to learn about like the real world and death And everything along the way without also having the commitment of that.
Rym: chinchilla is gonna live 20 more years.
Rym: That's something I've noticed.
Rym: a lot of people Will like a lot of people who which chinchilla is I think specifically Don't actually know how long they live and assume that they live like a hamster or a gerbil or or a squirrel or something And then discover that they can live a lot longer and don't know what to do.
Scott: That seems to have a parent and out lives you.
Rym: Oh, yeah Dusty we got dusty when I was very young.
Rym: My mom still has dusty.
Rym: dusty will probably outlive both my parents the way Parrots tend to go dusty the bird outlive.
Scott: dusty the dog.
Rym: Yeah, dusty the bird still remembers me to this day despite the fact that I don't see dusty very often.
Rym: It's really funny and cute Mm-hmm.
Scott: Why wouldn't they yeah?
Rym: Well, it's not every animal would necessarily remember that kind of thing.
Rym: like different animals have different relationships with humans.
Rym: but One thing that's it's interesting how in America There's certain pets that society just treats as standard and people have a lot of basic knowledge.
Rym: like a lot of people get dogs and cats and hamsters and They don't know anything about those animals at all.
Rym: like a parent's getting for their kid like oh kids should have a pen.
Rym: I'll go to the Petco and get a pet.
Rym: or in the old days before a lot of places started banning this go to like One of those dodgy pet stores like literally in a mall to get like a dog.
Scott: There was a pet store in the mall.
Scott: there Lived for quite a while right, but it's like yeah, you know people.
Scott: I think people just don't think too hard about it.
Scott: They're like you know buy a dog all right.
Scott: You know you got to buy dog food.
Scott: obviously You know give it water, and you're in the pet store.
Scott: What else you got to do?
Scott: yeah, what else you got to do?
Scott: take it to the vet one time You know and then you're good to go.
Rym: yep And the problem is they just even those animals do require.
Rym: a lot of people have problems especially with a lot of dogs and cats.
Rym: Where the problem is they don't actually know shit about dogs and cats and they do the wrong thing Feed the wrong food train the wrong way and cause interesting social or physical Disorders in the animals that end up like.
Rym: a lot of problematic behavior of pets usually comes from owners Not actually knowing about those animals.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of times people will you know and you'll hear people say like oh my you know like.
Scott: they'll say little act like.
Scott: It's just the nature of their animal.
Scott: like you know Like yeah is your dog my dog isn't.
Scott: my dog is not very social.
Scott: It's like he doesn't go well with other dogs.
Rym: Have you ever introduced him to another dog?
Scott: How did your dog get that way?
Scott: You know?
Rym: yep, uh But at least with those animals so many people have them and so much like.
Rym: really basic knowledge is in popular culture that a Lot of people do well enough.
Rym: so those animals don't particularly suffer even if they're not necessarily raised particularly Well, like they might eat bad food and have like some minor health problems, but they tend to do also.
Scott: There's that also there's enough infrastructure around those Grocery store, there's dog food in this cat food at the grocery store, right?
Scott: You know if you go to a vet even in the middle of nowhere, they know what to do with a cat or a dog.
Scott: You know, it's common right if you show up with your I don't know monkey to the vet and you know Just a standard vet in a suburb.
Scott: They're gonna be like, I don't know what to do with monkey.
Rym: Yeah The classification there you'll.
Rym: you'll notice that normal vets will usually only be able to handle Dogs cats and a small number of other common animals and most other animals you might have as a pet are technically classified as exotics.
Rym: Many vets will not treat them at all.
Rym: Some vets will treat them but they'll warn you like yeah, I'm gonna do the best I can like.
Rym: I'm not an expert here But like for even rabbits like we have to take the rabbit to a specialized vet that can handle exotics.
Scott: And then there's the other kind of animal like, you know, gerbil hamster where it's like.
Scott: do you really take it to the vet?
Scott: It's sort of like I think you should.
Rym: I think generally it's sort of an aside goldfish goldfish.
Scott: Don't go to the vet, right?
Scott: It's it's a gold.
Rym: Those goldfish goldfish can live a long time and have a very different Profile from what most people think is most people drastically Terribly mistreat goldfish, right?
Scott: So we got.
Scott: so the fish I had right.
Scott: so I wasn't even like planning to get fish.
Scott: But you know We were at like the perm festival Right and they had the old throw the ping-pong ball in and get a goldfish in a plastic bag.
Scott: So I got.
Scott: I got a goldfish in a plastic bag and then I put it in like a bowl of water, right?
Scott: And then we went to the stood.
Scott: there was a little aquarium store in the mall, right.
Scott: and I was like, all right What do I need for the?
Scott: you know, the goldfish see a little bowl?
Scott: Right and they're like you got to put in distilled water.
Scott: You can't be putting in your sink water.
Scott: and I was like, oh, yeah.
Scott: And then they were like, yeah, you also got to put this stuff in the water So the fish doesn't get.
Scott: there's a disease called ik.
Scott: Yeah Thanks.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: what disease could you come like that?
Scott: What is the most disease name?
Scott: Right?
Scott: It's like We need a disease name.
Scott: He's got the ik.
Scott: It's a. basically the fish will get white spots and die.
Scott: I don't know what causes it or anything.
Scott: I'm not a vet.
Scott: All I know is that if you see a white spots a little parasite like a malaria kind of thing Okay, if you see white spots on your goldfish, it's not good.
Scott: Right and then it's like here Here's some fish food.
Scott: Shake it in the bowl.
Scott: Once or once a day, you know, it's like, okay.
Scott: So we got the bowl and we did all.
Scott: I just followed the instructions, you know I did what they told me to and The fish lived and it got pretty big started as like the tiniest goldfish and then it was like a couple inches long Goldfish.
Scott: and then one day my mom came home from wherever she was and the goldfish was not in the bowl It was on the kitchen counter.
Scott: So I guess he had a little jump.
Scott: So my mom picked it up and put it back in the bowl and it came back to life.
Scott: it wasn't dead.
Scott: So we're like, well, I guess it doesn't fit in the bowl.
Scott: So we would put like a cutting board so we couldn't jump out of the bowl.
Scott: And then we got a fish tank.
Scott: so then we had this big old fish tank and honestly, I was actually more interested in the Bubbly treasure chest than the fish.
Rym: Yeah, I honestly I generally find that fish aren't the best like fish teach different Sets of lessons to kids and I find a lot of kids seem to just get bored with fish After a certain point or a certain age unless they get into the technical aspects.
Scott: Yeah, I was mostly you know, like I had a friend who was like aquarium nerd, you know, like he was into aquariums But I was just like it looks cool.
Scott: I like it, you know, bubbly treasure chest.
Scott: Awesome, you know But I didn't actually you know, it's like the fish is just fish.
Scott: It's cool.
Scott: Watch it sometimes, you know I think like you're not like I'm making a relationship with the fish more interactive.
Rym: Cuddling with the fish I think like in general like other kinds of pets are just very much.
Rym: I think they can generally be a very positive influence on kids Like I know like the fact that we had pets my whole life Really shaped who I am as a person today.
Rym: like that I think I might have ended up being a very different person had we not had so many pets and animals.
Rym: because if you actually I've noticed most people who have problems with their pets another thing that they don't do is not just that they Don't learn like they don't have the book knowledge, but fine.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: They also just don't actually pay attention to their pets.
Rym: They don't actually like look at our pets behaving and think about like why is that dog doing that?
Rym: What's going on in their little brain?
Rym: like try to understand and empathize and like deal with that?
Rym: A lot of people just don't and then they're surprised.
Scott: Yeah the people are the people living their own lives and living the dog live their own life like it was a person and then only paying attention to the dog when it's like.
Scott: I feel like having some dog time.
Scott: the same way you would feel like I Feel like reading that book on the shelf and then when you're not reading it It's on the shelf and I think
Rym: that attitude is less than it used to be but it was definitely exacerbated by the Proliferation of shitty like puppy mill pet stores in malls and places like that.
Rym: I'm glad we're moving toward banning that kind of pet store.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, we just to round out my fish story.
Scott: So that fish was in that tank.
Scott: right lucky the fish.
Scott: and then we got a sec We're like, well, we got this big old fish tank now, right?
Scott: So we got a second goldfish a fancy-looking one and then we got a tiny little I don't know if it's technically a catfish But it looked like a catfish and it was really tiny and cuz.
Scott: it was supposed to supposedly like, you know Eat a lot of the dirt towards the bottom of the tank, which it did.
Rym: Oh, yeah bottom fitter That's your.
Rym: you were getting towards starting to make like a mini ecosystem, which is how yeah I'm a real aquarium has to be managed.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway the point that all that happened was the The fancy goldfish and the little catfish looking guy.
Scott: They both died before the original fish died.
Scott: The original fish last of the longest was eventually alone Right all by himself.
Scott: this this goldfish that you got for free at the at the carnival For like a ping-pong ball right.
Scott: that shouldn't have lived more than like a week.
Scott: I imagine none of the other fish at that little carnival probably survived.
Scott: a week lasted many years And then even though we kept doing every it preventative measure.
Scott: They got the egg, right?
Scott: So I Guess the egg is unavoidable.
Rym: Yep It's one thing that a lot of people who get pets especially when a family gets a pet for a kid Especially a longer-lived pet like not a hamster or something smaller.
Rym: They tend to also like.
Rym: there's a certain amount of Gross or grim animal husbandry knowledge that honestly people should know.
Rym: like when I was a kid You could definitely tell the people who had read at least one book that talked about the serious real stuff about dogs versus the people who had never done that and relied on their vets for anything like those are the people like.
Rym: the latter were the People who like didn't know they had to clip their dog's nails.
Rym: like that kind of nonsense would happen, but also like Guy kind of.
Scott: I don't know too many people like that everyone.
Scott: I know is like fuck.
Scott: I hate clipping the dog's name.
Rym: Yeah, oh god.
Rym: I hate dying you.
Rym: you think living a dog's nails is a pain in the ass?
Rym: It's got clipping a rabbit's nails.
Rym: Most rabbits do not fucking want you to clip their nails and they can kick.
Rym: you don't say they can kick way harder than you Would expect for a tiny little guy.
Scott: you're huge.
Rym: They're tiny just just holding down Yeah, but they're also fragile can't hold them down too hard.
Rym: You got to be very.
Rym: it's a delicate dance dog.
Rym: You can just like wrestle them down and cut the nail tranquilizer.
Scott: Yeah, so what's that thing people always post on the internet about cats like bunny burrito.
Scott: That will mess you up.
Scott: be smart use drugs.
Rym: I Like the the the burrito method of you wrap the small animal in basically a blanket and then pull the little leggy out And that's how you do it.
Scott: Well, there's also that thing like you grab a cat in a certain way, and then they just don't move get him by the scruff.
Rym: Yeah, yep.
Rym: But yeah, basically that kind of knowledge like it should be more normalized.
Rym: learning that stuff Even though some of it is gross and terrifying.
Rym: It's kind of your responsibility if you're gonna have a pet to know at least like more about the pet Same as if like not to compare to a car which is a very different thing.
Rym: The car doesn't have feelings.
Rym: But if you're gonna have a car you should at least know the bare minimum about how that thing works or else it's gonna run down and break way earlier than you'd expect or you're gonna go to a Mechanic way too late.
Rym: I know a lot of money and not understand what you're paying for.
Rym: There's a lot of tragic situations where people take a pet to the vet way too late And what would have been a $50 thing is now a $3,000 thing or a very sad conversation with the family.
Scott: You know the fact that you said the word animal husbandry made me think of a nerdy thing which is in Civilization 6 the first three the first three technologies that you research in civilization 6.
Scott: It's the first three available.
Scott: And so the most basic ones are animal husbandry Mining and pottery.
Scott: right and even someone even me It's like do I know pottery?
Scott: not really?
Scott: No, it's like.
Scott: do I know mining?
Scott: Not really.
Scott: Do I know animal husbandry?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: those are the three basic one.
Scott: Yes I Don't think sib6 should be like the defining, you know, the sib6 text tree should define.
Scott: You know how we should behave as a society, but the fact that most people Self-included don't know all that much about those three basic things.
Rym: I remember what I did my thing today a while ago about a tackle block like the practical use of police like That knowledge does not exist in a lot of people's heads because they don't have to do it on a day-to-day basis.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: it's like writing might be the earliest one actually.
Rym: Oh Yeah, thea ours are our rabbits.
Rym: Oh, we only have one rabbit or movie now.
Rym: But Theo his thing was he hated his nails getting clipped and he was mad about it.
Rym: But he didn't like.
Rym: when we clipped his nails It wasn't like he'd bite us while we're clipping them like panicking or anything.
Rym: Like we'd get him clipped.
Rym: he would after the nail clipping was done like make a face and Like with malice a forethought Bite us or bite a nearby thing on purpose as an act of anger and/or revenge like it was so clearly Intentional and so clearly in response to what we had done as opposed to oh, no I'm freaking out and I bit you but more like fuck you mom and dad bite
Scott: What did?
Scott: what do bunnies do out in the wild if there's no one clipping their name?
Rym: They only live two years out in the wild at best so they don't need it.
Rym: Also, they wear him down by digging and scraping and stuff.
Scott: Why don't you give.
Scott: let him have some digging and scraping then you may even clip less often.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but it's still not enough like clip You're still gonna have to clip at some point at least.
Rym: check out him.
Scott: Give him a diggin a diggin scraping rocks and really where isn't?
Rym: actually you can't and that reduces how often you gotta gotta clip them.
Rym: But that's something people to underestimate too.
Rym: Like how long do you think a squirrel lives?
Scott: I mean judging by the fact that there was one black squirrel in the park nearby and I saw it for at least You know four or five years in a row it's got to be at least that much probably.
Scott: Yeah, they could.
Rym: they could live like especially if they don't get sick or eaten by something.
Scott: I don't think there were two black squirrels in the same tree in the same park in consecutive years and it was a different one.
Rym: a good observation.
Rym: they can live like 14 to 20 years if they're well cared for like rabbits still like in the wild.
Rym: they make it like a year Maybe two just because it's so dangerous to be a rabbit in a house.
Rym: They can live more than ten years.
Rym: Just fine Okay Put a human naked out in the woods and got to survive on your own your whole life.
Rym: Not that likely.
Rym: you're gonna make it past like 30-something probably.
Scott: Well, not a domesticated human.
Scott: but is that rabbit that lives two years in the wild like dying on its own?
Scott: or is it cuz it got eaten if Never gets?
Scott: if it if it doesn't got eaten by anything.
Scott: Yeah, how long will it go for?
Rym: Not eaten but also like malnutrition or just like they are more susceptible to illnesses when they get older just like humans are.
Rym: Like if I eat some rotting meat when I was 15 I could probably survive that if I had a bunch of rotting meat today I might not look so good compared to how I would have handled that when I was 17.
Scott: Eat some rotting meat when you're your 60s like yeah Yeah, I don't know if you know the building we're in now.
Scott: actually you can bring a pet here.
Scott: They actually only charge.
Scott: they don't.
Scott: a lot of buildings in the city They want to make you have a pet fee where you can all the time.
Scott: This building just has pet deposit where you pay one time and they just told that money like that and that's your pet doesn't?
Rym: That's fairly fair.
Scott: I'm a building is the building's full of pets.
Scott: There's you know this dog and as long as your pet doesn't make trouble they don't give a shit.
Scott: our building.
Scott: There's also a size limit.
Scott: I guess I don't know what it is.
Rym: pets are technically not allowed in our building But there are a lot of pets in our building cuz the super literally doesn't care at all.
Rym: But we're looking around.
Rym: there's some pet friendly buildings in the area and Rents are way down in this neighborhood like right now for a short time.
Scott: Yeah, I got a Yeah better leave now.
Scott: But yeah, it's like I don't know.
Scott: What do we?
Scott: you know Amanda had like corgis?
Scott: I guess her parents just keep getting more for some reason.
Scott: Yeah, because they're they're losing it.
Rym: I mean all like most ever of my family.
Rym: Just keep getting pets cuz just I don't know pet.
Scott: It's like should I get one.
Scott: It's like on the one hand.
Scott: Maybe yes, but on the other hand It's like I.
Rym: you know if you two had a pet It would be a very enriching experience cuz it's still a pain in the ass.
Scott: the problem is like a pain in the ass.
Scott: Oh, it is invention.
Scott: someone's got to watch the pet.
Rym: I mean think of it this way though like if you had a kid that's a lot more responsibility.
Scott: No, no We're not doing that.
Scott: forget that nonsense.
Rym: think about it as like it.
Rym: you get some of those kinds of benefits And some of that pain in the ass, but it's way less.
Scott: one in someone's.
Scott: one person works at night.
Scott: Yeah, it's like oh great.
Scott: So I got to take care.
Scott: I got to do all the pet taking care of is you know?
Scott: Well, we just split money's not a problem.
Scott: Yeah, like I uh, well if someone we have one imagine if you were only awake at like night.
Rym: Well, you could get a patty that is of crepuscular and is awake both times.
Scott: You got it, but you can't take it to the vet at night.
Rym: or you know, yeah You shouldn't have to take it to the vet.
Scott: that often I'm just saying is that the responsibilities of take, you know, you got you get a dog, right?
Scott: You're you're not walking it, you know, well morning, right?
Rym: Well, that's the like.
Rym: if we got a dog because one person's
Scott: doing several dog walks The other person is doing not so much
Rym: like because we both work and it's not like eventually cope It'll be a post-covid time where we're out of the house all the time Like I would probably literally drop a dog off at doggy daycare all day every day while we were at work.
Scott: It's like, you know, doggy daycare is nice.
Scott: I actually saw a photo today of like, you know the world's I Assume the world's best dog walker.
Scott: There's like the semi-famous dog walker in the city.
Scott: They walk like a huge pile of dogs at once.
Scott: It's sort of amazing, but they only they're very picky.
Scott: They're like they won't walk the dog unless it's like the best dog.
Scott: So it's like this person's walking around with like the 10 or 11 best dogs that meet their approval all at once, you know But rather more than once a day.
Rym: probably like not just because I really like rabbits like because you know Every type of animal like whatever kind of pet you're gonna get you just have to learn about that kind of animal like.
Rym: I had to learn a lot about rabbits about a decade ago when we got two little bunnies because I didn't know a lot about rabbits, but Rabbits are very Specifically good as New York pets.
Rym: just because they're silent They don't really cause a bunch of damage.
Rym: They're litter trainable.
Rym: Like they'll just you can just train them.
Rym: They'll just go in a litter box.
Rym: Just like a cat would.
Rym: Their poop doesn't smell like anything at all.
Rym: Like the poop like if their pee smells a little in the litter box.
Scott: Yeah, does your apartment?
Scott: your apartment didn't smell like poop ever.
Scott: It smelled like hay.
Rym: Yep That hay is a very fairly pleasant smell.
Rym: It's like it almost smells like matcha like.
Scott: I'd rather not smell the hay, but there's.
Scott: it's.
Scott: you know, it's not.
Scott: it's not a bad smell Like.
Rym: I mean go to like my house.
Rym: when we were kids the house smelled like dogs because we had dogs dog house.
Scott: Yeah, I would rather hay smell than dog smell but I would still rather no smell than hay smell.
Rym: Yeah, but it's just especially during COVID.
Rym: Just having a little guy like mooching around the house has been a very enriching like.
Rym: it honestly helped us Just stay sane during this whole experience.
Rym: I only worry that he's gonna be mad if we start going to work again Because he's really used to like I'll be working and he'll just like wake up and come into the computer room and be like, hey What's up?
Scott: I Didn't really work out too.
Scott: Well, but I think in our lifetime we could have a robot dog that doesn't suck.
Scott: Yeah, it's possibility.
Rym: Look at how many people are emotionally attached to their Roombas like.
Rym: seriously.
Scott: I'm not even joking like that's a thing Yeah, and it's like it's not even to say that like you might be thinking like, oh, you know You just want the robot dog because you're lazy.
Scott: It's like well, hold on a second.
Scott: There are people who are lazy who don't want to have to take care of it as much But there's also people who might need the companionship of a pet but are incapable of taking care of it.
Rym: that feels of AI driven Companion is a big field of study Especially for people who are very old who might be experiencing cognitive deficits.
Scott: I'm seeing very senior or disabled person can you know be helped a great deal by like a nice doggo Yeah, but they can't take care of the doggo.
Scott: So suddenly now if they want to have one they got to have money to have someone else take care of the doggo.
Scott: And it's like it's a whole thing.
Scott: But you know, what solves that robot doggo.
Scott: Yeah At least it has to be good enough though that it actually, you know serves the purpose.
Rym: But I uh, I think it's because having pets is also something that's very.
Rym: it's not uniquely human.
Rym: There are other animals that have done similar husbandry type things But humans like weak and well because we've killed time enough.
Rym: on this episode We co-evolved
Scott: with dogs
Rym: like we've made dogs over time like they evolved with us and we kind of made them More able to socialize with us in a really interesting weird way Which is part of why I think dogs are the most common most popular like just out there.
Rym: pet Mm-hmm cats are a decent number two.
Scott: Yeah, we got horses too.
Rym: But what about the ethical concerns?
Rym: What if you have an AI robot dog that can learn and Eventually starts to get to the level of Apparent intelligence of a small animal a real one?
Rym: then what?
Scott: Good, it'll live forever.
Scott: It'll be friggin awesome.
Rym: Yeah, but what did you?
Rym: can you throw it away now ethics start coming in?
Scott: It doesn't.
Scott: if you throw I mean, it'll be able to take care of us all.
Rym: All right, we don't even have to find food.
Rym: We killed enough time.
Rym: I'm gonna go give my little rabbit in there some pellets and a couple crazins and then I'm gonna Watch the Rangers.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I was about to say lose, but I don't know.
Rym: I don't know how this game will go.
Scott: It's the Flyers will.
Rym: probably I feel like we'll win but you know what it'll.
Rym: probably I'll bet it'll be a moderate blowout But not a crazy blowout like four to one is my game.
Rym: We really we really did bad things to them I know but I feel like they had to have studied those games like what were we doing?
Rym: But it might be like like we are with Ovi like.
Scott: well I could go so I can go so I can go watch the counter-strike world championships a thousand times.
Rym: Yeah Like everyone knows Ovi.
Rym: He's there.
Rym: He goes to that spot and then he scores a goal.
Rym: Just don't let him go to that spot.
Rym: and then they scores the goal from that spot and the coach is like What did I fucking say?
Rym: Do you want to watch the video again?
Rym: Here it is.
Rym: It's like super meat boy.
Rym: Here's 10,000 OV's overlay.
Rym: They all go to the same spot and score a goal.
Scott: anyway.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Scott: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot-com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights Heidi McNichol Allen Joyce Link Eiji dread Lily Tana break Chris Reimer Clinton Walton crane paddock old man safe That's peacock mine snack Finn.
Rym: Cram fish just like a dude guy cuz Shia Yeah, 85 Ren from New Zealand.
Rym: review mad bull 34 cowards Ryan parents Sam Erickson Sherman von Harl Taylor Braun.
Rym: You hold the key to my heart and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: I'm recording this last bit after that unfortunate hockey game ended.
Rym: Feel like the Rangers.
Rym: chances of getting to the playoffs have dropped significantly.
Rym: But anyway for now I leave you with.
Scott: So the lady drove faster, but the strange car kept banging into it from behind.
Scott: So finally she swerved off the road into the woods and lost the other car.
Scott: And that's when she realized the man in the other car wasn't trying to hurt her.
Scott: No, he was trying to warn her About the X really maniac hiding in her backseat.
Scott: That and you know how I know because I was it maniac That's it he's out of here.
Scott: Only family he's got.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: This is not happy days and he is not the funds.
Scott: Hey, mr Listen you drain clogging last cookie eating collect call getting sponge.
Rym: I want you out of my house.