Rym: It's Tuesday, June 21st, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we're talking about save games.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, that Stanley Cup is a little bit of a rollercoaster right now in this final round.
Scott: I thought it was a sure thing for Colorado, but I guess not after yesterday.
Rym: In game one, I still thought it was a sure thing, but I figured it might be like they're all kind of close games.
Rym: Game two, uh, if I were a more impulsive and less wise person, I would have been going down to one of those sports betting places and throwing my fortune at Colorado.
Scott: I mean, you know, I even, uh, I wouldn't ever bet on a sports, but I was brave enough to tweet with a broom emoji in it after when only half a broom existed.
Rym: I mean.
Scott: But I guess goodbye broom.
Scott: The broom is gone.
Scott: No more broom.
Rym: So all I can say is that the Rangers ended at a good point.
Rym: They made it to the conference finals.
Rym: I was really happy with that.
Rym: Like, that was a fun time.
Rym: Uh, but I am almost glad that the Rangers do not have to be sacrificed against the Avalanche because that second game was...
Scott: Well, we saw the Rangers did nothing against, you know, they were complete garbage against Colorado during the regular season.
Scott: They just got destroyed by them utterly.
Scott: And it's like, all right, well, why would you even, you know, we don't need to play them again to know that we can't beat them.
Rym: Yeah, but the Lightning, the games were moderately close and there was some back and forth, but the Lightning were clearly the superior team in the end.
Rym: And then to see that team lose to the Avalanche 0-7 in a Stanley Cup final game was phenomenal.
Rym: And then to have that almost completely reversed in the next game at home, the best was at the end of the game there was an interview with I think it was Tamko's.
Rym: And the question was just like, what happened?
Rym: And he was like, we play well in front of our fans.
Rym: Like, what do you want me to say?
Scott: It's like, there must be some kind of home ice thing going on in these playoffs.
Scott: More than I've ever seen it before.
Rym: Well, Carolina, they're a home team.
Rym: They're a home home team anyway.
Rym: Like, even regular season, they tend to lose away and win at home.
Rym: That's just apparently been their thing for a long time.
Scott: I don't know what's up.
Scott: I'm just setting up with it right this season with teams, you know, winning at home.
Scott: But, you know, you look, it's like, you know, I think, first of all, Colorado has home ice advantage in the series.
Scott: And second of all, Colorado did better in Tampa than Tampa did in Colorado.
Rym: I want to say I saw statistics that if you get to a game seven, home ice advantage is basically negligible.
Scott: But I've seen those same statistics.
Rym: But it can be really strong before that point.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Yeah, but I was going to write off that game and just, like, bug you guys to play turtles.
Rym: But then, the Lightning kept scoring and I felt like I had to watch it.
Scott: You know, if I'm not in it, I don't need to watch unless the Cup is there, right?
Rym: Well, at some point, there'll be games where the Cup could come out.
Scott: Yeah, and then...
Rym: There can be no more than one, two, three, four, five more games.
Scott: I've lost enough time the past few months to hockey.
Scott: I know I've got to use my time for other things, reading comics, working on Geeknight's website.
Rym: Never mind all the money.
Scott: Biking.
Rym: Though at least I think back because, you know, I've paid you all but the last, like, 500-ish bucks of the hockey money through Apple Pay.
Scott: Oh, well, you'll have to figure that out.
Rym: Yeah, I got one more payment I've got to make and I think I'm past the reset point on the money limit to you.
Rym: I also realize why it blocked me extra because I'd already sent you a bunch of money for the other thing.
Rym: That same week.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: But anyway, I think back about how much money I spent on the hockey games that me and Emily used and then I think about how much hockey enjoyment I got over the last year-ish and it feels like the right amount of money.
Rym: I got about the enjoyment I expected from that amount of money.
Scott: That's because we paid face value and not resale value.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I mean, I looked at what those tickets cost on Stuff Hub because I thought about a game we didn't have tickets to.
Rym: I wonder if I could just get a couple tickets, maybe even get a slightly better ticket.
Rym: And they weren't just, this was more like what 3080s cost at the height of crypto bullshit prices.
Rym: I got props actually to the teams, to the fact that there is a way to buy the tickets at MSRP.
Rym: Somebody gets to buy them at MSRP.
Rym: They could just auction them off and make a fortune.
Rym: But they don't.
Rym: So speaking of tickets, speaking of auctions, speaking of things that used to always sell out in the news, PAX West badges are live.
Rym: So if you intend to go to PAX West, they're live.
Rym: It is notable that nothing is sold out.
Rym: They are not at all sold out because we're still in the middle of a global pandemic.
Rym: People have not rushed back to PAX's and other conventions.
Scott: There's too many factors here, right?
Scott: There's obviously safety is still a factor, right?
Scott: Somebody died at the last PAX East.
Scott: We don't need to have, PAX is not something worth sacrificing literally any human life on the entire face of the earth.
Scott: If it's still going to be a risk of somebody dying, there is no reason to have a PAX.
Scott: It's not worth it, right?
Scott: That is, right?
Scott: So that's A.
Rym: The economy is in free fall and a lot of people who might otherwise decide to go to cons anyway, this is just PAX.
Rym: This is across the board.
Rym: This even includes vacations.
Rym: Like I got a beach house for us and our friends for later in the summer and there were way more openings than there typically are because people are canceling.
Rym: The economy is going to be a big problem for a lot of people.
Scott: Alright, well that's an issue, right?
Scott: Not to mention, it's not just the economy of people not having money.
Scott: It's the economy of like.
Scott: the plane ticket prices are way up.
Rym: Yup, well prices are across the board.
Scott: I don't know what the hotel prices are, but you know.
Rym: But at least, Seattle isn't necessarily cheap.
Rym: Some good news, a lot of other cons have dropped various mask and vaccine requirements and at least now, and I trust that PAX won't renege on this like certain other cons did and basically destroyed themselves.
Rym: The official statement on the badge buying thing is that they're still going to check full vaccination status.
Rym: They're still going to require masks at all times.
Rym: They're not changing any of their policies at all.
Scott: But yeah, it's also on top of that, it's still a question of like what is the PAX provided content at West going to be like?
Scott: How much industry is going to show up?
Scott: What kind of panels are there going to be?
Scott: It's like if the con itself is not as big and incredible, it's like it's not worth flying over for.
Scott: And especially when the flying over is more costly.
Rym: So it's like going there is harder and more dangerous and you're getting less for what you're paying.
Rym: It's like so because, you know, I was at the last two PAXes to do a panel and PAX East, the most recent one, what I could say about it is that it had all the normal things of a PAX.
Rym: And it even had mostly, nearly parity with older years, like industry presence in the panels.
Rym: But the main theater was a little sparse and the expo hall was more like an expo hall from like 2010, 2011, not like an expo hall from like 2019.
Rym: Way fewer big booths.
Rym: They were still there, but not as many.
Rym: There are plenty of space in that expo hall.
Rym: Not a lot of lines to do the stuff.
Rym: It was just generally sparse.
Rym: So if you're an expo hall only person, you'll get like 80% of a typical PAX, maybe 70%.
Scott: I mean, in terms of all, you know, I mean, if you look at what happened with E3, it's like, you know, just this past week or two, right?
Scott: All these other game companies were just sort of doing, you know, Internet announcement type event things, right?
Scott: Rather than, you know, E3 or whatever.
Rym: But worse, you know, what do I want to do?
Rym: tabletop?
Rym: And it is difficult.
Rym: It's difficult to even have a conversation in the tabletop area, as I tried to do in normal times before COVID.
Rym: But if everyone's wearing masks in that rumbling tabletop hall.
Scott: Well, in West, it's not so rumbling.
Rym: West is much better.
Rym: But at East, in that rumbling tabletop hall, nobody could hear what anyone was saying.
Rym: And it was notable how sparse the tabletop area was and how much open space there was if you were going to play tabletop games.
Scott: And I think, you know, the final thing is that, like, if I go to a convention and I'm going to spend, you know, the, you know, we used to go to when we went to anime Boston.
Scott: It's like, that's what I consider what it would be like if I was like, you know, we went to anime Boston back in the day.
Scott: We would do a lot of panels and we would attend a few panels and concerts, right?
Rym: But a few, like the high, like the top tier.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But there was very few people there who, for, you know, some of those later ones, right?
Scott: We had very few acquaintances there who were enjoying the con with us.
Scott: It was just us, right, walking around, looking around.
Scott: And we even with all that stuff, we were doing a pile of panels and going to stuff, right?
Scott: We ran out of things to do, go to the deals room artist's alley.
Scott: And then we were just like, well, all right.
Scott: So if I go to a PAX and I don't and all of my friends don't go to play tabletop games to fill in all those hours, it's like, I'm going to do a panel.
Scott: I'm going to go to panels, even if I enforce.
Rym: Emily and I saw everything at PAX East in about an hour and a half.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Even if I enforced to eat up additional hours.
Scott: And went to some panels that were like on my maybe list.
Scott: It's like they would end up being a lot of time where I'm just like sitting around waiting because I don't have a bunch of friends also there to play a constant flood of tabletop games.
Rym: At a normal PAX pick any hour of the cons open.
Rym: If I go to tabletop, I will find at least one person I know who will want to play a tabletop game right then and there.
Scott: So if the crew is not there, it's like, well, it's like there's a lot of I spent a lot of effort.
Scott: Money, time traveling to go to a thing to spend a lot of time sitting there.
Scott: It's like that's not happening.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So and yeah.
Rym: So I will very likely be there doing a couple of panels because I have some business reasons to be out there anyway.
Rym: Emily will likely also be on at least one panel or helping coordinate one TBD on all that.
Rym: But we'll be out there.
Rym: But we're not going to stick around to like hang out or play games.
Rym: So if you're there, maybe we can say hi, but we're pretty much going to be doing business.
Rym: And then GTFO.
Scott: And I mean, I imagine that's what, you know, like industry people do.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, they probably have a booth, but then they probably.
Scott: Here's the thing.
Rym: I've been to a lot of conventions, gaming cons, but also just a lot of work cons where that is what I do.
Rym: And pre covid, that was still really fun.
Rym: Even I didn't have my people in town.
Rym: I couldn't play tabletop games because grab a few people who are around or some pseudo strangers who seem cool.
Rym: Go out to dinner with them.
Rym: Hang out in a bar with them.
Rym: Go somewhere else and do a thing.
Rym: There's something in the city to do.
Rym: Walk around.
Rym: But with covid, I'm not doing indoor dining without a mask.
Rym: There's like B.A.
Rym: for B.A.
Rym: five variants that seem to like skip all immunity right now.
Scott: I mean, I stopped paying attention.
Scott: I just look at the number and I'm like, still too big.
Scott: That's all.
Scott: That's all I do.
Rym: So you don't even get the fun of like being there as an industry person, because when I travel for work, a lot of the fun I have is lavish dinners on the company dime.
Rym: And not really doing that in a covid era like outdoors.
Scott: I don't know how true this is, but I've heard whispers that the booth prices are not necessarily dramatically lowered despite lower attendance.
Rym: Well, the Pax four day badge is two hundred and thirty five dollars.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like if there's less people at the con and the con is less happening, it's like you have to lower the expo booth price.
Scott: It's like you can't keep it high, you know, even though there's inflation or whatever.
Scott: And that means prices go up.
Scott: It's like but the value of that good specifically is down.
Rym: I still don't think Pax is even about.
Scott: even if the value of money is less, the value of the good is also less.
Rym: I think cons like this in general, we'll see what happens next year.
Rym: But until we're at a point where they generally go on mass and people are as an edge.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's right to do so.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And as an aggregate, people are comfortable with that and accept that cons are not going to be back to normal.
Rym: And I don't think twenty twenty three, they're going to be back to normal either, to be honest.
Scott: If the booth price went down, though, then I could consider getting a tiny booth at a con where all my friends were not there.
Scott: Because I would have this booth to enjoy the con with.
Rym: Yeah, I had a good time.
Rym: That one that had that one Otakon where we had an artist alley table for GeekNights.
Scott: I think we you know, we would do a much better job if we had a booth now.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: We were we were dumb idiot babies back then.
Rym: We had no idea what we were doing.
Rym: Though we made a shit ton of money selling those T-shirts anyway.
Rym: Anyway, relative to how much money I had at the time, that was a pretty good stack of cash.
Rym: Anyway, also the profit margin on those are old old night T-shirts because I got them screen printed direct.
Rym: I paid like a dollar eighty per shirt.
Rym: We were selling it for twenty bucks and I sold a couple hundred of them.
Rym: That was a good amount of money anyway.
Scott: So other news.
Scott: Street Fighter six is announced.
Scott: It's coming at some point.
Scott: And there's a lot of stuff going on with it.
Scott: You know, they're not afraid to make big changes and whatnot.
Scott: But there's one part of the Street Fighter six news I want to focus on.
Scott: And that is that they've added what's basically easy baby mode.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And what this means, if you never played Street Fighter is the controls of Street Fighter.
Scott: You got to stick right.
Scott: You know, forward, back, crouch, jump, et cetera.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then you got six buttons.
Scott: Light, medium, heavy in both punch and kick.
Scott: So six buttons, light, light punch, like kick, et cetera.
Scott: The new control scheme.
Scott: Now, this is not to be right.
Scott: So we're clear.
Scott: You can still use the old control scheme.
Scott: I'm one hundred percent confident that in any competitive scene and in any professional player and any seriously competitive player, they will still be using the original control scheme and it will still work as it always did.
Scott: And they might not even let you use the easy one.
Rym: It's probably, probably definitely won't based on what I've learned about it so far.
Rym: I suspect even if tournaments did, if you are not great at Street Fighter and you try to use the modern control type, you will still get crushed fighting with class.
Scott: I assume the modern control type.
Scott: It basically, even if you use it, it seems just worse than using the correct or traditional control map.
Rym: But easier and more accessible for the player and people like me who are preternaturally terrible at all fighting games, except Bushido Blade two and Soul Calibur two, but even Soul Calibur only if I'm playing Voldo.
Scott: Anyway, so the new control scheme, the modern control type, which is basically designed for people who suck ass at fighting games.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But want to be able to play and actually do some special moves.
Scott: What they've done is most game pads, which is what people are going to be using.
Scott: They don't have fight sticks, right?
Scott: Have four buttons on the front.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's always been annoying as far back as Street Fighter two turbo for SNES to try to play with regular Street Fighter because you had to map like two of the attacks to the LNR buttons or some shit.
Scott: And like Sega Genesis and Saturn had the six button controllers, but not anything after that.
Scott: PlayStation, nothing, right?
Scott: GameCube, forget about it.
Scott: So what they've done is they said, all right, you only got four buttons instead of six.
Scott: What are we going to do?
Scott: Well, we'll take three of the buttons and we'll make one of them light, one of the medium and one of them heavy.
Rym: Notice Scott did not say punch or kick.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You won't know when you push the button if it's going to be a punch or a kick.
Scott: You have no control over that whatsoever.
Scott: It'll be dependent on your character, what they're doing, how close to the enemy they are, et cetera, et cetera.
Scott: But you basically push the heavy attack button and they might do heavy punch.
Scott: They might do heavy kick.
Scott: You don't know.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And how much does it matter?
Scott: Well, if you're a professional, that's unusable.
Scott: But if it's just you and your friends who suck at fighting games and you both suck and you're both using that mode, that's actually going to make it a much more enjoyable game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then the final button is a fourth button.
Scott: What do they do with that button?
Scott: Well, what they've done is they've turned it into much like the B button in Smash Brothers where it's the special attack button.
Scott: So you press the B button and depending on where the stick is pointing, you know, and things of that nature, all your different special moves will come out.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like if it's Ryu, I'm just going to guess here and say that, like, you know, special forward would do a Haruken.
Scott: Special up would do a Shoryuken.
Scott: Special down or special back would do the Hurricane kick.
Scott: Something like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Something, you know, that's my guess of what it would be like with this special mode.
Scott: Now that that in a professional setting is just cheating and should not be allowed.
Scott: But for someone like me, where half the time I try to do Haruken and it doesn't come out, that makes the game playable.
Scott: Basically.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So it's, you know, Haruken is just hit the special button.
Scott: Oh, it's just plain B.
Rym: Shoryuken is stick to the right.
Rym: High blade kick is stick down.
Rym: It's that that's what's going on here.
Rym: I was close.
Scott: I was close.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, but you get the idea.
Rym: So I should play this and just be a flowchart.
Scott: So, I mean, I think that, yeah, I think what this, you know, is, is like.
Scott: we're often, you know, as people who played FPS, we're better at them than we are fighting games by a large, large margin, even though we're not even that good at FPS.
Scott: Compared to pros.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Is that, you know, we're always like, oh, you got to use keyboard and mouse.
Scott: It's like this.
Scott: And it's like, it's true.
Scott: Keyboard and mouse is superior.
Scott: Someone is not using keyboard and mouse will just lose to you.
Scott: It's right.
Scott: It's just better.
Scott: But it is also less accessible.
Scott: It is easier to play an FPS with a gamepad and auto aim.
Scott: It's just you won't be as good.
Rym: Case in point, that's how most people play Fortnite, but they don't match those people with people who have a mouse and keyboard.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, you know, while I would never, you know, argue that like, oh, the gamepad way is better or the right way or anything like that, I've also never going to say that it shouldn't exist.
Scott: Like, it's like, let the other people who are not as good, not mouse and keyboard people, not don't have PCs or whatever, let them have access to these games.
Scott: Maybe that's how they find out that they enjoy them so much and then will upgrade.
Scott: Then they enter the competitive scene or if they don't enter the competitive scene.
Scott: OK, well, they're going to be playing perfectly happily in their noncompetitive scene with other people just like themselves.
Scott: OK, go right ahead.
Scott: You're not bothering anybody doing that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So for that to be added to Street Fighter is now taking a game.
Scott: You know, even if you know what, you know, it's like.
Scott: even if almost nobody who plays with modern control scheme ever upgrades to regular, you know, how many people only play mini golf and never actually play serious golf.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like you're still going to allow a whole generation of people now to enjoy Street Fighter, who might not have ever played a Street Fighter, you know, alternatively.
Scott: Enjoy all the people who are Street Fighter pros who know that six buttons is the one true way.
Scott: And they're right.
Scott: Are going to continue to play with six buttons and you can just ignore all the four button people.
Scott: So what do they give a shit?
Rym: And this will call this will be a nice stepping stone, because I think what this will do a big problem in fighting.
Scott: I think it might hurt as a stepping stone, because like if you get used to four button and really enjoy the game and then try to go to six, you basically starting from nothing.
Rym: They actually talk about that.
Rym: They have designed it to be a stepping stone in that some of the like, if you do a grab and a few other things, if you input real controls, they will also work.
Rym: And they've designed it.
Scott: Oh, so you can still do a hadook in the old way.
Rym: I'm not 100 percent sure on the details here.
Rym: I'm reading into like a paragraph worth of an interview with someone who works there.
Rym: But they were talking about it.
Rym: And basically they're hoping that it will be a stepping stone to get people to understand the basic interplay of the game.
Rym: Kind of like how you don't teach someone how to play, say, hearts by immediately getting into the passing strategy.
Rym: You teach them, avoid the hearts, like the basic strategies of the game, the basic give and take of the game.
Rym: So this will teach people and let them experience the real give and take of the game before they have to back up and learn all this technical nonsense.
Rym: We'll see how it goes.
Rym: I think it's a noble experiment.
Scott: I hope it succeeds because I can't say that I'll buy it or I'll play it.
Scott: Just because, you know, I have too many things going on in life already.
Scott: I'm trying to cut things out.
Scott: But it is, you know, interesting.
Scott: I would definitely love to like, you know, if I was in a place that had the game set up, I would love to try it with the old control scheme and see what's what.
Rym: You know, if only we could go to PAX, that's the kind of thing I would go poke at.
Scott: Yeah, for sure.
Scott: At the Capcom booth.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So in some other news, you can read this article if you want to know more about what happened.
Rym: But basically, so I own a modest amount of Hasbro stock.
Rym: Full disclosure, that's part of my direct investment portfolio.
Rym: This is not investment advice.
Rym: I'm not saying you should buy it, but that is what I have bought is a significant percentage of my non-retirement investing.
Rym: And as a result, I get to vote in the shareholder meetings and I don't have that many shares.
Rym: But an election happened in the board that was controversial and tricky and a big deal enough to where I didn't just get the normal emails and texts and people calling me trying to get my proxy vote, like which card to vote on.
Rym: Because I get that all the time.
Rym: Most people who buy.
Rym: if you have like one share of something on like TD or something, very likely you'll get a low level amount of harassment to make sure you vote with the board or whatever, whenever there's a shareholder election, because that's low hanging fruit.
Rym: But there's an activist investor, Alta Fox, which is basically a capital management.
Scott: This is public information.
Scott: You can just read articles about this.
Rym: But they're basically like this capital management company.
Rym: They're similar to the kind of company that like gutted Toys R Us.
Rym: They're, in my personal opinion, they as a company are bad news.
Scott: Isn't that private equity, the Toys R Us game?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I don't want to get into all the technical details of how this all works, but here's what they did.
Rym: They bought a huge stake in Hasbro, like 2.5% of all the outstanding stock.
Scott: They bought it.
Rym: And then they started pressuring the board to do a bunch of bullshit, which mostly came down to spin.
Scott: They only have 2.5%.
Scott: That's 97.5%.
Scott: That's against them.
Rym: Because the way this works is that that stake will vote the way they want.
Rym: And then they go after all the other shareholders to try to convince those shareholders that if they help them take over the company, they'll make the stock price grow, like they'll make the company better and make us more money.
Rym: And they basically proposed this weird nonsense about taking Wizards of the Coast, splitting it off into its own company, and radically restructuring how Hasbro works.
Scott: I have noticed a lot of companies splitting things off lately, right?
Scott: You had AT&T split off WB, and just like today or the other day, Kellogg's split off their cereal from everything else that Kellogg's owns.
Scott: There must be something that's happening that's causing these split offs to happen for some reason.
Rym: So in my personal experience, not speaking to any particular split up, I'm going to be very clear about that.
Rym: Usually what's going on is in a tight economy, the split lines will be along, some of the bits will be likely very profitable, and some of the bits are very risky.
Rym: And the smart people or the well-connected people are all going to stick with the bits that are likely to make money, and it's a way to basically quietly get rid of the stuff that isn't that profitable or that you're a little worried about.
Rym: Also get rid of your low performing employees at the same time without actually firing them.
Rym: That kind of conversation is not uncommon, is what I'm going to say.
Rym: But there are a lot of other reasons this could happen.
Rym: You might want to split one off because you want to sell it because you think the market will give you more money than it's worth.
Rym: Or you want that money to do something else with one of your other divisions.
Rym: There's a lot of ways this could go.
Rym: But long story short, they failed, obviously, this company, they did not succeed.
Rym: But they were trying to take advantage of some turmoil in the board of directors of Hasbro around someone dying, someone leaving, the stock not growing that much.
Rym: And Hasbro's board was like, look, we know toys, we know what we're doing.
Rym: Yeah, the stock hasn't grown.
Rym: Dipshits, we pay dividends.
Rym: We pay dividends.
Rym: They're good dividends.
Rym: God damn it.
Rym: I'm obviously paraphrasing and putting words in their mouths, but that's basically what they said.
Rym: And they issued a statement that was like, look, kind of like in The Simpsons when you could vote for Homer to be the trash commissioner or the guy who knew what he was doing.
Rym: They were like, look, if you want Hasbro to keep doing what it's been doing and not fuck up, vote for the existing board.
Rym: But if you want these jackasses to ruin everything, by all means.
Rym: And these jackasses went so far, they were really trying to make this happen.
Rym: They were calling my relatives.
Rym: They called Emily's mom on her landline.
Rym: They called my father.
Rym: They tried to call my dead grandfather.
Rym: They were going after people associated with me in any way because I had not yet voted.
Rym: So I figured out which side was doing this.
Rym: And it was the dipshit Alta Fox people.
Rym: So I pointedly voted against them, irrespective of everything else.
Scott: That's one of those rare cases.
Scott: Usually when I have a vote, it's like, you know, for a stock thing, I have so few shares, it doesn't mean anything.
Scott: But I always vote against usually what the board wants because the board is usually old white capitalist dudes.
Rym: Usually I vote against a lot of the board things because I want younger people to be in charge of these companies.
Scott: But it's a rare instance, I guess, where it's like, OK, there is something worse than...
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So I fell in love with this channel and it's basically this guy whose job is to go around, I think Berlin.
Rym: So he's in Germany, unclogging stormwater gullies and storm drains and like...
Scott: Wasn't there, didn't we do a thing of the day on a guy like this already?
Rym: That guy is different.
Rym: That guy was like culverts.
Rym: And it seems like he's more of a hobbyist.
Rym: Like some of them, he just finds one and does it.
Rym: Because he wants to see it happen.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: He's just doing it on his own.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: This is a very different type of video.
Rym: This video is a half hour long.
Rym: This is start to finish what it looks like.
Rym: One, if you are doing labor in a reasonable, relatively socialist country that respects the dignity of your labor and pays people a reasonable wage to do very critical work that is usually ignored by tech people.
Rym: And two, someone who clearly very much cares about his job.
Rym: And over this half hour, you see exactly what it takes to unclog a stormwater gully that has gotten some roots in it.
Rym: And you see the entire process in real time.
Rym: And it is fascinating.
Rym: Also, Berlin's civic infrastructure is so nice compared to anything I have ever seen in America that I weep.
Scott: I mean, yeah.
Rym: And it is so satisfying when he finally gets those roots out of there and you see the water flowing through the gully again.
Scott: I mean, I think that's the real key with these videos is the satisfying part, right?
Rym: But the process on this one is good, too, because the satisfying part, it is 27 minutes of just edging and waiting for it.
Rym: And at the very end, you get it.
Rym: But at several points as you're watching, you might think like I did, why doesn't he just do X?
Rym: You're watching him.
Rym: You're like, it seems like he's moving really slow.
Rym: Just just fucking go for it.
Rym: But then a little while later, he'll make it get to the next step of the process, like he'll remove something.
Rym: And then you'll see, oh, if I had tried to unblock this, I would have just broken a bunch of shit because I didn't know what I was doing.
Rym: There is a lot of skill and knowledge that's required for this.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: So this dude, he, you know, pay phones, I think they removed the last public pay phones in Manhattan.
Rym: Oh, they did.
Rym: There's the whole thing about it.
Rym: You could you could go.
Rym: There was a bunch of people watching the ceremony when they pulled it away.
Scott: Anyway, at least the last working ones.
Scott: I've seen some non-working ones about.
Scott: I know where they are.
Scott: There's some that like have no handles and don't work, obviously, but I've seen them anyway.
Scott: So this dude got a pay phone.
Scott: You know, it's not hard to get one.
Scott: You go on eBay or whatever and buy one.
Scott: There's plenty of them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You could buy all kinds of old shit like that.
Scott: And he wanted to hook it up in his house for for fun.
Scott: Obviously, he wasn't going to hook it up to the actual landline and fucking call people.
Scott: It's like, why would you do that?
Scott: That makes no sense.
Scott: And also, no one knows that number.
Scott: And also, what if someone does know that number?
Scott: Some of these pay phones ring you real loud in your house.
Scott: You don't want that.
Scott: What he did is he got a device that seems obvious in retrospect, but I never really thought of it before.
Scott: But what it is, it's basically just a little box with two, you know,
Scott: R.J.,
Scott: whatever connectors are 11, if I recall correctly.
Scott: Yeah, we just you just plug two phones into it.
Scott: And guess what?
Scott: You've now got yourself a two telephone phone system.
Scott: You pick up one phone and it calls the other phone and you pick up the other phone and it calls the other phone.
Scott: So you could just have two phones in your house that call each other.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And so he put the pay phone on the wall in like the kitchen or wherever is some kind of living area.
Scott: And the other end, he got the cool, clear, plastic, you know, 90s phone.
Rym: That phone was so great.
Rym: Like everyone I knew had that phone.
Scott: Yeah, he just bought one of those on eBay for a few bucks and put it in his daughter's room.
Scott: So now a few times a day, the daughter, you know, she's like, you know, a child picks up the phone and it rings.
Scott: And, you know, dad can get up from work and pick up the phone and talk to his offspring.
Rym: It's cool because there was in the 70s, late 60s through mid 70s, the thing that was really popular in American house design was intercom systems.
Rym: There would be intercoms in like every major room of the house.
Rym: And you could just like call other parts of the house.
Rym: And that stopped being a thing because in retrospect, it was really silly unless you had a really big house.
Scott: I mean, I have it.
Scott: I could just, it's only useful for talking to the door person and the person who someone's trying to get in the front door.
Rym: I have it too.
Rym: But you know what it is now?
Rym: I can just message Emily on Discord on her phone that she's got with her.
Rym: Like I have my phone with me no matter what.
Scott: This person's child, this person's child is not phone age, but also just the novelty of this.
Rym: Also, I got to say scrolling through this thing of the day, that thing looks so slick on his wall.
Scott: They installed it properly.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I kind of want one now.
Scott: I've seen a lot of people install them, for example, like in a basement that has, you know, a pool table and a payphone and a gumball machine.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, and all those sorts of things going on together to make like a cool, you know, recreational room kind of deal, aesthetic going on.
Rym: So like if I was rich enough to have an apartment big enough to have an arcade in it, like a small aesthetic arcade, I would definitely have a payphone on the wall.
Scott: A jukebox would go in there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, all that kind of stuff.
Rym: It's cool, Biz.
Rym: In the matter of a moment, the Geek Times Book Club book is Nine Fox Gambit.
Rym: I am more than halfway through the second book in that series.
Rym: And all I got to say is, you know how many times you read the first book?
Rym: and I give a little warning about the second book?
Rym: I really like the second book so far.
Rym: Like it just keeps going.
Rym: It picks up.
Rym: It picks up seconds after the end of the first book.
Scott: I imagine that's what was going to happen.
Rym: But not too far into it, you will encounter first the incest twins.
Scott: Uh oh.
Scott: That's not good.
Rym: That is extremely, extremely direct.
Rym: It is unambiguous.
Rym: It is just like, by the way, reader, I present this to you.
Rym: These are two very major characters.
Rym: You will not get away from them.
Rym: And this is going to be a thing.
Scott: And they're twins and they fuck each other?
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Scott: There's biological twins for the same parents?
Rym: One of them is a hexarch.
Rym: And one of them is basically the brother who they grew up together as a child together.
Rym: And he has gotten plastic surgery to be identical to the hexarch and acts as his body double.
Rym: But also, they fucking... And everybody knows it.
Rym: Everybody's cool with it.
Scott: Oh wait.
Scott: But they're not actually twins.
Scott: They're just brothers.
Scott: They're biological brothers.
Scott: Okay, so it's still incest, but they're not biological identical twins.
Scott: No.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: It's still bad though.
Rym: It's not the Prince of Nothing situation, but it's there.
Rym: And two, if you thought the violence that is depicted in the first book was squeaky, strap in in the second book.
Rym: Because they start going after the heffen.
Rym: And as much as you might think from the first book that the heffen, "Alright, they're against the hexarchs, so how bad could they
Rym: be?".
Rym: They are not great.
Rym: And I'll leave it at that.
Rym: They are.
Scott: I thought they were going to be the good democratic people.
Rym: No, the democratic people are just the heretics on that one fortress.
Rym: The heffen have their own motives.
Rym: The hexarchs are like, "What the fuck is wrong with the heffens?
Rym: God
Rym: damn.".
Rym: Even the cow.
Scott: The cow.
Scott: So basically the hexarch...
Rym: I'm going to spiritually quote Judeo and also one of the actual hexarchs.
Rym: What the fuck is wrong with the heffen?
Scott: So the hexarchs are the Marquis de Cat, but the heffen are... They're not the green forest folk.
Rym: No, they're more like the birds.
Scott: The birds?
Scott: Oh, damn.
Rym: Actually, no, they're more like the lizards, I gotta say.
Rym: The lizard folk?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Their technology is gross and terrifying, but oddly compelling.
Scott: But otherwise, the night fox... What's their calendar look like?
Rym: No one can figure that out because it's so different.
Rym: But basically, so a 12-year-old child and a bird and some moss together and then make them play Cat's Cradle and that's how their calendar technology works.
Scott: Uh-oh.
Rym: And I am not being figurative.
Rym: But anyway, night fox gambit is great and it's the GeekNights Book Club book.
Rym: The next Thursday show, we're going to do it.
Rym: However, this coming Thursday might have to skip the show because the Asifa... There's an LGBTQ+ film festival, an animation film festival that we used to go to every year during Pride around this time of year.
Scott: Until one time.
Rym: I go every year.
Rym: The rest of us go every year.
Scott: I went to it one time.
Rym: You're the only one who only went once.
Rym: The rest of us go every year.
Rym: It's a thing.
Scott: How many times is every year?
Scott: Two times?
Scott: Four?
Scott: I think four.
Rym: It started before then, but I didn't know about it.
Rym: But it is at like 7 p.m.
Rym: at that same bar with the outdoor area and I'll post a link to it.
Rym: Very, very likely to be there with most of my crew.
Rym: We'll see if Scott is also there.
Scott: Depends on the... I think the weather is going to determine.
Scott: It's going to rain for the next few days.
Rym: If it's pouring rain, I might opt out as much as I love this festival.
Rym: I don't want to bike in pouring rain.
Scott: I did see some good animations the one time I went.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I would like to go.
Rym: I still think back to that one that was just a collection of the dark network of gay porn that was passed around in the early BBS eras.
Rym: That was a fascinating film.
Rym: But otherwise, Scott's been working on the website.
Rym: We're getting close.
Rym: It's coming.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: The only con that GeekNights will have any presence at for the foreseeable future is going to be PAX West and likely it's going to be just me.
Rym: And I don't really have anything else.
Rym: I don't know what we're going to do about Magfest.
Rym: I feel like it's still going to be too soon to go to a con like that.
Scott: I am somewhat hopeful for PAX Unplugged.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: The thing is I highly doubt PAX is going to remove the masking requirement and I can't imagine enough of our friends are going to be excited about getting into an expo hall to play tabletop games and masks versus just gathering at one of our houses that same weekend and playing games comfortably.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: A lot of factors there.
Rym: Let's just dive right into it.
Rym: Save games.
Scott: Never talked about this.
Scott: Thank you listener for this good show idea for once.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, that listener most of the time gives episode ideas that I have to shoot down, but occasionally has an amazing show idea and saves us a lot of effort and thinking of a show idea.
Scott: Good job.
Scott: Save games.
Scott: So we often joke.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because we're so old to the younger people.
Scott: We say I got save games older than you, kid.
Rym: And like, yeah, I literally have a save game from 1987.
Rym: That is it is still good because not that long ago I put that Final Fantasy one cartridge in and it still worked into a real NES.
Scott: So video games.
Scott: Right.
Scott: When they were new, they started out, you know, being, you know, arcade games, oscilloscopes, primitive computers, 70s, you know, 60s, 70s, 80s.
Scott: And there was no way for those games to save anything other than the high score.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The high score list.
Scott: That was it.
Scott: A very small amount of storage because old computers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Nowadays, we're like blessed with amazing storage capacity.
Scott: We have SSDs.
Scott: We got big giant magnetic spinning disk that hold terabytes of data.
Rym: I got a 30 terabyte NAS up above me.
Scott: We have cloud services like S3 that just have a ridiculous petabytes of storage capacity.
Scott: It's like it's, you know, but in the earliest days of computing, storage was actually the most limited, most expensive, difficult part.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like you would get this computer, you know, had transistors or vacuum tubes or who knows what and what kind of storage, a magnetic tape that was really slow and could barely hold anything.
Rym: Many times.
Rym: Nothing.
Scott: A lot of early computers.
Scott: That held like a kilobyte.
Rym: A lot of early computers.
Rym: You would load programs into it via some means like a cassette or more likely.
Rym: A paper tape.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: With holes in it.
Rym: And the best you could do is output to that same medium, which was challenging, especially in the early days.
Rym: Right.
Scott: They were slow.
Scott: They were unreliable.
Scott: They were cumbersome.
Scott: They were, you know, go on YouTube and find videos of people like setting up super old computers.
Scott: And like the whole beginning process is just like typing in a program by hand in order to get the computer to load a program from a storage device like a magnetic tape or a paper tape that can only be read linearly in one direction and not written to.
Rym: It's like storage sucked on old computers, basically, which meant early games, early arcade games, that high score list, almost every old arcade game, if you unplug it, that list is instantly gone because they couldn't actually store them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the storage devices were big, loud, cumbersome, slow and expensive for a long time.
Scott: And therefore, any game that wanted to save anything would typically use what's known as SRAM.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Your computers today have DRAM, dynamic RAM, which if you want to know how it works, look it up.
Scott: But static RAM is basically just flip flops.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which is just a few transistors.
Rym: You don't know what those are.
Rym: There's an ancient episode of GeekNights where we explain what a flip flop is in basic electronics.
Scott: You can also go on YouTube and probably find a thousand videos showing you what a flip flop is.
Rym: The name is descriptive.
Rym: They can flip and flop between states.
Scott: One flip flop is basically a storage device that holds one bit of data, zero or one.
Scott: And it's very small and you can have a lot of them and they don't use a lot of electricity.
Scott: So in the earliest computers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, you could flip flops were basically, you know, the storage device of choice.
Scott: But there's still RAM.
Scott: You still have to provide power to keep them on.
Scott: If the power gets cut, they lose everything.
Rym: So your RAM and your computer uses actually a surprising amount of power because it is constantly refreshing the data that's in it or it'll literally disappear.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, so the arcade machines and the NES games that had, you know, batteries in them and whatnot, they were using SRAM chips to hold some small amount of data in memory and remember it as long as the battery didn't die or the power didn't get cut.
Scott: And then if if if the power was lost, that's a good buy.
Scott: save game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The only way to have like a more permanent save game was like the Famicom disk system.
Scott: Or if you are PC gaming in those early days and you had disk drives and extra disks to save your save games onto, which were not cheap, were not easy generally.
Scott: And it's like those that was not for most people.
Scott: Most people did not experience save games until like, you know, the Super Nintendo, the Genesis, those both had some games also that use batteries and SRAM.
Scott: So did the GBA, you know, the Game Boy a little bit.
Scott: But real save games didn't really come about until PlayStation had memory cards pretty much.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Though there was an era and the end PCs had and when PCs had more hard drives.
Rym: Though there was an era with especially cartridges like the NES, there were the games that had the little battery in them.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I'm saying, that those are SRAM just saying yes, but you couldn't save that much on those.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like there was very.
Scott: the amount of data you could save was very small and very limited.
Scott: But case in point, Pokemon for the Game Boy had so much like compression technology going on so that they could actually save your game.
Scott: And like you could, you know, it could remember what was in the PC and what was in which box in the PC.
Scott: and what with the?
Scott: you customize the names of your Pokemon, you nickname them.
Scott: It's like they were pushing it to the limit with that.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But NES games that did not do it this way had a way to save games by put by saving them on a physical piece of paper that you as a kid would write down a code of some kind.
Rym: If you ever used a code to resume your progress on an old video game, that code was just literally what would have been stored into that SRAM if you had that in the chip.
Rym: So basically it was getting you as a kid to save the game yourself.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: And it's, you know, when the amount of data that was being saved was very small and could be encoded in a clever manner, like the way Mega Man games.
Rym: I was going to bring up Mega Man because I remember when I figured out how to give myself an E-Tank.
Scott: Yeah, with the dot grid.
Scott: Well, I just I just had from magazines and friends, I had the codes that took you to Wiley with full everything.
Scott: But yeah, it's like, you know.
Rym: But think about this.
Rym: It's interesting because on one hand, a kid playing, you think, well, I saved my game.
Rym: This is my password.
Rym: But having mornosis, you realize that anyone who got to game to that same state would get the same password.
Rym: It's not saving your game.
Rym: It is just an encoding of a state of the game in on a philosophical level.
Rym: Save games are just saving the state of a game.
Rym: And the explosion of storage technology and computing technology got us to a point to where games could have extremely complex and persistent states that were not possible previously.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, the capacity for saving a game actually created, you know, that technological advancement changed games themselves.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like if you couldn't save the game, then basically you had to design a game where where every time you played, you were starting from the same place.
Scott: And the game would be enjoyable to replay, even though you were always starting from the same place every single time and redoing whatever it was you were redoing at the beginning every single time.
Scott: So you wouldn't want to make a game that was, you know, where all the good parts were at the end and no one would ever reach them or a game with like a lot of stories and chapters.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, I guess you could let the player just choose their chapter, but it's like that means you're going to have to let someone just start on the last chapter if they want to.
Scott: Nothing you could do about it.
Scott: You know, you guess you could have cheat codes that'll bring up the, you know, various level selects, but that's basically the same thing as a password.
Scott: So, yeah, once save games became a thing and there was more data that was able to be saved, games like Pokmon, all those JRPGs primarily were the first ones, I think, that really took advantage of having a long game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Where, you know, you would start and, you know, where you left off Final Fantasy 1, whatever.
Scott: And without that ability to save, those games are unplayable.
Scott: Nobody is going to beat any of those in one sitting ever unless they're a complete wacko.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I had a few games I liked as a kid that did not have any saving capacity and I was never able to beat them until emulators because I couldn't sit there that long.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: What are you going to do, pause the game and just leave the NES on like all night?
Rym: I tried that a few times.
Rym: Didn't always work.
Scott: Or even if you could, it's like, okay, but you get to the hard part, you got your one shot at the hard part, you try to do it, you fail.
Scott: And it's like, okay, well, I just need to practice that hard part a few times, but to get another practice shot, you have to get through the whole game again.
Scott: It's like, if you can save, at least you can load your save and just keep trying the hard part over and over until you get it and not have to keep redoing all the other parts every single time.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now this opened up a lot of the games that we like today, like a game like Civilization.
Rym: Well, you're going to play that over weeks, possibly.
Rym: You couldn't save your game, save the state.
Rym: It's a game over, literally.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's hard to even think, you know, even today, games that are not in themselves a long game, they still end up having lots of things that you save, right?
Scott: Unlocked characters or, you know.
Rym: Well, look at the new Turtles game that we'll talk about in a future episode.
Rym: It has a stateful and a stateless mode.
Rym: You can play it the normal story mode where you'll unlock stuff and like there's some sort of progression.
Rym: But you can also put it in arcade mode where it's basically, you've got X continues, X lives, it's completely stateless, go notched, it's just like the old days.
Rym: And I appreciate that.
Rym: Game design has changed a lot and I think there's a lot of things we can talk about in terms of how saving games and save states and all these things can affect game design.
Rym: For example, a lot of games use the concept of you can only save at certain points, which becomes a checkpointing system in a sense.
Rym: So like early Final Fantasy games, you'd often have a save point and then an arduous quest like get into that marsh cave, get the crown and get back out.
Rym: And you got to finish that entire quest in one go.
Rym: if you don't make it out before you can't save your game.
Scott: Yeah, now some of that does, like you just said, stem from, you know, a good or maybe sometimes not so good game design concept, right?
Rym: Because that adds a sense of peril.
Scott: Before a boss fight and after a boss fight and whatnot, right?
Scott: But also in not wanting to let the player, like if you just let them save whenever, well, they might, you know, be one bad guy, save, jump on a goomba, save and like slowly beat the game that way.
Scott: But they also stem from a technological limitation in that if you let someone just save in any old place, right, it's like, well, that's a lot more data that you have to save in the save file.
Scott: Like where did they save?
Scott: What was the state of the game when they saved?
Scott: And by having specific save spots, it's like, okay, you could have these discrete spots where saving happens.
Scott: You don't need to account for situations where they might save in some weird spot or, and you can clearly encode like, you know, which save spot did they save in?
Scott: They saved in save spot number seven.
Scott: It only takes up one space in the memory to figure out where the character should be in the game.
Scott: If you don't have that, well, now you need to encode the full location of the character.
Scott: They were in level seven at this coordinate and this coordinate, right?
Scott: It's, it might not be that much more data depending on the game, but it could be more.
Scott: And it was very much at a premium in those early computers, you know, systems of how much data you could save.
Rym: And nowadays there are basically zero technical limitations on how saving and suspending and all these different things work.
Rym: So now anything you encounter, except in extremely esoteric situations are going to be game design decisions.
Rym: And at this point, the intersection of game design and accessibility and playability becomes a very dynamic and changing and interesting space that we, there's no way we can fully cover in one episode of GeekNights.
Rym: For example, some games, the idea of permadeath, let's forget the history of where it came from.
Rym: So nowadays you can make a game where you can save your game, keep going, save your game, go eat dinner, load the save file, play again.
Rym: But if you die, all those save files get deleted because you want the concept of permadeath, permanent death.
Rym: Slay the Spire is an example of this.
Rym: You can stop playing at any time and save your game.
Rym: Like if you're busy, house is on fire.
Rym: You don't keep playing Slay the Spire, like pause the game, save it and leave.
Rym: But you can only load a save file once effectively.
Rym: So you can't save the game, try something, fail, go back, load the save file, try it again.
Scott: Well, except you can because if, you know, not officially, but it's just a file on your computer.
Scott: You could go and just move the file, copy it and then copy it back into position.
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: Cheat, basically.
Rym: And as well, we've always said, unless there's competition involved, there's no such thing as cheating in a single player game.
Rym: So play however you want.
Rym: That's why I do applaud the fact that permadeath type things still exist, because I think they do serve as a very interesting challenge, that an interesting aspect of parallel to games.
Rym: But I like the idea that you can opt out of that.
Rym: And since you could fuck with the game anyway by hacking it or cheating in some fashion, why not just make it an option that you could turn off in a single player game?
Rym: And a lot of games do that.
Scott: Well, that's true.
Scott: There are some options, especially a permadeath option that, you know, games will let the player choose, because obviously there's no point in forcing that on someone.
Rym: But if that game is a competitive game with a ladder, you can't do that.
Scott: Well, maybe it depends.
Scott: But here's the thing.
Scott: You could take that argument even further.
Scott: A save file is just data in a file, right?
Scott: For example, I loaded up some old gold box D&D games on GOG, right?
Scott: And it's just the save file is just a fucking file.
Scott: So and you're like you're sitting there like rolling your character's stats.
Scott: I didn't do that.
Scott: I rolled up characters with random stats.
Scott: I opened up the save file in a hex editor.
Rym: Oh, look, suddenly 18 strength, 18 charisma, 18 dexterity.
Rym: 18?
Scott: You mean 99 strength, 99 charisma, 99 dex as the highest number that would fit in the file without breaking the game.
Scott: Oh, let me just give myself all the best equipment and a million HP.
Scott: And it's, you know.
Scott: Thank you for saving us, SOH character.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: so, you know, it's like trying to prevent if as soon as you have a save file in some way, trying to prevent the player from having full control over what's in that save file is just sort of like you're just taking advantage of their technological, lack of technological prowess.
Rym: It is effort.
Rym: Like if you're on a Nintendo Switch playing a game that has a permadeath option and you turn that option off, what percentage of people would bother to try to recover that save file?
Rym: Well, if it's a no.
Scott: But if it's an option, then there's no point.
Scott: But if you're making a JRPG today, for example, I would argue that not only if you want let's say you want to have permadeath in your JRPG for some reason.
Scott: OK, go ahead.
Scott: Make an option for that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But why not have also an option for literally everything that's in the save file?
Scott: Let them choose which save spot they're at, which characters are in the party, what their levels are.
Rym: And a lot of games do this, even if it's not super well documented with the debugger mode.
Rym: A lot of games have a debug mode you can access in game if you know what to do.
Scott: Give the give the players a save editor.
Scott: Almost no one does that.
Scott: There's plenty of save editors that, you know, people have made.
Rym: Civilization games were notable in the early days that they documented all of this and encouraged you to fuck around.
Scott: Yes, though very few.
Scott: But the vast majority of games do not expect the player to even realize that save editing is a possibility.
Scott: But it very much is pretty much for every save game ever.
Scott: And I think that we should make save editing more accessible.
Scott: It's like if it's a single player game, who cares?
Scott: If someone was wants to see the game ending, it's like they could see it on YouTube.
Scott: What does it matter if they used to edit their save file to see the same thing they could have seen on YouTube?
Scott: Who cares?
Scott: But yeah, there's a thing.
Scott: Speedrunners use it a lot.
Scott: It's called save scumming, where you basically use a save game.
Scott: You intentionally save your game.
Scott: And then you do something that can't be undone, usually to acquire information, like maybe in a randomizer game.
Scott: So let's say you're playing Link to the Past randomizer and you have the mushroom.
Scott: It's like, well, you could use the mushroom to give it what you're supposed to do with the intended use.
Scott: You give it to the witch and you get a random item from the witch in Link to the Past.
Scott: But there is a glitch in Link to the Past randomizer where if you have the mushroom, you can basically do fake powder and go to the magic bat and get the magic pat to give you the magic bat item.
Scott: Even if you don't have the magic powder that you would normally need, you know, there's a trick you can do with the mushroom.
Scott: But if you gave the mushroom to the witch, you can't do that anymore.
Scott: So what you can do is you can save your game, give the mushroom to the witch, see if what the witch gives you is any good.
Scott: If it is, okay, fine.
Scott: But if the witch gives you some garbage, just load the save game, undo what you just did, and then go give the mushroom to the magic bat instead.
Scott: And you're sort of somewhat cheating by saving, but it's part of the game because the other player, you're racing another person who's playing the same game and they can do it too.
Scott: So it's not cheating.
Rym: Well, never mind save states.
Rym: And it's notable that, you know, that was something that only existed in emulators for the longest time.
Rym: But like today on the switch, if you use the NES or the SNES emulator built in there, you can just rewind time and make save states and all the stuff that emulators use to do.
Scott: So a save state goes beyond a normal save game, right?
Scott: A save game is like the game itself has designed a system for saving specific data to load later.
Scott: A save state is literally freeze the state, you know, because my computer has so much storage, I'll just freeze the entire emulated computer.
Scott: All of its RAM, all of its everything and save it to disk and load it up later as if the computer was on the whole time, as if the NES was paused that whole time.
Scott: And I can have as many of these save states as I want because my hard drive is enormous and I can load any one of them that I want.
Scott: And it's like, so any previous game state that I have managed to achieve, I can rewind to that and basically beat any game.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Like you could play Contra and move forward an inch, save, move forward an inch, save, got hit, load, and you'll eventually beat Contra without dying even if you suck.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: This is a perfectly fine way to play because one of the things that, again, this now becomes purely a game design decision.
Rym: Some games have a sort of punishment where there are parts of the game that are hard to get to and are themselves hard.
Rym: So you have to be good enough to get past the hard part and then you have even fewer attempts at the harder part because you don't always get there.
Rym: But with save states, beat the hard part and then just try the harder part over and over and over again.
Rym: So in a way, save states help players gain mastery of games by letting them micro-practice and target the parts of the game they engage with.
Rym: Whereas in the old days or games that prevent this or don't include this as a game design aspect, you generally play the early parts of the game more often and the later parts of the game less often and are less good at the later parts.
Rym: So, like in FTL, you don't fight the mothership that often on the harder modes.
Scott: I mean, I think you'll see, you know, most games these days, the AAA games and whatnot that are long, they don't necessarily have saved because the save state of the game is so much larger because it's a more complex game.
Scott: You can't load it and save it that quickly like you can with an NES emulator.
Scott: It would be like instant.
Scott: But they'll just let you quick save or full save and just make as many save files as you like and load them however you like.
Scott: And it's like, go ahead and do whatever, you know, save as much as you want, you know, to get through this game.
Scott: It's a single player game.
Scott: You're going to get to the end somehow, right?
Rym: I mean, I used to save, like in Half-Life 2, I used saving the game a lot like how I would use my fingers and choose your own adventure books.
Rym: I'd see something that obviously looks really dangerous.
Rym: I'd save my game and go fuck with it and it kills me.
Rym: Then I'd load my game and either fuck with it more carefully or not fuck with it.
Rym: Like, I wonder if that'll kill me if I jump in there.
Rym: Save game?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yeah, I think some of the times, right, is like this, you know, the saving is used, you know, when something is like difficult or challenging and you want to learn it.
Scott: But sometimes it's actually sort of, you know, allowing the player to conquer bad game design, right?
Scott: There'll be something in the game and the player like doesn't know, right?
Rym: Can I land on that platform is such a common terrible design problem.
Scott: Right, it's like, can I stand on that?
Scott: Is that fire?
Scott: Does this item, you know, I have one ice item.
Scott: If I use the ice item, will it make, will it work on that lava?
Scott: It's like, I've only got one shot.
Scott: Let me try it.
Scott: I'll save, try it, and load if it doesn't work, right?
Scott: Otherwise you try it.
Scott: It's like, that was your one shot.
Scott: It's like, god damn it.
Scott: You know, and I think that's, you know, when you see situations like that in games where the player's knowledge is lacking and they're using saves to overcome that, I think that's a sign of a bad game design.
Scott: Like you shouldn't have a situation where a player has to make a decision based on ignorance.
Rym: The galaxy brain is.
Rym: you design a game around that where the players want to take radical experiments, but you design the game where you don't have to save and load.
Rym: It handles it more gracefully.
Rym: Like Prince of Persia pioneered that rewind game design, that game mechanic, the rewind.
Rym: I'm a big fan of the rewind.
Scott: Yeah, rewind is good.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, we've already gone on pretty long, but another aspect is tabletop games.
Rym: On one hand, they intrinsically save themselves because if you just walk away from the table, barring a little bit of, unless the game is lacking something like a whose turn is it marker, or you have to make sure you leave the game at a defined point where you know where in like the turn order or the states of the game that are not determined by physical components are, then all the rest of the state of a tabletop game is saved by the nature of the fact that it's a tabletop game.
Rym: But at the same time, that's a lot like RAM in that if something jars the table ever so slightly, it's destroyed and unfixable.
Rym: We used to, I remember, occasionally take a picture of a game just in case so we could reset it back up.
Rym: Rarely did we actually reset it back up, but we had the option.
Scott: I think part of the problem is that, you know, even if you save the physical state of a game, saving a tabletop game has this mental state.
Scott: Well, video games does too, right?
Rym: Yeah, so like Civ games, if I pick up an asynchronous Civ game, I'm sort of in this cadence because I only play so many at a time and I remember what's going on because it's refreshing my brain.
Rym: But if I go take a save game from when I played Civ by myself, I will be materially worse because I don't remember all the details of what I was going after.
Rym: Like, was I going for like a campus in that district?
Rym: What exactly was I doing?
Scott: There's all this information related to a game that is not in the game itself, that is in your mind, your brain state, that is unsavable and you don't have an amazing memory.
Rym: A lot of that is your strategy, things you remember other players doing.
Rym: Like, wait, did Scott need a lot of iron in this game?
Rym: or am I remembering wrong?
Rym: Was I trying to corner the iron market to fuck Scott or did I have some other reason?
Scott: This also happens in the single player video games, right?
Scott: It's like if you're playing Final Fantasy 7 and you save it and you load it again a month later and you forget the plot, it's like, just start over.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: I, in Final Fantasy Legend 1 on the Game Boy, I walked away from it for like a year or two as a kid and I hadn't beaten it.
Rym: I picked it up one day, I was like, I should finish that game.
Rym: And then I load the game, I see my characters, I go through my inventory.
Scott: It's the one with the tower.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I didn't remember which direction I was going in the tower, like which stairway was what.
Rym: And it wasn't obvious and I tried to start a new game to see, it still wasn't obvious.
Rym: So I basically walked in a direction fighting monsters for a while and it took me like at least a half hour of play to figure out what direction I should be going in and what I was supposed to be doing next.
Rym: Modern games handle that a lot better, thankfully.
Scott: Well, I think what has helped those situations a lot now also is facts, right?
Scott: Just go online and look up a, you know, a guide or something.
Rym: Yeah, that used to not exist.
Rym: Also a lot of games, like even Zelda games pretty early on started incorporating a character you can go talk to who will remind you of at least something in the forward thinking that you still need to do that you could go do to get you back on some track.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Games have done quite a lot to try to help players get back into them after loading a save after a long time.
Scott: But even if I loaded Breath of the Wild now, I'd still feel like, just start over.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I mean, I load my save file now and I've beaten the whole game pretty much.
Rym: Which has not much to do.
Rym: But if I had a save file that was like halfway through the game, fuck, start over.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Scott: So, you know, and then I guess we could, you know, there's a lot to say about saving with regards to multiplayer and statefulness MMO type things.
Rym: The fact that civilization games cannot fucking do it for the like, I'm sorry.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And the only thing I really want to say about that is that, you know, saving is sort of integral to those games because they're about statefulness.
Scott: There's this shared global state that you're all modifying.
Scott: But I really wish that someone would make one that was sort of not stateful, right?
Scott: Like imagine an MMO where you actually, you can't save anything and you, you know, it's like we have all these roguelikes.
Scott: It's like you play the MMO, you start a new character, you play until you die, and then you start a new character and play until you die.
Scott: But MMO.
Scott: It's like, if that exists somewhere, I haven't heard of it, but I want to see that.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Link Egeed, Red Lulu, Tenebrae, and a bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names.
Rym: Chris The Dog, Chris Rymer, Clinton Walton, Dex Finch, Chi-I85, Rebecca Dunne, Review, Madbull34, Coward, Sam Erickson, Jordan Von Hurl, Stop All, The Downloading, Taylor Braun, The Next Stationist, Anglington West, Anglington West Station, and several other people whose names I will not say.
Rym: Stay safe out there.
Rym: We'll see if we do a show or if we go to that screening on Thursday.
Rym: Or if we do both, we'll see what the timing looks like.
Rym: But for now, I simply leave you with...
Scott: [MUSIC] [MUSIC].