Scott:
Rym: It's Thursday, March 31st, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: We are back from a long, unplanned hiatus to talk about James Bond, the mostly fictional spy.
Scott: Mostly?
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, yeah, we had a longer hiatus than we've really ever had on GeekNights, except in extremely rare circumstances in these, what, 16-plus years.
Rym: Do a bunch of random stuff, you know, like Friends came over.
Rym: We had some work stuff.
Rym: Eventually, like, Scott had a hockey game, and then I had to go to London on a business trip, but we're finally back.
Scott: We might have actually been able to get in a few shows there, but nobody realized that at some point in history, I don't remember exactly when, the GeekNights, Monday, Wednesday, Tuesday, Thursday offset was offset.
Rym: I actually know the date it happened, because I had filled my work calendar with permanent recurring meetings to make sure no one ever tried to schedule me.
Scott: I could scroll back on the calendar and figure out exactly when it was.
Scott: But we waited.
Rym: I was curious if anyone would notice.
Scott: Nobody ever noticed, but yeah, this should have been a Monday, Wednesday week if we had never fucked up, but we fucked up once, and it was now a Tuesday, Thursday week.
Scott: So, if we hadn't made that one fuck up, maybe the break of GeekNights episodes would have been shorter.
Rym: Yeah, maybe the whole reason we've never had long hiatus was because of the previous, original GeekNights schedule.
Rym: It just lined up with our lives, like the ebb and flow of wanting to see people and do things.
Scott: But yeah, a whole bunch of stuff happened on GeekNights days, and since it's not our job, and we don't really care if we miss a show, no one's paying us to do this, we're not obligated.
Scott: We just, and we don't have a lot of ideas, you know, okay, let's skip, fine, okay.
Scott: But that doesn't mean we're dead, it just seems, you know, obviously we're not dead, we're here.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Speaking of which, so in the news, guess who had COVID?
Rym: That's why we didn't do a show on Tuesday.
Rym: I tested positive within hours of, well, basically within about 12 hours of landing back in the US after a week long trip in the UK.
Rym: I am, as of now, basically completely recovered, but I'm still gonna isolate for another two weeks.
Scott: Yeah, so the two things I gotta say about that is, number one, man, it must suck to spend, like, so many years of your life hiding inside only to go outside once and immediately get, it's like-
Rym: Yep, I go out for the, like, alright, I'm gonna do this business trip, I'll wear a mask, like, the whole damn time.
Rym: Yep, the slightest misstep, it immediately gets me, it immediately gets Emily.
Rym: It's
Scott: like, imagine going into the woods and you've got this manual that's, like, how to not get eaten by a bear, and you got your, you know, bear repellent, and you got, you know, all kinds of, you got every bear precaution in the universe, and you're out in the woods for years, never ever ever getting in trouble with a bear, and you let your guard down for, like, a second, and a bear eats you.
Rym: Well, you know, that's how my bike got stolen in Beacon.
Rym: You know, I used to bike, we used to bike to the train station in the morning, because parking spaces there were hella expensive, and one day, I forgot my bike lock, like, I had it somewhere else for some reason, and I thought, what are the odds?
Rym: I kind of just jammed my bike into the pile of all the other bikes, bike was stolen that day.
Rym: Granted, that was the bike I stole back.
Rym: But, yeah, thankfully, because I had two vaccines and a booster, honestly, it felt like a really bad cold, but not even the worst cold I'd ever had, and 36 hours later, like, I'm feeling good enough to do a GeekNights.
Rym: Don't know if I'd feel like going, like, doing eight hours of work, but I can do an hour of podcasting.
Scott: The other thing I gotta say is that you only got this because your work made you go to London.
Scott: You wouldn't have been going to London if your work didn't make you go.
Scott: I
Rym: don't know, it is clear that if I had kept my previous levels of, like, isolation to the point that I was even avoiding things people we know were doing, like, where everyone has different levels, I probably could have kept avoiding it, but my worry is, going to the UK showed me something that, I guess, because I've been so careful and lived in New York City and, like, haven't really left New York City that much, like, we went way upstate to ski in the winter, and, yeah, like, I expected people to not give a shit about COVID, like, up in this rural area, but New York City, people are still treating it pretty carefully.
Scott: Not as much now.
Rym: Yeah, but still more so.
Rym: When I got to the UK, I gotta tell you, so I land, come out of the airport, go to my hotel, every bar, and it's, like, morning, every restaurant, every bar all day, completely packed with maskless people, shoulder to shoulder.
Rym: London was more crowded indoors and, like, more filled with spittle than I have ever seen it pre-COVID.
Rym: It's like nobody, no one was wearing, not one person was wearing a mask.
Rym: Even in New York, I still see the occasional person wearing a mask outside, and the majority of people wearing masks indoors.
Rym: Our building still requires you to have a mask on to come in.
Scott: So, what I gotta say to that is, since your work made you go, is this a workers' comp situation or what?
Rym: It could be.
Rym: I could think about exploring that.
Rym: I have negative PCR.
Scott: It wouldn't be a large claim, right?
Scott: It would probably just be a small settlement.
Rym: Well, 'cause the problem is the damage to me that I can prove correctly.
Rym: Very small.
Scott: Very small.
Scott: Not zero.
Rym: But I do have a negative PCR test from every other day on the entire trip and a negative rapid test every day.
Rym: I definitely caught it on the trip, guaranteed.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, you know.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I'm the kind of person who would, like, you know, try to do the workers' comp just for the principle of the thing, like, you know.
Scott: And also, you know, there's a lot of reports, like, hey, that even if you get, you know, I don't know how true all these things are, but I've seen a lot of comments and studies that are like, you know, hey, you got a COVID, but, you know, and you got over it and you feel fine, but actually, you know, it messed with your brain or it messed with you in some other way, you know, something like that.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well, even beyond that, so apparently now PCR tests basically won't work on me for 90 days is the line.
Rym: Like, they'll just show positive even though I'm not anymore.
Rym: So I am now exempt from being tested if I go anywhere.
Rym: All I have to do is sign a thing saying I've had COVID confirmed and nobody gives a shit.
Rym: I don't have to do any testing anywhere, which is interesting.
Rym: But also, my immunity theoretically also only lasts 90 days.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, they're letting people into, you know, that square garden without vaccine.
Rym: I mean, the last hockey game I went to with you, you and I were wearing masks.
Rym: That kid sitting to the front left of us was wearing a mask.
Rym: And I think one other person was wearing a mask on the other side of the arena.
Scott: There are still some people, but it's like the majority are not and they're not checking for vaccination anymore.
Scott: They're just like, fuck it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So my worry is my real fear is that it's unavoidable.
Rym: And that means that we have a society of just failed.
Scott: because while I mean, we knew it was going to become endemic at some point.
Scott: But is is this endemic or is this still a pandemic?
Scott: I don't know how to tell.
Rym: Even if like masking and other things that started to fall away, I feel like the thing we as a society, society should have doubled down on more than anything else are the vaccine mandates requiring the vaccine to go places because that is the big line between.
Scott: I think we should.
Scott: I still think you should hold.
Scott: I'm not even joking about this.
Scott: I think you should hold people down and jab them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Too bad.
Scott: Unless unless you do.
Scott: Obviously, the true medical exemptions, obviously.
Scott: But the you know, the nut job who just is a denier, hold them down and jab them.
Scott: I got no problems with that whatsoever.
Rym: There is the the fear of the slippery slope of bodily autonomy.
Rym: That's why the compromise usually is we won't force it on you, but you are now denied access to all public places.
Scott: You're basically under house arrest.
Scott: You know, we could talk about slippery slopes again.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like, you know, there's a constant thing in our society where it's like because of some principle.
Scott: It's like we don't want to go down a slippery slope.
Scott: But it's like, OK, you're afraid of the next step on the slope, but you're OK with the first step.
Scott: It's like, well, yeah, but I don't want to do the first step because I'm afraid of the second one.
Rym: Just don't go down the second step.
Scott: Just don't go down the fucking second step.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like.
Rym: what if the anti-fascists start attacking people who aren't Nazis?
Rym: Like it's in our name.
Rym: That's that's like.
Rym: the only thing anti-fascists are after is the fascists.
Rym: If the fascists go away, they don't go after someone else.
Rym: They go home.
Scott: The point is society as a whole would be better if we would, you know, go down slippery slopes and just not slip on them.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That there's good stuff down the slope.
Scott: Just a little ways.
Scott: Go down and grab it and come back up.
Scott: Don't fuck up and fall down.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: How hard is that?
Rym: But the vaccine mandate seemed to be just the most ridiculous thing to go away, considering that that's the last major measure we have that society will tolerate.
Scott: Yeah, I feel like, you know, I'm not an expert.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it definitely should have been the last.
Scott: That's the easiest thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So, yeah, don't go out and get it.
Rym: Obviously, like if you haven't gotten it yet, I highly advise you to try to keep avoiding it.
Rym: But if you do get it, I guess for me personally, it was not as bad as I had feared.
Rym: Mostly because I was vaccinated.
Scott: Well, you might have permanent unseen damage.
Scott: True.
Rym: But also the benefits of vaccinated, healthy, young and lucky can be a factor.
Rym: So do not rely on being all four of those things because nobody is all four of those things forever.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: In fact, you might be some of all four of those things and afterwards not be all of those things anymore.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So you got any news?
Scott: What was my news?
Scott: I forgot.
Rym: You are Queens, LaGuardia.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: So the second worst airport to fly into in the greater New York City area.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So LaGuardia Airport, you know, which is infamously not a great airport, is actually super close to where I live.
Scott: I could comfortably.
Rym: I have walked home from flights that landed in LaGuardia more than once.
Scott: It is possible to walk there.
Scott: It is trivial for me to bike there.
Scott: It's that close.
Rym: It is also not hard to walk out of that airport, walk down city streets and then get out of subway.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: JFK, though, is is a much better airport, but it's way out there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, not way out there, but like I got to use trains to get over there or buses or something.
Scott: It's like, you know, you're not walking to JFK.
Scott: I could bike to JFK.
Scott: It takes a while.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And they're not doing that with luggage either.
Rym: So what does that just carry?
Rym: They have the Rollie behind you like.
Rym: Yeah, sure.
Scott: Despite being so close, LaGuardia is actually harder to get to.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: There's a bus that if you try to take this bus, my experiences with it are thusly you'll stand at a spot, a stop three or four hours before your flight because you're a New Yorker and you're paranoid.
Rym: The bus comes.
Rym: It's already full.
Rym: The doors don't even open and it leaves.
Rym: This will keep happening until you give up and call a cab.
Scott: So, yeah, despite being physically much, much closer, it is much harder to get to its right.
Scott: It's closer to Manhattan.
Scott: It's it's like, you know, it's like it makes no sense.
Scott: So our previous shitty governor wanted to build a train like a special train that goes to LaGuardia from the subway.
Scott: Good idea on paper.
Scott: But the route selected for this train was inane.
Scott: It involved going way past the airport and then taking a train backwards.
Scott: It would only be beneficial for someone from Long Island who could take the Long Island Railroad and then go to the airport easily.
Rym: I remember when we saw that original map and all of New York collectively said, what?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Most of the people I was most of the people who go to the airport, over 50 percent are coming from Manhattan.
Scott: So it makes sense to have the train going from Manhattan to the airport on the left, the west side, not the east side.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So that was the plan.
Scott: We got a new governor, new governor.
Scott: Not perfect.
Scott: Got some problems.
Scott: But still, I guess at least one.
Scott: Point better than the previous governor.
Scott: That's not hard, but maybe even two points better.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Still got problems, but better and improvement by at least some measures as change plans.
Scott: And they had the Port Authority of New York, New Jersey.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Who runs these things?
Scott: because don't even get me into that.
Scott: What the Port Authority is.
Rym: There's a movie.
Rym: There's an old movie that's obscure that talks about the Port Authority.
Rym: You can find anyway called Nothing Lasts Forever.
Rym: It's basically a documentary.
Scott: So they had some public hearings.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Of, you know, what the fuck should we do?
Scott: We're not going to.
Scott: you know, we're not doing the old plan.
Scott: What should we do to make LaGuardia more accessible?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Transportation wise.
Scott: So I had previously attended similar hearings for a city bike.
Scott: I did one that was a city bike workshop, which is where should we put the city bike docks in your neighborhood?
Scott: And that one, the format was you sit at a table in a circle.
Scott: Right.
Scott: With a group of random people that you happen to be at a table with and you discuss.
Scott: And there are many such tables within, you know, and there was a Department of Transportation employee at each table.
Scott: And they they collated their data afterwards.
Rym: My answer is put up in every corner, every every intersection, whole city.
Scott: I did a one of those for the Crescent Street bike lane, which is now existing and now has a concrete barrier.
Scott: Oh, yes.
Rym: So get this.
Rym: When I landed from London, my cabbie, I fell asleep in the cab in my mouth, just like.
Rym: And he wakes me up, he's like, Crescent Street is closed.
Rym: I'm like, what?
Rym: All of it?
Rym: He's like, yeah, all of it.
Rym: How where do you live?
Rym: And when I got when I finally got home, I saw they had blocked Crescent Street because they were currently craning in the new barriers.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's all there now.
Rym: It's beautiful.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So and I already saw a black car that it somehow wedged it at an intersection, wedged itself in and appeared to be stuck.
Scott: So anyway, so that was the same format for that one.
Scott: Then I did a bus, a bus route one, and the bus route one was of the worst format.
Scott: This was the sort of town hall format.
Rym: I mean, the bus anything is always the worst format.
Scott: Where they do a slide show for the MTA, does a slide show, and then people then form as the idea that, oh, we're talking about buses, we got to make the presentation way worse.
Scott: And then townies line up for the mic.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that was a bad time, that one.
Scott: So the LaGuardia one, this is Port Authority.
Scott: So we went to Department of Transportation.
Scott: We went to MTA.
Scott: Now we're at Port Authority.
Scott: How does the Port Authority run the public, you know, workshop for how do we make LaGuardia less shitty to get to and from?
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: To their credit, this is the best format I ever seen.
Scott: I think this format should be used for a lot more things.
Scott: The way it worked is they rent, they had a ballroom at the local wedding venue type place.
Scott: And on each side of the ballroom, it was like a science fair.
Scott: There were basically a poster board on an easel and each poster board had a transportation option, right?
Scott: Some sort of thing that could be built and an attendant, right?
Scott: Someone who worked for the Port Authority, who was very knowledgeable and could answer questions and explain the thing that was on the poster board.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like the kid at the science fair.
Scott: And so what you would do is you would go in and at your leisure, you would walk around examining the boards and talking to the people.
Scott: And then there was a long table full of laptops and you went up to them and you typed in whatever the fuck thing you wanted to type in.
Rym: See, that's how you keep the crazy townie.
Rym: The crazy townie can type their screed into this text box.
Scott: The crazy towner, the crazy and you could submit the form as many times as you want.
Scott: So the crazy townie can write 10 screeds and it's not bothering anyone else.
Scott: And they can just read it or delete it afterwards.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the normal people can type in what they're going to type in and then you can leave at your.
Scott: you don't have to sit there and listen to anything.
Scott: You know, so this is an excellent format.
Scott: A lot of the people who were standing at the boards were extremely knowledgeable.
Scott: I learned all kinds of things I didn't know.
Scott: And the thing that I found the most encouraging was that, you know, they had so many options, right?
Scott: Not only did they have the existing option that, you know, the previous governor wanted to do, they had different light rails, subway extensions.
Rym: That's the big one.
Rym: The fact that they included subway extensions because it is somebody to build a subway extension to New York compared to anything else is like it's orders of magnitude more money for reasons.
Scott: Protected bus lanes, ferry ferry terminals, like so many options they had.
Scott: underground, above ground, go along the Grand Central, go into the BQE.
Scott: And they were like and not only that, but they were like.
Scott: these options are not mutually exclusive.
Scott: They're like we could do the ferry and the bus and the subway extension.
Scott: They don't bump into each other.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Like, you know, imagine an airport with more than one way to get out of it.
Rym: That's what most European airports are like.
Scott: That wasn't a car.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So most of my input was pretty much like, hey, none of these options that you.
Scott: you have lots of options here, boat, train, bus.
Scott: Right.
Scott: All kinds of things.
Scott: I don't see any bike or foot options on here, which again, for something that is so fucking close.
Scott: I'm like, just put a city bike dock there.
Rym: Come on.
Rym: Yeah, because you know someone would use it.
Rym: In fact, there were some flights where I would have used it.
Scott: If you're doing a flight where all you got is a backpack, carry on, it's like, you know, I could totally city bike to LaGuardia and back.
Scott: No problem.
Rym: How liberating that liberating would that feel to land from a flight somewhere, walk out of the airport, get on a bike and just bike home?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And in like 15 minutes to 20 minutes, maybe tops.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Probably about as long as it takes to take a cab out of there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I say, you know, who knows what they're going to do?
Scott: Are they going to choose what I said that they should choose?
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: But excellent format for workshop.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I feel like the only way you could go better would be to let people type their screen.
Rym: But if you could come up with questions about the proposals that let you do a conjoint analysis of the like mean preference of the group instead of people just trying to get their own idea out, like when you force people to choose of the 14 options, which you like better, 11 or 14, like force those kinds of decisions.
Rym: You can tease out ideas that people, some of them were mutually exclusive, right?
Scott: Like.
Scott: there were two different subway extensions.
Scott: One goes through Astoria, right?
Scott: Like.
Scott: and then one like a long dip Mars and another one goes north out past Astoria, like behind all the industrial shit, past the power plants and then takes a hook to the east.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I was like having a line that came from Manhattan under the river and under Randall's Island all the way across and just intersecting the top of it.
Rym: Mars, then just going all the way out into Queens.
Scott: That wasn't one of the options.
Rym: No, that that that wasn't even that was barely an option in the original subway.
Scott: There was an option to improve the, you know, the buses that go, you know, over Randall's Island.
Rym: So anything to make Randall's Island more accessible to people without cars, because that island is a treasure and the buses that go there are the worst.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So we've talked about Dua Lipa on GeekNights a few times.
Rym: Fantastic performer, fantastic musician.
Rym: And Dua Lipa has a song called Levitating.
Rym: Scott made it his thing of the day a while ago.
Rym: I think it was you.
Rym: I think you called Dibz on it.
Rym: The music video was the thing of the day, not the song.
Rym: Yeah, because the song is great.
Rym: The song has a music video.
Rym: The song also has an official music video animated in the style of Sailor Moon.
Rym: And it's just delightful.
Rym: So some band or some label that represents a band is suing Dua Lipa, claiming that the song Levitating is, in fact, plagiarizing their song.
Rym: And their song does sound superficially very similar to the song.
Rym: So Adam Neely has done a very helpful video where he shows that thousands of songs are just as close to both of these songs as the people are suing and how this lawsuit is absolutely ridiculous.
Rym: It's almost definitely guaranteed to fail.
Rym: But if it succeeds, it destroys the concept of music copyright, basically.
Scott: Well, it's already sort of been destroyed, right?
Scott: So there's a huge issue going on in the music industry.
Scott: It's been going on for a while.
Scott: But basically, you can get money for free if you can get songwriting credits on a song.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So let's say, you know, Rym writes a song completely on his own.
Scott: He's never listened to anyone else's music in his life.
Scott: He's only listened to public domain classical music.
Scott: He's never listened to anything else.
Rym: Like when I was in IBM and I signed some stuff saying I'd never used real Java.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And he writes some song and it sounds like doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Scott: Doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which is not a classical song.
Rym: Right.
Rym: No, but mine's got a little "ch" in it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So Rym writes that song, literally legitimately, 100 percent on his own.
Scott: You know, but then someone else comes along and is like, hey, I wrote that song, actually.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Listen to my song.
Rym: And vanilla ice starts playing his song.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then someone else comes along and says, I wrote, you know, it's like and there are only so many fucking songs that can be made.
Scott: And there's so many people using samples these days and all their songs.
Scott: So what ends up happening is rather than fight a protracted legal battle, which is just often, you know, not worth it, even if you win a lot of hit songs these days, the song writing credits get chopped up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Not just the people, you know, you'll usually have a group of songwriters writing the song initially and then more and more names just get added on there with various percentages, just getting a piece.
Scott: Everyone's got to get their piece.
Scott: So when someone listens or performs to the song and royalties come in, the money is getting divided up.
Scott: You know, these micro pennies from their Spotify streams are getting divided up amongst all these people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like if you write a song, even if you write it completely on your own, it's like if it sounds similar to something else, which it probably will, and that person is listening and litigious.
Scott: or, you know, it's like there's free money in it for them.
Scott: And this for you, you only have things to lose.
Scott: You have nothing to gain.
Scott: You're probably going to end up giving them a piece or fighting.
Scott: So, you know, it's a tough choice.
Scott: So this keeps happening because the incentives are all misaligned and the system is broken.
Rym: And this one is really interesting because Adam does a really deep sort of musicological analysis of it.
Rym: But then he also points out that this lawsuit does something weird.
Rym: All the other lawsuits, all the ones you're probably more familiar with, they make at some point in their legal argument, a music theory argument like they actually bring out music theory and shows like notation and chord progressions.
Rym: And they make this case that they are fundamentally the same song.
Rym: But here, this lawsuit actually doesn't do that at all.
Rym: And it seems to focus entirely on specific older songs that sound like this song without actually doing a musicological analysis.
Rym: So his argument, at least, is that this is an even easier lawsuit for Dua Lipa to win because they can just point out even older songs that sound even more similar.
Rym: There's prior art and the whole thing gets thrown out.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: OK, so I just went to Rollingstone.com, you know, the music industry magazine.
Scott: I did a search for songwriting credits.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you're ready for listen to these headlines.
Scott: March twenty twenty two, Lizzo reaches settlement over Truth Hurts songwriting credits.
Scott: March twenty twenty two, experts do a Dua Lipa one.
Scott: March fourth, Post Malone skewers.
Scott: musicians suing for Circles credit can't prove original contribution.
Scott: February twenty eighteen, right.
Scott: Frank Ocean's who's blonde producer over songwriting credits.
Scott: Twenty fifteen, Paul McCartney talks, Nix McCartney, Lennon songwriting credit.
Scott: Twenty nineteen, Rolling Stones finally give back bittersweet symphony songwriting credits.
Scott: Twenty twenty one, which Natalie Hemby performed.
Scott: Oh, that's different.
Scott: OK, the point is this keeps.
Scott: those are the.
Scott: obviously those have articles on Rolling Stone because those are, you know, the biggest of the bigs.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, you know, there's a lot.
Scott: Twenty twenty one, Noah Ford, you should be clarifies R. Kelly credit on Drake certified lover boy.
Scott: It's like this, you know, goes on and on and on.
Scott: This is what is happening in the music industry and has been happening for the past five to 10 years.
Rym: And it seems like a big part of it is if these do go to trials, which they have in some cases, juries don't understand any of this and they sound kind of the same.
Rym: So juries tend to say yes.
Scott: Yes, there have been.
Scott: I forget which case it was, was sort of like, you know, one of the Campbell's straw back ones.
Scott: But there was like there was some big ones that, you know, went and set a bad precedent.
Scott: And that's why people keep going after it.
Rym: But yeah.
Rym: So her twenty twenty song, the people suing her saying it's their twenty seventeen song and their twenty seventeen song sounds like it's based heavily on songs from like going as far back as the thirties.
Rym: So, yep.
Rym: So anyway, what's your thing of the day?
Scott: What the hell was my thing of the day?
Scott: Oh, right.
Scott: So this video is from twenty fourteen, I think it's old, but it was new to me.
Scott: So deal with it.
Scott: So the University of Georgia, a warm place, relatively speaking, it is a you know, the University of Georgia is still an enormous university.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Big, you know, not like RIT, a small private university where we went.
Scott: It's like a huge, huge place.
Scott: Lots of lots of students.
Scott: So they did have an ice hockey team.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I think they still do.
Scott: It's they're the Bulldogs.
Scott: But I think that the ice hockey team is the ice dogs.
Scott: So but they didn't have an arena, an ice hockey rink, at least not a permanent one that was on campus or anything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But in twenty fourteen, I guess they wanted to play some home ice hockey games.
Scott: So what they did is they got a portable ice rink from Ice America, which is a company that can set up an ice rink basically anywhere you pay them to if you can afford it.
Scott: And they set it up in the ballroom because they have an enormous fucking ballroom at their at their university.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like tremendous, really big enough to hold a full size ice rink and seats.
Scott: And in this video, Ice America shows how they set up a portable ice rink indoors in just a big room with no right.
Scott: It's like without making water fall through the ceiling to whatever's below.
Rym: I mean, we did it.
Rym: We did an episode water in the ceiling for a reason.
Rym: I cannot imagine a more perfect storm of water in the ceiling than trying to make an ice rink like this.
Scott: They get they get a full sized Zamboni in there.
Scott: They get, you know, grandstands in there.
Scott: Not that many seats, but enough seats.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like they get, you know, how many layers of ice and they set the whole thing up and like in a warm place, by the way, in, you know, 48 hours or whatever, you know, not it doesn't take them long to set it up.
Scott: I don't know how long it takes to undo it, but it's pretty impressive.
Scott: And if you have enough money and you need an ice rink and you want to put the ice rink somewhere that ice rinks shouldn't be, but you have enough room for it.
Scott: I if Ice America still exists and you're in America, I think they're the ones to call.
Rym: In the moment, the GeekNights Book Club book that we are going to do an episode on for, let's say, two weeks from now.
Rym: Let's do it.
Rym: The next Thursday show.
Rym: So April 14th, you've had.
Scott: you've had three months, which is, you know, if we weren't fucking up and spending two to three years, three months is a good amount of time to read a book that took me less than two weeks, maybe.
Rym: So I'm near.
Rym: I've read a bunch of it.
Rym: I'll definitely finish.
Rym: This is such a show.
Scott: We didn't finish it, even though you took a. you went to London, all that.
Rym: I was actually really busy on the trip and then I got sick.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Lick it, licking, licking people.
Rym: I mean, I mean, the trip was a doorknob licking convention.
Rym: So in retrospect, that might have that might have been more more excuses for workers come.
Rym: You know, the worst thing was when I was like walking around, I was wearing a mask and I was the only person in London.
Rym: I think every single person I interacted with had to say something about the mask.
Rym: Like, oh, you Americans like everyone's like, oh, you're paranoid.
Rym: Like an American.
Scott: Yeah, well, I got sick from you dirty.
Rym: So this book is very New York.
Rym: I really Scott said this before, but I want to reiterate, I want to know what you think of this book if you don't know anything about New York City.
Scott: Or even if you know things about New York, but you know, you're not you don't you're not.
Rym: you know, you haven't spent a lot of time and even I thought of your Manhattan and then quote the outer boroughs until I moved here.
Rym: Then I started to recognize, like Queens and Brooklyn are very different from each other and Staten Island is technically part of New York City.
Rym: I kind of didn't know that when I was a kid.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, most mass media doesn't usually deal with subject matter that the wide audience wouldn't know without like teaching it to them first.
Scott: A superhero movie won't even assume, you know, the origin of the superhero.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, they got to make sure that, you know, Batman's parents are dead and Spider-Man got bit and Superman's an alien.
Scott: But it's like if you go watch a movie about baseball, they don't teach you what baseball is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They assume, you know, what baseball is.
Scott: if you're going to go watch fucking, I don't know, Bull Durham.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But this book, it's like it assumes, you know, what New York is just the way Bull Durham assumes, you know, what baseball is.
Scott: So, you know, if you don't know enough about New York, I'm still really curious how the book comes across.
Scott: Some some of the listener have told me, but I want to hear from more of the listeners.
Rym: So.
Rym: And the other thing I can say is that every character, like this whole book, every time a new character appears, they are absolutely fantastic without exception.
Rym: Mm hmm.
Rym: Even the bad characters, when they actually show up, are great.
Scott: Well, because it's like it's they're great and not that they're people you like the most, even though some of them you like the most or many of them.
Scott: But they are so exactly correct.
Scott: It's like, yep, that's that guy.
Scott: That's exactly how that kind of guy is in the real world.
Rym: When you meet Staten Island girl pretty early on, it's like, wow, wow.
Scott: I've interacted with what Staten Island girl is like.
Scott: Yeah, 100 percent.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I know that person.
Scott: I'm not friends with that person, but I know I have met that person.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: I definitely I know a lot of Manny's in the work that I do.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: But it's so like without spoiling things, it's so self-aware.
Rym: Like, man, you know, Manny is a good guy in terms of like what the story is trying to do, but also a checkered past, shall we say, like not.
Rym: not everything that Manny does is good and or that many did was good because that, you know, Manhattan's identity is about a lot of the cruelty that has been inflicted by Manhattan, not just about the cool parts of Manhattan.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Anyway, anything else?
Scott: Meadow packs is real soon and it's actually happening for real.
Scott: I'm not going.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I will be there Thursday, April twenty first.
Rym: That is long outside of my quarantine period.
Rym: Of course, I'll take negative tests before that or I'll just bail.
Rym: But Thursday, April twenty first, seven p.m.
Rym: Bumblebee Theater, a live and significantly updated version of Atari Game Design.
Rym: I think it'll be fun if you're not there.
Rym: I'm going to video it, of course, just like I did for Unplugged.
Rym: So do not go to PAX East just because I'm going to be there.
Rym: I will definitely put that panel online before the end of PAX East, just like I did with PAX Unplugged.
Scott: You know, I'm not holding out any hope for PAX West, but, you know, I might go.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: Yeah, I I'm like.
Rym: I'm cautiously optimistic as I am about many things.
Rym: We'll see what happens.
Scott: I'm not setting any expectation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I'll decide when the time comes.
Scott: I would like to go, obviously, but I'm not going to.
Scott: I'm not going to set myself up to be like disappointed by not going or anything like that.
Rym: The exciting thing I'll just mention briefly is that PAX, once we're post covid and like we're going to PAX is like normal again, PAX has started to set up interesting panel adjacent, but not just panel like content types like I do.
Scott: You know, assuming PAX survives or other conventions survive as well.
Scott: I do think that, you know, many conventions have sadly died, but they're the conventions that live are definitely have been invigorated.
Scott: You know, they're not selling out their tickets.
Scott: So they're trying a lot harder content wise, you know, doing things that we thought they should have done a long time ago, experimenting, et cetera.
Scott: And I like that.
Rym: So, yeah, like if it wasn't covid times, we would have I feel like we would have done like this.
Rym: upcoming PAX East might have been one of those.
Rym: We signed up to do too many things conventions.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, even in the mid to late 2000s, we were trying to get conventions to try out, you know, things that conventions weren't already doing kinds of content.
Rym: Otakon used to not mail its badges.
Rym: They accused Scott of threatening them by telling them to mail the badges.
Rym: And look where we are now.
Rym: Everybody mails the badges.
Rym: The problem is, if PAX does all this stuff, we're running out of things we wanted that cons haven't done.
Rym: We haven't come up with many new things.
Rym: I guess the last one would be curated screenings at anime conventions.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, let's move on to the I can't believe never done a show on James Bond.
Rym: Like I thought it felt like one of those things we just had to have done.
Scott: Yeah, it's one of the major franchises of, you know, media entertainment in the, you know, the the English speaking world and even the rest of the world.
Rym: And it's one that is still going.
Rym: The reason we thought of it is I suggested, you know, on the flight home, I watched No Time to Die, the last Daniel.
Rym: I guess spoilers.
Rym: It's the last Daniel Craig, James Bond.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But I watched it.
Rym: It was OK.
Rym: It was an above average Bond movie.
Rym: It was the second best Daniel Craig movie, though I haven't seen Quantum of Solace or Spectre.
Scott: I only saw the first Daniel Craig one and that's it.
Rym: The thing is, Casino Royale was great, except my only complaint about that as a bomb.
Rym: I hardly remember it was that it kind of followed the book too closely.
Rym: And the book has a few like improbable events that happened, which depending like, I guess the Daniel Craig, James Bond felt too gritty and realistic for the somewhat unrealistic thing that happened in the last third of that movie.
Rym: Anyway, but now like a Pierce Brosnan where he's just got magic.
Rym: He's basically just a wizard.
Rym: Like every James Bond is different.
Scott: So, yeah.
Scott: So, I mean, James Bond is pretty significant in my life media wise because, right, it was significant in my parents life, especially my mom is like a huge James Bond fan, like big time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like before like, you know, I guess my mom also like Star Wars a lot.
Scott: But you got to remember, before Star Wars even fucking existed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like she was going to see every James Bond movie in the movie theater as soon as it came out.
Rym: And unlike, say, Indiana Jones or how by the time Star Wars existed, your parents had been through three bonds.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: It's like there were the James Bond movies kept coming.
Scott: It's like, you know, they were.
Scott: they were like this constant, always their thing, much easier to be a fan of back then.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Look, sixty two, sixty three, sixty four, five, seven, nine, seventy one, seventy three every year or year or maybe two years at most.
Scott: And it's like even when, you know, Star Wars comes and overshadows it, it's like, oh, got three Star Wars movies.
Scott: Whoa.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like James Bond didn't stop.
Scott: He just kept going.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There was there was a.
Rym: there was a long pause after Timothy Dalton.
Rym: It was a while before there was more bond.
Scott: Remember between Timothy Dalton and Goldeneye was that was the break period.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But it's like for a long time it kept going.
Scott: And then once it got started again, it kept going again.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So in it, you know, it's still going now.
Scott: We'll see when they start up again.
Scott: But, yeah, it's like we had an ever present thing.
Scott: And also, I think that, you know, it was introduced to, you know, we read a lot of stories from nerds who go about impressioning their kids the wrong way, trying to force their kids to like the same thing they like.
Scott: You know, I've read some possibly false stories on, you know, various redheads.
Scott: It could have been made up.
Scott: But, you know, they're believable stories, at least where, you know, some parent names all their kids after Harry Potter characters and makes everyone watch Harry Potter and cosplays Harry Potter all the time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like and the kids aren't into Harry Potter.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: that's not the healthy way to do it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, but, you know, my mom, it's like she wasn't like sit down or watching James Bond.
Scott: She was like she really only did two things, which was a. You know, express to us that she was a big like, you know, she.
Scott: she was not ashamed to let everyone know she fucking loved James Bond.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And to shoot watching his model was on TV.
Scott: And wouldn't be upset if she would like make anyone watch.
Scott: But it's like, why wouldn't you watch?
Scott: the movies are actually fucking good.
Rym: Some of them.
Rym: I mean, I think like my parents just put on Star Wars one day and about 20 minutes into it, suddenly my kid brain was like, wait a minute, this is really.
Rym: this is cool.
Rym: This is my favorite thing on Earth now.
Rym: My parents didn't try to indoctrinate me into Star Wars.
Rym: They just put it on and I happen to like it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So James Bond itself started out as some books.
Scott: Have you ever read a James Bond book?
Rym: Only Casino Royale.
Scott: I've never read any James Bond book, so I can't.
Scott: I can't tell you if they're good or not.
Rym: Oh, which apparently is the weird one where like the licensing was different for that one compared to every other James Bond book.
Scott: Yeah, they're all written by.
Scott: what's his name?
Scott: What's the guy's name?
Rym: Fleming.
Scott: Yeah, Fleming.
Scott: But anyway, the movies.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They adapted the books and the movies.
Scott: And that was what the broccoli is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: What a great last name, broccoli.
Scott: I'm pretty sure the broccoli family estate has the movie like control of the movie biz part of it.
Scott: But yeah, it started off, you know, black and white movies.
Scott: The first one is a Dr.
Scott: No.
Scott: Right.
Scott: With the rocket.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: No was the first one.
Scott: Nineteen sixty two with Sean Connery, the dragon playing James Bond.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then after Sean Connery stopped doing it late.
Scott: They switched to Roger Moore.
Rym: You already skipped someone.
Scott: Oh, did I?
Scott: Who did I miss?
Rym: Lazenby.
Scott: Oh, who cares about Lazenby?
Rym: Because remember, he did one and then Sean Connery came back.
Scott: But Lazenby was.
Scott: no one cares about him.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So no one cares about Timothy Dalton either.
Rym: You know, I care about Lazenby because for for whatever reason, that was the bond I saw first.
Rym: I have this memory as a kid.
Rym: So get this.
Rym: I had a memory as a kid.
Rym: This movie was on.
Rym: And as the spy stuff going on, it was on my grandparents gigantic projection TV.
Rym: And all the adults were like talking about it disparagingly.
Rym: And then I was like, what's this movie?
Rym: It looks pretty cool.
Rym: And all the adults were like, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Rym: You haven't seen any of these.
Rym: And they made a big hoorah.
Rym: And they were.
Scott: they were they were right.
Rym: And they were like, no, we're going to we're going to watch.
Rym: And they dug out and we watched Sean Connery, James Bond instead, because they didn't want that to be my first bond.
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: I was like five.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, so then you had Roger Moore, right, who was actually.
Rym: I think it was Thunderball, if I really think about it.
Scott: Well, that's like the best one.
Scott: That's like anyway.
Scott: And then you had Timothy Dalton, who no one cares.
Scott: And then you had Pierce Brosnan, who, you know, I think if not for the video game, nobody would have cared.
Rym: He's.
Rym: it's weird because I already encounter people who are very nostalgic for the Pierce Brosnan era of Bond, even though I'll admit it is my least favorite era.
Rym: But I don't count the one offs like.
Scott: I mean, he's better than Lazenby and Dalton.
Scott: But that's about it.
Rym: I mean, Dalton got twice as many Bond movies as Lazenby.
Rym: So sure.
Rym: But I did not like the Pierce Brosnan Bond at all.
Rym: Like he was just he was a magic wizard man wielding magic wizard gadgets.
Scott: Yeah, like everything.
Rym: And then you had the super fake and the current guy until just now.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Daniel Craig, second or third favorite Bond, depending on how I'm feeling.
Scott: I guess he's third after Brosnan and Connery.
Scott: But that's the thing that makes the James Bond movies different from all the other sort of franchises, is that there's this that connection where it's like there's an actor who's playing Bond and a set of movies.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And, you know, it doesn't matter who all the characters are.
Scott: It doesn't matter what the plots are.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like the set of movies where that actor was James Bond.
Scott: It's like I don't even know actors names, but I know all the James Bond actors names.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like art are like a set.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like you don't have fucking like, oh, the Star Wars where, you know, Hamill was Luke and then the Star Wars where Daniel Craig was Luke and the Star Wars where that doesn't look like.
Rym: In fact, look what they're doing.
Rym: They're using CG to make sure you still have the original player, like character and actor in a role.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Whereas James Bond is like, you know, it's like it's unique in that way.
Scott: Is there anything else you can think of where there's a character and the person who plays that character is sort of, you know, there's the there's the.
Scott: I don't know how to describe it.
Scott: There's
Rym: this similar but distinct thing that you see, especially in some anime where like Lupin anime or I don't know it the where you have the same character mostly drawn the same way, but even played by the same voice actor, possibly, but radically reinterpreted by whoever's writing and directing each movie.
Scott: I do think you see a little bit of it on, you know, on the theater.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Stage Broadway.
Scott: Because you'll have you know, you'll have a play and it's an original cast.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So and so plays the main character.
Scott: And then obviously the play has to be shown internationally in other languages and other places.
Scott: It goes on tour and you have a different cast.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The person that the famous person stops being the main character, someone else takes over on Broadway for the extended run.
Rym: But they tend not to radically reinterpret the role unless the production itself is radically reinterpreting the role.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: That's the difference is that when you do that with a with a play, it's still the same script, the same story.
Scott: That's like this.
Scott: It's like if they just made Thunderball over and over and over again with a different James Bond.
Scott: But this it's like.
Scott: it's, you know, the same character, the same universe with different stories, but the same, quote, universe.
Rym: It's like the lazy Matsumoto verse in that you can't actually make a very clear, good connection between every single movie.
Rym: That's 100, not every single movie.
Scott: But there are some that you can connect to.
Scott: There are some that fit together.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, like all the Daniel Craig ones literally are just a progression, like they all just are sequels to each other.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: And there's there are like some that like involve, you know, Specter, like some Sean Connery ones and whatever that sort of go together a little bit.
Rym: Well, they'll bring common elements together.
Rym: Like they'll always be a money, like they'll always be these elements in the movies, but they might act very differently, be portrayed very differently, serve different roles.
Rym: James Bond films always seem to try to do one twist in each movie that wasn't like what you expected from a previous movie to the point that you wait for.
Rym: Like, where's the Bond twist?
Scott: But, yeah, so I guess, you know, what makes James Bond right, regardless of who the actor is, right, you know, and regardless of, you know, what flavor is being put on it, I think what makes it fun is that, you know, you get a little bit of everything no matter what.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like you get you get action.
Rym: Usually there's a pretty big action scene in the first five minutes of the movie.
Scott: Usually it's usually it's that the best action in the cold open movie is going to be the chase scene.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It always starts with action.
Rym: That's why I was such a big fan of Daniel Craig, because when they brought him onto the scene, Casino Royale, first scene in media rez chase scene, almost like a James Bond movie is going to start with that.
Scott: Almost right.
Scott: And that the chase scenes are not all.
Scott: there's plenty of car chases, no shortage, but there's not just car chases.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You get, you know, the skiing chases are really incredible.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Were they?
Scott: I don't even know they might.
Scott: were they the first some of the earliest slash best ski chases.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I mean, some of the best scenes in Inception were the ski chases because they were very Bond movie like.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Total, total Bond ski chases there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So different kinds of chases you got going on a lot of boats going on.
Scott: A lot of swimming and all kinds of stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I remember, you know, Live and Let Die.
Scott: Which is not a not a good one, but it's like my favorite one.
Scott: It has good aspects, at least.
Scott: I can recognize first Roger Moore one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: First time it was the first Roger Moore.
Scott: One was Roger Moore.
Scott: You know, even though I like Sean Connery better than Roger Moore, Live and Let Die is like, you know, because there's the campy chase scene.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We have the boats and the cars and the ridiculous, you know, racist Southern cop guy.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it's like.
Scott: it's like the three way chase between Bond, the cops and the bad guys.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's got, you know, like the hovercraft going over the road to the other side.
Scott: You know, it's like that's a really good, you know, that's almost I'd say that like in terms of, you know, comedy car chases and movies from Hollywood, it's like Blues Brothers one, Live and Let Die two.
Rym: I believe that maybe number three is obviously Blues Brothers.
Scott: Way ahead.
Scott: Number one, not even close.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So you get you get stuff like that.
Scott: You get the comedy is always there in some aspects.
Rym: That's something a lot of people like.
Rym: I don't like the Pierce Brosnan movies because they just they feel really fakie.
Rym: But don't get me wrong.
Rym: They are funny and I appreciate that.
Rym: And some of the people who are mad about some later James Bond movies, they try to argue that, well, they're too funny or they're too like there's too much comedy injected.
Rym: But there's always been comedy that comes from the people who complain about the politics in Star Trek, in these newer Star Trek's like, what were you watching?
Scott: And then, you know, you have this mix going on where you sort of have the, you know, you know, serious spy stuff, right?
Rym: Like, you know, try to stop, you know, Cold War stuff, you know, the plots are actually kind of stupid and fakie.
Rym: There's always right, like megalomaniac, like exactly villain or this ridiculous magic weapon.
Scott: Yeah, it's something on the man.
Scott: It's a mad scientist, science fiction villain mixed with the real world, you know, dictator, evil communists or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Autocrat, you know, villains like combined into one.
Scott: So it pulls the wacky mad scientist down a bit to where it's not just, you know, nonsense.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it makes what would otherwise be like a really sort of uninteresting, boring, like a Tinker Tailor soldier's spy kind of spy thing.
Scott: And makes it more fun.
Rym: Yeah, because real spying would be more like, all right, he's dressed like a nerd and just quietly living in the city for a month writing things down.
Scott: Yeah, that's exciting.
Scott: And then on top of all that, you have these sort of Bond, you know, taglines.
Scott: don't have a cow man stirred.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, Q with a funny gadget and a car that shoots a missile.
Scott: The tropes and cliches, you know, that are, you know, they bring, you know, familiarity, nostalgia, fun, you know, whatever, to connect them all together.
Rym: Like if you've seen a few Bond movies and then you watch any random Bond movie, something in it will evoke specific memories from those other Bond movies.
Rym: Pick any three and you'll find connections between them like, oh, yeah, they all had a Gatling gun in the headlights of his car.
Rym: All three of them did.
Rym: Like, you'll always find something.
Scott: If you made if you tried to make some other movie and you did any of those things, like you've had a car with an ejector seat, right?
Scott: Someone's going to be like, that's a, you know, James Bond rip off right there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, you know, there are movies with cars and ejector seats, but but, you know, you just can't help but think of James Bond when you see that, because even if they weren't the first to do it, it's like it's like they just have ownership over, you know, some of those those things like that in some way.
Rym: I think it's worth pointing out that one aspect of Bond films that I personally appreciate, even though there's such a tiny part.
Rym: I mean, the music is fine, like they have their motif that they use, but specifically the opening credits in Bond.
Scott: Yeah, it's that's one of that's one of the nostalgia, you know, things, right.
Scott: And they always they always open every James Bond movie.
Scott: You know, you get the end media res action scene.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then it goes, you know, right.
Scott: It comes across the thing right with the shoots, the screen, right.
Scott: The blood comes down and then there's always the opening is always some sort of really artistic, you know, thing with lots of like silhouettes of naked people swimming and some song playing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's always a song for the movie.
Scott: The title of the song is the name of the movie.
Scott: Right.
Scott: One time, I think they got Madonna due to the song.
Scott: You know, it's always some big time song they pay to have made just for the movie.
Rym: I haven't seen some of the older bonds in a while, but I think the best opening sequence I can remember from any Bond movie is actually from Skyfall, even though Skyfall itself.
Rym: the entire end of that movie is absolutely stupid.
Scott: I mean, I can't remember which opening goes with which movies, so I can't really.
Rym: It's not a particularly good song and a particularly good like the theme.
Rym: It was a card theme that all the Daniel Craig movies have a similar sort of theming to them.
Scott: But the point is, it's you know, if you want to talk about which just the songs alone again, live and let die is a song that you will listen to.
Scott: No one's going to put on you only live twice, like just because they want to listen to that.
Rym: I am confident there are people who just listen to someone.
Scott: Well, right.
Scott: But, you know, live and let die is like it's like Paul McCartney wings.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know.
Scott: So, yeah, I guess what else is there to say?
Scott: Like some of the best ones, right?
Scott: If I say not, you know, I already said my favorite one is live and let die.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Best ones are going to be, you know, Thunderball.
Scott: Is really up there.
Scott: It's probably number one.
Rym: Thunderball's got a lot of very pack, like specifically tense scenes, especially when I was young and I hadn't seen a lot of James Bond movies yet.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Scott: Let's let me look at a list of them.
Rym: Yeah, I just found a list.
Scott: I'm trying to remember which one is which and miss one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I could just go down the list of ones we've seen and briefly comment.
Rym: I had not seen Moonraker until I played the N64 game.
Rym: And there was the Moonraker laser.
Rym: And I was like, oh, I guess I should see that James Bond movie.
Scott: Moonraker is fun for it's like if you're a kid, it's like super fun because it's all in space with lasers and Jaws and all that great stuff.
Scott: I actually had like some collectible Moonraker cards, like trading cards, which had photos from the movie printed on them.
Scott: But not really a great movie.
Scott: Think about it.
Rym: License to kill is the is the Timothy Dalton one I saw.
Rym: I never saw the living daylights.
Scott: That one has the best title.
Scott: license to kill is the best title because that's one of the sticks.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Sean Connery is a license to kill.
Scott: That's how come you can just go around shooting bad guys and not worry about it.
Rym: That was a fun thing about Casino Royale.
Rym: That opening scene is him just murdering a dude to get his 007 license.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I like you only live twice a lot.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because the whole the whole shtick like, you know, James Bond fakes his death and it's like a whole.
Scott: you know, the premise is really good.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The man with the golden gun.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: You know, it has that sort of Paradise Island thing going on.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I worry it doesn't hold up that well as a movie like it.
Rym: just it's a little too slow.
Scott: It's like he's going after the man with three nipples.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like, again, that's just really fun.
Scott: You know, shades of Goldfinger.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Somehow the bad guy is involved with gold.
Scott: In some way.
Rym: Well, that's because there's these recurring stories, this recurring arcs.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Like no time to die is all about.
Rym: Guess what?
Rym: Specter.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And Blofeld and Blofeld and like all that nonsense is back.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I guess Octopussy has that whole like, you know, the island vibe going on.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Setting right.
Scott: That's.
Scott: the other thing is that the James Bond movies always have like a different international setting.
Scott: There's a lot of traveling going on between locales.
Scott: All right.
Scott: The Faberg egg.
Scott: Right.
Scott: James Bond is like super worldly.
Scott: He's going all over the place to do his spy.
Scott: different countries, you know, and you get to see architecture and, you know, the, you know, local markets and, you know, industrial places that you get to see just a lot of stuff in these movies.
Scott: You know, you get some of the fun that you get by actually traveling the world.
Scott: You sort of feel that a little bit when you watch pretty much any one of these.
Scott: I don't think there are any that take place like strictly like in like London only.
Scott: It's like he only goes to London.
Scott: It's like go to the like.
Scott: there's any.
Scott: you know, I can't remember if you actually I used to do any do any spying there.
Scott: It's usually somewhere else.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Bond wouldn't work as like a one room play.
Rym: Like no, no, no story they tell could work like that.
Rym: It's always like, oh, we figured out the problem in London.
Rym: Now we've got to go to Jakarta to meet the guy to do the thing.
Scott: I forget which one it was.
Scott: Was it Tomorrow Never Dies or was it The World Is Not Enough that had...
Rym: What happens in it?
Rym: Because I watch most of the older ones, all the Roger Moore ones, I mostly watch on my grandparents giant projection TV when I was young.
Scott: It was it was The World Is Not Enough.
Scott: And all I could remember from The World Is Not Enough, 1999.
Rym: Yeah, that's I don't think I saw that one.
Scott: All I remember from that is that Denise Richards, who is really hot, like, wow, there's always which is the other aspect of Bond movies that perhaps, you know, especially the older ones that does not hold up so well is Extreme Misogyny and Male Gaze.
Scott: There's always several Bond ladies going on.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The fact that they're even called Bond ladies as if tells you everything.
Rym: So later Bond property, later Bond movies would try to either poke fun at that concept or invert it with varying degrees of success.
Scott: Yeah, well, not in 1999.
Scott: They weren't.
Rym: No, but like no time to die.
Rym: It was interesting because Bond meets a Bond woman at the point in a Bond movie where there would be that scene and she sits down and she takes off her wig and she starts undressing a little bit.
Rym: And he's like, you're moving fast.
Rym: And she's like, well, this is how you normally do, don't you?
Rym: Hi, I'm the 007 like they just inverted on him.
Rym: Then he meets another woman who he thinks is a Bond woman.
Rym: She's a CIA agent.
Rym: Every woman he meets is as skilled as him and is trying to trick him to do something.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, there were examples of that in older movies where the, you know, the Bond woman wasn't just some like, you know, do nothing.
Rym: But you just said it was.
Rym: it was always a wasn't.
Rym: just like they'd have one exactly quality one.
Rym: Right.
Scott: There would be.
Scott: there would be women who were capable spies, you know, on their own.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Strong and active and CIA agents or, you know, other aid, you know, cooperating agents of some kind.
Scott: But there was still a sexual element to it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know that it's like.
Scott: it's like, yeah, she's going to help me shoot some bad guys and then we're going to get it on.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was like, you know, or I'll be sad that she's dead and get it on with the one who's still alive at the end.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, a lot of James Bond movies end with James Bond getting it on in a train or a boat as the camera pulls away.
Rym: They also.
Rym: the first third has him get it on with the first Bond woman who then dies and drives him into the plot.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, you know, that that element of save and bang the girl is is there and is probably, I guess, the least good part.
Rym: Well, you know, if you want to see what like if you remove this because James Bond movies, they weren't all great.
Rym: Like, I enjoy them, but a lot of them are not great movies.
Scott: Well, I mean, I don't think, you know, even the you know, it's like, OK, I said Thunderball was the best one.
Scott: Agree or disagree, whatever.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It's not on my top ten movie list.
Scott: Thunderball deserves to win the best Oscar picture in the best picture Oscar in no year.
Scott: There is no year in which Thunderball is the best picture against any.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It's like, you know, so I feel like if you put that in theaters next to whatever was playing in eighteen ninety nine, you might have won an Oscar if there was an Oscar.
Scott: Find the year with like the shittiest movies you can find.
Scott: And I guarantee you that whatever won best picture that year that, OK, you know, it might not be that much better than Thunderball, but it's better.
Rym: But for because they were they were consistent enough and somehow it became an IP that Americans in particular, but also internationally, it became known.
Rym: not many not as many people remember the Flynn movies, which are basically knockoff bonds.
Rym: And imagine Bond without even this barest hint of self reflection and like adaptation to the times.
Rym: That's what the Flynn movies are like.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, there are plenty of, you know, action movies that focus on one dude who's a spy or agent or cop or.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, and it's like, you know, like, you know what, you know, some of them continued.
Scott: How many diehards are there or how many lethal weapons are there?
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, I guess, you know, they're slightly.
Scott: they each have their slight differences.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's still like there's an action hero in a series.
Scott: But they weren't able to carry on for, oh, 60 to 40, 60 fucking years plus.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's what as any movie series carried on that long, even close.
Rym: It's awesome.
Scott: I mean, we could see with the explosion, I guess Star Wars is, I guess, like 10, 20, 10 to 20 years younger, but it has way less movies, way less.
Scott: James Bond is like three or four or five times as many movies as Star Wars does.
Scott: Star Wars is nine.
Scott: Yeah, of course.
Rym: Now what we could see, it'll be really interesting to see if there start to be Bond TV shows or TV movies or streaming things instead of just pure traditional theatrical releases like every other company that owns a long running IP is doing.
Scott: Well, there was James Bond Junior.
Rym: There was James Bond Junior.
Scott: And was there I think there's James Pond, I believe.
Rym: I mean, there's lots of parodies of James Bond.
Scott: James Pond, underwater agent for the the Sega Genesis.
Rym: I know there were one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine James Bond movies before Star Wars was in theaters.
Scott: Yes, exactly.
Scott: There was.
Scott: I also wonder, right, you know, all these James Bond video games, you know, especially Goldeneye for N64.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But also I think, you know, I make fun of that game because, you know, I had a computer at the time.
Rym: But if you ignore the fact that, yes, technically there were computer FPS is if you were lucky enough to have a computer back then for most people in that era, Goldeneye was possibly the greatest video game they had ever seen.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, but it's like if not for Goldeneye, would James Bond have carried on?
Scott: Yeah, because remember, Goldeneye would have been able to make it from the 90s to the 2020s.
Rym: Well, Goldeneye, because also the movie remember Timothy Dalton might have killed James Bond like after license to kill.
Rym: That was nineteen eighty nine.
Rym: Goldeneye was nineteen ninety five.
Rym: You can go read a Wikipedia article on why there weren't Bond movies during that period.
Rym: A lot of it had to do with Bond.
Rym: wasn't that popular anymore.
Rym: And a lot of people were blaming Timothy Dalton or the writing.
Rym: There was a lot of debate as to what was going to happen to James Bond.
Rym: Pierce Brosnan and that franchise, like for whatever reason, nineteen ninety five was the year Bond exploded again.
Rym: It could just as easily have been a flop and ended Bond.
Scott: Yeah, especially when you think about like the amazing movies that came out in nineteen ninety five.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, you had.
Rym: I got to make sure I don't say a nineteen ninety six or nineteen ninety seven movie.
Scott: No, I think it was not.
Scott: I think it was ninety four were the good movies.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Scott is going to say ninety five.
Rym: You got Batman forever.
Rym: No, no.
Scott: Ninety four was the Rangers.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, Johnny, I think it was ninety three and ninety four.
Scott: So I guess maybe that's what happened.
Scott: is that, you know, in ninety three, ninety four, all those good movies came out.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then, you know, people are, you know, big on movies.
Rym: And then in ninety five, there's less Ventura to the net.
Rym: Oh, oh, twelve monkeys.
Scott: OK, it's not like every movie was good, you know, or bad.
Rym: Twelve Monkeys was good.
Rym: Billy Madison was good.
Rym: by a very narrow definition of it's the second best Adam Sandler movie.
Scott: Yeah, no, but like ninety three and ninety four were like some of the biggest movie years ever.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Tommy Boy, ninety five and a lot of movies that I remember.
Scott: Yeah, I made you say you were the right age then.
Rym: Yeah, that was an era when I was still going to the theater a lot and I had a lot of free time and I saw a lot of these movies in the theater.
Scott: Yeah, but I guess if ninety five had had weaker competition, seven, the Brady Bunch, Crimson Tide, The First Night, Waterworld.
Scott: Yeah, maybe that.
Scott: maybe it was timing that helped out to Goldeneye there a bit as well.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: A lot of big blockbusters in that time.
Rym: Also, there's a lot going on then, but also it was a reimagining of James Bond.
Rym: It turned him into a wizard, which at least worked like.
Rym: that was an era when movie effects were getting better and they could pull off crazier effects.
Rym: You got to say as much as I don't like Pierce Brosnan Bond movies, the action scenes are a lot tighter than the Sean Connery action scenes.
Rym: If you watch a Sean Connery Bond movie on a modern 4K screen, like a Blu-ray of it, the effects don't look great.
Scott: Well, for the time, though, it's I think, you know, the James Bond movies in terms of Hollywood effects and production occupy this place where, you know, they're not at the absolute Star Wars pushing the boundaries of what can be done right with with cameras and, you know, technology, computers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But what they are is high, high budget.
Scott: They always have a lot of money.
Rym: They were doing the best they could do for that era for like that.
Scott: Showing you like the best of what can be done with the established right stuff.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like if you think a car, if you watch a Sean Connery car chase and you're like, that wasn't that great.
Rym: I could see the rear projection.
Rym: Go watch any other car related scene from any movie released in that same year.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, you know, that's it's like it's always.
Scott: it's like a showcase of like, you know, not some, you know, push the the art form forward deal.
Scott: But it's like, you know, take the established right techniques that we and equipment and technology that you already have and just throw money at them, do it the best that it can be done by the book that's already been invented.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So James Bond wouldn't do like a Tron.
Scott: C.G.
Scott: before it's good ideal.
Rym: I guess the way it feels is if you watch original Star Wars movies, the lightsaber fights are like they work, but they're not great.
Rym: Like just the way the actors move.
Scott: They were great.
Scott: If you watch them, then they were.
Rym: But they weren't even anything better.
Rym: But they weren't even great by like sword fighting from contemporary movies standards.
Scott: What you know about sword fighting.
Rym: True, true.
Rym: But like watch, I don't know, Obi Wan's fight with Darth Vader and then immediately watch.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: That's like the weakest one.
Rym: It is.
Rym: But then but but that's also the best Star Wars movie.
Rym: So watch that and then watch, I don't know, Yoda fighting someone from a later Star Wars movie.
Rym: And you can see a lot of differences and you can make a lot of comparisons.
Rym: and the just the cinematography science is not quite as tight in the old movie in terms of like how to make the action scene look actiony.
Rym: But it's still a good scene.
Rym: And that's what I would say about the old Sean Connery bonds.
Rym: Like there's still even if you can see he's clearly driving in a fake car with the rear projection, the scene still like pulls you in.
Rym: You still like kind of forget that and start to be like, oh, shit.
Rym: When like he takes a sharp corner, the the the plausible like your body and your brain will agree that it is still a compelling scene despite seeing the seams around the edges.
Rym: That is the most high compliment I can give to old Bond movies.
Scott: Well, I mean, consider this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So Thunderball came out in sixty five.
Scott: And he's got the scene with the jet pack.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like by today's standards, it's you know, it's OK.
Scott: I can see what you did, how you made the jet pack happen.
Rym: I mean, the rocket here was in nineteen ninety one.
Rym: And that jet pack scene does not look that much better.
Scott: No, it doesn't.
Scott: But also look at other movies from nineteen sixty five.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like sci fi movies.
Scott: Like what?
Scott: I've never seen any of these that I just googled up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, you know, Nightcrawler from outer space, I guess, you know, it's like crack of the world.
Scott: I even know what that's about.
Scott: Voyage to the prehistoric planet.
Scott: It's like those are probably even more hackneyed looking.
Rym: Hey, Frankenstein meets the space monster.
Scott: Yeah, I'm going to hazard a guess and say that those are not pulling off the, you know, the dude in a dude in a costume or whatever thing, you know, very well.
Rym: So.
Rym: But yeah, what I guess I actually of all the James Bonds, I have enjoyed watching the Daniel Craig ones that I watched, which is only three of them.
Rym: And now after the show, I have this weird urge to go back and watch some older Bond movies.
Scott: Yeah, I feel like, you know, it would not be a waste of time, even if some of these, you know, are not the greatest.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like Timothy Dalton.
Rym: Some of these I just have like Timothy Dalton.
Rym: I remember this long scene with a helicopter and literally nothing else.
Scott: Yeah, I feel like it's really, you know, well, I said none of these are Oscar winners.
Scott: Maybe some of them are.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But I feel like it's not a waste of time to watch all of them.
Scott: Really, you know, maybe maybe I'll go back and catch up on, you know, whatever I want.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: You could get away with watching the first one that each actor made because.
Rym: They tend to be pretty similar.
Rym: Like the Sean Connery Bond movies didn't change that much from beginning to end.
Rym: From what I remember, I have not seen Dr.
Rym: No.
Rym: Since I watched it on a TV at my grandma's house.
Scott: Yeah, Dr.
Scott: No, you know, is one of those.
Scott: it's, you know, it's more mad scientisty if you couldn't tell by the title.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's, you know, it's with that the rocket at the end.
Scott: Yeah, it's like that's that's, you know, that for a kid, at least that makes it real exciting.
Scott: You know, the same way that Moonraker is exciting for a kid.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, so, yeah, James Bond, I think, you know, you know, it's a unique, you know, other big media property.
Scott: I think it's unique in a lot of ways.
Scott: It has positive and redeeming aspects.
Scott: It has bad aspects.
Scott: But I guess, you know, whether we want it to or not, it's going to.
Scott: they're going to keep making it as long as people keep putting money behind it and people keep going to see it.
Scott: And I think the only thing that could really kill it is if, you know, newer is interest.
Scott: Oh, if older generations die and newer generations don't pick up on it.
Scott: You know, I guess if you didn't have a mom who is a super James Bond fan putting it on all the time and you happen to also like it or if you haven't seen any, you probably I would recommend that you do.
Scott: It's it's.
Scott: you know, it's not as worth your time as watching legendary movies of, you know, the greatest.
Scott: But, you know, your life is, you know, it's short, but it's long enough that you've got time to watch some James Bond.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando Kay for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this end of hiatus GeekNights episode are Heidi McNichol, Alan Joyce, Link Idji, Dread Lily, Tenebrae and a bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names.
Rym: Chris Haddad, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Help Computer, Kishaya85, Rebecca Dunn, Review Madbull, 34 Coward, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Harl, Taylor Braun.
Rym: The next station is Wellesley, Wellesley station and several people whose names I will not say.
Rym: We're back.
Rym: Expect us to be on our pretty much regular schedule for a while.
Rym: I think we have enough in the hopper, though we'll have forgotten, as is GeekNights tradition, every possible opening bit, every possible anecdote, whatever you just got from this episode.
Rym: That was it.
Rym: We'll be grasping at straws come Monday.
Rym: But for now, I leave you simply with...
Scott: Who's the friendly little bee playing oh so happily, buzzing here and buzzing there, easy buzzing everywhere, Maya loves and Maya cares, Maya gives and Maya shares, Maya likes to play around, but she'll never let you down, Maya the Bee.
Rym: Maya, Maya the Bee, see her flying through the air, buzzing here and buzzing there, saying catch me if you dare, busy buzzing everywhere, Maya the Bee, Maya the Bee.