Rym: It's Thursday, November 17th, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: We're talking about Chinese food.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, once we get past the point where it's too cold to bike and it gets dark early because we, uh, stupidly leave daylight saving time and go back to bad time, there's this period between when I can ski and when I can't bike.
Rym: And while there's some hiking and a little bit of camping I can do there, I really would like it to just dump a bunch of snow and I could just go right into ski season.
Rym: So it turns out, upstate New York, right now, if you don't live in the northeast of the
Rym: U.S.,
Rym: you probably won't even know this is happening.
Rym: What might be, what is on track to be one of the larger snowstorms in New York State history is about to hit Buffalo and Rochester and is not even gonna bring a whisper to the other parts of New York State from what I can tell.
Scott: I mean, it's got the top parts and not the bottom parts.
Rym: Yeah, not even the top parts.
Rym: Only the western parts because this is not cold snow, this is lake effect snow, so it's only along the lake and nowhere else.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it's, uh, it's how it goes.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But, uh, based on the reporting I'm seeing today, they're projecting what might be, if the projections are true, it's going to be one of the largest snowfalls in that region in recorded history.
Scott: Potential historic lake effect snowstorm hammering Buffalo up to three or four feet expected.
Rym: That is, that would be cool, because I would like to have an excuse to not go anywhere.
Scott: It's also hitting up near the top parts of New York also, but, you know, near the lake up there, right?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: You know, it's not hitting any of the ski mountains in New York State.
Rym: Not even close.
Scott: Uh, there should be some mountains.
Scott: You gotta go way up there.
Rym: I mean, there really aren't mountains by the lakes.
Rym: The mountain, like Hunter Mountain, and then when you head further north, you're going to start going, uh, into other states.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: Check my map here.
Scott: There's no, there's no mountains up by, like, uh, what is this?
Rym: Yeah, yeah, remember, do you remember at any point at RIT, because even when I was poor, I would ski if I could.
Rym: I never really went skiing, did I?
Rym: There is no skiing anywhere near RIT.
Scott: You didn't have any money.
Rym: Even if I did, there's nowhere to ski.
Rym: And also, you can get into ski resorts real cheap or free if you know what you're doing.
Scott: Yeah, there might be some snow if you go up to, like, you know, Saranac area, Lake Placid area, but it won't be as much as it is down low.
Scott: But, like, lakes are low, right?
Scott: They're down.
Rym: Yeah, but also this storm, this specific storm, is going to be lake effect snow, and lake effect storms are very regional.
Rym: And this is a traditional storm that happens over that specific lake between Michigan and New York.
Rym: Yep, so, uh, in the news, the American midterm elections happen.
Rym: And in an interesting twist, for those of you who aren't Americans, of course, American voters are by and large fickle, kind of stupid, random, never mind all the gerrymandering and evil that happens.
Rym: But there's a trend that is so common and so repeatable that it is like a conventional wisdom.
Rym: Whenever we have a president who is elected in one of our major elections, which happen every four years, no matter what party that president is, the issues literally don't matter.
Rym: Whatever party they are not in will invariably win Congress in the midterm election.
Rym: that happens between those four-year elections.
Rym: So every two years, we have a midterm election.
Scott: Right, so the basic logic is that, you know, basically people who are voting are always cranky.
Scott: You don't get a lot of happy voters who are saying, "Things are
Scott: great!".
Scott: That's pretty rare for things to be great, right?
Scott: Now, think, when have things been great?
Scott: What year?
Scott: What year was that when everyone felt that everything was awesome?
Rym: I mean, no year that I was alive.
Scott: Right, no year.
Scott: So, basically, whoever's president, right, gets, you know, from people who, you know, whether even people who are paying attention and understand how government works, even those people psychologically give credit and blame to the president, even though...
Rym: It's unwarranted, like the president doesn't control gas prices, but yet that's a specific thing people get mad about in America.
Scott: Right, so when people vote, it's like, you know, there are some people who actually, you know, say, "Well, these are my policies.
Scott: This is what I believe in, and this is the party that most closely matches that, and I'll vote for
Scott: them.".
Scott: And there are some people who just basically have some other logic, name recognition, who knows what their logic is, right?
Scott: And a common logic is, "I'm upset.
Scott: This party, this color is in charge, and there I don't like what the way the world is now, so I'm gonna vote the other color, and then when that one's in charge and it sucks, they'll vote the other
Scott: color.".
Scott: They just keep doing this, and it's like, can you actually meet an individual who will tell you that that's what they believe?
Scott: Maybe not, but if you look at the voting results, that pattern is there, right?
Rym: We're doing some work training, and at work I'm getting trained on like data science, and it's actually like really easy stuff.
Rym: I already knew, but this is like broad training for a lot of people.
Rym: And the API and the model we used as an example in the course was, "Predict who someone will vote for based on factors," and the lab guides you to the fact that zip code and race is literally all that matters.
Scott: -I mean, population density, but that's zip code.
Rym: -That's zip code.
Scott: -Yeah, but yeah, so it that it.
Scott: currently the president is Democrat, therefore it would be expected in this election, right?
Scott: You know, just the way things go for there to be a shift to the red side when the blue side is in charge.
Scott: That's, you know, it's same thing happened, right?
Scott: When Republicans are president the next election, shift over to the blue side.
Rym: -And we're talking like in our house, which has over 400 seats, like for you not Americans, a shift of like plus 30 or plus 40 seats in the opposite direction.
Rym: These are usually big shifts.
Rym: So America went into this election in our usual, you know, existential crisis on the verge of just falling apart into chaos and civil war and whatever, and the Democrats actually lost almost nothing.
Rym: They barely are losing the house.
Rym: This was like a, they still lost.
Scott: -They are losing it.
Scott: They are losing it, so it's lost, but they're losing it by like a handful, right?
Scott: And that handful, if, you know, New York specifically hadn't had some gerrymandering drama, might not have, they might not have lost the house.
Rym: -Oh yeah, we could have moved the house.
Scott: -I mean, and it also bears repeating, even though everyone knows this already, that without gerrymandering, the Democrats would never lose the house ever.
Scott: Like if you just count the total number of votes, right, and did a proportional representation in the house, the Democrats would be way, way ahead.
Rym: -I mean, without gerrymandering on the state level, America would have the Democrats, who were like the center-right party, and some other minority party that was the left party.
Rym: The right wing would barely...
Scott: -But the point is, is that, you know, did they, you know, even though there was the shift to the red side, as expected, and it was much less than expected in terms of the real results that matter, the vast majority of the people voting, well, I don't know vast, but the majority of the people voting voted blue.
Rym: -Actually, this election, a slight majority voted red.
Rym: It's just, there's been a separate change.
Rym: -Really?
Rym: -Yeah, there's been a separate change.
Rym: Districts that are already safely red are getting redder and redder and redder.
Rym: Like, right wing people get all of the votes.
Rym: And meanwhile, the blue districts, like in New York City, Republicans made huge gains, but if you look at the map...
Scott: -But only in South Brooklyn.
Rym: -In three neighborhoods, North Brooklyn, in one specific neighborhood, South Brooklyn, in another specific neighborhood, and Staten Island.
Rym: -Right.
Rym: -Nowhere else.
Scott: -We gotta say, those neighborhoods are the kind of places that, you know, voted Democrat, but they were voting for people like Cuomo, right?
Scott: It's like, they are the kind of people who, you know, well, Staten Island was full of Trumpy people, right?
Scott: So that's different, right?
Scott: But South Brooklyn is full of the kind of person who, you know, it's like, you know, you imagine, when you go to those neighborhoods, right?
Scott: Obviously, you know, I'm not going to stereotype everyone who lives in those neighborhoods because it's very diverse.
Rym: -Biking through those neighborhoods, a lot of Trump flags, for one.
Scott: -Right, but just like the rest of New York City, right, you know, those neighborhoods are very diverse, but the feeling of those neighborhoods and, I guess, a large portion of the population there are, like, what you might imagine as, like, an old New Yorker, right?
Scott: Some old Brooklyn mafia guy or, you know, some old Russian guy, right?
Scott: That's what I think of when I think of those neighborhoods.
Rym: -Or tight-knit, insular, religious communities that vote as a bloc.
Scott: -Well, that's the Northern Brooklyn.
Rym: -Yep, who, this election, mostly went Republican.
Scott: -Yeah, I mean, they have always.
Scott: -Yep.
Scott: -But the thing is, those people would vote, you know, Democrat when they saw a person like, you know, an Andrew Cuomo, who is a lot like them, right, on the, as the person to vote for, right?
Scott: But, and, you know, against, say, you know, like, they would prefer a Cuomo to a Trump, that sort of, right, demographic, right?
Scott: But, when you have, like, a woman running for governor, that kind of demographic is going to be, like, right?
Scott: Because they're still misogynist and whatnot and sexist and all those other things, right?
Scott: And so, then, you know, that kind of person, especially, you know, who's watching the news too much and believing all the lies about crime rates and all that, what nonsense, right?
Scott: -Yep.
Scott: -That person then would vote for, I guess, the person who, thankfully, will not be the governor of New York, Zeldin, who is basically a Trump guy pretending not to be.
Rym: -Yep, he, they are, the whole narrative for all the people outside of the city in this state was, basically, "Crime is high, therefore, we should go full fascist," and that was kind of Zeldin's actual message.
Scott: -Yeah, I mean, that's always the message, right?
Rym: -But he was polling so well.
Scott: -We've had, we've had strong, you know, it's like, there's no logic to it, right?
Scott: It's simply, it's, it's, it's a straight appeal to emotion and, you know, the simplicity, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, and it's been going on for, for decades and decades.
Rym: -But there's so many things wrong with it.
Rym: It's not even just, "Oh, crime is not actually historically up by these wide
Rym: margins.".
Scott: -Well, no, no, first of all, no, the first thing you have to say, you got to realize, is that when the, when the politicians come out and say, "Crime is high," right, they don't mean, "Crime is
Scott: high."
Scott: What they're saying is black, right?
Scott: That's what they're saying, right?
Scott: They're saying, "Black is high," right?
Scott: It's like, there's.
Scott: no, they're, right, they're saying, "Vote for me," right?
Scott: "I am, I am white, and I will, I will send the, I'll have more police and take care of the black
Scott: people.".
Rym: -But also, even if, even if somehow crime were really high, they're also saying, "We're just going to flood the streets with cops and make everyone's lives worse.
Rym: They're not actually going to do anything about
Rym: crime.".
Scott: -Well, I think, well, they, the problem is, is that people, I think even people on the left, right, just not the extreme left, like us, right, it's like, people just sort of have this, they don't think about it too hard, right?
Scott: They don't investigate it, they're not taught it, right?
Scott: They just sort of have this, you know, really simple logic of like, you know, "Oh, there is crime, therefore
Scott: police.".
Scott: The same way you would think, "There's fire, therefore
Scott: water.".
Scott: Or, "There's a mess, therefore paper
Scott: towels.".
Rym: -But whereas if something's on fire, a firefighter will come and put that fire out and try to help you.
Scott: -The problem is, is that very simple logic, right, is like, "Yes, water does put out fires.
Scott: Yes, paper towel does clean up
Scott: messes.".
Rym: -But police don't put out crime.
Scott: -Police don't solve crime.
Scott: That's a, it's just a wrong thing, right, as people don't realize that that's wrong, and it's very hard to convince someone that's wrong, because it's such a basic ingrained thing.
Rym: -Like, there was this thing that just happened recently in New York City, where if someone got attacked on the subway, while that's very rare, it's not zero, and there was a cop there on the platform.
Rym: Cop didn't do shit, cop just cleaned up after it was over, he didn't help anybody.
Scott: -Police don't prevent crimes, right?
Scott: They just don't, even if you, even if the, what if everyone in society was a cop?
Scott: It's like, would there still be crime?
Scott: It's like, it's like, we've spent billions and billions of dollars on cops, they're already everywhere, and crime goes up.
Scott: You know, the, it's obvious that if cops worked, there wouldn't be crime.
Rym: -Even worse, people talk about how, "Oh, well, they show up, you know, they deal with the fallout from crime, the side effects of crime, they investigate crime, they solve
Rym: crime.".
Rym: No, they don't.
Rym: The rate at which crimes, major crimes, are solved has not risen with increased police at all in America anywhere.
Scott: -No, but anyway, but the point is, is that you, racist people will campaign, right, on crime, the media will cooperate because, you know, television, all they have to show on nightly news is crime, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, in New York City, even if the crime rate is low, it's like, there will be a handful of crimes every day, even if we reduce crime, and New York's already has less crime and is safer than most other places there are, period.
Scott: -Yeah.
Scott: -It's just that the rate is so low, but the population is so high, there's always gonna be some, some crime to report on, so if you watch New York Nightly News, no matter what year it is, no matter what the crime rate is, they've got crime stories to lead, right, that will terrify people who are watching the news, right, and convince them to vote for some candidate who comes out and says, "Yeah, crime's a problem.
Scott: The news isn't doing it because they want a particular candidate,".
Scott: at least in most cases, some cases they do, but the news is doing it because that's what drives ratings, right, and it hurts our whole society in this way, and notice as soon as the, the day the election's over, crime's not a problem anymore, right, suddenly crime is, crime is not, right, it's like, the news is still showing those stories, but the politicians aren't talking about it anymore the day after the election.
Rym: -Except our piece of shit mayor who, after the election announced he's gonna end all cash bail reforms because that is, quote, "Why the Democrats lost
Rym: upstate.".
Scott: -Well, that's it, right, it's, whatever, we could talk about that all day.
Rym: -Yeah, but there's something else that happened that I think is real important to touch on briefly.
Rym: In New York State, we lost a seat in the House because the state is losing population.
Rym: Let's not get into the fact that the census was not run very well.
Scott: -Who knows if we really lost population or not.
Rym: -But the city gained population, the state overall lost population, but the state, the state could gerrymander itself.
Rym: We could draw the districts in New York State to where there is one Republican and everyone else is a Democrat.
Rym: We kind of tried to.
Rym: That got thrown out by the courts by the judges who were appointed by Cuomo.
Rym: -Right, well, well supported by Cuomo, appointed by Republicans.
Scott: -Okay, so New York, rightly, you know, I guess in principle at least, right, has some rules to prevent, you know, horrific gerrymandering.
Rym: -Most blue states do, and most red states don't.
Rym: -Right,
Scott: if every place had those rules, it would be all good, but basically they handcuffed themselves into having these rules in the first place, so that's mistake number one, right, and then mistake number two was it's like, okay, they went to go and follow the procedures that, you know, that were within the law that they created, right, and they tried to push it as far as they could, but because that law was there, they couldn't push it that far, and then what Rym just said is that, you know, it was up to some judges to decide, and Cuomo, a Democratic governor, the previous governor, right, who, you know, was forced to resign because he was such a piece of shit, he put Republic, even though he's a Democrat, he put in Republican judges, right, that's why those South Brooklyn people are okay voting for him because he was that kind of person.
Rym: -So, basically, New York State might be the reason the Democrats didn't somehow hold the House.
Scott: -Right, it was like a couple seat tilt, the fact that, you know, New York didn't gerrymander as hard as it could have, right, could have gotten an extra seat or few, which would have tilted the entire country.
Scott: -Yeah,
Rym: but to put this to a positive light, the thing you should take away is not New York State drama, like New York State, we got to start this out, and I think it's doable because there aren't that many, it's not that often there'll be a Zeldin-like figure that can drag voters who normally don't vote in the state to the polls, but this was actually a huge victory for democracy and for Democrats.
Rym: The fact that we're holding on to the Senate and we're holding on to enough power to where they can't, the Republicans can't fuck things up too badly over the next two years, and it seems like the primary reason this happened is a lot of swing states went pretty hard blue, a lot of swing districts went pretty hard blue, the primary reason was abortion.
Rym: They take trying to ban abortion nationally, they pushed too far, and the backlash was real.
Rym: -Yeah,
Scott: you know, people don't care about, you know, the thing, if Republicans are doing evil shit, you know, Trump doing evil shit when he was president, right, and people, it wasn't going to change people's votes if he was, you know, running, you know, genocide camps for, you know, migrants crossing the border down south.
Scott: because those people who were voting for Trump are unaffected by that other than they see it on the news, and when they see it on the news they kind of like it because they're sadistic and evil, right?
Scott: -Right.
Scott: -But if the Republicans actually do something that impacts people's lives in a noticeable way, directly, immediately, right, then yeah, that's, you know, that's going to turn people out, right, so that's why gas prices turn people out and abortion is going to turn people out.
Rym: -So don't walk away.
Scott: -Basically do whatever you want as, you know, if you're running the country, it's like you don't have to follow your principles or what you said because only nerds who are paying attention to politics pay attention to that or care, right, but to get the votes of the mass populace, the things that affect their everyday lives, right, or that they believe affect their everyday lives like crime.
Rym: -So I want to, I want you to take away from this election that this was actually a surprising victory and a hopeful one, like this, this puts us in a way better position than a lot of people expected.
Rym: Do not buy into a media narrative that Democrats fucked this up or somehow in disarray, but the Democrats honestly did the best that anyone's ever done in this kind of situation before in all of American history.
Rym: So you got any news, Taylor Swift?
Scott: -Well, it's not Taylor, it's not Taylor Swift's news, right?
Scott: It's Ticketmaster news, right?
Scott: So Taylor Swift came out with the album, right?
Scott: People love it, I don't even listen to it, I don't really care, it's not my deal.
Scott: If you like it, good for you, congrats, you know, anyway.
Scott: -Congrats?
Rym: This reminds me of way back, I met some co-workers' kid and the kid was like, "Oh, how old are
Rym: you?".
Rym: And the kid was like, "I'm
Rym: seven.".
Rym: And I was like, "Oh, congratulations, good
Rym: job.".
Rym: And everyone's like, "Wait,
Rym: what?".
Scott: -I mean, there are people who are like, you know, they're like huge, huge fans, like this is like a big deal for them.
Rym: -They call themselves Swifties.
Scott: -Congratulations.
Rym: -And no, we're not talking about the Global International Payments Network.
Scott: -I mean, there are people, like Swifties are like, you know, actual like people in the fan club, like big time, right?
Scott: But it's like, you know, Taylor Swift's music goes beyond just the fan club, it's like everybody, right?
Scott: At least almost everybody.
Scott: Anyway, the point is, is that she's going on the tour, right?
Scott: And the tickets go on sale, so obviously it's going to be, you know, big time packing, right?
Scott: It's like, yeah, you got people reloading, you got your freaking scalpers, you got the bots.
Rym: -It's the same as PAX, we've talked about this a million times, the unsolvable problem.
Scott: -Right.
Scott: No matter, right, so beyond the unsolvable problem, right, the fact is, is that Ticketmaster, during the pre-sale, right, in which case, in the pre-sale is basically, it's on sale, but you need a special code, but everyone fucking knows the code, right?
Scott: So it's basically when it's on sale, right?
Scott: When the tickets go on sale, so many people hit Ticketmaster, it went down, right?
Scott: Because it's not that great.
Scott: And now you can go, and I think even John Oliver had a thing about Ticketmaster, but like, there are so many places, if you want to read about what's wrong with Ticketmaster, you can read and learn everything that's wrong with them, right?
Scott: All the problems with scalping, and how most of the tickets don't even get to the Ticketmaster, they're already sold, or, you know, sectioned off for other people, and how Ticketmaster's a monopoly, and obviously antitrust would go a long way towards solving that problem, and such and such and such, right?
Scott: But Ticketmaster went down, and now basically, there's going to be the real sale is going to come, but the real sale, first of all, most of the tickets are already gone.
Scott: There's like not many left, because they were all in the pre-sale, which is the real sale, right?
Scott: It's like, but there were, you know, there's supposed to be a time at which they're just on sale, with no code necessary for the people who couldn't look on Twitter and find the code, okay?
Scott: So, but they're going to cancel that, because like, we can't handle the number of people who are going to come in, and there's almost no tickets left anyway, right?
Scott: There's like going to be a million people trying to fight over like 20 tickets per showing, or whatever concert, right?
Scott: So they just canceled that whole thing, and now that's a big ticketmaster that I think a lot of people don't realize in this discussion, right?
Scott: Is that forgetting about all the issues that everyone already knows about, and have already been discussed to death, the issue that is not discussed to death is that Ticketmaster, the company, their customer is not people who are buying tickets.
Scott: Their customer is not even the scalpers, even though they are very friendly with the scalpers who are going to, you know, run their spots and buy all the tickets and get margins or whatever, right?
Scott: Ticketmaster's only customer are venues, buildings in which concerts, sports, theater, and other major events that are ticketed happen.
Scott: That is the only person that Ticketmaster gives a fuck about, right?
Scott: Because as they get with those venues, the venues sign an exclusive contract, right?
Scott: And now Ticketmaster doesn't give a shit about anything that happens after that, because number one, as long as the events happen in the venues and the venue is running itself, the tickets will get sold, right?
Scott: Someone is going to see that concert, right?
Scott: And how many people see the concert has no relation to which ticket vendoring service the venue has chosen, and Ticketmaster will get a cut of all those tickets no matter what.
Scott: It's like, it doesn't fucking matter if they provide a good service or a bad service or if buying the tickets is nice or convenient or if it's a pain in the ass, right?
Scott: It doesn't matter, right?
Scott: The Taylor Swift concert in that venue will sell out, no matter if it was Ticketmaster, Eventbrite, Telecharge, Scott Rubin's ticket company, doesn't fucking matter, right?
Scott: Those tickets will get sold and the company that sells the tickets will get a service charge and every ticket sold.
Scott: End of story.
Scott: So Ticketmaster, all they have to do, the only people that they have to sell to are the venue, to convince the venue to sign an exclusive deal with Ticketmaster and not with somebody else.
Rym: Now if you think the venues have any interest in altering this arrangement, well, we've been through this before.
Rym: Pearl Jam had a huge public fight with Ticketmaster over the same issue back when I was in like middle school, and guess what?
Rym: Fucking nothing happened.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Okay, so as long as Ticketmaster, as soon as Ticketmaster gets that deal signed with the venue, they have that pile of money from that venue for the term of that deal, the end.
Scott: The rest of it, nothing else matters, right?
Scott: As long as Ticketmaster gets the ticket sold and stays up enough, right, and provides enough service to sell the tickets, they're good, right?
Scott: It doesn't matter how shitty it is as long as it gets the tickets sold.
Scott: So what would convince a venue to leave Ticketmaster?
Scott: Well, Ticketmaster would have to fuck up so royally that tickets don't get sold, right?
Scott: It's like, "Ah, why is this Taylor Swift thing that should be full only half full because your site's been down that
Scott: much?".
Scott: That would be a problem.
Scott: That will never happen.
Scott: Ticketmaster stays up enough for that to not happen, right?
Scott: What else could convince a venue to leave Ticketmaster?
Scott: Well, you would have to have a competitor to Ticketmaster, right, that can a) less service charge.
Scott: That way the venue keeps more money, right?
Scott: Money talks, right?
Scott: But b) your new service has to be proven, right?
Scott: Their venue is not going to take a risk, right?
Scott: They know Ticketmaster is a safe bet.
Scott: So your thing has to be proven to work, right?
Scott: As proven as Ticketmaster is, which is, you might say, not very proven, but it's like, they got the ticket sold, right?
Scott: So you have to be, the venue is not going to take any risks, right?
Scott: That if they switch to you and piss off Ticketmaster and can't go back to them, that not all the tickets will get sold properly.
Rym: And not just got all the tickets sold, but handled all the logistics related to how those tickets are redeemed.
Scott: That's the last thing, right, is that you don't, people think, when they think about ticketing, they're just thinking about the base problem, right?
Scott: There are X tickets.
Scott: Each one is unique.
Scott: You have to distribute them and price them and whatnot and show a seat map and the basic, right, that part.
Scott: There are so many edge cases in the ticketing business of things that happen behind the scenes, in front of the eye, on the side.
Scott: Different venues have different requirements, laws and regulations in different states.
Scott: Just so many fucking different things you have to deal with.
Scott: People returning tickets, you know, someone wants to sell it.
Scott: It is so handy, just, you know, tickets for people with disabilities and special areas, right?
Scott: There's so many edge cases that you have to deal with.
Scott: And Ticketmaster, having been in the business so long and having, you know, control of every venue already handles 100% of those use cases.
Scott: All of them.
Scott: Ticketmaster, that's why behind the scenes, I've seen Ticketmaster systems behind the scenes.
Scott: They're garbage because it's some conglomerate, it's a mess of duct tape and old bad code.
Scott: But that piece of shit, old system, it handles every use case, all of them, every single use case is handled.
Scott: So your competing system has to handle 100% of the use cases.
Scott: If you handle 99% of the use cases and you go to a venue and once in that venue, that use case might be ultra rare.
Scott: It happens like once a year, right?
Scott: But Ticketmaster handles it.
Scott: It'll, it'll just work.
Scott: And you don't, you don't have code for that yet because you haven't been in this business a hundred years and you don't have a code base with, you know, decades of institutional knowledge in it.
Scott: They're not going to go with you.
Scott: They're going to go with something that doesn't meet all their needs, right?
Scott: So you have to meet more use cases that Ticketmaster, or at least as many.
Scott: And even if you did that, it's like, okay, we do everything that Ticketmaster does.
Scott: And we've proven that we're reliable and right.
Scott: We're going to charge you less money than Ticketmaster does.
Scott: First of all, how is it even possible for a new company to do all those things?
Rym: I mean, uh, there's the secondary market companies that even they're struggling to get into that like secondary market, right?
Scott: It's like, there is no way to convince a venue to go with you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the, you know, the obvious is the antitrust thing would be good, right?
Rym: I think that's the only way to solve this would be government action, which with our current structure is I think, I think, right.
Scott: Well, yes, maybe.
Scott: But I think, yes, a government action, but not just an antitrust government action.
Scott: I think you simply need a government action that says that clearly defines the process and procedures.
Scott: right for selling tickets, right?
Scott: When there is an event, it's like, you may not, right.
Scott: It has to specifically prescribe, like you can't set aside tickets.
Scott: Every seat in the venue must be made publicly, right?
Rym: You can't, you know, I don't think such measures would be popular among even just regular people who want to go to events.
Scott: I think you could, it depends what they are, right?
Scott: You have to be very careful with this and you have to, it's going to have to be really complicated, right?
Scott: You're going to have to worry about all different kinds of events and different venues, right?
Scott: You know, but you can at least have some more, you know, guidelines, right?
Scott: Where it's like.
Scott: basically the way tickets are sold is completely, you know, defined by Ticketmaster and the venues, they in the, and the, you know, the, the people putting on the shows, right?
Scott: They just decide amongst themselves what's best for them.
Scott: And the, the, the ticket buyer has no input on the process of ticket distribution, right?
Scott: So the government simply has to come in as the representative of the people and be the input on, well, you know what, we don't want to have our say as the people who attend the events, we should have some say in the method of ticket distribution.
Rym: It should be a lot like the passenger bill of rights that we can't actually like fully realize with airlines.
Scott: That's a similar thing, right?
Scott: The airlines run the airlines and the airports with the way they want to, but there is an FAA that does put some regulations down.
Rym: With a little heavier hand.
Rym: And they should say things like, if you bump someone on voluntarily, you owe them like a hundred thousand dollars.
Rym: Fuck you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You, you know, make it so that like, yes, you have to, if, if the demand for the show is too high, you have to use some sort of random allotment system, right?
Scott: You can't take a greater percentage of the tickets of the, in the total venue space and set them aside for VIPs or whatever, right?
Scott: You have to let the public in, right?
Scott: If you're going to sell tickets to the public, you know, you can't just, you know, get sold them to yourself as like, right.
Scott: You know, the service charges can only be so high, right?
Scott: All these kinds of rules you can put in there and that would go a long way towards fixing it because.
Rym: Well, the problem is there's no actual incentive for anyone to fix this.
Rym: Nobody cares about this enough to vote because of it.
Rym: Nobody is willing to say, well, fuck that.
Rym: I won't go see Taylor Swift.
Rym: If they're a Taylor Swift fan, they're just going to suck it up.
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: So they'll do whatever they have to do to see.
Rym: Well, literally never talk about this issue because the last thing they want is any complication or disruption.
Rym: The artists.
Scott: Well, the one, the one thing that could disrupt them that has come close to happening right is taxes, right?
Scott: Ticket taxes.
Scott: They are terrified of ticket taxes.
Rym: Why do you think so many nerd conventions have memberships and badges, but they don't have tickets.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: But the point is, is that there have been lots of discussions in like state legislatures.
Scott: Remember in New York, you know, maybe a decade ish ago.
Scott: I want to say, right.
Scott: It's like, there was almost going to be some, you know, big ticket event tax coming down.
Scott: And they were like, fuck, fuck, fuck.
Scott: They sent the lobbyist army out because if that went through, that would have shut down several ticket based businesses, basically.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, because, you know, the margin goes down or the price goes up and then it's like, you know, whoever's some middleman taking a cut is now suddenly out because everyone else needs to get up.
Rym: Now, of course, there is the underlying problem that the only reason there's a middleman taking a cut on secondary market scalping, all of that is because the demand is higher than supply and the price is lower than the price point.
Rym: People are willing to pay.
Rym: And that is an unsolvable problem.
Scott: Even if even if they raise the prices to what people are willing to pay just from the outset.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's still.
Scott: you're still going to have, you know, these systems of unfair distribution because it's like you can't raise the.
Scott: it's like there's like.
Scott: it's like, OK, we'll make the Taylor's tickets a thousand dollars.
Scott: They still sell out.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like three thousand.
Scott: It's like a what?
Scott: It's like you're either going to get.
Scott: there's no line you can draw where either a there's enough there's more people that will pay the ridiculous price than there are seats or once you get too high, it's like, OK, well, now you can't even.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: it's like it's almost like there's a single dollar line.
Scott: It's like, well, there is.
Rym: And that's that's why one thing you can do is go from on that line.
Scott: You go from complete sell out to like half empty because it's like, OK, I'll pay four thousand.
Scott: But five thousand.
Scott: It's like, no, no one can afford.
Rym: That's why you do one of those auction styles where the first ten tickets are ten thousand dollars each.
Rym: And if they don't get sold, the allotment grows to twenty and the price drops to nine thousand nine hundred ninety nine dollars.
Rym: And it just slowly ticks down until until they're all sold.
Scott: I think some system like that, but you'd have to remove the waiting and the and the work, right?
Scott: Everyone would just go and type in the amount they're willing to pay.
Scott: And then the system would just do it and email you whether you got to.
Rym: But then, of course, only rich people ever go to any major event again ever.
Scott: But it's already kind of only there's only so many Ferraris made every year.
Scott: Only rich people drive them.
Scott: It's not any different.
Scott: There are plenty of other events that are less popular.
Rym: Meanwhile, I'm going to see Emily and I are going to go see Perov Stelar in concert in like February at in New York.
Scott: Is it is it sold out?
Rym: It was not sold out over the weekend when I checked and tickets were like fifty bucks like G.A.
Scott: because that's not.
Scott: that's not some huge show.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You know, I just I don't.
Rym: I basically generally avoid huge things.
Rym: The only huge thing I'll go to regularly is hockey.
Rym: And we just have season tickets that we share.
Rym: So half a season share a shared half a season because, yeah, an actual season would be, well, as much as I love hockey, I could not use an entire season.
Scott: We would need some more people in.
Rym: Yeah, we would.
Rym: That would that would be.
Rym: I like hockey, but I like hockey enough to go to.
Scott: if I was retired, I could do it.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Well, if I can retire, if if a world exists where I can retire, I absolutely would love to be the kind of old New York guy who has a range of season ticket.
Rym: I don't even care.
Rym: Give me a terrible ticket.
Rym: Just go to every home game.
Rym: Be the guy where people recognize my voice.
Scott: I mean, if you want to do it economically, you could buy them like you would buy them last second tickets from on the second hand market.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I'm an old man.
Scott: The thing is, that would never get you into like the crowded, sold out games that only get you into.
Rym: You know, you want to be the old man who's been sitting in the same seat for 20 years and like people around you know how annoying you are.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So I got to step through a little history for this thing of the day because I'm going to link to first.
Rym: This was like a TikTok meme from not even that long ago.
Rym: Get the fuck out of here.
Rym: And it's just this little like short video that was kind of funny.
Scott: I didn't see the meme until Rym sent it to me.
Rym: I did not see the meme.
Rym: I did not know the meme existed.
Rym: I started playing Disco Elysium.
Rym: And one of the most popular videos about Disco Elysium is actually a meme where someone has recreated that TikTok meme in Disco Elysium with the characters in a way that makes sense to the characters.
Rym: And it's really well done.
Rym: But my thing of the day is someone has taken the concept of the meme and galaxy-brained it into the test chamber from the opening scene of Half-Life 1. very well.
Rym: It is funny on its own.
Rym: If you understand the meme, it makes sense.
Rym: If you understand Half-Life, it makes sense.
Rym: And that is my thing of the day.
Scott: This would be like if we never did the original Steamed Hams and we just went straight to a Steamed Hams variation as like the first thing of the day.
Rym: We are already two transformations deep from the original meme.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Okay, my thing of the day.
Scott: So we got a problem in that we have a thing of the day policy of not using things of the day from the same source repeatedly.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: Otherwise, PBS SciShow would have been my last 20.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But we have another problem in that magicians are doing amazing magic tricks, right?
Scott: Are an often somewhat frequent source of things of the day, even since early days of GeekNights, because nerds like magic, right?
Scott: But the problem is that there's really only one major big platform for magicians to get attention on a large scale these days, which is a single television show.
Scott: Penn and Teller's fool us, right?
Scott: And that's why the show it's like, it's like, it's just like some show on CW, but it's still going, right?
Scott: That show's been going on for a long ass time.
Scott: It's still going on.
Scott: And it's like, yes, because that is, it's like, not like back in the day where you could be David Copperfield and get your own special or be Penn and Teller and get your own TV special.
Scott: that stands alone.
Scott: That doesn't happen anymore, right?
Scott: The only way for a magician to get like larger and more well known, right?
Scott: Is to be on that show, right?
Scott: And that's, I think largely why the show exists.
Scott: And it's a good thing the show exists.
Scott: Um, so, but the problem is anything in the day we do of a magician is probably going to be them on that show.
Scott: So, um, but what they, one good thing the show does that I like a lot is when people appear on that show, the show lets them post a video clip of their performance on their own YouTube channel.
Scott: So if I were to go on the show somehow, even though I can't do any magic tricks whatsoever, not even fucking cup and balls.
Rym: I mean, you, you, you can do magic tricks on the level of my thumb disappeared.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Not, not, I'm not even that good at that one though.
Scott: Um, then I would be able to legally post the video of me on that show on the GeekNights, YouTube channel, right?
Scott: They would let me legally do that on purpose.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And so that's like, if you go on YouTube and you search for fool us, you start seeing results from all these different magicians channels.
Scott: So this particular one, someone posted in the forum, I hadn't seen before.
Rym: I've seen a lot because I've gone down the rabbit hole of this individual within 15 seconds of their, uh, opening video on their channel.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I've watched, you know, I've gone on YouTube and watched full us performances for like an hour at some point, right?
Scott: Just seeing a whole bunch of them.
Scott: Um, especially the ones that fool them.
Scott: Cause those are the better ones.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: But this one, I hadn't seen someone posted it in our forum, which you should go to.
Scott: And it is a card magician, primarily a card magician named Danny Dortiz from Mexico.
Scott: And this guy is I think supposedly, and I believe it, the best living card magician, right?
Scott: Like he was an apprentice of some other legendary card magician and as somehow the, the apprentice has surpassed the master.
Scott: I don't know if the master is still alive.
Scott: He was an old guy, but like for like, they say that like from the age of four, Danny studied under this guy and it's like, I believe it.
Scott: It seems true.
Scott: There's evidence, there's photos of them together.
Scott: Um, but this is just like a really happy jolly dude.
Scott: And usually when I watch magic, I can sort of guess how they did it.
Scott: Have some idea how they did it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I have no fucking clue.
Scott: The YouTube comments don't know how he's doing it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I don't know what the fuck this was going on here.
Scott: This guy just like makes a big mess out of the cards.
Scott: There's no way that he like kept them in order or sorted them.
Scott: And then somehow it's just like unbelievable.
Scott: Um, whatever, but yeah, this guy's supposedly the best living card magician.
Scott: I believe it.
Scott: So watch it, uh, watch his YouTube video.
Scott: The thing of the day is this YouTube channel.
Scott: And by the way, uh, if you pay him money, he has like courses.
Scott: He'll just teach you how to do this, these tricks.
Scott: So I guess people know how they're done.
Scott: Um, but, uh, I'm not about to pay to find out cause you know, if I didn't have a day job, the only thing I think I would use magic for if I learned it, cause I wouldn't go into a career in magic.
Scott: You know what I would use it for?
Rym: I would use it to do little simple tricks, like at a gaming table while we're setting up a board game, like close up magic for one person.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I would do it for yet for the social aspect of it.
Scott: It's like, I'm waiting in a line, you know, and it's like, impress the people nearby, right?
Scott: Traveling in a foreign country, impress the children.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, that's, I think, you know, the level of magic that I would ever consider putting effort into learning, but really impressive magic takes too much effort and I'm lazy in the better moment.
Rym: The GeekNights book club book.
Rym: I'll leave the unseen.
Rym: I am going to start reading it this weekend because Scott admitted that he read at least one page.
Scott: I have not read any further.
Scott: I read the one page.
Rym: I'll leave.
Rym: the unseen is a middle Eastern cyberpunk adventure.
Rym: And that's all you really need to notice to know that you should come on.
Scott: It's like, you don't even need to say all those words to get us to read the book, right?
Scott: You can just say a few of them.
Rym: in an unnamed middle Eastern security state, a young Arab Indian hacker protects watched groups from surveillance and tries to stay out of trouble until he falls in love with the wrong woman and unleashes a forbidden text thought to be written by the gin.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: Love me a good gin story.
Rym: Also, we will be live at PAX unplugged on Sunday, December 4th at 1130 AM Eastern time in the crab God theater.
Rym: with why is this game taking four hours to play updated to?
Scott: maybe we're going to drive to Philly and we're going to drive back in the same day barring no unforeseen circumstances like, you know, a positive COVID test the day before or anything like that.
Rym: So if you, if you want to see us there, see us on Sunday, we will not be at packs other days.
Rym: Uh, also partly because even if we wanted to, all the hotels are sold out, so we really have nothing.
Rym: So we're just going to drive out and next year, 20, you mean 2023, 2023 Zenkai con.
Rym: I had panels all lined up.
Rym: I even have a hotel.
Rym: I wasn't paying attention because I only look at the packs.
Rym: That is the most, uh, the next one on deck.
Rym: Pax East does not exist in my brain until December 5th.
Rym: And yeah, Pax East over lives.
Rym: Zenkai con.
Rym: So sorry.
Rym: Uh, that sucks.
Scott: These tickets just went on sale.
Scott: They're March something.
Scott: You can look it up.
Scott: It's still four days.
Scott: They're going to require masks thoroughly, but they are no longer requiring Vax.
Scott: Uh, they make, make of that what you will sadly kind of make sense.
Rym: Cause I gotta say having just gotten my physical New York state's, uh, database just doesn't fucking work anymore.
Rym: There is no record of any of my boosters.
Rym: No, my doctor was like WTF.
Rym: And then he looked, he's like, they don't have mine either.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, uh, anyway, yep.
Rym: Otherwise, uh, of course, since in the collapse of Twitter, follow us on other places, our discord's cool or forums.
Rym: Cool.
Rym: You can even subscribe to my crap on Mastodon, but don't at me.
Rym: I won't see it.
Rym: It's a one way feed.
Rym: Like we got stuff, go find it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: We're not hard to find on the internet.
Scott: No matter how many platforms collapse, we still have our own websites.
Scott: I'm going to be making, I'm gonna be making some more websites soon.
Scott: I'm working on making websites, GeekNights, website, Scott website, all kinds of websites.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I can't go wrong with website that doesn't get copyrighted except by lawyers.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So I guess let's just get right into it.
Rym: Put a little marker there in the audition for the main bit.
Scott: We did a show order my dinner right now.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: It happens to be Chinese food.
Rym: We did a show back in June of 2018 on Indian food.
Rym: We've done many food shows over the years.
Rym: Uh, so of course the most important disclaimer, we're two white dudes who live in New York.
Rym: We are not experts on Chinese cuisine in any capacity.
Rym: We're working from what we know about it and skimming Wikipedia.
Rym: And we're mostly focused on our personal enjoyment and experiences with Chinese food.
Scott: Uh, well I actually, I have, um, I have in my time studied the history of Chinese food briefly and attended and, uh, many museum, actually more than one museum exhibit about the history of Chinese food in America.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I specifically even went to the food museum that when the entire place, which is only really, you know, it's not that big, it's like a garage, like a large garage, but the whole thing was a special Chinese food in America deal.
Scott: Um, and I spent a lot of time there, but despite having all that knowledge, I am not a source for you to attain that knowledge.
Scott: Um, we can just summarize and say basically, you know, Chinese immigrants came to the U S primarily in California were very much, you know, persecuted, discriminated against, et cetera.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And ended up, you know, starting right.
Scott: Businesses selling Chinese food, but it wasn't the Chinese food, the way it was made in China.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was an Americanized version of Chinese food differing because of, you know, the pallets of American people, their expectations, all sorts of factors, ingredient availability.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: A various reasons they created what was a new ish style of food, right.
Scott: A newish restaurant aesthetic, right.
Scott: That, you know, sort of simultaneously, you know, played into the racism, right.
Scott: And the stereotypes, right.
Scott: Um, while also providing something that was different and still delicious, but not authentic necessarily to the food that is eaten in various parts of China, which is, you can't even really say Chinese food as a, you know, a thing because every different part of China has different food.
Rym: And they're radically different.
Rym: Like the parts of the food that comes from the parts of China near Mongolia is so different from like Sichuan food or the Chinese food.
Rym: You're probably imagining in your head the same way.
Scott: Like you can call McDonald's American food and it's like, yes, McDonald's is the same everywhere in America, but it's like the food in Florida is very different from the food in New York.
Scott: It's like in New York, you got garbage plates and in Florida, you got, well, we'll let that, we'll let that be.
Rym: But, uh, yeah.
Rym: So I grew up, uh, in like the white part of the Midwest in like very suburban area.
Rym: So until I got to college, honestly, I had only ever had American style Chinese food and Mongolian inspired Chinese food.
Scott: Because I'm going to guess that most of the places that had those foods in Michigan were places that were like Panda express chain ish places.
Rym: Uh, the Chinese food.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: The Mongolian food was both chains, but there were also for just reasons in the area I live specifically, there was a lot of actual Mongolian food, like more than you just happened.
Scott: You just happened to be near a neighborhood of Mongolian people.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: Kind of like how, if you live in a certain part of Detroit, there's a lot of like really authentic Polish food, just like right there because there's a Poland town
Scott: or in New Jersey, there's like areas you can live in New Jersey where there's just lots of Indian food.
Rym: And also it's not like major cosmopolitan cities like New York city, you can get food from almost any region on earth in that city.
Rym: It's a weird case.
Rym: So yeah, but having Chinese food, but I didn't know a lot about it until college.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I right.
Scott: Had family that, you know, I was born in New York city and flushing, right.
Scott: Even though I moved to Connecticut and I was like one, right.
Scott: But my family was New York people, right.
Scott: You know, only my immediate family moved to Connecticut.
Scott: The rest of my family, extended family was still in, you know, New York, right.
Scott: New Jersey, et cetera.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And no one ever left the, it was still very close to, it came to New York city often.
Scott: You know, so it's like Chinese restaurants are a thing in New York.
Scott: There's like one on every block basically.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like you can't.
Scott: And while they're all serving, like mostly the same menu, kinda right.
Scott: You know, with the same sort of repeating items that are mostly the same, you know, each one's a little bit different.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like everyone, anyone who lives in New York city has like a mental map of the standard American Chinese food places near them.
Rym: And like, they're ranked by like, which what's the good one.
Rym: What's the one that's open late.
Rym: What's the bad one to never hit the order from.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So if you're in an area that's like outside of New York city, right.
Scott: Most where there isn't, you know, a dense Chinese population, right.
Scott: You're going to get just that sort of, you know, Americanized Chinese restaurant, right.
Scott: You're in Connecticut.
Scott: We were in beacon.
Scott: We had one upstate.
Scott: We had one.
Scott: Um, you know, they're there.
Scott: I mean, there were, there were some Rochester too, right.
Scott: It's like they reach pretty far away from New York city, right.
Scott: California has them, but you know, the, the, the ones in New York are just like, there's a certain style to them.
Scott: Like they had the same menu, right.
Scott: They're all getting like their fortune.
Scott: cookies all come from this one factory.
Scott: They're all in the same wrapper, right.
Scott: It's like, you know, the egg rolls I think are all my, you'll get like the same egg roll, like a lot of them, because I think they're like centrally manufactured, right.
Scott: Some places are making their own, but it's like, there are certain things that are just like the same at all of these places.
Rym: Now, you know, by different people, what does sort of side that I sort of remember from my childhood, the era of Uber Eats and grub hub and all that stuff is relatively new to America.
Rym: When I was growing up, there were only two kinds of food that you could get delivered to a house in the suburbs.
Scott: Oh, we didn't get delivered.
Scott: We would order it on the phone and then my dad would drive out and get it and bring it back.
Rym: We could get Chinese food delivered and we could get pizza delivered and nothing else.
Scott: I mean, I'm sure we could have gotten it delivered, but it's like, we just didn't.
Scott: We always went out to go get it.
Rym: But like Chinese food, American style Chinese food and pizza were like the only two foods in my entire childhood that were commonly and easily ordered for delivery to your house.
Scott: We would also, right, it's like some of the restaurants are clearly takeout or primarily takeout, like they have a tiny little seating area, right.
Scott: But there were some that had seating and like we would go and eat at them.
Scott: The food wouldn't be any different, but it's like you would just go and do that.
Rym: We'd go eat at the Mongolian places, but we only ate at, I only really ate at Chinese restaurants regularly when we got to RIT and we'd go to China Gate pretty often late at night.
Scott: Well, most of the time we would eat at one would be on, you know, Christmas, right, where you go.
Scott: Chinese food movie situation, right.
Scott: And you had more people, right.
Scott: And then when you have more people and you go to one of these places, you could order and share instead of just getting the one entree for yourself, right.
Scott: And that was nice.
Rym: So I guess in terms of the Chinese food I like, like jumping ahead to that, I think Szechuan cooking is my favorite regional like type of food from that area.
Rym: I just, I like all Szechuan dishes just about.
Rym: I like the Szechuan spices.
Rym: That's my go-to, by default, bar none.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, well if you're talking, you know, authentic Chinese food, which is available in New York City, right, in Chinatown and Flushing and LIC, which is now becoming the third Chinatown.
Rym: Yeah, there are already like, there are five Chinese restaurants near us I can think of that are authentic to specific regions, only opening in the last four or five years.
Scott: It's like, you know, if you're talking about the real Chinese food, it's like nothing beats the dim sum.
Scott: The dim sum is the champion, right.
Rym: Of course, even that can have a lot of regional variation.
Scott: It does, but it's like it really doesn't matter which variation it is.
Scott: I'll take any dim sum you've got.
Rym: My favorite style of dim sum, and I could not articulate in detail all the differences because I don't know, but in my experience I have always particularly enjoyed what people will describe as Hong Kong style dim sum.
Rym: It might be a byproduct of the fact that I've spent a lot of time in Hong Kong, and I would go get dim sum there a lot, and it is different from the dim sum I get anywhere else, including the really authentic places like in New York City that we'd go to.
Scott: Well, sadly, the one, the mega big, you know, what the Jinfeng.
Rym: Oh my god, I'm so sad about that.
Scott: That one closed during the pandemic, that one.
Scott: I went there many times.
Scott: I
Rym: remember my first experience with dim sum was at RIT when Mike took us all out, and we went to the dim sum place in Rochester, and he ordered everything for us, and I'd never had that style of Chinese food before, and I remember being weirdly obsessed with the egg custard.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, well that was, you know, that was also the first time I had it, right, because it's like, you know, somehow Rochester just happened to have one of those, one or two of those places, right, and it's like we didn't have that in Connecticut.
Rym: Yeah, and if you've never been to one of those places, like the way they're formatted typically, even in Hong Kong, they're formatted like this.
Rym: Imagine a big banquet hall, like the kind of hall you go to for like the school math awards or something, like the band night or something like that, or a wedding, and it's just filled with tables.
Rym: The tables are huge.
Rym: They'll seat like 8 to 16 people,
Scott: right, like a circular table that has like 10 plus seats at it,
Rym: and if you come in, they will just sit you down at a table with other people, and carts, unless
Scott: you got 10 people, and you can fill up the whole table,
Rym: and carts will just roll
Scott: around,
Rym: and you basically just wave at people and flag them down and ask for specific dishes that you want, and at the end of the night, at the end of the time when you're done eating, they will just come over and have a bill of all the food you already
Scott: missed.
Scott: You missed.
Scott: the important part is that on your table is a piece of paper, right, and so what.
Scott: they push carts around with food, and you look at the cart, and you tell them which items from the cart you would like, and as soon as when they add items from their cart to your table, they pick up the piece of paper, and they mark down that what your table has taken those items, and then when you're done, they look at that piece of paper, and they see, you know, which items you bought at which price points, and then they charge you, right, so you basically you eat until you're not hungry anymore, so you never buy too much or not enough food.
Scott: with this, you know, situation, right?
Scott: The only difficulty is that like you might like see an item and get it, not knowing what it is, or not liking it, or which I was always down for my because I didn't know about Chinese food.
Rym: when I first encountered dim sum, my philosophy was I will try anything, and they're pushing it around.
Scott: If they're pushing it around and offering it to you, it's edible, and someone likes it, so I might like it, so I basically didn't actually learn the names of a lot of the dishes I would eat.
Rym: I learned to recognize things I particularly liked, but I would just point at random stuff, and it was almost always great, and the few things that weren't...
Scott: If it wasn't good, why would they be pushing it around?
Scott: They would try to push around what, bad tasting food?
Scott: Why would they do that?
Scott: They're a restaurant.
Scott: That doesn't seem like a good business idea.
Rym: I mean, I don't particularly like cartilage, and I don't particularly like intestines, like those foods I don't like, but I have tried them at dim sum places, and sometimes I've even gotten them and realized until it was too late.
Rym: It was totally fine, just not my preferred dish.
Scott: The only downside is that you might get some items, whatever's getting come around, but then you won't realize the full extent of what could be out there, and it's like you learned there are certain items.
Scott: after you go a few times, you learn there's certain foods you really want, and it's like if you just buy the first carts that come to you, you'll be full, and then later on the cart with the thing you wanted comes.
Rym: It's like, "No, I'm
Rym: full!".
Rym: Yup, like the little sesame buns filled with red bean come around.
Scott: Right, like if you really want an egg custard, it's like, "Well, you better not fill yourself up before an egg custard cart appears," right?
Scott: And will one appear?
Scott: You don't know.
Scott: Maybe there won't.
Scott: Who knows, right?
Scott: You might be able to... You can sometimes ask for items specifically too.
Scott: There'll be like a waiter or waitress will come, and you can be like, "I want this specific thing," right?
Scott: And maybe there's no carts pushing that thing around, but someone will make it for you and bring it out anyway.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: See, in dim sum, pretty much any kind of shumai dumpling, like I don't even care what's in it, I'll just get...
Scott: You can't go wrong with anything that looks like a dumpling.
Rym: Anything that looks even remotely dumpling adjacent, I'll pretty much just eat, and it's always great.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right, so in terms of the Americanized takeout Chinese food, right, the go-to items, right, is I gotta have the wonton soup.
Scott: I'm all about the wonton soup, because you get, with the wonton soup, you get the combo of dumplings and soup, right?
Scott: You know, it's not the soup dumplings, there's like a special item, right, that are hard to eat, and you can't really deliver those, and, you know, they're delicious, but they're also not... You can't eat those too often.
Rym: I usually throw my fried wonton strips, like those little guys, into my soup.
Scott: Yeah, that's what they're for.
Scott: But, you know, some places the wonton soup just isn't good, right?
Scott: You know, it's like the broth should be like really rich, right?
Scott: And the wontons themselves should have like a lot of flavor.
Scott: Sometimes, like there's a bad place in our neighborhood, and it's like all their food doesn't taste like anything, but the wontons specifically, it's like they don't taste like anything.
Scott: Like there's no flavor at all.
Scott: The soup might as well be water.
Rym: Remember the time we were at Beacon playing Burning Wheel with the whole crew, and a bunch of our friends who weren't from the area went to the Chinese place that was across the street from Alex's apartment, because they were like, "Well, it's close.
Rym: How bad could it
Rym: be?".
Rym: And they poo-pooed you and me, who went to the other place on the other side of town that had good Chinese food, and I remember I tried some of the food that they had all gotten, and it tasted like nothing.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's like all these places, you know, they're not... It's not like.
Scott: there are some chains, like, you know, Panda Express, but for the most part, like these places are not chains.
Scott: They're all owned by different people, but they're sort of all operating from the same playbook, the same way.
Scott: that like laundromats, dry cleaners, these other sorts of small businesses, you know, bodegas, mostly operate from the same playbook with some amount of variation, right?
Scott: But some of them, it's like, you'll know wherever you live, you'll have a few of them, and you try them all usually, or you talk to people and you find out.
Scott: It's like, yeah, one of them is going to be better than the other ones.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I know a particularly good one out in, like, Regal Park area of New York, right?
Scott: Oh, is my food here that quickly?
Rym: Oh, wow.
Rym: It's got some Chinese food.
Rym: So the listener has described soup dumplings as the heron spear of Chinese food, and I cannot disagree.
Rym: I really like soup dumplings.
Rym: I'll even eat, like, the chain soup dumplings because you really can't go wrong with them.
Rym: Actually, I have... So I was just...
Scott: If you're curious how long it takes for Chinese food to be delivered, I click the button sometime during things of the day, like when things of the day were over and the food just got here.
Scott: So that's how long it takes to click a button and get Chinese food.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I'm not even editing that out.
Rym: I was chatting with the listener.
Rym: The listener said, we were talking about soup dumplings in the chat, the heron spear of Chinese food.
Scott: Perhaps.
Scott: Perhaps it is.
Rym: Well, because they're great, but they're only great if you get them fresh.
Rym: Like, if you don't eat a soup dumpling within about 45 seconds of it coming to your table, you're effed.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's a special, it's like a special, luxurious treat kind of deal.
Rym: At American Chinese places, I like the crab rangoon.
Rym: Like, I will eat that crab rangoon.
Rym: That's something I actually specifically really like.
Rym: I like, and I like wontons, like, pretty much any sort of wonton-y thing.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: When it comes to the entree, I'll usually, I'll go for, you know, the things that are really popular, right?
Scott: It's like, they're popular for a reason.
Scott: The General Tso chicken, the sesame chicken, chicken with cashew nut, you know, some pepper beef kind of deal.
Rym: I'll do, I'll do the pepper beef or like a lo mein.
Rym: Lo mein's my, like, lo mein dish.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Any kind of noodle deal, fried rice deal.
Scott: All that kind of stuff.
Scott: I love the, I love the egg roll, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That's just a soup.
Rym: Assume if I'm at a Chinese place, the egg roll came and I ate it already.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Uh, you know, I like anything that's got like a big pile of vegetables, like water chestnuts and, and, you know, snow peas and all that biz, you know, tiny mushrooms and tiny corns and all the, all those guys, carrots, you know, celeries, all that biz in there, right?
Scott: And some kind of sauce.
Scott: Any one of those is fine.
Rym: But really in terms of more authentic Chinese food, I was thinking real hard during this whole show, it's hard to beat Szechuan for me, partly because that is the style of Chinese food that has the, the numbing spice.
Rym: And there's a lot of like dried out fish type things, a lot of salt.
Rym: Like it just, it speaks to my, Oh God, I'm drooling.
Rym: Literally just drooled.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of Happy Communist.
Rym: A bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names.
Rym: Case care makes music.
Rym: Chris Haddad, Chris Raimond, Clinton Walton, Dex Finn, Joel Hayes, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Harl.
Rym: Stop all the downloading.
Rym: And several people whose names I will not say at their request who are very correctly giving us just $1.
Rym: So yeah, we're still continuing to be on our.
Rym: I will simply leave you with... I did it.
Rym: Second in line and all I had to do was miss eight days of work.
Scott: With the money you would have made work and you could have bought tickets from a scalper.
Scott: In theory, yes.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Give me thirty thousand tickets.
Rym: That'll be nine hundred and fifty thousand dollars please.
Scott: Look the thing about that is I only got ten dollars on me.
Scott: Can I pay you to rest later?
Scott: Sure.