Rym: It's Thursday, October 20th, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym, and this is the GeekNights Book Club.
Rym: Tonight we are talking about The Binti Trilogy by Nnedi Okorofo.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So, uh, there was a news recently that, uh, The Phantom of the Opera was going to close on Broadway.
Scott: Which has been running, right?
Scott: I mean, I think the show is as old as 1986, but it's in New York since, like, '89, maybe?
Rym: I mean, I saw it at the Pantages twice.
Scott: In Detroit?
Rym: Yeah, actually, no, that's in Canada.
Scott: Oh, in Canada.
Rym: We would often, for a lot of reasons, we would head over to Canada to see shows instead of seeing them in Detroit.
Scott: I mean, you know, it's the same, you know, usually when there's a traveling show, it's the same, this one cast goes around the country, right?
Scott: So, wherever you see it, if it's not, if you're not seeing it in a place where there's a centralized theater like Broadway, West End, et cetera, right?
Scott: A foreign country, then you're seeing, you know, the same show is going to be in Seattle and Chicago, right?
Scott: So, they just go around.
Scott: Um, so anyway, it was closing.
Scott: Now, I had seen it on Broadway in 1990x, right?
Rym: You know, I think I also saw it in Detroit because I saw it three times in two different theaters.
Scott: But you never saw it in New York.
Rym: Never saw it in New York.
Scott: Well, you know, it's very different if you see it in New York.
Rym: I mean, sometimes they are, sometimes they aren't.
Scott: No, this is, no, this is definitely different because not having seen it in New York, right, a lot of the show is built into the theater.
Rym: Oh, you mean like the chandelier that's over the audience that comes crashing down almost into the audience.
Rym: that happens?
Scott: I mean, that is one major component, but there are others besides that.
Rym: Because like Les Mis, even the Detroit show in the old days had the rotating stage.
Scott: Rotating floor is very important for that show.
Rym: Which the new Les Mis apparently does not have, so I have no desire to see it.
Scott: No.
Scott: But anyway, so, I mean, Phantom has a whole bunch of other shit.
Scott: It's got moving staircases in the back, it's got a hole in the floor the guy jumps into, it's got the descent, you know, I guess spoilers.
Rym: I remember all those things happening in the shows I saw, and weirdly, the one in Canada was the same as the one in Detroit, as far as I can remember.
Scott: Anyway, so, it was closing, right, and Amanda never saw it.
Scott: Ever.
Scott: And I'm like, well, I'm like, well, why the fuck, we can just walk over there.
Scott: It's right there, it's not, you know, there'll be a bunch of tourists, but whatever.
Scott: So I went over and saw it, and I was like, you know, I saw this in the 90s, and it was, you know, terrific.
Scott: But it's like, who's the cast now?
Scott: Just some, you know, life Broadway employee, you know, cast people, right?
Scott: Who are obviously going to be talented at singing and dancing, but it's not like ultra-famous people or anything, you know.
Scott: And I'm like, they do this show, they've performed this show in that theater tens of thousands of times, right?
Scott: And it's like, you know, A, goddamn, that's hard work to do all that, what a pain in the ass.
Rym: Like, even imagine us, like, it takes some effort to do an hour of being animated on a stage, doing a panel where we mostly ad-lib everything.
Rym: Imagine doing that, like, every day.
Scott: Sometimes twice, almost every day, like, they take one day off a week, but some days they do it twice.
Scott: It's like, Jesus Christ, what a pain in the ass it is to do that fucking show that much, right, for that many years, without stopping, right?
Scott: It's like, holy shit.
Scott: And it's like, so how much effort are they really going to put into any one performance, right?
Scott: Are they giving it 100% every time?
Scott: It's like, no way, not a chance, right?
Scott: So I'm thinking like, well, you know, I'm just going to bring someone who's never seen it while there's still a chance to do so.
Scott: The London show, post-pandemic, when it came back, came back in a reduced fashion, right?
Scott: The New York one is the only one I know of on Earth that is still doing the complete original production.
Scott: Though there are rumors that after it closes, it may eventually come back in a reduced fashion.
Rym: Oh, definitely, just like Les Mis did, like Les Mis is the pattern now.
Scott: Man, it's going to come back, but this thing has been going since 1980-something, right?
Scott: Oh, it's been going longer than a lot of people have been alive, right?
Scott: You know, but I haven't seen the thing since last millennia, right?
Scott: So I'm going in with, you know, the expectation is that, yeah, the show is good, the music will be great, right?
Scott: You know, the instrumental music.
Scott: But I don't know how well these people sing.
Scott: I assume they'll sing well.
Rym: I'm imagining this leads to it blowing you away because it was full effort.
Scott: It's not full effort, you know, but even if it's not full effort, that show still fucking kicks ass.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: That show is so good, right?
Scott: There's a reason it was there for 30-something years, right?
Scott: Even, you know, I mean, you know, talented people giving it 80%, it's like, fuck yeah, Phantom of the Opera is awesome.
Scott: If you have a chance, it's not going to be hard to get tickets, even though it was more crowded in there than I expected.
Scott: Obviously, lots of tourists and students and that kind of group, you know, old people.
Scott: But if you have the opportunity or can make the opportunity, it's going to close like in February.
Scott: And if you've never seen it, get your ass down there because it'll go away and that'll be it, right?
Scott: You'll never have a chance.
Scott: I also want to say, you know, revisiting the story of Phantom of the Opera, right, not having thought about it much in a long time, right?
Scott: Adult Scott now sees the story somewhat differently.
Rym: I can see that.
Scott: My current interpretation is that basically the Phantom is like this incel dude, right?
Rym: Oh, absolutely.
Scott: The Phantom is just a cranky incel guy, right?
Scott: And he happens to be talented at many things, right?
Scott: Like, you know, music and, you know, science and whatnot, right?
Scott: He's a talented, intelligent person, but he's, you know, an incel with low self-esteem because of his deformity.
Rym: But also, I always comfort him as a character who ends up blaming the problems he causes himself on that to a degree.
Scott: Right, the moral of the show, spoilers, the moral of the story.
Scott: Phantom doesn't win.
Scott: Right, well, obviously.
Scott: Is that he's like, "No one will love me because I'm
Scott: ugly.".
Scott: And then she's just basically like, "No, I don't like you because you're fucking evil murdering
Scott: people.".
Scott: That's why.
Rym: If you had just, like, helped me sing better.
Scott: Your soul is dark, not your face, right?
Scott: And that's the moral, right?
Scott: And I'm like, you know, in the concept of incels not being a, I mean, they were a thing, but the word, you know, that wasn't in the, you know, cultural consciousness.
Scott: But now that it is, it's like, oh, that's another reason this show has held up for so many years because it's so fucking true.
Rym: It gave voice to that specific archetype of problem person.
Scott: Yeah, so the other thing about the show I think that really makes it last a long time is that it's cool, right?
Scott: It's other Broadway shows, even the long-lasting ones, have a lot less coolness factor to them.
Rym: The set pieces, like that scene in the end with, like, the people climbing down the big, like...
Scott: Well, that's the very end.
Rym: Yeah, the cage thing, all those, like, just spectacle pieces.
Scott: Right, but it's like, you know, Les Mis is kind of cool, Cats is not that kind of, not that cool, right?
Scott: It's like a lot of, the aesthetic of a lot of shows doesn't have, you know, sort of that badass darkness aspect to them, right?
Scott: You know, Titanic's not really cool, right?
Scott: You know, the Disney ones, they're Disney ones.
Rym: You know what actually had that pretty well was the Jekyll and Hyde.
Scott: Yeah, that was an okay one, right, in terms of coolness.
Rym: Yeah, the relevant story was, like, they were really stretching what little there is to that story to make a musical that long.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, well, that's the other thing, Phantom isn't that long, right?
Scott: They have this original book, right, and they don't stretch it.
Scott: They're just like, "This is what we gotta work with,".
Scott: and there it is, right?
Scott: And after the intermission, there's not much left, right?
Scott: It's like, you get the intermission, and then the second part is not that long, right?
Scott: It's like, "The
Scott: end."
Scott: All right, so yeah, if you can see it, go see it.
Scott: It holds up perfectly well.
Scott: No Ozymandias here, right?
Scott: It's still a full statue with no ruins, you know?
Rym: And you look, and you're like, "Yeah, look at
Rym: that."
Rym: Especially because there are enough people on Earth who can sing that one note.
Rym: All right, so Binti, the Book Club book.
Rym: I picked Binti, but we're gonna talk about the entire Binti series, because it is a trilogy, and it is about as long-- It is three tiny books.
Rym: Yep, it is about as long as a short-ish novel as a whole, and I've already forgotten exactly where the first book ends and the second book ends, because it's so short and so much happens.
Scott: Yeah, the three books are so short individually.
Scott: I'd say an hour each, right?
Scott: It's like three chapters of The Tale of Genji, basically.
Scott: And combined, it's still a short book, right?
Scott: Even if you put them all together.
Scott: But despite the short length and word count, page count, however you want to measure it, and the speed at which you can read the whole thing, the amount of stuff that happens, the amount of characters, the amount of meaning, the amount of everything that is in there, is just as much stuff as you would get in some full-ass thousand page, and I didn't feel like--.
Rym: Oh, no, because it is dense with content and allegory and meaning, but every sentence advances something that you're interested in.
Rym: There is not a wasted word in this book.
Scott: Right, it's dense without being heavy or difficult to get through.
Scott: It's not dense like the Silmarillion.
Scott: Right, it's not dense like you're walking through a bog.
Scott: It's dense like there is a cheesecake which is rich in flavor, but it is light and fluffy, and you eat the whole thing really quickly and don't feel full, but it was still tasted of richness.
Scott: It's still a cheesecake.
Rym: So I got to say, irrespective of the GeekNights book club, if you have not read the Binti trilogy yet, we're going to spoil everything in it.
Scott: We don't remember where one ended and one began, so if you've only read one book or two books, then I can't promise I'm talking about something from only book one or something like that.
Rym: Though at the same time, it would be very hard as a human to have read just that first book and not immediately read the first page of the next book.
Scott: I'm glad that we only started this after all three books were available, so that I was able to immediately go and get two and then three.
Rym: Yup, so we're going to spoil everything, and also I will just say that these are fantastic books, and I urge everyone listening to this, if you have not read it, just go read it.
Scott: If you're a nerd, if you're listening to this, you're going to like it, right?
Rym: Yup, you're going to have a lot of thoughts about it, you're going to have a lot to say about it, you'll have a lot of opinions.
Scott: If you have not yet acquired the books and are going to do so in a legal fashion, I guess the cheapest would be a used bookstore, but if you're using some other method like buying ebooks or brand new books, look for some sort of box set or something, or a three-in-one, you'll probably save some money.
Scott: If you buy one, then two, then three, you might end up losing a couple dollars.
Rym: So, 100% recommendation, like this is a top-tier book.
Scott: Well, I mean, yes, 100% recommendation, but I have almost nothing negative to say about the books, can I point to anything that's bad about them?
Scott: Not really.
Scott: But, they're not like fucking masterpieces.
Rym: Well, I'm not saying this is in the top ten books of all time written by humans.
Scott: It's weird, it's like, can you name any flaws?
Scott: No.
Scott: Well then, shouldn't it be an S-tier all-time great masterpiece like fucking Shakespeare or something?
Scott: Right?
Rym: But in terms, I would say, in terms of the GeekNights Book Club, it is in the S-tier of, just read it, don't even worry, just read it, no matter what, no matter who you are, there's no one who should not read this book.
Scott: Yeah, an illiterate person should learn to read this book.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: But also, the reason, not just for spoilers, but we're going to, it's the GeekNights Book Club, it's a book club.
Rym: The whole point of a book club is that you talk about the book with all the people who've read the book.
Rym: So, to remind all of you, because, you know, the Genji really set us back on book clubs for a while, we're going to talk about this book like you have also read it.
Rym: We're not going to explain the plot.
Rym: We're assuming you have read the same words that we have read, and now we are reacting to and interpreting those words.
Rym: So, it's not just, oh, we're going to spoil everything, which, the book has some radical twists that often happen mid-sentence along the way.
Rym: This book is like, alright, I see where this is going, I see where this is going, then you read a sentence and you're like, wait, what?
Rym: You almost back up and read the sentence again because now everything's changed.
Rym: And that happens at least three or four times over the course of, there are revelations that are, I guess the scope of it grows with every chapter in ways that you won't expect.
Scott: So, let's talk about it, I guess, in a not spoilery way for a brief time, right, as we usually do.
Scott: So, what the hell is Binti about?
Scott: Well, it's this person who is, you know, of college age, I guess, right?
Scott: You know, I guess late teens.
Rym: I think she's 16 or 17, living in Africa somewhere.
Rym: And it's not exactly clear when.
Scott: Well, on a planet that is some, right, you know, it isn't explicitly Earth, right, it's some planet, right?
Scott: In a multi-planet galactic society of some kind.
Rym: Yep, you do get more specific details later in the book, especially when you get some flashbacks, but when it's presented, you're just presented with this person in this culture in a time that is definitely the future compared to the kind of time we live in now.
Scott: Yeah, it's a sci-fi, futur-y, space travel kind of place.
Rym: Yeah, like, they have cell phones and internet, but they're obviously more advanced and special than what we have today.
Scott: Right, and the culture that this person is a part of, right, is a special and important culture that basically makes cell phones, right?
Scott: No one else, no other cultures or societies can make smartphones.
Scott: Therefore, because of their ability to be the ones who make those, their culture endures and sustains, despite being kind of a minority, and the society is largely dominated by another culture.
Scott: that are sort of colonizers, kinda?
Scott: A little bit, right?
Scott: They largely run the show in this area, though not in the galaxy, but on the planet.
Rym: Yeah, it's very much apparent that the Himba that the main character comes from are a traditional culture that is, to a significant degree, oppressed by and exploited by this larger culture that is sort of in the cities surrounding them.
Scott: Yeah, and both of the cultures are sort of conservative in their own different ways and advanced more or less in different ways, right?
Scott: You know, with good aspects and bad aspects, right?
Scott: They're just different people with different ideals, different ways, different traditions, different everything.
Rym: Yep, not necessarily good or bad.
Scott: They live near each other and somewhat depend on each other.
Rym: Just different and complex.
Scott: Yes, but the Himba are very much outnumbered in their geographic area, right?
Scott: By a lot.
Scott: They're not the government.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So, the main character, Binti, basically gets accepted to the Space College, and the Space College, Umsa University, is described as- Basically, they were eleven.
Scott: Yep, but- Literally.
Rym: Yeah, like, imagine there are countless alien species and, like, the most ridiculous post-Star Trek universe you can imagine, and the smartest beings in the entire galaxy go to this one university, it's the most exclusive place there is, and Binti is not just- like, humans definitely attend this university.
Rym: They're the minority.
Rym: There are not many humans there.
Scott: There's not many anything there.
Scott: It's a lot- it's a few members of every different, you know, sentient alien species.
Rym: Yep, but there has never been a member of her culture there, ever.
Scott: Right, well, it's sort of, you know, against her culture, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, she applied to there in secret, you know?
Rym: A family vaguely disapproving, and she sneaks off in the night and gets on a spaceship and goes to the university with a full ride, basically.
Scott: Yep, and then adventure happens.
Rym: And adventure happens suddenly, like, a couple ch- like- Yep.
Scott: There's not a lot of pages.
Scott: It happens on the next- she takes off, and then adventure happens immediately.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So, uh- Terrifying adventure.
Scott: Seriously, from this point forward, major, major spoilers, so, I literally had to, like- It's hard to talk about the plot- in such a short set of books, it's hard to talk about the plot beyond page, like, two, and not spoil everything.
Rym: Yep, but what I would say is that what's interesting about how, like, the scope of the book expands.
Rym: suddenly, like, every chapter or two, there's something you learn that greatly expands the scope of what is going on, and, like, what is at play.
Scott: Especially at the very, very end.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: The end of the third book, it's like, you know, after, like, the major climax, it's like the sort of epilogue denouement at the finale is, like, just vastly expands the scope of what, you know, and makes everything that happened previous look small.
Scott: But I guess- In, like, just two or three pages.
Rym: These explosions of scope are definitely direct allegory to the themes of the book, and also the literal reality of what is happening to the characters, because as Binti goes to college and learns about the world, you also have this sort of backfilling of everything has a more complex deal than it appeared at first.
Rym: Literally everything.
Scott: Every culture, every person, every piece of technology, everything you are presented with, you learn a new piece of information- It isn't like this one terrible secret of space like a lot of sci-fis have that you're trying to resolve and answer.
Scott: It's like every different component of every proper noun has its own terrible secret of space to think, you know, the true motives, the true reasons, the true history of each thing.
Scott: So you're constantly being exposed to new things and, you know, it's not like this is one end goal, right?
Scott: And I think that's part of what contributes to the richness, right?
Scott: Is that there's just so much happening all over, right?
Rym: So, spoilers!
Rym: The moment when the Medusae attacked the ship and murdered everyone, I literally had to back up and read that paragraph again because there was a moment of, "Wait, what?
Rym: Just what?
Scott: What
Scott: happened?".
Scott: I also had to clarify as like, "Is that really literally what just
Scott: Yes, yes it is.
Rym: 'Cause it was instant.
Rym: That was the first like tone shift, like, okay.
Scott: The short number of pages in which such a monumentous, dramatic, huge thing happened.
Rym: Especially because it was following.
Rym: what I would expect is a semi-typical plot of, "Alright, she's on the spaceship going to the
Rym: university.".
Scott: "Meets a boy on the
Scott: spaceship.".
Rym: "He's kinda cute.
Rym: She's exploring these new cultures and these new
Rym: ideas.".
Scott: The spaceship is sentient and awesome.
Scott: It's a giant space shrimp.
Scott: It's biological in some way.
Scott: It's not just a machine.
Scott: It's pregnant or whatever.
Rym: But I had a sense of where this was going and then the Medusae killed literally everyone on the ship instantly.
Scott: And it's like suddenly they're on this ship going to space college with everybody and then boom!
Scott: The ship is attacked and everyone dies except her immediately.
Scott: In like a paragraph.
Rym: And what was interesting, like form is function.
Rym: Kinda like how when you watch the Skycrawlers movie, you start to fall asleep because it's so boring.
Rym: But that sort of helps you appreciate the moral of that movie.
Rym: Now you have no idea where this is going to go.
Rym: Like from that point, I could not tell where, like this could go in a number of directions.
Rym: Just as Vintie is locked in her room on the ship and the Medusae are like outside banging around and like they keep coming back and they're like, "Are you still in there and
Rym: alive?".
Scott: At that point, I was like, "What can even
Scott: happen?".
Scott: I'm trying to think of what the outs are.
Scott: It's like, well her family doesn't even fucking know.
Scott: Literally everyone's dead.
Scott: She's trapped in this room.
Scott: She doesn't fucking know anything.
Scott: The Medusae are just evil and they're gonna murder literally everybody.
Rym: Except that the ship's pilot was okay too.
Scott: Oh right, right, right.
Scott: It's like, but you didn't know that.
Rym: Nope, you don't know that until later.
Rym: And they're trying to kill her.
Scott: And it's like the only out I'm imagining is like, "Okay, I'm guessing the sentient spaceship, which is a living being, will do something about this,
Scott: right?".
Rym: It's like, you know, what other- I like how we don't find out what the ship was thinking about all of this until like the last two chapters of the entire trilogy.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, I'm like, "Well, I was thinking that, well that's the out, the ship.
Scott: But the ship hasn't done anything yet.
Scott: It didn't stop this from happening.
Scott: So what the hell is it gonna do now?
Scott: Just arrive?
Scott: Is it gonna refuse and fly to space university no matter what the bad people
Scott: want?".
Rym: And then it escalates so quickly that before you know it, you're at the university.
Rym: She is now half Medusa.
Rym: She is standing before like this university council of aliens.
Rym: And now you realize, oh, there are a lot of extremely inhuman aliens.
Rym: There's like five of them that are even similar to the Medusa who at this point had been described as extremely alien and mysterious.
Scott: And now there's like- Yeah, this is right up my alley.
Scott: I'm all about the all kinds of messed up different aliens that are radically different from just some humanoid green guy, right?
Scott: It's very star control style where it's like, "Ah, this alien is just a gaseous form.
Scott: And this one you can't even see.
Scott: And this one is made of refracted
Scott: light.".
Scott: And you go from the Medusa- This one is a classic pile of tentacles.
Rym: Like the Medusa are unknown and mysterious and they're at war with the Kush for reasons we don't understand.
Scott: They're jellyfish people.
Rym: And like no one's ever talked to them.
Rym: And then we get to the university and like three of the professors speak the Medusa language.
Rym: And they're like, "Oh, it's Medusa.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: What's up?
Rym: Hey
Rym: guys.".
Scott: There are some Medusa people who are students there.
Rym: Yup, not from that particular species, but very similar, related, not really explored.
Rym: And I still was at that point now, I was not sure if the university was good or bad.
Scott: Oh yeah, I didn't know at all.
Rym: Like at that point, when the professors are debating what to do, knowing now that they knew everything, I figured that they stole that stinger on purpose.
Rym: I figured a lot could be going on.
Scott: I was also thinking like, is there- there must be a situation here where there is no galactic governing body.
Scott: It's just all these separate, you know, each race of alien species or planet or whatever.
Scott: There must be local governments everywhere and the university is just like its own entity that governs itself and nothing else, right?
Scott: And that's why some, you know, professors, I guess, are meeting and, you know, acting as a governing body, you know, for a population of people that live there, right?
Scott: Because I guess there is never anywhere in all three books any mention of like some sort of, you know, UN or anything like that.
Scott: Because if there was, you would say, well, where the fuck is it?
Scott: It would be- it would be involved, but it isn't.
Rym: But what I do really appreciate is that I'm glad the university ended up just being pretty much a benign force of knowledge, peace, and understanding.
Rym: Like it was good and it tried hard as an entity.
Rym: It was not a bad guy.
Rym: And even in the beginning, you know, they meet and they're like, oh yeah, that stinger was fucking stolen and that's shitty and we're giving it back and we're sorry and oh my god.
Rym: Like immediately.
Scott: And then, by the way, you want a full ride?
Scott: Yeah, that's an example of like, you know, sort of the, you know, of like just how there isn't a single terrible secret of a space, right?
Scott: There's like these many, many, you know, many resolved plots, right?
Rym: Because I suspected there was still something sinister about the university at several points along the way.
Rym: Like when Okwu, the jellyfish guy, that's her friend, is learning weapons and you thought he was going to kill the professor, but that was actually just his final exam and it was fine.
Rym: Like there are a bunch of points along the way.
Scott: See, I mean, I was questioning the university until that we actually got there.
Scott: And then once I got there, it sort of felt like, you know, I guess maybe because I've seen they were 11 more than once.
Scott: But it sort of felt like that.
Scott: that same situation where, you know, there's the university presents itself as sinister upfront and you hop over that barrier and it's like there's the truth on the other side.
Rym: I guess there was one moment where I wondered about the university.
Rym: It was the last time I wondered.
Rym: And it was when she was studying the Edan, like the magic rock with that one professor.
Rym: And then she left to go home and she just thought to herself like there was one of those moments that this book does a few times and other great books have done it.
Rym: Where you have one throwaway line at the end of a chapter where the main character was like, I wish I had paid more attention to what had just happened because it explained what happened later.
Rym: And it just kind of left you with that.
Rym: And that was right after the professor had basically said, all right, go home with the jellyfish guy to the planet with all the diplomacy stuff.
Rym: And I thought, I wonder if the university had some ulterior motive, but then clearly not.
Rym: And that was the end of that thread of suspecting the University of malfeasance.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So, you know, I guess but yeah, it's like the Stinger plot.
Scott: It's like, ah, why did the aliens attack this ship and murder everyone?
Scott: Well, because, you know, they're they're like leaders, you know, Stinger, like a part of his body.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Was like chopped off and stolen.
Scott: Like like an artifact and absconded with to the university, like the university was the British Museum or some shit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they were like, hey, give that shit back.
Scott: And the university just sort of and it's like you think, well, that's you know, you're presented with that sort of MacGuffin motive thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Early on.
Scott: And you got to imagine that right when you're presented with that kind of thing, that that's going to be the climax.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Resolving, you know, getting that when they finally get the Stinger.
Scott: But it's like, no, they get that quickly.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like instantly they give it right back to him.
Rym: Like, we're sorry.
Rym: Here you go.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: so there's like.
Scott: you're presented with a thing that's resolved, but there's more book to go in a short book.
Scott: You know, that's the only thing I think that carries on for a long time is the magical device that she has.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But even that one, you know, where it's like, ah, the truth of it doesn't come out until much later.
Scott: She's constantly like reminded of it, focused on it, working on it, studying it, has a professor helping work on it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like they're not like ignoring it, like, you know, a lot of magical, you know, girls in anime or whatever.
Rym: I guess nobody, no character in this book ignores something that a reasonable person would not ignore.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, ah, the girl has the magic item.
Scott: And then at the final episode, we learn what the magic item is.
Scott: It was a key to a door or it was a this or it was a that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the whole in between time, it's mostly ignored.
Scott: It's like not not at all.
Scott: It's like I have a magic item.
Scott: I will spend all the spare time figuring it the fuck out from immediately.
Scott: And it's constantly focused on nonstop.
Scott: And even though the final truth of it doesn't come out till later, subtruths are constantly revealed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's progresses and is constantly emitting bearing fruit.
Rym: And I like the the radical expansion of the universe we're interacting with because so quickly.
Rym: So suddenly we learn about the space university and like the ridiculousness of the wider world that these cultures play a part in.
Rym: And then we learn, you know, as we go on, like we learn, oh, the desert people.
Rym: Oh, they got space internet.
Rym: They're way more advanced than fucking anyone.
Rym: And even the himba were prejudiced against them as being savages because they just didn't know, even though they made smartphones for them.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And that even at the very end, like, oh, the himba, actually, they got a secret society and all sorts of not like they got stuff going on to literally everybody's got something going on.
Scott: It's almost like, you know, when the author was doing like some world building exercise, were like they just started with a character and were like almost playing like some solo RPG.
Scott: It's like, OK, I'm allowed to write one paragraph.
Scott: Then I have to flip over a card to add something new to the mix doing that.
Rym: But it played well into the sort of overall themes of the story, because if you look at this as a story of cultures interacting, you have a person who lives in a culture that that is traditional and oppressed by the people around it culturally, yet has both redeeming qualities and negative qualities like their culture is pretty sexist and was holding people like Binti back.
Rym: But also their culture was way more reasonable about a lot of things than like the coach.
Rym: But they were oppressed by the coach.
Rym: But they also were in turn effectively oppressors, at least they thought they were of the desert people who they disrespected.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, just about every one of the different cultures presented, it's like there's not some clear good guy, bad guy deal.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Of like colonizer, colonized, like you would, you know, it's like every single culture and different group of species or whatever they are.
Scott: You know, has positive and negative aspects, even.
Scott: Right.
Scott: These these ridiculous, you know, the Medusa who just come out as like, you know, genocidal murderers.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Immediately.
Scott: Really?
Rym: What's funny is they're a lot like Klingons in Star Trek, like very, very Klingon.
Scott: Pretty even I know that that's true.
Scott: It's like you got to think that they're bad.
Scott: Right.
Scott: All you've seen of them is they came and just murdered a bunch of innocent people, students.
Scott: It's like that's as bad as it gets.
Rym: But like at the very end, when Binti is trying to make peace between them and she's like, look, fuckers, what did you think they were going to do when you attack their leader and cut off a part of his body?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like they were just they're just.
Scott: they're still bad because, you know, getting vengeance in that way isn't good.
Scott: But it's like they they're not just, you know, genocidal maniac species or whatever, just going around, you know, killing everyone.
Scott: It's like they just become evil when there's a reason they had their own bad.
Scott: You stole from them.
Scott: And that's also bad.
Rym: But thus we've got the sort of intertwined allegory of Binti is literally becoming more than human and more than she's becoming culturally more than just him.
Rym: But even though that is where she came from, she is also becoming physically more than just human through multiple stages along the way.
Rym: She's half the deuce, half spaceship, half human with you, also with the alien Internet in her brain.
Scott: Like, yeah, well, I think that's you know, that's what allows her to sort of be the main character.
Scott: And, you know, she brings all the you know, her story, what she does brings all these different groups together.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But also, you know, incorporates them into herself.
Scott: So she's not it's not you know, it's sort of, you know, not just into herself, but also by default, incorporates part of herself into them.
Rym: No cultures interact without both of them changing.
Rym: No people interact without both of them changing.
Rym: No things interact without both of them changing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, you know, you can't really be you know, she's like a translator slash diplomat.
Scott: And, you know, ends up being forced into that role, even though that's not what she wanted.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, it's hard to be you know, if you're if she was still just herself.
Scott: And hadn't become part Medusa, part spaceship, part whatever.
Scott: Then it sure makes it a lot harder to bring those groups together because you'll always be seen as just representing the interests of, you know, who you are.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But by be actually literally becoming right.
Scott: The other, you know, kind of person.
Scott: Right.
Scott: At the same time, it's like she could garner the trust of everyone.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It was very appointed moment.
Scott: Not really possible even in the real world.
Rym: It was a very pointed moment when she did convince, you know, the warring leaders to make peace, have a truce and it all fell apart anyway.
Rym: But the fact that she saw that the Medusa chief was surprised and sad and the Kush king was also surprised and sad that it was neither of them was.
Scott: it wasn't their fault.
Scott: It was that sub sub guy.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The general dude or whatever his name was.
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Rym: it was that the peace was not that easy to achieve between their two cultures.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like even if you get, you know, like I mean, you can see even in the history of the real world, there have been times when you've had world leaders from countries that are really mad at each other.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Sign a treaty, shake hands, do a photo op.
Scott: But that doesn't mean that all of the people of those countries are now happy with each other and chill.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or that, you know, there might be a change of government or some other people, you know, government isn't just one person, even if it's a dictator or a monarch or something.
Scott: You know, some general goes off or someone else.
Scott: Yeah, it happens.
Rym: But this but all this happened in the book, too.
Rym: I would say the top line primary theme that stands out to me in this entire work, this trilogy, is that having a broader perspective is never bad.
Rym: Learning more is never bad, even if you don't like what you learn, because the only reason Binti is able to do the things she does is because she learns and embraces and evolves as she interacts with other cultures and sees a broader and broader universe.
Rym: And she doesn't forget where she came from.
Rym: She doesn't reject the culture she came from wholly, but she also does not slave it like stick strictly to the conservative elements of her culture that are like like the sexism that aren't necessarily ideal.
Rym: She grows to become something more than incorporates both of them.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, to go to bring up Broadway again, I think the primary, you know, theme message is a fiddler on the roof.
Scott: It's like, you know, you got the tradition.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then you got the kids.
Scott: And do the kids like, you know, give up on where they came from?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, no, but, you know, their horizon broadens outside this little village and also terrible.
Scott: It's, you know, terrible things come and happen to the people living there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That forces them out of their little shell.
Rym: But like Binti was right to expand out of her shell.
Rym: She was right to leave and see the world.
Rym: And she came back better for it.
Rym: And her people were better for it because that war was going to happen anyway.
Rym: That is very much apparent.
Rym: The kush.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If she was not on that ship.
Scott: Right.
Scott: What would have happened instead?
Scott: Well, everyone on it still would have died.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Umza University would have been attacked by the Medusa.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, you know.
Rym: But the part that I guess surprised me the most was as soon as we meet the desert people, my first thinking was, all right, what's their deal?
Rym: Because by that point, there have been enough.
Rym: Everybody's got a deal.
Rym: that when she actually meets the desert people, I'm just thinking, all right, sums up.
Rym: What's their deal?
Scott: The desert people, I think, you know, when I first when they first came into the picture, I was like, well, this is a little bit tropey.
Scott: Right.
Scott: To have like the mysterious people in the in the in the sands, Fremenish kind.
Scott: I imagine to be Fremenish kind of.
Rym: I did it first.
Rym: And I love how they're like, the fuck's wrong with you?
Rym: We're just on Twitter.
Rym: Like, what's up?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You can have Twitter too.
Rym: Your dad just didn't hook you up to it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: But, you know, they're these mysterious people from the same.
Scott: It felt like a trope.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That was just coming in to, you know, to fill out the last book there.
Scott: But then it's like, no, actually, your dad is one of those people.
Scott: It's like, oh, what?
Scott: Oh, he was hiding it the whole time.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, he was ashamed of it.
Rym: You see, the Himba are pretty directly racist against the desert people.
Rym: The Kush are pretty directly racist against the Himba.
Rym: And there there's complexity to all of that.
Rym: None of them are 100 percent right about any of their neighbors.
Rym: And if any of them had learned more about each other, there would be less conflict.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But at the same time, the desert people are very rightly like, yeah, you guys all kind of suck at this and we're just going to do our own thing with our super alien Internet.
Rym: And good luck.
Rym: Have fun with all your nonsense.
Scott: Well, I think it's it was, you know, the rare depiction of, you know, a technology like basically Internet.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or instant messaging.
Scott: That wasn't like computer bad, you know, a robot destroy sci fi.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was like actually the Internet people are a lot better off in some ways, you know, and it's kind of cool and awesome that they have Internet.
Scott: It's Internet's great.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But also, I was very logical representation.
Rym: I very much enjoyed the way her connecting to space Twitter Internet felt, because imagine someone, a human, an intelligent human being from, I don't know, Roman times and just stick them in front of a computer with translated Internet and just bombard them with it.
Rym: Like Latin, Google, like the Twitter, Google is far and I see it.
Rym: All the nonsense that we take for granted would be confusing and terrifying to someone who didn't really understand the scope of what the Internet was capable of.
Rym: And that is portrayed very well, I think.
Rym: But, you know, like the himba, like, oh, they're crazy.
Rym: They wave their arms all the time.
Rym: You made them.
Rym: It's like, oh, yeah, because they're literally constantly typing.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: I the spaceship stuff was interesting because I also I suspected.
Scott: Well, you know, that's my favorite deal.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: You know, that had something very, very similar happens in the third of the nine Fox Gambit books, like almost identical.
Scott: I mean, any any any sci fi book where the ships have the spaceships have names, which I don't know if the culture was the first one to do that.
Scott: Definitely not.
Rym: But I guess there's a difference.
Scott: There's a difference between ships having names like Star Trek where it's like, you know, it's a navy and they have a designation versus the ship being a character with a name and some sort of, you know, intelligence to it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like Kit and Knight Rider.
Scott: Is basically it's a character.
Scott: It's not a, you know, place or vehicle.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or weapon.
Scott: It's actually a character.
Scott: So, yeah, the the shrimpy the fact that the shrimpy also is is nice, but I like that.
Rym: they make a point that every one of these cultures, regardless of their differences, even regardless of the negative and problematic aspects of some of their cultures, every one of them learn something about the other cultures that they would not have learned on their own.
Rym: Like even the desert people learn about the trees and their deal from the himba, who they mutually thought were primitive, because all there's there's always there's some thing gets one of those ideas of as societies evolve, you take all the good parts from your past and you try to merge them together and you collectively try to shed the bad parts.
Rym: Maybe you disagree on what's bad and it's kind of how societies evolve over time.
Rym: Like the sexism about the himba, probably just objectively bad.
Scott: But I mean, that's that's trying to, you know, allude to the the message that we're hearing, you know, often in the real world, which is that like, you know, a lot of I guess on Earth, right, the highly advanced, you know, so-called developed or whatever you want to call them, the golf playing nations, I think is the best term.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The colonizer places that are, you know, have high technologies and Internet's or whatever.
Scott: Actually do have something to learn from the places and cultures that they view as lesser or primitive.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's like there is knowledge there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Not all of it is true.
Scott: But there are, you know, like their agricultural practices and other other sorts of things that are have been well known.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Amongst other peoples for centuries, millennia, how long that are ignored or discounted or, you know, whatever, because, you know, those are viewed as primitive societies or lesser than and that their knowledge isn't isn't worthwhile because you have the most advanced knowledge.
Scott: Therefore, what do you have to learn from anyone else?
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the book tries to teach you that lesson.
Scott: That is a true a true lesson to learn.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And if you zoom all the way out, the moral could be everyone would be better off if they got to go to college and also got to study abroad because they would bring something new back home to where they came from.
Rym: And everybody is better for it.
Scott: I don't know if everyone needs to go there, but it's good if enough people go.
Scott: And from every culture and those people and that when those people come back, right, they are, you know, respected and listened to.
Rym: Yeah, because Benji is not respected to listen to when she comes back.
Scott: That's something I think me and I think many people can identify with would be families sending you off to college to get educated.
Scott: And then you come back and you tell them things and they don't listen to what you learned.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Like, oh, no, university ruined my child.
Scott: Like you literally told me.
Scott: you literally told me my whole life that it was important to be educated and learn things.
Scott: You emphasized education so much.
Scott: And now I've learned and I've learned so much.
Scott: I've learned more than you learned.
Scott: And you won't listen to me.
Scott: It's like, yes, I do still have things to learn from you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, I'm not going to discount you like some colonizer might discount, you know, the culture that they've colonized.
Scott: But it's like there are things that I've learned that I know are true.
Scott: And you're arguing with me, even though you really, really wanted me to go learn those things and paid a lot of money for me to learn them and got mad when I didn't learn them well enough.
Scott: And now I'm telling you the thing I learned and you disagreeing with me like you thought the education was so important.
Scott: Why aren't you respecting the education that you thought was important?
Rym: So one thing I like is we don't really get a sense of when any of this is set or even specifically where the year XDXDX until when Binti is on the space Internet.
Rym: And she basically starts reading the space Wikipedia and she finds out like it was basically a smartphone era in like Namibia or somewhere in that region where the golden aliens were came down and the people there just use their technology.
Rym: And also we're like, you know what?
Scott: Oh, I forgot about that.
Scott: But that was like the best part.
Rym: I was one of my favorite scenes in the entire desert.
Scott: That's because that's another trope.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Is like the visiting, you know, super aliens, the precursors, the even better the aliens that are better than all the other aliens, you know, like the in 2001.
Scott: The monolith guys.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, there's always one alien species.
Scott: That's not just another alien species.
Scott: It's like the precursor godlike.
Rym: Even Star Trek has that.
Rym: And like they meet them at one point.
Rym: Oh, they do.
Scott: I didn't know.
Rym: I didn't know that.
Rym: The moral of that one is other than the humans, pretty much everyone is like, fuck you.
Rym: There's no way that's true.
Rym: We refuse to believe it.
Rym: And it's never spoken of again.
Scott: OK, but anyway, that's that's a common trope in sci fi, the great precursor species.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the desert people.
Scott: Their history, you know, was that, ah, yes, these golden aliens.
Scott: Right.
Scott: These precursor great species of amazingness visited them long ago and bestowed upon them the technology and befriended them.
Scott: Just like the old conspiracy theories about aliens in Egypt or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it was true, at least within this fictional world.
Scott: They were all just chill.
Scott: And then disappeared.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They never saw them again because that's the trope.
Scott: But then she goes to the back to the university at the end and there's just people from that species chilling and like, oh, yeah, hey, how are those desert people doing?
Scott: We should go.
Scott: It's like they're not some magical precursor species.
Scott: They're just another alien race, just like all the rest that just happened to go on vacation there for a while.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I love the same as anyone else.
Rym: We just wanted a referral to the university.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like it's like that's just turning that trope on its head was just like so fun, even though it was a small part of the overall story.
Scott: It was really satisfying.
Rym: So there was a minor bit that comes up near the end, but it's brought up.
Rym: It's alluded to several times along the way, mostly with Binti and the red clay that she puts on her body.
Scott: And like there's a lot of that's that's throughout the whole book.
Rym: But at the end, it culminates when she's with the desert guy and she's like, it's taboo for anyone, even like a husband, to see me without this on.
Rym: And I'm ashamed.
Rym: And he's like, but that's your culture.
Rym: I don't have that culture.
Rym: So I just see it as an adornment.
Rym: It shouldn't be taboo to you because I do.
Rym: I come from a different place.
Rym: And then he's like, so this hair, nobody's allowed to touch.
Rym: This is the special hair to my people.
Rym: But you know, you're not part of my culture.
Rym: Go ahead and touch my hair.
Rym: And that whole scene was a really interesting meta depiction of like what taboo means in society.
Rym: And it was a good way to talk about the kinds of conflicts that happen in the real world today around things like drawing a picture of the Prophet Muhammad.
Rym: And I thought that was a very like, I think, if nothing else, that section of the book is the kind of thing that if I were a teacher in an English class and I was our social studies class and I made them read this book, we would do a little unit on like that part of the book.
Scott: But yeah, the whole, what's the word for the clay?
Scott: I can't remember.
Rym: Otize, Otize, something like that.
Scott: So I think that's maybe one of the most important things in the whole book.
Scott: And I can't believe we didn't mention it until now.
Rym: Well, I love the growth of like, she makes it at home and then she's on an alien planet and she misses it.
Rym: But then she like makes it on the alien planet and it's not the same, but it's still part of that lineage and tradition.
Rym: And we just see that sort of evolve.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's, you know, it's, I guess it's, you know, the same as say, like, I don't know, I'm trying to think of an actual earth culture equivalent, right?
Scott: Because I don't know of any people that like cover themselves in mud every day.
Rym: Well, it's interesting because she finds it as a comfort because it ties her to her culture and her people.
Rym: But also she starts to see that it is definitely used to some degree in a sexist way by her own culture.
Rym: And she starts to have a nuanced understanding of it.
Rym: And I like how she still wears it and still respects it, but she has a broader understanding of its true meaning and where it comes from.
Rym: And it's a choice as opposed to something that is afflicted upon her by her culture.
Scott: I guess it could be a parallel to be like, you know, the Muslim women wear a hijab on purpose, right?
Scott: As opposed to someone making them wear it because...
Rym: Or someone forcing them to take it off.
Rym: Neither of those options is a good option.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: But it's also, right, not only does it serve to bring that message, right, but it also is sort of like a mental health thing, right?
Scott: It's like whenever she's like, you know, when she doesn't have enough of it, she's like feeling insecure, right?
Scott: And like, you know, and it's like, you know, when she's feeling nervous or whatever, she can like smell some or, you know, get some extra and it makes her feel better, right?
Scott: Sort of like a security blanket kind of deal.
Rym: You know, that's a fun aside.
Rym: You know, she clearly, like from what happened on the ship, she is suffering from anxiety and PTSD and having panic attacks.
Rym: And I like how her cell phone is just like, she gets therapy and her cell phone has an app that is like, listen, you're having a panic attack.
Rym: Take deep breaths.
Rym: Like it's fine.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: But how the, you know, the mud that she rubs on herself is serving like these multiple purposes throughout the story, right?
Rym: I mean, it's a healing solve for the, uh, for Oku.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And, uh, yeah, like there's not that much more I can really say unless we start going like plot point by plot point or character by character.
Rym: Let's see who stood out.
Rym: The, uh, the grandma in the desert is like, I think my favorite character because she is very much.
Scott: It's what you would expect from an awesome desert grandma.
Rym: She's very just matter of fact, like, oh, honey, don't, don't, don't look at that much Twitter that quickly.
Rym: You got to ease into it.
Rym: Come on.
Rym: But I was like, oh yeah, my piece of shit son decided he was going to throw this away.
Rym: He barely talks to me.
Rym: And then she's like barely meaning he does talk to you.
Rym: What the fuck?
Rym: Dad never told me.
Rym: Dad had access to the space internet this whole time.
Scott: I have to go with, you know, the spaceship again.
Scott: At the end sends, it's very super Metroid situation, right?
Scott: The baby ship comes to the rescue at the end.
Rym: The baby ship is so cute.
Scott: You can't even see it.
Scott: It's a book.
Rym: But the way it talks and she's like, oh yeah, mom sent me.
Rym: Didn't quite explain everything.
Scott: It befriends, it basically, you know, combines with her right.
Scott: The way that, you know, Samus and the baby Metroid have a symbiosis of kind, right?
Scott: But I like along those lines, how, and then she goes to space university and they're like, oh, you're, you're, you're, you're tied up with one of those spaceships.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Some of the other students are also, but that's a big deal when they test, like how far away should I be able to get from it?
Rym: Like there is definitely an undercurrent of curiosity is a worthwhile pursuit among all sentient beings.
Rym: Because anytime something weird happens, Binti and whoever she's with, they experiment and try to figure out what to do.
Rym: Like they don't just take things for granted, which I think is very important.
Rym: So absolutely read that guy.
Rym: I hope you read this book and didn't just listen to this, but, uh, I very much thought this book was great.
Rym: I think, uh, Nettie's works continue to be amazing and good choice.
Scott: Good choice.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, uh, do you want to announce or do you want to present the choice?
Rym: We haven't figured out exactly like when you present the choice, should I have to pick right now?
Scott: Oh, I don't care about that.
Scott: I'm just thinking about the rules.
Rym: We haven't set the rules for how the book club is going to go.
Scott: So here's the story.
Scott: I went to, I have a, you know, wishlist of books.
Scott: I have, right?
Scott: Books I want to buy.
Scott: I haven't read yet.
Scott: I went to that list and I said, well, I guess I'll just pick two books on the list.
Scott: That way, no matter which one Rym picks, it's a book I want to read.
Scott: Really simple.
Scott: Can't go wrong with that, right?
Scott: Just pick two books from the list, whatever.
Scott: So I go to the list and I go down the whole list and I noticed like the two books on the list had the same author.
Scott: And I was like, I never heard of this author.
Scott: I don't know who, I don't know.
Scott: I never heard their name before.
Scott: I don't know who they are.
Scott: I don't know anything about them.
Scott: I've never read any of their books, but somehow two of their books got onto my book wishlist at completely separate points in time, right?
Rym: It's not Umberto Eco, is it?
Scott: No.
Scott: And it seems like they've only written two novels, but they've written many other things.
Rym: It's not Simon Rushdie, is it?
Scott: No.
Scott: They've only written two novels, right?
Scott: So the author, I don't know if Rym even knows this person because I didn't until recently, the author is G Willow Wilson.
Scott: Do you know this person?
Rym: I don't think so.
Scott: So G Willow Wilson is a person who has mostly written comic books, right?
Scott: And I think is most known for creating the Ms.
Scott: Marvel character.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: I didn't, okay.
Scott: Kamala Khan, right?
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: So this is the person who invented the character of Kamala Khan, has written lots of popular recent-ish comic books, is exactly the same age as us, right?
Scott: She was born in 1982, right?
Scott: She's wrote some X-Men.
Scott: Oh, what is it?
Scott: Wikipedia says she first encountered comics when she read an anti-smoking pamphlet featuring the X-Men in fifth grade.
Scott: She started watching X-Men every Saturday, right?
Rym: Oh my god, so we come from the same comics lineage.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: So this person has written two books, novels, right?
Scott: One book is Alif the Unseen, and the other book is The Bird King.
Scott: The Bird King I think is the newer one that came out pretty recently, and the Alif the Unseen is the one that they wrote some years ago, right?
Scott: And then I'm like, "Well, this person is clearly some excellent writer who is one of us old millennial X-Men watching
Scott: type.".
Rym: Oh, fuck.
Rym: I just skimmed a really high-level summary of both of those books, and they are equally compelling.
Scott: Right, so I'm probably going to read both of the books.
Scott: I don't care which one you pick for us to discuss.
Scott: I can't lose.
Rym: Ooh, it's really tough.
Rym: Which of these two?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't care if you pick now or later.
Scott: It's up to you.
Scott: Those are the two books.
Rym: I'm going to set a precedent of being willing to pick right now, having just seen the choices, and I'm going to choose Alif the Unseen solely because of the word cyberpunk, and cyberpunk has been very front of mind lately.
Rym: And I'm very interested in, quote, "In the novel, a Middle Eastern hacker named Alif discovers a book of gene tales which may lead to a new age of quantum
Rym: computing.".
Rym: Just put that straight into my veins.
Scott: Alright, well here it comes, right into your veins.
Scott: And look at this.
Scott: If it wasn't for Book Club, Rym wouldn't even know about this book.
Scott: Or this person.
Scott: And I don't know how these two books got onto my wish list without me knowing who this was before I went to choose the books.
Scott: And if I can predict the future, it doesn't really matter which road Rym picked because I pretty much can guarantee once he finishes the Alif the Unseen, he's going to read The Bird King next.
Rym: I mean, you know me.
Rym: You know how I do with books.
Scott: That's how we do.
Rym: Oh, let's read one Wheel of Time book, 14 books later.
Scott: I mean, I haven't started reading either one either, but I can probably say that's the same as going to happen, right?
Scott: It's like, how could these be?
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this GeekNights Book Club episode are... The next station is Finch West, Finch West Station, and a number of people who have chosen to either not have me say their name, or who, rightly, have decided to give us the minimum possible donation on Patreon, which is perfectly fine.
Rym: So, yeah, this was a really good book.
Rym: I look forward to this next book.
Rym: I'm not sure if I'm actually going to make Scott choose between Foucault's Pendulum and the book by the voice actor of Garak from Star Trek.
Rym: I might actually make him choose between that and a Simon Rushdie book, partly because, while I like that book and I'm enjoying it so far, I don't think Scott has any fucking context for what's going on, so it might not be the best introduction for him into Star Trek.
Rym: But anyway, we'll see what he chooses, we'll see what I choose to give him the choice of, but for now, I simply leave you with... ...additioning for Field Reporters, Andy and Ollie.
Scott: Back to you, Andy!
Scott: Back to you, Ollie!
Scott: Oh, okay, no, no, no, no, forget it.