Rym: It's Tuesday, February 1st, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: - I'm Scott.
Rym: - And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we're talking about lifestyle games.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So, we did a show on food boxes, 'cause we, you know, we get food boxes here.
Rym: Oh, yeah, yeah.
Rym: We just got a couple of food boxes yesterday.
Scott: Yeah, for the first time ever, I think my food box is, like, just not gonna show up.
Rym: - Whoa.
Scott: - There was supposed to be a blue apron here yesterday, and when I checked the tracking, you know, it's in that state where it says, like, the label was printed and they're awaiting the package to arrive to start shipping it.
Rym: That's happened to us once or twice.
Rym: One time, they were like, "Look, it's not gonna come.
Rym: Sorry.".
Scott: Like, they emailed me.
Scott: They automatically, I guess, their system automatically detects when the shipping isn't gonna come on the appointed day, so it automatically sent me an email that was like, "Look, if it doesn't come tomorrow, it's still fine, 'cause it's full of ice and it's cold as hell outside, but if it doesn't come tomorrow, we'll give you a full
Scott: refund.".
Scott: And sure enough, it's today.
Scott: It's still not here yet, and the tracking still just says, "Label
Scott: printed."
Scott: Nothing.
Scott: So, I don't know what the hell I'm gonna eat this week.
Scott: I'm gonna have to, like, even though we ordered a pizza for lunch, I guess, what am I gonna eat for dinner, more pizza or something?
Rym: - We have a plethora.
Rym: - We have a cornucopia of food boxes and food if you needed some food.
Scott: - I mean, you know, it's more like, you know, "Amanda, what's she gonna
Scott: eat?".
Scott: She usually, you know, I usually cook the box, right?
Scott: And then she'll take the other half of it to work, 'cause it's two servings.
Scott: But it's like, if I don't cook it, what's she gonna, she's gonna eat something for a night, you know?
Rym: - So, meanwhile, going to two hockey games a couple days in a row, I did something that I haven't done in a while.
Rym: Yelled a lot.
Rym: Also, wearing a mask the whole time.
Rym: You kind of yell louder, 'cause you can't hear your own voice as much.
Rym: And I'm not talking in my real life as much as I do, and I kind of hurt my throat a little bit from all that yelling.
Scott: - I hear that.
Scott: I didn't hear it until you went, "Eh," before that you sounded fine.
Rym: - It's the exact same thing that I used to feel after every single goddamn convention until I learned to do radio voice all the time at conventions.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: I just didn't think to talk that way, 'cause for the last few years, other than talking to you on this and doing work meetings and talking to Emily, I don't really talk to people much.
Scott: - I pretty much only talk at work meetings, and yeah, not a lot of talking.
Rym: - And work meetings are, well, it's funny, 'cause half my work meetings are about like this, like I'm this on, and the other half of my work meetings are very like, "Yes, I have submitted the report,".
Rym: very subdued, Brandon.
Scott: - My work meetings are like, if I'm in a meeting, generally I'm just listening, and then when there's something I gotta say, then obviously I come out and I'm like, "Hey, this thing, this thing, this thing,".
Scott: right?
Rym: - My meetings are very different.
Scott: - When other people are talking, I'm just sitting there.
Rym: - Most of my meetings are me talking most of the time.
Scott: - Yeah, poking at some web browser, reading an article, listening carefully, listening also carefully.
Scott: - Very
Rym: rarely, if there's a meeting that I have to attend, like for political reasons, like the product manager has to be there, but it's a meeting that doesn't matter at all, I've learned to be able to play Overwatch while looking on the camera, like I'm, and I actually am paying attention, but I don't need to pay that much attention.
Scott: - Nope.
Rym: - So yeah, so the other thing, I was thinking about this, 'cause I beat Zelda 2 recently just for shits and giggles.
Scott: - That's what you have time for?
Scott: Did you finish the Tale of Genji?
Scott: You have two days.
Rym: - I got two chapters to go.
Rym: You were right, the college years, like the post big moment.
Scott: - It reads easier.
Rym: - It reads easier, it reads different, and it also is structured a lot differently, like it's more like a modern novel.
Scott: - Also, less happens.
Rym: - Well, I would argue that in some ways more happens compared to very early chapters.
Scott: - But also less happens.
Rym: - Yeah, but less, it's more like the drama intersects really quickly, but then also diffuses really quickly.
Scott: - Anyway.
Scott: - It also is gonna, just warning, it just sort of ends suddenly with no resolution.
Rym: - So I've been reading chapter summaries after I finish chapters, and one of the chapters I just read, after I read it, I went and read a chapter summary like yesterday, and the chapter summary was like, there is a lot of evidence that this chapter is a forgery, it was written later, it was probably not part of the rest of Genji, there was a whole thing about it.
Scott: - Yep, all kinds of stuff like that.
Rym: - Yep, and there's a lot of that with everything after the shortest chapter in the book.
Scott: - Yep.
Rym: - So, but anyway, so in Metroid, what would you say is the most high concept thing that Metroid 1, the game, did in terms of game design?
Scott: - High, most high concept thing?
Rym: - Something that hadn't really been done before, or that was really notable.
Scott: - In Metroid 1?
Scott: - In Metroid 1.
Scott: - In Metroid 1, I guess the thing that Metroid did differently was that you had smooth scrolling, and not the pitfall one screen at a time.
Rym: - Yep, you can go in multiple directions.
Scott: - Right, yeah, it went up and down, and left and right, and it also had, you know, a lot of that secret finding going on that other games didn't have.
Rym: - What about the title?
Rym: When's the first time you see a Metroid?
Scott: - Oh, like close to the end of the game?
Rym: - Yep, you basically get to this area at the end of the game, and these Metroids you've been hearing about the whole time, they don't exist, you've never encountered one, and then suddenly you're on a weird part of the map, and there's fucking Metroids in your business every single screen.
Scott: - Yeah, it's Torian.
Rym: - So, I remembered that Zelda 2 had enemies that were only in the last castle, and that's just something I remember, there's those way more dangerous sword guys.
Scott: - And Zelda 1 has that too, you got the eyeball, what's the eyeball guy's name?
Rym: - I used to know that guy's name.
Rym: Zelda 1 Eyeball Guy.
Rym: But Zelda 2, not Eyegore, is it Eyegore?
Rym: No, that's not...
Scott: - I'm not talking about Goma the Spider, I'm talking about... I've got, just keep talking.
Scott: -
Rym: So when Zelda 2, the game progresses, because by that point other Zelda's, other games that come out, but Zelda 2 is doing the thing where you start to encounter a bunch of different classes of enemies as the game goes on, but in the very end of the game, it just starts to max out at the blue guys, like the blue versions of everything are the hardest damn things in the game.
Rym: Then you get into the castle at the end, and not only are there none of those blue guys, but there are like six or seven completely new unique things you have never encountered before in the whole game, different patterns you've never encountered, that final dungeon has like enemy concepts that you have never encountered up to this point.
Scott: - Maybe Mario 1 has that too.
Scott: - A little bit.
Scott: - Suddenly you get a Koopa, it's like suddenly, I guess it happens before like the eighth Koopa, but it's like suddenly Koopa's throwing hammers, right?
Scott: It's like, oh shit, right?
Scott: Suddenly there's a water world in the middle of world eight.
Rym: - Blue Knight was the hardest thing you have ever seen in Zelda 2. up to that point, and suddenly there's no blue knights, there's this other knight that looks different who's jumping around and flying and has a million hit points, and the statues are all different, and I just noticed that and I see that.
Rym: The giant slime only appears in that dungeon.
Scott: - I mean a lot of games did that, that's not unique.
Rym: - Not that many games at that point in gaming had several completely unique monsters that only appeared in the final level.
Scott: - Well how many games are there that even had at that time, how many games were there that were sequential games that had an ending and a story and different guys, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, there weren't that many games that could even meet that qualification by their structure.
Rym: - There's a decent number, but yeah, not that, like Guerrilla War had that technically, sort of.
Scott: - You know, Contra, I guess had different guys.
Rym: - Yeah, but it was always different.
Rym: It's more that Zelda really sort of leads you into, all right, you have hit the blue Rizzrobes, you've hit basically the most dangerous shit, and now we're gonna do the final dungeon, you get in there, not one blue Rizzrobe.
Rym: There's a different kind of wizard.
Scott: - All right.
Rym: - That game holds up okay.
Rym: It actually does, it was pretty easy to beat and I enjoyed it.
Scott: - I mean, Zelda 2 isn't terrible as a game overall, but it's just like, compared to most other Zelda games, most other Zelda games are legendarily S-tier, so it's sort of like a second half of Death Note situation, where like, even if that second half of Death Note considered on its own out of context is an okay normal manga, it feels like a shit manga because you just, it's part of Death Note 1, which is like A-tier, right?
Rym: - But also similarly, having played Zelda 2 again recently.
Scott: - Zelda 2 coming after Zelda 1 is like, okay, if you just put out Zelda 2 on its own, if it was not a Zelda game, if it was some other game, it would be like a B to C-tier game.
Scott: - I
Rym: think a little higher than that, but I will admit, as a kid, I liked Zelda 2 a lot, but then when Zelda 3 came
Scott: out and I
Rym: played Zelda 3, I immediately recognized that it was refreshing to play Zelda 3 compared to Zelda 2, I felt that.
Scott: - Of course, Zelda 3's S-tier.
Scott: But yeah, Zelda 2, I think because it was attached to Zelda 1, right, it gets a lot, people think of it as like C to D-tier.
Rym: - Well, people also lose the context of - It's not legendary.
Scott: - Nintendo was very much at that time trying to make radically different 2s, there's a lot of reasons they didn't release the real - Nintendo has, no, well, that's only because you have a US perspective where Mario 2 was different, whereas it wasn't really different, right?
Scott: The real Mario 2 was just like Mario 1 with poison mushrooms, then it was harder.
Scott: But Nintendo does and continues to have a history of not wanting to ever just take a game and make another game in the series.
Scott: that's just like that game they just did, right?
Scott: It's like, especially Zelda, right, they're always making, every Zelda game is like a different kind of game, you know, mostly, you know, they don't like to just keep, you know, it's kind of interesting.
Scott: they're going to do Breath of the Wild 2 because I guess just so much money they can't not do it this time.
Rym: - Well, also we'll see where and how it departs from Breath of the Wild 1, too, like we haven't seen the game yet.
Scott: - Sure, but, you know, they keep, Nintendo always takes a game and tries to do something, you know, they don't just do a sequel that's like, okay, more of that same thing you just had, only another one.
Scott: They always spin every single time, even if it's a smaller spin.
Scott: You think about like Mario Sunshine being a spin, right, where it's like, okay, you know, it's still a 3D Mario, but we'll give you this water thing going on, you know, Mario Odyssey, okay, it's a 3D Mario, is it really a spin?
Scott: Yeah, look at all shit they did with the hat.
Rym: - They'll also take chances and be experimental sometimes, like they'll alternate between being really experimental and being really safe, but they'll make some stinkers along the way if they try to experiment.
Scott: - Yeah, they just don't feel, you know, they won't do what other game companies do, where it's like, okay, it's Call of Duty 10, the same as all the other Call of Duty's, just another one.
Rym: - Oh, which is kind of relevant to the main bit we're going to talk about, so I guess we should get into the news first, because there are two huge news in gaming.
Rym: First off, right after all the other acquisitions we were just talking about, Sony felt left out.
Scott: - Mostly the Microsoft Blizzard one, which the FTC is going to have a look at, which they should.
Rym: - Yep, FTC better look at this one, too.
Rym: Sony was left out.
Scott: - Can the FTC look at a Japanese company like that?
Rym: - Depends on how much of a US presence they have.
Scott: - Okay.
Rym: - Of either the acquirer or the acquiree.
Rym: - All right.
Rym: - Granted, my personal, this is not investment advice, I have no special knowledge, I am not a registered investment advisor, is I suspect that the FTC will take zero action against anything related to gaming at any point in the next decade.
Rym: I just cannot see that happening, but Sony...
Scott: - They haven't taken action yet.
Rym: - Yep, Sony is acquiring Bungie, completing the miracle of life, so everybody needs a lifestyle brand or a lifestyle game or a set of IP they can really hang their flag on.
Scott: - So if anyone doesn't know, Bungie got their start making games like Marathon, which was like the FPS that people with Macs played, because they couldn't play, you know, Doom as easily, right?
Scott: But you know, Marathon was actually pretty good, but then they struck it really big with Halo, obviously, and then, you know, Microsoft had them, but then at one point Bungie split off from Microsoft, but they left Halo behind, so Bungie, so Microsoft kept the Halo and let the Bungie part go, Bungie went on to make Destiny, right, which is their current, I guess, game, and now Sony is bringing them in, and I feel like they've really bounced around a lot, like Destiny used to be in like the Battle.net app, and now it's not, now it's, right, it's like they, and now Activision, that Blizzard Activision has now went back to Microsoft, it's like all kinds of different directions going on here,
Rym: and
Scott: I also, I remember there being like some drama involving like, the last time I thought about this company, because I don't play their games, as I remember years ago reading some drama involving like, right, there were some writers that were writing, probably Destiny, I imagine, and then like they had to switch to some other writers, and the guy was mad or something,
Rym: yeah, well Destiny's a weird hybrid in that every one of these big companies needs a lifestyle or lifestyle adjacent game to keep like a player base in their orbit and monetize them forever, and Destiny might be the perfect storm of that kind of game for this.
Scott: Yeah, it's successful and big, but not
Rym: mega big, it's just kind of like
Scott: regular big,
Rym: and it's kind of like take a loot shooter like Borderlands, but also make it kind of an MMO, like that's sort of what Destiny is, if I tried to describe it to someone,
Scott: yeah, I never played it, but I always got the feeling it was a bit Helldivers-y, where there's like a plot, but you know, that's, there's something like that,
Rym: yep, so that's, I never played it, it's the magic circle of you, you have all these attributes, you have a bunch of lore that a certain set of your players will care about, a bunch of PvE or cooperative type content, which a good chunk of your players will care about, a competitive aspect so you can keep those people in your orbit, a way to sell hats, and leveling up in progression and stateful stuff to keep people there forever.
Rym: The people I know who play Destiny play primarily Destiny to the exclusion of everything else.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: I mean that's, you know, the kind of game that is
Rym: exactly that kind of game, this doesn't superboat, the worst thing is the games industry just in the last like couple months has consolidated to a degree above and beyond the trends that were happening up to that point, but we've hit a sort of balance of power, I think, with this acquisition in that the balance of power among the major players has remained relatively constant by these acquisitions.
Scott: Yeah, I get that, you know, the anti-trust people generally feel like as long as you're not a monopoly of one, they'll let biopolies, or in this case, triopoly, they'll
Rym: also let monopolies exist if there's no evidence that they're exploiting the market, which I think is a terrible loophole that should be removed.
Scott: But as long as there's still separation between Microsoft, Sony, and Nintendo, it's like regulators aren't going to understand that Nintendo is actually separate.
Scott: Nintendo sort of has a monopoly, right?
Scott: If you consider their market to not be the same market as, you know, Microsoft, Sony, and then...
Rym: And these games don't directly compete with each other, but there's no way to explain that to a regulator, and the nuance there is that would not survive even the briefest interaction with the United States Congress, let alone the FTC.
Scott: Yeah, and plus the language of the law was written for, you know, train and oil companies, right, which bears no resemblance to the modern world.
Rym: Yep, because the real problem is more that there are companies that have so much power and dominance that they can control the narrative conversation and ecosystem around games.
Rym: Even though they don't have a monopoly, gamers can choose among three large companies for their primary game.
Rym: So it'll be interesting to see what comes of this, because Destiny probably could be a lot bigger with the right marketing and the right investment.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: They might just be hiring them for the... It is an extremely talented team.
Scott: They might just have them create some... Because PlayStation, you know, they need some exclusives to make you buy a PlayStation.
Scott: They might just have them make some games.
Scott: And, you know, we already heard the news that they decided that at least the next number of Call of Duties are still going to be cross-platform, or at least, you know, Sony said they were confident in, you know, so at least the next few, right?
Scott: But who's to say that whatever they make Bungie make next or whatever they are making now won't be PlayStation exclusive?
Rym: So there's one thing that's interesting here...
Scott: Because Microsoft is okay with games at least going to cross-platform on PC.
Scott: Sony, you know, has some PC stuff, right, like that God of War thing just came out, right?
Scott: But, you know, for the most part they only let that happen way after and some games never because that's the only reason to buy a PlayStation is if they have exclusive titles.
Scott: So, whereas Microsoft is okay with stuff going on PC because that PC runs Windows, so they're okay with that.
Rym: Several articles about this from like The Verge and other places, they do point out that Fortnite seems to be a big part of what drove this.
Rym: And one thing that I just looked up and confirmed, if you look at the top 10 games played on PlayStation 5s, Fortnite is number one.
Scott: Yes, Fortnite, far away.
Scott: On every iOS, yep, probably iOS, probably Switch, probably PC.
Rym: And Fortnite captures a really, really lucrative demographic.
Rym: Fortnite is almost like sitting in between Roblox/Minecraft on one side and Destiny, Borderlands, Overwatch-type games on the other side, like Destiny.
Scott: Absolutely.
Scott: Destiny sits in that middle sweet spot there.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: So, Fortnite is so powerful that Sony seems to want to court the right side of that ecosystem.
Scott: Yeah, but you can't, I guess Epic is the one they can't buy, right?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Granted, if they somehow... Nor is Valve.
Rym: Valve remains the, not a dark, Valve is just sort of invincible because of the structure of the company, like...
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Valve is invincible for a bunch of reasons that you can probably intuit, we've talked about on the show.
Rym: There's another huge news, which is yet another big acquisition.
Rym: Wertle, the game that took web browsers and the internet and Twitter by storm, has been bought by the New York Times for what appears to be a seven-figure deal.
Scott: No, that's good for that guy.
Scott: He made a webpage with a clever, well-designed game.
Scott: It's a static page.
Scott: He served it up and then waited a long time.
Scott: It got discovered and he made seven figures.
Rym: He said in a press release quote, "In the low seven
Rym: figures.".
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You made at least a million dollars, right?
Scott: Some millions.
Scott: It's like, that's the nerd dream.
Scott: That's my dream as well.
Scott: Congrats.
Scott: Congrats, dude.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: If any corporation wants to spend the low... Look, for the low seven figures, you've got a simple game.
Rym: For the low seven figures, we can offer you an entire goddamn podcast.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: But it's fascinating here because Wertle, well, there's a few things going on, but Wertle is trivially cloned because game mechanics are not copyrightable.
Rym: You could make a game.
Scott: There are many clones.
Scott: There was a big fiasco with clones on the App Store, some of which are still there.
Rym: Many of those were taken down only because they used language.
Scott: I went to the App Store, there's still some there and they're highly ranked too.
Rym: But the ones that got taken down were the ones that could be confused for the real Wertle.
Rym: It was about trademark, not about game mechanics.
Rym: Because game mechanics are just fundamentally not copyrightable at all.
Rym: So we could make a game and call it unlicensed free word game, and it's just Wertle and free and not owned by the New York Times.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: So the other thing that a lot of you need to realize, we talk about this kind of often, it comes up on gig nights, but at least every few months, the New York Times has a significant games division.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So especially for puzzles.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: So which are talking nerds, right?
Scott: So they have.
Scott: they have the crossword puzzle is the biggest, right?
Scott: They have all the crossword, the best crossword makers in the world are working for them.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And before any of you think, how hard is that?
Rym: Like we thought we did a whole show on crossword puzzles.
Rym: That is some of the hardest.
Scott: crossword puzzles have to be handcrafted and authored.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the New York Times also has some machine generated, some hand authored puzzles.
Scott: They've got their little spelling bee game, which is actually really fun, but I'm not going to pay money to play.
Scott: I've just played it for like the free demo once in a while.
Scott: They've got their Sudoku's, I think are machine generated and not that great, but you know, whatever.
Scott: Uh, they've got like their, what's the chess puzzle, right?
Scott: It's like, what's the move to win here, whatever.
Scott: Uh, I don't know if the jumble still exists.
Scott: Wasn't it, you know, the jumble, which always has a funny little, I don't know if they own that either, but someone, I think that syndicated the jumble by someone else, but regardless, there is a New York Times official crossword app, which is a really good app by the way.
Scott: Um, and if you install it on your phone or tablet, then you can do a mini crossword every day, but if you don't do it within 24 hours, it goes away and they give you a different mini crossword.
Scott: So you get a tiny crossword every day that literally takes like a minute to do.
Scott: And if you want to do anything else, you got to pay money.
Scott: If you get a subscription, you can do everything.
Scott: There are over a million people with that subscription.
Scott: It is a big deal.
Scott: So you have a million subscribers.
Scott: You don't need to work, right?
Scott: You're good.
Rym: So obviously Wordle is like exactly the kind of game that fits into the New York Times ecosystem.
Rym: So you might be asking yourself, why did the New York Times pay low seven figure sum for a game they could have just cloned with zero consequences.
Rym: They are buying the eyeballs of people who are playing Wordle today.
Rym: I am confident Wordle will remain free forever.
Rym: There is no way they would put that behind the paywall.
Scott: Maybe, but regardless, they definitely are going to leverage the popularity of Wordle to try to boost their game subscribers in some way.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: What that way is remains to be seen, but they're going to do it.
Rym: Well, couple that with what we talked about before where New York Times bought the athletic, which we pay for.
Rym: So maybe I'll end up with a New York Times subscription anyway.
Scott: I mean, if there's a subscription that gets me the games and I think I said this when we did that news, if there's one subscription that gets me the athletic and the puzzles, I would probably pay for it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The New York Times itself just comes along for the ride.
Scott: Like, oh, the price they're charging for the puzzles alone.
Scott: The last time I looked was not worth it to me, especially since my recent ish thing of the day, cracking the cryptic YouTube channel, plus their discord server, you know, with their, their high level Sudoku's.
Scott: the pencil puzzles, right?
Scott: And the whole puzzle internet community with the puzzles that they are hand crafting, that are mostly free are like unbelievable.
Scott: There's no reason for you to go.
Scott: If you're looking to do that kind of puzzle, you don't need the New York Times.
Scott: And then you could even get into the cracking the cryptic Patreon, right?
Scott: They didn't pay me to tell you this, you know, you just Patreon them.
Scott: And I think that's a better deal than New York Times, uh, puzzles, I guess, unless you want to do crosswords.
Scott: Uh, but I think, you know, I would say crosswords are better than regular Sudoku, but they're not better than the handcrafted, you know, next level Sudoku's.
Rym: So, so I learned something just now about the bungee acquisition that I think we want to step back to briefly.
Rym: Uh, the D there's a bunch of talk about how the deal is actually kind of unusual, uh, bungee, like formally will maintain complete creative independence and operate independently.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Even self publishing was probably like, we know how you so many, you know, companies like to work, right?
Rym: You know, and it's honestly, that's smart because much like wordle, if something's doing a really good job, the worst thing you can do is buy it and then fuck with it.
Rym: That is how so many cool things get destroyed when big companies buy them.
Rym: And it seems like I suspect that both Microsoft and Sony with their relative acquisitions recently are going to be very careful to not ruin what was good about the companies and the IP they bought.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, sometimes you do acquire something to shut it down because it's a competitor, but that's not this case.
Rym: No, definitely not.
Rym: I mean, wordle was not competing with the New York times puzzle section.
Rym: Bungee was not competing with Sony.
Rym: No.
Scott: Well, it's bungee was competing with Sony.
Rym: Yeah, but not in a, not in a way that was going to impact the specific game that Sony had that destiny was rubbing up against.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You're just competing with Sony Fortnite, which runs on Sony platforms.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So, uh, on my birthday this year, a video got uploaded and, uh, I noticed it and I watched it and it's 34 minutes long.
Rym: I encourage you to watch the whole thing, even if you feel like this might be a boring topic, because I already know this information.
Rym: You may know this information, but it makes an interesting argument, uh, not an argument, but sorry, it frames it a different way.
Rym: It's titled the unreasonable effectiveness of JPEG and on one hand, it explains in very understandable, but very technically correct detail how JPEG works, the compression algorithm for images, but it frames it pointing out the fact that the reason things like JPEG and MPEG and a lot of our modern, uh, algorithms for compression work is that it's really signal processing that an image is basically just a
Scott: signal, signal processing is just a, you know, a different way to, of mathematically modeling, right?
Scott: The same, you know, it's like, what's it, what's it?
Scott: you, you, you hook up to your, even though if you're USB, right.
Scott: Is it is a digital signal, right?
Scott: You hook, you hook up your oscilloscope, right?
Scott: It's like you could, instead of using binary logic to examine, you know, whatever data is coming down your USB cable, you could treat it as signal processing and process it in a different, you know, it's, that's how computers are.
Scott: Everything is signal processing in the real world.
Scott: Things boil a different model.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Things boil down to.
Rym: basically, you can make a big equation that will generate a signal that is analogous to the real thing you're trying to model, but much simpler and takes the end with much less space needed to convey this information.
Scott: And mostly the reason, I mean, if you think about it, you know, it's like, look at back in the day, you VHS tape, right?
Scott: You know, if you put, you know, VHS tape quality, even if you turn as super VHS and turn it all the way up, right.
Scott: It, you know, it's just recording an analog signal from the radio waves in the sky to a VHS tape, right?
Scott: They're pretty much directly, uh, and then it's going to play them back off of that magnetic tape to your TV as go in the antenna hole.
Scott: So the TV thinks like basically that's what was being broadcast, right?
Scott: So you, the quality you get on a VHS tape with that analog recording, you know, it's not great, but if you were to make a digital compression of like, you know, even the best H two six, whatever MPF, FM peg you've got, and try to save that to a VHS tape as a magnetic digital device, that's going to be so much worse.
Rym: So think about the analog recording video on a VHS tape could not be stored on that medium in a digital form.
Rym: Think about that.
Rym: Really think about what's gotcha said, right?
Scott: Because I mean, well, cause you know, if you have the signal, right, you know, an analog signal has lots of values, right?
Scott: You know, so if you look at it, it's a sine wave, right?
Scott: It's bendy, right?
Scott: You know, and if it's in, if it's in between zero and one, that still has some meaning, right?
Scott: When you have a digital signal, only the five volt and the zero volt of any meeting, right?
Scott: Everything else is just timings, right?
Scott: You're ignoring everything in between your clock cycles, basically, right?
Scott: All that information is wasted.
Scott: Whereas analog signal, right?
Scott: The whole signal is used every, you know, whatever, I guess it's in infinite.
Scott: I don't know how far you can zoom in, you know, with one unit of time, there's no such thing.
Rym: Yes, there is actually with the Planck's constant.
Rym: There is a minimum unit of time and a minimum unit of interaction in the universe.
Scott: All right, so one Planck's constant of time is the resolution, right?
Scott: You know, it's like every, you chop up the analog signal into that small of, you know, segments, right?
Scott: You're using the whole magnetic tape, right?
Scott: You know, every single piece of it.
Rym: This is also why, like, one thing you could say is that the fast Fourier transformation, like the ability to do quick math and Fourier transformations is probably more important than most other digital technologies we've come up with.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty much, like, you know, the most important, you know, one of the most important maths that's been, you know, invented.
Rym: See, I put this on a Tuesday because...
Scott: In terms of, like, practical usage, right?
Scott: And every actually gets used to do things in your everyday life, but you don't know what's there, as opposed to fancier maths that are just...
Rym: Well, case in point, a lot of what I'm doing right now to record and then later upload GeekNights involves that technology, or would not happen the way it happens today.
Scott: Yep, the audition that's recording my voice and the software that's sending our voices over the internet to each other is all doing plenty of fast Fourier transforms, so are probably the hardware devices and the mixers and all that kind of stuff.
Scott: They're all doing that same math in various ways.
Rym: I also learned something as a result of this video, that there's two different entropy encodings that could be used for JPEG, and one of them, the arithmetic one, is far superior, like, it's better in every way, but IBM had a patent on it, and as a result nobody ever used it.
Rym: So what do you got?
Rym: I assume a cool gaming thing.
Scott: Yeah, so somebody out there decided to take the map, the overworld map of Zelda 1, a map that I have memorized in my brain down to almost the pixel level, at least in the first quest, and they recreated the entire map in Legos, including the enemies.
Scott: It took them 25,000 Lego pieces.
Scott: It's enormous, and there's a YouTube video where basically they pan a camera over it so you can examine all of it in very closely and see their their handiwork.
Scott: It's not, like, incredible, amazing, like, the result, because it's really not a high resolution thing that they replicated.
Rym: But when you zoom out, like, the zoomed out view, it looks pretty great.
Scott: Yeah, and also they, uh, I think just the effort involved, right, could you imagine sitting there doing this?
Scott: Especially, like, some of the details they put in, like, they clearly made, like, a base layer and then a water layer, and then you could see, because, like, the lakes are inset, so, like, all the land is on top of lakes, right?
Scott: And then the trees are, so the verticalness of it, um, clearly had a lot of work and thought and planning going into it.
Scott: So, uh, I don't know where they're putting this.
Scott: I certainly don't have room for it in my apartment, but, uh, good job.
Rym: It was, like, they immediately just took it down.
Rym: They took it apart as soon as it was done.
Scott: Oh, after they made the YouTube video, yeah.
Rym: I imagine it was very sort of soothing and fun as an activity to just work on this every day.
Rym: So, in the meta moment, the GeekNights Book Club book, which I, uh, we should be doing our episode on it on, uh, Thursday in two days.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: It's, uh, we've hit the end.
Scott: Our first of, our first of maybe a couple few episodes.
Rym: Yep, we'll do at least two episodes, I think.
Rym: I think on Thursday we're just gonna react to the book as a book, because I have to read some more history and, no, I wouldn't even say brush up on, but learn more about the Heian Era.
Scott: Yeah, see, I don't need, I'm gonna feel like, you know, if we're gonna talk about the meta of it, I'm not gonna, like, research the history more than what, like, I've already just happened to find out, like, mostly
Rym: I want to react to, like, what I learned as a result of reading this book.
Scott: Yeah, but, you know, there clearly are lots of meta things to discuss even without studying them.
Scott: If you actually care about, like, the actual, there are people who, like, research this for a living, you can just go read what they wrote.
Scott: There's no reason for me to either, you know, be wrong or read what they wrote and regurgitate it to you.
Rym: But I guess we'll react to the book as a waste of time.
Rym: We'll react to the book as a book for the first episode, and then the other episode.
Rym: we'll talk about, like, the meta around it and, like, how it, how, like, we interpreted and experienced it compared to other novels and, like, its place in history, etc.
Rym: But I don't regret it.
Rym: I feel like the, honestly, Covid is what made it take so long because I didn't read much of anything for, like, that first year in quarantine.
Scott: It was a, it was a big conflagration of factors.
Rym: Lots of factors.
Scott: You know, but now, you know, like I said, much like baseball players who swing the heavy bat and then to make the other bat feel lighter, even though that doesn't actually work, the next book club book that we are going to do, I'm 80% done with.
Rym: Yep, and I imagine, I didn't start reading it yet because I was, I'm 80% done with a book club, unannounced book club book.
Rym: But I feel like it'll be a real fast read for a lot of reasons.
Scott: That's how fast I can read when a book is written, uh, modernly, I guess is the word.
Scott: A contemporary novel.
Rym: I don't have to look at a footnote to remember who someone is.
Rym: And even then, I forget again by, like, two pages later.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So, uh, yeah.
Rym: Otherwise, no real cons coming up.
Rym: I'm putting in some panels for PAX East, but the odds that we will go to PAX East to actually play games in PAX are basically near zero.
Scott: Pretty low.
Scott: The most likely- Not zero, but it's low.
Rym: The most likely situation is either myself or me and Scott will go for, like, one day to do some panels and hang out, but that's the extent of it.
Rym: There's no way I'm at PAX East for more than one day in April.
Scott: So, uh, yeah.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: We'll see how it goes.
Rym: Otherwise, we really got nothing going except a bunch of, uh, side projects, uh, working on some non-convention panels still that, uh, might just- Making a new GeekNights website.
Scott: It's coming along, uh, you know, at a pace that is, uh, much better than it was previously.
Scott: I'm getting held up a lot trying to make the RSS feeds real.
Rym: I'm also playing a lot of Fortnite lately.
Scott: I probably would be if I didn't have to install the Epic Store.
Rym: I mean, I had that same reservation.
Rym: I only have one game in the Epic Store and that is Fortnite, but, uh, I gotta say, uh, just before we get into the main bit, I liked PUBG when we were playing it, but- Yeah, it was okay.
Scott: When we played it, I enjoyed it for a couple years ago.
Rym: But now I played Fortnite a bunch, and the other day- Quite a few years ago, actually.
Rym: A bunch of us went to just play PUBG, and, uh, trying to play PUBG after having played a significant amount of Fortnite is like trying to read an even more silted translation of the Tale of Genji, having just read a real book.
Scott: I haven't even played Fortnite even once in my life, and I played PUBG years ago.
Scott: At least, it had to be pre-pandemics with two or three, three plus years ago.
Scott: And going back to PUBG now, it's like, not having played Fortnite even once, PUBG is just not great.
Scott: It's got a lot of issues.
Scott: Yeah, so having played- I can see why the player base really disintegrates.
Rym: Having played Fortnite will amplify that by an order of magnitude, because everything that is slow and tedious about.
Rym: PUBG is just erased from Fortnite.
Rym: Like, nothing.
Rym: At any point, you will never encounter something that's not worth interacting with in Fortnite.
Rym: Anyway, so we got right into it.
Rym: Lifestyle games, like, uh, PUBG.
Scott: Yeah, well, so what is a lifestyle game?
Scott: So, you know, most, you know, people in their lives, uh, when they interact with games, you imagine that it's like, oh, you, you know, you have a game that you play over here, a game that you play over there, right?
Scott: Maybe you even have a game that you play every single day.
Scott: Like, maybe you have a phone game that you have to check in on every morning.
Rym: Like Whirl, I play every morning before I do a work meeting.
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: Or, like, I play a tower defense every morning.
Rym: Or, like, in the evening before I go to bed, I often play one Slay the Spire.
Rym: Like, I just play one Slay the Spire, and then I go to bed.
Scott: Right, but that's not really a lifestyle game.
Scott: A lifestyle game is a game in which you don't necessarily have to play it every day, but you probably are, or playing it most days, but it's a game which not only, you know, you're playing it a lot, but it suddenly occupies a place in your life.
Scott: Like, it becomes a part of your daily existence, right?
Scott: Like, you're now in communities for that game.
Scott: You're thinking about the game when you're, and the game is constantly, you know, refreshing and adding things and bringing you back and giving you a reason, right?
Scott: So, examples of lifestyle games.
Scott: Something like Magic the Gathering, right?
Scott: You're going, you're hanging out with people who play Magic.
Scott: That's not, it's part of your social existence.
Rym: Now, that last bit is not necessarily true, though.
Rym: For example, Counter-Strike 1 6, I would argue, is, for a lot of people, a lifestyle game.
Rym: That game isn't updating.
Scott: Right, well, Magic could be a lifestyle game for one person and not for another person, right?
Scott: You could play Magic in a way such that it is not your lifestyle, but it is definitely marketed and sold and pushed in a way to where they're trying to get that lifestyle customer, right?
Scott: A part of their recreational life is, like, centered around Magic.
Scott: You're paying attention to the competitive scene.
Scott: You're perhaps even trying to compete.
Scott: You're spending a lot of money on it frequently.
Scott: You're following it in the news.
Scott: You've got, like, Magic news sites.
Scott: You're listening to Magic podcasts or, you know, watching Magic YouTube channels, right?
Rym: Like, I'd say the archetypical example of a lifestyle game is chess.
Scott: World of Warcraft.
Scott: Chess is also chess.
Rym: I, like, I play chess.
Rym: Scott's played chess.
Rym: We all know how to play chess.
Rym: I'm not great at chess, but I'll play it.
Scott: I'm awful.
Rym: But, like, I would play a game of chess here and there, uh, but, uh, I'd rather play the Duke.
Rym: I don't know, nor am I interested in my ELO rating in chess.
Scott: Like, I- Mine- I know mine is near the bottom.
Scott: I'm sure- Not the absolute bottom, but way down.
Scott: There are definitely people I can beat in chess, but people who have played more than, like- Yeah, I can beat people who don't know how to play chess or, and people who, like, have never studied anything about chess.
Scott: I will beat them.
Scott: The last time we played a game of chess- One opening, I'm gonna lose.
Rym: The last time we played a game of chess, you beat me, and that was at the Brickhouse Pizza Place in Beacon in the waiting room.
Scott: Let's, let's play a game of online chess.
Rym: I would play a game of online chess with you.
Scott: I, uh- Just once.
Rym: Since then, I'd actually- No looking up online, no looking up openings or getting- Well, well, so, so, uh, no from this point, because I memorized a couple openings a few years ago.
Rym: Uh-oh.
Scott: I've never, I've never- I, I heard about names of openings, but I don't know any of them.
Rym: Yeah, I, uh, I actually, when I play chess, if I ever play it, uh, I always start with a Polish opening, because I learned that one many years ago, and it's extremely effective against novices.
Scott: All right, well, you're not allowed to look up what the Polish opening is to confirm whether you're- Nope, nope, I'm going based on the, what I remember the Polish opening to be.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Which roughly, well, I'm gonna save it as a surprise now.
Rym: Yeah, neither one of us can read anything about chess until we play this game.
Rym: That's the rule.
Rym: Well, I mean, at least- You know what we should do?
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: Total aside, we'll pick a day, let's just live stream us playing that chess game.
Rym: That could be fun.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: We could make that- Some chess person, tell us what chess apt is.
Rym: Yeah, tell us, tell us the best way for the two of us to play a live streamed single game of chess.
Scott: Yeah, bad chess, real bad.
Rym: Like chess so bad, you're gonna- Yeah, any of you who know chess are gonna really be disappointed.
Scott: I'm gonna play it the same way I play every other perfect information abstract game.
Rym: Generally, the way I play chess, I'm real bad until there's so few pieces that I can actually predict how it's gonna go and then- My heuristic is gonna be make a move that costs me the least number of dudes and maybe kills Rym's-deeks.
Rym: Yeah, my goal is get in Scott's grill and hope that he makes a mistake.
Rym: Like, that's how I play chess.
Scott: Maybe try to upgrade a pawn, that would be sick.
Rym: My main goal is never let the other person upgrade a pawn no matter what.
Scott: Well, this is not happening.
Rym: So yeah, we do not play chess as a lifestyle game, but you know what games I have played as lifestyle games in the course of my life?
Rym: Magic.
Rym: When I played Magic, I played it as a lifestyle game.
Rym: I was so deep into Magic, it was like- I was thinking about Magic for like 30% of my waking hours when I played Magic.
Rym: Counter-Strike, I tried to get legitimately good at Counter-Strike.
Rym: I played Counter-Strike so much.
Rym: In retrospect, it's embarrassing.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, Magic, was it a lifestyle game?
Scott: It was sort of borderline because I think it would have been if I had the greater ability to go to more tournaments and get more community involvement.
Scott: I was only playing it with kids I knew, but it was basically- Oh, I went to tournaments.
Rym: I played in a lot of tournaments.
Scott: Right, I went to one.
Scott: I was talking about it.
Scott: I was reading magazines.
Scott: I was buying books.
Scott: I was buying cards.
Rym: I was making decks and playing matches against myself to test those decks out.
Scott: It was like one of my primary activities for the one to three years that I was involved.
Rym: Now, what's interesting is that I think I've noticed most of the discourse about lifestyle games, everybody talks about ortho games almost exclusively.
Scott: Well, because a game that has a competitive scene has a much greater ability to become a lifestyle game because it gives people a reason to go.
Scott: So, you think about most professional sports, they're all lifestyle games, right?
Scott: So, someone who's playing tennis, right?
Scott: It's got a ranking and everything, right?
Scott: If there wasn't a competitive scene around tennis, it would be much harder for it to be a lifestyle game.
Rym: I would argue that Civilization could not have been a lifestyle game until the era of streaming because now there's this weird adjacent place where there are people who play a game exclusively and deeply, but they're live streaming and trying to break things.
Rym: There's this whole universe of people who have basically forced Civilization 6 to be a lifestyle game despite not playing it competitively at any point, but that's kind of an edge case driven by streaming.
Rym: I think we want to focus on ortho games, but two, most tabletop games are incapable.
Scott: Tabletop RPGs are usually the one.
Scott: The Lizards in Dark Places is a lifestyle game for a lot of people.
Rym: D&D is a lifestyle game.
Rym: It was a lifestyle game for me for a long time.
Scott: That's what I just said.
Rym: Yeah, but it's because of that human element.
Rym: Meanwhile, on the other side, most tabletop board games could never be a lifestyle game because the space of competition solidifies into a perfect meta if you actually play them a lot.
Scott: Yeah, you know, the game space is too small.
Scott: There's not enough replay value.
Scott: No one will ever have a better scene, and not only that, the game needs to have some sort of life to it, right?
Scott: Some sort of evolution, right?
Rym: Or it has to have so much depth that it doesn't... Counter-Strike 1.6, the cap on skill is infinite in a game like that, effectively.
Scott: Right, that's why tennis doesn't really need to change because people get old, and the skill cap is infinite.
Scott: You can always run faster, hit the ball harder, hit the ball trickier, right?
Scott: There's no limit.
Scott: The human body is the only limit, but for something like, you know, Carcassonne, it's like they could keep putting out more expansions.
Scott: A lot of them are competitively viable.
Scott: That really hurts, but it's like, you know, it's like there's only so much Carcassonne can give before you've exhausted all of it.
Scott: There's nothing more to see there, and there's not enough social... It's like, even if you have a community built up around it, if it doesn't evolve, it's not a deep enough game like chess or tennis.
Scott: There's nothing else to be said or discuss.
Scott: You've arrived at the answer to Carcassonne.
Scott: It's just going to be random tile draws and seat position that determines who wins any game, and the game doesn't die.
Scott: It just can't sustain like somebody's, you know, being someone's primary interest in their recreational life that they're like so devoted to Carcassonne that, you know, it defines them as a human being.
Scott: It just ends up being a fun game to play now and then, which is fine.
Scott: It doesn't have to be a lifestyle game.
Rym: Yeah, and when I think about it, like, I think there are a lot of different reasons why people, certain kinds of people, gravitate to certain kinds of lifestyle games at different points in their lives.
Rym: For me, the main reason, like the lifestyle games, just thinking about all the ones that achieve that for me, were either a role-playing game type thing or they were a competitive game I was good enough at to experience flow state reliably when I play it.
Rym: Like games that I am not good enough to get to to ever experience flow state don't really do that for me, but like Overwatch, Counter-Strike, all the FPSs I'm pretty good at.
Rym: I just feel like it's almost like soothing to the brain to play a game that I understand well.
Rym: I don't need to learn anything new other than get better at this thing, and I'm playing like within a universe that I know.
Rym: There's people that I know.
Rym: There's spaces that I know.
Rym: It's just, it's a fun social thing.
Rym: that's very easy to see.
Rym: why someone could take a game like Overwatch and make it the only game they play.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, the last game for me that was a lifestyle game was Netrunner, which was Lifestyle for several years.
Scott: I started Netrunner because I saw it highly ranked on BoardGameGeek and I said, "What's that?
Scott: It's Cyberpunk.
Scott: I guess I'll buy it and see what the deal is,".
Scott: and then I found out, "Oh, it's one of those, it's just what I always wanted.
Scott: It's a collectible card game, but you have to collect and buy all the cards,".
Scott: and then I found a community.
Scott: Once I had the community, it's like, "Well, now I'm hanging with these people.
Scott: We're competing,".
Scott: and it was really nice to be able to play a game against people who understood the rules, were trying to win.
Scott: You could play fast.
Scott: You could play repeatedly, and the game kept changing.
Scott: It's like there's an social activity, the game itself, that I could spend a significant portion of my recreational time invested into it, and money also, and not have it get spent.
Scott: It wouldn't run out.
Scott: It kept giving.
Scott: When I gave it, it gave back until it died.
Scott: It's not technically dead now, but- But it's dead.
Scott: Yeah, well, they got the fan-run Project Nisei thing, which is really high quality, but it's not what it was before.
Rym: No.
Rym: Well, like PUBG.
Rym: PUBG distilled down to the people who have decided they will be there till the end.
Scott: But that social- We talked about what a lifestyle game is.
Rym: But I guess that community part actually is so important because it also gives you an automatic social context in that you know everyone you're playing this game with can talk to you about the meta of the game.
Scott: So we're talking about what a lifestyle game is, right?
Scott: So why would you make a lifestyle game versus, if you're a game company, video game or tabletop, right, versus making a one-off game?
Rym: Well, it's way cheaper to take a game that already exists and add stuff to it than it is to make a new game from nothing.
Scott: Well, I don't know about that necessarily.
Scott: I guess a video game, yes.
Scott: But you know, tabletop game, not necessarily.
Scott: Developing expansion, you know, printing materials is necessary.
Rym: I think that's the reason why there are fewer lifestyle tabletop games that have succeeded long term.
Scott: Well, I think it's because the tabletop ones, I think, is the only restriction that, you know, hurts them is that you need to have the people to play with in person, right?
Scott: Because without the social aspect, it's done.
Rym: Yeah, like Imagine if Netrunner existed in a state where you could click a button and you're immediately matched with someone who's about your skill level.
Scott: They did, but the user interface was shitty and unofficial.
Scott: And it still exists.
Scott: Anyway, but it's like you're a game company, you make a lifestyle game.
Scott: What you get is, you know, you think about if you're a single person who makes a game and puts it out there and it sells a pile of copies and it's like, okay, you got a pile of money, but it's not enough money to live the rest of your life, right?
Scott: You need to make another game.
Scott: Well, that game might not be a hit.
Scott: You're gambling each time you make a game.
Scott: If you can make a lifestyle game and make it stick that and you can build your right, that game will build over time.
Scott: Any other game is just going to go down.
Scott: Most sales will probably go down over time unless suddenly there's a new like renewed interest from somewhere, right?
Scott: Like settlers gets a renewed interest in it, you know, once in a while.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: People who play lifestyle games tend to evangelize the lifestyle games they play because they want more people to play it with them and they're desperately afraid it will die, right?
Scott: If you can create a game that is a lifestyle game, then as a, you know, as the person who makes and sells it, you can now live off of it more securely as it's a constant revenue stream and not just this one big blob of risk that you're going to repeat rolling the dice over and over again, hoping that you hit enough times to be able to pay your bills.
Scott: If you can hit on a lifestyle game, then you're all set.
Scott: And if you fail on the lifestyle game, well, that initial first set you produced wasn't any bigger a risk than any other tabletop game that you would have failed on, right?
Scott: So you're better off rolling the dice with lifestyle games over and over until one hits.
Scott: And then you can make that your life, right?
Scott: Running that game.
Rym: So thinking more about when I played lifestyle games, it's, there's also this aspect, at feel like there's more I could get out of it.
Rym: Anytime I hit a point in a game where I feel like there's nothing novel or different I could get out of it, or I feel like I could not get better reasonably.
Rym: Like there's nothing I would do differently.
Rym: I lose interest.
Rym: But like most of the lifestyle games I've played in my life were FPSs where the skill cap is literally infinite.
Rym: And no matter how good I am and how good I feel like I'm playing, if I'm playing, I could win a game or lose a game and think I could have done that better.
Rym: I could have learned something and done something differently.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, that's going to be just automatically true for any sport, period.
Rym: That's why a lot of sports are lifestyle games.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The human body has no limit, right?
Scott: But any, if it's not a sport like chess, it needs to be so incredibly deep, right?
Rym: I think there's also an aspect of if a game is sufficiently complex or difficult and you as a person have invested enough in it to reach basic proficiency, it feels like a waste if you don't use that proficiency.
Rym: Like, ah, I spent all this time to get decent to this game and then I just stop.
Scott: Not necessarily.
Rym: There's definitely a sunk cost for some people in like, I got good at this game.
Rym: I'm going to fucking play it now.
Scott: Eh, sometimes.
Scott: Depends.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I think the bigger thing to keep a lifestyle game going, you know, it's like, that's true that if a game does run out of depth, that it will end.
Scott: And that's why the game set to keep changing and adding to themselves, uh, to keep it going.
Scott: But I think more, what keeps the lifestyle game going is just the social aspect, right?
Scott: It's like you could have a game that's deep as hell.
Scott: And if the social structure surrounding the game collapses, then that's going to be the end of it, right?
Scott: If someone plays magic, but their friends stop have suddenly have a different interest and aren't talking about magic anymore.
Scott: That's it, right?
Scott: Unless that person finds new friends or goes to the game store or something, you know, if the game store has a, is running some tabletop RPG, and then they stop running it frequently or whatever, it's like, that's it.
Scott: That game is going to die.
Scott: Even if the publisher keeps publishing more stuff, that's really high quality.
Scott: You know, it's like, you know, what, you know, net runner, even before the publisher, you know, I mean, they messed it up quite a few times in various ways, but what really killed it most was simply less people showing up to play it at the, you know, at the, at the meetings, it's like, you know, we had, we were having tournaments like twice a month with crowds showing up, you know, we had, we'd have store championships, people filling up every seat.
Scott: And then later on, it's like, you'd have a meetup and there'd be like, you know, sometimes you'd show up and like, no one else would show up and you'd go home.
Scott: And so maybe one person shows up, you play a couple of games and go home.
Rym: Well, just like in a video game, you go to the matchmaking and 10 minutes go by and it hasn't found you a match.
Rym: You're a little worried now.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's not just about the game.
Scott: You know, it's all.
Scott: the social part of it is, you know, combined with the game, the game becomes, even if you suck at the game, right?
Scott: You're still like involved in the community around it.
Scott: You're following the game.
Scott: You're into the game as your primary interest.
Scott: And it's your connection to this community.
Scott: Uh, you know, that can keep you going in it.
Scott: Well, look at us.
Rym: Neither one of us ever got good at Counter-Strike.
Rym: We were not great, but we played it a lot in college, but I feel like we wouldn't have played it if it weren't for the fact that so many people we knew were also playing it.
Rym: If I joined a server half the time, you and half our friends were there in the server playing with us.
Scott: But I mean, we weren't hanging out in like Counter-Strike, you know, forums or no, like, you know, it wasn't that it didn't have that next level where Counter-Strike was the focus of your life.
Rym: But we would play it every day and we did play it a lot.
Scott: And when we were playing it a lot isn't enough to make it a lifestyle game.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well, we were close to it.
Rym: We were close to that in that it was part of our lifestyle.
Rym: We were playing it regularly.
Rym: And also we would talk about it when we weren't playing it.
Rym: And I noticed as we talked about it, less that coincided with us playing it less.
Rym: And that coincided with a few of us stopped playing Counter-Strike to play other games.
Rym: And that sort of destroyed the broad interest among a lot of our friends in playing Counter-Strike.
Scott: I even see Link to the Past Randomizer being a lifestyle game for a lot of people.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: And it's like they've got, you know, they have a competitive community, but yeah, a lot of people play it who are really, you know, not maybe not even as good as I am, but I see them and it's like they're up and they got a Discord, right?
Scott: The Discord is huge.
Scott: How many people are in that Discord?
Scott: Let me see.
Scott: Hold on.
Scott: There are, get out of the way.
Scott: Eleven.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: They have so many rolls.
Scott: Eight, eight, over 8,000 people have the Discord for Link to the Past Randomizer, right?
Scott: And like that community, you know, they keep it going.
Scott: They have daily races, weekly races, right?
Scott: There's streaming, there's spectating, there's new modes, there's new people working on tools.
Scott: There's so many different ways to come at the game.
Rym: And it's self-fulfilling.
Rym: I think a lot of people would not play Randomizers as much if there wasn't the culture of you can share it, you can play it with other people, you can talk about it.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: They got races, they got, you know, it's like there's different ways to play it.
Scott: And you can also, you know, you can come into that community and be like, you could, you could be a, like a, you know, like a sportscaster for it, where you just, you know, that's what your, that's your involvement in the community.
Scott: But now you're still in that sort of lifestyle game space, even if you're not, you know, the champ or trying to be the champ.
Scott: Some people aren't any good at it, or some people are good at the stream, you know, non-competitively, but people like their stream because they're a streamer, right?
Scott: They want to watch them, whatever.
Rym: I do think too, a lot of people speedrun it, some people don't.
Rym: A lot of people get into lifestyle games, partly because like, it's a game that they play every day.
Rym: And for most people, they don't play a lot of different kinds of games.
Rym: Like we're like, the people who play a lot of different games from a lot of different genres across a lot of different platforms and media are relatively rare in the gaming world.
Rym: We did a big panel about this at PAX many years ago, like why it's so hard to find anyone to play the game you want to play with.
Rym: But if you play the same game long enough, most people will have a few hobbies and that game becomes a hobby, just like any other hobby, just like woodworking or something else.
Rym: It becomes the thing they do when they get home from work.
Rym: Even if they don't engage that much with the community, it's still sort of a lifestyle game in that they come home, they play two hours of Counter-Strike, then they go about their life.
Scott: Yeah, you know, if you're a person who plays a lot of different games, right?
Scott: I mean, you look at us, we come after work, we're like, what game should we play tonight, and we can't even pick one.
Rym: Like one night I play Fortnite, the next night I'm reading Tale of Genji, the night after that I'm playing Overwatch by myself, the night after that we're playing Civilization 6 competitively in a group.
Scott: Right, it's like if we had a lifestyle game that we are all in the community of, right, and like focusing on it, you know, if I'd gotten any of you people to play Netrunner instead of the other people I met, but I guess it was good, I met a lot of good people playing it, you know, then it's like we could have just gone, you know, we would just be playing, it wouldn't be any question like what game do we play, it's like there's one game and we're playing it, right, that's our game.
Rym: It would be the situation where I'm cutting class, I'm like, hey Scott, when are you coming back, I'm playing Counter-Strike.
Scott: But yeah, it's, you know, I think the main question, I think, is like if you have a lifestyle game, it's like what percentage of your life do you end up dedicating to it, and then when you look back on your life as a whole, do you regret?
Scott: It's like I played Netrunner for a handful of years, right, but if it had gone on several years longer, like if I was still playing it, I think it was mostly, you know, last decade, right, you know, earlier.
Rym: Well, like if I was still playing Counter-Strike 1.6 literally every day, either I'm a pro or that is my only hobby.
Scott: Right, but like if I was still playing Netrunner as much as I did back then, all the way up until this point, it's like when I look back as an old man, it's like what's my obituary gonna be, played Netrunner?
Scott: It's like, you know, it's like even if you don't think that that's, that's not an unhealthy activity, it's not a wrong way to spend your time, you know, there's nothing wrong with playing, you know, if you some MMO, you just play it a whole bunch, but you
Rym: might have missed out on something, like think about as
Scott: long as it doesn't, you know, if it's not hurting other parts of your life, you know, you're eating, your hygiene's okay, you're not neglecting your responsibilities, right, you know, whatever, you know, there's nothing wrong with playing a game a lot, but will you have a regret when you only are going to be alive for so long, will you have a regret looking back on your life as a whole and being like, wow, I spent like 10% of my life only playing Game
Rym: X,
Scott: was that the life, you know, that was my life, I can't live it again.
Scott: Or you
Rym: can get a very myopic view where say you don't regret it, like you love Magic, you played Magic, like that was the only game you played your whole life, like great, like you, you look back on your deathbed and you think, fuck yeah, no regrets, maybe you missed out on a slightly different game.
Rym: that would have given you a much broader perspective on games or things as a result, even if you have zero regrets about it, like when I talk to people, like I know some people who pretty much just like Magic is the only game they play, and that's fine, like they have other hobbies outside of gaming, but the only game they play is Magic, but it's interesting that they tend to have extremely limited opinions on games generally, and any game conversation they really can only express or talk about it through the lens of Magic, the only game they play.
Scott: That is definitely a danger with a lifestyle game is that if you are most, a lot of people, like you said, who play a lifestyle game probably have not played a lot of games in total, and yeah, their perspective gets very warped and limited to where that one game that is their lifestyle game becomes the lens through which they view all other games, right, and that can be, that can be dangerous.
Rym: Yeah, that, that is how you get things like last hitting in MOBAs.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: [Music].