Rym: It's Wednesday February 23rd 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are reviewing.
Rym: Mamoru hosted us 2021 film Bell.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So a classic a trope on GeekNights like if there's a TV tropes page about GeekNights What are the things that we list?
Scott: someone did make one?
Scott: I don't know if it's still there.
Scott: Oh, I hold it is.
Rym: look it up while we're talking But I feel like one of the things that would go there is Us saying one or two things either warm today or the inverse of that and The reference of which are stolen from both of which is stolen.
Rym: Almost every joke we have is stolen But it was.
Rym: it was warm today To a degree that I'm mad about because if I'd known it was gonna be this warm I would have fucking taken today off work.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know 66 degrees Fahrenheit is Not what I would say is like really warm.
Scott: It's not beef time 66 degrees Fahrenheit, but on February 23rd Right.
Scott: Oh
Rym: February 23rd when it was like snowing a few days before that and I was the
Scott: last time I went Outside I was touched by snowflakes falling from the sky at least a few of them
Rym: Yeah, and then tonight it's gonna be freezing cold again Like Rapidly like a cold front's gonna come in and ruin this right
Scott: and now yeah, but like in the morning when I woke up You know, the sky was overcast and then in the afternoon the Sun was hurting my eyes again.
Rym: Yeah It's.
Rym: uh The problem is what I need.
Scott: meanwhile while it was and you know It was 66 in New York City at that exact moment our friends in Albany It was 36 a 30 Fahrenheit degree difference.
Rym: in that short of a distance There's gonna be a 30 degree Fahrenheit distance for us between today at around 1 p.m.
Rym: And four hours from now.
Scott: Yep, I guess we must be on like the edge of some pressure system.
Rym: Yep Oh, you hear that wind just like rising and rising outside over the last hour.
Scott: There's a noise cancelling headphones now.
Rym: Well, yeah The windows open but that led to another problem because the dirt bikes found out that it was warm.
Rym: I guess someone told them.
Rym: What I heard out the window a little while ago was the loudest dirt biking I've ever heard Outside of when DMX died and there was that procession Mmm, but they eventually left.
Rym: I think they got over the Queensboro Bridge, so they're gone at least for now.
Rym: Okay, but the worst is if it stays cold, I'm fine cuz I can go ski.
Rym: if it stays warm I'm fine biking and all the other sports I do.
Rym: but when it's in between the two or flipping back and forth I can't do anything Like if the weather if I know the weather shitty.
Rym: Well, like play a board game or I'll like plan to play Civ for six hours.
Rym: But I'm in this like period where I can't actually plan anything.
Rym: So I waste a day like this working and then it'll be like a shitty day tomorrow.
Rym: but I didn't make a plan to do something with that time.
Rym: and yeah We're just old men ranting about the weather.
Rym: That's what happens when we do a podcast for 16 years give or take Mm-hmm.
Rym: So in the news we got to talk about this verse.
Rym: It's not anime related or comic related or anything, but it happened today and it's real bad.
Rym: So we have to talk about it.
Rym: We cannot cover this in a lot of detail nor should we because you should go read real reporting about this and do whatever it Is you're gonna do.
Rym: the governor of Texas today?
Scott: Basically issued an order saying that I thought it was a law that the Texas legislature passed.
Rym: No, the Texas governor ordered this.
Scott: he ordered all state different.
Scott: that's different from what I thought.
Scott: so I thought wrong.
Rym: Yep so basically what the Texas governor ordered is that all gender affirming care or even the recognition of a gender that's different from quote Sexuality which is we all know that we all know that is the gradient.
Rym: people who don't believe that are just wrong.
Scott: Basically said that affirming that or recognizing that is child abuse That a doctor is a governor have the power to do this by order in Texas.
Rym: Yes Texas is a real.
Rym: Texas is a real fucked up state.
Rym: governors in America have broad powers and in Texas governors have extraordinarily broad powers.
Rym: Okay, I remember Texas is a state that literally cut itself off from the rest of North America's power grid.
Rym: There are exactly four like interconnects for electricity in all of North America once Quebec For reasons you can imagine.
Rym: two of them are the United States and the fourth one is just Texas by itself.
Rym: They did this on purpose for terrible reasons and this goes further.
Rym: It also requires Anyone who encounters a child who expresses trans identity in any way?
Rym: Should that has to be reported so that their parents can be investigated for child abuse.
Scott: What if you don't report it?
Scott: That's that you could be prosecuted for endangering a child even though there's no that even though there's no law It's just an order.
Rym: basically the the best way I can describe you.
Scott: when you go to court The lawyer is gonna be like, yes They broke government order from the governor as opposed to so
Rym: it's basically the attorney like the Attorney General Of the state that the equivalent of the Department of Justice of the state are all saying This is how we interpret the law.
Rym: This is how we'll prosecute these things Uh-huh.
Scott: So what?
Scott: but I guess they're just counting it as child abuse as they have an existing child abuse law.
Scott: And that's what.
Rym: that's basically what they're doing and there's a lot of details and nuance that I'm skipping over.
Scott: I guess there's gonna be some court fights saying well, here's the problem.
Rym: the Anything like this will eventually go to the Supreme Court, which has been extremely Not on the side of justice, especially around issues lately.
Rym: I would argue the Supreme Court is literally illegitimate right now based on how it's progressed.
Rym: So we can't rely on the courts and Texas it might not make it to the Supreme Court, you know, yeah Well, we'll see how this goes.
Rym: But this like this is a rapidly evolving fucked up an extremely dangerous situation for kids in Texas.
Rym: The good news one little glimmer of hope.
Rym: multiple County legislators People in different levels of police in various parts of the state mayors Have one by one made statements basically publicly saying they will refuse to follow this order.
Scott: But I mean there's even in the reddest of states, right?
Scott: There's the places where the people live.
Rym: It's pretty much only blue places in Texas which are doing this which is very obviously.
Rym: Yeah So, uh, this is breaking like news.
Rym: that's gonna progress.
Rym: But the only thing I want to point out that I think you should all internalize because I realize and I tweet about this a lot, but you shouldn't read my Twitter.
Rym: my Twitter is like 50% me screaming about politics 20% weird skeletons and the rest is like pictures of rabbits, but basically the all those photos you see from Nazi Germany like Nazi Germany like all those book burnings.
Rym: a Big percentage of those book burnings were actually from a specific incident where the Nazis went and burned all the LGBT resources in this one Institute and Very few people who use those photos talk about what was actually being burned.
Rym: They talk about oh the Nazis burned books.
Rym: They don't point out that the Nazis actually went after the LGBT community Hardest and first in terms of direct actions that they took against them as a community.
Rym: So Use that knowledge as you See fit and honestly treat 19 treat 2022 like it's 1922 and do whatever it is.
Rym: You need to do.
Rym: Also leave Texas if you can.
Rym: a lot of people can't.
Scott: I mean, you know if you can but you know It's if you have a business.
Scott: don't do business.
Rym: Oh, yeah, if you can boycott the state of Texas, absolutely We need to treat it like a failed state.
Scott: that's in Texas, you know, if you go on like, I don't know.
Rym: I mean I was already.
Scott: if you're shopping online and you see like something you want to buy look and see if it's from like Us maybe it's an Etsy or something, right?
Scott: You can usually see where the Etsy person is from.
Scott: if they're from Texas don't buy from them.
Rym: Yeah, it's not.
Rym: it's rough though Because a lot of people are trapped there.
Rym: So just follow the news find figure out like I'm trying to figure out exactly what charities to donate to that love the most impact And we'll see what happens.
Scott: I mean, you know, that's the story of pretty much all Suffering right is you know, someone is lives within political borders that you know, do not align You know with them right and it you know ranging from you know like Texas to like, you know, Uyghurs in China or You know a gay person in Russia, right?
Scott: It's like, you know You people are stuck living in a place then the politics of that place or not are not good for them.
Rym: And the worst part is Because of the way the United States is structured.
Rym: There's almost nothing we can do to stop this from outside of Texas.
Rym: nor can people within Texas effectively stop it short of civil disobedience and mass protests and drastic like extra legal actions partly because the only way to actually stop this legally would be a federal law or Supreme Court ruling and Electing a different governor of Texas.
Rym: Yep, which is difficult because we didn't pass the Voting Rights Act.
Rym: So Texas is.
Rym: the vote is so suppressed in Texas that even if the majority of Texans disagree with this It would be very difficult to displace this governor Mm-hmm.
Rym: And yeah, I I don't know what to do about it.
Scott: I'd just keep an eye on this one because the Republican You know you do what you can do, but you know, you're ultimately.
Scott: You know one person.
Scott: you can't what can one person do something but you know a collective action can do more and then What can you do more than that?
Rym: Not much but mark my words and mark the words of activists.
Rym: This isn't an isolated incident.
Rym: Texas is for the Republican Party of America the incubator of.
Rym: basically the idea Is that about every?
Scott: no actually they pretty much all all the red states are incubator.
Scott: They're trying everything everywhere to see what works.
Rym: It's more that Texas in particular is the model because remember Texas is the state where they took control of the textbook industry.
Rym: Texas is a large state that has to suppress going in Florida.
Scott: They got stuff going everywhere.
Rym: Yeah, but Texas is a state that if the vote weren't suppressed could be blue.
Rym: That's why it's often the incubator because that is a test of how far can they push it in a place?
Rym: That isn't just completely controlled by the Republicans.
Rym: How far can they push voters?
Scott: Even like the red estate like what fucking Idaho or something?
Rym: Oh West Virginia might actually be.
Rym: West Virginia is also the whitest state 97% white.
Rym: last I'd look that up.
Scott: Right, but what percentage there's still?
Scott: probably like what 30 40 percent blueness even It's.
Rym: I mean that I don't want to derail this to another.
Rym: we we could do a Thursday show on this if you want to.
Scott: I'm just saying there's people who are stuck there.
Scott: That's that was the point.
Rym: Oh, there's people stuck everywhere, but Texas now is People and materially dangerous to trans children.
Rym: Yep So, uh not to you know, it's tough to talk about something like that and then just get on with the newscast.
Rym: So I don't want to just pull a so anyway in the news but just really don't.
Rym: don't let this one slide like pay attention to that one and Don't go if if we're the first people you heard about this from I Don't know subscribe to like one more person on Twitter or something like Jesus.
Rym: So, uh, I guess in other news There is comics news.
Rym: That is bad.
Rym: Comixology has basically been destroyed by Amazon.
Rym: like.
Scott: well Comixology was bought by Amazon a long time ago, right?
Scott: So Comixology was sort of like the.
Scott: it wasn't the first ever I don't think but it was basically the biggest and strongest digital comics Seller.
Scott: right sort of like I guess, you know the Spotify or Netflix of comic books in the in the US You know and you could see.
Scott: you could subscribe to various comics to get them in digital ebook form legally.
Scott: You know the prices were you know in sort of this in-between spot of not being so ridiculously inexpensive that it was a no-brainer But not being so expensive that it was like a ripoff.
Rym: but above everything the experience like a Lot of people have tried to make comics readable in digital form with technology a lot of factors in play there But different kinds of comics right?
Scott: That's the reason I have like this huge shelves behind me.
Scott: Yeah is because this you know.
Scott: a lot of comics You know have different formats especially ones that were made in the print era before digital comics were a thing and It's like there isn't even though it's just a 2d image.
Scott: there really isn't a way To present, you know the comic in a digital form.
Scott: It's like yeah taking a movie and making it an MPEG instead of film as long as the resolutions high enough.
Scott: It's like, you know, right a mp3 versus a CD.
Scott: It's like yeah, okay yeah, but if you just scan in even with the highest resolution scanner and make a JPEG out of a two-page spread in a book, you know, it's not the same.
Scott: It's actually not the same.
Scott: It's like one of the few Mediums of art where it's like I guess sculpture would be another one.
Scott: It's like yeah looking at a 3d model of a sculpture versus going to the sculpture physically where you can touch It is not the same if they let you touch it.
Scott: Yeah There's some mediums of art that transform to digital with fine and there are some that don't and comics is one of them Above all else.
Rym: what comic solos you got?
Rym: absolutely right is their reader Was one of the best like it were right.
Rym: so well, I've read I mean down the comics on that thing over the years.
Scott: The only way that they could really compete with things like piracy of comics Which is real easy to do you can just download tour instead of like every Marvel comic that came out this month.
Scott: Right every month someone puts that together from scanning and whatnot.
Scott: The only way they could compete and actually sell digital comics was you know, they made software that provided wasn't perfect But it was still probably the world's premier and best digital comic reading Software across platforms.
Rym: and when Amazon bought it that kept working just fine until very recently.
Scott: Amazon was doing a weird thing where it's like if you went to amazon.com and look for a comic it would you could like Buy it on Kindle and comics ology, right?
Scott: It was like the same purchase like, you know, there's like a manga that was on boat.
Scott: You know It.
Scott: just say buy on Kindle and comics ology six bucks.
Scott: you buy it and then you could now read it in the comics ology App or on your Kindle.
Scott: Yeah, I guess if you're reading a normal format black and white manga, that's actually pretty nice to Kindle paper.
Rym: why it's pretty in the paper way for a simple black and white comic.
Scott: But if you're gonna read a Marvel superhero full-color x-men, you know 24 page issue Kindle's not gonna cut it.
Scott: the Kindle app on your computer isn't gonna cut it.
Scott: No, the Kindle app in a browser on your iPad isn't gonna cut it.
Rym: But the comics ology reader did a pretty damn good job.
Scott: Ology reader was the best that you were gonna get.
Scott: but you know time went on.
Scott: I think you I feel like it's been years since Amazon bought them.
Scott: Yeah, and Amazon's pretty much like.
Scott: alright That's enough of that comics ology biz.
Scott: Let's bring it all into the Kindle zone.
Scott: Are they even gonna keep the brand comics ology?
Scott: It's like, you know, yeah, I don't even know.
Rym: Happen here.
Rym: But the thing that people are reacting to the strongest is that the reader that replaced it doesn't fucking work.
Rym: Like you can't read comics in this thing.
Rym: Like it is broken I if you're watching the stream like I'm looking at House of M right now, which I was reading so I had it in my Library, uh, you can't zoom.
Rym: you can't zoom in and out.
Rym: it done.
Rym: It's non reactive.
Rym: if you try to zoom it like changes pages.
Rym: if you force zoom with the browser You don't actually get a quality increase.
Rym: It just zooms in.
Rym: unlike these it's Unusable garbage.
Rym: Yeah, I literally cannot read these comics now.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know the Like look at this.
Scott: Yeah, I mean this is the reason that I buy.
Rym: You know, even though I'm doing it notice how it's not fucking doing anything.
Scott: and now suddenly I'm said I buy a lot of comics on paper because even the Kindle even the comics ology app was not perfect.
Scott: But this new thing is like this enormous step backwards.
Scott: It's complete trash compared to the original comics ology app as it was.
Scott: so I guess Amazon just really doesn't want people to buy those comics digitally anymore.
Scott: and The company's publishing those comics, right?
Scott: I guess Marvel DC.
Rym: Oh if I was a comic author I would not even want my comics to be on this platform if that's the experience right.
Scott: and like the publishers though It's like, you know Marvel is like, you know, they're okay with this move.
Scott: It's like those people who were bought paying money for legal digital comics when they could have pirated Right.
Scott: Are they gonna now go to the?
Scott: they're not gonna keep paying if the app is this garbage, right?
Scott: First of all, how many are gonna stick with it?
Scott: I can't imagine that many.
Scott: How many are gonna go and buy paper comics?
Scott: can't imagine that many.
Rym: so here's the question was this insult It?
Rym: was there some intentional reason to make it a worse experience?
Rym: or is Amazon just actually that incompetent.
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: I guess it's such a small.
Scott: It's one of those things where it's so insignificant compared to their larger business that they just don't care.
Rym: They've got like the weakest product manager and like the C team of engineers on it like right.
Scott: It's like the.
Scott: you know, the decision-making power came from some brand people who are like we all.
Scott: we bought this comics ology thing.
Scott: We got to integrate it with the Kindle thing.
Scott: get that comics ology out of here, right?
Scott: They're just making some brand level decision and then you know, they want to like.
Scott: oh Why are we paying all these people to work on this comics ology app?
Scott: We got a Kindle app at already, right?
Scott: Why let's just you know merge people get rid of.
Scott: people say, you know save money.
Scott: They're not thinking about.
Scott: you know, the the details down there.
Rym: Oh and the other big change that many of you Just my guess based on what I know about there is another big change.
Rym: It's uh, but it didn't affect us, but I only found about it from reporting.
Rym: All the subscription stuff is no longer available outside of the US.
Rym: Yep, US only I think a lot of it is.
Scott: you might get rid of the subscription parts actually entirely.
Rym: I feel like they will.
Scott: they're just gonna make it individual by which is all I've ever done was individual.
Rym: Yeah, Amazon has never liked subscriptions like even for like shows that have like ongoing seasons Like they.
Rym: they always made it a confusing mess and they and I never make it easy for you to just say Give me all the Steven universe as it comes out.
Rym: Like they'd always kind of fun.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I'm reading I'm buying every volume of Chainsaw Man.
Scott: I have bought legally on Kindle And I have to remember like when a new one's out and go find it and click buy with one click or whatever And it sends it to my Kindle.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, the worst thing is this is the kind of episode we would say Hey, so you should use this instead as far as I know.
Rym: There's nothing I can't think of any.
Scott: you should you should Pirate or use some other, you know free app, even though it won't be as good Find a way to use the old comics ology app.
Scott: Someone will hack something together by Sarah.
Rym: come by paper comics again And just like give them away or don't or just don't read just you know, read something else instead.
Scott: Complain to the publisher.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, it's uh, it's rough.
Rym: And if you if you doubt how bad this UX is I'm gonna link to an article that shows like details Exactly how.
Rym: but it's so much worse than you're imagining.
Scott: Yeah All right, so some smaller You know, but significant news is so everyone, you know, we all everyone knows Miyazaki for listening to this episode.
Scott: You got it.
Scott: That is right and you know Everyone thinks that Miyazaki's anime because that's most of his work as biggest works for all animations and everyone I think hopefully knows That he did manga before then and Nausicaa being the one that's the most popular right much like, you know, Akira has a manga that is longer bigger You know not quite the same as the anime really right?
Scott: Nausicaa is much the same way.
Scott: there's this huge sprawling epic tale of Nausicaa and The movie is just sort of a you know, sort of Small piece of it cast through a prism, right?
Scott: It's still amazingly good right in both cases Akira and Nausicaa anyway.
Scott: But did you know that Miyazaki made other manga besides that?
Scott: He did but they've never been available legally in English or even I've never even seen them available illegally in English either maybe somewhere but One of them is going to be published in English legally Shuna's journey from 1983. so a manga that's as old as I am almost It's gonna be available later this year in English Translated.
Rym: I'm pretty excited about that.
Scott: Yeah, so that's that's.
Rym: you won't be able to read it.
Rym: on comics ology.
Scott: It's like you had me a Zaki manga as you were holding out on and these manga companies are publishing like some Some garbage.
Scott: No one's ever heard of.
Scott: and like two people read right?
Scott: It's like come on people.
Scott: If there's legendary all-time great mangas Bring those on over you.
Scott: I thought you know, you thought you finished the job back, you know last decade It's like no you didn't you didn't finish the job.
Scott: get back on it All right now.
Scott: real sad news.
Scott: So there is a person named Kazutaka Miyatake Who is a mecha designer, right?
Scott: So a lot of the robots and other, you know mechanical things in many old famous animes like space battles of Yamato and Arcadia my youth and Macross Plus, right This guy had a large hand in designing You know the mecha's of various kinds and ships and things in all those anime.
Scott: I can't a mat, you know and that It's an interesting position in that, you know as an artist and creator You had such a large hand in making something that was so significant To a lot of people.
Scott: like the design of like a particular airplane in someone's favorite show can end up being like this legendary creation.
Scott: But the actual compensation for doing that work is like in the amount of work that this person did.
Scott: I can't imagine they don't have other jobs besides mecha design because like there's only so many things that they worked on.
Scott: Yeah, right you know, but Tragedy has struck This person in that there was an electrical fire in their apartment.
Scott: this dude is like, you know old.
Rym: he's 72 He's like and he was Escaped but he was injured in the fire and lost his apartment.
Scott: He lost his apartment and he lost his wife Yeah in a horrible fire.
Scott: It was like devastating.
Scott: So this person has created Significant meaningful artworks that have a place in people's hearts around.
Scott: the world was never I can't imagine was ever compensated.
Scott: well You know was living in this tiny apartment.
Scott: it got set on fire, you know He lost the person he loved the most in addition to all all kinds of stuff.
Scott: He's been living in Right.
Scott: Oh, look at this a government that you know for what.
Scott: I'm sure there's plenty of bad things We can say about the Japanese government, but the local government provided him a place to live.
Scott: in the meantime in the US you'd he'd be on the street, right.
Scott: so Unless he had a relative or something who knows what or so there was a GoFundMe to raise some money To help this guy out, you know tens of thousands of dollars, which is you know, not a large amount of money Considering, you know the the grand scheme of the world.
Scott: But it's just a real sad story, especially in the context of like, you know, a lot of other tragedies.
Scott: I keep seeing in You know the Japanese Animation and manga world right you had, you know the arson attack in Kyoto, I guess also involving fire, right?
Scott: You know that was that was way worse than this and this is already extremely terrible.
Scott: Yeah, you know for an industry that pays you basically right almost nothing right as a whole, right?
Scott: It's this is just a microcosm of the the greater industry right where you have people doing works that you know Creating art that have huge cultural significance.
Rym: They're impactful.
Rym: They're beloved right to certain people.
Scott: There is not a lot of compensation for it.
Scott: You know the lives of those people isn't necessarily, you know that luxurious Unless you're like, you know the few people who are like mega hits right, you know, just know like to Miyazaki for instance I'm sure he's doing alright.
Scott: and Meanwhile on top of that you have all sorts of additional dangers and tragedies.
Scott: You know some that befall all of us like pandemics, but also You know like the in the Kyoto thing you had, you know, but disgruntled people coming at them.
Scott: Yeah, right It's just like these little old animators Just doing.
Scott: they're doing their drawings and they got to deal with extra bullshit on top of the bullshit Everyone else already has to deal with.
Rym: yeah all within the broader late capitalist dystopia that we all live in.
Scott: yep, so Your daily reminder Anime industry, huh?
Rym: but anyway things of the day.
Rym: I realize I just did the but anyway thing.
Rym: like I said, I wouldn't in the beginning of the show But here we are 20 minutes later.
Scott: Anyway, so, uh, this is very much my kind of thing not just like the YouTube video about it But this is this is a rare instance of Rym has a thing of the day Probably better than my thing of the day.
Rym: It's a in real life.
Rym: This is the kind of shit I like am really invested in.
Rym: like.
Rym: imagine you're hiking through the woods just like in the middle of nowhere.
Rym: You find a pipe or you find a hole and then you poke a stick in it and you realize that that hole goes Way deeper than the stick.
Scott: and then you want to give you any specifics because my memory is not that good But I've definitely had experiences of this nature.
Rym: I've climbed inside of old aqueducts before I've broken into buildings.
Rym: I Spent hours poking around inside of an abandoned refinery like an oil refinery the Texaco owned in Beacon.
Rym: So what do these kids do think of the day?
Rym: They found a really deep mystery pipe in the woods.
Rym: But unlike young Rym, they live in a world where they just have a GoPro.
Rym: They strapped a flashlight and a GoPro to a string and they just lowered the GoPro as far as they could lower it into this Pipe and then they pulled it out and then they looked at the video to see what the fuck was down there.
Scott: Yeah, the only disappointing thing is that you know, it's a directional flashlight.
Scott: So yeah got to the bottom.
Scott: They couldn't see that much.
Rym: I think what I was fascinating is when they got to the bottom.
Rym: There's actually something down there.
Rym: There's like a big cave.
Scott: Yeah, they're right.
Scott: So I think what you could do is you could actually go back for a rerun Find some you know, take some like flares or something and shove them down the hole first and then send the go.
Rym: I go further.
Rym: I am confident I in an environment like this cuz I'm pretty sure I know where this is roughly.
Rym: And you know where this is because the kind of forest it is implies the region.
Rym: But I didn't even have to do this research because when I scroll down one of the first comments is Geologist here the first 15 feet or so are still.
Scott: Geologist knows exactly what the fuck's going on in a hole.
Scott: the ground geologist is like.
Rym: It's probably.
Rym: y'all just might as well be hole-in-the-ground experts probably like on the in the Appalachian Mountains like maybe upstate, New York.
Rym: This is it's this kind of thing.
Rym: It's that kind of thing.
Rym: It was probably an old-time natural gas.
Rym: Well, they probably you can see the drill bit at the bottom like that thing.
Rym: That was the drill bit for when they drilled it.
Rym: They probably accidentally found a giant cave which fucked up their natural gas like.
Rym: well So they gave up and drilled somewhere else and this is just what they left behind.
Scott: Is there any gas?
Scott: I mean guess if you throw a match down there would that explode because they dug a hole?
Rym: Try it like they were gonna do a natural gas thing.
Rym: It's probably not there anymore.
Rym: the holes open and venting.
Rym: You can read this comment.
Rym: I'm not gonna read the whole thing, but that's why I made it the thing of the day.
Rym: We live in a world where some kids can find a hole and throw a GoPro down it for funsies and immediately Some rando on the internet can actually from that video alone explain in detail What that hole is with a high degree of accuracy.
Rym: That is an amazing world to live in if we can just deal with all this other shit that's going on.
Scott: Yep, even just 10 15, you know years ago that hole if someone came across it would have been like, you know Some kids might throw some rocks down there for fun.
Rym: Then I might I might have risked like lose my flashlight just throw it down there just to get a glimpse and then that's it.
Rym: Maybe throw a match down there, which?
Scott: Depending on when it was water at the bottom.
Rym: There was water at the bottom unsurprisingly All right.
Scott: So now my thing of the day, which is still quite good.
Scott: So there's this dude I think he's in according to the video is in Iran and He's got one leg.
Scott: It's a one leg, dude.
Scott: I don't like a lot might be Despite being a dude who's got one leg.
Scott: this dude Parkour's Like.
Scott: wow, he Parkour's like, you know better than I'm ever gonna park my whole life.
Scott: That's for sure, right?
Scott: So it's pretty pretty cool.
Scott: And whenever I see videos like this, you know, I have two thoughts.
Scott: one is I definitely don't want to end up, you know in a situation where my body is damaged or missing a leg or anything like that.
Scott: But if I'm ever so unfortunate that that does happen, even though I do I will do my best to avoid it.
Scott: I would hope that I have the psychological fortitude to you know, make the most of it like, you know, this dude is and not just Be sad one leg.
Rym: I think about that a lot because honestly but like similarly when I see I ski a lot like I ski pretty hardcore stuff.
Rym: that's like a main hobby of mine, but Very often what I'm skiing I'll see people skiing in sleds like.
Rym: there are skis for people who are paralyzed from the waist down.
Rym: There are.
Rym: now there's a form of skiing for blind people like you can ski where Basically two people ski like near you with leads and they can talk on you and sort of guide you and shout directions.
Rym: So you can ski and they're like sort of guiding and being your eyes.
Rym: There's all these cool adaptive things and I just.
Rym: it's very much that same sentiment.
Rym: I think if something unfortunate ever happened to me, that is what I hope I would be capable of doing.
Rym: I hope I can be as good as gear as that blind dude that I see fucking killing it over the moguls When I'm out there at a trail somewhere and you know to be honest, you know my current extremely abled body that I have That pretty much.
Scott: I don't think I have any, you know significant disability time.
Rym: Things start to go downhill in a hurry as I've discovered.
Rym: that's true.
Scott: Even with even with two functioning legs, like I can't ice skate for shit.
Scott: I'd probably be better at sled hockey with one leg Though I will say this I had two legs regular hot.
Rym: I got to play a little sled hockey in the Cub Scouts when I was a kid.
Rym: It is hard as shit.
Scott: It is so hard.
Rym: I Could probably be better at that than regular skating.
Rym: just cuz I've seen you skate.
Rym: full disclosure.
Rym: Like you should see what I look like trying to snowboard.
Rym: I am I am.
Rym: it is.
Rym: it is embarrassing In the moment the GeekNights book club book.
Rym: So refreshing to say this.
Rym: Yeah, it is the city we've been.
Scott: I'm gonna mention what the buck used to be.
Rym: It is the city we became by NK jemisin, uh, we're gonna do the show like within a month.
Rym: We might record it like way in advance of that, but we're gonna do the show in a month.
Rym: So you got about a month to read this thing.
Scott: one listener in our discord told me that they're 20 something percent done with it.
Scott: So, you know people are moving right along.
Rym: It's a fast read.
Rym: It's a good read.
Rym: It's a very GeekNights book.
Rym: It's a very New York book.
Rym: It's got some beats that are gonna drop where you're gonna go.
Rym: Damn That's what room was.
Scott: No, I didn't finish it yet So you didn't get to the beats.
Rym: that I know but you and Emily have repeatedly told me that there are beats without spoiling them and I know they're coming.
Rym: I I'm really excited to plow through this book.
Rym: I don't think it's gonna be a long read.
Scott: I Just imagined the beat again and I got.
Scott: I got the thing.
Scott: I do want to hear from people though who are not new people who are familiar with New York City.
Scott: Maybe you've never been here.
Scott: You've never lived here.
Scott: Maybe you only visited a couple times, right?
Scott: You're not like a New Yorker by any stretch because this book is so New York.
Scott: I want to hear from people who are not so New York and how the New York and this comes across Like.
Scott: do they like?
Scott: do you not understand what's going on?
Rym: There's the things just really curious about that too Cuz like when I before I moved here like today even to like the mid Hudson Valley or RIT Like I knew New York City's a thing But like and I knew like Oh Brooklyn's a thing.
Rym: I guess that's part of New York City and I'd heard of Queens.
Rym: I didn't know Staten Island was part of New York City at the time.
Rym: I literally didn't And I knew the Bronx was the thing but like I didn't know which one was which or where they are Anything about them.
Rym: and even when we when I first moved here, I had that NFT guide and it was like Manhattan Not the bad kind.
Rym: now No, the old the only good NFT was the not for tourists book.
Rym: Which was it was basically imagine a book that does what a cell phone with Google Maps does today just for New York City.
Rym: Yep in Adara before people had smartphones like it was real important book But the whole book was just Manhattan.
Rym: and then it had one very small chapter called the outer boroughs in case you venture there.
Rym: So, uh, yeah otherwise We'll probably have some virtual panels at a thank icon.
Rym: We'll probably have a panel or two at PAX East.
Rym: Maybe just me maybe me and Scott.
Rym: that's all like up in the air.
Rym: Of course, but no, you know numbers are looking good.
Scott: I plan to go to PAX East for probably also Traveling all that way just to do a panel is kind of a pain in the ass.
Rym: Oh, yeah it is but it's weird is I almost miss that cuz?
Rym: I've ever my life outside of GeekNights until kovid was Flying around the world constantly for work shit going to Boston for like one meeting and then taking the Acela home Like that was a life I lived.
Scott: so I mean if it was, you know I guess if it was safe to eat indoors that you probably won't be then like suddenly.
Rym: Oh if it was safe to eat indoors I would go to PAX East like for a day or two like maybe the worthiness of the trip would rise Significantly up because Boston's good restaurant seemed though.
Rym: I have bad news.
Rym: based on a cursory examination of Google Maps The number of restaurants within walking distance of paxis has dropped Precipitously.
Scott: Oh, no, I would suggesting like if I'm going like if let's say this it's perfectly safe, right?
Scott: But I'm only going to paxi.
Rym: And then when we're done we go to the good part of Boston and even those good to go to that Indian place.
Scott: Or we could go to the breakfast the secret breakfast then go to paxi's then go back go to the Indian play park over there For dinner right then get that ice cream from the place Triton cafe if that's still there something like something like that, right?
Scott: Yeah, we could we could make it good But without the indoor dining situation, you know going there because indoor dining is like the less.
Rym: I don't think I'm gonna do that anytime soon Especially because even the places that are good enough vaccine mandates are about to drop them.
Rym: So I'm even less inclined to eat indoors without a mascot any time.
Scott: for the foreseeable future We're still gonna see how it goes.
Rym: Yeah, but It depending on the situation we could take the like.
Rym: we could take the Acela there and back.
Rym: It's a pretty quick trip.
Rym: If you take the Acela, it's a lot of money though for one lousy Yeah, or I'd be willing to drive us there cuz I'll be going anyway.
Rym: That's a lot of time though, but then I don't have to wear a mask during the whole trip.
Rym: I like I guess But the problem is driving to Boston wouldn't be that much cheaper than the Acela because not just holes.
Rym: parking in Boston Is like if you put made a list of things Rym Is unwilling to deal with and is mad about.
Rym: parking in Boston is like weirdly in the top ten on earth not counting things like fascism, so Anyway, if Pax East was only during the summer, oh my god, then it wouldn't matter.
Rym: Yeah, we go to that barbecue place That's outside.
Scott: Well, if it was in the summer, we could arrange it so that we bike to Pax East.
Rym: Whoo, I get a bike home eminently doable Bike home from Pax East and you just keep our bikes in the hotel room Yeah, or even we drive there, but we bring the bikes and we just bike to everyone around lunch.
Rym: We bike to the secret breakfast place.
Scott: Well, they have bike share in Boston true.
Rym: It's kind of like city bike.
Rym: last time I used it It was not that expensive, but that was in like 2014.
Scott: I want to say I also don't know where the fuck I'm going.
Scott: That's the difference.
Scott: the city bike.
Scott: I know where the hell.
Rym: I actually do know I've spent a lot of time in Boston only they I vaguely know.
Scott: I know the general direction.
Rym: I've probably spent literally 10 to 10 X more time in Boston than you have in my life.
Rym: So Anyway, anyway, let's get right into it.
Rym: so Marlboro Hosanna is one of those rare people like in spitting distance of people like Satoshi kong in that Basically bad in a thousand or at least bad in like 990.
Scott: Yeah, he's like.
Scott: he's like in the 900 sites.
Rym: Yeah in that in that he's never made a stinker but of the seven movies he is made one.
Rym: We all pretty good.
Rym: We've reviewed all of them on gig nights.
Scott: We have it.
Rym: Yeah, I think we have girl.
Rym: Oh, I don't think you ever watched the girl who left her time.
Rym: I don't think I saw wolf children What I saw the theater least I saw it in the theater.
Scott: I think I didn't.
Rym: how why did you anyway?
Scott: I've seen all of them.
Scott: I missed that one somehow.
Rym: Well, we should watch it.
Rym: It's okay It's not his best movie, but it's good.
Rym: I liked it a lot.
Scott: But So we never saw.
Scott: I never saw those Digimon ones either though.
Rym: Yeah, those are technically short films, so they don't count.
Rym: Okay, so he is done.
Rym: Oh One of the one-piece movies which happens to be the best one-piece movie.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that was that's the only one I saw And the secret best one I've seen.
Rym: but also that movie is basically the weird one-piece movie.
Rym: It doesn't fit into the rest of them kind of like beautiful dreamer.
Scott: It's one of those ones where it doesn't fit into the continuity because it's like we go to an island We have an adventure then it's over the end, right?
Scott: So but also it's kind of anything.
Rym: It's kind of just slayers the motion picture with different characters way more.
Scott: that is.
Scott: that's what makes it good.
Rym: Yeah way more literally than you might imagine.
Rym: when you watch it You know when the beat drops and that one you'll be like, oh Rym wasn't kidding.
Rym: It is literally the same goddamn movie.
Rym: It's basically yeah the girl who left her time, which I think is the second best film.
Rym: like good God is that movie great summer wars?
Rym: Fantastic film wolf children.
Rym: I think I cried like six or seven times during that movie.
Rym: the boy in the beast.
Rym: super fun Mirai, I want to live in that house more than I want most things on earth.
Rym: And Belle the one that just came out right.
Scott: so it didn't just came out.
Scott: it came out like last year.
Scott: We could have gone to see it right away, but we didn't.
Scott: yeah because kovat It came around again and we didn't see it.
Scott: cuz go.
Rym: but then I could got us.
Scott: I could have seen someone Pirated it from an online film festival that I missed and I could have watched that.
Rym: but I did Emily and I got it.
Rym: But cuz you know Emily has film connection.
Rym: So we got invited to an Oscar Oscar screening with free tickets.
Scott: Well, I well that was just.
Scott: that was just the initial screening.
Scott: Yeah, I could have bought tickets.
Rym: Yeah, but that was it.
Rym: It was like other people could go to it and the covert numbers were worse then.
Scott: But I think what you know, that was just the first screening and I guess you were under the impression It was some special difference.
Rym: Well, cuz we got invited to it sort of separately and there was another function and other stuff around it.
Scott: It was just the first screening.
Scott: that was you know, I said I'm not buying tickets to even though I could have anyway.
Scott: so then luckily the the museum near us just had a screening and one only museum that I have ever And am currently a member of the Museum of the moving image great place Yep, so which is?
Rym: I can just still think back to that Chuck Jones exhibit they had there.
Scott: yeah, so There's you know, they do this from time to time and I guess I can possibly rely on them to do it More often is you know, there's.
Scott: they got nerds right in the place.
Scott: They got video game exhibits and shit, right?
Scott: You know?
Scott: So they've been showing the hot anime movies and like second runs after the.
Rym: the other theaters run them and their theater is small Extremely high quality like Soundproof has basically yeah, it's it's.
Scott: they have this theater and they basically it's.
Scott: it's basically like the a-plus movie theater, right?
Scott: It's like they're constantly upgrading it You know to make sure that it's the best a movie theater can be they gave it got 70.
Scott: They're 70 millimeter projector.
Scott: They got everything they require at least for now still vaccination to get in and it was the strictest Policy I've ever seen.
Rym: I have to wear a mask the whole time and they don't even sell concessions.
Rym: nor are you allowed to bring food in and The capacity is at 50%.
Scott: they won't sell all the seats.
Scott: Yeah, right and they like this place is super paranoid.
Scott: They upgraded all their ventilation systems and like Yeah.
Scott: So it's like okay.
Scott: They're that paranoid and they have all those policies and the numbers are way down Right.
Rym: I think we can go to this movie and it was weird because that's the first time I've been to a movie theater since like two plus years Since like March 2020.
Scott: I don't even remember the last time I went to a movie theater.
Rym: I remember the yeah We finally got to see the frickin movie that we waited so long Or the actual title of the dragon and the freckled princess?
Scott: right, so Obviously we had seen plenty of trailers.
Scott: We knew it was gonna be about music.
Scott: We knew it was gonna be about some sort of VR cyberspace similar to summer wars.
Scott: We knew it was gonna be a Beauty and the Beast deal.
Scott: Did I say that already?
Scott: It's.
Scott: if it's not it's apparent from the title.
Rym: yup, right and what we know from early like people who had seen it before us was everyone kept talking about how beautiful it is and You could clearly see that parts of it are.
Rym: we're sort of 3d CG and parts of it look 2d Mm-hmm, which is part of what the movies about of course.
Scott: yep, so The early reactions were all like tremendously positive But then when it came out in the US I did.
Scott: I saw some positive reactions and I started to see some more Mixed or negative one.
Rym: I can't say most.
Rym: most of the negative reactions I saw were I hate to stereotype this way old people who didn't seem to understand it Like they didn't get what it was talking about.
Scott: Maybe who knows?
Scott: regardless, you know.
Scott: And an original anime movie that isn't you know, it's not an adaptation of Beauty and the Beast despite heavily referencing it.
Scott: So it's like I'm always you know, we always say I'm gonna be excited for that.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So we went we saw it and I think it was pretty good.
Rym: I think it was phenomenal.
Rym: It's not like the best like it's not in my top 10 movies ever But I think it's mom or hosted as third best film far and away.
Scott: It's it's definitely among his movies.
Scott: It is one of the better ones, but I don't think it is good enough to elevate him to like the next level.
Scott: I still put him and Makoto Shinkai sort of like behind.
Rym: I Think this is Bell is materially better than anything Shinkai had except possibly his first work.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I think they're on like the same level but regardless granted your nails anyway, but What's interesting is that one just watch it like if you'd like.
Rym: if you haven't watched it like just go watch it as soon as you right.
Scott: and Because whether we're gonna think about whether this movie is an eight nine ten, you know a minus Yeah, it's a. it's a movie that you should absolutely go see if you have the opportunity to see.
Rym: there is no reason for Anyone any human who has the capacity to see this movie to not see it Like it's just.
Rym: it's a perfectly fine movie and it has a lot to say.
Rym: I took a lot away from it.
Scott: Can I name a movie that came out in 2021?
Scott: That's better than this movie.
Scott: It's like, you know, and I I don't.
Scott: Was it gets doing right better than this?
Rym: Yeah, it was doing better than this is a very Complex and difficult question to answer that.
Rym: maybe this asking me the same.
Scott: I guess I put him on the same quality overall.
Rym: quite say I was similarly excited for different reasons But you know why this is a better movie.
Rym: This is a movie.
Rym: Dune was part one That's true.
Rym: This is a complete movie.
Rym: It ends it says everything it needs to say.
Rym: and I'm gonna be to say something a little more controversial Because I've seen summer wars again more recently than you.
Rym: It kind of is in some ways a better and tighter summer wars.
Rym: that addresses The reality of the internet and the reality of how people use technology far more Realistically than summer wars did.
Rym: well in a bit in a bit We're gonna assume you saw it and we're not gonna like spoil spoil But we have to reveal some things to talk about this movie with any depth.
Scott: Yeah, I Think that the movie was actually an inverse.
Scott: summer wars, right?
Scott: Whereas summer wars, you know the majority of The you know story of summer wars is taking place outside of the cyberspace Real world and cyberspace intrudes into the real world and causes problems.
Scott: and cyberspace is like this small Thing off to the side in summer wars, but the climax of summer wars ends up being in fully in the cyberspace.
Rym: So imagine the early internet where websites and like early social media are really isolated not like you could.
Rym: only there was a time when you could look at how you Interacted on the internet and look at your real life and they were for a very brief period very separated from each other.
Rym: that separation was fictitious and Disappeared as soon as technology spread more and that movie sort of addresses how that happened.
Rym: like suddenly the problems of the internet.
Rym: Nope, they're in the real world.
Rym: Guess what?
Rym: Hospitals are having problems because of internet shit.
Scott: So in Bell you have a complete integration of the cyberspace and the real world.
Scott: Right, people are occupying both spaces at the same time, you know events don't like just happen in one place or the other.
Scott: they happen overall and There you see those events in both places.
Scott: Yep,
Rym: and I go further and say that just
Scott: like the real world
Rym: this movie like the core message of it fundamentally if you just zoom out is that Especially if you look at kids today like people younger than us who live in the world as it is today The internet is just part of the real world is just part of their lives.
Rym: They're inseparable.
Rym: you can't pretend that one is somehow different or special and the prop problems people have in both sides follow each other and Everyone is living a dual life whether they realize it or not.
Rym: and this movie Portrays that in a just profound and direct way.
Rym: And I guess Summer Wars had a lot of kind of fakie technology as part of it like the encryption stuff in the past.
Rym: We're like, it just didn't really map.
Rym: This Bell almost maps one-to-one to the reality of how young people interact with the internet and how it works for them.
Rym: It's just a much more realistic movie despite being set in a future.
Scott: It's like they despite the unrealistic You know put in some things in your ears and you're exactly like it's.
Rym: it's showing.
Rym: It's kind of like how Ghost in the Shell.
Rym: Ghost in the Shell standalone complex to use an anime example.
Rym: It portrays very realistically how information Travels on the internet and the problems that causes in the real world.
Rym: But it shows that to you via cyber bodies and ridiculous nonsense that does not exist in the real world Right.
Scott: So then you so compared to Summer Wars, it's integrated versus separated But then the climax of Bell right.
Scott: whereas the climax of Summer Wars is resolved in cyberspace Climax of Bell is is in the real world is right is what matters and that's why I think this movie is so great And why I'm.
Rym: I think I have a slightly higher opinion than you.
Rym: That's really what I'm focused on the fact that this movie in the end basically says look What's the what's the premise of you?
Rym: the the virtual world the metaverse of this universe?
Rym: Escape yourself start a new life.
Rym: and what's the climax of this movie?
Rym: You are you.
Rym: you cannot escape yourself by going to the internet?
Rym: That's a dream that a company is trying to sell you as a famous song You can't hide from yourself.
Scott: However, you go.
Scott: There you are.
Rym: and But it goes deeper than that like something Like the way the movie portrays this.
Rym: there's a scene where the main Bell's friend her main the main character her friend is Helping her become a vtuber.
Rym: basically like that's what's happening?
Rym: Like you get a sort of montage of it and she's this like gremlin II internet person like guy and her avatar in the you universe is this sort of gremlin II look in ghosts, but there's a scene where she is logged in and like interacting in the metaverse But she's also sitting at her computer turned around looking at the main character talking to her and behind her.
Rym: on the screen her avatar is emoting and doing the thing she's doing in real life and it really like that scene in particular Crystallizes this duality and just portrays it in a really interesting way.
Rym: and you see that type of portrayal throughout the movie Right.
Scott: I mean, I don't disagree with any of that But I think the reason I think the things that brought the movie down For me is as nothing to do with like, you know the message or the plot and in fact the characters in this movie.
Scott: I think it's got amazing characters.
Rym: They're very human characters, right?
Scott: All the characters are like interesting and have personalities and are right and they're funny.
Rym: this kind of movie in anime in particular just generally doesn't tend to have a particular kind of like direct comedy that This movie has a scene in a train station that I was laughing out loud almost uncontrollably Right.
Scott: I think that the parts of this movie.
Scott: I think they just brought it down was that you know in the beginning It's a little bit disjointed right?
Scott: They they clearly took this opening scene Right like the epic, you know sort of you know singing on the whale thing I can see in the trailer as the opening scene of the movie, but chronologically that's not where the movie starts.
Scott: it's like immediately after that they sort of rewind and Go back to say how did we get there?
Scott: And it just be you know at that beginning it just becomes a little Disjointed and I was like for like a couple of minutes.
Scott: I was like wait to seven before after.
Scott: it's like we went back.
Scott: Is this a flashback?
Scott: did we flash forward yet?
Scott: Oh, we're not flashing forward.
Scott: We just rewound after the first scene and then pressed play and then when we got to the first scene we skipped over it.
Rym: I can see that.
Rym: I mean I guess it felt natural to me like I got it immediately like there was zero Confusion or like I didn't even think about that.
Scott: and then I can see where does that?
Scott: where exactly?
Scott: Chronologically does that first scene like insert after the rewind right?
Scott: It's like, you know, it wasn't clear, right?
Scott: So it's like.
Scott: I knew stuff that was then then didn't know it wasn't, you know, anyway, so that was a little bit.
Scott: And then the other thing is that you know, there were a lot of quality Concepts I think and like many messages Inserted throughout the movie like the baseball player guy and or the singing the tumbler-doxing brigade Specifically yeah, the singing grandma's.
Rym: Yeah, well we spoil a little bit the singing grandma's.
Rym: the moment when they reveal a piece of information among themselves Was a very good moment in that movie.
Scott: Oh, it's real good But you can clearly see you know The movie was trying to say a bunch of more things.
Scott: right that were all good things to say that were relevant But it often said them as sort of like.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: it was like sudden and out of nowhere like insertions Right.
Rym: It's like see I didn't really see that though.
Rym: I saw it more as they felt like natural evolutions of how I guess It was almost.
Scott: it was almost jump-cuddy where it's like.
Scott: well who could?
Rym: ah, you said it.
Rym: So this is what I was getting at.
Rym: This is hard to articulate.
Rym: Who could this bad guy be?
Scott: Let's Google search is it this guy this guy this guy?
Scott: But that's load
Rym: really naturally for me like that felt like how the internet is and I and
Scott: suddenly it's like someone's just doing a Google search and then that Google search they just did it's like with like instantly suddenly It's like know that those those things they just searched for.
Scott: that's actually important Right, even though they it was on the screen.
Rym: So here's a theory I have because that Would you disagree?
Rym: and this is good faith?
Rym: Like I'm not trying I'm not making fun of you or trying to make some weird point.
Rym: I have a point about the movie that You and I are too old to be truly in touch with like the zennials below us Like we're we can't a hundred percent know them, but let alone people younger than that I obviously can't hundred percent know them.
Rym: But you know, we we are closer to them and understand them better than say people older than us.
Rym: But we are not a hundred percent in touch with what kids today like.
Scott: No, I mean cuz you know It's like on the one hand I see I see some of the things that they're into And I don't I don't poop on them because I learned my lesson not to poop on the kids But I yeah when I see the things that they like it's like, okay, they must like that sort of thing But I don't like that.
Scott: would you disagree?
Rym: With the statement that I am NOT saying that I am like radically closer in touch to those kids But I am a little closer to the younger generation than you are in terms of sensibilities like a little bit
Scott: I think you do like some internet trash stuff more than I yeah.
Rym: Yeah I'm just saying like I am closer to that.
Scott: I'm not saying that is good or bad I'm simply saying that in that one aspect that you know, you would enjoy You know a homestuck or an undertale and I wouldn't.
Scott: so that's not even.
Scott: that's not even that young right?
Scott: That's old.
Rym: All right Yeah, right Sans undertale is a boomer boomer character.
Rym: Yeah, so, uh, I noticed that people who are the closer someone is to zennial and younger the more Not necessarily positive reception of the movie they had but the less they have the kinds of questions or complaints that you have.
Rym: Because the things you described as being jarring did not register at all to me as jarring.
Scott: that Google You know, I would have cited in general.
Scott: I like a movie that has establishing stuff.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but I would have but I what I would have said.
Scott: they had things that happened and you know mattered that were not given Enough frames of animation to establish them before they met.
Rym: so my theory is that someone with a younger internet sensibility would Not notice that or not see it as jarring or almost expect that I was even gonna cite later.
Rym: Like I had a note that one of the things I wanted to talk about was the Google search part because I was about to say before you jumped in and said a different thing that that scene was one of the best examples of Having the internet act like it really does for people in the real world and how things are.
Rym: like some drama happens in real life.
Rym: suddenly There's a bunch of private net messages and a bunch of Google searches and some doxxing and nonsense.
Rym: that's happening and it's rapid-fire It's resolved and people move on.
Scott: and too bad on the one hand.
Scott: That's correct.
Scott: But on the other hand, it's like, you know, if there's some if there's some sort of thing like that and it's like, alright Let's go to the reddit thread and it's like, okay.
Scott: Here's people are suspecting You know, it's a B or C. It's like.
Scott: that's just all a bunch of bullshit.
Scott: I'm not gonna take it, right?
Rym: it's like that would be real internet when it's like Like they dare like the internet Docsis and narrows down.
Rym: one of the mystery is to like this set of people and then one by one you see like the dot the mob of internet bullshit reached back into the real world and then suddenly a Baseball player has to like issue a statement and like all these echoes happen.
Rym: All I'm saying is that the way those scenes were put together I think that's part of it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But I'm saying the way those scenes were put together like your complaint about them the jarring nature The lack of frames paid attention to them like how it just moves on the quick rapid cuts.
Rym: I think that is just the sensibility of a younger internet generation that I Am a little too old to be close to and you are for various reasons further from.
Rym: so it bothers you more than it bothers Me.
Rym: hence, I did not even notice the complaints you raised until you raised them in this podcast just now.
Scott: Well, I think you know, it's not really I don't think has to do with sensibility.
Scott: I think this is you with.
Scott: you know, cinematography Oh, but I think that style of I don't know if that's.
Scott: I don't even know if that's actually the sensibility of younger people.
Scott: Or you know, is it just he wanted to cram a lot of things into the movie and he didn't have time for all that?
Scott: So he's rather than cut things he squeezed him, but I felt like the way it was squeezed.
Rym: It doesn't.
Rym: I guess my opinion is the way it was squeezed made it punch more and work better in the film and tell the Film story better.
Rym: and you disagree.
Scott: I'm not going to assume that because the you know The creators decision.
Scott: is it because the creator knows the audience so well, right?
Rym: Oh, yeah I know I am still going from.
Rym: the author is dead Until I get a chance to maybe like ask him a question.
Rym: So because I did get to ask the Toshi kana question once and he was very much like nope That was not our intention.
Rym: In fact, we didn't even know how that show was gonna end while we were making it.
Rym: We had described how things go.
Rym: we had to scramble to make those last two episodes.
Rym: We literally didn't know how paranoia agent was gonna end until we started production of the penultimate episode.
Scott: Yeah Alright, so let's talk about some other things.
Scott: So first of all music movie.
Rym: Obviously, I was listening soundtrack on loop.
Scott: It heavily focused on music because the main character like this is about.
Rym: this is not a spoiler.
Rym: She's a vtuber.
Scott: straight up easy Macross plus a girl becomes a vtuber and that's a big Right, so they released the soundtrack before the movie, you know, they focused on the song and the trailer, right?
Scott: You know when we're talking about the Beauty and the Beast aspect, we're talking Disney Beauty and the Beast.
Rym: It's a musical To the level of there is singing.
Rym: there is deep homage To the point that there is a scene where the beauty and the Beast dance together and it is just roses.
Scott: There's a room full of roses as opposed to the single rose.
Scott: it like it is not just alluding to the original Beauty and the Beast.
Scott: You know fairy tale.
Rym: it is referencing the Disney point that it has a Rotating CG scene of a dance that is identical to the one in the Disney one Which if you were.
Rym: if you don't remember when the Disney Beauty and the Beast came out there were Documentaries talking about how they made that one scene, right?
Scott: So they also instead of a bunch of talking China They had a bunch of those a eyes little group of a eyes.
Scott: They were so cute.
Rym: Yeah, I love the little see.
Rym: an enemy like the Beast lives in a castle all alone.
Scott: He's a sad dude, right?
Scott: So but while all those like incidental things and homages to Beauty and the Beast are there The overall story is not a story is not the story of Beauty and the Beast.
Scott: No, right It's like they just took those elements the well scenes and references and setting character.
Scott: But the story of Beauty and the Beast like doesn't align with this one that much.
Rym: Well, I would argue it aligns more than you're letting on but I can't.
Scott: a Gaston named Justin?
Rym: Well Gaston is literally just like the the mod of a tumblr or a subreddit that's full of angry Doxing furries.
Scott: There is an angry mob who wants to.
Scott: you know, it was against the Beast right just like original.
Rym: But why are they against the Beast?
Rym: because the Beast is a troll who does go around wrecking havoc And I can't say more without spoiling major emotional a slot.
Scott: I mean I can spoil original Beauty and the Beast right and a Beauty and the Beast.
Scott: the Beast kidnaps Belle's dad, right?
Rym: But I guess that without.
Rym: When you watch this movie think about how the Beast acted in the universe.
Rym: Why Belle and the Beast interacted at all?
Rym: Why Belle was able to reach the Beast in the end?
Rym: and then what the actual?
Rym: Climax of the movie is on that rainy street.
Rym: All of that together is very close to some of the fundamental themes of Beauty and the Beast even Disney's Beauty and the Beast Even though the literal plot points of that movie diverge wildly.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I'm saying.
Rym: The plot is not the same but all these other things You know are in and I would say the way what the Beast represents and what it is in terms of the actual story once you see what the whole story was is Fantastic and extremely well done.
Rym: and a similar story was told in Hypno space outlaw Kind of literally
Scott: and
Rym: it's it's an important story because a big theme of this movie is there are people who act online a certain way differently from how they act in the real world because of trauma or issue in the real world.
Rym: and this movie it Won.
Rym: one hand it shows the worst parts of the internet because what are the worst parts of the internet right now?
Rym: doxing brigades Bullshit mobbing online her lighting.
Rym: Yep swatting real been.
Rym: but what are the good things about the internet?
Rym: These are two human beings who pre-internet could never have met and no one could have Helped the person who is the Beast.
Rym: they're just cut off from the world and alone but the internet allowed them to find someone they could trust and talk to.
Rym: a Connection that was positive was made that could not have been made pre-internet Mm-hmm.
Scott: It shows you the you know, good.
Rym: Well, it's showing you more than those other movies and the Beast of Social media and the internet.
Rym: the modern internet brings great three things and terrible things and we have to take them all.
Scott: It is true that you know, there's not a lot of other movies at least not ones that I've seen.
Scott: You know most of the times when you get a cyberspace, it's like, you know some far-future unrealistic cyberspace Right or you know some ancient archaic idea that doesn't match reality.
Scott: It's like this is you know, the?
Scott: the VR part of it is not, you know real but everything else about it matters.
Rym: Perhaps the contemporary internet like right now Even though you're seeing our physical faces if you're watching a live stream the Rym and Scott you know from this is not Actually the Rym and Scott in real life though.
Rym: They are similar.
Rym: They are not the same.
Scott: All right, so I do want to talk about the one scene in the movie the best possible scene.
Scott: Should we say spoiler line in and the train?
Rym: Oh the train station I was.
Rym: I did not expect a scene like that to happen and Much like the elevator scene in Evangelion.
Rym: There is a power in having a silent Unmoving frame persists on a screen in an animated saves.
Scott: it also saves money.
Rym: But it was just long.
Rym: and like we're sitting in the theater and as that scene unfolds bit by bit people in the audience start laughing and it just kept growing and growing and growing to the point that the entire crowd was just like Defying at a relatively straightforward joke that was just executed very well.
Scott: in some ways it does feel like it could have been one of those movies where someone thought up a bunch of amazing scenes and then found a Way to stick them together.
Scott: and if that is the case, this is one of those scenes that they thought of in advance.
Scott: They want to stick that in.
Rym: well Cuz there's that there's a sub theme with that kid in particular around.
Rym: it's the same message as master Keaton and some other things We've talked about in that you can do something for fun.
Rym: You do not have to be the best at it to do it at all.
Rym: and the sharing of hobbies and like why do you?
Rym: Why do you sing?
Rym: Why do you do anything?
Rym: is a big part of this movie too?
Rym: Look at the of the vtuber who got completely eclipsed by Belle and her revelation at the end.
Rym: She's just a person like me.
Rym: like that kind of story I don't have to be the best to do a thing at all.
Rym: and that character was part of that story Their virtual idols.
Scott: Yeah, it's not quite the same thing.
Rym: Uh There I think they're very close to being the same thing because What we're not at Belle does not have an AI.
Rym: that is continuing to be Belle when Belle's not online.
Scott: I Guess yeah, it's not the same as Hatsune Miku, right?
Rym: Yeah Where there is no one would be it's more Matt cross plus where there is a person who is Sharon Apple Which is why I'm saying it's more vtuber because that's what vtubers are.
Scott: they make a persona that but a vtuber isn't necessarily like Making and performing music, right?
Scott: It's just well They're making it performing and you're lying on self with a different, you know, you know graphic right avatar instead of your own face, but a Virtual Idol is like specifically Singing dancing.
Scott: Yeah performing.
Rym: Well vtuber is a superset of virtual idol maybe.
Scott: Anyway, uh So the scene of the scene of the train station spoilers, I guess.
Rym: Yeah, it just it was.
Rym: it was really so Movie just stop listening cuz we're gonna.
Rym: we're gonna spoil a few things, but we won't go crazy on spoilers, obviously Right.
Scott: So the scene in the train station.
Scott: So some of the parts of the scene I saw coming way in advance like the fact that the really popular girl was actually nice And not a jerk.
Rym: Yeah, the Clearly the the two awkward characters who are actually popular Don't realize that the person who they think is the popular one is just as awkward as them.
Rym: like that.
Rym: That's a trope that I enjoy in general Right.
Scott: Also, you know, you could get a hint actually from the excellent animation.
Scott: the popular girl in the opening scene Right is like oh, she's so pretty and popular and talented but she's doing a funky dance with a saxophone and Like and the way that dance is animated is just so fun to look at right I could tell and I was like wait That's the popular girl that they're all, you know, we have to try
Rym: to try hard band nerd.
Scott: Okay I'm like, I'm like.
Scott: she's definitely a weirdo, right?
Scott: She's not like why?
Scott: She's not like mean girls, you know ultra popular princess, you know, clearly, right?
Scott: You could tell right away.
Scott: and then in that same scene they introduced her.
Scott: they introduced weird canoe guy Right and you could just tell immediately like, you know, yep, you know canoe guy and the saxophone girl.
Scott: that's gonna happen Cuz it's you know, it's one of those things where it's like everyone thinks.
Scott: the two popular kids wanna you know The hot dude, you know wants to get with the popular girl.
Scott: But no, they both want it's a double up right as they both want to do with the the less popular You know weirdo people anyway, but so in this train station scene that all comes to a head, right?
Scott: And you know the it's.
Scott: it's great because in some animes and mangas Especially older ones you get that sort of.
Scott: never ask her out deal.
Scott: Yeah, where there's so, you know teenagers who are shy and timid and miyaka Tomahome right it never happens.
Scott: Did you get that reference?
Rym: at least as old as I am right?
Scott: or the more popular thing I guess these days is you get like those ones where just get together right at the beginning, right?
Scott: And you get this relationship that goes for the show, right?
Scott: Here, I think they struck this really great balance where you had the you know, the teenage You know hesitance and shyness Right present But they still got together right and not just at the last possible second.
Scott: And they got together in a way that is hilarious right, they managed to work in the comedy to you know, sort of ease off on the Sort of like ooh Kind of feelings right already, you know to make it to make it work.
Scott: So but yeah, it's just like suddenly like the movie which is you know slows down at that point like a whole lot like to stillness like Rym said To give you this very real world real feelings kind of see Right that you know, I wouldn't be surprised if that scene was like, um, you know couple minutes long.
Rym: Oh, yeah It was.
Rym: it was much like not much.
Rym: not much happens like the Evangelion elevator scene like no, we're gonna make you sit here It's just gonna just gonna keep going and every time you think okay, that was long enough.
Rym: It just keeps going.
Rym: Yeah, so the scene for me and a minor spoiler when the old people you know cuz you know the girl Bell like she's a vtuber and she's keeping her identity secret like only her friend knows.
Rym: but kids all know the well.
Rym: kids all think the adults don't know what's up and when all the old people are like Like oh, yeah She must be having some drama with the vtuber stuff Like we should go help her like the adults knew the entire time.
Rym: just like in real life Adults are way more savvy than kids know and I think this movie the fact that it called that out So directly at the right moment in the movie was just great.
Scott: I think also.
Scott: you have to realize though that this is set not in a you know in some Near-ish future, right?
Scott: So if if this is what if this is what 2050?
Scott: I don't know what year it is, right?
Scott: But you know those old people are basically are us or mate younger than us?
Rym: Well, imagine us if we had kids.
Rym: our kids couldn't hide shit from us that they were doing online.
Scott: I would know every point is that those old people are people who grew up in some kind of Internet.
Scott: They weren't like our parents who grew up in y'all 20th century almost entirely.
Rym: Yeah, we were the.
Rym: we were literally the last generation that had an analog childhood everyone after us digital from day one
Scott: But the movie sort of you know, you takes the fact that it knows you're watching the movie in 2021 Right, even though it takes place in the future and therefore it can sort of pull aha and remind you that yeah There's.
Scott: oh, you know, even though we've only showed you mostly younger people using this internet No, the whole society is really using it.
Scott: Yeah this service, right?
Scott: It doesn't get that many users if it's all kids.
Rym: Yeah and I mean, yeah, just movies great.
Rym: We've talked for a while and I'm hungry.
Scott: So I'm way hungry.
Scott: I got to order a food Yeah, then we went long.
Rym: So they go wrap it up there because what else could we say?
Rym: go watch and see this movie as soon as you safely and Easily can it.
Rym: it's a it's an original anime movie by a great director and it's great.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi McNichol Ellen Joyce link it you'd read Lily Tenebrae and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names Chris hadad Chris Reimer Clinton Walton Dex Finn kashaya 85.
Rym: Rebecca Dunn.
Rym: review mad will 34 cowards Sam Erickson Sherman Von Hall Taylor Brown.
Rym: the next station is Summerhill Summerhill station and a number of names that I'm not going to read at this time per the request of the people who have Donated money to GeekNights.
Rym: So now I simply leave you with Leila my says wait.