Rym: It's Monday, November 21st, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we're talking about Federation and federated architecture, and not the Star Trek kind.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, a little parable that is relevant to the conversation Scott and I had right before the show.
Rym: That's my opening bit today.
Rym: It's short, but there's an old parable that's called various names, but it's roughly the man and the hunting dog.
Rym: So, a man says he's gonna go hunt, and the hunting dog is like, "Okay, uh, Master, I'm your hunting dog, I'm ready to hunt.
Rym: I'm gonna go hang out by the door, and we'll go as soon as you're
Rym: ready.".
Rym: And then the man goes and cooks some breakfast, and the hunting dog is waiting.
Rym: And then the man goes and looks for his shoes, and the hunting dog is waiting, and now the hunting dog is bored.
Rym: And the man forgets that he didn't make his gunpowder, didn't put his shot in his gun.
Rym: So the hunting dog gets bored, and the hunting dog wanders off to have a drink of water.
Rym: In the moment the hunting dog is gone, the man comes to the front door and starts angrily shouting, "Where is my hunting dog?
Rym: Why is he always late for
Rym: everything?".
Rym: And that is what happened right before we did the show, but more importantly, it got really cold really quick in New York.
Rym: There was no falling.
Scott: We had to turn the heat on.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It went from like, "I'm still comfortable in shorts and a t-shirt, and like, I'm running outside," to, "I had to wear my ski base layers running that half-marathon race over the
Rym: weekend.".
Scott: It's cold.
Scott: Yep, we turned the heaters on.
Scott: This year, though, however, taking a much more disciplined approach to reduce heating costs.
Rym: That's not an option for us.
Rym: Even if we set the heaters at the lowest possible setting, it gets warm in the apartment.
Rym: In fact, if we turn the heaters off, all the ambient heat in the room actually keeps the apartment scarily warm.
Scott: No, what I'm saying is, like, you know, the heaters, right, it's like, we got three of them.
Scott: So it's like, at night, turn two of them off that we're not using.
Scott: That kind of situation, right?
Scott: It's like, don't turn the bedroom one on during the day, just close that door, make that a cold room, and then just, you know, turn it on when it's time to go to bed.
Rym: So the one in the computer room basically never turns on anyway because of all the equipment in here.
Rym: And the bunny room, we can't, like, get cold because the bunny's in there.
Rym: We don't have as many options.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But yeah, the internet says that to be the most energy efficient, I guess, you know, obviously the most energy efficient would be to freeze.
Scott: But, you know, it says that you should keep your heaters at your thermostat during the day when people are actually using the rooms at 68.
Scott: And then, at night, you should lower it to 60 because you're under a bunch of blankets, right?
Scott: And that every degree that you go up from that, not only are you spending a lot of energy, right, but you are costing yourself 3% more money per degree.
Scott: So if you set it at the very nice 60...
Rym: Well, with a lot of caveats, like, in an apartment building where you don't pay for heat and it's just a boiler that's running whether you use it or not.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Scott: Obviously, we're talking about where you control the heat in your living space by a degree.
Rym: Yeah, like, mostly if you have a house.
Scott: Right, you know.
Scott: But yeah, like, if you can set it, then it's like, think about it.
Scott: If you're setting it to 70, it's like, what's 3% times 0.3 again, right?
Scott: Another compounded another 3% on top of that.
Scott: It's like, that's your heating bill right there.
Scott: It's like, you know, I've always complained, you know, there are people who are real misers who, like, you know, always, everyone's cold.
Scott: It's like, it shouldn't be cold, right?
Scott: But, you know, it's like, I'm wearing a hoodie inside, right?
Scott: It's like, it's fine, you know.
Rym: Honestly, though, our apartment gets so warm, even if the heat's not off in the winter, just, you know, nature in New York City and, like, this particular apartment.
Rym: I'm often wearing, like, shorts and nothing and it's still warm and even sometimes I just have to open the windows in the winter.
Scott: You know, there's a lot of factors that go into it, but, you know.
Rym: Or RIT, where we had to keep the windows open so it didn't get dank.
Scott: Right, so, you know, saying for the sake of your wallet and also the climate change, right, don't just suddenly crank up the heat because it's cold.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So, in the news, you might have seen this.
Rym: The FCC has a new, more accurate broadband map of where there is broadband, how much of it in America.
Rym: And you can zoom in to pretty shockingly specific detail now in a way that you couldn't before.
Scott: Yup, so the reason that the FCC collects this data and produces this map is that they can, you know, they've got a lot of, there's a lot of reasons, right?
Scott: So, first is that, you know, people, you know, people who live in the United States can see what internet is available where, right?
Scott: Just a consumer public good information, right?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Businesses would also be looking at that, right?
Scott: But also the FCC is regulating these broadband providers.
Scott: So, when they make certain promises like, ah, we'll provide, we'll increase, you know, broadband coverage in rural areas or we'll promise these speeds in these places.
Scott: It's like, well, let's see what you actually delivered, right?
Scott: You came to us and said you did it.
Scott: Let's see what you actually did and let's look at the, you know, the reports, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, it's taken a long time to update the map.
Scott: The previous map was very old, out of date, inaccurate.
Rym: And it was not granular enough.
Rym: It was on the level of a census block, which is really big.
Scott: The new map, you can look at like, you know, a single address and it'll tell you like which providers are there at the address, how fast their services and how much they charge for it.
Scott: And it's like pretty much the whole country is covered.
Scott: So, this is going to be really useful for, you know, it's going to do a lot to put pressure on the internet service providers, right?
Scott: People can look at, you know, all sorts of shenanigans can now be uncovered, right?
Scott: Journalists can look and see if like there's price gouging going on in certain areas, right?
Scott: Towns who are, you know, doing, you know, zoning and all that kind of stuff can be like, hey, you know, Verizon, you want to wire up our town?
Scott: Well, look at here, it says you're not doing it, right?
Scott: All kinds of stuff like that is going to go down and this should result in improved, you know, broadband coverage for, you know, anyone who wants it.
Scott: The question is, you know, it's like there are still people who want it, plenty of them, but I think the number of people that want broadband is actually going down.
Rym: I've definitely seen that.
Rym: A lot of people I know professionally, like not our close friends in nerd circles, they don't have any wired internet of any kind.
Rym: They just use the cellular networks or WiMAX or like something like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I feel like some people, you know, a lot of people just get a Wi-Fi in their house and that's it, right?
Scott: You know, maybe, but that counts as broadband, but a lot of people aren't doing that.
Scott: They're just phones and tablets are connected to, you know, cell towers if they're in the area.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they don't have Wi-Fi in their house even, some people.
Rym: People have 5G hotspots and that is literally their broadband.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Some people.
Scott: It's like, yeah, if you live in an area that has wireless coverage, you know, and you don't have computers, you just have a tablet and or phone.
Scott: It's like, okay.
Rym: This is going to be, I think in the long term, this is going to be an interesting new digital divide.
Scott: Of course, the rural areas that don't have broadband don't have wireless either.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: They just got nothing.
Rym: But this will really help people who say want to move where, you know, you look at a house or you look at an apartment somewhere and pretty much anyone involved in that transaction is going to lie to you about your internet options because they just want you to buy the house.
Rym: You really need to be able to see.
Scott: You could look and see like, hey, wait a minute, there's a house that's like, you know, the apartment building next door has files.
Scott: How come this one doesn't?
Scott: Ravel, ravel, ravel.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know.
Rym: So this is going to.
Rym: this is actually still a pretty big deal.
Rym: And this is coming partly because the U.S.
Rym: government and the FCC has actually done a pretty good job at regulating like Internet access compared to other countries.
Rym: Look at what Internet's like in Canada, like Canada's got a lot of advantages over the
Rym: U.S.,
Rym: but Internet access in Canada is the worst.
Scott: It's bad.
Rym: It's like it is worse than most other countries.
Rym: Honestly, it is terrible.
Rym: Every Canadian I know, they have like metered bandwidth with really, really low limits and they're paying like double what we pay.
Rym: So in some other news, this is a huge deal.
Rym: You might remember a while ago there was big talk of a rail union strike, as in choo choo trains in the U.S We're talking about freight trains mostly.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So not so much the passenger trains in the U.S.
Rym: That strike was averted because a number of the large unions had voted to ratify a labor deal that had been reached with the U.S.
Rym: federal government.
Rym: These workers are kind of special in that they can't just strike.
Rym: There's consequences and nonsense that I don't want to get into because there's a broader picture I want to talk about here.
Rym: But think about like air traffic controllers now, like they're not allowed to strike.
Rym: There's all sorts of weird situations.
Rym: But these unions, they were going to strike.
Rym: The deal happened with some of the unions.
Rym: Now, and this is news from basically today, late last night this started to break.
Rym: A bunch of the unions who hadn't signed the deal have now said, no, we won't do it.
Rym: In fact, we're still going to strike.
Rym: The strike will start on December 9th if a deal isn't reached, apparently.
Rym: And all the unions who signed the deal basically said, yeah, if any union strikes, we all strike because these working conditions are intolerable.
Rym: And of course, union solidarity.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if you don't know what the deal is, just to briefly and perhaps inaccurately summarize the situation.
Rym: It's so much worse than you think it is out there.
Scott: There are freight trains in the
Scott: U.S.,
Scott: even though there's, you know, you think that we wouldn't.
Scott: The trains in the U.S.
Scott: have really declined over the past century or two.
Scott: But freight trains still carry a lot of goods from here to there in the United States.
Scott: Amazon Prime packages.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's a freight train that's going to bring them from some port to the middle of the fucking country.
Rym: One estimate is that the freight rail network in America constitutes two to three billion dollars worth of economic activity generation per day.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So a lot of stuff is on freight trains.
Scott: Now, the problem is that not enough people are in the profession of engineering a freight train.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like we need a certain number of cars, train cars of goods to move a certain distance per day for everything to get where it's going on time, especially perishable things.
Scott: You know, but also nonperishable things.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that means you need a certain number of train engines that can pull those cars operating and moving a certain number of hours at a certain speed per day.
Scott: Which means you need engineers.
Scott: They don't drive themselves.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So there has to be a certain number of engineers working at any given moment.
Scott: Piloting driving trains all the time, 24/7.
Scott: And if the number of engineers that are driving trains goes too low, shit starts not showing up on time, et cetera, et cetera.
Scott: So what's happened is there aren't enough people in that profession who have the training, who have the skill, who are willing to do the job, who haven't quit or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Who are alive and able to do the job and legally allowed to do the job, et cetera.
Scott: Who can do it safely and properly.
Scott: So many things have been done to sort of get around that labor shortage.
Scott: Number one, they're overworking those people.
Scott: Obviously, that's the first go to move of the capitalist overwork the labor.
Scott: Number two, they are making them drive longer trains.
Scott: It's like, well, if I can't drive two normal size trains, I'll have one guy pull an unsafely long train.
Scott: It's like three miles long.
Scott: The person doesn't even know what's going on at the back of the train.
Scott: They'd have to walk three miles to see what's going on back there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's unsafe and dangerous and, you know, all these sorts.
Scott: We won't let them have sick days.
Rym: That's pretty much the big thing.
Rym: They are not even asking for more money.
Rym: These workers, despite generating what, two billion dollars of economic activity a day, they are not asking for more money.
Rym: All they're asking for is the ability to take sick days off and have a few vacation days like they're not.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I'm sure if there were enough train engineers, right, to get all the boxes, you know, the train cars to where they're going on time, that even the evil capitalists who run the train companies would be like, OK, all right.
Scott: The reason they're not letting them have sick days and overworking them is because there aren't enough of them.
Scott: If they let them have the sick days, then they probably won't be able to get all the boxes where they need to go.
Rym: But the union has made a very strong case that the reason they can't hire anyone is because no matter what the pay is, the pay is actually pretty good.
Rym: In a lot of cases, the working conditions are so intolerable that no rational person would take this job unless they're forced to.
Rym: This is like this destroys your life.
Rym: You literally cannot take days off.
Rym: You're on call.
Rym: You're working long shifts.
Rym: If you get sick, you have to come to work or you are punished or fired.
Scott: So what do you do, though?
Scott: It's like if you make the working conditions right, you sort of get when that when the labor shortage gets to a certain point, you get into this difficult situation where it's like, well, if you don't overwork the people you have, you fall below the threshold and you're in big trouble.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you have to overwork the people you have.
Scott: But overworking the people you have makes it impossible to attract new people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then you can't escape the pit that you're in.
Scott: And I'm seeing this happen not just in trains.
Scott: I'm seeing a lot of people I know in a lot of different professions and fields.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In similar situations where there is understaffing.
Scott: Because there isn't enough supply of people who can and will do that job.
Scott: You know, we saw the story where there was a hospital and the emergency room was like way out of control in terms of patients versus staff.
Scott: And they called not that's the nurses called 911.
Scott: The fire department who has EMTs could at least do something to help staff them up a little bit temporarily, which as that's good.
Scott: We could talk about that situation.
Rym: So many of these teachers, they get paid so little that like a lot of people would be really good at being teachers.
Rym: We wouldn't have a shortage of people who could be good teachers, but we don't pay teachers any money and we make them work in an extremely dangerous environment.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So it's like, you know, even if we increase the pay.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And improve the conditions, it's like that might solve some of these cases of labor shortage.
Scott: But as a whole, it's like, are there enough people who are ready, willing and able to do necessary work in, you know, distributed geographically in all the places where we need the work to be done?
Scott: And the answer may in some cases be like, no, it's like, no matter what we do, there just aren't enough people to provide service to the rest of the people in our society.
Scott: And the consequence of that, I think, is that, you know, obviously economic decline.
Scott: But the reality that you'll face as a normal person is that the level of service will decline.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like you won't, you know, stores that will have less hours or goods that you used to be able to get easily.
Scott: You can't get those goods anymore because they're not shipping them to, you know, to your area.
Scott: You'll have to suffer with whatever goods are, you know, made closer.
Scott: I guess, you know, it's like this, you know, the emergency room, they, you know, it's like it might be further away to go to the emergency room.
Rym: Now, it's probably for most sectors.
Rym: Medicine is a complicated one where there's a lot more going on.
Rym: But in a lot of sectors, there is almost definitely enough of a workforce to do this work for a reasonable wage and reasonable working conditions.
Rym: But one, we would need as a society to pay for training.
Rym: And when I say training, I mean like people have to be able to, without already having a job to support themselves, go somewhere or do something to learn these skills and learn these crafts.
Rym: We need to pay people to do that.
Rym: Like not everyone can afford to go to college and not have a job for a while or work a job and take care of family and go to college.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's so backwards, right?
Scott: It's like we as a society, we need more doctors, right?
Scott: Or we need more trained engineers.
Scott: And then we say, and someone says, I'll do it.
Scott: I will be, I'll work and I will serve, I will serve the public good.
Scott: I'm a, you know, giving generous person.
Scott: I will dedicate my life to making everyone else's life better by becoming a doctor or train engineer or whatever it is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then they'll say, okay, if you want to learn that skill, come take the training class.
Scott: It costs this much money.
Scott: But wait, what?
Scott: You said you needed people to do the job.
Scott: Why do I have to pay you to learn to do the job?
Scott: You are the one who needs.
Rym: It's that dog comic.
Rym: No take, only throw.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: It's like, what?
Rym: But it gets even worse because we also, let's assume we solve that problem.
Rym: Like the labor supply is not the problem.
Scott: We could be in a situation where even if we solve that, right, there's a timing issue where it's like, okay, we'll train you.
Scott: We'll pay for you to learn how to drive a train.
Scott: It will take five years training.
Scott: It's like, we don't have five years.
Scott: That's too late.
Scott: And we, but if we let you do it any sooner, you won't be trained enough and you'll fuck up and derail a train.
Scott: So what are we going to do?
Rym: But it gets even worse because even if we solve that problem, a broader fundamental problem, and again, it comes back to capitalism and our society, is that the rail trains are a public good.
Rym: Just like mass transit is a public good.
Rym: They cause economic activity to happen.
Rym: They make the world work.
Rym: They make lives better.
Rym: And yet as a society, we demand that these things generate a profit for someone instead of paying for them and investing in them so that the output is not profit, but the thing existing in the first place.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like the, even if the train company itself comes at a loss, right?
Scott: It's like, yes, but all the businesses that use the train, right?
Scott: If the train moves faster and nicer and better, right?
Scott: The profits of all those companies will increase and sort of collectively cancel out the loss on the train.
Rym: Case in point, the internet.
Rym: The internet was built by the government and then given to the private sector to do whatever the fuck they wanted with.
Rym: And now what percentage of our entire global economy just runs on this internet that the government built for us?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's like, and the thing is we have other parts of, you know, our society that we don't, you know, demand profit from like roads, right?
Scott: This is why we have a car problem, which we demand.
Rym: We demand profit from like a subway that would get cars off the street, but we subsidize the roads that are causing a scarily high percentage of society's problems.
Scott: With free parking for everybody.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So the last thing that you should internalize is, I did pull up the stat, 40% of all long distance trade in America runs on these trains.
Scott: If there is a strike, 40% of the shit that's on the shelf in your stores would just be gone.
Rym: This strike idling 7,000 trains would trigger immediate long-term retail product shortages and widespread manufacturing shutdowns.
Rym: But now no one who does that job deserves to take a day off if they have COVID.
Rym: So you wonder why I'm a communist.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So what if I told you that Maxis not only intended to release, but had a demo-able version of SimCopter that would run on the N64?
Scott: Right, now I remember SimCopter, I remember seeing it in the game store on the shelf, and I remember hearing that like, yeah, you could fly a helicopter around your SimCity 2000 cities, and I was like, oh, that's cool.
Scott: But like, it didn't seem like, like even at that time, when it was brand new, it didn't appeal to me as something that was worth spending money on.
Scott: Like I imagined myself flying around my city and looking at it and being like, that's cool.
Scott: And then playing a little game that it's like, I guess it's a game like you can rescue people with the helicopter or something.
Rym: Yeah, and like break up traffic jams and like, if the SimCity has a fire, go fight the fire, that kind of stuff.
Scott: Sure, but it's like, I'd rather just play, I don't know, fucking...
Rym: I mean, 1990, mid to later 90s, I'd be playing, what, TIE Fighter, X-Wing, Quake, like I had played 8 games today.
Scott: Yeah, right?
Scott: Sif 2.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, MechWarrior 2, it's like, in 1997, this was not a hot game.
Scott: But I didn't realize until Rym just said so, this game, I thought it was a PC only game.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't realize until I saw this article on the Video Game History Foundation, which I'm just going to read the tagline.
Rym: In 1997, Maxis revealed a new version of SimCopter for the N64.
Rym: Two years later, it disappeared.
Rym: We found out why.
Rym: And what follows is a shockingly detailed, extremely well researched, long and fascinating article.
Rym: This is a wild ride that is worth reading all the way to the end.
Rym: Good lord, is this fascinating.
Rym: This is the kind of primary journalism and historic, basically like video game archaeology that the world needs.
Rym: My hat is off to you.
Rym: This article is fantastic.
Rym: And at the bottom, tons and tons and tons of sources, including interviews with Shigeru Miyamoto about this.
Scott: So, in a, also video game preservation story...
Rym: Ooh, an unintended theme!
Scott: Perhaps a less positive one, but not entirely negative, right?
Scott: There was, you know, a game called Ridge Racer.
Rym: Ridge Racer!
Scott: Which, you know, but people, we joke about the Ridge Racer guy, right, hyping up whatever, I think it was a PSP Ridge Racer, I think.
Scott: I forget what it was.
Rym: But Ridge Racer won.
Rym: There weren't really games like that before Ridge Racer won.
Scott: The original, this article will tell you the history of Ridge Racer, but it was originally, you know, a sort of top of the line driving sim for the day.
Scott: And that technology went on to be used in the original Ridge Racer, which had versions of which had like three monitors, right?
Scott: Three CRTs.
Scott: And was like, you know, pretty high quality deal.
Scott: Ridge Racer was a big deal.
Scott: And apparently, I didn't know, there was a game called Ridge Racer Full Scale, which was basically Ridge Racer, but you sat in a full size car, well full size in quotes because it was a Mazda MX-5, which is like the tiniest car.
Scott: But it was still a car, right?
Scott: Obviously, it was just like the body in the seats with the engine, I don't think.
Rym: If I still didn't think that cars were a literal existential threat to humanity, an MX-5 is actually the kind of car I'd probably have.
Scott: The point is, is that they put this car, right, and they wired up the pedals and the wheel and the buttons in the car to an arcade machine.
Scott: Some arcade boards, I think like three or four boards, right, for the arcade machine.
Scott: And then for monitors, they had three giant CRT projectors, right, that were just taking up your full field of view.
Scott: So it was like you're playing Ridge Racer, but like in a full size car, which is why it was called Ridge Racer Full Scale.
Scott: And to set one of these up was a lot of money and not many of them were set up in the world.
Rym: I mean, in the space of this thing, you could put like 12 crane games.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So the question is, is like, hey, are there any of these left?
Scott: And there was one left in the UK and it was in some sort of one of those arcades.
Scott: that's like in a warehouse somewhere.
Scott: But if you read the article, basically I'll summarize it so you don't have to read it if you don't want to.
Scott: Is that somebody went there and played it and it wasn't in great shape, but they got it barely working and they broke a bunch of records on it.
Scott: Like the best Ridge Racer racer went there to go and set all these records and record them and, you know, get speed runs or whatever.
Rym: Talk about a world record.
Rym: no one's going to beat on real hardware ever again.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: And then, you know, it fell into more disrepair and someone got it out of the warehouse.
Scott: But then it was like, oh no, there were like photos of it, like out, like outside in pieces, rotting, not doing great.
Scott: Whoever had it wasn't taking good care of it.
Scott: You know, everyone was worried, something, something.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then more recently, I don't know exactly when this article is from, but I guess more recently than that, somebody was like, hey, I bought this house and all this stuff was left over and they suspect it may have been the original, the person who had it sort of getting their shit together and tried to not
Rym: act like they were the person.
Rym: The comments on this article are from yesterday and today, so I think this article is very new.
Scott: They're trying to act like they weren't the person who let it rot outside.
Scott: They were a person who bought a house and discovered it, right?
Scott: So they don't know.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: The point is there were, they had some of the game, you know, ripped from the roms, but there were some graphics chips, right?
Scott: They're like these empty graphics in the game because that were special for this version.
Scott: But those seem to be, are now being recovered, right?
Scott: So good news for Ridge Racer full scale, bad news for Ridge Racer full scale.
Scott: I don't think it's going to be a lot of work to set up the hardware.
Scott: We'll see if that ever happens.
Rym: I feel like the best bet would be for someone to emulate or make an equivalent similar experience with a car as like a thing.
Rym: That's the kind of thing some nerd would just like roll into magfest one day with.
Scott: Yeah, I think, you know, that would be cool is like somebody else, you don't have, you know, it's like, it would be cool to get actual Ridge Racer full scale, but it's like, just make a similar setup, get a car, right?
Scott: Take all the shit out besides the steering wheel.
Rym: You can get a car that doesn't really work for negative dollars.
Rym: People will pay you to take that car.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Put it down, right?
Scott: Set up the wheel and the pedals so that they are a controller, right?
Scott: Use a tiny circuit board in there, right?
Scott: And then get a computer.
Rym: Get a new enough car to have electronic throttle and stuff so you can hook into that instead of having to like build components.
Scott: Projectors that are low latency enough, right?
Scott: And hook everything up to a computer and write a piece of driving simulating software that displays on three projectors.
Scott: And then if you want, you could run Ridge Racer full scale in MAME on that computer.
Rym: Do it with Hachiroku, make an initial D.
Scott: Sure, go ahead.
Rym: In the meta moment, the GeekNights Book Club book is Alif the Unseen.
Scott: I read a chapter.
Rym: I read one and a half chapters.
Rym: Ooh.
Rym: Alif the Unseen is a masterful- Are you counting chapter zero?
Scott: The chapter I read was chapter zero.
Rym: I also counted chapter zero.
Rym: Full disclosure.
Rym: Alif.
Rym: the Unseen is a masterful debut novel, an enchanting, incredibly timely adventure worthy of Neil Gaiman.
Rym: In an unnamed Middle Eastern security state, a young Arab Indian hacker protects watch groups from surveillance and tries to stay out of trouble until he falls in love with the wrong woman.
Scott: So I'm wondering, right?
Scott: So here's the question, Rym, right?
Scott: So chapter zero is a lot like say like Princess Bride where it's like, you know, the grandpa and the son, right?
Scott: But it's also, the way it's written, it might not be an outside situation, right?
Rym: It might be that chapter zero is inside the same universe as- I am predicting now, I am confident- Chapter one.
Rym: I am confident, and if I'm wrong, I'm wrong, that chapter zero is within the story itself directly.
Rym: I am very sure- I'm 50/50.
Scott: Chapter zero could either be Grandpa Princess reading Princess Bride or chapter zero could be in the universe 50/50.
Scott: And I kind of like that.
Scott: it's constructed that way.
Scott: That's clever.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Otherwise, PAX Unplugged 2022. on Sunday, December 4th at 1130 AM Eastern Time in the Crab God Theater, also known as Room 113B.
Rym: We will be there with "Why is this game taking four hours to
Rym: play?"
Rym: With significantly less dunking on Everdell and more talk about things like Marvel Snap.
Rym: Because I think I, in the original version of that panel, I spent way too much time talking about Everdell.
Rym: That game, however, does take way too fucking long for how good it is.
Scott: Well, because when Sutton gets on your- Gets caught in your craw.
Scott: Yeah, it's like when Rym gets a thing caught in his craw, he just can't stop himself from talking about it way too much.
Rym: Well, it was partly because that was the first game, like, playing Everdell once was actually the impetus for the original "This game takes too long" panel.
Rym: Because I remember I was playing it, and there was one card, exactly one card, that has a weird, like, political- See what I mean?
Scott: See exactly what I mean.
Rym: Yeah, but I saw that card, I was like, "Wait a minute.
Rym: That card is literally the reason this game takes so
Rym: long.".
Rym: WTF.
Scott: My process for writing a panel is, I got something.
Scott: I gotta say, let's go find supporting evidence.
Scott: Rym's process for writing a panel is, run a comb through his craw, and let's see what lands on the table.
Rym: What was I mad about over the last few months?
Rym: Ooh, here's a panel on why competitive and casual can't coexist.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Rym: Otherwise, of course, Twitter is just dying, like, find us in other places, stay tuned, just go wherever.
Rym: We don't know where everyone's gonna be, but we're gonna try to just put our stuff everywhere.
Scott: Do you think you have something so important to say that, like, I need to hear it, like, you really, like, need to interfere in my life and get information to me?
Scott: Well, you know what, if you wanna do that, you can send me an email.
Scott: Yeah, worst case- My email's not hard to figure out.
Rym: Worst case will block you if it's bad, and you can't email me anymore.
Scott: Our website is frontrowcrew.com, and you can find us on the internet so easily, right?
Rym: But I wanna point something out.
Rym: The GeekNights Forum has been, or like, the entire forum, the old forum and the new forum, are online still.
Rym: Like, we archived the original GeekNights Forum, it is there.
Rym: It is online.
Scott: I was just going through yesterday looking at the bill for the hosting, and I'm like, man, we're paying five bucks a month just for the old forum.
Scott: I don't think there's any way that I can fix that and make it cost less.
Rym: There might, I think there could be a way, but it would cost us so much effort that the five bucks is worth it.
Rym: I can start paying for the five bucks if you want, but anyway, that's- There's some other costs I can reduce on hosting other things.
Rym: Yeah, but I just wanna point out, the collective GeekNights Forum, it existed well before Twitter existed in a meaningful way, and I suspect it will now officially and formally outlast Twitter.
Scott: So, if you are- GeekNights existed pre-Twitter, and it will exist post-Twitter.
Scott: I think, you know, as long as we live, you know, and nothing else ridiculous happens.
Rym: I hope that in the retirement home, we're still doing GeekNights at least, like, once a month.
Scott: Yeah, I think we could easily beat Facebook, right?
Scott: But my advice to you youngins- Free spec does predate us, though, so.
Rym: Yeah, but my advice to you young- I mean, Facebook appeared while we were in college or leaving college, but my advice to you, if you're younger than us, this might feel existential, and you're looking for a new platform to go to.
Rym: That is not the way to look at it.
Rym: Every platform fails.
Scott: We've seen platforms come and go several times.
Scott: It's just been a while, so.
Rym: I've seen Facebook's collapse off the shoulder of a riot, like you.
Rym: I have used so many fucking platforms.
Scott: Or Cuts and Friendsters and MySpaces and Napsters and- LiveJournal, DeadJournal, like- LiveJournal still exists, kinda.
Scott: There was a forum- You can make one if you want.
Rym: I found an inside of Prodigy that I roleplayed as an elven wizard extensively for years, and I didn't know what to do when Prodigy went down.
Scott: I think, theoretically, if I still had- I think it might still be possible to play Gemstone with my- Ooh.
Rym: I found a speedrun of Mad Maze, so I actually watched what I missed because my 2400 bond modem could not save Mad Maze.
Scott: Ooh, I should watch that.
Rym: Yeah, I'll make that my Thing of the Day.
Rym: Alright, let's get into it.
Rym: So, one of the reasons we're doing this show is, Monday shows are hard to come up with, but two, a lot of people are trying to find an alternative to Twitter, and a lot of people are telling those people that Mastodon is that alternative.
Rym: However, very few people understand what the deal is with Mastodon, and Mastodon's architecture is confusing to people who don't understand the concept of Federation.
Scott: Right, so we're gonna talk mostly about Federation, and then at the end we'll complain about the specifics of Mastodon.
Scott: So, the idea with Federation is basically, that's the way internet applications are supposed to work, right?
Scott: All the early internet applications, and the ones that still underpin, you know, what we use on the internet today, are federated protocols, right?
Scott: HTTP, right, with web, right, is federated, right?
Scott: Email is federated.
Scott: There was a thing called XMPP that still exists.
Scott: that's federated instant messaging.
Rym: Well, think about DNS.
Rym: We did a show on DNS a long time ago.
Rym: DNS federates down till it points you eventually at the small, little, private, fully-owned empire.
Rym: that'll answer your question of what IP address you're looking for.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, what Federation just means generally is that, as opposed to, say, centralization, right?
Scott: It's not just one computer, but it's owned by one company, and one organization, and one set of, you know, technological people have access to it, and they are centrally orchestrating all of those computers in concert, right?
Scott: And that's it.
Scott: There's no, like, other Twitters or anything like that, right?
Scott: So, a federated model is decentralized, right?
Scott: It's like, anybody can have a Twitter.
Scott: I made a Twitter.
Scott: It's called ScottTwitter.
Scott: Rymd made one called Rymd.
Scott: We can all make Twitter servers that are stand-alone and completely independent of each other.
Scott: Imagine if the web, right, HTTP, never became popular, right?
Scott: Like, no one else used it, but you could still make one web server.
Scott: That's the only web server, and if someone had a web browser, they could visit it, and it would work.
Scott: It just wouldn't be any other websites, right?
Scott: That's the one.
Scott: But then, someone else could set up a second website, and it's like, do those websites have anything to do with each other?
Scott: No.
Scott: They're two completely independent things, right?
Scott: It's just, they're both speaking the same language.
Scott: HTTP is the language they speak.
Scott: So, if your web browser speaks HTTP, you can visit these different web servers, right?
Scott: If you have an email server, it's like, I can just start an email server.
Scott: No one can stop me, right?
Scott: You don't need a license for that or anything.
Scott: There's no law.
Scott: You could just start trying to send emails and saying, hey, if anyone wants to send me emails, send them here, right?
Scott: And just start getting and sending emails.
Scott: People might block the hell out of your emails because they're spam, but you can try, right?
Scott: You just start up your own email server.
Scott: What's anyone going to do about it?
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: And this is how the internet should work, right?
Scott: Because it's like, A, resiliency, right?
Scott: You can't take email down.
Scott: Gmail might be down, but email can't go down.
Rym: B, this way you can have a separation of concerns.
Rym: Someone can run the web server that does X completely independent of any dependencies on the person who runs the web server.
Rym: that does Y. I don't need to coordinate with Scott if I'm going to make a website or do anything.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You don't need anyone's permission to get in on the game, right?
Scott: You could even, if you want to, you know, this is going to be a guide for how the language is spoken, right?
Scott: And you could divert from that guide.
Scott: No one's going to stop you, right?
Scott: But your shit might break if someone else tries to speak to you in the standard dialect and you have a weird dialect.
Scott: But maybe you get other people to agree with you and start speaking your weird dialect and you could add more features that other websites don't have or other emails don't have or, you know, it's like you can do stuff like that because everyone does what they want.
Scott: Everyone's in charge of their own computers.
Scott: They use their own computer to do their own thing, but all the computers speak the same language.
Scott: And when you have a lot of computers independently governed but speak in the same language, powerful things start to happen.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like you can start sending emails to people.
Scott: And as long as everyone's, you know, cool with it, it's going to work.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's kind of weird when you think about it.
Scott: It's like, you know, I have a computer at Google and I tell that computer at Google, Hey, Google computer, send an email over there to Microsoft computer and the Microsoft computer.
Scott: So some bits are coming in on that Microsoft computer and the Microsoft computer agrees to look at those bits.
Scott: Like you could just send any old bits.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it's gonna and it's and it's gonna actually agree to look at those bits for free.
Rym: One of those things I could from a Linux command line right now, I could cat dev you random into and pipe that straight into a TCP connection to Scott's IP address if I wanted to.
Scott: Yeah, you could just start sending random bits to Microsoft's email server on the SMP port.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it would look at those bits and it would look at them and say, that's not an email garbage.
Scott: But you can do it.
Scott: And it's like their computer will look at bits for free, but their computer is programmed such that if the bits that come in, look a certain way and it looks at those bits and it says, that looks like an email.
Scott: It's from someone at Gmail.
Scott: Does everything look right here?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: This actually came from Gmail and it's for someone at Outlook.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I'm going to actually pay attention to these bits that just arrived from the internet.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And I'm going to do what they say and put an email in someone's inbox.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's not spam, right?
Scott: Doesn't say Viagra in that email.
Scott: Okay, let's do it.
Scott: Let's do it.
Scott: We're going to do it.
Scott: So it's like these companies and different people who have completely separate unrelated computers, right, are agreeing to like send bits to each other, look at whatever bits show up and behave in a certain way when those bits show up and they actually do it.
Rym: Like you're used to email addresses, something at something dot something like that.
Rym: You just think about that.
Rym: What does that mean?
Rym: That is the result of a nest of federated services using other federated services.
Rym: In the old days, if you were on Prodigy, you had a Prodigy username.
Rym: You want to message another Prodigy user, you just type their name.
Rym: Just like in an old phone network, you would just dial like the four local digits and that would connect you to someone on the local switch.
Rym: And that was it.
Rym: So that at sign was sort of an invention.
Rym: that was an appropriation of a sign that was used for another purpose.
Rym: You're literally saying I want Scott at a pressure on that.
Rym: I want to talk to the user, Scott.
Rym: And the at sign is saying and I'm telling you that I know Scott lives at a pressure net, wherever the fuck that is.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't care, but that's the address I'm putting on the envelope.
Scott: And all the computers involved, even though they're all owned by separate people, right?
Scott: All those computers have been configured to speak the same language and follow roughly the same rules.
Rym: Just like the Global Postal Service works, fill out an envelope.
Rym: Anyway, any human in the world will read that and eventually that envelope is going to get to the country you send it to.
Rym: That country has its own postal service, its own laws, its own nonsense.
Rym: But unless it's North Korea, they're very likely going to deliver that envelope where you want it to go.
Scott: They're willing to accept and look at bits that come, you know, electric signals that come from it pretty much fucking anywhere.
Scott: And as long as those bits, the data lines up, they're willing to obey and do what the bits say.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like even if you just visit a website, it's like you go.
Scott: you create a TCP IP connection with a Google server.
Scott: Google will just allow anyone who has a computer to make a TCP IP connection with their servers just for free.
Scott: And then you send over the wire the bits of like, you know, the letters get forward slash and they'll send you no money.
Scott: The HTML, JavaScript, JPEGs, whatever that constitute the Google homepage, they'll just send it to you.
Scott: Here it is.
Scott: You want it.
Scott: Here you go.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like these people just set up computers that will talk to the public according to rules for free.
Rym: Now, I think part of what happened with people who don't go to tech school, like learn this stuff, learn Internet history, learn architecture, learn to code is that most people go to only a few websites and don't think about this that much.
Rym: So they don't quite realize that almost everything on the Internet is federated, even if you end up going to the same website 90 percent of the time you go online and
Scott: you're effectively
Rym: living within one sort of non-federated system like Twitter or a specific social media network like Facebook.
Rym: Facebook interfaces with the rest of the world via a lot of protocols, but Facebook itself is a proprietary, non-federated platform that does its own shit.
Scott: Well, this is what happened in the 90s.
Scott: A lot of people who had Internet in the 90s had AOL specifically, but also CompuServe Prodigies.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: We're going to talk about XMPP or Jabber.
Scott: I'm sure other countries had them also, right?
Scott: You know, different services and those services were, you know, not federated, right?
Scott: AOL was just there was one AOL and that was it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You had to pay to get in there.
Rym: ICQ, you had a unique number, whole world.
Rym: There was no my name at something.
Rym: I was 15036112.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But, you know, what happened is those things died and the federated services, the Web just beat them all.
Scott: Right.
Scott: A lot of people were just dialing into AOL, minimizing it and opening up Netscape Navigator.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Rym: I googled for my ICQ number and I found it in my profile on the Oticon forum.
Scott: OK.
Rym: And nowhere else.
Scott: I'll do that later.
Scott: But the point is, what's it called?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So, you know, after right after that went on for a while.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, there's this old.
Scott: this is saying people like to use lately, which is like there used to be more Web sites.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, well, actually, there's more Web sites than ever.
Scott: It's like you're just not seeing all of them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because you're not going to them.
Scott: They're out there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's just you're not going to them.
Scott: It's like most people are just going to a few Web sites.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Your Facebook, your Twitter, your whatever, your ticktocks, your Googles, Amazon, eBay, you know, whatever.
Scott: And those Web sites are basically embedding or including or linking to all the other content.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And people are just doing everything through, you know, these single services that are, you know, it's like they are Web sites.
Scott: So the Web is federated, but the single Web site on its own, it's like the only one that's providing that particular service.
Scott: Right.
Scott: As a solitary thing.
Rym: So a lot of you, a lot of people like I. actually there's an article in WAPO talking about how much of a problem the fall of Twitter is going to be, because so many governments like use it to make official note of it.
Rym: Like there's a lot going on there, but a lot of people consume the news by looking at Twitter.
Rym: They get a whole feed of just links to Web sites and embedded nonsense from Twitter.
Rym: Twitter's where they get everything.
Rym: Not like the old days with RSS, where you would have an RSS reader that was hitting 100 different RSS feeds all over the Internet.
Rym: You have all of that collapsing into one proprietary platform, into one proprietary feed.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, yeah, so some of the other federated things that people don't know about.
Scott: We mentioned XMPP.
Scott: So XMPP was basically in the days of AIM, AOL Instant Messenger.
Scott: There was also MSN and Yahoo Messenger.
Rym: And ICQ was still around.
Scott: Yeah, ICQ.
Scott: But all those messengers were individually centralized.
Scott: It's like you couldn't message someone on MSN from AOL.
Rym: So on your desktop, you had an MSN client and ICQ client and an AOL client always running all the time.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Or just one of them and didn't talk to people on the other services.
Scott: But there was a thing called XMPP, also known as Jabber.
Scott: And Jabber was basically federated instant messaging.
Scott: I mean, it still exists, but it's just not heavily widely used.
Rym: Yeah, the protocol.
Rym: This is important to what we're going to say in about eight minutes.
Rym: The XMPP protocol that came out of Jabber outlasted Jabber itself and is now a critical part of the Internet.
Scott: Yes, XMPP is still around, but not a lot of people use, you know, some people.
Scott: I'm sure nerds aren't, right?
Scott: But the way it worked is like, you know, AOL and Google actually both at points in time supported XMPP.
Scott: And what you could do is, I actually did this, is I had my own XMPP server that I ran at my own domain, right?
Scott: Like, was it at Front Row Crew or at whatever?
Scott: And people on AOL and people on Google Hangouts could message me and I could message them all with my one instant messaging account.
Scott: And it's like, all these things are talking to each other.
Scott: But then AOL and Google both pulled the plug on that, right?
Scott: Now, why were they federating their instant messages and then unfederating them?
Scott: Well, the reason is pretty.
Scott: from a capitalist perspective is pretty clear is that if the service you are providing, right, becomes federated, then you yourself become basically a commodity.
Scott: Just a dumb pipe?
Rym: I was about to say a dumb pipe, which if you look at pure technology, the dumb pipe architecture, meaning the things that just connect information sources and destinations like sources and things together, those have to be as stupid and simple and reliable as possible.
Rym: You don't want to put all your logic in there.
Rym: You put the logic at the endpoints.
Rym: That is almost universally a superior architecture to smart pipes.
Rym: Pretty much categorically, the exceptions are so rare we don't need to really talk about it.
Rym: But you can't make money being a dumb pipe, so unless someone's willing to run a dumb pipe as a commodity service, dumb pipes really won't exist.
Rym: The Internet is one of the last dumb pipes.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like you think.
Scott: if you just provide an email server, it's like, well, those are just free and open source.
Scott: It's like anyone could just speak email, right?
Scott: It's like the only way you make money on email, I don't even know if they do make money, is Google, they get you to use their email by providing a superior user interface and spam filtering and all these other things on top of the email, right?
Scott: It's not the emailing.
Scott: All they did was do the emailing.
Scott: It's like that's federated.
Scott: You don't need them for that.
Scott: It's like, you know, they provide all these other benefits on top of it, right?
Scott: And then that's what allows them to put ads or charge money for the service.
Scott: But if you're just like Twitter, well, if anyone could just start run their own Twitter, it's like Twitter doesn't really provide anything beyond filling up your feed with the right messages.
Scott: In fact, they don't even do a great job of it.
Rym: They provide racism, they provide ads, they provide spam.
Scott: But like if Twitter was federated and I could run my own Twitter and it was literally Twitter, but it was my server, it's like Twitter would just go out of business immediately because everyone would just run their own, the end.
Scott: With their own rules and they wouldn't, right?
Scott: Twitter wouldn't be able to collect anyone's data.
Scott: They wouldn't be able to send ads to anyone, right?
Scott: All they would be doing is running computers that send, you know, tweets back and forth so that they get to the right places and that would be it.
Scott: It's like that doesn't get you anything.
Scott: It's like, does Twitter have the best Twitter client?
Scott: No.
Scott: Gmail has the best email client.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's like there's nothing they can do about that, right?
Scott: So that's why people don't want to make open federated protocols because there's no money in it.
Rym: Even though the architecture is generally superior.
Rym: And thus we get to, what's the deal with Mastodon?
Rym: Mastodon is basically just an implementation of a way to use a protocol called ActivityPub to do something like what Twitter does.
Rym: That's pretty much the most succinct way to put it.
Rym: So I, you know, I bought a new domain.
Rym: I bought Rym.social because I don't trust platforms and Twitter dying was a big wake up call.
Rym: I let my guard down for a second, a second, more than a decade.
Rym: I heavily, I used Twitter heavily.
Rym: I lived in that ecosystem.
Rym: I didn't really like have alternatives to it.
Rym: And now I got to abandon it.
Rym: So I got Rym.social.
Rym: I have a domain to do whatever I'm going to do in the future.
Rym: So if I want to be on Mastodon, I could run a Mastodon instance on my domain Rym.social.
Rym: And then my address on Mastodon would be Rym@Rym.social.
Rym: And I can subscribe to anyone else using Mastodon anywhere in the world unless they block me.
Rym: They can subscribe to me and the ActivityPub protocol kind of just makes it work.
Rym: That's basically what Mastodon is, a single implementation of this protocol.
Rym: And there's a whole bunch of other very similar things like PeerTube or there's one for podcasts.
Rym: There's a million of them.
Rym: They're probably all going to fail over time, but they're all out there.
Scott: So you could go and read it.
Scott: Actually, it's a W3C protocol, the ActivityPub protocol.
Scott: You can go read about it.
Scott: You can implement it yourself or you can get some libraries.
Scott: Mastodon is just currently a popular program that uses that protocol to do basically what Twitter does.
Scott: But you could do other things with the protocol.
Scott: You don't have to make a Twitter.
Scott: You could do other stuff.
Scott: The point is, is that Mastodon's specific implementation of this protocol doesn't seem to be that great.
Scott: It's got a lot of issues.
Rym: Which we won't really get into in this show, but having read the documentation for the server itself, it would be a pain in the ass to run.
Rym: In the old days, before modern Steam, if you wanted to run your own Counter-Strike server on your own bare metal, it's one step less pain in the ass than that was.
Rym: That's about what it feels like.
Rym: It's not that well documented.
Rym: There's weird options.
Rym: It does mostly just work if you get it going, but the way the servers implement Federation and the way they actually do it lead to a lot of unintended consequences.
Rym: So I don't think Mastodon is going to be the thing in the end, but I do think some evolved form of activity pub and some federated world is going to be the future of Twitter-like social media.
Rym: The danger is, if that doesn't come to pass, it's because capitalism has drawn people to invest big money and build even more non-federated proprietary platforms and prop them up.
Rym: Like pushing people into TikTok and that kind of service.
Scott: So if you're looking historically, what I predict will happen is you look at other federated things and it's like, well, there was email before Gmail, but email before Gmail had a lot of problems, spam and all kinds of issues.
Rym: Remember trying to run Squirrel Mail for our own purposes?
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Bad user interfaces, all kinds of issues, but email didn't fail over time.
Scott: Now there's several current email choices that are just fine now.
Scott: I use Gmail because that's what I happened to use back in the day and it's hard to move.
Scott: It's not what I would use if I had to use email today.
Scott: The point is that what was originally looked at as like the winner, the protocol of email lived the whole time.
Scott: Some before I was born, even all the way till now.
Scott: But the winner and the email field kept changing, right?
Scott: And probably will continue to change.
Scott: So we're only sort of still getting started with the ActivityPub federated protocol and the current winner of Mastodon, I think is just going to be like the first one and it'll fade.
Scott: And the other ones will come along and those will be more, they won't last forever, but there'll be more long term winners.
Scott: You look at things like the Apache web server, which felt like the only web for a long time.
Scott: That was the web server.
Scott: It's like, but now not so much.
Scott: Now people use Nginx and all sorts of other web servers.
Scott: Apache is not as popular for new projects anymore, really at all.
Scott: Just any protocol you think of, that's still around and you can see like, ah, there was an old winner in that field, right?
Scott: It's like, and now there's a new one.
Rym: So what does it mean for you?
Rym: Do not assume that whatever platform you move to in this space will continue to exist or be the winner and expect that the sort of Twitter Pax Romana, like this weirdly long period where Twitter was just dominant in this space, that was an aberration.
Rym: You're going to see over the next decade, probably the fairly rapid rise and fall of several Twitter like and Twitter adjacent implementations using activity pub or similar protocols.
Scott: I think also is just, you know, understand, right?
Scott: What it means when something's federated, right?
Scott: And that much like with email, it only works right when you behave according to the rules, you understand the architecture and whatever instance is like your home instance or instances right in the world, right?
Scott: A federation of all the servers that are out there has good governance that you agree with.
Rym: And be wary, the larger and more powerful any particular implementation gets, the more they will be able to break the rules and force everyone else to deal with it.
Scott: So, you know, you think about like, you know, the way that Gmail can force, you know, can change the terms of how email works, right?
Scott: It's like, if Gmail blocks your email, it's like, guess what?
Scott: Your email server, no one's going to use it.
Scott: Because people need to email people who are using Gmail because they got a lot of users and they won't use your email if it doesn't do that.
Scott: If Gmail, you know.
Rym: You might join a Mastodon instance and find out that half the people you want to follow, you can't follow because the instance you happen to join, everybody else blocked for some reason.
Scott: I think that, you know, we could talk for a while about.
Scott: I think Mastodon, one of its big mistakes is it seems to me like when you start an instance, all other instances are unblocked by default.
Scott: I feel like it should be the opposite.
Scott: that like if you start a Mastodon instance, everything else should be blocked by default.
Rym: Yeah, but then, because the whole idea is that it's like email, anyone can subscribe to you.
Scott: Right, but email only works, right?
Scott: Because like you said, you have to, everyone's obeying the rules, but there's a mega, mega spam filter.
Rym: 99.9999% of all email is blocked by machine learning algorithms.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That's the only reason email exists.
Rym: Why do we get so much spam, phone call spam?
Scott: Apparently, according to a quick Google search, 36% of email is spam.
Rym: Whoa!
Scott: I wonder if that's because so many- Their estimate's as high as 73, but no one says 99.
Rym: I wonder if what happened over time, I'm just thinking about this now, if basically bad actors who exist and try to spam like just get dev nulled everywhere, like they just go to black holes everywhere in the world.
Scott: Regardless, whether it's 36 or 73 or 99 or even two, right, it's like without spam filtering, right, people are focused a lot on like, you know, abuse and, you know, harassment and all these things.
Scott: And they should be, you know, with very good reason.
Scott: But, you know, spam is the first and the biggest enemy, right?
Scott: It's like people complain about freedom of speech.
Scott: It's like, oh, freedom of speech people, even they aren't defending spam, even though spam is freedom of speech, right?
Rym: Of course, I very strongly believe that commercial speech is not free.
Rym: Speech is free, commercial speech is not.
Scott: The point is, is that whatever, if you're doing federation, it's not centralized, that means everyone needs to spam filter, right, on their own.
Rym: And guess what?
Rym: That is really hard to do on your own.
Scott: Yep, which is why a lot of the centralized thing, one of the reasons the centralized things became dominant, right, was that they weren't spamming.
Scott: You know, Twitter only succeeded because it solved its spam problem, right?
Scott: But now, oh, look, as Twitter is failing, spam starts coming through.
Rym: I closed my DMs on Twitter a couple days ago because suddenly I started getting a whole bunch of spam DMs out of nowhere.
Rym: That had never happened to me in the history of Twitter until this last week.
Scott: It's like as soon as spam comes through, everyone abandons ship, right?
Scott: So if you federate, spam, each instance in a federated system is on its own to protect itself, right, from anyone coming along with messages or requests or speaking the language of the federated protocol.
Scott: People are going to try, can come to your instance and speak whatever they want to speak and you have to be ready to handle that properly.
Rym: Now, one fear I actually have is that because federated modern solutions are going to come and go and there's going to be almost like this warring states period of sort of chaos and like Macedon will probably die and something else will replace it.
Rym: I worry that the vast majority of people are going to see that as confusing and annoying and just go to a completely proprietary platform like TikTok and never leave.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, people who will do that, I don't really have any interest in communicating with or subscribing to, so that'll be fine for me.
Rym: But that will not be great for the public discourse and public interactions.
Scott: Well, I mean, for discourse, it'll be fine.
Scott: But I think the problem will be for commerce, right, is that people who are dependent on these sorts of systems for their commercial interest, right, whether it's email newsletters or post about my products I'm selling on Instagram, whatever.
Scott: It's like, you know, those people have become beholden to these systems in the way that, you know, someone making Photoshop plugins is beholden to Adobe.
Rym: But it's even worse because anyone who uses platforms to reach audiences other than people who already know about them and follow them, that starts to overlap with spam in that it's not content that everyone necessarily wants to see in their feed.
Scott: It's just a real.
Scott: it's a real tough world out there.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So but anyway.
Rym: And it's about to get tougher like this.
Rym: There is no quick and easy answer to the fall of Twitter.
Scott: Just, you know, I guess the point is understand, you know, Federation, how it works, right?
Scott: Independent computers talking to each other versus one person runs all the computers, the end, and understand what that means for you.
Scott: And it's the way to go.
Scott: But you had to be prepared for it to make it work in your favor.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Linki G, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, a happy communist, a bunch of people who rarely don't want me to say their names.
Rym: Case Cair makes music, Chris Haddad, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Joel Hayes, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Horl.
Rym: Stop all the downloading.
Rym: and several people who are correctly giving like a dollar or something instead of the five dollars to get me to say their names.
Rym: I'm real hungry.
Rym: I'm just going to leave you very simply with something you really should have seen coming.
Rym: If you can guess what the title is going to be by the way this game will actually start.
Scott: As a matter of fact this screen also brings back memories for me as well.
Scott: I'm sure it does for some of you and I'm sure you're dating yourself by saying that you remember.
Scott: I don't know if you remember this particular opening.
Rym: This was actually on the original PlayStation game as well when it was loading the game.
Rym: Of course I'm not a very good player even there.
Rym: Game is powered by Namco.
Rym: It's Ridge Racer.
Rym: Ridge Racer!
Rym: Remember that one?