Rym: It's Tuesday, July 5th, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we are talking about streaming games to devices, not like on Twitch.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, there won't be any GeekNights next week because, uh, at least me and a bunch of our friends are just going to the beach.
Rym: Private beach house.
Scott: I would be going to the beach, but next week, uh, you know, I haven't, I haven't worked for the past, uh, month.
Rym: Oh, I am, I am well aware.
Rym: I think you have pointed out that you are not working.
Rym: Literally every time I've interacted with you via any medium for this entire period.
Rym: And I can't blame you because I would do the same.
Scott: Uh, tomorrow I'm going to the beach.
Scott: Just, well, who's going to stop me?
Scott: I have a job to go to.
Scott: Tomorrow looks like a good beach day too.
Scott: Uh, so I'm just going to wake my ass up early and go to the beach tomorrow all day.
Scott: Uh, but, uh, other than that, yeah, next week, starting Monday, uh, my new job will begin.
Scott: So I guess I'm not going to go to the beach then.
Scott: Uh, however, on Friday next week, I won't be working or the Friday after that or the Friday after that.
Scott: Because, uh, that's the only reason I really accepted this job is because I'm never going to work on Friday.
Scott: That's what they said.
Rym: So... You know, like you said before, it's a situation where that's what you wanted.
Rym: Like, you can't say no to an offer like that if someone's like, "Here is exactly what you asked for.
Rym: We'll do
Rym: it.".
Rym: Like, all right.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, imagine going to negotiate with someone.
Scott: and they're like, "All right, what do you
Scott: want?".
Scott: And I'm like, "I will sell you this ballpoint pen for one billion
Scott: dollars.".
Scott: They're like, "All
Scott: right.".
Scott: You're like, "Uh, what,
Scott: what?".
Scott: I was like, "Uh, I guess I'm giving you the ballpoint
Scott: pen.".
Scott: It's like, I didn't want to give it to you.
Scott: That's why I said some ridiculous number.
Scott: I kind of need the pen.
Scott: It's my last pen, but I was planning to just walk away from this conversation with pen in hand.
Rym: Well, just like recruiters.
Scott: But you said yes to the billion.
Scott: So I guess I can't change my mind now.
Scott: I already...
Rym: Yeah, like recruiters bother me all the time.
Rym: So I usually give some like, "Eh, my minimum salary is like 500
Rym: grand.".
Rym: I just say something to make them go away.
Rym: But if someone says, "All right, let's keep
Rym: talking."
Rym: I do keep talking to them at least a little bit further until I find out what evil shit they're up to.
Rym: And then I tell them to pound sand.
Scott: But meanwhile, I turned off all LinkedIn settings to like, "I have a job, don't leave me
Scott: alone.".
Rym: I have never changed my LinkedIn away from, "Don't bother
Rym: me.".
Rym: It's never mattered.
Rym: It's never changed anything.
Scott: Or before I even went to day one at the new job, I've already got two recruiters.
Scott: They stopped for a little while, like a couple of weeks.
Scott: I already got two, like,
Scott: "Hey.".
Scott: But at least now I have a new line for recruiters, which is, now when I go and I'm like, "You know, I'd really like to work four days a
Scott: week.".
Rym: Now, daddy three.
Scott: I really like to work three days a week.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Three?
Scott: Well, I already work... Anytime a recruiter talks to me, I go back, "Look, can I work three days a
Scott: week?".
Scott: I'd be like, "Right now, I work four.
Scott: I work four now.
Scott: My current job, four.
Scott: So you want to pull me away?
Scott: Three.
Scott: Three days a
Scott: week.".
Rym: Some advice.
Rym: If you have a perk like that or a high enough salary, usually you don't want to tell a company that you're talking to to apply to.
Scott: No, I'd never tell them the money.
Scott: I would never tell them a number ever.
Scott: When people ask about money, the line I've been using that has worked well is, "I live in a New York City apartment.
Scott: I can see the skyline out the
Scott: window.".
Scott: Right?
Scott: You figure it out how much money I need.
Rym: Usually what I say lately is, "X is my minimum salary to have a
Rym: conversation.".
Rym: Like if it's not that, that's the bare minimum I would accept.
Rym: If that is not even on the table, like let's just end this right now.
Scott: I don't like to tell a number.
Rym: Well, I make that number pretty high.
Scott: Yeah, but you can get into trouble, right?
Scott: If their number was like way, way, way higher than that.
Rym: Yeah, but that number is high enough to where.
Rym: if it was higher than that, it actually wouldn't affect me.
Scott: Well, consider this, right?
Scott: Let's pretend that in a different universe where I had been better at school, and instead of playing battle tech in the basement, I studied more computer science.
Rym: Yeah, miserable life.
Scott: And at the time at college where we graduated, and there were like those little Google quizzes lying around in the cafe at the college, right?
Scott: And I had actually been able to do that little Google quiz, and I had gotten a job at Google as a computer programmer of some kind or software engineer in the year 2005.
Scott: And let's pretend that I had stayed at Google from the year 2005 to the year 2022, and for some reason never quit, even though there were many occasions on which my morality would have forced me to quit.
Scott: Putting all that aside, if that universe happened, by all information I have available, you would be making six to eight hundred K probably right now.
Scott: You're way off.
Scott: Well, you're way off.
Scott: No, the numbers that I have seen suggest that if you are a software engineer at Google, with how many years is that?
Scott: Seventeen years.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I guess seventeen.
Scott: God, with seventeen years of tenure, I would be making one point seven or eight million dollars a year.
Rym: Yeah, I did realize I recently was looking at what the actual compensation structure is for companies like Amazon and Google for some comparative research.
Rym: And yeah, it's like a product manager.
Rym: Like what I do now, that equivalent of those kinds of companies pays between seven hundred and twenty two point one million.
Rym: But anyway, it's gaming day and you're going to the beach tomorrow and I'm going to be next week.
Rym: So today and most likely Thursday will be the last episodes of GeekNights for a little bit.
Scott: So it's got to get situated a new job until we'll be able to do a lot of GeekNights starting to, you know, a few weeks from now to two weeks away, because, you know, I think it is pretty much going to be back to normal.
Rym: We're past all the known disruptions.
Rym: So in the news, I know I can't ignore it.
Rym: Got to talk about it at least briefly.
Rym: But there were several mass shootings in America over the weekend.
Rym: But one of them was extremely, you know, crazy white right wing Nazi in sell a guy with a sniper rifle, basically.
Rym: But the news I have, because the real news will talk about all that in detail.
Rym: And if you really want to know the details, even though it's not going to affect your life that much, you can go read about it.
Rym: But the news I have is that we're in sort of an interesting situation now as people who live in America, in that our Supreme Court, as you may know, has basically
Scott: ended
Rym: New York State's gun laws, the laws that are the primary reason there's very few gun deaths in the state compared to like every other state that doesn't have these laws.
Rym: And the Supreme Court just ended them all.
Rym: So what New York?
Scott: just some of them.
Rym: Well, it ended the big one.
Rym: So they basically said you got to give anyone who wants to carry a handgun the right to carry a handgun.
Rym: You can't require them to have a good reason to have one.
Scott: So what do you think has to be a certain kind of reason?
Rym: You're generalizing dramatically.
Scott: It's a very specific thing.
Rym: You cannot require any reason now.
Rym: You must give a permit unless there is a specific item on an enumerated list.
Rym: that means you should not give that person.
Rym: It's permissive as opposed to restrictive.
Rym: is basically how this is going to shake down.
Rym: New York responded by rapidly passing a law and we're going to have a referendum and a state constitution amendment basically adding a million new gun restrictions to basically prevent the outcomes of the Supreme Court decision and go even further, like some of the biggest gun restrictions the state has ever passed and basically daring red states and the Supreme Court to do anything about it.
Rym: New Jersey now, I think this news is today, basically is now doing the exact same thing.
Rym: And we're seeing a wave where all the blue states are now passing massive new gun controls because it's literally impossible to do anything at the federal level.
Rym: And we're getting to a situation, it's not a civil war, but it's something that I've seen a lot of people referring to as a cold civil war in that we're going to see very likely over the next decade in America a radical divergence between the laws in blue states versus the laws in red states and it's just going to keep escalating.
Scott: That's what Republicans wanted.
Scott: They kept yelling about states rights.
Scott: It's like, you know, that's what they wanted since the actual civil war, right, is, you know, they weren't the Confederates for all of their evil ways.
Scott: They weren't trying to conquer the union, right?
Rym: They just wanted their, their particularly awful practice.
Scott: They would have been happy to keep being evil slaveholding people down South and let the North do whatever the North was going to do.
Scott: So today those same people are perfectly happy to, you know, let, right, you know, where they live, do that their way.
Scott: And then, you know, where we live, do our way.
Scott: But of course, if they have the opportunity to make someone else do their way, right, they'll do that too.
Rym: Well, I mean, it's actually, it's a little simplistic because they did aggressively force Northern states and non slaveholding states to protect slave rights and they actually aggressively, you know, bleeding Kansas and all the skirmishes.
Scott: Well, yeah, they wanted, right, they wanted us to return slaves that had to run away from them.
Rym: Well, they also wanted to make sure that every new state was a slave state.
Rym: And there's lots of other stuff going on, but basically because Reconstruction failed, that never ended.
Rym: And here we are again.
Rym: We've got all the blue states banding together to pass massive gun restrictions, massive abortion protections, birth control protections, gay marriage protections, everything.
Rym: Meanwhile, red states are aggressively doing the exact opposite as fast as possible.
Rym: And they're going to try to use the Supreme Court to undo all these new laws that the blue states are passing.
Rym: And all I want to say is pay attention to the first time one of these blue states or one of these compacts of blue states refuses to follow one of these things that the Supreme Court does, because at that moment, America is on a very different trajectory.
Scott: Well, you know, the Supreme Court has been refused before.
Scott: It has.
Rym: And here's hoping that we can fix the Supreme Court in some fashion.
Rym: But to get away from that into gaming news, because it is Tuesday and we skipped a few gig nights and everything.
Rym: I saw you were playing a game called Nobody Saves the World.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, there's a steam sale going on right now because it's, you know, the holiday in the United States.
Scott: If you're in another country, I don't know if it's a holiday for you, Canada.
Scott: Your holiday is pretty close.
Scott: Like, it's July 1st, right?
Scott: Canada Day, whatever.
Scott: I think I might be wrong on that.
Scott: But anyway, so steam has to be a big summer sale around now.
Scott: And I didn't have to go to work.
Scott: So given that, you know, it wasn't a day to go to the beach, I bought a steam game and, you know, followed my policy of buy, install, immediately play.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I saw this game on there called Nobody Saves the World.
Scott: And I said, that looks like a little, you know, sort of Robotron shooty action RPG kind of deal.
Scott: And it's highly rated.
Scott: And I watched a little video for a second and I'm like, all right, looks cute.
Scott: I'll try that for, you know, $20 out of $25 total.
Scott: And I tried it.
Scott: And sure enough, it's an action RPG, you know, game where you level up, you know, you kill guys, they drop gold, you pick it up, right?
Scott: You move around and you attack or shoot in four directions based on, you know, whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's got cute characters, cute story, nice art, you know, nice calm music.
Scott: The music actually is kind of, it's not, it's not like music you would play, like at a soundtrack on purpose, but it's sort of like in the background.
Scott: It's like, about this game that's worth talking about.
Scott: that is significant is the way that they have turned the systems on their head, right?
Scott: If you think about the normal, you know, action RPG systems, right?
Scott: The Diablo system would be like, you know, the, the model, right?
Scott: You pick a class.
Scott: that is your class.
Scott: You know, you have stats, those are your stats.
Scott: You gain abilities as you level up and equipment as you level up and you choose them and you are built.
Scott: You're making a build.
Scott: This is your build.
Scott: You are the wand wizard.
Scott: You shoot with wands.
Scott: That is what you do.
Scott: You are the necromancer.
Scott: You summon skeletons.
Scott: That is what you do.
Scott: And you do it the whole game and you just get better at doing that.
Scott: one thing, right?
Scott: You polish and sharpen that one pointy stick as sharp as you can make it.
Scott: And that's how you play those games.
Scott: And I think every grindy level up action RPG I've ever played, almost all of them follows that kind of system, right?
Scott: This game does not do that.
Scott: What this game does, nobody saves the world is you start out as nobody, literally like this white humanoid creature that has amnesia.
Scott: Like it's nobody.
Scott: And you have one attack, which is slap and you kill some bad guys and you love and you unlock, right?
Rym: Rat.
Scott: And now you can freely, at will, at any time, freely transform from nobody into rat or vice versa.
Scott: It would be like in Diablo, if you could just change your class instantly, like necromancer, wizard, fighter, just whenever the hell you wanted.
Scott: Like you could like swing a sword, turn into a wizard, shoot some wands, turn into a necromancer, raise a skeleton, turn back into a warrior, right?
Scott: Instantly, right?
Scott: So, and as you play with each individual, you know, you unlock these different classes in sort of like a tech chart.
Scott: And at the top, of course, is the dragon, right?
Scott: Which I haven't gotten yet.
Scott: And with each of the different, you know, classes, creatures, transformations, there are quests to go on and the quests are specific to the class, right?
Scott: There are general quests that sort of level you up as a whole, but those are boring.
Scott: But each class has specific class quests.
Scott: Like for the rat, it'll be, it's like, Oh, you're the rat.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Kill 10 enemies with the rat's bite attack.
Scott: Now kill 20 enemies with the rat's other attack.
Scott: And then you do those.
Scott: And when you do those things, the rat specifically levels up from like F to D to C to B to A. You know what that's a little bit like?
Rym: The weapons in Secret of Mana.
Scott: Yes, exactly.
Scott: And however, once you get to like B rank, so let's say you get the rat to B rank, right?
Scott: Well, what happens now, once you get a high enough rank, you unlock more ability slots, more abilities, and you can actually import abilities from other that you've unlocked on other classes to sort of mix and match.
Scott: So you can have a rat do the, the wizard's, you know, magic attack.
Scott: You could, you could assign that to like button X or Y or whatever.
Rym: Kind of like Final Fantasy 5.
Scott: It's like the rat's, the rat's normal attack is always going to be the rat's bite.
Scott: You know, it's never going to change and you can't, the rat's basic attack, that bite, you can't move that attack onto anyone else, right?
Scott: Cause it's, that's the rat, you know?
Scott: So there's always a reason to transform, but the other three attacks on the three other buttons, you can import or export those from the other classes, as long as you've unlocked them and leveled them up sufficiently.
Scott: And the game will force you, right?
Scott: To do combinations on purpose.
Scott: For example, like there was a class, I was like, I was someone else.
Scott: I forgot who I was.
Scott: And it was like, Oh, you want to level up the, I don't know, the night or something.
Scott: I forget which one, uh, kill 10 enemies with the rats, you know, attack.
Scott: And it's like, what it's like, it forces you to do a specific combination to get, you know, ahead.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, it'll be like each, there's four different attack types.
Scott: There's like, you know, bludgeoning, piercing magic and dark, I guess poison and like certain enemies will have like a shield on them so that you can only damage them with the right type of attack.
Scott: And so like, let's say you're the magician.
Scott: Most of the magicians attacks are like the magic type, but one of the quests for the magician will be like, you know, pierce the 10 enemies with the piercing thing.
Scott: And it forces you to get a piercing ability from another class, import it to the magician, find enemies who are vulnerable to that and use it on them in order to level up the magician to the next rank.
Scott: So then you could help fully unlock whatever's beyond the magician, you know, the dragon or the monk or whoever else is up there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So as you play the game and there's different situations in the game, like, Oh crap, I'm in a water level.
Scott: I better turn into the mermaid or the turtle, right.
Scott: To go in the water.
Scott: Oh, I'm in a fire.
Scott: You know, it's like you're constantly changing and rebuilding and reconfiguring and you have to level up fucking everybody.
Scott: Cause even if you're not going to use that character, you have to get their abilities to import to another character.
Scott: And it's like, you're forced to play everybody.
Scott: You can't just focus in on your one deal, your one build and level it up.
Scott: And that's it.
Rym: You have to go out to Dr.
Rym: Chaos.
Rym: You got to play all the family members to beat that game.
Scott: You have to play the whole game.
Scott: You're thinking about legacy of the wizard.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like I said, the wizard, you don't have to play all the characters to beat that really.
Rym: I mean, I did see a speed run where you can do anyway.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Speed runs.
Scott: But anyway, the point is, yeah, you're sorta have to, and it's like, as the game goes on this situations, we have to like transform constantly, like, you know, transform, fight, fight, fight, transform, fight, fight, fight.
Scott: And you're constantly strategizing and reconfiguring right.
Scott: Making different builds.
Scott: It's like you go into a level and it's like, man, what's, you know, the situation here.
Scott: I got these bad guys, these bad guys and this water.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So how do I get a mermaid or a turtle or a ghost?
Scott: Cause the ghost can float over the water.
Scott: Like what abilities can I give them to deal with this level?
Scott: I guess maybe I'll need to use two or three guys and switch between them to get through this level.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, if you get it wrong, you just, you just get killed because it can't even hurt anybody.
Scott: So that, you know, it's like, it makes it fun to play.
Scott: It keeps it interesting.
Scott: Uh, you know, and it's like, there are situations where like, yeah, you can't, you know, you're grinding, but you're not really grinding.
Scott: Like you could sit there and kill bad guys all day and never level up really that much at all, because you have to do it in the specified way, according to the class that you're currently using.
Scott: Otherwise it doesn't get you anything really.
Scott: just gives you some gold, maybe, you know, and even getting a bunch of gold doesn't help because the shop sells out of like upgrade coins and then tough, tough shit.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So should I get it?
Rym: It looks fun.
Rym: Looks cute.
Scott: It does have a two P co-op situation that I have not tried, which I think would be really fun with two people transforming.
Scott: And that would make some of the levels easier because then you wouldn't have to individually transform so much.
Scott: Like if there's two kinds of bad guys in one area, you could both be the right class to deal with those and then deal with, you know, I deal with these half of the guys and you deal with those half of the guys and so on.
Scott: So if you like an action RPG for cheap on the PC, you know, you, uh, this is a good game, I think.
Scott: Uh, and it's really, I really like the forcing you to play all the characters system as opposed to the grind one character system.
Rym: All right.
Scott: So good, good design, good game design.
Rym: It looks like it's on the switch and PC and let's on everything.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So in some other, uh, news, uh, key forge, which has been languishing, we talked about it a while ago where they, they messed up the algorithms.
Rym: They couldn't make more.
Scott: There was, there was basically what, what the rumor was.
Scott: I don't know if this is confirmed is that there was a ransomware and I guess it's like, how could you lose an algorithm?
Scott: It's like, I guess there was a ransomware and it got their backups too.
Scott: So they would have to basically read software from scratch or pay a ransom.
Rym: There's still cagey about it.
Rym: Cause even this article for with the new news says, quote, unfortunately key forage went on an indefinite hiatus in 2021 due to unspecified issues with the underlying algorithm that created new decks for the game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That makes, it doesn't make any sense that like you have software and the software just stops working.
Scott: That's not a thing that happens, right?
Scott: It's like people could fix that.
Scott: The only explanation that really makes sense.
Scott: I don't have any evidence that this is the case.
Scott: But it was a rumor, so it might not be true.
Scott: I don't want to get in trouble, but the only thing that makes sense is that every copy of the software and source code that they had was ransomware.
Scott: And either they paid the ransom and the ransom, you know, I don't understand why people who do ransomware actually unlock the software, right?
Scott: It's like, if I was a ransomware person, I'm already evil.
Scott: Give me another million.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I'd be like, I'd be like, thanks for the free money.
Scott: Your shit's still encrypted.
Scott: Deal with it.
Scott: I threw away the keys.
Scott: Good luck.
Scott: They're right.
Scott: Doofus.
Scott: Um, you know, but I guess that would hurt anyone in the future trying to collect ransom, you know, whatever.
Scott: But the point is, is either they didn't pay, they paid in the ransom where people didn't unlock it or, you know, but yet they must've just lost all the software.
Scott: And the only option would then be to rebuild all the software from scratch, which is a Herculean effort that would not be worth what Keyforge is going to bring in.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like once they had the Keyforge machine set up, you know, the level of popularity that had had attained made it worth it to carry on with the game because they were making more sets.
Scott: So clearly it was economically viable.
Rym: Well, you know, we reviewed it a while back and it was a really cool idea, but the gameplay got pretty boring pretty quick.
Rym: And I didn't even play all the decks that I own.
Scott: I mean, it was no Netrunner.
Scott: I do still have some sealed Keyforge decks, so maybe I'll keep those around anyway.
Rym: So long story short, the news today, actually from a couple of days, like a week ago, is that Asmodei is who currently has Keyforge.
Scott: is they bought.
Rym: Fantasy Flight Games is now selling the intellectual property rights for Keyforge to Christian Peterson, who was the founder of Fantasy Flight Games.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's sort of like, you know, you ran the company, you made this game, right?
Scott: We're not making the game anymore.
Scott: You can have the IP back.
Scott: So the IP, I guess, includes the trademark, the word Keyforge, the art, the characters, the universe, the story, all that.
Rym: And now it'll be.
Rym: it's owned by a company called Ghost Galaxy that is, quote, developing a next generation software engine for developing procedurally generated card games similar to the system that generate Keyforge.
Rym: So basically this company seems like it's going to double down on.
Rym: what can you do with this concept?
Scott: There are at least one other people company, I think, that did a similar thing, but I don't know how successful it's been.
Scott: I really, I wish someone would just do it digitally entirely.
Scott: It's like if there was a card game, you know, as good, you know, it doesn't have to be, even if it wasn't Netrunner.
Scott: good, that's a big ask, right?
Scott: But just, you know, as good, better than Keyforge.
Scott: good with a UI that was at least as good as like, the UI has to be good, like ideally Hearthstone.
Scott: good, but it could be Race of the Galaxy good, it could be, you know, Root good, right?
Scott: And as long as, you know, the UI was good enough, they were like, hey, pay a dollar, right?
Scott: Or, you know, buy a season or something and you get this many random decks, something like that, and there were people online playing it, like, I could be convinced to play that based on circumstances, right?
Scott: I'm not entirely opposed to getting involved in that kind of game.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, honestly, the only reason I eventually bounced very slowly off of Hearthstone was all the grinding for like any sort of real competitive play just wasn't worth keeping up with.
Scott: Or paying money.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Wasn't worth that much money to me, especially because I can just keep playing Overwatch and I don't have to pay any more money for that.
Scott: You know, Hearthstone, I did pay some monies for it, right, you know, for a while, you know, because I was playing, at the time, I was playing it a lot, right?
Scott: So my calculation was like the amount of money that I was paying for it versus the hours.
Rym: Yeah, you don't know the times have changed.
Rym: I very seriously considered paying for a Fortnite Game Pass/Battle Pass thing for this current season.
Rym: That's how much Fortnite I'm playing now.
Scott: That's all cosmetic shit, though.
Rym: Yeah, uh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: I thought you're the person who doesn't open loot boxes and stays with the-.
Rym: I actually have almost a thousand loot boxes again in Overwatch.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: In some other news, this happens all the time, but it's worth noting because a lot of gamers, especially younger ones, seem to like forget that this is the thing that can happen.
Rym: So Ubisoft, known for just shutting down its old games, has announced that they are shutting down 15 of their slightly older games' multiplayer in the fall.
Rym: So this fall, if you play, like, Auto 2070 or Assassin's Creed, like any Assassin's Creed, I guess, or there's this whole list of games that I guess had multiplayer in some fashion, but multiplayer is all gonna stop working.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: This is what happens when they have a multiplayer and they don't let people run their own servers, right?
Scott: You can still- you want to play or have just peer-to-peer multiplayer.
Rym: It's also what happens when a game's multiplayer is not- some games are designed around their multiplayer, and some games have multiplayer, so they can put that on the box or get that little bit of extra juice in the game.
Rym: But not every game is Counter-Strike, and I did check before we did the show to make sure.
Rym: So today, right now, go to Steam.
Rym: Number one game on Steam is still fucking Counter-Strike in the year 2022.
Rym: By a wide margin.
Scott: Yeah, you know, I think, you know, this really, you know, from a company's perspective, right, is like maintaining servers for an online multiplayer game is work, right?
Scott: It's a pain in the butt.
Scott: It costs money.
Rym: Especially because Counter-Strike's like- I paid for Counter-Strike GO when it came out, so I could play it right now, use their servers, they're not going to get any more money out of me.
Scott: Yeah, if nobody is playing the game, and there's no revenue stream for the game, and then it's like, why would you keep those servers on?
Scott: It just makes sense to turn them off.
Scott: You know, the problem is, is like, you know, well now, you know, it's like- it's only really bad from a preservation standpoint, and like, hey, you know, there's this- it's sort of like, you know, I guess the first thing to ever happen to this was like the BT Zelda, right?
Scott: The satellite Zelda 1 from Japan was like the first case of this.
Scott: It's like, you can't go and have that- it was an experience that someone crafted.
Scott: that now cannot be had, and, you know, there are things like- there are other things like, we can't experience, I don't know, tribes 2 as it was, we can't experience what it was like to fight in the game, right?
Scott: It's like they're, you know, um, so it's like, we can't expect to preserve every experience that has ever existed, but it's a meaningful historical thing with video games, you know, we talk about it all the time, because we are still early in the history of video games.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, some of the, like, many of the first video games, like the earliest ones that ever existed, were during our lifespan or not that long before us.
Scott: Yeah, like the earliest video games, like the pongs, were like 70s, 80s deals, right?
Scott: You know, it's like, and it's like, it's only 2022, that's like less than 50 years really of video games, and in terms of video games being a big cultural thing, like, really not until the 90s were they big, right?
Scott: So we're talking 32 years of video games, 32 years of movies, you're talking, like, think about movies, that's like movies from the 40s, maybe, not even, right?
Scott: It's like movies from the 40s are like, you know, historical, like, monumental things, so video games that come out now are as gonna be as historical monumental as movies from the 30s and 40s are now, right?
Scott: Movies, I mean, movies from the 50s and 60s are historical monumental, right, masterpieces of all time, right?
Scott: Hell, even some from the 90s, so, you know, so it's like the ones being made today, even though they don't seem, I mean, a lot of them are garbage, but a lot of movies in the 70s were garbage, but then there's the ones that survived.
Scott: Several video games made now are going to be all-time great masterpieces worthy of preservation, and if they have an online component that is not maintained, well, that's kind of fucked up, that's sort of like burning half of a film reel, you know, kind of deal.
Scott: I think
Rym: what's really notable here, the two things that stand out to me, then we'll move on, because this is not the topic of the show, is that one, Counter-Strike is some fucking magic that it has remained so popular for so long, large, like, fundamentally unchanged, like, it's tweaked, it's gone through three different engines, there have been tweaks to it, but the core of Counter-Strike, pretty much the same as it was when we were playing, like, beta, whatever, when they added the P90, when we were at RIT.
Scott: I mean, the fundamental concept of, shoot people, try to do a thing, you're not just trying to shoot people, try to do a thing.
Rym: If you die, you're dead, like, super realistic.
Scott: Yeah, when you die, you're dead, and then you wait for the next round.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Actually, I have this weird urge to play Counter-Strike now, but I only want to play with friends, not with people who are good.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: And two, that any game that's bigger than Counter-Strike, or even close to Counter-Strike, really has its own launcher and will never be on Steam, is the way that tends to go.
Scott: That's because, you know, if you're making a game that's multiplayer like that and is big, you're making money on some sort of transaction, DLCs, subscriptions, skins, pay-to-win, something, right?
Scott: You're not making money and selling the game itself.
Scott: What's really messing me up, though, is that- You need to be on Steam and let them take a cut.
Scott: You need some sort of external payment system platform that's your own to get all the money.
Rym: Number four on this list is somehow still Team Fortress 2, and I almost want to join a server to see what the fuck is even happening in there.
Scott: People are playing it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But, uh, two last little newses, we'll get into, uh, the rest of the main bit.
Rym: So, uh, if you were trying to get Pokemon cards and you couldn't because there was a shortage, well, guess what?
Rym: The Pokemon company had a strategy to get more cards into the market, and it succeeded, and you can easily get your Pokemon cards now.
Scott: I don't know how- it's not- I don't know if it's super easy, but you can get Pokemon cards now, right?
Scott: They increased production dramatically, right?
Scott: Um, you know, it was never-.
Scott: it's not like they ever had an issue of supply chain.
Scott: It's simply that they were producing the same amount of Pokemon cards they always produced.
Rym: But interest seemed to have taken off.
Scott: Demand just jumped dramatically and caught them by surprise, so it took- takes a while to ramp up production in response to demand, right?
Scott: And now they've caught up, and I think you'll see, uh, if demand drops, which you gotta imagine it will, right?
Scott: Then you're gonna see a glut, and it's gonna- because they'll take time to ramp the production down.
Rym: Good!
Rym: I hate the secondary market in collectible card games.
Scott: Oh, I hate the secondary market too, but- is actually a decent card game.
Scott: It is!
Scott: It's-.
Scott: the only thing I have against it is- it's not the best card game, but it's decent.
Scott: I'll play it, why not?
Scott: Um, and, you know, it has some- some unique elements to it.
Scott: Uh, is really that it's- the gambling for children is the- is the problem, right?
Scott: But, at the moment when demand drops, and the production is still high, and the market is glutted with the Pokemon cards, I am considering going out and just buying, like, a whole fuckin' box.
Rym: If you do this, I will do it too.
Rym: There's no reason not to.
Scott: That's what I'm saying, let's just go out and buy, like, a box of boosters, like, you know, for, you know, for a reasonable price.
Scott: It won't be cheap, but, you know, a reasonable price, not some overpriced, right?
Scott: And then, with just whatever set that happens to be, will be our Pokemon cards for the rest of our lives.
Rym: I mean, for all that, I could just go home and get my magic cards, like, the revised cards.
Scott: I have them right here, I don't need to go home, I got- I got all my cards.
Scott: But to give you a sense of the scale, so- I still got the Netrunner cards.
Rym: Last year, the Pokemon company printed, uh, so normally, they print between one and two billion Pokemon cards a year, that's their normal rate.
Rym: They've made 43 billion since the game launched.
Rym: Last year, they raised that, and made almost 4 billion.
Rym: This year, so far, they have printed 9 billion.
Scott: So they've printed a po- more than one Pokemon card for every person on Earth, just this year alone.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And if you thought- If you count all the Pokemon cards ever printed, basically every human being alive right at this instant could have a handful of Pokemon cards.
Rym: 43.2 billion Pokemon cards have been printed to date, not counting bootlegs and counterfeits.
Scott: If you took all the Pokemon cards ever made, at this moment, and made a big pile, and everyone walked up to it, each person could take, like, six, seven, maybe even eight cards off the pile, and when the last human, the only remaining human with no Pokemon cards walks up to the pile, it'll have about six, seven, eight cards left in it.
Rym: Another way to put this, I'm just gonna quote this article that I linked to in Polygon, "More than a quarter of all the Pokemon cards that have ever been printed were printed between 2020 and
Rym: 2022.".
Scott: I still have my Pokemon cards from the 90s.
Scott: They're all beat up and probably not, you know, but they're way old.
Scott: They're from the first set.
Scott: They're legit.
Rym: I bought 'em.
Rym: So speaking of cards that are easy to get, because cryptocurrency is basically predictably collapsing into the pile of shit that it's always been- Video cards are plentiful.
Rym: You can get top tier, like, 3080s at MSRP or below.
Rym: They are just- All right, Newegg, components.
Scott: Let's go to the Newegg test.
Scott: Newegg, video cards and video devices, desktop graphics cards.
Scott: All right, let's try to get a GeForce RTX 30-.
Rym: I'll go to Amazon and try to buy a 3090.
Scott: All right, let's get a 3080, and we're gonna sort by-.
Scott: All right, I just bought a 3090 that's on sale.
Rym: 20% off for 1500 bucks.
Scott: Oh, we only want new ones, and we only want ones sold by Newegg, not by, like, third party sellers, right?
Scott: All right, 800 bucks.
Scott: Isn't that the MSRP?
Rym: Pretty much.
Rym: And there are so many video cards on the market.
Rym: now, like, you can just get the exact specific video card you want.
Rym: MSRP or close, no problem.
Rym: So, everything's coming up Milhouse.
Scott: All right, I mean, you know, I don't need one.
Scott: I'm still waiting for 4080, 5080, 6080, something like that.
Rym: I was gonna get a 3080, but at this point, I have to build a whole new computer by 2025 anyway, and I already put that 3080 Ti in Emily's workstation, so I think I can hold out for the 4080 and a new computer.
Scott: Yeah, 4080, yeah, probably.
Scott: Just wait until 2023, 2024.
Rym: Actually, the hard thing is what I want, but they're hard to get is, so an index VR headset that has a cable that plugs in the back of your computer, and then has a junction on the end of it, and then you plug the headset into the junction.
Rym: So, like, if you trip and fall, it'll pull out of the junction instead of fucking up your computer.
Scott: Like a mag safety.
Rym: Yeah, so it's hard to get just the piece of that that goes on a computer, because what I want to do is just leave one of those plugged into both our computers.
Rym: When Emily's not using her workstation, I could just use my index on her computer at full frame.
Rym: But, uh, I can't find that cable.
Rym: Oh, because it'll be easier to swap than swapping out, like, a-- Yeah, otherwise I'd have to climb behind and unplug, like, an HDMI cable and, like, multiple USB cables and all this crap.
Scott: Couldn't you just-- Well, you could, A, turn the computer around backwards.
Scott: B, you could just get, like, an extension cable that has, you know, to extend from the back to the front.
Rym: Extension cables get dicey with USB 3.
Scott: It's just got to be a good one.
Rym: Even a good one, there's trouble you can run into.
Rym: You run into latency issues.
Scott: You could also, you know, if it's a USB cable, you could just have a front USB port hooked up to the right spot on the motherboard.
Rym: Really, it's the, uh, because I got to plug-- I have to plug the additional HDMI into the back.
Scott: Yeah, I was going to get an HDMI extension over to the front also.
Rym: Yeah, but that can also give you difficulties considering the high frame rate and resolution that's being pumped over that cable.
Scott: It's wires.
Scott: It is wires.
Rym: I've looked into this.
Scott: It's going to be fine.
Scott: People putting extension-- As long as it's a proper cable, it's going to be fine.
Rym: Well, the problem is the cable length that's already on the headsets approaches the limit of what those cables are intended to handle by itself.
Scott: Uh, I've-- every time in my life, I mean, I'm sure there are definitely instances where cables get too long and they don't work.
Scott: But every time in my life I've ever seen a, you know, a sign or a warning or some sort of limit.
Scott: that said, this is technically how long this cable can be within spec.
Scott: Much longer cables have functioned perfectly.
Rym: Yeah, depending on what you're doing.
Rym: USB 2, you can get away with a lot.
Rym: USB 3, I have actually run into problems before.
Scott: No, anyway.
Rym: But at the same time, that was putting, like, a 20-foot extension cable somewhere, so.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day!
Rym: America celebrates the 4th of July by blowing things up and shooting people, but I figure we'll have two firework-related things of the day, so I'll start.
Rym: It is the 10-year anniversary of one of the most notable firework shows that ever happened.
Rym: San Diego 2012.
Scott: Wasn't this a thing-- I'm pretty sure this was a news or a thing of the day 10 years ago.
Scott: Someone check on it.
Rym: Yeah, well, if it is, then I'll eat a hat of some kind.
Rym: But, uh, so 10 years ago, on the 4th of July, the city of San Diego had some official fireworks.
Rym: Whole bunch of barges, a lot like the Macy's fireworks that we have in New York.
Rym: They're all synchronized with the controller.
Rym: It's a fancy professional show.
Rym: Due to a mistake, the-- instead of the show going off as sequence, the controller barge launched every single firework for the entire show in order as fast as it could, and every other barge did the exact same thing.
Rym: And what happened is amazing, and I'm glad it happened at least once, but I don't know if it needs to happen again, because that was a waste of a lot of fireworks.
Scott: Yeah, how-- it's like, it's kind of ridiculous, awesome, but dangerous, but also entertaining to see.
Rym: It is, like, as whatever you think this looks like, if you have never seen a picture of this-- It just looks like a fire.
Rym: It looks-- it looks like a nuke is going off, like, in the distance.
Rym: It is amazing to behold.
Rym: And the best part is, you see the crowd, if you watch this video, go from excited to worried to debating leaving to excited again, because it doesn't even last that long.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We're talking 35 seconds.
Scott: You know, the finale of a fireworks show, they tend to, you know, they set off a lot of fireworks, right?
Scott: It's like a big ending, and it's always sort of the same, because fireworks artists, right, you know, people who figured this out, is like, they realize that's about the limit to where, like, if you set off more fireworks than that at once, it's really not enjoyable anymore.
Rym: The fancy fireworks, the Macy's ones we just watched, of course, the finale will do layers where, like, there's a low ground effect finale, and then a higher finale, and then an even higher finale to avoid that problem.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's only so many guitars you can have until such a point where it's just this solid noise, and it, you know, there's nothing to it.
Rym: You can only have so many backup singers screaming everything louder than everything else behind Meat Loaf.
Scott: Yeah, it's like some people, you know, there is a time and a place for that.
Scott: just a wall of noise nonsense, but if you actually are trying to create something discernible, then there's a limit to how much you can fill, right?
Rym: All right, so what do you got?
Scott: So, if you don't want to set off a whole bunch of fireworks really rapidly, because there's a limit to that, why not just set off one firework that's really, really big?
Scott: The biggest ever, in fact, apparently- Sixty-two inches?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Holy shit!
Scott: If you're ever asking yourself, "What is the world's record for largest single
Scott: firework?".
Scott: Here it is in Colorado.
Scott: They made the world's largest single firework.
Scott: They fired it up into the air.
Scott: It exploded really big.
Scott: Boom!
Scott: It's a pretty standard firework.
Scott: Uh, someone in the comments did a fuck ton of math accounting for, I don't know if their math is right- I mean, the first comment is, and I quote, "Everyone gangsta till a mushroom cloud
Scott: farms.".
Scott: Yeah, but there's a comment on the YouTube comments.
Scott: I don't know if it's true, but, you know, it could be true.
Scott: They claim to have accounted for, like, the air pressure, the elevation, the temperature, et cetera, and thus figured out how high it went, how big the explosion was, et cetera, et cetera.
Rym: That seems plausible.
Scott: Yeah, it's definitely, you know, math that could be done.
Rym: So here's a question I have for you.
Rym: Why doesn't the Tsar Bomba count as the biggest firework?
Rym: What's the difference between a firework and a bomb?
Scott: A bomb is not a firework.
Rym: But what's the difference?
Rym: Because the bomb, they didn't bomb anything in particular, they just blew it up to look at it, basically.
Rym: Like a firework.
Scott: A firework scatters, you know, like, you know, fizzle materials, right, around, and then- So does it nuke!
Scott: And then those set on fire and create light.
Scott: A bomb, you know, it basically scatters force.
Rym: But a nuclear bomb also scatters a big light show.
Scott: But it's not scatter, I guess, you know, someone on the internet, there's definitely a semantic argument.
Scott: But also there is a material difference between a firework and a bomb.
Rym: I'm just saying I'd like to know what that difference is.
Rym: Either this is the biggest firework ever launched, or Tsar Bomba is the biggest firework ever launched.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: In the meta moment, the GeekNights Book Club book, which, unless something happens, we'll do the show, on Thursday this week, Nine Fox Gambit, I finished.
Scott: There's a problem in that I read this book before it was even selected as the book club book.
Scott: I had finished reading it already.
Scott: How much will I remember on Thursday?
Rym: Judeo, The Deuce of Gears, Woman Form and Man Form, Calendars, Utena Duels.
Scott: Yeah, you know, I remember plenty.
Scott: It was most memorable.
Rym: I've read the entire second book.
Rym: My Warning Stand.
Rym: Everything I've warned you about, like, just be ready for it if you keep reading.
Rym: And I'm gonna start the third book probably, like, this weekend.
Rym: Because I gotta know how this all ends.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But yeah, otherwise, we, well, GeekNights will very likely be live, maybe with Scott, more likely without Scott, with at least one panel at PAX West.
Rym: But I will not be hanging out, or I will not be hanging out at the con, really, other than that panel.
Rym: And who knows what cons we'll even be able to go to in the foreseeable future.
Rym: We'll see what happens.
Rym: It's still COVID land.
Rym: The one thing I'll tell you is that, based on looking at Twitter just now, a lot of people got COVID at Anime Expo.
Scott: So, and the evidence is that the-- I'm not paying attention at all to Anime Expo.
Rym: Anime Expo, well, it's funny, because on one hand, Anime Expo was a, as far as I can tell, a shit show.
Rym: Like, it was just run like crap.
Rym: But that's not news.
Rym: Every Anime Expo is like, it's always been like that.
Rym: Before COVID, it was like that.
Rym: But there are a lot of people claiming that they tested positive shortly after Anime Expo having gone to it.
Rym: And I would believe it based on the terrifying, unmasked crowds that I saw in those images.
Rym: So yeah, be judicious.
Rym: I would suggest avoiding cons, even if they're masked, even if they require vaccines, for at least the near term.
Rym: Because it looks like the BA5 variant of Omicron, COVID, is spreading through the US like ridiculous wildfire.
Rym: And people are just dropping--.
Rym: people are coming down with this like crazy.
Rym: So stay safe out there.
Rym: And cons, at least for the next several weeks, seem like a terrible idea.
Rym: So we're not talking about, like, streaming your game on Twitch or YouTube or whatever.
Rym: We're talking about that game streaming on a high level-- and there's a lot of directions we can take this.
Rym: We might even do some other shows that zoom in on some aspects of this.
Rym: When the game you are playing is running on some hardware, somewhere, and you are playing that game on a different device.
Scott: So this could be-- Or at least the input and output devices for the game, whether they're a monitor, a gamepad, whatever, are not directly connected to the computer that is running the game software.
Scott: There is some sort of network wired or wireless link in between, as opposed to a direct USB sort of link between the inputs and outputs and the computer that is running and rendering the frames of the game.
Rym: And this is a concept that-- it's interesting, in computing, this is actually how basically all computers worked for a very long time.
Rym: Nobody had a computer at their desk.
Rym: They had a completely stupid terminal at their desk that was basically just a controller that was connected via a very long, effectively like serial cable to the actual-- Or a telephone cable depending, you know.
Rym: To the actual computer that was sitting somewhere else and running everything for everybody.
Rym: And that's how all early computer games worked.
Rym: There weren't computers you could run games on.
Scott: Other oscilloscope games I think were-- Is an oscilloscope a computer?
Scott: We're not going to talk about that now.
Scott: The point is, computers started out that way.
Scott: Then we had the personal computer where you actually had a small enough computer that you had one all to yourself.
Scott: And then after that, when networking started to pick up, we got the idea that there would be this thin client.
Scott: That like, well, what if we got one really big supercomputer?
Scott: And that way we didn't have to make so many of these personal computers that just sit around doing nothing most of the time.
Scott: We could give everybody their own really cheap computer with a really fast network connection.
Scott: And the big computer will do all the work, right?
Scott: And the little tiny computer that everyone has will just sort of receive and send over the network.
Scott: And what we've arrived at in reality is some sort of combination of the two ideas, right?
Scott: We have this.
Scott: cloud computing is huge.
Scott: We have these massive computer warehouse places where there's shit tons of computers doing all kinds of work.
Scott: Right?
Scott: And meanwhile, everyone has devices that often are just input and output, right?
Scott: You do some hello Siri and it sends your voice to Amazon.
Scott: It processes and gets you your answers and then the answers come back.
Scott: If you don't have internet connection, it ain't gonna work.
Scott: Siri is somewhere else, right?
Scott: You're effectively doing that when you say hello Siri or whoever, hello Apple, Google, same shit, right?
Scott: Visit a website.
Scott: All the website shit's happening somewhere else, not on your computer, right?
Scott: Your computer's just inputting and outputting.
Scott: But your computer, your phone, your tablet, whatever is still really powerful because we still do some stuff locally, mainly gaming, right?
Scott: The idea of doing this network thin client streaming of games is an old idea.
Scott: I remember hearing about it as early as like even the late 90s because game companies, game publishers, software companies in general wanted to do this, but game one specifically to get away from piracy, right?
Scott: They're like, well, if we don't give you the game, there's no way you can pirate it, right?
Scott: It's the game.
Scott: There's one copy of it.
Scott: It runs on our computer.
Scott: We can charge you money for it and you can't have it.
Scott: You can't modify it, whatever, right?
Scott: And so as gamers, we didn't like that idea.
Scott: We didn't like that idea because A, we wanted to pirate games.
Scott: That was one major reason.
Scott: We like pirating, right?
Scott: We didn't have a lot of money.
Scott: We were kids.
Scott: We wanted to play games.
Scott: We had time.
Scott: We didn't have money.
Scott: So we didn't like that.
Scott: We also didn't like that.
Scott: Like, hey, well, this means how am I going to mod my games, right?
Scott: How am I going to preserve backups of my games?
Scott: If I pay for the game and you shut down, like we just talked about in the news, how am I going to keep playing the game?
Scott: Um, you know, what if you change the game tribes too, right?
Scott: And I don't like what you changed.
Scott: Now I can't play the old version of the game.
Scott: You know, what if we, what if I lose my internet connection?
Scott: I can't play the game now, right?
Scott: What if I have a LAN party, right?
Scott: It's like, how many copies of the game do I got to buy?
Scott: Everyone's got to pay you, you know?
Rym: So this idea sort of came and went and for a long time, every time this idea came, it was basically impractical and it wasn't time for it.
Rym: They were all sort of failures, bad ideas, done for the wrong reasons.
Rym: But now in the current era, because we're going to talk about the current state of things a little bit, we have bandwidth, we have devices, like smartphones are extremely powerful.
Rym: The ecosystem is so different now to where a bunch of forms of this are perfectly viable today.
Rym: But also at the same time, companies keep trying to do some forms of this that even if they are plausible and viable, are still just failing, which I find funny.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So the biggest failure, right, was Google Stadia.
Scott: We've talked about it probably when it was new and we ignored it because it's not worth talking about.
Rym: I found a news from February 4th, 2022, which I queued up.
Scott: Only five months ago.
Rym: Yeah, that basically said, according to Business Insider, Google's planning to salvage the Stadia technology and is looking for someone to buy it and or license it or use it for their own purposes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the problem with Google Stadia is that the way it works is that the games are running on Google's computers, right?
Scott: And your computer, it streams you the video of the game, right?
Scott: So as long as your computer can stream 1080p video, you can see the game, right?
Scott: It's no different than watching a 1080p stream on Netflix or anything else, right?
Scott: And all you have to send to Google is the inputs from your gamepad.
Scott: And there'll be some latency, obviously, but hopefully not much if your network connection is good, especially if it's wired.
Rym: But that's a load-bearing thing you just said.
Rym: A big problem with Stadia and with a lot of these services, even the in-house ones, we'll talk about like Steam Link in a minute.
Rym: Most people don't have, like internet got worse inside of most people's houses.
Rym: We hit broadband, everyone had wired internet.
Rym: that was super fast.
Scott: Now we have even faster internet, but the vast majority of people- We're living in Fios, so you got to remember a lot of people are living in places with not as good internet connection as we have in our Fios.
Rym: But even worse, even people with good internet, most people's in-house internet is Wi-Fi and Stadia and things like it often do not work well over Wi-Fi.
Scott: Yeah, well, I mean, the newer Wi-Fis, the Wi-Fi 6s and whatnot, you get the good routers and the good radios.
Scott: It is significantly improved.
Scott: There is a dramatic difference, but latency is still a thing.
Scott: But the latency only really matters for some games in some scenarios, right?
Scott: Even if you're playing a single-player FPS with ridiculous graphics, let's say Doom Eternal, right?
Scott: It's like single-player, that latency from that, assuming your bandwidth is good, it's not gonna be an issue, right, for normal play.
Scott: It's only the latency is at the point where it's only an issue if, A, you've already got a network deficiency of some kind, right, or processing deficiency of some kind, or B, the game you're playing is a really tight, really real-time game, a fighting game, a multiplayer FPS, a competitive e-sport with a real-time component, right?
Scott: A lot of games don't even have any real-time component at all.
Scott: They're like a turn-based game.
Scott: Civilization, you could just play Civilization Stream.
Scott: What does it matter?
Scott: It's like, it probably worked better.
Rym: I mean, I've often played games like Hearts of Iron, like all those simulation games on my laptop in the other room, streaming with Steam Link from my desktop right here.
Scott: Yep, so Stadia, technologically, the streaming of the games was fine.
Scott: What wasn't fine was the way they tried to sell it, which is like you had to still buy the games.
Scott: It's like you would get Stadia, and I know people who had Stadia from getting a free trial, and they had the free trial, the free trial ran out, and then they stopped, right?
Rym: I don't think I've ever met anyone who paid for Stadia.
Scott: Me either, but it's like you have Stadia.
Scott: Let's say you want to play a game, GameX.
Scott: You only had to buy GameX, like.
Scott: the same way you buy it on Steam.
Scott: I don't know if the price was reduced, but you never actually get to download GameX.
Scott: You're just buying the right to stream GameX all you want, and it added to your Stadia library, and it's like, that's not gonna fly, right?
Scott: No one's gonna do that, because they could just buy GameX on Steam.
Scott: It's like, why would you do that?
Scott: That makes no sense, right?
Rym: It was interesting, because this is a problem where the technology was adequate for the use case, but no one was interested in how that was monetized or how it was delivered.
Scott: It could make sense for somebody who has enough computing horsepower to stream 1080p or 4K video, but does not have a video card advanced enough to render 60 FPS of full frames, because decoding video frames that are already rendered is less computationally intensive than actually rendering frames in real time with a GPU.
Scott: You don't want to spend $800 for a 3080.
Scott: If someone else has a 3080, and you're basically just renting it, it's like, that might not be a bad deal, you know, just considering the scenario.
Rym: But it would assume that you don't need that 3080 for anything else.
Rym: Every game you want to play is on Stadia.
Rym: If there's even one game you want to play that's not on Stadia.
Rym: that needs a good video card, you had to buy the video card anyway.
Rym: And that's where I think Stadia really failed in the end, was that the majority of the addressable market of a product like Stadia, when it came out, were people who played games already, and thus either already had a gaming console or already had a gaming PC.
Scott: Or both.
Rym: Yeah, likely both.
Scott: Which all had GPUs in them, right?
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: If somehow the GPU shortage carried on, or the GPU factories exploded, and now we would centralize the GPUs into one place, but maybe not everyone should have a GPU.
Scott: We could talk about that, how it's sort of wasteful.
Scott: People have these powerful, powerful things.
Scott: They're actually really inefficient processors that use lots and lots of electricity, right?
Scott: And people have them just sitting in their computers, we manufactured that, which caused climate damage, and it's like, there's a lot to talk about there.
Rym: We could also point out, there's a side argument that we hit a point where from the 1080 onward, a 1080, even today, is good enough to play literally almost every PC game on Earth.
Scott: I got a 1070, and I've never found a game that I can't play perfectly.
Rym: Yeah, you might not use the most ridiculous render settings 4K 60 FPS launch.
Scott: I usually put it on 4K full settings.
Scott: You say that, but what game?
Rym: Name a game that you've run at full, maximum, absolute maximum quality that can be set, 4K 60.
Scott: Let's see, let's go down the list.
Rym: 'Cause I can do that with Overwatch with a 1080.
Rym: That is the most GPU-intensive game that I can do that with, with a 1080.
Scott: I mean, I haven't played that many--.
Rym: Well, I'm saying this is you don't play games that push the GPUs.
Rym: I know what games you play.
Scott: But I do occasionally.
Scott: I've played a bunch of Resident Evil games.
Scott: We played PUBG that one time recently for like an hour.
Rym: You did not turn PUBG to maximum render.
Scott: Yeah, I did.
Rym: Maximum every setting?
Scott: Well, my monitor's 4K, so I put it in 4K, and then I maxed everything else out.
Rym: 16 X MSAA?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: There's a maximum thing.
Scott: I'm not picking through the settings.
Scott: I don't got time for that.
Rym: I'm just saying.
Scott: You're not even gonna notice.
Rym: The real point is that most people who are gamers, who play PC games, have a GPU already, and even if you have a pretty old GPU, it is good enough for 99% of all PC games that have ever been made.
Rym: In fact, my HTPC, which I'm gonna replace soon, it is-- Mine's got a 1050.
Scott: It's good forever.
Rym: Mine is a core-- It's a fifth generation i3.
Scott: Mine's an i3.
Scott: I don't know what generation, though.
Rym: It's got a GTX 450 M in it.
Scott: All right, that's pretty old.
Rym: It can still play a lot of the Steam games that I would play in the living room, and you know what it can do perfectly?
Rym: Steam link to my desktop right here.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So when I build a new HTPC, I'm not putting a GPU in it.
Rym: I'm just gonna get an Intel CPU, because I know those can output 4K 30 to a TV.
Rym: That's all I need.
Rym: I'm good to go.
Scott: There's an argument to be made, actually, for doing the opposite.
Scott: It's where put the massive video card in the HTPC.
Scott: Now, when you play games on the monitor with your gamepad and you're having a party, it's gonna be-- And then the rest of your devices in your house, especially if you're an Apple person, you can get all Macs, which can't play games.
Rym: Two problems with that.
Rym: I want an HTPC that's so tiny, I literally tape it to the back of the TV that's mounted on the wall.
Scott: I mean, you can do that too, right?
Rym: Two, a good video card is loud as shit.
Scott: Only when it's doing its 3D biz.
Rym: And three, that's not gonna work for Premiere.
Rym: There's no Steam link to make Premiere work on my workstation.
Scott: But I'm saying, if you're an Apple person, the Apple chip can handle Premiere.
Scott: The only reason the Apple computers can't play games is because the games weren't made for them.
Scott: But Premiere is made--.
Scott: Pretty much everything other than games is already natively running on the M chips out there.
Scott: All your Adobe's and everything.
Scott: So it's an option for Apple people to get one Nvidia GPU, basically, put it in a box in the house somewhere, and just use Steam link to stream from it to whatever computer or iPad or iPhone you want to actually play games on.
Rym: But basically, right now, today, there's sort of two options for this.
Rym: Because arguably, a lot of consoles, they're running the game locally, but they are tied to or restricted in some way based on computers somewhere else.
Rym: But that's sort of a separate problem.
Rym: But we basically either have, you have a device that streams from the cloud in some fashion, or you have a gaming PC, and you're using something like Steam link to stream within your house.
Scott: Those are sort of the two-- - You can use Steam link from outside your house.
Scott: It works for games that aren't so intensive, obviously.
Rym: - It requires a little bit of a moderate amount of knowledge to set that up so it'll actually work.
Scott: - Not really.
Scott: You just open up the Steam app on your phone and it connects.
Rym: That is, I have encountered people we know who struggled with that profoundly.
Scott: - All right, well, I mean, the point is, it's a really good option, I think, for not the 3D games, right?
Scott: - Yeah.
Scott: - But like the turn-based type games or the much simpler games.
Rym: - Like, look, I can use Steam link and take a sieve turn my fucking iPhone.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: It works.
Scott: - I mean, they do have sieve for iOS.
Scott: It is direct.
Scott: They do have a direct version.
Rym: - There's no sieve for iOS.
Rym: that'll run on my iPhone natively.
Scott: - I think there is.
Rym: - I don't think it runs on the iPhone.
Scott: Is it iPad only?
Rym: - I'm pretty sure it's iPad only.
Scott: - It might be iPad only, but it exists.
Rym: - Also, even if it ran on the iPhone, wouldn't I have to pay for it?
Scott: - Yeah, that is one, Civilization specifically, they fucked it up and you have to buy the game like twice.
Scott: But basically, I still think-- - Other games that might not be the issue.
Rym: - Services that stream the games like Stadia did aren't really, like, it'll be hard for them to succeed at scale.
Rym: And I think it's the same problem that happened the last, every time someone's tried this.
Rym: One, the average gamer who cares enough about gaming to be playing PC games already and doesn't just have-- - To buy a subscription or pay for some gaming service.
Rym: - Yeah, they do not trust services like that.
Rym: Like, the only reason we trust Steam is that it's been around so long and hasn't fucked us.
Rym: Nobody trusts anything else.
Scott: - Right, now, so there are some scenarios where I think this is gonna work out.
Scott: One scenario where it's already working out is the Xbox Game Pass thing.
Scott: The Xbox Game Pass, I tried to use it once and it didn't work.
Scott: But I have friends who use it and it is kind of a good deal.
Scott: It's like, you pay a subscription and it's sort of like Netflix.
Scott: It's like, there's a lot of fucking games on there that you get for a small price, right?
Scott: Some of them might come and some of them might go, but it's like, you just get access to this enormous game library.
Scott: If you're not someone who has an enormous Steam library, it just makes economic sense to get the Xbox Game Pass, get all those fucking games, you know, you can probably beat them in the time that they're on there.
Scott: If you're actually playing lots of games, just like, you know, I canceled Netflix and all the other streaming services 'cause I wasn't watching anything.
Scott: But if you're actually playing lots of games and you get that subscription, you're gonna get value from it.
Rym: - If that Xbox service existed when we were at RIT.
Scott: - Yeah, it'd be so, you know, I wouldn't have had a pirate games.
Scott: It would be just so many games.
Scott: I'd be like, I can just play that game came out.
Scott: I can just play it right now without paying 60 bucks.
Rym: - And I think that is going to be the evolution of consoles.
Rym: I think consoles are basically just purpose-built PCs effectively that will run local games, but also integrate directly and seamlessly with the streaming platform that the company like Microsoft will run for it.
Rym: And I think that's gonna be a big part of the gaming ecosystem.
Rym: I don't think those services will capture PC gamers though, because they will never have the coverage.
Rym: I think PC gamers are primarily going to continue to be a relatively niche audience.
Rym: And I think they're gonna run games locally or they're going to stream games from some other local device they own.
Scott: - Well, you got to run PC gamers also, you know, include all the people who like to, you know, go on itch IO and install all kinds of weird games and emulate things.
Rym: - Things that aren't on services.
Rym: Stadia is not gonna have like quest for glory 2 on it.
Rym: You're buying that from GOG.
Scott: - It could be, you know, but you never know.
Scott: But you know, but most people are just playing like the games that come out, right?
Scott: And so, you know, the consoles, the PlayStations, those actually don't really make money, the hardware.
Scott: They've always, you know, had a razor blade kind of business model from what I've heard, right?
Scott: Where they make their money selling the games and the accessories and all those things.
Scott: And the console is just like this loss leader to get you into the ecosystem.
Scott: And if they can do away with the console and sell you just something really cheap, that's just a video out and a network hole or build it into a TV, right?
Scott: Like no more PlayStations, you just buy a PlayStation television, a television that has PlayStation and you buy the subscription to PlayStation that you're just always paying for.
Scott: And now you've got PlayStation games all the time.
Scott: It's like, that's gonna make them more money, I think, if they can get people to sign up for that.
Scott: So the last, did you disappear?
Scott: - I'm here.
Scott: - Oh, okay.
Rym: - I just didn't say anything for a second.
Scott: The last streaming game situation is also something Steam has done, which is the Steam play together deal.
Rym: - Which is I think an under known and under appreciated feature.
Rym: If you don't know what this is and aren't using it, you're missing out.
Scott: - Right, so the way it works is this, right?
Scott: So I buy a game and this game that I buy has local multiplayer, either co-op or competitive, but local multiplayer, couch multiplayer.
Scott: But I'm alone at home because as a pandoodle, right?
Scott: And no one is here to play games with me.
Scott: And my friend is at home and I paid 40 bucks for this game.
Scott: And my friend doesn't wanna pay 40 bucks, which would then allow us to play network multiplayer.
Scott: Normally both people had to buy Counter-Strike and then you play Counter-Strike together.
Scott: You can't, the way this works, as long as the game is a couch co-op game, well, we don't really need two copies.
Scott: then, do we?
Scott: Right, let's say it's, I don't know, Goldeneye.
Rym: - We just need to get all the inputs from all the players into the game and get the shared single video output, basically multicast to all the people who are trying to play the game.
Scott: - Exactly, so I boot up the game on my computer and effectively it uses the same streaming that Steam Link uses to show whatever's on my screen to my friend, Rym.
Scott: Now Rym sees the game and I see the game, even though my computer is doing all the work, Rym's computer is just playing video.
Scott: My computer is being a Netflix with one customer, basically.
Scott: And Rym's game pad, all his inputs from his game pad, his computer is sending them to my computer.
Scott: and my computer thinks two game pads are plugged in, even though one of them is very far away over the network and the other one is directly plugged in by USB.
Scott: and now we're playing couch multiplayer co-op or competitive games, even though there's only one video card that has any power to it, right?
Rym: - Now some games will get into weird states and not work that well if you have more than two players, but by and large, it does just work and that alone is extremely impressive.
Scott: - Especially if your computers are powerful, if your network is good and your computer is powerful enough, at least, right?
Scott: Then like I played Streets of Rage 4 co-op this way and you wouldn't know it wasn't local.
Scott: I challenge anyone if I set up two computers, you wouldn't know which one was the one running it natively.
Scott: How would you tell, right?
Scott: Like it would be some audio file, just 50/50 shot, right?
Scott: Guessing which one was the one that was native.
Scott: Some other games you might be able to tell because if the resolution is too high and the network quality isn't perfect, it'll start to like, you'll see the resolution will sort of get a little pixely and such to maintain the frame rate, but it's really amazing and useful technology and it's like, yeah, that's actually a good reason for streaming games.
Scott: And the final reason for streaming games, right?
Scott: That sadly, I think is sort of incompatible with the reasons that no one would stream games is that you can prevent cheating that way.
Scott: If the game is running on some other computer that's under no control of the players, no one can cheat.
Scott: How are you gonna cheat?
Scott: You'd have to hack into the central system to cheat.
Scott: It's not gonna happen, right?
Scott: You might be able to cheat with like a Quake playing robot or something, but you're not gonna be able to cheat the traditional way that everyone's cheated, right?
Scott: So that can ease the developer burden a lot, not having to worry about cheaters, but any game where anyone would care about real-time cheating is a game where people are gonna care about the latency of the streaming.
Scott: And therefore now no one's gonna play it even though it's cheat proof.
Scott: because the only way the game is playable competitively in which the only time anyone cares about cheating is when it's competitive.
Scott: So if it's not competitive, who cares if you cheat?
Scott: If it is competitive, great, you stop cheating.
Scott: at what cost?
Scott: Latency, now it's unplayable competitively.
Scott: So what are you gonna do?
Scott: But that can be solved.
Scott: I think there might be a solution where like, maybe for like esports LAN parties, you have a local computer running the game and you stream it out to people on the, right?
Scott: And so now this latency is not much of an issue 'cause it's so local and so fast and yet also no cheating.
Scott: It's possible, I don't know.
Rym: So yeah, it's an interesting ecosystem and some things really haven't changed much in the last decade in this space.
Rym: And I encourage you if nothing else to try out all the ways this works in Steam because it mostly does just work and is honestly impressive.
Rym: And once I build a new HDPC and get a new TV in the other room, that's pretty much, I'm only gonna have one computer that has a video card and everything else is just gonna stream from that computer.
Scott: - I mean, as an idea that started out as completely reviling and no gamer would accept it under any circumstance has now shown that there is some merits to it that are positive for everyone.
Scott: But there are still many of the demerits turned out to also be true.
Scott: So, but it's gonna be a thing more and more, especially as the technology continues to improve making it even more feasible.
Scott: - GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: - Ervin Von Harl.
Rym: Oh, stop all the downloading.
Rym: Taylor Braun.
Rym: And I leave you tonight simply with...