Scott:
Rym: It's Thursday, November 3rd, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are talking about the Beatles' Juice.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Alright, so the chair I'm sitting in is the same chair that I bought 15 years ago.
Scott: And when we bought this chair, we talked about it on GeekNights, and Rym, at the same time, bought a different chair from the same place.
Rym: Oh my god, that episode was a long goddamn time ago.
Scott: There's a GeekNights episode in 2007 where we bought these chairs, and if 15 years of evidence isn't enough for you, right, it's like the expensive chair is clearly superior, right?
Scott: Any chair I bought prior to this chair has fallen apart, you know, it was not any good, right?
Scott: This chair has lasted 15 years, it's more comfortable, etc, etc.
Scott: The Aeron chair would have been just as good, just a different chair, right?
Scott: However, this chair, after 15 years, has broken the arm, right?
Scott: I guess I must have a habit of just leaning on the right arm, because it literally, like this plastic piece, just broke.
Scott: This is pretty thick, it's like, you know, cordless.
Rym: You know, I gotta say, actually, so both these chairs had lifetime warranties, and we did a whole episode about these chairs.
Rym: I just want to take you back to the year 2007, because I just looked in the original GeekNights forum, and the first response to the episode where we bought these fancy chairs was a name that I forgot, until just now, Killarney.
Rym: I can't believe that 220-somethings bought a chair like this.
Rym: I guess PT Barnum was right.
Rym: You mean to tell me you couldn't find a chair?
Rym: Dude is mad that we bought awesome chairs, and I gotta say, it turned out that buying the awesome chair was the right thing to do.
Rym: If both our chairs disintegrated to dust now, if you amortize how much we spent on them over the years between 2007 and 2022, this is one of the best deals in my entire life.
Scott: You know, we always say, it costs more to be poor, it's fucking bullshit.
Scott: If you don't have enough money to drop a thousand bucks on a chair all at once, or 800 all at once, then it's like, you gotta deal with shitty chairs, and over time, all those shitty chairs add up.
Rym: Remember my shitty chair at RIT where the back fell off and it smelled bad?
Rym: Right.
Scott: It's like, over 15 years of shitty chairs, you're gonna spend more than $1,000, and your body's gonna be less comfortable, and you know, whatever.
Rym: My shitty chair was $700.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, we could make another rant about gaming chairs, but the point is, this chair did break, so 15 years is how long the expensive chair lasts.
Scott: However, unlike the cheapy shitty chair, where you'd probably have to just buy a whole new chair, right, I was able to contact the company that makes this high-end chair and get some replacement arm parts, which will come in the mail eventually.
Scott: They weren't free, but apparently the chair is so old, they no longer make this specific arm, right, which has, like, pads that move a little bit left and right.
Scott: They make pads that move a little bit left and right, but they won't fit directly onto this chair, the ones that they still make, so they have, like, a retrofit kit that you can get, right?
Scott: See, this is what happens when you buy a high-end product that's, like, some share from Staples for $100 would not- this would not be an option.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Something- anything you buy on, like, Amazon with a brand name like "U-turn-it-glow-something-something" isn't even going to exist six months after you buy that thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: This company had, like, a customer support per- a real human emailed me and sent, like, an invoice and all kinds of- right, and they- they helped me out figuring out which I- what I needed to refit.
Scott: I sent them a picture and I'm like, "Can this be
Scott: fixed?".
Scott: They're like, "Yes, buy this exact part number from this cat," right?
Scott: It's like, you know, and so apparently the- the better option, or at least was to get the- if you buy a Freedom chair today, this same chair today is obviously not exactly the same as it was 15 years ago.
Scott: If you were to buy this exact model today, the newest version, the arms don't move back and forth.
Scott: They're just straight, um, but it's much cheaper to just get those.
Scott: and do I really need- they don't move back and forth that much.
Scott: It's, like, an inch in either direction.
Scott: It's, like, not a big deal.
Rym: But I- it was- it was nice, but yeah, it's not everything.
Scott: Yeah, so, uh, I ordered- they had to- I had- I couldn't just buy the one arm.
Scott: I had to buy two arms, uh, and also two pads.
Scott: I had actually replaced the- every squishy part of this chair in the past.
Scott: I replaced the arm pads, which was free a long time ago, but that wasn't broken because, uh, you know, the chair broke over time.
Scott: It's because I- I stabbed the thing accidentally.
Rym: Yeah, the only thing wrong with my Aeron chair is there's some foam bits in the lumbar support, and they are brittle to the point that if I so much as touch them, they'll crumble into dust, so I gotta replace those.
Scott: So also the- pads, the head- the squishy upholstered parts of this chair, I did pay to replace, um, because an Aeron chair is- I guess that's the one main advantage of it, is it's not upholstered.
Scott: It's just that mesh material, so if that doesn't really wear out so much, I guess if it did, it would just rip, right?
Scott: And then it'll be over.
Scott: That's the end, right?
Scott: Whereas this chair has upholstery, sort of like a car chair, only much less thick.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, the difference- the Aeron is all like that pellicle, like the- that- the only part of it that in any way could fall apart is that foam and that one bit.
Rym: Yep, so I did replace- I- I did pay to- Oh god, I just touched it, and like a big chunk of it just fell off.
Rym: I really gotta get that fixed.
Scott: Why'd you do that for?
Scott: You could buy probably a replacement pad.
Rym: Oh no, I- I already- I reached out to Aeron a while ago- I reached out- not Aeron, I reached out to the company a while ago, and they were like- Herman Miller.
Rym: Yeah, oh yeah, it's covered under warranty, that's a normal thing.
Rym: I just haven't actually like done the thing yet.
Scott: I actually do own an Aeron chair right over there that I bought.
Scott: I think I told this on the show when it happened, but you know, I was looking- when I was still working in offices, right?
Scott: I wanted to get an Aeron chair, and I was like Craigslist did, and I saw- or Facebook Marketplace, I forget which one, and some dude nearby just happened to be getting ready to move to California and had an Aeron chair of 200 bucks, and I went- I ran over there,
Rym: and I checked it out.
Scott: So my old company had- It was a real- it was a real Aeron chair, a pretty recent one, and I'm like really, 200?
Scott: And he's like yep, only 200, and I just- I'm just like BAM!
Scott: I ran out of there before he could say- or change his mind or anything.
Scott: Just like- I wheeled it down the street, I wheeled it to Manhattan, I wheeled it back, I wheeled that chair all over to make do with the $200 Aeron chair.
Rym: So my old company, you know, we moved offices, and we moved into an office that basically the company had like gone under, so it was filled with Aeron chairs.
Rym: They were just there.
Scott: I mean, when I worked in the middle of nowhere, it was a- it was a disaster recovery office that was filled with Aeron chairs.
Scott: that I think they- they got from New Orleans.
Scott: They- when they closed- when the hurricane, they closed the New Orleans office, and I think all those Aeron chairs were in the disaster recovery place that I was working.
Scott: And there were just so many of them, and it was only like two to three people working there ever.
Scott: Usually, most days, it was me only, so.
Rym: I've also seen people selling Aeron chairs that are clearly just fake knockoffs.
Rym: There's a lot of knockoff Aeron chairs.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I guess the one good news out there, if you're the kind of person who's thinking about gaming chair, if you can afford it, Herman Miller, the Aeron company, is now making gaming chairs that are also legit expensive chairs, but are also gamer styling.
Rym: They are the only company I would trust to buy a chair like that.
Scott: Yeah, so I think if this chair was actually dead, like truly dead, I was gonna go and at least sit in some of those to see how they do.
Rym: I think we've talked to those on GeekNights, but just to be clear, gamer chairs are worse quality than like a Shido Staples chair.
Rym: Like, they are not good chairs.
Scott: And they cost more.
Rym: Yeah, but they wear out just as they're not good.
Rym: They're not that comfortable.
Rym: They are bad chairs.
Scott: Yeah, so, yeah, Herman Miller has the Herman Miller X. It's actually a Logitech.
Scott: The Logitech, it's a Herman Miller Embody is a chair that they already have.
Scott: They have a Herman Miller Logitech Embody chair.
Scott: This chair is too expensive.
Scott: I would not buy the $2,200 chair.
Scott: $2,200?
Rym: Just buy an Aeron chair.
Rym: God damn.
Scott: The $1,000 chair is just fine.
Rym: You know, I still have the physical receipt from when we bought these chairs with all the like original warranty information from Sam Flax.
Scott: I don't know if that store doesn't exist anymore.
Rym: It doesn't, but I have the original piece of paper with both of our chairs and our signatures and everything.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, it's like a carbon copy.
Rym: Yeah, so in the news, of all the things that are happening in our late capitalist dystopia, this one is probably not the worst or most important thing, but it's worth calling out.
Rym: because fuck this, and I deeply, deeply hate every single human being who contributed to this event that is occurring.
Rym: It is supposedly happening today in New York.
Rym: I refuse to go see it.
Rym: I hope I don't encounter any light from it, but I'm doing the thing that we did back when we did the episode where we talked about the chairs, where we spent like 10 minutes talking about how we bought something without saying what it was that we bought to build up that moment, but not actually saying it.
Rym: So I'm doing that now again, bringing us full circle.
Rym: So New York City's skyline is going to have 500 drones in the air, I think over the East River, showing ads with lights in the sky.
Rym: They are projecting fucking advertising into the sky against New York's will.
Rym: I mean, I'm not going to say the name of the company.
Scott: Skywriting has been a thing for a long time, but skywriting.
Scott: and when you go to the beach, people fly off with, you know, the banners behind the little planes.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: This is a gigantic moving animated digital billboard lit up that you can't ignore.
Rym: New York City like deeply bans this stuff, and apparently the company that's doing it, they know this, but they don't want to advertise in New Jersey because nobody in New Jersey has any money.
Rym: So they're advertising at New York, but the drones are all taking off from New Jersey and apparently they can't come to New York, can they?
Rym: They're going to stay over the water at the midpoint between New York and New Jersey so they don't get in trouble.
Scott: I mean, technically, if one of the drones went over the line into New York, the police could shoot at them.
Rym: I would love for that to happen.
Scott: I think that I think that's true.
Scott: I think it's I think like if you fly a drone in a legal place that there is like law enforcement can shoot at me.
Scott: I heard someone said that.
Rym: I don't know about New York City, but in other cities in in America and globally, there are net guns that they use.
Rym: And I saw video in Singapore of a government drone that carries a net and is designed to capture illegally flying drones to then try to track down who flew them and deal with them.
Rym: So, yeah, according to the law, someone did the research.
Rym: This would be super illegal.
Rym: And there's a big fight over this whole thing because of the technicalities involved.
Rym: This is not the first time some company in New Jersey has tried this shit.
Rym: Apparently, many years ago, some New Jersey company had billboard boats with super bright LEDs.
Rym: They were sending up and down the East River and there were years of lawsuits until eventually they were, quote, the article run out of town by a combination of state and city lawsuits.
Rym: So, yeah, I despise this.
Rym: If you took part in this, I hate you.
Rym: Advertising has already ruined enough things.
Rym: We don't need to ruin the pleasant skyline from New York City and the quiet waterfronts that we all enjoy.
Rym: So what do you got?
Rym: Some other late capitalist hell, it looks like?
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: So if you are someone who knows anything about printing or graphic design or anything like that, you know about a company called Pantone.
Scott: And what Pantone does is they're a company that basically just does a lot of color science and color management work for you.
Scott: And if you use their system, right, you know, you pay the money.
Scott: It basically makes it really easy to pick out a color, right?
Scott: See that color on your computer and then know, because, you know, you're digitally encoding that color in your files, that when you print it, that's the color you're going to see when you print.
Scott: If you were to like, you know, and like if you're going to get, you could get some paint mixed and the paint would be exactly that color.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It's like, you know, that GeekNights' banner we made a long time ago, which after we get the new website up, gonna make new little banners to bring to cons with the new styling.
Rym: But I printed that using Pantone colors, because if I gave a file like a Photoshop file to the printer and I specified Pantone color codes in the Photoshop file, they would print exactly what I specified using specific ink.
Rym: And if they fucked it up, they would have to reprint it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So like if you were, say, a company.
Scott: And you made a new trademark logo, you know, and maybe maybe your colors are green and silver.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you're like, OK, the green for our logo is this green, this specific one.
Scott: And it's Pantone number whatever.
Scott: And now anyone who's in your huge, gigantic company.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's in some style guide somewhere.
Scott: So whether they're making a logo for a website or making T-shirts and they need to get dye the T-shirts correctly or they're printing out flyers or they're making a TV commercial or the mascot is going to have a wig.
Scott: that's the same green and silver color.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like the color can be the exact right color.
Scott: With the Pantone system.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the Pantone system isn't free.
Scott: That company's got to make money because it's it's not just like some you think why this would be a consortium.
Rym: Right.
Scott: You think why would it be something that costs?
Scott: like what work is involved?
Scott: Like, I can just pick a color.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's not that easy.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, I know.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: There is.
Rym: there is a what I know about this space.
Rym: There is a lot of work and a lot of employees involved in this.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So a lot of color science and things like that.
Scott: So I didn't realize.
Scott: this is just a side note that has nothing to do with the news story.
Scott: There's a company called X, right.
Scott: Which is a company that I knew about.
Scott: that I didn't realize.
Scott: X, right.
Scott: But Pantone, what X, right, makes is they make these little cult.
Scott: They make these color checkers, which I kind of wanted, but they're too expensive for at least my purposes.
Scott: And it's basically like these little cards that have a bunch of color swatches on them.
Scott: And if you're doing photo or video work, you can hold up this little color swatch in your video or your photo.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In in the same lighting with the same camera equipment with the same settings.
Scott: And then when you go to process your video, usually video, but could be photos, you use that little software and you say, hey, software, here's the.
Scott: here's the frame of the video where I'm holding the thing.
Scott: There's the thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Look at it.
Scott: Look at what values the camera recorded.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you know what colors those actually are, because you know what I held up the the carefully manufactured and printed object that you sold me.
Scott: So now you can calibrate my colors perfectly exactly the same every time.
Scott: And it's literally like it's not cheap.
Scott: It's like a few hundred bucks to get one of these things.
Scott: But it's like once you have it and you have the software, it's like a one click operation to get perfect color in every single video and photo ever.
Scott: So it's kind of useful.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That company bought Pantone and then another company that I've never heard of called Donahue Corporation bought X, right.
Rym: That probably explains why suddenly Pantone is all agro about stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So when did they buy Pantone?
Scott: in 2012?
Scott: So it's been a while, 10, 10 years ago anyway.
Scott: So what happened?
Scott: Well, Photoshop has had support for Pantone for a long time, which is obviously kind of a necessary thing.
Scott: If you're a professional graphic designer, Photoshop is your main deal.
Scott: You're living your life in that program and you're going to need to get the colors right.
Scott: And you're going to need some Pantone support.
Rym: And Adobe had some sort of licensing deal with Pantone, the deals of the details of which are actually hard to suss out and murky as we'll get into.
Rym: Like no one, no one knows the full story because they're everyone involved is being very quiet and there's a lot of lawyers.
Scott: The point is, up until recently, if you have if you had the real Photoshop, you could make files and in those files, you could specify, you know, I'm going to paint in this area of my image with this specific Pantone color.
Scott: And when you saved the image, if you sent it to a printer, the printer would match the color correctly because you're using the Pantone system and everything would be great.
Scott: Photoshop is or has removed this because of, I guess, fights, business fights with Pantone slash X, right?
Scott: Slash Donner.
Rym: Adobe is making accusations at them.
Rym: They're making accusations back at Adobe.
Rym: No one knows the full story.
Rym: What we do know is they are requiring using a third party.
Rym: plug in that if you have any Adobe software and you want to use Pantone, you got to pay Pantone 15 dollars a month.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So that's the new the new deal.
Scott: If you are some sort of professional and you really need to specify Pantone colors, right, and get things exactly right in that way, you're going to need to buy this plug in and pay Pantone 15 bucks a month to make Photoshop do what it used to do for zero dollars, 15 bucks a month.
Scott: I mean, if you're buying like the Photoshop Lightroom only photography package bar, that's right.
Scott: It's like that package.
Scott: Let's see, Adobe creative.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: What does that cost right now?
Rym: Is that 15 bucks a month?
Scott: I haven't looked at one.
Scott: It's 20 a month.
Scott: So it's 20 a month to get Lightroom and Photoshop in the photo package.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That includes Lightroom, Lightroom, classic and real Photoshop on desktop and iPad and a terabyte of cloud storage.
Scott: Twenty bucks a month.
Scott: So to add Pantone support a single feature, you're almost doubling the price of that creative cloud package, even if you got the full creative cloud package for fifty five dollars a month, which includes literally every Adobe thing there is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: All the Adobe software's right.
Scott: That's a twenty seven percent markup to add this single feature.
Scott: You have to pay twenty seven percent more.
Scott: Is the Pantone color system and access to it and the ability to use it worth the equivalent of one third of all the Adobe software that Adobe makes?
Rym: I would say for ninety nine percent of all users of all Adobe software, the answer is absolutely not.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if I was Pantone.
Scott: It's like, yeah, there are professionals, people out there in the industry who need this.
Scott: We're going to basically be blackmailed or whatever or extorted.
Scott: I guess extorted is the right word in paying this fee.
Scott: And there's nothing they can do about it.
Scott: Will those fifteen dollar fees per month add up to more than the money they were just getting from Adobe as like the general license deal?
Scott: That is the question.
Scott: Now, the thing is, when people are even if people in the short term pay this extortion fee right to Pantone, will they those people, I guarantee you, right, if they care about money at all and they're looking at their expenses, they're going to be looking for alternatives, any alternative they can.
Rym: Now, here's where Internet artists.
Rym: This is one of the last discourses I saw on Twitter before I stopped using it.
Rym: So it was fresh in mind.
Rym: A lot of Internet artists, the same people who say, oh, the gift is just as good as Photoshop or like they have weird ideas about alternatives to Adobe software because they don't understand like professional commercial use cases versus personal like that whole space.
Rym: I don't want to stick my hand in it.
Rym: Some of you are really already mad, but they were really misunderstanding this.
Rym: Like, you can't copyright the hex code of a color.
Rym: Like, yeah, the hex code of a color does not do what Pantone does.
Rym: Pantone is for one thing.
Rym: One hundred percent consistency.
Rym: If you are printing something, if you are not printing things and you do not paint 100 percent accurate manufacturing, yeah, like brands, commercial stuff, you really don't need this for anything else.
Rym: But worse, they were all passing around all these alternatives to Pantone.
Rym: None of those do.
Rym: Not one of them does what Pantone does.
Rym: They are just people trying to trick you into using their thing, using this Pantone thing as an excuse.
Rym: Those things will not do anything for you that regular old Photoshop color codes don't already do.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, for example, I opened up, if you go to Google and type color picker, there's a color picker that's built into Google, right?
Scott: So when I opened it, it automatically started out on this nice green color, 32A852, right?
Rym: Oh, that's not as good as 238023, but it's a good one.
Scott: It's a very nice green.
Scott: Maybe Google knows me so well, it can pick close to my favorite color just knowing, right?
Scott: Who knows how it decided which color to start on in the color picture.
Rym: Oh, it started on the same one for me.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So I could take that color and I could select that color in Photoshop and paint something and save it as a PSD, right?
Scott: And then I can go to the paint store and I could say, I would like to paint the wall of my house 32A852.
Scott: It's like, they can't.
Scott: It's like, it won't be, it's like, there's no way for them to make that exact color, right?
Scott: And even if it's like, it would be a whole process, right?
Scott: To figure out how to get that exact same color in the paint.
Rym: That is why if you were an adult and you're painting your house, you get swatches that are actual samples of what it'll look like in the real world.
Scott: Someone took the paint, painted it, dried it, right?
Scott: And vice versa, right?
Scott: Let's say I go to the hardware store and I buy a bucket of paint, you know, and it's called, you know, mauve or something.
Scott: And then I, what am I going to do?
Scott: Now I want to make, I paint a mural outside my house, right?
Scott: And now I want to on the computer, right?
Scott: In Photoshop, paint something in Photoshop, the exact same color as the paint that I just painted the wall with.
Scott: What am I going to do?
Scott: Take a photo of the wall, right?
Scott: Open it up in Photoshop.
Scott: You got, even if I get the white balance and everything exactly right, it's like, it's a lot of work to then figure out the exact text code, right?
Scott: To paint whatever that paint was that was on the wall and have it be exactly the same such that if I were to then go to a printer, right?
Scott: And print out what I painted in Photoshop and hold it up next to my mural for it to basically be perfectly camouflaged because it's the same, right?
Scott: Go ahead.
Scott: Try to do that with a hex code only, right?
Scott: And now do it for a fuck ton of colors because that's what Pantone does.
Scott: They do that for fuck tons of colors.
Scott: So what I would choose any one of the Pantone colors and avoid all of that labor.
Rym: If you are not like a super professional working with brands but you're making physical things, what you can probably do is have a relationship with the company you were printing with because what I have printed things over the years, like serious things, even though I just send them a file, I've usually gotten a proof back, I have talked to them, I have been able to like chat in a window, like they'll give me ink options.
Rym: If you know your printer and talk to them, you could probably say like, "Hey, here's the file.
Rym: By the way, we want that green to be this Pantone
Rym: color.".
Rym: Just say it out loud or put it in an email and they can probably take care of it even if Photoshop doesn't support it.
Rym: And also, I typed it into that color picker just to make sure my memory wasn't faulty.
Rym: Yeah, 238023 remains my favorite green.
Rym: Like, goddamn.
Rym: That hex code I remember to this day.
Rym: That is a good green right there.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: I bumped into this randomly.
Rym: I just bumped into this.
Rym: It's a cute channel.
Rym: It is Himari and Bear.
Rym: And they're just short little animations, like 2D animation, uh, of this girl and often also this bear.
Rym: And they are short, they're adorable, they're funny.
Rym: And what I'm linking to is titled, it's a one minute and ten second long short titled Test of Courage.
Rym: And it is a double knockout system test of courage between the girl and the bear.
Rym: that is Halloween appropriate.
Rym: It is worth watching and I'll edit that.
Rym: It is funnier than you're going to expect.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So, uh, nerds love a magic trick, right?
Scott: But we've seen so many magic tricks and especially with the Internet giving up so many secrets and being able to watch videos and slow-mo and all this stuff.
Scott: It's like, you know, it takes a pretty amazing magic trick to be worthy of thing of the day-ness, right?
Scott: So this one is you're gonna have to decide for yourself, right?
Scott: What you think about this one.
Scott: Rym thinks there's some video editing.
Rym: Well, I think there is some video editing, but I am not sure if that is germane to the physicality of the trick.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: The magician in the video is moderately famous.
Scott: There are many other videos of them doing the trick as well.
Scott: They put a stopwatch in the video to sort of make you believe it's not edited, which I just want to point out.
Rym: irrespective of this video that is trivial to do compositing with, uh, to avoid, to have a stopwatch there that's not actually there or vice versa.
Scott: Could be.
Rym: In fact, I watched the Captain Disillusion where he specifically showed exactly how to do that.
Scott: And also, the magician in the video claims that you can hire them and they will perform and request this trick and they will perform it for you live.
Rym: So I kind of want to find out how much that would cost.
Rym: Imagine if we have a party in the future.
Scott: I think it's, I think the price is really going to depend on where this guy lives, right?
Scott: He's probably in Vegas or LA or some shit where the magicians live.
Rym: If there was ever, if we were like at a convention like for GeekNights someday down the road and it was reasonably feasible and cost effective to hire this guy to like come to the convention and perform for us, I would consider paying to find out if this is a video trick or a legit trick because it would be really funny if you pay him to present it and he's like, "Yeah, it's a video trick.
Rym: Don't let out.
Rym: Here's your money back.
Rym: Haha.
Rym: Wink.".
Scott: But the, uh, the trick, uh, if it is not a video trick or even if it is, just even thinking of this trick is still, uh, quite impressive.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, I mean, and if you look at the YouTube comments, usually YouTube comments are like, "Ah, I see how you did it.
Scott: Someone down there knows
Scott: something.".
Scott: Right.
Scott: All the YouTube comments are like, "Oh, I see how they're all sarcastic.
Scott: Like I see how you did it.
Scott: Years of practice and lots of
Scott: talent.".
Scott: It's like, there's no actual answers down there because, uh, it's, it's impressive and hard to, hard to figure out how the hell he did it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I can think of, I got my vague ideas for how you would do it.
Rym: if it is not video trickery would be around either being really good at spinning a poker chip to land somewhere.
Scott: That's how I think it is.
Rym: Or having some way to, having some way to control where the poker chip will go, like a magnet thing.
Scott: We already know that people with slate of hand can control a card in a deck, right?
Rym: They can, no matter, I am confident he could wash a specific card to a specific part of the table in pretty much any circumstances.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: That's the part that's, you know, I've, I've seen magicians do that shit with cards before.
Scott: How could he spin a poker chip and get it to land in the specific spot he wants?
Scott: That's right.
Scott: That ain't easy.
Scott: Maybe he just practiced spinning poker chips a whole bunch and he can make them land where he wants them to land.
Rym: Like Juggaboo Jones with his 2d6.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I, so like I said, I, the thing I can't tell either is if the compositing like blurriness that I see is that could also be encoding artifacts because I see it in two of his videos about this, but at the same time, bad encoder settings could also cause that.
Rym: So I am ambivalent and I am unsure.
Scott: Anyway, magic trick.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: In the moment, the GeekNights book club book is a leaf.
Rym: The unseen too bad.
Scott: I can't see it.
Scott: I did update the website with the link to the book and whatnot.
Scott: I bought it.
Rym: I'm going to start reading it.
Rym: We will do the show before too long.
Rym: It's not a super long book, but it is not, it's not a binty that you're going to read in like one sitting.
Scott: No, I don't actually don't know how long it is.
Scott: Cause I have a digital version.
Scott: I didn't look how long it is.
Scott: I have not started reading it yet, but it is on my phone and my kid is a, it is a cyberpunk novel that is in some sort of a middle Eastern mythological cyberpunk setting.
Scott: And the author, you know, like I said, when I announced the book, the notable thing was that somehow this author got two of their books onto my personal book wishlist, even though I didn't know who they were and they only wrote two books.
Scott: And it's um, be a G Willow Wilson got famous, you know, inventing, you know, Ms.
Scott: Marvel, the newer Ms.
Scott: Marvel.
Scott: So, and they wrote these two books.
Scott: One of which is the first of which is a leaf, unseen.
Scott: So I'm going to read that.
Rym: I'm actually pretty excited.
Rym: Just what, what this looks like, it's about seems very much up both our alley.
Rym: Uh, and I remember we're using the new format.
Rym: So Scott picked two books and I had to pick which one of them to read.
Rym: And this is the one that spoke to me more.
Rym: I hope I was correct in that decision, but I'm probably going to read the other book anyway.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I think they're just, I don't think they're related other than having the same author.
Scott: They're just two novels.
Scott: I don't think there's a series.
Rym: I read one book by an author.
Rym: I like, I read all their books.
Rym: I read one book in a long series.
Rym: I just read all of them.
Rym: really hard to avoid that in my life.
Scott: and other book news, right?
Scott: Our previous book club book city.
Scott: We became the, at the sequel to that book.
Rym: The world we make came out like yesterday day before they uploaded a little YouTube video, like a really short thing that was like, Hey, it's out.
Rym: And you see a little technical guys coming out of Staten Island and little promo that they did.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Also the New York public library tonight, I guess if anyone is watching this live, right?
Scott: The New York public library.
Rym: There are nine people watching this live right now.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So nine people who have heard this on November 3rd, 2022.
Scott: It actually might've started already at this point.
Scott: Um, we're missing it, but that's all right.
Scott: There is a live discussion with the author and K. Jemisin and LeVar Burton at the New York public library.
Rym: That is two extremely powerful people about this book, right?
Scott: It's like a book release chat thing.
Scott: So, um, you know, and what more appropriate place the New York public library for the New York books here, right?
Rym: Oh man.
Scott: So nine people watching this, you want to, you want to leave this stream and go find that stream instead.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Nothing I either of us say at our lives will be more interesting than what those two individuals might say.
Scott: I'm hoping to find a recording and watch.
Rym: Oh otherwise in the moment, uh, you know, Scott's working on the website, uh, we'll be at PAX Unplugged doing a panel called why is this game taking four hours on Sunday?
Rym: I have made a significant update to that panel already based on Marvel snap, uh, which I think is relevant to the conversation.
Rym: Uh, otherwise we're just, you know, doing our thing, doing geek diets pretty regularly again up until the usual December hiatus, but I don't foresee any more, uh, unexpected hiatus, at least till next year sometime.
Rym: Tiny chance.
Rym: I'll have to go to Germany for a week in December, but, uh, we generally get fucked over and only do a few episodes in December.
Rym: Anyways, that wouldn't be that different from, uh, normal times also.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Last thing.
Rym: I'm not using Twitter.
Rym: Don't at me.
Rym: Like I literally do not see ats anymore at all.
Rym: Do not mistake GeekNights, things appearing on Twitter from, uh, to be me looking at Twitter in any capacity.
Rym: Only my DMS are open.
Rym: Uh, however, if you want to hang out with us, remember there is a GeekNights, discord and the GeekNights forum, and I'm making a concerted effort to replace some percentage of the time I have clawed back into my life by not looking at Twitter anymore to look at the GeekNights, discord and the GeekNights forum.
Rym: I've seen me replied a little more often than I have for the last couple of years.
Scott: Also, you know, contacting us is not hard.
Rym: We're like I'm Rym at frontrowcrew.com a pressure for like that.
Rym: That works.
Scott: YouTube, YouTube.
Scott: Does YouTube still have a DM system?
Rym: I am way more likely to read an email than any other means of contacting me, especially if you don't know me.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: But the point is, is that there's like this Reddit DMS.
Scott: You're like, you can find us.
Scott: It's not hard if you know how to internet.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: I am trying to studiously flag anything that automates tweets to not let people reply to them just in case.
Rym: I don't want like weird racist stuff to appear in the mentions, but if you still use Twitter and you see weird racist shit like attached to anything I tweet automatically, let me know.
Rym: I will go clean that up at least for a while.
Rym: We'll see how Twitter even goes anyway.
Scott: Anyway, so Beetlejuice, when we were six years old in 1988, Tim Burton, the director of movies and other creative things, right?
Scott: Infamous person.
Scott: We're not talking about, you know, his life much, but he had just become semi-famous thanks to Peewee's Big Adventure, which was already at that time as a child, one of my favorite movies ever.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: I love the shit out of Peewee.
Rym: When I was a kid, I watched the show and that movie was another situation, which is very relevant to Beetlejuice.
Rym: That's why I'm telling this anecdote.
Rym: As a kid, I did not pick up on the fact that Peewee's Big Adventure was a comedy.
Rym: I saw it as the serious movie that paired with the TV show.
Rym: that was silly because they stole his bike and he's trying to get it back and there was Large Marge and it just felt like a serious adventure if he has to get his bike back.
Scott: Yup, exactly.
Scott: So, Tim Burton, having had a success, right?
Scott: Hollywood, you know, that's how they did, especially back then.
Scott: It's still how they do.
Scott: Once a thing is a hit, they're like, okay, more of that, please.
Scott: We're not going to take risks on someone new and we already got a hit.
Scott: Let's see if they can keep making hits, right?
Scott: And they set Tim Burton loose and that was the height of Tim Burton, right?
Scott: He went off and he did some, you know, Batman '89.
Scott: He did some Nightmare Before Christmas shit.
Rym: Batman '89 is my second favorite Batman movie.
Scott: Yeah, so he just went off, right?
Scott: And, you know, Beetlejuice was like, it's like, you know, the first step was Peewee.
Scott: The second step was Beetlejuice and he was at the peak and he plateaued, but that plateau was high, right?
Scott: And he just kept cranking out the hits for a while.
Scott: And where is he now?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: What's he doing now?
Rym: Yeah, he feels like he has turned into a one-trick pony.
Scott: He's not where he was then is the point.
Rym: But regardless, I saw one of the last tweets I saw with someone saying, you know what?
Rym: It's really good that Beetlejuice got made before he encountered his current milieu.
Scott: Yeah, so Beetlejuice, this one movie, just this one comedy, you know, movie came out in 1988.
Scott: It didn't, right?
Scott: And it was just a stand, like, a standalone comedy movie that didn't have anything else really going on became, like, a big intellectual property.
Scott: Not on the Star Wars level, not on the Indiana Jones level, right?
Scott: But, like, on a somewhat surprising level.
Rym: I mean, one, it got a cartoon.
Rym: Like, weirdly, I like a pretty big cartoon.
Scott: There were cartoons, there was clothing, action figures, merchandising.
Rym: But it was also, it was one of those things that literally everyone in America knew of, had seen, and had opinions about.
Scott: Yeah, and not only did it become a thing, right, it sort of stayed a thing.
Scott: I'd say it's on maybe, like, the Robocop level, right?
Scott: That's about the level it's at.
Rym: I mean, the musical apparently is back again.
Rym: Again?
Scott: I thought it was gone.
Scott: I saw a poster in the cancel.
Scott: We'll have to look it up.
Rym: I mean, it premiered in 2018, so I'm pretty sure it came back.
Rym: Yep, it reopened at the Marquis Theater in Broadway in April of this year and is scheduled to close next year.
Rym: It is ongoing right now.
Scott: Okay, it's gonna close soon.
Rym: I've heard it's terrible, so.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: But the point is, this intellectual property of this one movie that, right, was significant enough that it became, it's still a thing, right?
Scott: And I think as long as people who are alive in 1988 are still alive, it will still be a thing, right?
Scott: I mean, you think about it, you know, that's sort of a pattern for Tim Burton besides the Batman, which is not something he made, right?
Scott: It's like Nightmare Before Christmas was just one movie.
Scott: It didn't even have a TV show as far as I know or anything else, but every single fucking Halloween, there's like half the Halloween decorations are actually Nightmare Before Christmas decorations, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, you can't, you can't escape the Jack Skellington.
Scott: He's everywhere, right?
Rym: Yep, but like Beetlejuice was, is such a good movie.
Rym: I have seen it at least a dozen times, like my family.
Scott: It's been quite a while since I've seen it, but I saw it many times.
Rym: It's one of those movies that I think I have almost memorized just from being a kid and watching it over and over again because it was in that era when I was a kid and would watch movies that I liked over and over again, but I think I know every beat of this fucking movie.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well, I mean, when I was a kid, right?
Scott: Six years old, come on, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like that movie was really, there were, you know, like a lot of it goes over your head, right?
Scott: Adult jokes and things like that.
Rym: But also it was another movie where as a kid, I saw it as a 100% straight horror movie.
Rym: It was not a comedy.
Rym: It was just scary.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Scott: But the things that, you know, really appealed to me about that movie when I was a kid were, you know, the fun parts.
Scott: And they were like, there's really just like three major fun parts of the movie, right?
Scott: Sandworm parts, right?
Scott: Dune.
Scott: I don't know if it was a Dune reference or not, but Sandworm parts.
Rym: There's no way that was not a Dune reference.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Calypso dance around the dining room table part.
Rym: My brother and I would sing that song over and over and over again.
Scott: That song, it's like the same way that Wayne's World made Bohemian Rhapsody a thing, right?
Scott: Again.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Again, if you didn't say again, that would have been a terrifying statement, but it brought it back.
Scott: But, I mean, there were a lot of people who, you know, were younger and didn't, you know, weren't there for Bohemian rap for, you know, a lot of people discovered Queen and Bohemian Rhapsody because of Wayne's World.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, I was six years old.
Scott: I didn't fucking know, right?
Scott: Anything about, you know, Calypso music or bananas, right?
Scott: When I was, it was Harry Belafonte, right?
Scott: I think, yeah.
Scott: Anyway, pretty sure that's who it is.
Scott: Anyway, but I didn't know that song until Beetlejuice came out, right?
Scott: And it's like, but now I think it was our first grade, second grade or something like that.
Scott: We were just, we were all over that song, right?
Scott: It was on repeat, thanks to that movie.
Scott: But it also, and then the third, the third fun part of the movie is the end, right?
Scott: Where Beetlejuice is like turning into all sorts of ridiculous shit, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, as a kid, you know, the wedding scene, right?
Scott: So that was very memorable.
Scott: And, you know, the earlier parts of the movie, you know, only had a few sort of really out there scenes, like, you know, when he goes to the afterlife and there's, you know, messed up shit there and whatnot, right?
Scott: You know, I guess a lot of the movie is just humans talking to each other, but the humans talking to each other, this is a confluence of, it takes place entirely in one house.
Scott: There's no scenes outside the house, really.
Rym: Well, other than the very beginning and this and the sandworms, but there is kind of outside the house kind of, it was an all star cast with fantastic writing and fantastic acting.
Rym: The humor, when it's not the crazy stuff Scott was describing, is so understated and just like, it's the exact kind of dialogue driven humor that I love.
Rym: This movie trusts the audience to get all these little jokes.
Rym: And even if you miss all of them, the movie is still enjoyable.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And that's the thing is it's not one of those movies that has a type of humor that only appeals to a certain demographic, like maybe like an Austin Powers one is like so many like, you know, penis jokes for the teenagers, right?
Scott: Or the, you know, the Adam Sandler, you know, appealing to just the kids.
Rym: This is the movie that me and my little brother, who was like four, watch with our parents and our grandparents and friends of the family.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's also a timeless humor.
Scott: It's not like celebrity jokes or jokes about the eighties or anything.
Scott: It's like, you could watch this now.
Rym: Oh, the, the villains.
Rym: And I still say the villains are that family that moved into the house, except Lydia, especially uncle Otho.
Rym: That is the same archetype of a terrible yuppie family that would work.
Scott: Those kinds of the kinds of people, those kinds of people are still a thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: They haven't changed.
Scott: Even like the same scenario, other than the technology of like, you know, old telephones and things like that and no cell phones and old CRT TVs and things like that that are in the movie.
Scott: It's a timeless movie, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, human nature and whatnot.
Rym: And then what do you got?
Rym: those got a family?
Rym: They die.
Rym: They basically go to a bureaucratic hell and become ghosts separately, dipshit, like yuppie gentrifiers by a house, like out away from the city and decide to destroy its character and make it a horrible, like white person's vision of how rich people live while making their terrible art.
Rym: They have a goth daughter who hates that shit and hates living there.
Rym: And then they hire an evil demon lawyer that even hell has kicked out and hijinks ensue.
Rym: Like, that's the movie.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, it's also sort of a, you know, like a story.
Scott: It's not a story about, you know, like divorce.
Scott: No one actually gets divorced right in this movie.
Scott: But you still, you know, you know, it's that scenario where the child, right?
Scott: Lydia, right?
Scott: Is like, you know, there's her real biological parents, right?
Scott: But she's like, actually these two ghosts who I've known for five minutes are better parents, right?
Rym: It actually is a really, it's a story to a degree about found family, but also how just because someone helped you out once does not mean they should necessarily be included in your found family.
Rym: Beetlejuice is a piece of shit and you cannot forget that.
Scott: Well, Beetlejuice is not part of the found family.
Rym: He wants to be.
Scott: No, Lydia and the two ghost people are the found family.
Rym: Yeah, Beetlejuice tries to worm his way in there though.
Scott: Right, right.
Scott: And Rym already talked about how, you know, the all-star cast of this movie, right?
Scott: Winona Ryder and whatnot, right?
Scott: But, you know, Michael Keaton, right?
Scott: This guy at this time, right?
Scott: It's like, that was like the peak of his stardom-ness, right?
Scott: He kept working with Tim Burton.
Rym: Dude plays Batman in the first serious attempt at a Batman movie since Adam West, the year after Beetlejuice, right?
Scott: So, I mean, you know, his name sort of, I guess, at least from my perspective, like, you know, kind of inspires chuckles a little bit, right?
Scott: It's like, he's not taken seriously as like, you know, some great actor, right?
Scott: But it's like, watch this movie, right?
Scott: And watch Batman.
Scott: It's like, look at the range on this guy.
Scott: It's like Michael Keaton was getting these starring roles in the late 80s, early 90s.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Mom, which a movie as a kid I love, Johnny Dangerously, right?
Scott: It's like, people might go, haha, you know, Michael Keaton, right?
Scott: And not think of him as like some high-brow Shakespearean dude, right?
Scott: But it's like, no, Michael Keaton can act really well.
Scott: It's like, he's extremely talented individual, right?
Scott: You know, I don't know.
Scott: It's like, the thing is, it's like, you know, I don't know a lot of celebrity people, right?
Scott: But I know who that is, which is rare.
Rym: That is notable that you know the name of a celebrity and know more than like one thing about them.
Scott: Well, it's like, I know the movies that he was in that I saw, right?
Scott: And I knew that he was good in those movies.
Scott: And, you know, I know, at least I think I know what people think of him, but I don't know anything about like his life or what he's doing now or what kind of person he is or anything like that.
Scott: You know, he might, I don't know.
Rym: What's he doing nowadays?
Scott: Sleeping?
Scott: Working?
Rym: He's working.
Rym: He's in a bunch of stuff.
Rym: All right.
Rym: He's also done voice acting.
Rym: Like, he does a lot.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, it's like, you know, people look at like, you know, the kind of movie he's in, right?
Scott: Like, you know, we mentioned a Mr.
Scott: Mom or a Beetlejuice.
Rym: You don't know Mr.
Rym: Mom?
Scott: I know what it is.
Rym: Okay, just making sure, because that movie, no one younger than us has ever heard of that movie.
Rym: Right.
Scott: I'm just pointing out that it's not like some highbrow kind of role, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So it's like, you know, because he's not in like some serious Oscar-winning type roles, right?
Scott: You know, you sort of, you know, he's not treated, you know, as a serious type, but it's like, look at it.
Scott: It's like, let's see you go act like Beetlejuice, right?
Scott: It's like, if someone else was the Beetlejuice, right?
Scott: You would be like, ah, not as good as the original.
Scott: It's like, yeah, of course, right?
Scott: It's really hard to do that.
Rym: But I guess, let's see, well, like the things Beetlejuice, what it got right?
Rym: is it like sort of juxtaposed this ridiculous scenery.
Rym: Like, you got to talk about the sets in this movie feel like a like a stage play.
Rym: Everything's exaggerated and tall and gothic and weird and looming.
Rym: Not just the hell world, but like the yuppies are making their own hell world with this house, right?
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, it's, that's the Tim Burton, right?
Scott: It's like, so Tim, prior to this, you know, the Peewee's Big Adventure, right?
Scott: You know, it had, you know, the Tim Burton sort of pacing and structure, right?
Scott: But it didn't have the visual aesthetic of Tim Burton, which I've been to a Tim Burton museum exhibit.
Scott: And it's like.
Scott: that aesthetic did exist prior to that, but it wasn't really in Peewee's Big Adventure that much, right?
Scott: It was subtle, right?
Scott: But here he was finally able to take like his personal, you know, like the kinds of things that he was drawing or doing on his own, his own personal aesthetic and put it right onto the Hollywood big screen, right?
Scott: And when it succeeded with Beetlejuice, he was able to then sort of, you know, he then had the permission to just keep doing that.
Scott: And that's when you started seeing, you know, the Edward Scissorhands.
Scott: and it's like, you put the Edward Scissorhands, you know, just, you could take still frames from that and put it up next to Beetlejuice.
Scott: And even somebody who didn't know who Tim Burton was would think that those are like in the same movie or paintings by the same artist or whatever, right?
Scott: Because he established his aesthetic with the public and then carried it forward from there, right?
Scott: But Beetlejuice was the first one.
Scott: That's where he, it wasn't the first one that was in that style.
Scott: It was the first one in that style from him with the public, people seeing it, identifying him with that.
Rym: And you definitely got this parallelism in the movie of like.
Rym: the set in the real world is becoming increasingly nightmarish in parallel with seeing the literal hellish afterlife in like the, like the, like the literal afterlife, that book and everything.
Scott: And at the very end of the movie, spoilers, right?
Scott: They set the house back to normal.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And you'll have that like ridiculous nonsense juxtaposed with like really meek one-liners and like totally mundane conversations among regular people.
Rym: As a kid, I wasn't afraid of Beetlejuice.
Rym: I was afraid of Uncle Otho.
Rym: He actually was the one who I was scared of as a kid.
Scott: I don't know if I was scared of any individual character.
Rym: Someone like Otho would scare me today, but for very different reasons.
Scott: But, well, yeah, but I mean, I think I was just scared of the, the situation, right?
Rym: You know, weirdly as a kid, cause I was into ghosts.
Rym: I was, I was excited about the situation.
Rym: Beetlejuice seemed like a cool demon to make a deal with if you were careful about it.
Rym: And like, they kind of messed that up.
Rym: Like I basically saw everything is cool.
Rym: And Uncle Otho was like the evil guy who is using this power for the wrong purposes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I think the last thing, you know, about the movie specifically is that, you know, in terms of, I guess, representation of a teenager with a, you know, a goth aesthetic, right.
Scott: On the Hollywood screen, right.
Scott: It's like prior to that, you know, any sort of goth kids were, you know, put, you know, in, in TV or movies were showed as like, you know, bad delinquent outcast type kids.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Lydia's just cool.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's the clothing, the dark makeup, et cetera.
Scott: And sort of the teenage attitude.
Scott: But she's the only one with like, you know, a decent head on her shoulders in like the whole fricking movie.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Because the ghosts don't know what's going on.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Dipshit.
Scott: The whole fact that the nice, the nice, the nice ghost people, the, you know, the, the people who become better parents, even though they're dead.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, they're clueless though.
Scott: And, and meek.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Beetlejuice is just bad.
Scott: Her at her biological family is awful.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And she's like the only common sense person.
Scott: But yet, uh, you know, these other people, right.
Scott: Or like wearing more normal type clothing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or at least somewhat more normal.
Rym: They're the real monsters.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, whereas she, who has, you know, the, the visual aesthetic of being some, you know, goth type outsider actually is the most normal put together human being or person or ghost or monster, whatever in the whole, the whole show.
Rym: So, which makes it extra weird when they made a hundred episode long Beetlejuice animated TV series that was wildly popular.
Rym: But in that one, Beetlejuice is a protagonist and has given Lydia powers and they go on adventures in hell.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So basically what goes on in that cartoon, which I, I never, I didn't watch it a bunch, but I watched like the entire, I know how to watch the whole thing, but it's not that good.
Rym: It is not worth watching to a modern.
Scott: It wasn't one that I turned on on purpose, right?
Scott: Where like, Ooh, it's on, let's go watch it.
Scott: It was one where if it was on before or after or happened to be on, or I flipped through the channels and there it was, I'd watch it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was that level, but yeah, it's like, they're like, Hey, the kids love that Beetlejuice movie.
Scott: But there's no other stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, we're not going to make a live action TV show.
Scott: That's too expensive for 1988.
Scott: Tim Burton's busy making a Batman.
Scott: We can't get him to do anything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But this is somehow popular with the kids, even though it was a movie with like, you know, strip club jokes.
Rym: It's funny.
Rym: somehow popular with the kids was definitely a thing through like the mid eighties, like lady, like 82, 83 through like 91.
Rym: There were a lot of things that the whole world was like, wait, why do kids even know what Robocop is?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I guess we got to make a Robocop cartoon, which I mean, I think that was, you know, I think, you know, we could talk about how.
Scott: maybe a joke, Joe camel, right.
Scott: But it was perhaps intentional on the parts of some corporate overlords in those times.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But anyway, uh, you know, so they made this animated show.
Scott: I don't, I'm sure I could Google and find out the history of who pitched it and how it was made and why it was made, but it lasted a long time.
Scott: There are a lot of episodes and it's not good.
Scott: I mean, I think it's, you know, I don't have to watch it in a long time, so I don't know.
Rym: Well, even as a kid, it felt like a cynical catch grab because they added all these extra characters who were completely one note.
Rym: And it was just, it was like this episodic nothing show with like one liner jokes and bad voice acting.
Scott: It was definitely this kind of thing where if you're a kid, even as a kid who is six, seven, eight years old, right?
Scott: Less than 10.
Scott: It's like you saw the real Beetlejuice movie and you watch that and you liked it and you're turn on this cartoon and you're upset because even a kid, right?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: The adults underestimate the kids.
Scott: Even a kid can tell that that is not, that's not right.
Scott: Beetlejuice is the wrong voice, right?
Scott: That's not him.
Scott: That's not how he acts.
Scott: They're living in the house somehow, right?
Scott: But they don't really spend any time in the house.
Scott: It's like every episode.
Scott: they go to the hell world, which is nothing like the hell world in the movie at all.
Scott: It's like some big, like, you know, open terrain that has a circus tent or like some houses and other.
Rym: It felt hollow like the Mario Brothers cartoons felt hollow and that they were like, they had the barest surface details and that was it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it's like there was some interesting designs for some of the monster characters that were, you know, living in the hell world.
Scott: Like wasn't there a guy who was like just legs or something?
Scott: You know what?
Rym: A lot of them were a lot like the Ghostbusters monsters from the Ghostbusters cartoon.
Rym: And there was a French skeleton guy that had like terrible jokes, but he was a funny.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: The French skeleton.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's coming back now.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I forgot about him.
Rym: But, uh, it was just as a kid, it was weird to me, but my little kid head cannon was, I guess Lydia, like, Oh, there was the cowboy guy.
Scott: He wasn't just legs.
Scott: He was like a rip up of the Looney Tunes red guy.
Rym: I just kind of assumed that Lydia like learned dark magic and I don't know, castrated or lobotomized Beetlejuice.
Rym: And like that was just like, he was just this demon at under her control now.
Rym: Like that's kind of how I saw it because that Beetlejuice is nothing like the absolute piece of shit that is Beetlejuice in Beetlejuice.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, you know, he wasn't in the cartoon and he wasn't like, you know, in the movie he was a bad guy.
Scott: He was up to no good, right?
Scott: In the cartoon, he's like slightly mischievous and naughty, but he is clearly a good guy.
Scott: A hundred percent on Lydia's side, right?
Scott: You know, they're, they're together in conflicts on the same team, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Not like the movie where he was a predator worming his way into her life against her will.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Completely different.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So then there was a musical that I haven't seen and know nothing about.
Rym: So I'm going to read, cause I read a little bit about it.
Rym: and Oh, there was a review that said something great.
Scott: I presume it's just a re like a, the movie only live and with singing what everyone has said about it.
Rym: Like collectively the critics seem to agree.
Rym: It feels like a, an amusement park ride that you don't move and it just happens on stage.
Rym: It's just a bunch of shit happens.
Rym: The end like big set pieces and shit moving around in a ridiculous set and like nonsense flying out over the crowd and animatronics and all this crap.
Rym: But like, no one seems to have anything else to say about it.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So I don't know if it's any, it's going away soon anyway.
Scott: So I mean, I don't think it's, you know, but the thing that's noteworthy about it is that it exists in the year 2022, right?
Scott: This property of, of this character from this one lousy movie.
Scott: Well, one good movie, but just one movie spawned this whole nonsense, right?
Scott: There hasn't even been a Beetlejuice two movie or any like nothing, right?
Scott: So fun show musical merchandise.
Rym: There have been like four or five earnest attempts to make a sequel to Beetlejuice.
Rym: The Tim Burton tried to get one going in 1990 titled Beetlejuice goes Hawaiian.
Scott: And that sounds like a very nineties sequel to me.
Rym: And they really tried to make it happen.
Rym: And they got the actors involved.
Rym: And, uh, basically then Keaton was like, uh, are we doing Batman returns?
Rym: And then they did Batman instead.
Scott: They kept trying to make more money with the Batman.
Rym: I think as, so as recently as February of 2022, they are currently filming an untitled Beetlejuice sequel.
Rym: is Michael Keaton in it with Michael Keaton and Winona Ryder, quote, reprising their roles.
Rym: Principal photography is apparently ongoing.
Rym: Uh, I have zero faith.
Rym: This will come out directing it.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Well, that's, is it like old man, Beetlejuice?
Scott: That would be a thing, right?
Scott: If they did old man, Beetlejuice, the best part would be is old man, Beetlejuice.
Rym: You play it straight.
Rym: You get the, as much as the original cast as you can back.
Scott: And like, you may be like, what if that piece of shit, you know, I mean, obviously, well, I guess he's like undead.
Scott: So it was like, does he really age?
Scott: But you could just say he does.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Just be like, like, like a piece of shit, but he's really old and weak now.
Scott: And you know, Lydia was there in, was that in that spot in life, a human who knows about the supernatural world and knows it's real and had ghost parents and grew up to be, you know, now a middle-aged woman.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, and it's like, what would her life be like?
Rym: They all, they all come back to like, deal with something.
Scott: I think it would just be, I would think, you know, uh, Lydia, this is how I would write it.
Scott: I don't know what the actual plot they've come up with is right.
Scott: Is if you're going to do a C I think, see, I think a prequel would be better.
Scott: We talked about this before the show, but if you're going to do the sequel, it's gotta be like, okay, Lydia is much older now.
Scott: Right.
Scott: She had ghost parents and, but is now a normal functioning adult who doesn't talk about ghosts with people because obviously that doesn't work.
Scott: People are getting like, what's wrong with you?
Scott: Um, but she gets caught in some shit, some real world shit.
Scott: And it's in such a tight spot.
Scott: She calls the Beetlejuice again and there it's really easy.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It would have to resolve.
Rym: The end would have to be, even though she knows the moral of the end would have to be, no, he's still a piece of shit.
Rym: The end.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: That would have, you could never reform.
Rym: Beetlejuice reforming.
Rym: Beetlejuice ruins.
Rym: Beetlejuice.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Uh, this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution.
Scott: 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon Patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, link EG, dread Lily Tenebrae, old bunch of people who really don't want me to say it.
Rym: Their names case care makes music.
Rym: Chris had died.
Rym: Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton decks, Finn, Joe Hayes, Rebecca Dunn, Sam Erickson, Shervin, Von Harl.
Rym: stop all the downloading.
Rym: The next station is York university, York university station, and a bunch of people who wisely are spending less than $5 per month on us.
Rym: We do appreciate your support.
Rym: We are trying to get back to doing panels at conventions.
Rym: We probably will start doing some, I don't know, Scott and I are discussing a potential new structure for some Tuesday episodes that, uh, Ooh, maybe we'll talk more about later.
Rym: You're curious bother Scott about it, but anyway, for now I leave you with.