Rym: It's Wednesday, January 12th, 2022.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: And I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we are talking about Centaur World.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, I've been planning since basically the quarantine began to re- like to get a new membership to a rock climbing gym and start rock climbing again.
Rym: Uh, because in Long Island City, there are like three rock climbing gyms in this neighborhood, like big ones.
Rym: And kind of like the thing we talked about with the chess places, like you'd think in a big city.
Scott: It's real popular.
Rym: People who compete with each other would like stay away from each other to go after customers.
Rym: But no, you tend to get concentrations of a bunch of places that serve the exact same customers in the exact same place.
Rym: That's just kind of how it ends up going.
Rym: So I'd planned to- I canceled my old membership because it was like 10 blocks away.
Rym: And there's a different gym that's only slightly more expensive that is literally downstairs around the corner.
Rym: Meaning in the winter, I am much more likely to go there at night as opposed to the one that's 10 blocks away.
Scott: And you go there- you go there like, what, super late when everyone's there?
Rym: My plan was I'll walk down there at like 9 o'clock, climb for a half hour and just fucking leave every night.
Rym: That's like- that's ideal.
Rym: And then COVID hit, so nothing.
Rym: Still not- for all the things I may or may not do in the current environment, going into a gym is not very high on the list of things I'm willing to risk it for.
Rym: So I've been playing a lot of DDR lately.
Rym: And I've noticed something because for a while when I played DDR during quarantine before, I was doing another exercise.
Rym: DDR wasn't my main thing.
Rym: And I'm very good at DDR, like you are very good at DDR.
Rym: A lot of our friends are very good at DDR because we were obsessed with it in ancient times, like fourth mix era.
Rym: But we're all also kind of scrubs, like none of us were good by any real measure, myself included.
Rym: And I hit this point when I started playing it again in my 30s where not only was I like not great, but even playing a lot, I just physically could not move my legs fast enough to do very hard songs.
Rym: that I was able to do when I was younger.
Rym: But I found just in the last few months when I've been playing DDR to an extreme degree, I am now literally better at Dance Dance Revolution than I've ever been in my life.
Rym: I can pass any nine footer before sixth mix and I can pass almost every nine footer in sixth mix.
Rym: I can do crazy bullshit.
Scott: That's what happens if you practice a thing a lot.
Scott: I mean, it's not a surprise.
Scott: I'm sure if I played DDR the same amount, I would also get better.
Rym: But I am finding where the actual limits of age are because the only song I cannot pass right now that I've passed before is Max 300 on Maniac.
Rym: And it's because I hit my max heart rate in the last third.
Rym: Like it's too much exertion.
Rym: Like I can't sprint that hard anymore.
Rym: So Max 300 is the only song I have done in my life that I cannot do now, but I passed like easily 20 songs that I was never able to pass before.
Rym: So I feel like I'm fighting the good fight against Father Time.
Rym: He's going to beat me in the end, but Little Mac is holding on to the third round right now.
Scott: Old man, old man, DDR grandpa, DDR grandpa.
Rym: You know what I want to be?
Rym: I want to be the skeleton.
Rym: You know how one of my life goals is to be that, you know, there's a type of old man that you see all around the world.
Rym: They look like a skeleton.
Rym: They look like they're 90 and they're out running at like 6 a.m.
Rym: in the middle of December on the street.
Rym: And you see that guy?
Rym: You're amazed they're alive.
Rym: It's kind of my goal, but now I have a sub goal.
Rym: I want to be the skeletal man at Magfest when I'm like 80 playing DDR.
Rym: Unlike the ancient machine in the museum part of the convention.
Scott: I was going to say, what are the odds of DDR machine will be there?
Rym: I mean, if I was rich enough to get an apartment that had like another room, there would be a DDR machine in that room.
Scott: If I had another room, I would have...
Rym: Air hockey table actually is higher priority, but...
Scott: I would have air hockey table and one pinball machine.
Rym: Just the best one?
Rym: Which one would it be?
Rym: If you had to pick right now and you had 10 seconds to decide, what would it be?
Scott: Well, the problem is, aesthetically speaking, I'd want to get a really old school one like Blast Off.
Scott: Like a 60s one, which is really styling.
Rym: One of the ones that has like the rainbow of brown and yellow colors making a loop.
Rym: Like that kind of styling?
Scott: The one, well Blast Off is different styling than that.
Scott: It's more like a retro sci-fi.
Scott: It's like a rocket taking off, right?
Scott: And then, you've got like a really good 90s one, like I love the Cyclone one and the Funhaus one.
Scott: You know, I love those ones.
Scott: That has like a gimmick to it of some kind.
Scott: But there's also the brand new ones that they're making right now, which are like really good, right?
Scott: They're obviously better than the old ones.
Rym: And I gotta say, you know where?
Rym: I think there's going to be a big one.
Scott: You've got the Addams Family one, it's like a cost a lot because that one's super popular.
Rym: Oh, the Addams Family, when I was a kid, the Addams Family one was 75 cents.
Scott: Yeah, it's one of the best ones.
Rym: Yeah, that's a real good one.
Rym: They had that, what was the name of the arcade I used to go to as a kid?
Rym: Now that it matters, it was built inside of a water park that failed inside of a mall.
Scott: Regardless, I wouldn't have more than one.
Rym: Yeah, you have one.
Rym: Just like, I mean at least you only need one DDR machine because you can put any DDR in that machine.
Rym: And you only need one air hockey table because you just need a regulation one and you're ready to roll.
Rym: So yeah, got any news?
Scott: Do I have a news?
Scott: Oh yeah, so I don't know if people knew this.
Scott: I didn't even know this that well.
Scott: I sort of knew it, but now I actually know it, is that Initial D has a sequel called MF Ghost.
Rym: I see that Shigeno draws humans the way he's always drawn them and draws cars the way he's always drawn them from the manga.
Scott: And I basically haven't done it, you know, I got rid of my Initial D manga a long time ago.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, it's not down there anymore.
Scott: So regardless, you know, Initial D is still a thing, right, that I read a lot of, I watched a lot of.
Scott: I still like Eurobeat music, especially in the summer.
Scott: It's not really a good winter music.
Rym: I've been thinking about Initial D a lot, really unrelated to this news because of my news, but anyway.
Scott: Okay, well, it sort of leaked, accidental, preannounced, but got taken down.
Scott: But the Internet Archive still had it that they're going to make an MF Ghost anime in 2023.
Scott: And like there was a video trailer, but then it, I don't know if it's still there or not, but I definitely watched it and shared it with everyone.
Scott: And it sure enough, it looked like an Initial D anime, but from the year 2022.
Scott: And the only differences I noticed were A, the Eurobeat music wasn't there, which tells me either A, they're not going to have it or B, they just didn't have it yet.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And that's a deal breaker for me.
Scott: It's obviously a deal breaker.
Rym: Without Eurobeat, it's just watching a PlayStation car race.
Scott: The other thing that I noticed was that they had in the animation, they animated drones following the race because it's 2023.
Scott: So obviously illegal street racers use drones to follow the cars down the mountain to remotely spectate the entire race.
Rym: I appreciate that touch because you know there's going to be a race where the drone interferes or something.
Scott: I don't know, but my question is what the fuck drone has that kind of operating range where you can be at the top or bottom of a mountain and still get signal to it?
Scott: The mountain's pretty tall, right?
Rym: There are drones.
Scott: I guess if the mountain's not that tall or if the road goes around to the other side of the mountain, it's like, what are you going to do then?
Rym: Well, you don't need radio.
Rym: Remember, there are drones.
Rym: you can tell to just follow an object, follow a transponder, all sorts of stuff like that.
Scott: I'm just saying, if the drone doesn't fuck up, that's a really good drone.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: Of course, it's not a real drone.
Scott: It's an animation of a drone.
Rym: But also, it implies something about the Initial D universe.
Rym: that was implied by the original show because Takavi never fucking changed those tires, as our friend George likes to point out every time we talk about Initial D. In the real world, you have to replace the tires on that car every single goddamn day.
Scott: Pretty much, yeah.
Rym: I imagine, much like when I talk about my news, which is actually a Geek Byte, someone is funding all of this racing.
Rym: Maybe Boonta's a secret billionaire, has a friend.
Scott: The illegal street racing of Initial D and MF Ghost is suspiciously well-resourced.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Like, the cops never show up on this road.
Rym: Like, every Tuesday, they just know not to be there.
Scott: But if you're on the ground in the town, you can hear screeching tires in the distance and roaring engines.
Rym: They're like, what's that?
Rym: And everyone's just like, well, I don't hear it.
Rym: It doesn't sound like anything to me.
Rym: I'm actually moderately into this, especially if it's really focused on the car racing, because frankly...
Scott: It's been long enough since I watched one that I could be tempted to watch another one, especially if there is some new Eurobeat tracks going on.
Rym: So, to segue, this is actually a perfect and unplanned segue, because our friend's riding that way.
Scott: Also, on top of that, there is a... I don't know if it's a new car, but it's a car I didn't know about, probably because it's a Japan-only car, or because...
Rym: Oh, right, the car ads.
Scott: Because I want to ban all cars, but there are some new Initial D car ads for the Toyota GR86, which I guess is effectively the current incarnation of the AE86, which is the Initial D car.
Scott: And apparently the GR86 is what the dude drives in MF Ghost, so, you know, it's like, I want to ban all cars, but you know what?
Scott: If I had to buy a car now, it's like, I was in Japan, I guess.
Rym: I mean, I'm not going to get a Nissan Skyline.
Scott: I'd like a nice little hatchback.
Scott: But this is more fuel-efficient than a Skyline.
Rym: True.
Rym: But also, talk about, like, that is the kind of promotion that probably will actually earnestly be effective in selling cars to nerds, for real.
Rym: So if you're feeling that itch, our friends at Red Natalie got really into this show, and it doesn't look like the kind of show that we would get into.
Rym: But what if I said the show is basically, take Initial D, but distill it to its essence and cut out absolutely everything that drags at all.
Scott: What is there to cut out?
Scott: It's already just essence.
Rym: So imagine if they're like, we're going to have a race.
Rym: It cuts to the race.
Rym: The race just happens, and then it ends, and then another fucking race happens in the same episode.
Scott: That's pretty much Initial D, yeah.
Scott: But also, cross it- With most sports anime?
Rym: Cross it with- cross it with Utena.
Rym: A little bit.
Rym: This show is nuts, and I actually really enjoy it, and it takes-.
Scott: What show are you talking about?
Rym: So the show is called Skate as an SK8 The Infinity.
Rym: It's a short show.
Rym: I think it might have more seasons coming, but season one just ends and seems to tell a story.
Rym: There's 12 episodes.
Scott: Are the episodes full length, or is it a short show?
Rym: Full length episodes.
Rym: There's 12 of them.
Scott: Oh, there's only not a lot of episodes.
Rym: Yeah, it's Bones.
Rym: It's lusciously animated, and basically the plot of this show- I'm geek biting it because I'm about to watch the last episode.
Scott: Is it just sports anime of skateboard?
Rym: Sort of.
Rym: So basically, it's about a kid who's kind of a scrub.
Rym: Like, he's a good skateboarder, but he's a scrub.
Rym: And this other kid comes to town, and the other kid's the Takumi.
Rym: He's a snowboarder whose family had to move away from Canada and forced to live in Japan in a hot place.
Rym: And he's bored, and he ends up taking up skateboarding, and because of his snowboarding skills, he ends up being the god of skateboarding.
Rym: Like, he is the best skateboarding human in history, effectively.
Scott: I don't know how well snowboarding skills translate.
Scott: I've never been able to even balance on a skateboard, so just going flat.
Rym: There is overlap between the sports because the muscle, like the skills you learn, translate to a degree, but the physicality you learn.
Scott: I was gonna say, if there was a lot of crossover, I would have expected to see Tony Hawk trying to snowboard.
Rym: He might.
Rym: There is a lot of crossover.
Scott: Who's the famous snowboard-y guy trying to skateboard?
Rym: Yeah, I do not like snowboarding as a sport.
Rym: Skiing is objectively better for the kinds of things I like to do.
Rym: But anyway, so this show, the villains are like Fist of the North Star villains in some cases.
Rym: One of them is basically just Akio.
Rym: It is so over-the-top and so condensed that it is actually worth watching.
Scott: So it's not trying to be realistic.
Scott: It's wild.
Rym: It's weird.
Rym: It's hyper-realistic up to a point, and then there's a big gap, and then it is just ridiculous bullshit.
Rym: But it's interesting to see that the parts that are realistic are hyper-realistic.
Rym: And what I'd say is it's very true to how skaters feel about what they're doing and what it feels like to skateboard and snowboard.
Rym: But the literal reality is what's happening.
Rym: They do the gutter trick like in Initial D, but with the skateboard around the side.
Rym: One dude is this Fist of the North Star looking villain, and he powers up an attack where he's going to attack someone in the race.
Rym: But what he actually does is light a bunch of firecrackers and throw them at the dude or pull out a laser pen and just point it at his face to get him to mess up.
Rym: But the funniest part about the show is, to give you an example, the Fist of the North Star villain, he's just some schlub who works at a florist by day.
Rym: And all these people have alter egos where they go to the dueling arena to have their beefs on their skateboards at night.
Rym: And to pull this back into the Initial D thing, there is a rich person funding this ridiculous nonsense.
Rym: He has bribed all the police to never patrol this mountain on the days they're going to have races.
Rym: And it pulls the real world into this ridiculous nonsense in ways that Initial D never did.
Rym: And honestly, I really enjoyed it.
Rym: I ended up watching the whole goddamn thing.
Rym: It's only 12 episodes.
Rym: So, in another news that I guess only me and weirdos care about, but I've talked about this before.
Rym: There was a webcomic that I like.
Rym: I think it was doing something interesting called Mr.
Rym: Boop.
Rym: It is about the real life human being who ends up in a relationship with Betty Boop, the animated character, and marries her.
Rym: And it is just fucked up, violent, adults only, weird nonsense.
Rym: But I really liked it.
Rym: It was doing something.
Scott: I never read the whole thing, and I never followed it, but I think there were occasions where I got a link to it, and then I just read a pile of it in a sitting, like maybe half hour worth or whatever.
Scott: So I knew it, and then I was like, "That's enough of that.
Scott: I know what the deal
Scott: is.".
Rym: You know what?
Rym: It's one of those things where I would say, "It's not necessarily for everyone.
Rym: It's not even that necessarily for
Rym: me.".
Rym: But you look at it and you go, "You know what?
Rym: There's something going on there.
Rym: Someone appreciates
Rym: that.".
Scott: It's a clever idea.
Scott: Decent enough execution for the concept.
Rym: And actually it actually tries to say something in the end.
Rym: It does bring it all back together into a kind of real point.
Rym: So Alec Robbins is now putting it out in a deluxe physical book.
Scott: Are they going to get sued?
Scott: Is Betty Boop in the public domain?
Scott: I didn't see her on the list this year.
Rym: I mean, I'm going to buy this book, so if it does get sued, I'm hoping I get the book before it gets sued.
Scott: Yeah, good idea.
Scott: I recommend, yeah.
Rym: Because I feel like Mr.
Rym: Boop is the kind of thing, like again, go read some to see if this is your thing or not.
Rym: I suspect most of you, your reaction will be, "What the fuck is
Rym: this?".
Rym: But I feel like this book will be something that at some point in my life, I will pull off a bookshelf and hand to someone and say, "I think you should look at what's in these
Rym: pages.".
Scott: It's definitely, you know, it's a thing that stands out, right?
Scott: Like you could mix, I could mix it in with some like other coffee table books that are obviously vastly superior, right?
Scott: You could have, you know, like I have my mouse guard coffee table book.
Rym: I've got my New York City MTA style guide for the entire subway system.
Scott: I got Wolf Walker's art book.
Scott: I got like Hellboy library edition, right?
Scott: All of those are way, way, way better than Mr.
Scott: Boop.
Scott: But if you were to put all four of those on a coffee table and a random person came in, right?
Scott: The Mr.
Scott: Boop one is the most like, huh, kind of, you know.
Rym: Because remember the whole original point of coffee table books was are ostensibly to be conversation pieces before people had smartphones.
Rym: And I think Mr.
Rym: Boop on the coffee table will definitely cause a conversation.
Scott: Or if I had, I kind of wish that I had, you know, some sort of office with a waiting room.
Scott: So I could put all coffee table books and no magazines and no ads.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So the other one I'll say, I'll quote a great man.
Scott: I don't know if it would be okay to put Mr.
Scott: Boop in there though.
Rym: I'll just quote a great man from fiction who said something.
Rym: and that's what I, that's my actual assessment of Mr.
Rym: Boop.
Rym: It was most memorable.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: This is not new.
Rym: It's not even new to me.
Rym: I saw it a while ago, but it was in a queue I have of things I was going to use as things of the day as backups.
Rym: If I didn't have anything new, that queue got too old.
Rym: So I'm going to go through it.
Scott: I'm fairly confident.
Scott: I've seen this before years and years and years ago.
Scott: I've definitely seen this at least twice.
Scott: I definitely remember like having it come up again at least at some point after my original seeing of it.
Scott: I strongly feel it was thing of the day in the past, but if we can't, Rym couldn't find it.
Rym: I couldn't find it.
Rym: I did try.
Rym: I searched for Italy, Italian, fake English, English, Italian, Adriano, Celentano.
Scott: So who knows?
Scott: Regardless, use it again.
Rym: It's a short video.
Rym: I'm just going to read the tweet that the person that I'm linking to tweeted about it because it says everything.
Rym: "Italian singer Adriano Celentano released a song in the '70s with nonsense lyrics meant to sound like American English, apparently to prove Italians would like any English song.
Rym: It was a hit and resulted in this, the greatest video I have ever
Rym: seen.".
Scott: Yeah, it's not a bad song, really.
Scott: It's kind of fun.
Rym: I like the video too.
Scott: The video is also kind of fun in a, I guess, Moscow kind of way.
Rym: I can imagine a cover of this on Eurovision being hot shit.
Scott: Oh yeah, probably.
Scott: But I mean, the thing is, if you think about this from the flip side perspective, right?
Scott: Imagine if I sang a song, you know, pretending to speak in Korean to make a point that, you know, K-pop fans will listen to anything.
Scott: They don't know what's being, right?
Scott: It's like, that's fucking racist.
Rym: You can't do that.
Rym: For this, there's a difference because this is definitely a response to the overbearing colonialist history presence of American pop culture globally specifically, which in the 70s in Europe was a huge part of pop counterculture.
Scott: That's the point, right?
Scott: Is that one is going against the colonizer where K-pop is not, we're still the colonizer in that relationship, right?
Scott: But there could be some distant future, right?
Scott: Not too distant even, decades, right?
Scott: Where, you know, especially the way the US is going, we're collapsing here.
Scott: Where we are no longer colonized.
Scott: That is not today.
Scott: Feel free to keep attacking us today.
Scott: But no, this is punching up, not down.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: It's also good.
Rym: Yeah, legit good.
Rym: The song is catchy.
Rym: I caught myself humming it before the show.
Scott: The person was good at music, right?
Scott: I think that's.
Scott: the other thing is that this person was trying to make their point, like, oh, any English song will be popular.
Scott: But it's like, actually, if you had made a shitty song, it wouldn't have been popular, right?
Scott: You made a good song.
Rym: But also, it is really hard to like babble or talk in a language where it sounds like that language, but isn't actually that language.
Rym: That is actually very difficult to do.
Scott: It's difficult to do without just being racist.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But even like, try to vaguely talk in German without actually using real German words.
Rym: If you know some German words, it's a challenge.
Scott: The only way I can only think, my brain only would know how to do it in a racist fashion.
Rym: Nah.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: Alright, so, what do I have?
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I've used, I'm pretty sure I did a thing of the day before.
Scott: Because the official Pokemon YouTube channel.
Rym: Which is a great channel, like legit good stuff.
Scott: It's a great channel, even if you only mildly enjoy Pokemon.
Scott: They have been occasionally releasing short Pokemon animations.
Scott: Now, we're not talking like episodes of Pokemon anime here.
Scott: We're talking like original short animations that take place in the Pokemon universe.
Scott: By various animators that are completely standalone and have nothing to do with anything.
Scott: And really, if you appreciate Pokemon at all, even a small amount.
Scott: Then you can appreciate these short, well done animations that are just free on YouTube with no ads.
Scott: They're just an ad for Pokemon in themselves, right?
Scott: There's no nonsense.
Scott: So I'm pretty sure I did a thing of the day for the previous one, which is about Gengar.
Rym: Oh, that one was good.
Rym: That's one of the best ones.
Scott: That's a real good one, the Gengar one.
Rym: Actually, the music videos that come out are the best of the Pokemon stuff, but this stuff's really good too.
Scott: The Gengar one wasn't really a Pokemon story.
Scott: It was sort of just a story about ghosts, school, and whatnot.
Scott: But just in the Pokemon universe, the ghosts happened to be Gengar and whatnot, right?
Scott: Friendship.
Scott: This one, there's a new one that just came out like yesterday, which is the Bidoof one.
Scott: And you already know when it's the Bidoof one, it's going to be something, right?
Scott: But this one is not only a good story, but it's also a very Pokemon universe story.
Scott: It directly translates to the mechanics of what's going on when you're playing a Pokemon game.
Scott: And it sort of takes that story from the perspective of the Pokemon.
Scott: It's like you think about a Pokemon game and it's a story of the trainer, right?
Scott: And this is like, okay, if a trainer caught a Bidoof, what would the trainer do with the Bidoof?
Rym: I know what I do with Bidoofs.
Scott: Right, let's tell that story from the perspective of the Bidoof.
Scott: And it ends up being a very, very good way to spend the few minutes of your life it takes to watch this.
Scott: So I can't use this channel as my thing of the day a third time, that would be wrong.
Scott: So watch this video, but also subscribe to the Pokemon official YouTube channel.
Scott: Or just stay on top of the original animations that appear there.
Rym: I mean, basically that's our rule.
Scott: There's almost definitely going to be more like this that are probably going to be just as good, if not better.
Rym: Oh yeah, this is very true to the Bidoof.
Rym: But in general, I feel like in the meta moment, we'll do the meta moment now.
Rym: In terms of our things of the day, we can only use one content creation source once.
Rym: Unless, like you said, the second thing is just so good.
Rym: But then that basically ends using that thing, I think.
Scott: What am I supposed to do?
Scott: Like I watch Lawyer several times a week.
Scott: Am I going to be like, cracking the cryptic Sudoku.
Scott: Just thing of the day, yeah, this YouTube channel I subscribe to, post another video.
Rym: I think the rule has to be simple.
Rym: There's actually a much simpler rule.
Scott: If you liked it the last time I did it as thing of the day, you would have subscribed to it already.
Rym: We can only use a source of things of the day, again, if we follow the same rule we followed for Jack Thompson.
Rym: The thing has to be an order of magnitude beyond the last time we used that source.
Scott: Yeah, like if Lockpicking Lawyer went and opened up Fort Knox, that could be thing of the day worthy, right?
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: But it's got to be a full order of magnitude.
Scott: Right, but today all he did was crack the door lock on an Audi something, right?
Scott: Some car.
Scott: He's done that so many times.
Rym: So in the meantime, the GeekNights Book Club book, which Scott has finished.
Scott: I have finished reading every goddamn page of the tale of Genji.
Scott: Eat a dick, I read it.
Scott: Also, I just want to say something incredibly rude I discovered.
Scott: I guess it's also a consequence of reading an e-book instead of a paper book.
Rym: Yeah, because at a paper book you would have discovered what you're about to say, which I'm also mad now that I know.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So we all know when it comes to nerds, nerdy books have maps, especially fantasy books.
Scott: If they don't got a map, you can throw that fantasy book right in the trash.
Rym: Yep, go find your copy of the Hobbit.
Rym: There's a map.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: If you open up a fantasy novel and there's a map in it, you don't need to read.
Scott: You don't need to know nothing.
Scott: Just take that shit home.
Scott: If you're at the library, just check that shit out.
Scott: You know it's going to be good.
Scott: There's a map in there, right?
Scott: Tale of Genji, if you're still reading it or whatever, it has maps.
Scott: Therefore, it's good.
Scott: But also those maps are at the fucking end, right?
Scott: They're after the final page in between the text and the, you know, the appendices and notes and footnote shit at the end, right?
Scott: The maps are in between.
Scott: So if I had the paper edition of this book, I would have, like, flipped through it and smelled it and seen those maps before I started reading.
Scott: But because I had the e-book edition, right, and the maps aren't listed in the table of contents, like maps page X, I didn't know about those maps.
Scott: until on the final page, there's a map and I go to the next page and the zoom in on a piece of the map.
Scott: And I'm like, I keep going and there's more maps.
Scott: And I'm like, motherfucker, that's rude as hell.
Scott: So anyone out there who's making e-books or making books, if you make a map and put it in your book, that's a good thing because now I know your book is good.
Scott: Also put your map at the start, especially if it's an e-book.
Scott: So I know it's there.
Scott: If you put your map at the end, you might not sell because I didn't see that map.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: This is why Scott never read the Wheel of Time.
Rym: Doesn't know?
Rym: there's a map in there.
Scott: There's a map in there?
Rym: There's maps in every one of those books.
Scott: I'm pretty sure I've read Wheel of Time.
Scott: I've read several Wheel of Times.
Rym: I'm the one who just kept going and read all the way to the end.
Scott: I read like four, five, several.
Rym: There's one like 13.
Rym: I don't even remember.
Scott: I don't know what happened in any particular book.
Scott: There's definitely teens of them.
Rym: Like I always say, in the time it would take me to summarize what the fuck happens in the Wheel of Time, you could just read it.
Rym: So yeah, we'll be doing this book club book like first week of February because I gotta finish the book, which I am well on track to finish this month.
Rym: And we got thoughts about Genji and about the environment.
Scott: I'm writing down a bunch of notes because there's so much to say.
Rym: I've been keeping like one short note per chapter.
Rym: Mostly so I remember what happened in each chapter or the things I was mad about or surprised by or etc.
Rym: along the way.
Rym: Because every time I think about the book, there's so much that happened that I'm currently like, "Wait, Genji, what the
Rym: fuck?".
Rym: I gotta remember, "Oh, but I was also mad about this and mad about
Rym: that.".
Rym: Anyway, otherwise, we got no cons coming up anytime soon.
Rym: Our panels are on YouTube.
Rym: Stay tuned for our new website and all the other stuff we got working on.
Rym: I guess we can just get right into our main bit with a show that snuck up on me.
Rym: I kind of ignored this show.
Scott: I knew it existed.
Scott: I knew that it was around.
Rym: And I knew it shook to a degree, but I just ignored it until YouTube, in its infinite wisdom, the algorithm one day when I looked at just the algorithmic suggestions, showed me a song from Centaur World.
Rym: And I watched the song, and much like how I watched the winter wrap-up song from My Little Pony, and I was like, "Wait a minute, this show has
Rym: music?".
Rym: I suddenly went, "Wait a minute, this show has music that's
Rym: Disney-quality?".
Rym: And I watched another song, and I was like, "Wait, there's multiple Disney-level songs.
Rym: How many episodes is this
Rym: show?".
Rym: "Oh, it's only two seasons?
Rym: There's 18 episodes?
Rym: Alright, I'm just watching it.
Rym: Nothing's stopping me now.
Rym: That's worth
Rym: it.".
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I only watched, you know, I knew about it.
Scott: I wasn't really planning to watch it.
Scott: But I watched three episodes just right now, the first three episodes, because we were going to do a show on it.
Rym: Which that covers, what, like six or seven full-on songs, I want to say?
Rym: You see the tornado.
Scott: There were several songs per episode.
Scott: I want to say at least seven or eight songs at least.
Scott: Maybe nine?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: There's many.
Rym: I can think of at least six songs that are full-on songs just from what you watched so far.
Rym: And there's even more songs later on.
Scott: So this show is basically, you know, I forget what the word people use for it, where you go into another universe like Escaflowne.
Scott: It's one of those.
Rym: But it's got a, the twist it has, like, I mean, spoiler, we're not going to spoil anything, this show's not even that long.
Rym: And also, like, the conceit, it starts with a serious, very angularly animated show that looks a lot like a typical kid's fantasy animated show.
Rym: There's a girl who's a knight, she's on a horse, there's clearly some sort of war, there's devastation everywhere.
Rym: There's a very serious and very good song as she's calming down this warhorse.
Scott: That was probably the best song of the songs.
Rym: Yeah, so that song gets reprised and remixed.
Scott: Some of the other songs are meh.
Scott: Yeah, it does get reprised.
Rym: Yeah, well, because that is the plot.
Rym: It starts with that, and then pretty much immediately the horse gets transported.
Rym: So it's not.
Rym: the rider gets transported to a magical world, no.
Rym: The show is about the horse, and the horse gets transported to a magical centaur world and is trying to get back to her rider.
Scott: I was actually confused at the start there, because...
Rym: Which was clearly intentional by the creators.
Scott: Right, the horse starts talking, and I was like, did the girl get transported in the horse's body and doesn't know she's in the horse's body yet?
Scott: Did she turn into a horse?
Scott: And then eventually you realize, no, the horse only was transported to the other world, right?
Scott: So that is pretty clever, right?
Scott: Usually it's like a magical girl with a pet.
Scott: No, the pet is actually the main character, not the magical girl.
Scott: The pet goes into the other universe, gains the ability to talk because it's fucking centaur world and it's a horse.
Scott: Or whatever magic.
Scott: And that's the main character.
Scott: And I was like, oh, alright.
Scott: That's points for originalness there.
Rym: And that is the plot.
Rym: The horse thing is all the way to the end.
Scott: Yeah, the horse is the hero that goes on the adventure in centaur world.
Scott: It's a normal horse, and it encounters all these wacky centaurs.
Rym: So centaur world, meanwhile, the fantasy world the horse goes into, on one hand, depending on how you interpret it, it's kind of like, what would be the fantasy world that a horse would imagine if we're going with this horse conceit?
Rym: Because everything's a centaur.
Rym: And I guess, take the most Pendleton Ward parts of Adventure Time, distill them, and make that the world.
Rym: That's kind of what centaur world is like.
Rym: And I do appreciate how the horse, basically, like the horse's personality is, I'm a war horse.
Rym: I fucking murder people.
Rym: That is my job.
Rym: Like, for real.
Rym: And the horse kind of freaks out about this world that she is now in with these weird, like, she reacts the way we would react in a world like this.
Rym: And the whole show is about, well, the first season is, how does the horse get home?
Rym: And you only saw three episodes.
Rym: What I can say is, the plot progresses extremely rapidly.
Rym: It is an escaflowne level.
Scott: The end of episode three is like, oh, okay, I see where this is going.
Rym: Yeah, but I'll say, like, you find out what's up with the rider, like, real quick.
Rym: I think you met Water Baby, best character in the show.
Rym: The shaman?
Scott: I agree that that is the best character that I have encountered so far by a lot.
Rym: So, Scott, did you get the "she's up to something" sense that I got from that song?
Scott: I got the "up to something" sense from everybody.
Rym: Yeah, so yeah, everybody's up to something, but Water Baby is up to something.
Scott: Of course she is.
Scott: That's obvious.
Rym: And she comes back and is a major character, but I guess the thing is, this show moves fast like the second half of escaflowne.
Rym: So, like, if you're wondering, like, hey, is Rider going to come back at the end?
Rym: No, you see what's up with Rider, like, before the end of season one even.
Rym: The Nowhere King, which I don't think you even got the Nowhere King song yet.
Rym: Yeah, you find out a good chunk of that deal, like, at the end of season one.
Rym: Everything resolves itself, like, pretty hard.
Rym: And the show just steamrolls to the finale at the end of season two.
Rym: Like, you will not have any questions, everything gets revealed, everything gets explained, and the character arcs are all actually pretty satisfying.
Rym: And even the centaur world nonsense is way more serious than it appears from the superficial initial episodes.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think I'm watching any more than three episodes.
Rym: You know what, the thing is, what you could do, just like with a lot of musicals...
Scott: I could read a spoiler and be like, oh, the good guys win, the end, okay, that's what I wanted.
Rym: You want to see where the show was going.
Rym: You could do the thing, like, you know musicals like Les Mis, how if you listen to the soundtrack, that kind of tells you everything.
Rym: And the non-singing acting that happens in between the songs is largely incidental.
Rym: Like, you can figure out the whole plot.
Rym: There's two YouTube videos that are just every song from centaur world in chronological order, and that'll pretty much tell you the full deal of the whole show.
Scott: So the problem is, is that even though I think every song I heard was like a rather well-made song...
Rym: Oh, the craft of the songs is like A+ didn't appear.
Scott: And it's like, wow, they put a lot of hard work, and they made, making songs is not easy, and they made a lot of them, right?
Scott: But none of the songs, right, the first one is definitely the best, it comes the closest, but none of the songs are like, that I heard in three episodes, which is a lot of songs.
Scott: Zero of them were like, soundtrack, I would get home and listen to this on purpose.
Rym: See, I do that, I was listening to the soundtrack while I was working today.
Scott: Right, you go, usually if you go see a Broadway musical, like a good one, usually there's at least two or three songs that are just like, you just cannot escape, you know, they're just inescapable earworms, like you're just done, right?
Rym: I would say, you know, disagreeing with you, about 75% of the songs from the show get stuck in my head instantly.
Scott: I was like, eh, it was a song, right?
Scott: I don't want to like, there was even one song in the third episode, I was just like, I'm just gonna fast forward through this song.
Scott: And the reason I fast forwarded through the song is because of two additional complaints I have, right?
Scott: So if you look at most musicals, right, the songs in like top tier musicals usually serve one of two purposes.
Scott: One is to sort of, you know, show you something that you didn't know already, right?
Scott: So if you think of like, Little Mermaid, right, you know, there's a song she sings with the, she's got the, you know, the spork, the fuzz doodle, right, when she's underneath her little hidey hole, right?
Scott: And it's like, you're learning, you didn't know that Ariel was like pining for the other world.
Scott: So she's got the part of the world song and you learn something from the song, right?
Scott: And it's expositional.
Scott: And the other kind of song that you get is sort of resolutional, where there's some conflict that's happening, right?
Scott: Or, and this, you know, maybe it'll often have two characters, right?
Scott: And there was a song that involved two characters in Centaur World, but not always two characters, it could be a single character with an inner conflict, right?
Scott: And in the course of the song, the conflict is resolved, right?
Scott: Like they sort of come to the conclusion mid-song, and then the climax of the song is like, we've decided this, or this is how I'm gonna go, or, right?
Scott: And so the song like is the plot.
Scott: Most of the songs in Centaur World, right, whatever they were singing about, was something you already knew before the song started.
Scott: And, so it wasn't expositional, you weren't learning anything, they were just singing about the feelings that already had been expressed in that scene or previous scene.
Scott: And if there was a conflict, you know, like there was with the duet song, it wasn't resolved in the course of the song, it's like they sang the song, and then the resolution came after that, and so the songs felt like they had no purpose other than to make it musical.
Scott: And so that, for me, allowed me, once I got through so many songs, and the fact that the songs were not earworms, that's why I fast-forwarded through one of the songs.
Rym: See, now I disagree that I find them to be extreme earworms.
Scott: Because I was like, this song is not telling me anything I don't know, and when I got to the end of the song, the plot had not advanced, and there was no, the thing that was unresolved was still unresolved, and I was like, I missed nothing skipping that song.
Scott: Nothing at all.
Rym: So what the show does, basically, is it takes the songs and sort of, they come back, now including the sort of sinister, unspoken, like what was the undertone of the song the first time it came, when it comes back, you sort of find out what were they all avoiding talking about and singing about, and then the songs are sort of different.
Scott: That's clever, that's good.
Scott: You look at Adventure Time, right, you know, the song, the door-opening episode, the best Adventure Time song, right, and it's like, that song is resolution-al, right?
Rym: Ah, but most Adventure Time songs are not that way.
Scott: And an earworm that you can't avoid.
Rym: Very few Adventure songs are actually that way.
Scott: I'm not saying that all the Adventure Time songs are great, I'm saying that that one is really good.
Scott: I'm just pointing out one example of one good example of the right way to do a musical, right?
Scott: But I'm saying, even Disney musicals, which, you know, love 'em or hate 'em or whatever, right, almost all of the songs in any Disney animated musical fall into the two categories I described, expositional or resolution-al.
Rym: You know, I realize one song you didn't hear from the next, I don't think you got the food song, but basically, No, no food song.
Rym: There's a whole song where all the centaurs are like, "Please, sir, where does food come
Rym: from?".
Rym: Like, they don't know where food comes from.
Scott: I did get hungry, though, with the pancakes, and also, I appreciate that the centaurs go to the bathroom, which most shows in general don't deal with, so I like that.
Scott: That was good.
Rym: So, at the end of that song, it cuts away from the music, and the horse is like, "What the fuck is wrong with
Rym: you?".
Rym: Of course, how do you not know where food comes from?
Rym: But then the horse realizes that the horse doesn't know where food comes from, either, because the rider just gives it to them.
Rym: And that sort of sets the tone for what the show's actually about when you get to the end.
Scott: I appreciated the glue moment in episode three.
Scott: The glue moment was very good.
Rym: Oh, in season two, when there's a war?
Rym: Yeah, centaurs don't know what war is, really.
Rym: But I would say, if you're not sure if you'll like this show or not, because I love the shit out of the show, and the music does get stuck in my head, and I do listen to it, just like I'd listen to Les Mis.
Rym: But, honestly, you could just watch the YouTube-- I should go listen to Les Mis.
Scott: That's on Spotify, for sure.
Rym: Master of the House.
Scott: See?
Scott: There you go.
Scott: That song is, A, an earworm.
Rym: I mean, George was singing it in Seinfeld when it was first a big musical hit.
Scott: It's an earworm, and it's expositional, right?
Scott: You don't know shit about the Master of the House, right?
Scott: The scene opens up, right?
Scott: You know, suddenly they're in this place, and it's like, "What's going on
Scott: here?".
Scott: "Well, let me introduce to you the best character in this whole entire goddamn
Scott: play.".
Scott: And you're like,
Scott: "Woo-hoo!".
Rym: I think part of your problem, though-- You don't know the Master of the House.
Rym: But part of what's going on, too, is there's almost a call to response, where the early songs in the show, they almost ask a question that they don't answer.
Rym: And then when the songs get reprised, like, "Water Baby" sings her song again, but in the beginning, the lyrics are like, "So that the people who won't do what needs to be done will finally do it,".
Rym: but doesn't explain what the hell that is.
Rym: When the song gets reprised, they use the key to do the thing, and then it's like, "Oh, that's the answer to the question that was not answered the first time the song came
Rym: up.".
Scott: I think that's probably the final reason that at least I wasn't compelled to watch the rest of the show, is because, hey, it does have a terrible secret of space, right?
Scott: Lots of them, in fact.
Rym: The secret is, on one hand, not as good as I expected in one aspect, but the secret of season one, like, what's the key and what's the door to everything, pretty solid, actually.
Rym: Right.
Scott: The point is, though, it's just, it's so obvious.
Rym: Obvious?
Rym: What do you think it is, then?
Scott: I mean, I can't, I couldn't tell you exactly what the deal is, right?
Scott: But the general deal, it's like, okay, kids adventure, right?
Scott: It's like, we know what's going on here, right?
Scott: In general, right?
Scott: We don't know the specific details of this fantasy world, right?
Scott: If you really felt compelled to know that, yes, you would have to keep watching.
Scott: But I wasn't compelled to want to know that, and, you know, it's like, yeah, I can see that the, you know, good guys are going to go a little cute kid adventure here and win.
Scott: I know what the deal is, right?
Scott: Maybe I'll just skip to the last episode.
Rym: All I'll say is there's actually a significant body count.
Scott: Okay, cool.
Rym: It's not quite as straightforward as you're making it out to be.
Scott: Also, each episode does have one of those, like, you know, learning lessons for kids, right?
Scott: Like, you know, it's like, Oh, is it better to play it safe?
Scott: Or should you be fearless and brave, right?
Scott: It's got sort of those, you know, you know, should you should you go alone?
Scott: Or should you stick together team right as the sort of, you know, the things that it actually, you know, has the moral lesson incorporated into the song and the plot, rather than being like, GI Joe says at the end.
Rym: So I haven't seen it to the end.
Rym: What I can say is the other thing it does that the reason I was really drawn to it.
Scott: Good for children, at least if they're old enough, I guess, but not too old.
Rym: It plays with the style, like the radically different styles a lot.
Rym: And it's a minor spoiler, but the horse slowly starts turning into one of them and slowly gets and like slowly is drawn differently.
Scott: Yeah, I figured that was come when it lost all the armor.
Rym: So I guess say Water Baby goes to the human world or say Ryder comes to Centaur, like those kinds of questions do come up and it moves further than you might expect it to in that regard.
Rym: But I was pretty satisfied with it, having watched it all the way to the end.
Rym: I love the shit out of the show personally.
Rym: And I do highly recommend you at least watch some of it to see if this is going to be your jam.
Rym: I think the music is better produced than a lot of...
Scott: If you have Netflix, right, and you like animation, then watch it and see, you know, no one's going to make you finish it.
Rym: But honestly, I would say if you're not sure if you'd like it and you don't want to watch, like you only watch a couple episodes like Scott.
Rym: Worst case, you know, if you don't care about like spoilers, just watch that compilation of every song from season one, kind of just tells the story of the whole show in the span of 20-ish minutes.
Rym: And some of the later songs are stuck in my head still, especially... I think there's another horse who is kind of violent in the real world and just fucking murders people left and right.
Rym: I think Becky Apples is a great character.
Scott: The best part of the show really is just.
Scott: they are very clever with the Centaur jokes, right, from the tornado and so forth.
Rym: One episode is just a riff on cats.
Rym: They go to the cat-tar village and the cats re-enact basically the play Cats every single day rather than face the problem that clearly everyone is avoiding.
Rym: Like they're going to go town to town.
Rym: Every town has a radically different style of music.
Rym: So every episode after those first three has a radically different like musical style of the songs for the area.
Rym: So the cats all sing like Cats musical songs.
Rym: The trees sing like modern folk song type stuff.
Rym: There's a bear-tar who's a basement dwelling nerd collector, like that guy, who sings a very different style from that.
Scott: That seems fun.
Scott: Also it has the obvious, they're following the rainbow road, it's like this obvious Wizard of Oz deal, only they're visiting five wizards instead of one.
Rym: And the wizards are all radically different from each other.
Scott: Shamans, they're not wizards, shamans.
Rym: Yeah, they're basically wizards.
Rym: Turns out Wabuu is basically flunked out of wizard school.
Scott: It's visit five wizards of Oz plot structure.
Rym: But that all gets resolved before the end of season one.
Rym: Like it moves pretty quick.
Rym: But I'll say I personally love the shit out of the show.
Rym: I do understand why Scott is like less into it.
Rym: But Scott, it'd be worth just watching the rest of the songs.
Rym: That's maybe ten more minutes of investment.
Rym: Ten or fifteen.
Scott: Yeah, I already fast forwarded one song.
Scott: Why would I go listen to more songs?
Rym: Yeah, but maybe I'll do a separate final thoughts because the only actual complaint I have with this show is that in the final episode of season two, like the final few episodes, it did something that did not happen in Centaurworld up to that point, but it's something that I'm seeing commonly in popular media lately.
Rym: It's the same thing that happened in The Mandalorian.
Rym: There was a long scene that was basically just circular dialogue where characters argue about what to do and basically just go in a circle instead of moving on to the interesting thing.
Rym: It only happens in this show in the final episodes, but I see it happening in a lot of media lately, more so than in some older media.
Rym: Especially Marvel shows are doing it in particular, but I'm seeing it everywhere.
Rym: The circular debate that just wastes four minutes of screen time.
Rym: You could have used fleshing out the Nowhere Kings backstory a little more, fleshing out the general a little more, fleshing out the other humans a little more.
Rym: There was a little bit of a wasted opportunity.
Scott: I think you often see that either A) they got time to fill and they don't know what to do, or they feel like they need to make things explained more.
Scott: They want to make sure that everything is explicit, like everything is said.
Scott: And you know I prefer the abstract, the less said the better.
Rym: Also, just in terms of representation standpoint, many of the characters are directly openly LGBT.
Rym: It is not part of the plot, that is just who they are directly.
Rym: And the arcs around that are just really well done, I will say that too.
Scott: I mean, none of that came up in the first three episodes, but I had a feeling.
Rym: Yeah, there's a great episode, the cat plays, suddenly Zulia is the zebra guy, there's this tiger tar, and they both sing a big duet together about, "Oh, I don't know
Rym: him.".
Rym: They're both like, "Oh, I don't know
Rym: Very clearly they know each other, and yeah, they have a history, they get back together in the end.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: But there's some surprising bits about all that too.
Rym: But yeah, I like the show a lot, I encourage you to try it, may or may not be your thing.
Rym: And yeah, I'm curious what any of you who do watch at the end have to say about what the Nowhere Kings deal was.
Rym: Because I did appreciate the moment in season two, when you see some flashbacks, and you just see a deer, and the deer is clearly got some drama going on related to a human woman.
Rym: And that is the actual plot of this show in the end.
Rym: Other than the sort of real meta, like the allegorical plot, which is just Horse's transformation.
Rym: Was Horse really a violent, murderous warhorse who loved to feel the crush of skulls under her hooves?
Rym: Or was that just a product of her environment, and maybe she becomes something different because she's in an environment that is not a war, and maybe that's actually what the show was talking about in the end.
Rym: But the main reason I like this show is that it was intended to be two seasons, it was two seasons, it ended, and that is rare.
Scott: I do appreciate the ending.
Rym: Look at Dragon King, they had to be like, "Look, we don't know if we're even gonna have more
Rym: seasons.".
Rym: So we had to like- Dragon Prince, of course.
Rym: The Dragon King is-.
Scott: I do appreciate the ending, but I also wonder if the ending is just a necessity of being so musical, you're gonna run out of songs, you can't go on.
Rym: I get the impression the songs took a lot of effort, considering the high production quality.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I'm saying, you can't go on.
Rym: Especially because as the show moves on, more and more of the songs are duets or ensemble pieces that are extremely tight.
Rym: That is hard to do.
Rym: Like, Martin Garrah was a bad musical, like I don't think- don't go look up Martin Garrah.
Rym: They had big ideas about it being the sequel to Les Mis in terms of popularity, but they had to write a lot of songs that had two to four tenors singing against each other, and there's a reason that musical cost too much to make and didn't succeed.
Rym: So yeah, it's Stemtar World, maybe Emily and I will do a Final Thoughts, because we basically steamrolled this whole thing as fast as possible once we got past the first couple episodes.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are... Heidi McNicholallen, Joyce Linke, G-Dread, Lily Temprada, a bunch of people who really don't want me to say their names, Chris Hadad, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, Kishiai85, Rebecca Dunn, Revue, Madbull, 34 Coward, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Horl, Taylor Braun.
Rym: The next station is North York Center, North York Center.
Rym: And several people whose Patreon names I will not say.
Rym: So yeah, I'm gonna play root in a second, so I'm just gonna leave you really quickly with... Ugh, Jeffica.
Rym: I bet Becky's got perfect hair.
Rym: Jeffica's got stupid, stupid hooves.
Rym: I'm never gonna eat another apple ever again.
Rym: Ooh, it really bunches my wool to think how badly she hurt you.
Rym: Baby girl, tell me a story.
Rym: I left my rider so that I could raise an army.
Rym: So that she could raise an army.
Rym: And the sea dog popped up and he said something alarming.
Rym: Ooh, well he's pretty.
Rym: He told me that my best friend's ridden.
Rym: No.
Rym: Another horse so pretty.
Rym: And her name is Becky Apples because of course it is.
Rym: Becky Apples, Becky Apples.
Rym: Oh, what a gorgeous, fancy schmuck.
Rym: Becky, how do you like an apple?
Rym: Because I think your apples suck.