Scott:
Rym: It's Thursday, June 15th, 2023.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is geek guides.
Rym: tonight We are talking about airplane food and Airport food.
Rym: Let's do this Talking about some worst-case food scenario.
Scott: Did you say the right?
Scott: Did you say the right day?
Rym: I absolutely said the right day.
Rym: I am.
Rym: I was studious about that.
Rym: I haven't had a Physical note.
Rym: I wrote with a pen on a piece of paper to hide me to say the right date.
Scott: I had a remember.
Scott: I remembered.
Scott: I'm like make sure Rym says the right day But I didn't remember to say anything before you said the day.
Scott: it was just after you finished and with show started.
Scott: I was like, oh wait, I remember I was supposed to.
Rym: There were ancient times where we record shows ahead more frequently, but that was back when one we did shows four nights a week.
Rym: You know ancient times and two we like.
Rym: we were trying to emulate penny arcade.
Rym: So we like really didn't ever want to miss a show.
Scott: so we would like record Do either not like right now.
Scott: I got too many things to do this week.
Scott: Nothing is really big have no travel or anything to interfere with the show.
Scott: No sickness, right?
Scott: It just happens coincidentally that two events that I feel were valuable enough to more value.
Scott: you know one-time events that are valuable enough to Cancel or delay.
Scott: geek that's happened here Tuesday exactly Tuesday and exactly Thursday.
Scott: We cancel Tuesday and we're gonna record Thursday on Monday.
Rym: But we haven't done this in a while because for the last I'd say seven years if we really couldn't do a show we just Bail on it, but didn't want to bail on two in a row, especially because as Covid is that we're bailing
Scott: quite a bit lately, right?
Scott: Let's on you know on bail here.
Rym: Yep It's partly because you know, like you said more Joe if I zoom out a little bit It's almost like all the things I wasn't doing for the last three years because I guess something was happening Are like all coming back into my life, but they're almost like more things are happening.
Rym: I have more things scheduled now in the year 2023 than I did in the first part of the year 2019 on a daily.
Scott: I mean, it's not it's not conscious, but I I am just lately doing doing things.
Rym: Yeah, and also our video game cup overflow with like two crazy degree.
Scott: I only got two video games right now I was the kingdom.
Scott: I've pushed away all other video games except those two.
Rym: I got two I got four I got those two plus Overwatch and fortnight.
Scott: I don't get that.
Scott: forget that.
Scott: All right
Rym: Yep, so, uh in one news and we're not gonna talk about it because you should just read the real news about it But it's big enough for us got to mention it the former guy, you know our piece of shit fascist former president Was arrested for the second time this time on federal charges like for real, right?
Scott: So the first one so the first one was not federal charges.
Rym: It was state charges and it's ongoing.
Rym: So he has an ongoing court case Because he is accused of a huge number of felony like fraud counts by New York State, right?
Scott: so this would be like if I robbed a convenience store, right and then I Did some smuggling of Fireworks like Tennessee to some right and so that one of them is crossing state borders and that's a federal crime.
Scott: Maybe like.
Scott: maybe I did.
Scott: just like some I flew a plane in with smuggled some drugs into the country.
Scott: It's a federal crime RICO act right and then I also robbed a convenience store.
Scott: so when I robbed the convenience store the court in New York is gonna be like, hey, that's like Larceny or theft or something, you know, some burglary Aggravated something right?
Scott: They'll probably get a whole list of charges Beating up the convenience store guy.
Rym: you're hereby accused of aggravated something.
Scott: And then so so they got.
Scott: so they're they're arresting me in New York, but meanwhile, there's some some other law enforcement somewhere else.
Scott: He's like, hey, we saw this Scott robbed the convenience store, but he also smuggled drugs into the country.
Scott: So we need to bring into this other court also.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then it's like if I let's say I get found guilty in both courts and they they want like one year of jail each.
Scott: It's like I don't know which one I go to first But it's like you don't get to you don't get to double up, right?
Scott: I would have to be in like a federal prison for a year And then when I get as soon as I get out New York would be there to collect me.
Scott: Take me to the New York prison for the second year and those crimes I mentioned obviously wouldn't be one year each.
Scott: But that's the kind of scenario we could see here.
Scott: if he's guilty on Charges in and counts in both cases and who knows if even more cases.
Rym: Well, there are.
Rym: so they're in Atlanta, right?
Rym: There's a Georgia case which is around Literally trying to steal the election like real just in Georgia.
Rym: Separately, there's the Jack.
Rym: There's the special counsel case of did he commit treason on January 6th and tried to steal the election?
Scott: But the point is if he gets multiple guilties from all around right all these sentences could pile up.
Scott: and if he survives one Sentence then, you know, I don't know how they're gonna decide who goes first, right?
Scott: Or whatever.
Scott: but they there could be.
Scott: as a day we're like, oh Trump gets out of prison and Well, so just the new case that he was arrested for on Tuesday that day could come so he would hopefully live to see that day.
Rym: I watched legal Eagles like Explanation of the indictment and he was like.
Rym: this is like the most Agro indictment I have ever seen.
Rym: like it is.
Rym: it is making it clear that this is like.
Rym: There's even photos of the boxes like in all the different places in the indictment not even like in the case.
Scott: They're in the indictment itself in black and white with my very limited Untrained not lawyer legal knowledge.
Scott: I'm pretty sure that any Federal charges they always have to have grand juries for federal charges.
Scott: Isn't that right?
Rym: I know and in fact the grand jury made the decision to indict independent of what any prosecutor wanted to do exactly.
Scott: So, I don't know people who aren't in the u.s I don't know if you have grand juries But what they are is basically but you know You're gonna have a trial.
Scott: if someone's a criminal you're gonna have a trial to determine if they're guilty or not guilty.
Scott: You have two lawyer two sets of lawyers.
Scott: all the evidence comes out.
Scott: There's a judge this jury you present your case You cross examine the witnesses and you get the other case and the jury has to basically with be Unanimous.
Rym: and the jury is like are you absolutely guilty or is there doubt, right?
Scott: There's always gonna be a standard in the u.s.
Scott: The standard for crimes is beyond reasonable doubt, right?
Scott: Anyway, but there's a grand jury and so it's for certain things.
Scott: before you do the regular trial You have this grand jury where basically the prosecutors right the people who work for the government right that the law the you know The cops.
Rym: now
Scott: the cop lawyer right gets a bunch of people together, you know normal people and he's like, here's all the evidence I got about that former guy and the crimes he did right and he's basically like do all you people think That I should go and try to have a real trial.
Scott: Yeah, right like.
Scott: and if they say if they say right They're like they're like, you know, it's basically sort of like.
Scott: hey if this was a real trial Do you think I could get a guilty right?
Scott: Do you think right?
Scott: should we press charges?
Scott: Which charges should we press?
Scott: How about this one?
Scott: Do you think he did that?
Scott: or do you think right?
Scott: and then the grand jury decides?
Rym: You know what you can and it's a really important check because this way if someone is very like likely not guilty The grand jury is like this case doesn't make sense.
Scott: Yeah Don't you don't waste our government's time and money having a trial for that crime when you got that flimsy evidence.
Scott: get this out of here.
Rym: Yeah also don't waste time of the person you're trying to indict and don't like slander them effectively by Announcing this charge and then they just get thrown out in court.
Rym: It's a pretty good check.
Rym: The fact that they got a grand jury to be like the fact right.
Scott: so when you get a grand jury to not only say Yes, you should do this trial but to say yes to this huge pile of charges and counts Yeah, right means that whatever they showed the grand jury Evidence-wise must have been very convincing and therefore it is also likely to be very convincing to a regular jury.
Rym: Yep, and the last thing I'll leave you all with is this one alone.
Rym: The maximum sentence for these 37 charges and this one indictment is a little over 100 years in federal prison.
Scott: Yeah, don't do federal crime.
Rym: Yeah, one of my favorite folks lately.
Rym: I don't even know where I got it from or if I made it up But as your lawyer, I advise you to not have done the things that you did.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So the federal crime don't do it.
Rym: and some other news.
Scott: there's been a string of Important famous or well-known people dying recently Alright, so let's do some some chronological order here cuz we got goods and bads, right?
Scott: So first one right sad news The Iron Sheik, so if you don't know the Iron Sheik, he was a professional wrestler.
Scott: is his history, right?
Scott: He came from Iran right back in the 70s 80s.
Scott: I forget the exact year, right?
Scott: He was actually like this really like his life story is pretty amazing But you know what he did it in pro wrestling like at the time.
Scott: It's like he was just sort of.
Scott: you know, he started out as like a good guy But then he basically turned into the bad guy, right?
Scott: Yeah, and I guess in some ways that you know sort of stoked right some Islamophobia Right at the time period right.
Scott: and Hulk Hogan was always like played his real American song.
Scott: We have American flags and shit right but it's like Iron Sheik was really good at it, right?
Scott: But over time right.
Scott: it's like, you know, his his contributions and his talents who are more recognized.
Scott: But of course like anyone in pro wrestling especially back in those days, you know It did.
Scott: his reward for his work was not great.
Rym: You know most pro wrestlers the reward for their work is dementia caused by head trauma and poverty, right?
Scott: He was also, you know helped.
Scott: there was a Twitter account that you know Let's.
Scott: he didn't run the Twitter account.
Scott: That's right It's me but the Twitter account while it was a funny which is good never hurts to be funny But be I think helped, you know promote his existence and appreciation of the person even though he wasn't the one doing those tweets.
Scott: Yeah, so But yeah, he passed away.
Scott: It's very sad.
Scott: You can.
Scott: there's plenty of information if you want to learn about him.
Scott: Okay on the list of graves to drag your behind on.
Scott: Pat Robertson noted I guess I don't want a piece of shit maybe like pile of diarrhea.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: So this dude was basically a right-wing Christian nut job.
Rym: He is almost personally responsible for the rise of the political Is a right in him is a significant a significant contributor.
Scott: He had this TV show and basically on TV in a lot of places like on the weekend He would just be sitting there right and all these Christian people would be watching him And he would say all kinds of awful shit
Rym: like really crazy stuff about witches are like indoctrinating your kids right.
Scott: all that like everything that you like think of is like stereotypes of well, not stereotypes.
Scott: truth right of Right-wing Christian nutty people like Pokemon is the devil.
Scott: D&D would do this right.
Scott: gay people are going to hell etc.
Scott: All right Every racist every ist in the universe is embodied within this dude.
Rym: He poisoned like a whole generation of American adults minds, right?
Scott: And now he's dead.
Scott: good Obviously, I don't think there's a hell but he believed in one.
Rym: Yeah I hope he was right so that he could go there, you know There's a culture book where there's a society that when someone dies they copy their brain And if they decide they were a bad person they put them in a virtual hell forever Mm-hmm.
Scott: So I guess the third person a sad story again, right?
Scott: At the young age of 38, right?
Scott: Ian McGinty has passed away.
Scott: If you don't know who Ian McGinty is he was a comic artist who also worked, you know on Adventure time being puppycat invaders.
Scott: right things you've heard of right and by all accounts everyone I know who's ever, you know, I guess worked with him Talked to him, right?
Scott: I do know people who've worked with him.
Scott: Basically, he was just like, you know, one of those people that like everybody loves like the greatest dude right ever And he worked in comics and his final tweet somehow Poetically and soul-crushingly was like like.
Scott: I just want to make comics with everybody right like that kind of person and It's probably you know, I don't know his exact cause of Death but you know the discussions that people have been having online are basically like yeah, you know Obviously comics don't pay.
Scott: well, right?
Scott: You know and this dude was like overworking himself making lots and lots of comics and definitely every comic artist I know over works themselves for almost no money Right, and I mean, you know, there is valid criticism to be had.
Scott: I wrote this in the forum of the comic publishers who do not compensate artists.
Scott: Well, that's been true since uh, Comic books were a thing, right?
Scott: Marvel was not you know, Jack Kirby.
Scott: You can go all the way back.
Scott: You can go in further back than that right to find comic book artists in the US and Japan and anywhere else.
Scott: I guess maybe in France you you you get okay with your you know, bond sna whatever.
Scott: I don't know how they're compensated but Yeah, it's not a you know, the fact is is that yes, the publishers aren't treating people Well, but the reality is that there just isn't enough money to treat people.
Rym: Well, yeah across the board everywhere not just in comics, but there's so many industries where Society values something but not individuals don't value it enough to pay much of anything for it.
Scott: think about the Imagine.
Scott: if I started if I tried to start a comic book publisher the the best one I would just the nicest Does everything the cool legit way?
Scott: I treat my labor like the best way right that whatever is I give them amazing deals, right?
Scott: It's like okay, so people buy comics.
Scott: I get revenue.
Scott: Well, I got to pay for the printing I got to pay for the advertising I got to pay for all the staff Salaries right the editors myself, of course, and I could have paid myself zero, right?
Scott: Yeah, even I'm not paying myself millions though like an evil person just a regular amount, you know.
Scott: So we take all the costs out of doing business, right?
Scott: you know insurance all the things you need for a business the electricity and Then I take the all the rest of the revenues from the comic book that sold and I divide it fairly Among the actual artists who worked on that book.
Scott: right eat unless the book is some ridiculous Crazy bestseller, right?
Scott: They're not gonna be making a lot of money Right.
Scott: Yeah, it's just.
Scott: it just isn't that much money for them to be.
Rym: look at us.
Rym: think of it.
Rym: I would eat that there's a video game.
Scott: even if it sells really well, it won't be enough unless it sells extremely well.
Rym: think about a video game that's pretty good and you look at it.
Rym: you think you know what.
Rym: if that were cheaper like If it was a dollar I might buy it.
Scott: Yeah, so so sad story.
Scott: the passing of Ian McGinty.
Scott: Okay, not sad story again, right person who?
Rym: I have a guess who the next one is.
Rym: I haven't seen your list.
Scott: Oh, there's a Mr.
Scott: Noted mathematician The park headline was famous mathematician has died Yeah, so if you weren't around in the 90s, you might not remember the 80s.
Scott: Yeah, but there was basically, you know, this this mystery there's a Unabomber.
Scott: They called him the Unabomber because he was bombing sending bombs like two universities, right?
Rym: Like it's our universities and airlines like the CEO and airline was killed by one of these true.
Scott: so basically someone just like sending bombs in the mail and you like open up the mail and a bomb goes off and Many people were severely injured.
Scott: Some people were literally killed by opening up and there was a bomb and it went off when they opened the thing and actually worked over the span of 17 years.
Rym: he was getting away with this to the point that it was.
Rym: it was one of those things that like everyone in America knew about this guy and was Low-key like either afraid of them or like would think about it a little bit when like a.
Scott: well if you were in up as you Know an airline, you know You know like an academic that might draw it similar to the other people who had received them Then you might be afraid and want to check your mail right.
Scott: normal people weren't?
Scott: it's like it wasn't gonna bomb, you know It's me.
Rym: Well, it was more than he was in.
Rym: it was in the news a lot.
Rym: So people had undue fear.
Scott: because it's such a story, right?
Scott: It's like people are getting bombs in the mail and dying.
Scott: Where are they coming from?
Rym: Right and to get away with it for 17 years and then the way he got caught was actually kind of nuts.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: it's like such a mystery right like the zodiac killer mystery or you know The?
Scott: you know, what's a good?
Scott: Jack the Ripper?
Scott: the mystery?
Scott: Who was it?
Scott: Right?
Scott: Who's?
Scott: who's doing this?
Scott: We can tell by the evidence by the patterns.
Scott: It's definitely the same person doing this.
Scott: It's not it's a repeat offender.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: It's like, you know the same reason people love Silence of the Lambs Like this is like a real-life.
Rym: I think there's an extra weird thing.
Rym: The thing that was going on that made this one scary to a lot of people was that unlike most crazy stuff like this Most criminals aren't that careful or that good.
Rym: there aren't like criminal masterminds out there who write.
Scott: most people who try to bomb things.
Scott: They're not smart and their bombs hurt themselves or don't work.
Scott: It's very rare for someone to be good enough and evil enough right.
Scott: usually someone who's smart enough to like make a bomb that can go through the mail and go off at the right Time and work is a smart intelligent person who that could succeed in society and wouldn't do that.
Scott: It's very rare that you have this combination of evil and smart enough to do evil, yep possibly crazy because the reasons he bombed were Yeah, shall we say like.
Rym: this is not a documentary.
Rym: you can watch a documentary if you're read Wikipedia.
Scott: But basically when they caught him it was a huge.
Scott: it was like the biggest news.
Scott: It was like 20 was like ever.
Scott: all the news is talking about this for days and days and days when they finally caught this.
Rym: You know and I remember because I was in high school When like the trial was gonna happen and he just played guilty like he didn't try to hide any of it.
Rym: when they caught him He was like, yep.
Rym: I was a bomber.
Rym: Let's talk about why I bombed like.
Rym: let's go.
Scott: So, yeah f that guy.
Scott: yeah, he was weird Herman in the woods.
Scott: interesting story for like, you know TV but You know, I think that often distracts people from the fact that no that was an evil dude.
Scott: Yeah He died in prison right where he wasn't gonna get out of that prison ever.
Scott: Anyway, so he was gonna die there eventually.
Scott: Yeah, okay the next right we have someone I've heard of which is the author Cormac McCarthy.
Scott: I've heard many people talk about these books.
Scott: I think some of them have been turned into movies, but you know what?
Scott: I've never read them maybe but ever I've read the road.
Rym: That's the only one I've heard of the road.
Scott: I know that that is a book.
Scott: I know that there is a book called the road by Cormac McCarthy and that is where my knowledge ends.
Rym: It's uh a lot of post-apocalyptic stuff cribs pretty like that from it.
Rym: Yeah It's got some problems like it's a it's a fine book and it broke some new ground.
Rym: But it's also got some significant problems.
Rym: is what I'm gonna say.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Well regardless this is a person who is making aforementioned bestsellers enough money to do.
Scott: well You know clearly a lot of people, you know had you know Very strong positive feelings towards many of his works and I don't know anything else about it.
Scott: It's just a huge famous person who's on the list of people who've died in like the last week.
Scott: So next right a really sad one, right.
Scott: so John Romita senior if people don't know All right, spider-man was by Stanley obviously and Steve Ditko was the artist, right?
Scott: Steve Ditko Had a mysterious fight with Stan Lee.
Scott: Alright, no one knows exactly what they fought over But after so many issues of spider-man They they split right and Steve Ditko went to go be a hermit who hid away in an office writing libertarian weirdo Comics, that's a charitable way to describe that.
Scott: but yeah, I Steve Ditko is amazing artist And I and by all accounts, I guess according to Neil Gaiman and other people who've met him like a nice guy to meet.
Scott: Yeah, I think he died a while ago.
Scott: or is he still alive?
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: but regardless After Steve Ditko left spider-man Stan Lee's 18.
Rym: He passed away.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I thought I remember him anyway after Steve Ditko left spider-man.
Scott: He's like.
Scott: well spider-man is the biggest thing since sliced bread in 1960 early 70s whenever that was, right?
Scott: It was only a few years.
Scott: in meanwhile No worthy.
Rym: in the year 2023 the previous episode of GeekNights spider-man is still the biggest thing since sliced bread.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Spider-man is the thing Stan Lee's like shit.
Scott: I got to get someone to draw this spider-man, right?
Rym: I need someone to draw pictures of spider-man That's right.
Scott: So he found this guy right John Romita and John Romita was basically doing like romance comics over at DC Right and if you look at his romance comics like you can see why You know Whatever criticism you want to have a Stan Lee, right?
Scott: It's like he was able to recognize that.
Scott: you know, this guy who was doing romance comics in that style, right?
Scott: You know doing not so much the action right of the other comic artists, right or like the wild stuff like Jack Kirby was doing right, but It's like that, you know soap opera emotion is what spider-man needed and so and you know John Romita was just gonna go and do like advertising work, right and make a bunch of money.
Scott: Stan Lee was like I will pay you whatever they're gonna pay you.
Scott: I'll match the salary, right?
Scott: You're the guy I need you to be the guy to draw the spider-man.
Scott: All right, and John Romita senior went on to draw spider-man for like a very long time.
Rym: They probably like he was part of that.
Rym: He was part of the creation of Wolverine.
Scott: He was yeah, he was probably Mary Jane, right?
Scott: Punisher Yeah, it's like.
Scott: this is an incredibly significant and important person in comics history in the US And the thing is.
Scott: it's like, you know, if you think about comic artists, right?
Scott: It's like a lot of them have like a unique Style to them and you can sort of see their style like oh, you know, you see like something that's all like a huge oil Painting.
Scott: it's like oh, it's an Alex Ross right?
Scott: You see some wild thing.
Scott: It's like oh, it's a that's a Bill Sienkiewicz over there right, but it's like John Romita.
Scott: The way he draws is like the default way.
Scott: It's like, you know everyone else right in comics.
Scott: It was like remixing him.
Scott: He was like the original track It's.
Scott: obviously he didn't invent spider-man right and to an extent extent when he started out.
Scott: He was trying to like, you know maintain the same style that Ditko had started.
Scott: but It's like you know, you see like a picture of spider-man and it's like that's what spider-man normally looks like.
Scott: It's like no, that's spider-man.
Scott: the way John Romita draws spider-man He just right is the way in the normal way, right?
Scott: So to be that good at art that your way ends up being the defining way Like that's the default style that everyone else is building upon you right is is I think not Appreciated enough.
Rym: Oh, yeah kingpin - yeah.
Scott: Yeah all these right.
Scott: It's like this is like reading.
Scott: and then so the other thing is that he had a child Right who is known as jr.
Scott: Jr.
Scott: John Romita jr.
Scott: Who also became Perhaps an equally legendary comic artist right and is still alive.
Scott: He went into dad's family business, right?
Scott: So The Romita family is truly You know, I don't think you would have yeah would.
Scott: I don't think you'd have any of the Marvel shit you got now Right Disney wouldn't own it.
Scott: It wouldn't be movies, right?
Scott: It wouldn't have become as big.
Scott: right because like what if Stan Lee after Ditko dropped out spider-man after a few years Right had had to get someone else who had some different style.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: instead of it's like iconic consistent style Right.
Scott: It's like what would spider-man it?
Scott: you know might have ended up just being a fad of the times or it might have been a lesser intellectual property that comes and goes now and then like a Transformers my little pony level of you know instead of being a universally recognized thing.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So Very sad the passing of John Romita and I think those are all the people have died But which is amazing because somehow fucking Henry Kissinger is still alive.
Scott: We can talk about that But I would the thing I want to talk about is that The a lot of these people who passed away right their ages were in 80s 90s, right except for You know Ian McGouty, right?
Scott: And so these people are Boomers, right.
Scott: and what we call the boomers because there was a baby boom.
Scott: There was a period of time in America where more after the war a lot of people made babies more babies Than at other times more babies than the previous generation and the following generations, right?
Scott: So because a large portion, you know, if you look at how many people in the u.s Are in a certain age right group, right?
Scott: That's the biggest one Except for the fact that now they're old right they're dying.
Scott: But if there's more of them, you'll see more of them dying.
Rym: It's the biggest generation in American history.
Rym: a high percent of them are at the end of their ticket, right?
Scott: So when they start dying, you will see more of them dying, you know.
Scott: And you know a number of famous people that are in that category is also greater because presumably the number of famous people is Evenly distributed across, you know population, right?
Scott: So you got so.
Scott: therefore Right your.
Scott: I think this is a trend that will just continue on a mathematical basis.
Scott: Yeah, right is?
Scott: you are going to see more frequent celebrity death news of Celebrities who are of that generation until they're all gone and then the slit the rate of celebrity death news is will decrease to match the population of Gen X and this is above and beyond lower the usual.
Rym: like we're like.
Rym: I'm 40 so Most of the famous people I could name are probably about twice as old as me because they were an institution in my life up To this point, so they're all at the end of their tickets too.
Rym: But this isn't.
Rym: this is now come Doubled by the baby boomer situation.
Rym: I didn't even think about the boomers.
Scott: yep, so that's and That's you know, it's bad because obviously, you know of the people we listed Several of them were good.
Scott: It's not like you're a bad person just because you're that old but It bodes well because Overall mathematically speaking that generation of people leans Politically in the direction we don't like.
Scott: yep.
Scott: And if enough of them die and we don't then that bodes well for election results especially
Rym: because that is a generation that has categorically held on to power and Jobs and wealth more so than generations up to that point to the point that that's why Gen X was so frequently.
Rym: So fucked up because they kind of got skipped over like all the Gen Xers Hit the top of their careers and then some boomer was their boss who didn't retire so they had nowhere to go.
Rym: They couldn't be promoted.
Scott: Yeah, and it was still boomers.
Scott: Yeah, so not only will the election results be swayed by these, you know mortality But also right when those boomers die, you know, they're there and they might have inheritors.
Scott: It's likely.
Scott: but even if they don't right that wealth goes to the state or wherever they Willed it to go some trust or organization or who knows.
Scott: but at least it will be free of them And there will be some increasing downward pressure of the wealth finally coming, you know, it's like Okay from your cold dead hands here we got it.
Rym: when a whale dies It sinks to the bottom of the sea and all those resources get redistributed exactly, so it's that will benefit society in a hidden way particularly when Kissinger finally bites it.
Rym: because I wonder Waypo just had an article that I'll link to because it's just great.
Rym: but at the time the title is just Henry Kissinger is turning a hundred.
Rym: a long-running meme wishes otherwise and it goes into detail about How Millennials and younger hate Kissinger and it's justified like fuck him.
Scott: So yeah, like I want to if you don't know like I mean if you want to talk about, you know We're talking about Trump II crimes, right?
Scott: It's like, you know what Trump did a lot of crimes and deserves many consequences for those crimes and has damaged society greatly right, but Kissinger did more of the war crimes right crimes against humanity.
Rym: I mean Trump might had.
Scott: Trump might have done some of those while he was in office.
Scott: Well here we go.
Scott: Is he mostly?
Scott: he's done the financial crimes when W's invaded Iraq for no reason.
Rym: You know the second time like when there was no reason to do it tons of war crimes happened And that was a horrible situation and they should have been tried in the hog.
Rym: But yep at the same time Yeah, but at the same time am I saying it right?
Rym: Yeah, hey Okay, I just saw I like almost swallowed.
Rym: I had like a phlegm.
Rym: Hi I never heard of the high but the collected war crimes of the US Iraq invasion as horrific as they were pale in comparison to what happened because Henry Kissinger opened his fucking mouth.
Rym: I'm gonna read one short quote.
Rym: I don't want to dwell on it because we want to get into the rest of the show.
Rym: But this is a quote you will never guess who said this Once you've been to Cambodia, you'll never stop wanting to beat Henry Kissinger to death with your bare hands.
Rym: You will never again be able to open a newspaper and read about that treacherous prevaricating murderous scumbag Sitting down for a nice chat with Charlie Rose or attending some black-tie affair for a new glossy magazine without choking.
Rym: Witness what Henry did in Cambodia the fruits of his genius for statesmanship and you will never Understand why he's not sitting and in the dock at the Hague next to Milosevic.
Rym: and that is a quote from Anthony Bourdain The chef.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that makes sense.
Scott: Yeah so he can't last that much longer and It's he is like you got when you have money and power that helps you last longer like.
Rym: at this point I think only Vladimir Putin might be like a person a human being who is still alive who has committed more total war crimes.
Rym: Maybe there's got to be some.
Scott: so there's a lot of You know, there's like a lot of really shitty dictators that people don't pay attention to because you know Like like, you know you get down to.
Rym: like Eritrea like the president of Eritrea is like is like the worst Nevermind And even yeah, so now Hussein did not deserve what happened to him and Iraq shouldn't have been invaded But he was still an absolute war criminal who deserves lots of war crime.
Scott: Yep I mean, I guess I don't know who you want to lay things on like, you know, China and the Uyghurs and yeah
Rym: but Kissinger the
Scott: the
Rym: most amazing thing is despite the fact that he's turning a hundred he seems to still 100% defend everything he did as moral and just and right and fuck the haters.
Scott: Well, I mean if you didn't change when you were 40 What makes you?
Scott: why would you ever expect something to change when they're like 90 your war crimes in your 40s.
Rym: He didn't change it when you were 80 and now you're 100 but anyway things of the day.
Rym: so, uh, you know play video games play D&D just Anything about history and you know vaguely that slings are a thing, you know call a rope You kind of swing it around and you can throw a rock real hard with it and you can throw that.
Scott: David and Goliath Come up.
Rym: or like any medieval or Roman military game where there's slinger units even fantasy empires had the hot.
Rym: the It had the halfling slingers was a unit.
Scott: you can recruit my very first second ed character cleric, right?
Scott: You couldn't use an edged weapon for some reason at a club in a sling.
Scott: I had I had a sling.
Rym: I just yeah, and the most famous and prolific kind of sling in the world is probably the Balearic sling Which is the one you're all imagining when you think of a sling other.
Scott: It's a couple.
Scott: it's a couple strings and a piece of leather and you put a rock in it and you swing it around.
Rym: So it is an ancient ancient ancient thing and there is like you could spend your entire life studying just this one Invention of humans possibly even invented Prehuman like.
Rym: that's the level of monkeys made it.
Rym: What I hominid prior to humans may have been involved because it was already a giraffe made one.
Rym: This was already a dinosaur.
Scott: T-rex was out there like
Rym: you know total aside, but I was reading a paper making a strong argument that based on how archaeology has gone so far a society about as advanced as humans Pre-industrialization could have existed before the previous big cataclysm and there would be no evidence of it for us to ever find.
Scott: It's possible.
Rym: It is possible.
Rym: I'm not saying it's plausible or probable but anyway this video in six minutes and 35 seconds will actually explain how this thing works and it's Really really cool how it works.
Scott: I mean, I thought I knew how it worked, but I guess I'll watch it and see if I'm wrong.
Rym: Yep, so it's got a trigger.
Rym: It's kind of like a gun.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, I knew that.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Rym: Most people I don't think know that.
Scott: All right, we'll see We'll see if I'm right I'm.
Rym: so it might be you and I are in the rare demographic of people who know more about this stuff than an average person Mostly because of video games and movies, I guess.
Rym: so What do you got?
Scott: Oh, so you've seen a lot of people especially, you know Astrophotographers, they love to do this one shot where you do a time-lapse Right with it with a big wide-angle lens and you you keep it completely still in a place that doesn't have light pollution.
Scott: And what happens is at night, right?
Scott: It's like you get.
Scott: you know, you see the sunrise You see the sunset and you see the stars right up above and then you see that the Milky Way and everything move Across the sky throughout the night.
Scott: and it's not that the stars are moving.
Scott: Oh, they are but it's that the earth is rotating.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: And therefore you're looking at a different in a different direction in space right in a you know, I guess it's 180 degrees Right.
Scott: because until you get back to the Sun again, right?
Scott: And that's a very common time-lapse that you see.
Scott: But in those time lapses right the earth is always just like at the bottom and like whatever you're looking at the cityscape Usually won't be a cityscape but you know trees or a mountain or it will just be sitting there And it'll change because the light will shine upon it and move but it's sort of just a static bottom of the frame.
Scott: So here art universe creative astrophotography.
Scott: Who's the photographer?
Scott: Does it even say?
Scott: Copyright Bartosz Wojcicki.
Scott: I hope I pronounced your name correctly.
Scott: Bartosz Had the genius idea.
Scott: I've never seen this before but it's sort of like obvious once you think about it.
Scott: But instead of locking the camera just on a tripod which means it's stuck to the earth You arrange so that instead the camera is locked at a specific point in the sky Right.
Scott: So now what you have is the same basic time-lapse But the sky doesn't move right the stars stay put and instead you see the earth rotating, right.
Scott: And it's really fascinating to just you know have this idea and then to see it executed and then just to see the night sky Stuck in place because really that is the thing that's stuck in place right and then to see the earth move.
Scott: You know, and I guess if you did this shot at different points in the earth, the rotation would be different.
Rym: Yeah So the closest I've seen I've seen people do this with like stunt tricks where they'll have a GoPro like mounted on their head pointing At their face.
Scott: so the world moves around them, but they're always like locked static instead Right, like if you did this at the North Pole It would be like a static shot basically like nothing would.
Scott: but if you did this at the equator It would be like really wild right?
Scott: It might make you dizzy if you do so.
Scott: Good job Bartosz.
Rym: yeah in the meta moment.
Rym: The geek dies book club was the satanic versus it is now.
Rym: This is how you lose the time war as recommended to us.
Scott: I guess I have to make a post.
Rym: I guess you do buy out one Bigelow's dickless wolf would.
Rym: Websites coming along Scott's working out a bunch of stuff.
Rym: I'm working on a much smaller piece list of things and We're gonna try to launch it.
Rym: I'm not gonna say any dates or schedules out loud on the show, but we've got some plans that are specific.
Scott: But you keep mentioning the person who recommended the time war because it's just a really funny name.
Scott: You should mention the author's Amal El-Moltar and I would.
Rym: I just didn't have it open in my.
Rym: I'm just looking at website and I went here because I hoped you'd made the post so I could just read the summary.
Rym: But you didn't.
Scott: so I'll make the post and that will help you remember it.
Rym: well okay, so uh, I think otherwise, let's just get right into it.
Rym: because Airplane food and airline food.
Scott: Yeah, this is art.
Scott: This is our new low-effort Thursday idea and we don't have another Thursday idea, right?
Scott: We already done so many food episodes, but we realized we can do this combo food plus place, right?
Scott: Yeah So we last time we were gonna do food plus stadium We ended up just doing stadium and that was already a long episode, right?
Scott: So now Rym got the idea.
Scott: We'll start with food plus Airport.
Scott: Maybe food plus stadium will come down the line.
Rym: Yeah so, uh One thing I got.
Scott: so this will be anecdotal mostly but I can say that my opinion you want to expand it to food plus Travel so you can do train food also or just do food Airport.
Rym: I think we should just do Airport because train food and air and airplane Train food also is such a different experience and I have a lot of very specific long-winded things to say about depends on the train Too.
Rym: Yeah anyway, but what I can say is that Sometime between the 90s and the mid to late 2010s Airplane food just got an order of magnitude better even at the bottom end.
Rym: Like I don't know what happened between food science or budgets or what and I'm not saying it got good.
Rym: But if you are too young to have ever eaten food Even in like business class or first class on a domestic American flight Before like in the 90s or the 80s.
Rym: It was basically poison.
Scott: Yeah, it used to be like a common joke like, you know Airline food, right?
Scott: It's like is awful the same way that like you'd have that joke.
Scott: We're like kids Brussels sprouts Spinach you right?
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: we know.
Scott: the reason that we like Brussels sprouts and spinach now is because they are literally not the Same as what people were eating.
Rym: Yeah on the 50s and 60s and basically old food on old airlines Especially in the 80s 90s was basically the same as a TV dinner.
Rym: If you don't know what that is Imagine the worst frozen food on earth.
Scott: Yeah, and so a lot of that is just you know, what's available in terms of food technology, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, we've invented a lot of you know, food processing techniques over You know the time that we've had airplanes and there's a lot of constraints when it comes to what kind of food Can you have on a plane right?
Scott: How how long is the flight at the flights longer?
Scott: You need food that's gonna be stable for the flight.
Scott: You need a place on the plane right to keep the food refrigerate or heat or whatever you're gonna do to the food, right?
Scott: It's like old old planes Couldn't really have a big fancy kitchen on.
Scott: We didn't invent that till you know.
Rym: later or even if we did one that's expensive.
Rym: If you have a kitchen like a real kitchen one How long is it gonna take to cook food in it?
Rym: and two that's a bunch of seats?
Rym: You're not selling because you're taking How many people are on the plane in mind.
Rym: you want to be a chef cooking with fire and then there's turbulence.
Scott: So right we invented the microwave.
Scott: at some point, you know, the airplanes are older than microwave ovens.
Scott: I'm pretty sure.
Rym: Ah Actually, so microwaves are really old Scott they can't hear they.
Scott: yeah, let's see invention of microwave oven 76. yeah All right invention of airplane.
Rym: Well invention of airplane versus If I first commercial spoke mass market transcontinental flight.
Scott: first commercial air flight was in 1914.
Rym: yeah, well that was a that was a different world.
Rym: That was very rich people, but I mean dangerous.
Scott: But if you're putting the microwave in the 70s, there were definitely people just flying in the 50s, right?
Rym: or you know And I don't know what airplane food was like in that era, but I imagine it was not exist.
Scott: I mean even if you think about like, you know Casablanca that movie came out in the 40s and it was just portraying normal people flying.
Scott: Yeah, so So at least 30 normal very rich people.
Scott: Yes, but that's still like 30 years between planes and microwave Flights couldn't be that long because he had to refuel.
Rym: a lot of long flights would stop a bunch of times along the way to Refuel get more food passenger or passengers would get out and eat the plane would refuel they get back out.
Rym: It would take off again Exactly.
Rym: Yeah, but in the in the modern era like in our era 80s 90s onward.
Rym: It was basically just awful food until recently.
Rym: So for most of my life until I'd say the 2010s My rule was never fucking eat on a plane ever.
Rym: It's not worth it eat before you close to eat after you fly never eat on the plane.
Scott: Well, I think just due to circumstance, right?
Scott: I didn't have too much experience with food on planes because Almost I think almost all the flights that I took in the last millennium the previous millennium Were short enough that there wasn't really like you weren't missing a meal on the flight to Florida, right?
Scott: It's like you and they would maybe bring a snack.
Scott: you would just get something that was you know, a shelf-stable cookie pretzel Right a water.
Rym: Let's remember the TSA until September 11th didn't exist.
Rym: So like when I flew in high school, you could just bring food and drink and anything you wanted on the plane.
Scott: No one cared Yep, and I think the first time I ate airline food was on my foot Israel, right?
Scott: So in the year 2000 Yeah, so this millennium and I don't remember what the food on the plane that was not a concern And it was really long.
Scott: So it was.
Rym: The microwave was invented for food production in 1946.
Rym: I don't know where you got.
Scott: was it on airplanes in 19?
Scott: was it something you could?
Rym: I think it might have been too big to Put on an airplane at that time.
Rym: Yeah anyway Uh Yeah, go to Israel first long flight.
Scott: Yeah, I mean that was it.
Scott: That was the first time I had food on an airplane and I don't remember it.
Rym: I think the longest flight I went on before I had a job that made me fly a lot or when Scott and I started Going to Pax's was going to Florida for band stuff as a kid But I didn't fly a ton.
Rym: So flying was always such a special thing that like packing your own lunch or like eating big meal and then going to the airport Just always made sense like until my adult life flight.
Rym: I wasn't like I was flying all the time.
Rym: Like I couldn't afford that.
Rym: So I sort of there was the era where Scott and I would fly a lot to Pax's like going out to Pax West every year became a thing.
Rym: and are we specifically would always fly JetBlue because it used to be good and Their deal was they wouldn't have a meal on the plane.
Rym: You could optionally pay for one, but it was added that yeah added that eventually and it was a simple meal.
Scott: It was basically this the meals that you could buy are basically adult lunchables.
Scott: Yeah, it's like things like crackers cut up fruits cheeses a chocolate and some grapes Maybe maybe a sandwich that was pre-prepared and refrigerated Things along those lines that you know, really, you know now there wasn't any cooking involved.
Scott: It wasn't like someone fried an egg for you or anything of that nature, right?
Rym: But that that era.
Rym: what we did and it became a thing is because JetBlue had a good terminal at our airport in JFK.
Rym: they had actually Wall overpriced pretty good restaurants in that terminal like above and beyond the phone.
Scott: That was after they built the new terminal.
Scott: There was the older terminal true true.
Scott: That was not as good.
Rym: It was not as good
Scott: but it was the thing with Okay, so the thing with terminal food right is that the first thing you have to realize is that at least in the United States Right, which restaurants get to be in the terminals is not determined by how good their food is or anything of that nature.
Scott: right because Airports are like such a bureaucratic thing with the FAA and all sorts of other business going on.
Scott: The person who gets to put a restaurant there is the person who is good At dealing with that bureaucracy.
Scott: Yeah So a lot of it is like these food service companies that specialize in knowing how to get their restaurants in airports, right and Those aren't necessarily the ones with the best food.
Scott: A lot of them are very Cafeteria style, right?
Rym: I mean the ones that are already are like the bad Delta terminal at JFK.
Rym: That's often like that separate building like it's just frozen.
Rym: It's basically the same as airplane food, right?
Scott: They want to give they want to put in, you know They don't care about how good the food is because there isn't really competition in there, right?
Scott: They have this captive audience.
Scott: you are in the terminal, right?
Scott: If you are making like a transfer and you're in that terminal you're gonna have.
Scott: if you want food Unless you got your own food, you're gonna be eating at one of those places.
Rym: You don't have time to leave and come back and because of the TSA you couldn't bring your own lunch Right.
Scott: So as a captive audience, you're gonna buy one of these foods.
Scott: So we're gonna charge you as much as we can for the cheapest food that we can and Just do what we have to do to get away with that.
Scott: Yeah now, you know you could if you're like smart You know eat and then go to the airport, right?
Scott: The problem is is that even if we got rid of TSA and everything There would still be like this waiting that happens.
Scott: Like you're not showing up five minutes before your flight.
Scott: That's not happening Right.
Scott: So even if you ate in advance, it's like there might be like this time period where it's like, you know You know some people I think a lot of people.
Scott: it's like you're gonna want to eat something Before you get on the plane at least a snack right and they can get you at the snack bar.
Rym: Yeah, cuz the snacks in the airport are crazy expensive and also bad and limited, right?
Scott: It's like ah, even even if you want to buy something totally safe, right?
Scott: It's like ah, you want to buy a bag of peanut M&M that normally costs at most a dollar.
Scott: a dollar 25.
Scott: They're like seven bucks, right?
Scott: You talk about movie theaters captive audience, right?
Scott: It's like this is worse than that and the selection so limited.
Rym: I remember I was in Chicago for some reason.
Rym: Me and Emily were though.
Rym: Yeah, I was for a wedding.
Rym: So we're in Chicago hair.
Rym: Yeah, we're flying We need to.
Rym: we want we want to drink something other than water like we like a beverage.
Rym: We don't want something alcoholic and I canvassed the entire Terminal.
Rym: there was no beverage I could buy.
Rym: that was not an artificially sweetened like soda type thing A Sweetened tea with like high fructose corn syrup in it or alcohol.
Rym: There was no juice.
Rym: There was nothing.
Rym: like.
Rym: there was no unsweetened tea and usually an orange juice at least there was.
Scott: That's that's of course.
Scott: That's a bunch of sugar.
Rym: But still yeah, it was like it was awful and there was nothing.
Scott: So usually if you go to the place, there'll be a place that has coffee.
Scott: You can usually get tea from them Hot water and throw it's a crappy teabag in it.
Rym: Yeah, but even they they didn't.
Rym: they had like pod tea that had sugar in it already.
Scott: Interest like.
Rym: I was really mad about it.
Rym: I was mad about it for like a month because it's stuck in my.
Scott: you were mad about it cuz you're hungry.
Rym: I was hungry and thirsty and I'd already decided not to your hang because the food your hangar your hangar added to your.
Rym: And that's really how they get you cuz even though you know The food's gonna suck at the airport like it's gonna be awful if you're in a hurry or you're already at the airport and you're hungry.
Rym: your options are go from hungry to hangry or Eat whatever slop at whatever price and just suck it up.
Scott: Now there's a second layer beyond the fact that you're trapped in the airport or on the airplane and there's no competition for food.
Scott: So if you're hungry your choices are be hungrier or pay.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: The second layer is that because you are hungry right hunger is the best spice so That they can give you a lower quality food, right and you'll you you have this hunger spice that will Right.
Scott: It's like they don't have to give you some fucking gourmet meal.
Scott: right for you to think that it's you know Better than it is because you were so hungry that it ends up, you know sort of improving your opinion of the food.
Rym: But even then it hasn't elevated that opinion above like two out of ten on average.
Scott: no Yeah, I think the saddest thing is like, you know when like?
Scott: if you go It's like the airport in New York and you try to get like a bagel with cream cheese.
Scott: It's like it's worse than like some bagel from the middle of the country or so It's like if they don't like why don't you have a New York bagel here?
Scott: it's like they just have the worst like steamed crappy bagel and like a lot of Charge you like seven dollars for it.
Rym: A lot of airports now are even worse.
Rym: They'll have a bunch of different restaurants, but they're actually just branding on the same shared industrial kitchen and the menu.
Scott: That's all of them.
Rym: Yeah, of course There's a few exceptions and most of those exceptions are international terminals in non-us countries, right?
Scott: I think the exceptions at least in the United States are actually surprisingly right.
Scott: the fast food, right?
Scott: It's in an airport like in New York on McDonald's in the airport is the same food as the McDonald's Airport if there's a McDonald's or a Shake Shack or a Wendy's or a Cinnabon or right?
Scott: It's like whatever kind of fast food is in there.
Scott: If you got a Chipotle in the airport, I don't fucking know, right?
Scott: it's like they're gonna be mostly the same as The ones that aren't in the airport and they're gonna have their own kitchen.
Scott: that's separate from the other kitchens and their own employees Right and like those are usually a safer bet in the US.
Rym: now I want you to internalize a sit-down restaurant or Scott Rubin of GeekNights has just said that there is a Scenario where fast food like that might be the better option and I agree with him.
Scott: like 90% of the time I eat at a Shake Shack.
Scott: It's the airport shake.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I have gotten a milkshake for breakfast at that Shake Shack at JFK on multiple occasions, right?
Scott: It's like how often do I go to?
Scott: I can go to Shake Shack whatever the hell I want.
Scott: How often do I go?
Scott: almost never?
Scott: Yeah, maybe once I can't remember.
Scott: Maybe the last time I went to one was when I had a job and I was going in the office.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I was actually recently.
Scott: I was meeting some people from my previous job and There's a Shake Shack downstairs at Grand Central now.
Rym: Oh, I didn't know that.
Scott: so we went.
Scott: we went down there Milkshakes.
Scott: only.
Rym: the last time I ate at a Shake Shack outside an airport was in March of 2019 before kovid because a co-worker wanted to eat there and I wanted to talk to him about non-work stuff.
Rym: So I went with him.
Scott: I went.
Scott: you know, I can't believe.
Scott: it's like I remember going when there was only one Shake Shack.
Scott: It might have been square right and it was the.
Scott: it was the only one and I would wait in line and eat there I would wait in line to.
Rym: Mostly the milkshake was the reason I was waiting in line cuz the burger was okay.
Rym: The burger is actually not the worst burger right.
Scott: the fry was fries.
Rym: Okay, but now they're fucking everywhere Like it's so the other x-factor in an airport, but this is only a privileged option that I only have.
Rym: Yeah, so here's the deal.
Rym: If you don't flood one If you're not flying business class because of rewards from something or your company's paying for it You're probably fucking up because it is so expensive.
Rym: What?
Rym: why would you spend ten thousand dollars to have a slightly nicer six hours on a flight like Exactly.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's like.
Scott: yes is is it uncomfortable in the back of the plane and the in some coach cheapo seat?
Scott: Yes, but you know what.
Scott: the plane goes at the same speed no matter what seat you're in.
Rym: now I would say for super long flights Like if it was ten thousand dollars to fly to Australia business class considering our coach ticket was like four thousand dollars then $6,000 is still like like two Computers.
Rym: Yeah, but that flight is not ten thousand dollars to Australia.
Rym: that flight business class is like twenty five to thirty thousand dollars.
Scott: That's a car right?
Scott: So it's like.
Scott: would you rather have a car or would you rather be a little bit more comfortable?
Scott: For you know some number of hours.
Scott: It's like you're it?
Scott: the flight length is the same.
Scott: So unless you are unseemingly wealthy It's like I will put up with basically whatever discomfort there is.
Scott: Given the price difference.
Rym: now I know the exception I'll make is I will.
Scott: someone else is paying on an international flight.
Rym: if I'm paying I'll almost always pay extra For that premium economy like in the middle because it depends on the price difference.
Rym: Yeah, you know sometimes like 5 to 2 X more and then business class is like 10 X more and then first guys is like 30x more.
Scott: Yeah, if someone else is paying and they're not gonna just like give me like and they're not just give me the money Yeah instead and it's not like an option then Yeah I'll.
Scott: it's like I'll take the airport lounge.
Rym: food is a thing where if you it's one of those traps.
Rym: where if you Experience it enough because like work lets you do it and like you only fly for work the next time you go to an airport and You can't go into that lounge because you're not gonna pay the ridiculous amount of money to have access to it.
Rym: suddenly the airport feels so much shittier because the way those lounges work they just have Super good completely free food.
Rym: You can like order meals in a lot of them and they'll just bring it to you and it's great unlimited alcohol unlimited drinks snacks waiters a shower, but the food is like legit good and I Do always eat in the lounge if I'm flying for work like on either end of my journey.
Scott: Yeah, I mean why wouldn't you write that if you don't eat there that means that's whoever paid for it, right?
Scott: I'll paid the $10,000 for the ticket.
Scott: that in the included in that price is the shower and the food As like.
Scott: if you don't take advantage of that, they're just keeping all that money.
Scott: Yeah, right and it's like even if you do take advantage of it They're still profiting right because the amount of they make so much money on the business tickets.
Scott: That's where like the most of these revenues are right.
Scott: because you think about the square footage of the plane Right the amount of dollars per square foot.
Scott: It's like it's all in the fanciest seats.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: That's where all the money is.
Rym: That's who's paying for the plane to actually if the airlines in the US could get away with just not having coach.
Rym: They would try.
Scott: They would yeah if they thought they could fill the plane also, right?
Scott: Could you get that many people to pay the fancy price for that to fill the whole plane?
Scott: Probably not, right?
Scott: There aren't that many people.
Scott: Who do that?
Rym: So the secret is get the free upgrade or have a program like.
Rym: I have enough points because all my work travel to her.
Rym: now I just have access to the lounges.
Scott: I always found it interesting that works like let employees keep all these points like if I was a work, you know It's like.
Scott: obviously I want to be pro labor because I'm such a nice person, but it's like I'd be like Hey, we're paying for these flights with a company credit card.
Scott: Those points are on the company credit card and we're gonna use those points to get tickets for employees to fly.
Scott: They don't belong to the employee to use for their own shit.
Rym: So why?
Scott: it's like I might use them on you if you're still my employee and for your next flight.
Rym: Look, I look into this a little bit cuz we talked about it a while ago And there's two factors that play a factor one.
Scott: I'm not gonna use it for like your family to go on vacation I'll just pay you well enough.
Scott: Well, you can do that.
Rym: factor one the airlines don't let them do that.
Rym: The points go to a human being.
Rym: they don't go to a corporate account Fancy.
Rym: okay, partly because the airlines They they.
Rym: basically if an airline or a codeshare gets you business traveler to put your Business traveler loyalty program in when you fly for work, you're getting points on that airline.
Rym: So when you fly for non-work, you're more likely to fly with that airline.
Rym: Mm-hmm airlines profit.
Rym: this is almost like advertising to wealthy people and like getting them to fly with you out of loyalty or Whatever.
Scott: I mean I would be happy to out, you know, would I be happier to have?
Scott: I mean I guess it's sort of be happy to have both right?
Scott: It's like and a person who might change jobs to be loyal to my airline for their non-business travel.
Scott: That's good Yeah But having a company be loyal to me for all of the travel of all of their employees that seems better Right.
Rym: The other factor is that you know, I work in capital markets.
Rym: I have spent kovat kind of messed it up a Terrifying amount of time flying all around the world.
Rym: I've been to like 20 countries.
Rym: I like.
Rym: I've flown to London 40-ish times.
Rym: I've flown to Singapore like 14 times.
Rym: like I fly a lot and it's picking up again as kovat winds down.
Rym: and If I didn't get points for that and what and they weren't putting me in business class, I would absolutely just refuse.
Rym: It's a perk because companies want employees to travel because it sadly does lead to business.
Rym: that wouldn't otherwise happen.
Rym: Like weirdly, I don't like that.
Rym: That's the way it is, but I've seen it happen first hand for too long But - I just wouldn't like it dick without that perk.
Rym: I would not travel for work at all.
Scott: Well, then it I mean if your employees are refusing to travel for business, you just have to give them more compensation.
Rym: Yeah, I mean sure if they gave me another couple hundred thousand dollars a year Yeah, I might be willing to fly but how much?
Scott: but but you'll do it for these points.
Scott: How much are the points worth in money?
Rym: Oh, you know what the points are worth.
Rym: I can fly Emily and I can fly business class for free when we go to Japan.
Scott: Right, but how much does that cost?
Rym: fuck if I know the cares.
Rym: all these systems work.
Scott: It just what I'm saying is like if that if you know the cost of business class tickets to Japan is like, you know 30,000 $20,000 right a car?
Scott: so?
Scott: but you just asked for a hundred thousand in a compensation boost.
Scott: So that does the math doesn't line up there.
Rym: Yeah, I just want more.
Rym: But you know what.
Rym: remember how you'd always say like I always said all my flights were so cheap But it was because I had so many points that I had status on Delta.
Rym: So like check bags were always free for me I didn't even know you had to pay for check bags because it was free because I only had to pay for it.
Scott: Yeah, you know you'd had to pay for check bags for quite a while, but I have never had to pay for check bags.
Scott: The check bags is only.
Scott: it is really just a consequence of the internet flight.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: No, absolutely.
Rym: That's a whole separate topic Wasn't?
Scott: if it wasn't for that.
Scott: That's the only reason they stopped including.
Scott: it is because the internet.
Rym: Yeah, but to get back to the airplane food.
Rym: What I can say is that there is all.
Rym: there is a stark difference between The food on flights within a country like if we talk about America.
Rym: Mm-hmm Even first-class on the fanciest airline that's flying between two cities in America We'll just have garbage food most of the time unless it's the second leg.
Scott: Even have a food it's gonna be snack.
Rym: Yeah, but even Flying coach like you booked the cheapest ticket on like Delta to London from New York.
Rym: the coach food is actually pretty good like Surprisingly good and it's just part of the flight Because that's a long enough flight and the way then because of the time zone difference flying over the ocean You actually do kind of want a meal on a flight.
Rym: And in fact, I would say eating the meals on long flights when the plane serves them will help you avoid jet lag Like and there's studies.
Scott: You should definitely eat when they give you the food.
Rym: Yeah, if it's a meal like that, they're like there's a practice go to sleep when they turn the lights off.
Rym: Yeah the airlines don't worry about.
Scott: don't worry about where the Sun actually is right when you're on the plane if it's a long flight you Pretend that the lights on the plane are the Sun.
Rym: Yeah, and you Like here's dinner eat it if you're not hungry.
Rym: if the flight attendants like dinners now for an hour and you're hungry Wait for that down wait that hour and eat then don't eat early.
Scott: Yeah But yet I think the other thing is that you know It's just a part of the problem is that we live in the United States, which you know, the food here is not as good.
Scott: That's a lot of other places.
Rym: I gotta tell you Turkish Airlines Holy shit, the food in premium economy on Turkish Airlines was better than like restaurants.
Rym: I paid a lot of money for in New York to eat it, right?
Scott: It's like if you go to another country, right that actually has food with flavor in it.
Rym: I'll tell you what I used to fly coach to India a lot because my other company wasn't as fancy in that regard and even booking like Air India or something in like the worst possible coach seat and like there isn't even a cushion on the seat Like I can feel the bar through it.
Rym: It's just miserable.
Rym: Oh the rice.
Rym: Yeah, I could just it was bad But the food was great.
Rym: That very aunty I ate on that plane was fantastic.
Scott: Like if you fly to Japan, I'm sure you can get like some great sushi on that flight.
Scott: Yeah, and if you fly to Florida, you can't get any sushi's not even a shitty convenience store one.
Rym: I guess that the big secret I'd share is that flying internationally in my long experience doing this Coach foods pretty good.
Rym: Generally when you're flying internationally Business class and up food is fancy restaurant food.
Rym: It's literally like here's your five-course meal like But the sommelier brings you a wine bottle.
Rym: It's like it's kind of nuts.
Rym: It's fancier than I eat even in fancy times on my own Yep, but premium economy on those kinds of planes is like the magic sweet spot because you get like a more limited version Of the business class menu.
Rym: You don't get the coach food.
Rym: you get like the waiter and the metal knife and the for real food on most airlines In premium economy if you're traveling between countries or over an ocean Like it's good food.
Rym: Yeah, I should post one of the menus like I. literally on my most recent flight back from Frankfurt I had a six course meal over the course of two hours on the flight.
Rym: It was not.
Rym: well that all.
Scott: yeah That'll help you distract you from any discomfort you have.
Rym: exactly I mean discomfort.
Rym: it was business class.
Rym: when I was tired I closed the door to my pod and laid flat in my actual bed that had a comforter.
Scott: But I mean, that's still not as good as a bed a real bed.
Scott: now still, you know It's just way way better than a seat with no leg a seat that leans back 1.5 degrees.
Scott: Yeah, exactly It's all.
Scott: it's all relative though, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: that's what I'm saying is like, you know in the airport the captive audience the limited choice Right the hunger right the the all that right makes you judge everything in a completely different way.
Rym: Lock me in a tube for 12 hours with no access to anything and then come to me with a McDonald's hamburger Six hours in.
Rym: there is a decent chance.
Rym: I'm gonna eat that thing and I'll be mad about it, but I'll eat it Right.
Scott: and the fact that a lot of the price is either you know is often is either hidden or not hidden from you based On the circumstances, right?
Scott: So, you know that five-course meal when you're in business class, you're like I just get this.
Rym: It's like well, you know you paid $15,000 for this flight, right?
Scott: It's like yeah It's like if you realize that that fat five-course meal that you're getting that's that's really good cost you $5,000.
Scott: suddenly it doesn't taste so good.
Scott: No You would never and even if you could have a restaurant on the ground that would serve you a meal twice as good you wouldn't $5,000.
Rym: I mean you just did in New York City.
Rym: if you spend $500 on a meal that is some of the best food you will ever have in your life.
Rym: You can't get much better than that.
Scott: Nope, not at all.
Rym: $50 meal in New York City is some fucking amazing food Exactly.
Scott: So it's like you don't realize that like on the one hand you're like, oh, it's amazing.
Scott: It's like no when you remember that you spend much money on it.
Scott: That's actually a terrible value.
Scott: It's like the worst You might have.
Scott: you might actually have better value back in coach Just shelling out the extra 20 when they come around to get the special meal.
Scott: Yeah value wise that might actually be better even though obviously doesn't taste as good.
Scott: but $20 of like, you know some micro transaction to get an extra sandwich is better than $5,000 for a $500 meal.
Scott: so yep.
Rym: So I guess I'm Boral is broadly context matters.
Rym: I think we can stop there.
Scott: We've gone on for Food is unique because airlines and airplanes are a unique situation and also food is required for life.
Rym: You can only go so long without it.
Rym: And like we talked about being angry If you're hungry, and it's been like a couple hours that you've been hungry I'm not even talking about starvation and like the horrors of existence if you're hungry and you remain hungry for four hours.
Rym: That puts even the most good-natured human in an increasingly stabby state Especially if their name is red, haha I ain't even the most hangry type of person in our friend group, but I'm up there.
Rym: I'm in the top quadrant.
Scott: at least you're very.
Scott: you're way up there Especially if you are hangry and you have to wait for something.
Scott: Yeah, you're like double.
Rym: If I want some coffee and I walk into a coffee shop and there's even one person in line I kind of just give up and go to the next coffee shop.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patreons for this episode of GeekNights That was recorded in advance.
Rym: if you couldn't tell Linky G dread Lily Tenebrae.
Rym: case care makes music.
Rym: Krista Dodd Clinton Walton Dex Finn Joe Hayes penny rhymer Rebecca Dunn Sam Erickson Shervin von Horl and several people who give like a dollar and thus are not above the line where I say your name at Least twice a week on average.
Rym: Yeah, we are.
Rym: we're at a pretty good pro bike lane protest because there's some bike lane drama going on New York City a little While ago, I bet we'll talk about it possibly on a future episode of GeekNights.
Rym: That's why I recorded this one at events.
Rym: So tonight simply leave you with.