Rym: It's Thursday April 20th 2023.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We're talking about magic.
Scott: I forgot to push record.
Scott: That's why I delayed my.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I push record and then said I'm Scott immediately.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: I Finished ye book club book a few days ago.
Scott: I think I said that in the last podcast.
Rym: I'll be ready to rock.
Scott: All right today was the day it was due at the library and I Admit to go earlier, but I just didn't.
Scott: thankfully the library was open today until 8 p.m.
Scott: so I went immediately after work and before the show and I go into the library and I go up the stairs and there's a. there's a metal hatch on the outside of the library.
Scott: This is book depository and I'm like, ah, yes like the olden days I love this book in a hole in the side of the building and Leave without having to enter or speak to a human like you used to do at the blockbuster video.
Scott: yep, and the hatch had a padlock on it.
Scott: now The padlock looks so shitty that I'm sure even me If I had if I had bought some some tools from the lock-making lawyer, I could have opened.
Rym: I am confident that padlock means this slot goes nowhere.
Rym: good do not.
Scott: There was no place of honor and there was no reason to even attempt that because the library was still open.
Scott: So I go inside and I see a librarian and I'm like I would like to return this book and I'm expect I'm expecting them To just take it out of my hands and let me leave.
Scott: that was not what happened.
Scott: They said use that machine over there.
Scott: now That machine over there was clearly not an ultra modern machine.
Scott: That machine has probably been there for at least a decade or two.
Rym: You got to get a crank out.
Rym: crank it a little bit till it starts sputtering like what's going on here.
Scott: I've you know, but me not having taken a physical book out of a library since Physical book out of the library.
Scott: that was our icy library.
Scott: So 20 20 something years, right?
Scott: Yeah 2022 was the.
Rym: 2002 was the last time I took a physical book out of a physical library.
Rym: So malice aforethought.
Scott: so the way this machine worked is there's.
Scott: basically it looks sort of like one of those big ATMs kind of like that or maybe more like Like the post office machine similar to the post office one.
Rym: That machine is impressive and that you can do fucking anything on it.
Rym: But it is also terrible because it takes about 10 minutes to do anything on it, right?
Scott: So the way this.
Scott: but this machine is much simpler and its functionality.
Scott: there was a screen and there was a big hole that was large enough to fit in most books and Basically the hole didn't even have a hatch.
Scott: It was just always open.
Scott: and we all you did is you took the book barcode facing down Right and you stick it in the hole.
Rym: What are the consequences if you put the book in the wrong way?
Scott: I guess it might tell you take it out and put it back in but basically as soon as it scanned the barcode Right.
Scott: It had a little conveyor belt and it took the book inside and I didn't hear like a cathunk like it wasn't dropping the Book, I think it was like elevating it somewhere that it doesn't damage it Or maybe bringing it into a room behind the machine possibly because there was a room behind the machine.
Scott: But the machine also had a large storage compartment anyway.
Scott: After it it took the book like in a second basically and then was like, alright Do you want a receipt paper email or none?
Scott: and I'm just like normally.
Scott: I would say none But I chose email just as I wanted to see right and it basically immediately emailed me Because it knew that I was the one who had the book and it was like yes you have we have confirmed you ever turned Your book on time.
Scott: This was the book.
Scott: Bye.
Scott: I was like, oh that's probably an old technology.
Scott: There's nothing particularly amazing about it.
Scott: It's a barcode scanner and a conveyor belt and a screened right and a network connection.
Scott: is nothing really fancy going on there.
Scott: It was just and it clearly wasn't new because it's that was a. you know It wasn't a shiny brand new machine with a ribbon cutting That way for a long time.
Rym: we don't as a society invest particularly much in our libraries.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like.
Scott: I just you know It was my first experience with a digital book return.
Scott: being someone who hasn't used The book I remember many score at RIT.
Rym: There's just a hole in like the desk like there's the.
Rym: there was the counter desk and there's a hole there and you just Throw it in the hall.
Scott: Yeah You would check the book out from a person who would scan it with a handheld barcode scanner and you to return it.
Scott: you put In a hole.
Scott: it went in a bin and someone's job was to process the bin later, right?
Scott: You did it.
Rym: and that was thinking back to blockbuster videos.
Rym: and it's funny because a lot of kids like think back to like.
Rym: Oh, I remember blockbuster video But we're old enough to remember that blockbuster video was the bad thing that destroyed all the good video stars that came before it like They never even well that era.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yes and no right because on the one hand we had the local video store, right?
Rym: Well, it was regional some local video stores a plus some local stores d-minus.
Scott: Well, it was a balance right the local video store had cool niche Biz right that you know, you couldn't find in a blockbuster which you know didn't have a very deep selection, right?
Scott: They had just popular stuff.
Scott: But if you wanted to see the thing that just came out in VHS just now Right the blockbuster had 50 some odd copies, right and it's like sure sometimes all of them would be taken.
Scott: Usually you could get like one or it's there would been being one that was returned.
Rym: And I remember because we had already seen Jurassic Park like twice in the theater and then we just own that one.
Rym: No, but when it came out on VHS, we were just cuz we didn't buy it right away.
Rym: We're just like Let's watch Jurassic Park and there's a wall of Jurassic Park and there was not.
Rym: there was no Jurassic Park tape behind any of those boxes.
Scott: Yeah, but you know what if you went that's the thing is you would go to blockbuster and like the whole wall of Jurassic Parks would be gone and then you'd go to the front.
Rym: But look in the bin and you.
Scott: but if you just went to them if you just went to the mall to whatever your store Was Suncoast or FYE or whatever you had right?
Scott: You could just buy it.
Scott: It was there just to buy for 20 bucks or rent but blockbuster five bucks.
Scott: No, not five.
Rym: blockbuster was 350.
Scott: I Guess I don't remember what?
Scott: Who's cheaper than right?
Rym: I mean that was 350 in late 80s dollars.
Rym: So that's like a hundred dollars today anyway.
Scott: Yeah, but the point was is that you know anyway, yeah.
Rym: So in some news, this is some pretty big deal news But it's unfortunately not as big as it could have been but we'll see because there's more going on here.
Rym: So if you recall during the previous American presidential election One of the candidates was an evil fascist who also attempted a coup to overturn the fact that he lost that election.
Rym: in America, there's a bunch of news networks and They're all pretty much like center-right through center-left.
Rym: And there's a couple that are like far far left by American standards meaning center-right by European standards.
Rym: but then there's one network that's basically just the fascist network like they just lie all the time like it is just Shockingly egregious propaganda.
Scott: and in America the way the way they get away with it right technically speaking is that first of all is the First Amendment.
Scott: it's not against a lot of lie if it's not liable or slander or something Right, and two they basically have some programs even though the network is called Fox News, right?
Scott: Yeah, some of the programs are like news at 11, which if you watch it is Typical, you know news.
Scott: It's not good, but it's like it's typical news.
Scott: Crime.
Rym: There was a car crash on Fifth Avenue.
Scott: Yeah, it's bad.
Scott: But it's just.
Scott: it's actually news right?
Scott: They're not lying on it.
Scott: And then they have programs like so-and-so fascist guy the show right where white guy rants at TV.
Scott: It's on a news network.
Scott: It says news on the screen, but that's not a news show.
Scott: That's basically just no different than some radio ranty guy just right.
Scott: and then those shows are.
Scott: the shows are all the lying happens.
Rym: Those shows are basically they're not.
Scott: they're not technically news.
Scott: There's.
Rym: it's like there's a clip from a movie that Rit is taken like so egregiously out of context that I cringe every time I ever see anyone reference it.
Rym: But if you ever seen an old movie called the network There's a scene where there's an old guy on TV like on a news looking show.
Rym: That's a lot like what Scott describes and he just goes off on a rant like you've got to get mad.
Rym: It's Fox News is basically that except that guy was crazy and being manipulated by the network.
Rym: This one's the other way around.
Rym: they know exactly what they're doing.
Rym: Everyone involved knows exactly what they're doing.
Scott: It's by design and they're okay with it.
Rym: Yep so, uh, of course, they just lied about the American presidential election and they egregiously defamed Of the company that makes most American voting machines along the way Dominion.
Scott: Yeah they basically just like here are legitimate criticisms of voting machines and electronic voting that many internet digital people have made and To make.
Rym: yeah, I don't have a high opinion of Dominion as a company.
Rym: No But they lied.
Rym: they literally just were saying Dominion stole the election from Trump like pretty much directly.
Scott: And it's not.
Scott: that part is not true.
Rym: and they also were uncritically airing claims about that by other people like Rudy Giuliani and down like the crazy people a pillow guy like all those types of people.
Rym: So, uh Their argument was that nothing we're doing is defamation because we're reporting on something newsworthy.
Rym: And is it not newsworthy that a presidential candidate and his team are saying that the election was stolen from them?
Rym: So they were saying that they were saying that those other people were saying instead of actually just saying it directly.
Scott: Well, I mean that's that's a legitimate argument.
Scott: But if you watch the broadcasts, you'll see that that's not true.
Scott: It's not true.
Scott: That's not what they were.
Scott: if if they were saying like if they had a news anchor be like, ah, yes Crazy right-wing person says this yeah, right But evidence is that is not true then they could.
Scott: then that's perfectly fine news reporting.
Scott: I imagine the other not evil or less evil news networks did report exactly in that fashion.
Scott: Yeah, but if you watch their news reports, it's like no they didn't do that Even though they might have said they tried to argue in court that they were doing something.
Rym: So in American defamation locks We have a lot of overseas listeners like I
Scott: was a lot harder to make a case here than many other countries in
Rym: the
Scott: US Countries, it's too easy to make a case
Rym: like in some countries in Europe and I'm looking at you Britain in particular.
Rym: Being right isn't necessary.
Rym: Like if you are truthful that doesn't necessarily protect you from defamation.
Scott: It's just one of those things where no country gets it.
Scott: right now really it's like at least if there is a country that gets it Right.
Scott: I'm not aware of.
Scott: Yeah, I just see all sorts of stories from all sorts of countries and every time I see a libel or defamation Lawsuit story.
Scott: It's either Wow, that country is way too easy or way too hard to.
Rym: it's always the first bear or the second bear.
Rym: Nobody's got the third bear.
Rym: Everything's just right.
Rym: Yeah, so but it goes way worse than this because so of course Dominion sued and in America you have to prove that one the claims were actually false and - you have to prove if I'm not a lawyer.
Rym: I'm summarizing that the people making the claims Weren't just stupid and wrong, but they knew it was wrong.
Rym: They knew it was a lie and they were doing it with malicious intent Intending to cause harm.
Scott: Yeah, well and it just so happens that there was evidence that they knew that they were lying red-handed evidence.
Scott: Their internal discussions were like we know this is a line.
Scott: we're gonna say it on TV.
Rym: Anyway, yep lawyers got all the internal emails and it's you've got all these fascist hosts sending each other like Emails and writing saying things like this bad shit crazy bullshit.
Rym: They were about to say is a lie.
Rym: I'm going to say it anyway for crime reasons.
Rym: effectively
Scott: Yep,
Rym: so they were almost definitely gonna lose this lawsuit because another thing that happened is They
Scott: not your opinion,
Rym: oh, yeah this no this
Scott: I agree with yep,
Rym: they withheld a huge amount of those communications Illegally and they got fucked over in court over it and had to hand over the rest and sanctioned by the judge.
Rym: so the trial against the fascist news network in America was about to happen and The Dominion was asking for 1.6 billion dollars in damages.
Scott: seems good.
Rym: Yeah They settled with Fox Literally like within an hour of the trial start like jury selection started and then suddenly everybody settled which is not uncommon in America.
Rym: That is like the most common outcome for trials except when poor people are involved.
Scott: That's a very basic strategy, right?
Scott: It's like, you know settle to avoid the costly Time-consuming trial that will only make matters worse for you and the American legal system.
Scott: Don't settle until the last second so you can get the best possible deal, right?
Scott: Why would you settle early exactly?
Scott: It's the same reason that people trading sports players wait until the trade deadline.
Rym: well you want to settle late too because it's all like.
Rym: bringing the jury in is actually the moment when a lot of people suddenly decide they want to settle because suddenly they go from I could win this case to Looking at a bunch of random ass people who couldn't get out of jury duty
Scott: and think well That's some that's something that they actually tell you in jury duty in the waiting room.
Scott: Right, is there?
Scott: like as they're like look, you know you sit on this jury There's someone else over there with some legal battle, right?
Scott: And just the fact that you are present in waiting here is like pressure on them.
Scott: Right to you know, have justice be served, right?
Scott: So even if you don't do anything and you're just sitting in a waiting room playing on your phone Right just being there the fact that you were there is Moving things along in the judicial system.
Rym: Yes and our society our judicial system is designed to try to encourage that outcome the idea being Courts are one of the last resorts in resolving conflicts.
Rym: adults should be able to resolve conflicts amongst themselves.
Rym: If they can't especially civil matters Yeah.
Rym: if they can't you arbitrate in some way and you go to a court if you cannot get redress.
Scott: and then because because courts are you Know costly not just to the people involved in the case But to all of our society.
Scott: every time there has to be a trial.
Scott: It's like it costs everybody time and money Yep, so Fox admitted that they lied.
Rym: They admitted that they're the fascist lying Network pretty much directly and they agreed to pay seven hundred and eighty seven point five Million dollars to Dominion voting systems to make this go away.
Scott: good, but too bad.
Scott: That's not enough money to shut them down Yep, it's basically pocket change to Fox.
Rym: They have like four billion in cash.
Scott: What stupid Murdoch evil guy worth terrifying amounts.
Rym: but Fox by itself has four billion in cash Because they've been buying back.
Rym: He's work 18.
Scott: He's well, it says he's worth 17.6 billion.
Scott: I don't know if that's down Yeah Or if it's updated but the point is if I lost an equivalent amount of my fortune to a lawsuit that wouldn't affect my life at all percentage wise if I lost 1/18 or 1/17 of my money Notice?
Scott: yeah, if you got $17 18 dollars and then you lose a dollar I Mean how how big of a difference?
Scott: Yeah, really, you know, I guess if that's all you've got then that's really big.
Scott: it's like he could lose 16 billion and he'd still have a billion and Live the same life of infinite luxury, right?
Rym: So it's a big deal.
Rym: It doesn't destroy Fox News, but it's a big deal because we've never had a defamation case like this.
Rym: settle for such a.
Scott: we just need 20 more of these.
Rym: well Fun news is they basically fully admitted.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we were we were lying that everything you said is true.
Rym: Dominion is also suing Newsmax in one America which are like if I don't have as much money and also if Fox is the fascist network, those are like Deeper fashion, like those are like is what it is just a word for that Like Fascist like.
Rym: put it underline it and put a little swastika next to it like they're terrifying entities.
Rym: So there is also the other voting machine company in America the other big one.
Rym: Anyway, Smartmatic has it almost heard of that one.
Rym: Uh, yeah, guess what?
Scott: I thought I thought it was.
Scott: I remember the one back and then it was d-balled everyone.
Rym: Oh, yeah people that was.
Rym: I have low Personal opinions of people anyway.
Rym: Yeah Smartmatic, which guess what?
Rym: I hadn't heard of either Was also defamed pretty much the exact same way by Fox and their lawsuit is still going through the courts right now and getting to the point of a trial.
Rym: they've seen Way more than Fox than Dominion sued for.
Rym: yeah So this is ongoing and this is honestly a pretty big victory for just Democracy and truth like it's pretty good news all around.
Rym: It's a pretty good outcome.
Scott: should have invested in voting machine companies.
Scott: No, I've invested a billion dollars for doing nothing.
Rym: yeah, I have.
Rym: I have invested more in defense contractors lately.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So I got any news.
Scott: Do we have a news?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: Cuz we're trying to do the show quickly before hockey so we can just go right into the wings of the day.
Rym: so algorithmic duration of Feeds is definitely just getting worse for a lot of reasons and we don't really need to dwell on that.
Rym: but the algo Just recommended to be a video and YouTube that I just happened to watch because it was short and it was animated and it's called Clown room and it was actually better than it's.
Rym: it's actually scary It's.
Rym: it's a so clown.
Scott: so people who are clown averse should not lie.
Rym: Oh if you are if you are clown averse if you're not down with that classy like do not watch down with the clown.
Rym: but clown room is a short Animated films a couple minutes long and it's basically about a guy who is being trained to work at some fast-food restaurant.
Rym: And I was like, here's how the fireworks and it's pretty straightforward.
Rym: And then the guys like oh, yeah, there's one last thing probably that this is that this is the room you're gonna interact with the most.
Rym: and he opens the door to the clown room and there's just a clown like tied to a machine and It just proceeds from there and I'm just gonna leave it at that.
Rym: It's it's.
Rym: it's pretty good.
Scott: Write it down next.
Scott: next third.
Scott: Well next Thursday.
Scott: It's not a book club clowns.
Scott: Do we do clowns clowns?
Rym: I don't know if we've done a show on clowns.
Rym: I'll figure that out.
Scott: It's cloud around.
Rym: Yeah, so what do you got?
Scott: What do I have?
Scott: so I don't know a hundred percent that this is real, right?
Scott: But it was shared a whole bunch on the internet last week and it seems real.
Scott: So I'm just gonna go with it.
Scott: And if it's not real it's like.
Scott: well congrats to whoever wrote this.
Scott: good job writing, right?
Scott: So if you if you don't know somehow You know Yuri Gagarin the first human being to ever leave the surface of the earth and be in the cold Defying vacuum of space and then return
Rym: where we were told that it is cold Yes,
Scott: the first person ever to do that You know inarguably.
Scott: Before he went up into space, right?
Scott: He wrote a letter to his family because you know, he knew he could very easily die.
Scott: It was super dangerous And no one had done it before.
Scott: and You know much like we talked about unlike our archiving data show, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, his family didn't have thankfully didn't have to read that that letter.
Scott: He died in a plane crash way later, but But he didn't die when he went to outer space.
Scott: so but the letter was if it's real was saved And is now available for anyone to read.
Scott: And it's quite a thing to read.
Scott: write a letter from a person who you know is basically still young has a family Yeah is going to do something even riskier than like, you know, Evil Knievel's or any pretty much anything Flying bomb
Rym: something that is both deeply tied
Scott: to a place with no air But
Rym: also tied to a growing military industrial first world second world bloc cold war where there's a lot of political stakes involved and it's complex a complicated situation and is Directly advancing some of the most important long-term science that humans have ever endeavored into.
Scott: yeah He wasn't.
Scott: he wasn't too concerned with that part.
Rym: Yes Actually, he was dude.
Rym: I learned a lot about him on the letter.
Rym: No, not in the letter, but in his life.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean he was you know, he was basically like pro-communism right?
Scott: He was a communist dude.
Scott: He wasn't.
Rym: he was he.
Rym: If you're ever learning you should read the story of him and the other people he worked with and what went on in that program.
Rym: He was not exactly fully on board with the way that was run.
Scott: Anyway, you should read, you know, if you ever have to do something like this You can you can crib crib notes from this letter and that's an AI generator.
Rym: I was about to say future humans are just gonna GPT-5 their living will and testament and their letter to their family.
Rym: Someone's gonna make an app of if I die write a letter to my family that I would have written before I died the end.
Scott: I wonder if I can get it to write Heartfelt sentimental things that like work and use them and get away with it.
Rym: I'm pretty sure you could.
Rym: I've been thinking a lot about how I could probably Literally train a model on the emails I send and receive.
Rym: that would write the emails I send and receive for me without me even seeing them.
Rym: that would accomplish Basically the same amount that my current emails accomplished today.
Scott: All right, we've done a show on that.
Rym: Yep All right in the meta moment GeekNights book club book Which Scott just returned to the library and I should be done with by the next Thursday.
Rym: show the satanic verses Some magical realism.
Scott: you want it.
Scott: you want to hear the verses that Satan has to impart upon you.
Scott: I mean those seem like pretty, you know, whether you're pro or anti-satan It seems like you would want to know what those verses.
Rym: if you're from Satan You don't want to know what he's got to say.
Rym: If you're anti-satan, you got to know your enemy.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I think so.
Scott: I think everyone, you know, there's really.
Scott: only you can either be even if you're neutral on Satan, right?
Scott: It's like well, you know, give them give them a chance.
Rym: I hate to say it though You just made an argument that you should watch some Fox News.
Rym: No, you kind of just did know you're.
Rym: why do you should know what your enemies got to say?
Scott: No, if your enemy is important like Satan telling Not lying Yeah, you should read this book.
Rym: I like it.
Rym: we keep saying if you have never read this book and you only know about it from his geopolitical context That was me last month.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I think you will just be surprised by what the words are in this book.
Rym: You will be very sad.
Scott: I had absolutely no clue what the words would be in this book until I read it.
Scott: I think you know now I know all the words.
Rym: I still think you will be most surprised by Like literally just the first chapter by itself.
Rym: You'll be like wait this This is Let's get right into it.
Rym: can't believe never done a show on this.
Rym: when I was a little kid like a like a little kid I was like many kids really into a few things.
Rym: I was really into trains.
Rym: He's really into dinosaurs.
Rym: I was really into space stuff and I was really into magic and illusions.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I wasn't like Really into it or like I was you know, like thinking about it all the time.
Rym: I had all those terrible like do a magic show kids as a kid.
Scott: I had one I had a Blackstone one.
Rym: I had the same Blackstone one, I think.
Scott: maybe.
Scott: But yeah, it's like.
Scott: but if there was a magic Back in the days of television there would be these magic specials on television, right?
Scott: There would be like an hour long or more of like an ultra famous magician.
Scott: Yeah, Lee David Copperfield Those two occasionally someone else.
Rym: I have a such a strong memory of David Copperfield doing his flying illusion like for the first time on broadcast TV.
Scott: I saw him do it and I saw him do it live and I was trying to figure out what that I never saw him Live.
Scott: I saw him live in Connecticut.
Scott: So but anyway, he's still got him.
Scott: He flew around the audience.
Scott: He was he was vertically above the people who were sitting.
Scott: He wasn't just on the stage going through hoops.
Scott: So something was going on.
Scott: Anyway, the point is is that when there was magic on it was like, ooh, I was excited right there was.
Scott: even if there was like, you know a magician at a birthday party or something like that like I was into it right and You know, I was trying to figure out like how the fuck they did that right knew that it clearly wasn't real magic, right?
Scott: Yeah, even though I was still believing in like aliens and other bullshit at that.
Scott: But I'd somehow knew magic was fake and I was always trying to figure out what the trick was.
Scott: And I guess when I was young, I just usually was not able to figure it out.
Rym: yeah, I have a I have this very distinct memory of because I also enjoy really low rent magic like the Bottom-tier magician doing like a six-year-olds birthday party like I enjoy watching that or watching do a good job at that.
Rym: Yeah, but I remember I was out of the Cub Scouts, but my little brother was still in the Cub Scouts but he was like a wee blows like about to get out of Cubs like Graduating off and They're doing a magic show for like all the Cub Scouts.
Rym: So it's a little aimed at an audience a little younger than my brother And of course, I'm at that age of.
Rym: I am too cool for fucking everything.
Rym: So I'm sitting there watching this magic show and my brother's watching it.
Rym: all these Cub Scouts are watching it and the whole time It's obvious that like the the rabbit placards are just like spinning around or something in those cylinders.
Rym: So it's very clear that he's changing the color of them by just rotating the face in some way.
Rym: I know that trick but It was obvious to the kids too.
Rym: and the little kids start yelling like no turn that around hand that to me.
Rym: right now The kids are going so agro against this harried like 40 something year old magician.
Rym: Just trying to entertain.
Rym: So finally the magician is like, oh you want to see it?
Rym: All right, and he hands it to the kids and fucking nothing that there's nothing in that object.
Rym: He had clearly Been making it look like it was a simple trick and it was a more complex trick to get the kids to react.
Rym: It was so staged.
Rym: I wasn't stunned by the magic trick.
Rym: I was stunned by how he fucking played that entire audience and put that hard to play a bunch of kids But still yeah.
Rym: But like an older audience like you wouldn't antagonize someone who looks like they're a haggard like 40 year old doing magic to try to Get by but he knew the kids would and that was part of his act.
Scott: Mmm, I like it.
Scott: I like it.
Rym: It's Day.
Scott: for that reason I got you know, a lot of the magic that I experienced in person other than you know, David Copperfield.
Scott: Yeah, I was in the mall one time and There was like some event in the mall where basically it was sort of like a trade show I guess and like there were people who basically had set up things to sell themselves right in the hallway of the mall, right?
Scott: So one one of the things in the mall was this magician who had set up like a whole like a little mini stage in The hallway in the mall like near one of the entrances where there's a lot of space, right?
Scott: And he's doing like magic shows on the hour like a couple tricks each with an assistant And he's trying to get you to hire him for your parties bar mitzvahs, etc.
Rym: Not a bad ad Right.
Scott: So this is the one time in my life where I'm like, I don't know how old I was Fucking.
Scott: no, right and you know, he's like.
Scott: he's like I need a volunteer from the audience.
Scott: My arm is coming out of my socket.
Scott: I'm like And I actually got picked.
Scott: Oh damn, right?
Scott: And so now now I knew I'm like, this is my chance, right?
Scott: I'm like, I know that he didn't pick a stooge from the crowd.
Scott: It's really it's me, right?
Scott: I can't you know, I'm gonna figure out.
Scott: I'm just gonna pay really close attention to what the fuck is going on, right.
Scott: and You know try to figure out what the hell is happening here, right?
Scott: And it was the old trick where like you stuff one handkerchief in my hand and then like a fuck ton of hate rainbow Handkerchief shit comes out, right?
Scott: It was that one, right?
Scott: So, you know, he's the thing is I'm paying so much attention Like what he's doing and try to figure it out that I wasn't paying attention to his instructions, really.
Scott: So he stuffs like the handkerchief in my hand All right, and he was doing like a practice countdown of like.
Scott: this is how we're gonna do it.
Scott: You're gonna count down one, two, three and then reveal right but on the practice countdown.
Scott: I Revealed right And but sure enough there was a fuck ton of hate.
Scott: it like, you know, he had done the magic already, right?
Scott: It's like basically, you know when he was stuffing the single handkerchief in my hand He additionally stuffed many more in there, right?
Scott: My hand was closed.
Scott: I was trying to look at what he was doing with his hand, you know.
Scott: But all I I guess the only thing I had to go on was I could feel that There's a lot more on my hand than that one handkerchief.
Scott: And that was you know, a pretty simple trick but I just remember like messing it up for that guy Even though it wasn't a total mess-up because like the magic happened But it was a slight mess-up because he had to be like, oh hey, you know yet.
Scott: He was off his you know You know presentation game.
Rym: Yeah, the what's the last music show?
Rym: I listen music.
Rym: last magic show I saw was at my brother's wedding.
Rym: We were in Vegas because that's where it was.
Rym: and Of course, why not go see Penn and Teller like it?
Scott: I mean, I feel like if you go to V everyone who goes to Vegas goes to see that right?
Scott: They've been there hundred years.
Rym: Yeah, they're not.
Scott: they're not there a hundred years because they're not selling.
Scott: Yeah, you keep selling out, but I got it They.
Rym: they perform in a hole.
Rym: they perform in the Rio which isn't even on the main strip and it smells like Sadness in there.
Rym: It is the word.
Scott: I feel like that's what they there.
Scott: That's their style.
Scott: Yeah No, I wouldn't what they wouldn't want to perform and like the MSG Perfect venue for them.
Rym: because you walk into this place you look around like wow This is a place that Penn Jillette would like go to feel sad on purpose and because that is how it fuels his soul.
Rym: but Seeing them live even from a crappy seat was just fucking phenomenal Like even in the nosebleed seat in the top of this arena.
Rym: you think that far away in a Vegas show where they're doing the same Show they've done like five times a day for years.
Scott: Change it now and then mix up the tricks a little bit But anyway half the tricks.
Rym: for once.
Rym: I had seen Penn and Teller perform before on TV or in specials But you know what still amazing like even knowing everything I knew about them.
Rym: No way to tell like you can't figure out you can't see the moment where they did the thing.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, I have guesses for some of the.
Scott: you know some tricks, you know some tricks.
Scott: It's like you can guess right and I have some idea but like the specific.
Scott: and the thing is The specifics of a lot of those things are just so elaborate that like you could never in a million years That's what that's when they cuz you know We talked about got the history at least of us enjoying magicians.
Rym: when I was young when we were watching like David Copperfield there was this pop culture idea that magicians are this very closed group of people with Secrets and like you never kind of are.
Rym: they kind are but not because a lot.
Scott: the reason they are though I think nowadays isn't you know, it's like there's an internet.
Scott: right people know things, right?
Scott: People can slow it up.
Scott: people have a high-resolution video now they can slow it down everything, right?
Scott: But I think the reason magicians are still secretive is because a lot of them don't make their money Performing a lot of them make their money developing and then selling tricks, right?
Scott: So if everyone in the whole world knows how to do the trick You know the illusion that you figured out and then developed and you know You but you maybe had to build equipment for or patent a thing, right?
Scott: It's like if everyone knows You can't make any money selling the trick to other magicians, right?
Scott: It's like there's a lot of magicians out there who are very good because they're highly talented in the realms of you know performance Practicing execution style storytelling etc, right?
Scott: But they're not people who can like develop a brand new trick Maybe one right or do it remix an existing trick a little bit and they go to other Magicians who have developed who are you know experts at developing tons of tricks and they buy tricks from them.
Scott: They follow the instructions and they practice it a thousand times and develop an act around it.
Scott: and that's how the business model goes.
Scott: No So that's why the secrets can't go out.
Scott: if I buy a tricks with someone and reveal the secret and then ruin their business Hey, I'm not gonna get any more tricks from them, which hurts me Especially.
Scott: if they're good at it and be they're gonna be super pissed.
Scott: They could sue me.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: that's what's keeping the secret.
Rym: but there was also trying.
Rym: there was a pop culture thing that was part of making magicians popular of the mystique of like Never ever reveal a magician secret.
Rym: because remember when there was that That's still yet.
Rym: It's that pop culture attempt to do the the mass magician and his whole shtick.
Rym: This is what the 90s I saw.
Scott: I remember that he was like.
Rym: I'm gonna show you how like all the big tricks are done one by one and They'll like.
Rym: they'll come after me if they find out who I am Like.
Rym: I'm in danger from the other magicians.
Rym: and then pendula.
Rym: it was like yeah now really that's funny though It's a good shtick but pendulum Penn and Teller were the ones who?
Rym: Made an alternate pop culture idea because they were the ones who were like, yeah We're gonna start showing how we do our tricks cuz you know what.
Rym: we can tell you how we're gonna do it.
Rym: We can show you how we're gonna do it.
Rym: You still won't fucking see us do it.
Scott: Well, I mean there's a. there's a particular genre of trick now that I've seen several magicians do where you have a trick and part Of the routine is to reveal how part of the trick was done
Rym: and tell her made that famous when they did the trick of With the little hands and the hankerchiefs in the box and then they did it with the clear wall so you could see that the trick is just.
Rym: Teller is Destroying his body and working extremely hard crawling around in this insane contraption the entire time.
Scott: But then this but then there's an additional trick.
Scott: Yeah that goes above and beyond right.
Scott: that is like Oh, you showed me how you did that.
Scott: But then it's like how did you do that extra part at the end?
Scott: I'll fucking know right.
Scott: Oh, yeah Yeah, you know magic is a is a you know, it's a fun entertaining kind of performance art.
Scott: I enjoy it a lot.
Scott: I risk, you know, I used to when I was a kid.
Scott: I enjoy it because you know the mystery.
Scott: how the fuck did they do that?
Scott: Right and nowadays it's more like You know the respect like wow, look at you know, they they they figured that out, right?
Scott: It's like they practice that so much.
Scott: they you know, etc, etc.
Scott: They got skills, you know, especially card people.
Scott: It's like they're like it's like there's some card people and it's like how did he do that?
Scott: The dude just has the ability to pull out the card he wants out of a deck of it.
Rym: You choose basically a thief from Dungeons & Dragons like you just got right.
Scott: It's like you can.
Scott: you can hand him a deck of 52 cards and say take the 14th card from the bottom out and don't touch any other cards and boop.
Scott: they could just do it right even though cards are really Thin.
Scott: yeah, it's like they just have practiced that skill of manipulating pieces of paper in a stack really really Adeptly and it's like that's fucking amazing.
Scott: If I try to do that the cards just spill all over and I've been shuffling cards since I was three because I'm gonna I'm gonna join one of the Euchre meetups that we're.
Rym: that we had you discovered a while ago.
Rym: here I was practicing something I haven't done in years many many years of Top and bottom dealing and like basically card cheating tricking just to see if I can still do it.
Rym: I can still I can still kind of do it.
Rym: I can.
Rym: I can choose a couple of cards that I'm dealing out and get away with it.
Rym: I think if I really want to with a standard deck of cards Like a lot of the times card magic right.
Scott: the.
Scott: the answer of how did they do that is they're just that good.
Scott: Yeah, it wasn't it.
Scott: There's not any trick to it or anything.
Scott: It's like they're just that good at Handling cards.
Scott: they could remember where a card is Retrieve that card.
Scott: they can memorize the order of the whole deck.
Scott: they can do also You know because they just practiced so much out that they can do that.
Rym: I broadly break the naive lead it not even the definition of.
Rym: I am NOT a magician who has any expertise But in terms of as a as a person who watches magicians I kind of break them up into.
Rym: there's magicians who do tricks like there's a prop or a Special device that they use to facilitate the trick like David Copperfield flying.
Rym: There's a special device like some mechanism.
Scott: There's got to be something or he's magic.
Scott: I Don't think he's right.
Rym: Yeah, if he was magic.
Scott: I don't think I know it wasn't a jetpack, right?
Scott: But clearly he always does it in a floaty loose shirt.
Scott: So he's got some kind of harness and definitely just harnessing dark wires.
Scott: But I looked but I when I was there in person right and it's like he's on stage and he's flying right.
Scott: it's like okay Well, there could be wires there, but he comes forward out of the stage.
Scott: He's above people right like, you know, you could look up and there he is, right?
Scott: So it's like are there cables out in the crowd?
Scott: I'm looking for the cables.
Scott: I did not see them if he had like the.
Scott: so I don't know what kind of fishing line.
Scott: But it's like there I was looking.
Scott: there were dark areas.
Scott: There were light areas colored areas.
Scott: I was trying to find any contrast whatsoever.
Rym: according to David Copperfield's patent He is supported by two fan-shaped arrays of fine wires that remained invisible to the audience due to the combination of lighting and thickness.
Scott: Okay, but yeah They were.
Rym: truly there is an entire Wikipedia article with diagrams and everything on David Copperfield's flying tricks Specifically.
Scott: there you go.
Scott: But I mean it was really impressive like it was when I was a kid and I didn't have internet to look that up Like I thought it had to be cables cuz what else the fuck could it be?
Scott: Yeah, it's not a jetpack.
Scott: It's not magic, right?
Scott: That's all that eliminates most of the options, but you could not see the cables anywhere, right?
Scott: How long did it take him to figure that out?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: The wires are about.
Scott: he's someone he didn't buy that.
Scott: I can see why he figured that out.
Rym: The wires are point to five millimeters thick
Scott: Yeah, but I mean the point is is that unlike other magicians who might buy a trick David Copperfield invented that and performed it Right, so he's whether you know as a person, you know, who knows but I guess he's a weird guy.
Scott: I'm sure you can be is can be validly criticized, but he is a talented individual for sure Yeah, but that is like one genre or type or component of tricks, you know the prop.
Rym: then there's the insane effort Angle, which is often a Penn & Teller trick.
Scott: We're now you can also combine the two.
Rym: Yeah They're more like components.
Rym: like you could have a trick that incorporates both of those and that.
Rym: but then there's Close-up magic, which I didn't really realize was this own genre until we started listening to Penn Radio And he talked a lot about like his card trick friends and close-up magic.
Scott: and right.
Scott: well I think the difference between the thing about close-up magic and I personally put a lot more value on close-up magic then.
Scott: Not you know not to say the stage magic is no good, right?
Scott: But with stage magic, there's two things, right?
Scott: One is that the audience the distance between the audience and the illusion is bigger Which means it's easier to hide things right because you know The audience doesn't have like a close-up view right with their eyes or ears or other senses.
Scott: You know that there's smell or whatever it is, right?
Scott: and so, you know you you don't have to be as as Quicker as clever to hide something because there's so much space right if you just you could do something where the audience isn't looking Like on the complete other side of the stage behind it behind a prop behind a big wall or a mirror or right?
Scott: And the second thing is that with stage magic you the magician illusionist has complete control of the environment.
Scott: Right, they control.
Scott: the entire space is like pre-prepared right for them.
Scott: You know, they did all kinds of stuff before you got in the room and that makes it You know takes away some of the magic even though there isn't any magic to begin with.
Scott: a close-up magician Right can perform the tricks right anywhere a crowded bar on empty on the street Right on the street.
Scott: They don't control anything.
Scott: It's like we're on.
Scott: there's no way that they could have prepared anything around here.
Scott: if they did that was a herculean effort, right?
Scott: so it's like the environment is not controlled by them and Also, usually the equipment might not be controlled by them, right?
Scott: It's like they could say hey go in the drugstore buy me a deck of cards.
Scott: you come out and they do a magic trick With it, right?
Scott: It's like it's a normal deck of cards.
Scott: So it's you know, and you're right next to them Like they're right there, you know.
Scott: If they gonna like you're staring at what the fuck they're doing and so are all your friends cuz they're trying to make a tik-tok Right and they you know, or you're sitting at a table in a bar and everyone's staring at them.
Scott: They're the complete center of attention.
Scott: this you know, it's a real table cuz it's the bars table.
Scott: It's not a trapdoor table It's not a. you know, there's nothing weird going on here, right?
Scott: They got their sleeves rolled up.
Scott: Everything is you know, but they still do it somehow and that is the most and that's a more.
Scott: it's a more powerful effect.
Rym: The do a close-up trick been able to partake in close-up magic.
Rym: It is just like it hits you in the gut like you're like staring at the thing and then it disappears and the trick happens And it's like your body just goes.
Rym: what the fuck?
Rym: I was looking right at it.
Rym: It was right there.
Scott: I was like, I know you's done it And They're not gonna do it again, yeah, like that's it too bad.
Scott: Come pay me and I'll show you how to do it.
Scott: It's like see thousand.
Rym: Yeah, if you're a rich person doing like a wedding or something I think the pro is move would be to just hire one of those like top tier close-up magicians.
Rym: Just wander around your wedding party doing close-up magic for people That kind of thing.
Scott: Maybe you know, it'd be good at the old people table or they're not dancing.
Scott: I mean, I'd be following that guy around all my kids take or the kids table if there are kids.
Rym: One thing I'd like.
Rym: I'm trying to think of what cuz nowadays most magicians I encounter.
Rym: like I watch their stuff It's usually in a YouTube video.
Rym: Covid for a few years definitely was a contributor to that but I can.
Rym: the only magicians I can name Are like a handful of people at pendula talked about a lot and like the magicians that were on TV when I was a kid
Scott: That the ones they saw on YouTube if I could remember their names
Rym: But like I remember Blackstone and Harry Anderson and David
Scott: Right.
Scott: So back in the day right when there were TV specials and when a magician could fill a whole, you know Theater a big theater magicians can make a name for themselves, right?
Scott: it's like no, but you know, whereas nowadays you could be the most talented amazing magician and It's you would not be able to reach.
Scott: but you know If someone came around today who was better than David Copperfield, right?
Scott: They could not eat in all aspects trick-making, you know performance style at everything personality.
Scott: They could not reach those heights Because there just isn't the the platform, right?
Scott: There's no.
Rym: David Blaine was one of the more recent ones who got a wide.
Scott: well It's like.
Scott: David Blaine is very good at Matt, you know close-up magic and things but he's a weird dude.
Scott: Prop he's got he's a really weird dude and a lot of the stuff he did wasn't just so magic II.
Scott: It was more just like, you know, I will survive in this.
Scott: Well, it was cute.
Rym: It was more like early magic like what Houdini would do.
Rym: It's more like that Right, but where there's no peril or the oddity or curiosity of it more so than the trick itself.
Scott: like your people It was still right.
Scott: It's like yes, he was in peril, but he would usually escape.
Rym: Well, yeah, but it's more that you're looking like you look at it.
Rym: One of the David Blaine things like he's just locked in some in a water thing with no obvious way to get air.
Rym: It's still very.
Rym: it's preying on the same thing that I think Houdini did where even if the trick is very well formed and very Safe as an audience member part of the appeal to the masses is wait.
Rym: He could die.
Scott: Whoa Right, but I mean just watching somebody do something where they're just like, you know enduring Suffering and not dying.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: that doesn't really qualify as you know, at least in my book as like.
Rym: I think the lines are blurry.
Scott: It's a. it's like an act of endurance, right?
Scott: But if you add you just have to add a little bit to it like, you know?
Scott: Ah, he was.
Scott: he was underwater in a box, but he escaped even though the locks are on the outside.
Scott: now There's a magic.
Rym: All right, how about some something that's impossible about in the water cube and you can see him in there with no And he just stays in there for like an hour instead of the three minutes that a human could do.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's a magic one, right?
Scott: Cuz it's like.
Scott: clearly he's What the same way that David Copperfield hid is flying.
Scott: yeah, I guess
Rym: what I'm saying more is that to me magic like this is a Broad and diffuse genre of entertainment and primarily it's entertainment and it bumps into a lot of other forms of entertainment and It would be very hard to draw the line unless you want to draw the line at.
Rym: is there an illusion Like as the illusionist as opposed to a new vocation is.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this auspicious episode of GeekNights Happy this holiday.
Rym: to all celebrated are Alan Joyce, Linkinji, Dre, Lily, Tenebrae, Case, Kari, Makes Music, Chris, Adad, Clinton, Walton, Dex, Finn, Joel, Hayes, Penny, Reimer, Rebecca, Dunn, Sam, Erickson, Sherman, Mount Hall, and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names tonight.
Rym: I Leave you simply with.
Rym: Come on Tally.
Rym: the guy said you had the security system in your memory banks.
Rym: You just have no long-term memory because you get high all the time.
Rym: Don't preach to me fatso.
Rym: I can preach to you all I want cuz you're stupid.
Scott: You're stupid.
Rym: Yeah, you're a towel.
Rym: You're a towel.
Rym: Just let me get high.
Rym: Oh god damn it.
Rym: All right fine.
Rym: Here's your stupid lighter.
Rym: Wait a second, that's it.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: Yeah, that's the melody to funky town.
Rym: No tally the entry code for what?