Rym: It's Tuesday, October 3rd, 2023.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We're reviewing counter-strike, which might as well be an episode from 2012 or 2002 or kind of strike to count to strike to.
Scott: Pretty sure we already did kind of strike a lot.
Rym: I gotta check to see if we did a counter-strike show.
Rym: I assume we did probably a long time ago.
Rym: That's got to be an early game nights episode.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, you know things are getting a little back to normal when what I'm about to say is so.
Rym: I was biking home from work like you do and This wasn't like a weird hobo attack or anything.
Rym: It was just I'm biking home and the previous day when I biked home There was just gridlock like all the cars in every direction.
Rym: Manhattan just couldn't move and there's this big nonsense.
Rym: But it was very apparent that that's just normal traffic now in New York Like there was nothing going on.
Rym: That was just it and I biked past it all.
Rym: it was cool today on my way home.
Rym: I actually stopped for a second because something weird was going on like I'm biking home up on the east side the east side and Then suddenly it's like really quiet and I stopped and I realized there's no cars anywhere which is weird Like no cars are driving next to me in the road.
Rym: No cars are going across at the road.
Scott: is this?
Rym: This is the I'm coming up.
Rym: what second Avenue?
Scott: Does the second Avenue go south?
Rym: then first Avenue?
Rym: I'm heading up on the east side the two one.
Scott: Well, you it could be a UN thing.
Rym: yeah, so what?
Rym: so I then notice that there's cops at every intersection blocking all four ways and multiple cross streets leading up the Queensborough Bridge are completely empty of cars and UN deal.
Rym: I don't know if it was.
Rym: I don't know what it was.
Rym: All I know is they were letting bikes through and it was the quietest most pleasant bike ride home I have had in a long long time.
Scott: It could be you know, some important person driving through or you know, yeah, I don't know what it was.
Scott: I was just yeah, that's not out of the ordinary.
Rym: Yep What was interesting is there are cops everywhere at some of the big intersections like?
Rym: yelling all the people who are in cars like trying to get to the streets if they even had a path to the street and But they were.
Rym: there's one cop who's just waving the bikes through like no you can go you can go just go just go.
Scott: It's not gonna hurt the VIP in their armored vehicle.
Rym: But there was also a giant dodgy looking FedEx truck that like looked wedged Up on the sidewalk under the Queensborough Bridge and there was much a cop standing around it.
Rym: Hmm, but that might just be normal, New York.
Scott: None of that sounds really out of the ordinary.
Rym: No, it was just nice and quiet on my ride home.
Rym: It was pleasant.
Rym: I wish they would.
Scott: it is.
Scott: it is nice when there's a.
Rym: I wish they would block all the cars.
Scott: more often cars are removed For any reason.
Scott: it's like that other day when I was running and then suddenly like I guess that also shows you is like You know the cop during rush hour.
Scott: It's like the cops could remove the cars and the world didn't end.
Rym: Yeah, the world might have ended for the few thousand people sitting in those cars were angry.
Rym: But you know who?
Rym: it didn't end for the orders of magnitude more people transiting through the same space.
Rym: So we're not in a car.
Scott: I mean and did the world really end for those people?
Scott: They just got.
Rym: I mean They're acting like it did.
Scott: Yeah Wait, you know however long and then you'll be home.
Rym: Yeah, mostly it's just.
Rym: it's it's stark because during kovat the thing that was very notable was anytime I went outside New York City was quiet in a way that I have never experienced before Covid and will likely never experience again except in brief moments Like when cops block all the cars off the street until we finally banned cars
Scott: if you just go somewhere else.
Rym: But I live here and most of my biking is here getting between places here Anyway got some news so you may remember.
Rym: we talked about how unity shot itself in both feet announcing a ridiculous monetization scheme that nobody liked Likely as part of its long fall into hell after it merged with that ad scam company some years ago.
Scott: Yeah, and they you know Did what most companies do when they fuck up which is try to say they're sorry and roll it back.
Scott: and it's like well Okay, you rolled it back and the thing you rolled back to is a lot less bad than the thing you tried originally Yeah, but you've completely now lost all trust.
Scott: I think there's a There's like an old saying that like, you know, I think it's like When trust comes in on foot and goes out on horseback.
Scott: It's like, you know, you can it.
Scott: to gain someone's trust takes a long time You know to prove that you're trustworthy and not you know.
Scott: It's like you don't want to rush in just trusting someone just out of nowhere.
Scott: That's called being a fool Yeah, but you can lose someone's trust in an instant.
Scott: you screw them over.
Rym: once that's it They're gone, right and the indications I'm seeing from the people we know the games industry and the chatter In response to this in those channels seems to basically be Nothing, they've walked back changes anything.
Rym: unity can't be trusted anymore.
Rym: We are continuing our path to get off of unity.
Scott: I mean, I think I do.
Scott: I read the new policy, you know, and it is, you know If you just take them at their word That is all they do that.
Scott: It's like hey, yeah, it's like it's alright.
Scott: It's like basically what they're gonna do is the really big games that really make a lot of money are gonna have to pay Different structure
Rym: which everyone else model that the other big game engine unreal already has Basically, and
Scott: everyone else can basically use it for free depending on what version they got this details and whatever.
Scott: but basically as long as you never make a bunch of money and is law and you know, If they if there's written text in there that says that you know, as long as you stick with this version Right, we won't force you into a new agreement except maybe and if they do change the agreement It'll only apply to like that future version when the agreement changes.
Scott: so you can stick with this version.
Scott: You know until whenever.
Scott: but of course eventually that version will be useless.
Rym: Yep so I feel like what's gonna happen is everyone who's got a game in process or was about to start may continue with unity because They've invested in using unit and a lot of people will not choose it for their next endeavor.
Rym: I would probably not choose it for any endeavor.
Rym: I was going to do because of all of this.
Rym: I just can't trust him.
Rym: but the unfortunate thing this other news here.
Rym: so why did unity do that in the first place?
Rym: because there is an another problem in the industry that the Engines don't really actually make enough money.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, it's really weird.
Scott: You would think that like, okay people are out there making lots of games lots of them.
Scott: There's so many no one can play them most of them don't make money and fail right.
Scott: and All the 3d ones most of the 3d ones across basically every platform are using one of these two engines.
Scott: It's all.
Scott: it's not a monopoly, but it's like it's you know, two only two competitors I've ever had about game engines.
Rym: was the pros and cons of epic versus unreal like it's never like.
Scott: if you want to make a 3d Type of game like those are your choices.
Scott: That'll get you on all the platforms for a modern game, right?
Scott: and the two companies that make those engines you think with so many games You know being built on your technology And if any of those games actually like tried to start from scratch It's like it would be impossible to replicate what those engines provide right?
Scott: It would take you such an enormous engineering effort They those all those companies that have to make little 2d games instead.
Scott: or you could use one of these other Engines that are out there and there are many.
Scott: some of them are even free and open source engines that are out there.
Scott: But they are so inferior right Technologically speaking that you basically cannot make a top tier game with them.
Scott: You can make a good game with them, but it's like people will be able to tell that your game is like Noticeably inferior right
Rym: and the cost of not using an engine like I knew if you try to just make a game any serious Significant game from scratch and you think what do I need an engine for that's gonna cost more than anything,
Scott: right?
Scott: So many it's not like.
Scott: like if you want to make a website and you think like this web frameworks out there You know your rubies on rails and your Django's and your PHP Symphonies and your Java whatever the fucks they have Springs.
Scott: I don't know fucking know.
Scott: this is 10,000 web, you know flask.
Scott: so many engines out there right for every frickin programming language, but those are all free right, they're all open source and they all are basically feature complete.
Scott: because Making a web engine is not such a great Engineering effort that you couldn't and you could make one.
Scott: you're on your own and basically it's really I could.
Scott: if I had to It wouldn't be.
Scott: take me that log to basically, you know, at least for the features that I needed to basically make my own.
Scott: It's doable.
Scott: All right, it's an achiever.
Scott: It's not like a Mount Everest, right?
Scott: It's like a you know a mount in your town.
Scott: Yeah, I hope no one lives in the Himalayas.
Scott: so But like to make a 3d game engine that is Cross-platform and does all that graphics biz and all that you know.
Scott: like all the things that a top-tier game does these days the engineering effort to make that is preposterous.
Scott: it might even be like, you know, like like a rocket launch and thus the problem.
Rym: unity and epic like unreal Effectively are subsidized for the rest of the industry for by various means because they themselves Need to make money by other mechanisms.
Rym: So epic the competitor unity has also now laid off 16% of its workforce and is trying to achieve quote financial sustainability.
Scott: Yeah, they think that the people run fortnight are not profitable.
Rym: Yeah, the biggest probably the most popular game on earth But that's it's way up there though It's one of them made like it is the fortnight is way up there.
Rym: talk about an example of a well-designed Successful fun game that terrifying numbers of people play.
Rym: if that can't even make money How is this one even gonna make money?
Rym: How is anyone gonna make?
Scott: it is making.
Scott: it is making it is too expensive.
Scott: I read an article maybe I'll find it but basically they talk about how there's a. you know There's a missing middle in game development.
Scott: right now We're basically you have your triple-a games your mega games with big budgets, right?
Scott: And then you have like, you know, you're there are they're successful But like your slay the spires or your vampire survivors that are like thrown together for almost no budget.
Scott: Right, and there aren't games that have like, you know.
Scott: It's like you've either got a budget of like a bag of ramen or you have a budget of a lottery prize.
Rym: It is really hard to support the middle of an industry like this.
Rym: That is the most expense To provide the things they need and the help they need for the least profit because only the two tail ends are gonna make money.
Scott: Nobody's making it any.
Scott: it's basically not a lot.
Scott: It's hardly any games with like a $50,000 budget $100,000 budget 200,000. those games.
Scott: Where are they?
Scott: They're not out there, right.
Scott: or again and games that not only not only the budgets But the time frame right.
Scott: you either threw it together at a game jam and a weekend or you spent three years on it.
Scott: Where is the six-month game that like, you know, you get together six months you get it out, right?
Scott: Where is that?
Scott: It's not here.
Rym: Well partly because the the entire industry sadly I think is built on a bubble of investor money and unrealistic expectations about free-to-play monetization models and or metaverse like nonsense.
Scott: Well, I think it's all you know, it's if you're because the Everyone wants to be roblox.
Scott: Well, we have this expectation right that you're gonna make this game.
Scott: You know with like we have this amazing technology to make fancy games, right and it's like.
Scott: well No matter what your game is making a game with that high-end technology Right is expensive.
Scott: It's like already.
Scott: you just budget right out of the gate to buy the developers computers is $3,000 per person.
Rym: The fact that a game like fortnight like a game that has servers or infrastructure or is online or evolves requires tons of constant investment.
Rym: and yet While probably the right way to fund that is the people who play it pay money.
Rym: We know that doesn't generate enough profits to fund a game like that.
Rym: free-to-play Extracts money from so you wouldn't otherwise spend money.
Scott: So you have a customer who wants a product that is highly engineered and expensive to produce All right, and yet is unwilling to pay what that actually costs.
Rym: yep, and meanwhile look at the older days like look at an NES game in the 90s.
Rym: Final Fantasy or Legend Zelda 2 and Mario 3 were both 65 and $70 at Toys R Us when I was a kid in 90s dollars and you paid money and you got a game Even in a single-player world in the modern era not many people are willing to pay Really any amount of dollars for a game.
Scott: All right, well, yep, that's so.
Rym: I don't know where this goes because basically unity was under the same pressures.
Scott: We've been waiting for.
Scott: you've been waiting as long as GeekNights exists for various bubbles to burst.
Scott: game development publishing bubbles ad bubbles.
Rym: They almost microburst like the people who are employed in these industries get screwed over and the industry contracts.
Rym: But then like the bubble reforms as people find some increasingly esoteric way To trick people to pay for something that weren't otherwise gonna pay for it.
Rym: Because that's the thing that really bothers me in the end.
Rym: The entire monetization model even around fortnight is Basically instead of paying for a game.
Rym: It is get people to pay for cosmetics who wouldn't otherwise pay for game.
Rym: So you're trick.
Rym: you're getting someone to spend money They wouldn't have otherwise spent with some sort of free-to-play Inducive addictive model that I have a lot of concerns about.
Scott: I feel like what happened was, you know in the early 2000s Right when the tech bubble went, you know, right?
Scott: It's like they blew.
Scott: they blew into it too much and it popped, right?
Scott: Yeah, and they're like, okay We'll get another balloon and try again.
Scott: and what they've been doing I guess as a whole is they learned.
Scott: the lesson they learned is don't blow too hard.
Scott: It'll pop right when it gets to when it gets too tight and the skin is too thin.
Scott: Let some air out Yeah, right It'll fart a bunch and then start blowing into it again.
Scott: And we're just blowing up and deflating this balloon over and over Yeah, and that.
Scott: and to avoid popping it.
Scott: and but every deflating part still sucks and it's like, you know It never holds it own.
Scott: It's never.
Scott: you never tie it shut Doesn't fly it doesn't take off.
Rym: Yep I mean well We've got two balloons that hold up most of the modern video game industry and neither one has enough air.
Rym: Anyway, you got any news?
Scott: Well, I don't have a news, I mean there probably is easy to find news.
Scott: but whatever I played this game that I paid a few dollars for Called Heretics fork, right and heretic I was.
Scott: I was willing to pay for it because based on everything I saw it was a combination of Other games that I had seen right.
Scott: there were slate aspire elements.
Scott: There were inscription elements.
Scott: There were tower defense elements.
Scott: There were aesthetic elements from like demons tilt or Death crown sort of that, you know, that's sort of really scary kind of horror hell pixel II kind of aesthetic going on Elements of What's it called the one where it's a hypno space outlaw.
Scott: Right, basically it was elements from a lot of games that were great games and it seemed like they were all combined in one game.
Scott: So I checked it out And what it is?
Scott: Heretics fork is basically It's more similar to like a solo tabletop card game like, you know Freedman's freeze Friday, and if you don't know about those basically, it's sort of like playing Dominion by yourself Right where you have a little deck and you play cards every turn Right and you're trying to optimize this deck.
Scott: and if you optimize it well enough to beat You know this AI or basically just to beat these numbers that are in the computer then you win.
Scott: So what's happening is every to every turn you draw four cards and you have six energy Right a lot like a slay the spire kind of deal and you can play cards and the cards Upgrade this tower defense that you've set that you have right and after you're done playing all your cards and not doing anything else You you basically say go and the tower defense just sort of happens and you either make it or you don't make it Right and it gets harder as you go on and the thing that makes the strategy comes in is that?
Scott: You can always take two cards that are the same level right and combine them to basically You know destroy them and get a card.
Scott: That's one level higher.
Scott: All right, but your deck always stays at like at least 13 cards.
Scott: They keep adding rocks to it automatically which like the worst garbage cars that you you can use.
Scott: but really what you do usually do with rocks is combine two rocks to get a level one card and Occasionally, there's all sorts of other mechanics in there that you know get some other cards and other stuff like that, but it's actually pretty fun because They give you like six Several characters to choose from and you're trying to beat the game with each character and all the characters play the game Somewhat significantly different.
Rym: I mean slay the spires got that going on.
Rym: The four characters are very different in how they actually play.
Scott: Yeah, the final character is the only one haven't beaten the game with yet They don't let you do the cards the normal way.
Scott: They have a money system where you destroy cards to get money and then you buy cards with the money.
Rym: Ooh, and it's yeah, it's like it's you know It's an extra dancer where you get the one character and instead of a rhythm game.
Scott: It's just a puzzle game Mmm, yeah sort of like that.
Scott: Yeah And then you know the main menu of the game is a lot like Hypno space outlaw where it's like this desktop of a computer And it's I see evil Clippy.
Scott: Yeah, there's an evil Clippy and basically there's a plot.
Scott: We're like, you know, you're you think you're playing a game But actually like you're you know torturing damned people in hell and maybe you're also a damned person in hell And you know that kind of thing, right?
Scott: Once you beat the game with all six characters There's this ad you get a key every time you win with a new character.
Scott: There's an admin thing You got to unlock.
Scott: I haven't gotten the final key so I can't even spoil it if I wanted to.
Scott: But it's you know, it's semi inscription.
Scott: as with the with the plot and Hypno space outlaw ask with the you know desktop interface.
Scott: so If that sounds like fun to you play it, it's not fun to me.
Scott: It's not the most fun thing ever It's.
Scott: I don't think it's as good as any of those games that I mentioned.
Scott: It's not as good as slay the spire.
Scott: It's not as good as it no space outlaw.
Scott: It's not as good as you know, any of those ones But it takes elements from all of them and combines them.
Scott: So if you are an enjoyer of those you probably will still enjoy this.
Scott: despite it not being as good It's still good enough that you know And it's in a bundle right now on Steam.
Scott: actually with this other game called 20 minutes to something What game was it on?
Scott: second as I've played that other game also 20 minutes - I don't see a bundle here.
Scott: Oh wait, the hair is still done.
Scott: Yeah, so 20 minutes till dawn is basically the same game as vampire survivors except Probably better because you actually you don't just automatically shoot you actually control the shooting.
Scott: It's got a good aesthetic - yeah, but it's basically 20 minutes till dawn is bait is like 90% the same game as Vampire survivor.
Scott: Yeah, so if you like vampire survivors Like I played vampire survivors up until they added like the gold system to it And then I was like.
Scott: that's enough of that.
Scott: But it's like if you want more of that, but you don't want the exact same game It's like is another one of those.
Scott: Yeah, so you can get a bundle together if you really want.
Rym: but anyway things Of the day I just bumped into this.
Rym: I thought it was super cute.
Rym: It's a little animation about Hobson a Miku set to the Adam on a Gucci song about Hobson a Miku And it just got stuck in my head and the animations super cute and she's hiding in your Wi-Fi.
Rym: That's all I got.
Scott: Yeah, I gotta say though that like, you know Miku being still being around.
Rym: Oh, yeah, Miku was a precursor I think every we said a lot about what Miku foretold for the future and Yeah It's still happening.
Rym: because real right
Scott: but like that's just an you know, I've been thinking lately that like You know of all the animes right that there are That you know our sci-fi and of course sci-fi is are always telling the futures, right and Saying um play gods and such and such.
Scott: but I'm feeling that you know, the world we're in right now is Probably closer to macross plus Any any other anime world right?
Scott: Yeah all the animes that's the one that got it the most right, right?
Scott: We're not in a Kira world.
Scott: Yeah, you know, we're not in a.
Rym: you know, we're We're like halfway between a macross world and a ghost in the shell world because they're both.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's like we're really close.
Scott: We are quite close to a macross plus world.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: I mean Hobson a Miku is Real and is out there
Scott: like the stuff that's going on right now, so
Rym: project a little bit into the future of Hobson a Miku like things coupled with large language models and there's gonna be entirely autonomous youtubers Intractorating kids into ridiculous nonsense,
Scott: but the fact that we finally have something resembling an AI and it's entertainment focused Primarily.
Scott: Yeah, and it's moving away faster than most people expected it to like people You know people are using it to make music.
Scott: Yeah, it's like Okay Thing of the day.
Scott: so this person what was their name?
Scott: doo-doo-doo Eric Wernquist, I'm gonna guess.
Scott: maybe they're Swedish, right?
Scott: With a name like Wernquist, but they might not be they might.
Scott: you know, who knows but they made a short film.
Scott: It's basically five minutes long.
Scott: The short film is called one revolution per minute And it's about a space station that turns that one revolution per minute and creates one half G's of gravity with its turning artificial gravity.
Scott: And it's really just.
Scott: you're watching, you know.
Scott: They basically rendered the space station in 3d right that there's a fictional one that they made and they did a really good job of it and It's sort of basically giving you a tour of the space station While there's a narrator speaking and nobody's on the space station, right or you know, please doesn't appear anyone's on it And you may see just looking around it, you know, they're showing off the good big fancy job They did rendering this thing and modeling it.
Scott: and while a narrator you know is sort of Giving sort of like a welcome to the space station like the thing you would hear if you had just landed and docked and got On board and it's you know, is that for five minutes?
Scott: But I got to say this would make a great intro to like a Bioshock esque video game, you know type of You know, that's what it feels like.
Scott: like.
Scott: it feels like you're watching the intro video to Something shocked the video game.
Rym: Yeah, I'm like where you're gonna be where the whole games.
Rym: and then it's like well good luck You're on your own.
Scott: the whole game is about to be you on this space station Exploring it figuring it out Metroiding who knows what the hell, right?
Scott: But it's just a movie it's not a game that's it.
Rym: So not that.
Rym: but you know Not a waste of five minutes of your day to watch this in the meta moment the GeekNights book club book Which we will do Shortly after the next book comes out.
Rym: and we've read it which won't be too long away.
Rym: the murder bot diaries.
Rym: I have read four point nine murder bots.
Scott: I Read all of them except for the one that isn't out yet.
Rym: Yep To the individual who said that the fifth book dragged and was long and the humans were annoying I think I have the exact opposite opinion.
Rym: that touched into the kinds of things that I am into and Now that I have a more context on what alien remnants are.
Rym: Yeah, it's just the alien aliens universe This is just the alien aliens universe pretty much straight up.
Rym: Yeah, obviously Yeah, but it it basically hits you over the head with that in the fifth book, especially the whole yeah All the corporations.
Rym: the only thing the only thing they agree on as these corporate libertarian hell companies Is that nobody's allowed to fuck with aliens because they're too dangerous alien shit too dangerous.
Rym: You need permits and we and no one ever gets a permit.
Rym: That's uh, that's the alien world right there and great Chris is definitely the kind of company that would send a ship to go do something it shouldn't.
Rym: Otherwise, we're gonna be a Pax West Pax West.
Rym: we were at Pax unplugged.
Rym: I haven't posted the news yet with the link cuz I'm waiting for the pack schedule to go up so I can link to it.
Rym: We will be live at Pax unplugged with a panel a brand new panel mastering game mechanics worker placement, we're gonna talk about nothing but worker placement mechanics for 59 minutes.
Rym: Gonna be glorious.
Rym: I think we have more than 59 minutes worth of stuff to say.
Rym: So we already got to figure out how to pare that down.
Rym: We will also be doing
Scott: to make the GeekNights' website
Rym: Live
Scott: this weekend, maybe We'll say
Rym: the only thing I got to do this weekend is I think at 6 a.m I have to do a practice run with my marathon or running team in Central Park and run 18 miles in a group.
Scott: I may attempt to bike to an apple orchard, but maybe not.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see I. hopefully it looks like the wildfire smoke is not gonna hang around too long So I should be fine for this.
Rym: our second event at Pax unplugged will be.
Scott: there was another event.
Rym: Okay Oh, yeah, we have a long slot in the learn and play.
Scott: I thought that I thought that that met him.
Rym: it was oh, yeah Because we will also be doing a learn and play And win meaning we're gonna teach strategy for real on the basics of trick-taking games.
Rym: We're gonna teach whist And have you all play like one hand a whist but not a whole game a whist cuz whist is literally obsolete.
Rym: Then we're gonna teach hearts.
Rym: Then we're gonna play a 40-point hand of hearts with everybody and then we're gonna play the wizard.
Rym: Yeah, I Feel like that cover is all like the core types of mechanics.
Rym: We can teach people around like what cards to shove into some idiots hand so they lose hearts like that kind of advice.
Rym: It'll be a good time Here, would you like some high spades?
Rym: Would you like all my high clubs?
Scott: I?
Scott: Have a problem.
Scott: I Did not push record until three minutes ago.
Rym: Oh, let me put a little marker there.
Rym: I Can salvage audio of you from the discord, it'll just be slightly shitty.
Rym: So for any of you listening at home the listener the the audio of Scott Before this point will sound before it before three minutes ago.
Rym: Well sound somewhat bad, but it'll be fine.
Rym: Don't sweat it.
Rym: Oh God, I changed the volume.
Rym: I'm gonna have to run a filter.
Rym: I can handle that.
Rym: Anyway, no biggie I will.
Rym: I can talk about that in the stinger.
Rym: Ah Let's just get right into it.
Rym: so Counter-strike is the game.
Scott: I'm trying to think of games.
Scott: Did an episode on counter-strike exclamation point on June 13th 2006?
Scott: So in GeekNights wasn't even a year old, right?
Scott: then we did an episode and counter-strike go.
Scott: first thoughts only in 2012 so six years after that.
Scott: so So we did an episode on counter-strike when it was six years old.
Scott: We did an episode and counter-strike go when it was brand new and counter-strike as a whole was 12 years old.
Scott: right now counter-strike is 23 years old.
Rym: Yep, and when we did that episode on counter-strike in 2006 we had already been playing counter-strike for six years, right?
Scott: But yeah, we're doing an episode on counter-strike when it's 23 years old and for its 23rd anniversary I guess close to it in its 23rd anniversary year.
Scott: They have released counter-strike 2.
Rym: Yep, so the progression is interesting.
Scott: Not 2.0, just 2.0 because you know Valve can't count to three.
Scott: So this is the end.
Scott: This is it.
Rym: This is the last counter-strike.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: They don't know how to count to three.
Scott: This is the end.
Rym: Granted I still do believe that half-life Alex is effectively half-life 3.
Rym: It's just they couldn't sell it to enough people because VR is not enough.
Rym: that doesn't have enough adoption.
Rym: Anyway, it is the best half-life game.
Scott: The first thing you need to know about counter-strike 2 and this is probably most of what there is to talk about actually is that You get it for free you get it.
Scott: Well, you get it, right?
Scott: It's like it is basically it.
Scott: they removed counter-strike go from the face of the earth.
Scott: It basically is taking up the same spot in the steam store.
Scott: So if you already had counter-strike go congrats.
Scott: you now have counter-strike 2 and you don't have counter-strike.
Scott: go Nobody has counter-strike.
Scott: go it is go on right.
Scott: Goodbye.
Rym: Thousands of Nerds who are specific about that particular version suddenly cried out in anger cried out in anguish and were suddenly Silenced.
Scott: and I gotta say like I understand kind of why they did that.
Scott: But also it's kind of bullshit right from a preservation standpoint from.
Scott: I bought that game standpoint.
Scott: Like imagine if I bought Mario 3 the counter-strike go also free to play.
Scott: I Don't know.
Rym: I think I'm pretty sure.
Scott: I think that we can.
Scott: the problem is is I think what they've done Is that because we had counter-strike?
Scott: Back in the day as a mod.
Scott: We got it for free and because of that we've had it for free since then Free.
Scott: I think that at some point other people had to buy Counter-strike like to get in and once you're in you're in.
Scott: but we were in.
Scott: We were sort of in at the beginning with it.
Rym: forget that there was also counter-strike source.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, what was interesting, but that still exists.
Scott: That's not gone.
Rym: Yeah, but what's funny is first I could tell no one plays it.
Scott: No, why would you think?
Rym: but counter-strike one six still has a lot of players.
Scott: Yes, that still exists.
Scott: Anyway, so That's kind of BS.
Scott: Another thing that I've seen people bring up this kind of BS is that because it takes up the same spot in the steam store regardless of counter-strike go still existing or not all of all of the reviews for a counter-strike go apply to Counter-strike 2. and if you were to filter If you were to filter the steam store and Sort of separate the reviews for counter that since counter-strike 2 was released since when counters You know and remove all the counter-strike go reviews counter-strike 2 actually has mixed reviews.
Scott: But if you look at the store right now Let's look at the store right now.
Scott: actually and let's see counter-strike 2 store page Because all the counter-strike go reviews are mixed in.
Scott: it has mostly positive and very positive Whereas if you didn't include those old reviews from 2012 onwards, it would be mixed instead.
Scott: So whether I don't not saying I agree or disagree with the mixed review, but just that hey It is like a new engine.
Scott: It's you know, a lot of things are similar But also not is it?
Scott: is it disingenuous to apply those reviews to the new game?
Scott: It's a controversy.
Scott: this is something, you know, I don't care too much about it, but it is a thing though.
Rym: fortnight has Just versions that change more than counter-strike 2 changed over counter-strike 1 6 just like randomly on a Tuesday.
Rym: Yeah, it's right Like Galactus shows up and kills everybody and then spider-man's there and then a bunch of weapons are gone and there's a new vehicle and the Maps totally different.
Scott: Yep Anyway, so counter-strike 2. we played it for quite a session and then Rym kept playing Because I got.
Rym: I'm gonna admit right now Overwatch is my primary like.
Scott: right now the game I will default to if I want a competitive series experience is still overwatch But I see the fight that basically puts what likely to be the final overwatch championship just happened, Florida one.
Rym: Yeah You know, I never.
Scott: it's probably the end.
Rym: It's funny because I love Watching the matches of overwatch league, but I do not care at all about the people or the teams or who wins.
Rym: I just watch the matches because they're the best overwatch players on earth.
Rym: and that is how I get better because it is you can Watch them from one of their eyes and see what the fuck they're doing to be better than me.
Rym: So I guess Counter-strike 2 I didn't play a lot of counter-strike God go like.
Rym: I actually didn't like counter-strike go that much as it went on Partly big for a lot of reasons that are kind of irrelevant to this.
Scott: I mean I didn't actually didn't hate counter-strike go.
Scott: the thing is and it's you know The same thing is gonna keep me from playing counter-strike 2. is it just like?
Scott: I'm not any good at these games I just get I just.
Scott: it's like back in the day.
Scott: It's like I got instant headshot at a lot even when there was all kinds of cheating going on, right?
Scott: But not it's not as much as I do now Like when we play counter-strike 2.
Scott: I was absolutely ineffective a debuts bear against real people.
Scott: I was barely playing.
Rym: Yeah, no, I don't think you had enough matchmaking data So it's hard.
Scott: No, I probably I could probably play a bunch until the matchmaking put me against other garbage players.
Scott: You can't click on heads.
Rym: I played about have five matches and then suddenly everyone and every server I joined in casual was about my skill level.
Scott: Right, but it's like.
Scott: it's not the game's fault that the kind of game It is was once the kind of game for me and is now not right.
Rym: Yep Well part of it too I think is that unlike you like I have been playing FPS is pretty like competitive.
Rym: FPS is pretty much continuously since 2000. like I never stopped.
Rym: I've been playing them just regularly for 20 years not counting the 10 years I played them before that.
Rym: so I just kept that going.
Rym: even though I am older and I'm slower I am finding I can still click on heads pretty well if I just continue to play and practice.
Scott: But it also doesn't help that even when I was playing FPS games very regularly, right?
Scott: I wasn't really that good at clicking on heads even on my best day.
Rym: Yeah But I guess the danger to me is that when we play Counter-Strike 2 together I had thought I had a lot to say for the review and I didn't think I'd play it that much.
Rym: But then I played some more and I hit a moment and I realized for me at least as someone who has played Every version of Counter-Strike kind of
Scott: played every version
Rym: Yeah, but I played them all kind of a lot like I kept playing them even when you stop playing them.
Rym: Counter-Strike 2 is a breath of fresh air.
Rym: and I say that because Counter-Strike go.
Rym: when you went into the game They put so much crap and all these different modes and all this bullshit around the skins like it was so front and center and the Missions and all the like stuff to trick you into buying a key to open a thing That it was like a chaotic mess like how Fortnite was.
Rym: and when I wanted to just play Counter-Strike like I remembered from the old days of 1.6 and swords hanging out at RIT Really couldn't find a server or a group of people who played that way and it just wasn't that fun.
Rym: Counter-Strike 2. when you launch it you get a completely empty screen And you just your guys standing there.
Rym: you can click a button and there's a small number of modes that are basically the modes you want and everything kind of just works and all the cruft has been pushed aside.
Rym: unless you look for it and When you do click into casual mode Most of the time the server you join with the people you play with.
Rym: It's about like how it was in the old days.
Rym: Like it's just refreshing.
Rym: people are playing Counter-Strike.
Rym: They're mostly trying to win.
Rym: The feel is just very different from every feel I got with the people I was playing Counter-Strike go with And I'm gonna play it a lot.
Rym: They've
Scott: made a lot of changes to the game that are Like, you know significant but also it's like, you know, the game has been around so long that like they're really polishing some some You know like really specific things but in a way that makes a big difference like the way the smoke works now.
Scott: They made it volumetric smoke.
Scott: It looks so good, right?
Scott: It's like bullets go through the smoke sort of you know, and I push make little holes in the smoke, right?
Scott: It's like they are really like the amount of polish that has gone on.
Scott: now Just one example the shadows.
Rym: the shadows are fully dynamic and look amazing But they're also game impacting because now there's some prices like, you know, right?
Scott: We're not talking about just graphical shininess.
Rym: here We're talking about things that actually matter for the game Like the smoke is a big deal because smoke is a big part of serious Counter-Strike play.
Scott: The way the mall the way the fire Molotov cocktails now work like you can get them to you can set water on fire with.
Rym: I was in a map and I was hiding in a spot that I used to like to hide in back at RIT because the map Hasn't changed much and I see Overhead a shadow of what is clearly a terrorist just goes boop boop boop.
Rym: So I know a terrorist is standing right above me and I just aim my stair-og straight up and shot him through the floor and killed Him.
Scott: Yeah, it's like this.
Scott: these, you know, you think oh the guy doesn't it matters.
Rym: Yeah, the sound the soundscape the sound whatever they're doing for the sound Counter-Strike was notable even in the 1/6 era for being Extremely good at helping you locate people because sound is a big part of what makes the game fun.
Rym: You're sneaking around.
Rym: walking versus running is a big deal.
Rym: hearings us one foot step.
Rym: It could be the difference between winning and losing a match.
Rym: the sound design to locate where someone is in this game is Somehow better and I can't articulate how but it is hyper realistic in a weird way that just works.
Scott: It feels really natural Yeah, but it's it's still the same game.
Scott: it's counter-strike you're bombing.
Scott: you're right.
Scott: The things is is that you know, you talked about all the how clean it is And I do appreciate that the menus and everything.
Scott: It's like just really straightforward and not a big mess.
Scott: However, it's like there were a lot of modes in Counter-Strike go that are now gone.
Rym: Yep, the modes like quick mode I was even called the mode where like the magic war games or something.
Scott: It's like you can't play gun game right now.
Scott: It's like they took it out.
Scott: Yeah, so it's not there.
Rym: We know gun game will come back.
Rym: I'm 100% confident.
Scott: I'm sure it'll come back eventually, but it's like you could play it and now you can't.
Scott: It's like I paid for csgo or someone paid for csgo.
Scott: And now that the mode is just gone too bad.
Scott: Yeah There's also.
Scott: it's like when you choose modes, it's like you're choosing like these map sets.
Scott: It's like map set one map set two and then like dust is your third us to dust specific to.
Scott: yeah It's like you can't just like choose the map you want directly and that's like you set up a server something right?
Scott: It's like Like if you only want to play nuke you really can't do that.
Scott: You have to it's like nuke and another map or in the same bundle and you're gonna sort of just be playing those maps.
Rym: Yeah, you get a vote because it'll keep groups together.
Scott: generally Yeah, but you can't just play like.
Scott: you can't pick one map that's not dust to and play it on repeat.
Rym: though What's interesting is unless you joined a very specific servers back in the day in the one six era There weren't many ways to do that then either.
Rym: like there were a handful of servers that were map specific.
Scott: Like there was a default the default counter-strike service back in the day Just had all like every single default map on a rotation in order except our server, which was just fy ic world.
Scott: Well, that's because all the cpu could handle was icy world with like a smaller number of players.
Rym: So the other thing that's notable and this is something that overwatch also did I think is very important Relative to the powers of modern game pcs and relative to how good this game looks.
Scott: counter-strike 2 will basically run on a potato Yeah, so on the one hand they did.
Scott: I believe they increased the requirements somewhat, right?
Scott: But you're right.
Scott: It only requires eight gigs of ram.
Scott: I didn't check what the requirements were before but it requires eight gigs of ram, which is like Any computer.
Scott: you buy the cheapest computer available geforce 610 m or better.
Scott: so basically Any old laptop that you buy any computer you buy new in the united like in the united states is going to play counter-strike.
Scott: Well, it's gonna be way above, you know, it can't run it.
Rym: my htpc because it has a gtx 450 m.
Scott: Yeah, so the the minimum cpu required is the core I. uh core All right, so the core i5 750. wait, is that a nahalem number?
Rym: that looks like a nahalem number.
Scott: That's a. so you got to imagine right?
Scott: We're currently on what the intel 14 series, right?
Scott: Yeah Uh, and so if this is a 700 That means this.
Rym: I think that's nahalam That this came.
Scott: this cpu came out in Yep, so you can see you can have a cpu That's older than counter-strike.
Scott: go and play counter-strike Two.
Rym: now even the recommended requirements.
Rym: They basically like cpu never matters.
Rym: But uh a geforce 2070 is what they recommend which is better than what I got.
Rym: I didn't turn the settings all up to max because I only got a 1080 still Mm-hmm, but with a 1080 without everything set to the max it looks phenomenal.
Scott: Yeah, um, but you know, you'll still.
Scott: I i'd love to try and get the exact computer like an i5.
Scott: seven With eight make gigs of ram and see how counter-strike two runs on it, right?
Rym: I guess I could turn all my settings down to the minimum just to see what it would look like.
Scott: Yeah, i'm sure that's probably would be similar but your monitor is too high.
Scott: res is the problem.
Scott: Yeah, right You I don't know.
Scott: if you'd be able to do 1080p with that setup you might have to do lower than that.
Rym: But I guess 720 in terms of the game like reviewing the game.
Rym: I mean, it's counter-strike.
Scott: There's only so much to say but The reason you don't already know counter-strike.
Scott: I mean It's a team-based fps.
Scott: There's bomb mode and there's Hostage mode.
Scott: Yeah, it's usually five on five, but you could have different numbers, right?
Scott: When you die you die until the next round.
Scott: there's no respawning like quake which was basically.
Scott: You know, I don't know if counter-strike was the first game to do that ever but it was the first game that made that a thing.
Rym: Right, you know what else did it?
Rym: did it?
Rym: action quick?
Rym: Do well action quick to the default mode was basically the same as counter-strike, but there was no bomb, right?
Scott: Right, and then basically you play until either one team is completely dead Or the bomb goes off or the hostages are rescued Or even if everyone's dead on the terrorist team who has the bomb.
Scott: if the bomb has been planted and it goes off The terrorists can still win even if they all die and do basically a suicide bombing mission
Rym: Or
Scott: old counter-strike
Rym: at other ones Like did the did the vip make it to the chopper or did the terrorists escape the prison?
Scott: And that's and mostly it's an fps where you're moving slowly.
Scott: You're not moving like quake where it's fast.
Scott: Uh, you start with the pistols in the first round and you earn money as the game goes on in sort of a snowball effect.
Scott: Um where the winning team gets more money to buy better weapons They have a better chance to keep to maintain their advantage But you still get plenty of money if you lose and you can come back.
Scott: It's not like a devastating difference.
Scott: You can choose what weapons you want pistols sniper rifles submachine guns big machine guns grenades of various kinds armors and all sorts of stuff And all the weapons are not so realistic like arma or you know pubg But they're also not unrealistic like doom or quake.
Scott: yep, you know, they're.
Scott: um, and the game is all about like Basically, you don't die in one shot, but you can if it's a like a head shot with a sniper rifle.
Rym: It's basically about like squad tactics like do when the shit hits the fan.
Rym: because you know The setting of counter-strike is the negotiation with the terrorist just failed and the swat team was just sent in.
Rym: and that's when a match starts.
Scott: Yep, or the swat team knows the terrorists are coming.
Scott: the terrorists are like fuck it We're gonna blow this shit up here.
Scott: come and that the you know It's that exact moment is when the game starts.
Scott: So all the stuff that before and after it outside of a terrorist situation are not addressed by counter-strike.
Rym: And I guess what struck me was in the casual modes of csgo.
Rym: It was like people were just kind of running around like not actually really playing and it wasn't that fun I have found playing in casual and competitive mode.
Rym: in the new counter-strike People are trying to win at about the same level as what I remember from RIT and It struck something in me.
Rym: I forgot how fun this game is when everyone's in the same At the same level and caring about the same amount.
Rym: because this game is fundamentally about moving as a squad Covering your teammates being tricky and trying to trap or ambush the other side.
Rym: Because if you're not moving and someone comes around a corner who is moving?
Rym: you were very likely able to kill them Because they won't be able to shoot you due to the fact that since they're moving their recoil is all over the place like they won't Be able to hit you.
Rym: so like your friend moves forward while you cover them They hide and cover the window.
Rym: while you sneak past you throw a flashbang everyone runs in and what the game is added is The radar is a lot a little better and more focused the ray.
Scott: I can't say that in old counter-strikes the radar was always there, but I never used it.
Scott: in fact I think there was a time where someone said someone told me to use the radar and I didn't realize it existed And you were
Rym: like it's not there, and we're like yeah, it is look at the upper edge of screen, and you're like oh fuck
Scott: Yeah, that was there the whole time.
Scott: I never noticed it, but also that radar was so useless even if you did look at it It was so different.
Scott: It was not a good radar.
Scott: It was like just.
Scott: it was like using the thing and freaking aliens right we're just dots And it doesn't show you like is that guy?
Scott: is that dot in the hallway?
Scott: is that dot up down right?
Scott: the new radar?
Scott: Was actually super useful, and I found myself looking at it a lot Maybe too much which is might be why I was getting shot and killed because I was looking at the radar.
Rym: They've added pings, and I don't know how much of this might have been in csgo But I never remember seeing it and other ways to communicate beyond voice and and also some of the hierarchy of attention types of things that games like overwatch and real world things like fighter jets use like the modern science of Attention hierarchies of user experience design so that the game is giving you everything you need to Naturally coordinate with your team without actually having to say words in the microphone, and it is shockingly effective because Counter-Strike had a reputation partly because one of the first games to be popular like this online at scale of having a popular
Scott: 23 years
Rym: But in the old days like if there's voice chat or text chat people just being absolutely horrible in those chats.
Rym: So far my experience in Counter-Strike 2 is that nobody's been horrible and teams are Coordinating at the level that required being in a ventrilo server in the old days Despite the fact that nobody is in voice and people are only using the nonverbal in-game communication.
Scott: And you don't want to be employees because they assume that everyone else is gonna be a piece of shit And they don't want to yeah, but that nobody's in voice.
Rym: everyone's just using the the systems in the game and I've saw in casual matches at my like I guess I'm probably the lowest possible skill rank People were playing the high-level game of rotate between the bomb points or Coordinate and be a distraction like all the kinds of ploys and clever plays that you think you'd only see among serious players.
Rym: I was seeing that for real and participating in it in casual games and that did not happen organically at any point.
Rym: playing Counter-Strike go over the years.
Scott: So the question is should somebody Play Counter-Strike 2.
Rym: I would say if you've never played a Counter-Strike You should play it just to see what the deal is with Counter-Strike.
Rym: If you it doesn't matter if you like it or not, it's been around for 23 years.
Rym: There's something to it.
Rym: You at least need to understand what there is to it.
Rym: Even if you decide it's not for you.
Scott: well, there's actually a valve complete pack that is like 50 bucks that has basically a portal one portal to Team Fortress to Like every or the portals all the counter-strikes all the half-lives all the all the everything that about ricochets even in there.
Scott: See, you know if you haven't if you have a computer and you haven't played all those games.
Scott: But yeah, if you've never played a Counter-Strike even if you have no interest in it just Do it like one time like for you know, what 20 minutes just know how to counter-strikes under see what it is.
Scott: Right, if you maybe you'll like it.
Scott: I don't know if you if you have counter-strikes in the past and have not in a while.
Scott: Should you come back?
Rym: Absolutely Yes, this is your best chance to see if it's still for you because I think a lot of people I guess
Scott: Have the mood for it, right if you don't if you're not if you already know counter-strike and you're not it's like this is Counter-strike, it's not gonna be something different than what you remember.
Scott: So if there's no counter-strike, I guess I'd the mood.
Scott: Then here you go.
Rym: I Not to get back into counter-strike.
Rym: I feel I almost felt like I was gonna play it to review it But then it bit me in a way I didn't expect and I think other people may experience the same thing if you slowly fell off of counter-strike During the go era.
Rym: This is a chance to see if you still like counter-strike because I feel like they have course corrected from the direction go was going Mmm-hmm.
Rym: It just felt a lot more like old counter-strike, which I think was better.
Scott: Hmm, and then I guess if you're already playing counter-strike, it's like, you know, you're already playing counter-strike all the time.
Scott: We don't you need to hear anything from us because we play counter-strike a lot less than you do.
Rym: Yeah, I may be playing a lot better and there is a mode I think we should talk about briefly and we can end on that.
Rym: There is a. you can make a local matchmaking group and this is a cool feature.
Rym: More games should do this So you and all your friends can share one code and be in a group and it'll basically match make among just your friends.
Rym: Yep, that's it.
Rym: Like think about the ramifications of that.
Scott: Well, it's like let's say we had.
Scott: it only really comes into a play if you have a lot of friends I like enough to be able to fill a server.
Scott: Right, it's like let's say you do have 10 friends at a LAN party, right?
Scott: It can basically line things up and get your teams pretty even right.
Scott: And what if I don't know if it'll work if you have more than one server's worth of people Like?
Scott: what if you have you know?
Scott: 50 people at a LAN party and Everyone joins?
Scott: is it going to match?
Scott: make amongst the 50 people and they make like 10 teams that are balanced You know?
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: Well, maybe I haven't actually tried it.
Scott: I just read about it.
Scott: They
Rym: had the thing where if you played on a private server that you just spun up you could enable a mode where after every Match it would rebalance the teams based on which team did better and who was responsible for them being better to try to make the matches as even as it possibly can among the people playing and it was Actually really effective and allowed a lot of people who would otherwise bounce off of that match to keep playing.
Scott: Yeah, but I got to say though, it's still don't if you're in a game that is not match made.
Scott: well, yeah, right It's still the same game.
Scott: one person who can click on heads You'll is gonna make their team win regardless of anything.
Scott: the other nine players do So.
Scott: but I got past that you might have to sit through a lot of games - until the matchmaking basically puts you up against nobody who can click on heads.
Scott: or if you can click on heads You might be stuck clicking on a lot of heads and winning but Against people who are vastly inferior and not giving you a good challenge until you get ranked up and are against other click on heads people.
Rym: I did revisit the old strategy of rather than just running out every match I hung back.
Rym: I looked at who is good on the team.
Scott: Let everyone else be the meat shield Yeah.
Rym: But also I followed.
Rym: like if a group of two people who were like near the top of the team and clearly knew what they were Doing were on my team I would follow them and Basically like cover them when they walk through dangerous places and just try to keep them alive.
Rym: And that actually allowed me to be a productive useful member of my team
Scott: and it also Is a good idea for lower skilled people and
Rym: it also wanted reminded me of things I'd forgotten like where to hide and like what the good points that places to have a firefighter are and it It meant that I survived long enough to fucking remember how to play this game instead of when we play
Scott: There.
Scott: there are maps that I remember like, you know, Italy office dust - Etc.
Scott: Yeah nuke, but they're also maps where if I did play them in their old versions, I do not remember It's really funny.
Rym: inferno is one of the old maps.
Rym: We played all the time, but it's I don't remember the layout well enough.
Rym: Yeah, it's so visually different that it's unrecognizable.
Rym: if you don't like remember the continuity And I don't think you ever played inferno in the go.
Scott: I definitely didn't play it well enough to remember it whenever I played.
Scott: Yeah, if I did It's like I was I felt like a brand new map to me and I was lost
Rym: even though it is the exact same map To the point that I hid in the spot I used to hide in the original days of that map and you know what?
Rym: It's still a great hiding spot and I won a couple matches by hiding there.
Scott: We should mention that there is a practice mode.
Scott: I did the practice mode against bots.
Scott: I don't know if you can change the bot difficulty Assume you can but the bots were so bad that I was just walking around mowing them down no problem.
Scott: So, I don't know how much of a practice that is.
Scott: and if you can't change it you I guess you can.
Scott: I just I'm Assuming you can.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: and then there is also a deathmatch mode, which I got really confused at.
Scott: it's awful Because in the deathmatch mode there are terrorists and counter-terrorists, but it's not a team battle like you and you kill anyone.
Scott: you see Deathmatch and when you spawn You like get a weapon, but you can still buy stuff in instead if you want to instead of what you're given And you get a few invincibility frames like it when you first spawned.
Scott: So it's like on the one hand you can sort of get kills like when you're spawning But it's also super dangerous when you spawn if like someone's nearby and catches you as soon as your invincibility frames go away.
Rym: There was a moment.
Rym: we both you didn't notice them every time either one of us spawn.
Rym: We just started counting the seconds and very rarely.
Rym: Did we hit the number five before we die?
Scott: Yeah, it's like right.
Scott: It's like either when you spawn it you see someone and you get them because you had invincibility frames and they were on.
Scott: they were Unready for you to spawn there.
Scott: or they didn't notice you.
Scott: or be you spawn and die instantly because someone was waiting for invincibility frames to go away.
Scott: Yeah, so It's not a great.
Scott: it's not a great mode, right?
Scott: I think it would be.
Scott: you know They need to do something different for spawning.
Scott: in a game Where you die so quickly and the map is so tight and there's so many people in the map when quake you spawn.
Scott: Usually spot, you know, the spawn points are sort of on the edges of a big map.
Scott: It's usually quiet there.
Scott: That's not where people are going around collecting quad quad damages and rocket launchers, right?
Scott: So you can usually spawn safely on a map full of players.
Scott: Yeah, you you know, even with the invincibility frames you can't really spawn.
Rym: I mean what they got to do is bring that gun game and team deathmatch.
Rym: Those are the two modes.
Rym: Those are.
Scott: those are much better.
Rym: gun game is just like that was I think was that invented in counter-strike?
Rym: That was the first time I ever saw that kind of mode.
Rym: Yeah for me It was the first time I saw I'd never encountered it before and so many other games have been like.
Rym: even overwatch has a gun game That is literally the same gun game you remember from counter-strike.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there's a long history of you know counter-strike mods But a lot of them were like stupid level up shit.
Scott: Oh that weird Wow one that like started Pokemon one.
Scott: there's all these.
Scott: there's tons of them.
Scott: They're all weird and zombie ones and all kinds of nonsense.
Scott: But the gun game was also one of those that actually happened to be good because it was really straightforward and made sense.
Scott: And I hope I'm sure they will but they have not yet brought it back which is like that's kind of sad.
Scott: It's like hey, you just made counter-strike 2 and it's less than what counter-strike go was mode wise.
Scott: That's you know, so I understand someone being upset about that.
Rym: I guess let us know if you're gonna play it.
Rym: if we have a critical mass of the listener then I don't have that.
Scott: We don't have 10 plus people.
Rym: If we can get enough people we can make a close.
Scott: Yeah, there's people who will nominally say like yes I will I want to but then when it's actually time there won't be 10 people there.
Rym: Yeah, we'll just play it play casually.
Scott: occasionally people will have bad internet.
Rym: I do occasionally pull a listener or two into my overwatch matches.
Scott: Yeah, one or two.
Scott: Yeah for sure.
Scott: Yeah, get that easily.
Rym: But but if we get enough all at least we're not a little making group and if it never gets used it never gets used.
Scott: Yeah We're not like those twitch streamers where like they have a big enough audience on their discord server that they can just make a game At any moment and fill it with people, right?
Rym: We also don't put in that much effort into scheduling games because we're busy Yeah in our 40s.
Scott: I don't that would require scheduling when I play counter-strike.
Scott: Yeah If I even play it, it's not like RIT.
Rym: where I come home from class I would play counter-strike.
Rym: Scott would come home and just join the counter-strike server.
Scott: I was in Yep, but counter-strike do is a thing now.
Scott: Here it is.
Rym: I'm gonna split my time equally between this and overwatch for the foreseeable minor.
Scott: at least my head is off to them for keeping something alive for 23 years and Maintaining the essence and not being a traitor to the thing it is, right?
Scott: They didn't like, you know, it's not like one of those remakes like.
Scott: it's bad now.
Scott: they didn't you know, it's they kept that same thing alive and Updated only the parts that were appropriate to update with the times and the technologies.
Rym: I also looked and it looks like you and I started playing counter-strike when beta 2 came out At the latest because beta 3 appears to be when the p90 was added and I remember the p90 being added and ever being Mad about it strike.
Scott: I guess whatever version was out in like September October of the year 2000.
Rym: Yeah, because November of 2000 is when the first non beta release happens.
Scott: So I played before then whatever was out in September October of the year 2000.
Scott: That was the first counter-strike I played.
Rym: so we played in the early early betas.
Scott: it was definitely beta something some number.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Rym: music can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce Linky G dread lily tenebrae case care makes music Chris Todd Christopher or Clinton Walton and death Mac Finn Joel Hayes penny rimer Rebecca Dunn Sam Erickson Shervin von Horl and several people whose names I will not say.
Rym: Yeah, Scott forgot hit record until halfway through the episodes.
Rym: I got to do a bunch of editing right now.
Rym: Yeah, I'm gonna use the backup audio for him.
Scott: So No record of a hurricane ever hitting Springfield.
Rym: Yes, but the records only go back to 1978 when the Hall of Records was mysteriously blown away.