Rym: It's Monday, January 2nd, 2023.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are talking about Microsoft Windows.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know, the operating system that some of you might have used at one point.
Scott: Sounds like Rym got the year right on the first go.
Rym: You know, I haven't fucked that up for a while.
Rym: That's actually one thing that I've gotten control of in my life.
Rym: Consistently.
Scott: You've had a...
Rym: I've had a few incidents over the years.
Rym: Usually, not the first episode of the year, because you're kind of on point for that one.
Rym: It's always like the second or the third episode of the year that I would fuck it up on.
Rym: You know, when you let your attention slide.
Rym: But yeah, we were gonna have a Maloki get together with our friends who live in Queens, New York party.
Rym: But the poop charts were off the charts, so we opted for a more recently traditional Discord New Years.
Rym: But we got out an old GeekNights tradition from the pre-GeekNights days.
Rym: And we played a game you might have heard of called Illuminati.
Scott: Have we ever reviewed Illuminati?
Scott: A game a lot of people might not have heard of.
Rym: I mean, not many people have even heard of Steve Jackson anymore if they're younger than us.
Rym: Have we ever done an episode on Illuminati?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: We're not hurting for Tuesday episodes.
Rym: I-L-L-U.
Rym: Let's look right now.
Rym: We have.
Rym: In 2008.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So we tried something different.
Rym: You know, our friend Pete put together something in TTS so we could play it remotely.
Rym: And it was good enough.
Rym: And it was totally playable.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: We played enough of the game to remember and feel what it's like to play that game.
Rym: And then we flipped the table at exactly midnight and that was the end of that.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: That was a good plan.
Rym: It scratched that itch.
Rym: if midnight had been later, if we'd started earlier.
Rym: I think I could have gone around the table like three or four more times and still be feeling it.
Scott: Whoa, that's a lot more times than I was.
Scott: I was ready for maybe one more time.
Rym: I find the point where that game gets to the Intolerable Zone is the first time someone makes a big move and you actually have to stop them because then the game literally turns into, "Alright, let's vote who wins in a very slow
Rym: fashion.".
Rym: Off to that point.
Scott: What's interesting is that, you know, two Steve Jackson games, right?
Scott: Illuminati and Munchkin, right?
Scott: One much more successful than the other financially, right?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Munchkin just prints money.
Scott: But both of them are sort of the same in that they have the core enjoyment factor is flip over a card and laugh at it, right?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, and the thing is both of them have that same mechanic of someone's gonna win on their turn, stop them till the game continues until eventually someone's gonna win and no one can stop them, right?
Scott: And then that person then wins.
Scott: The difference is that in Illuminati, right, the determination of which person that's gonna be that's gonna do the winning is based on voting, right?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Whereas in Munchkin, it's based on luck.
Rym: Yeah, well it's not 100% voting because there's a small amount of luck in Illuminati, but there's also the politicking matters a lot more.
Rym: because one thing about Illuminati compared to Munchkin, Munchkin, anyone playing that game can look at it and look at the hands and know who's winning and know like the state of the game.
Rym: But Illuminati, it's moderately obscured who is actually winning and there are big plays one could make and there's the final determinant.
Rym: The only problem being it's very hard to pull off.
Rym: You could have a joint victory in Illuminati, which you and I achieved once.
Rym: We tried it another time where you fucking betrayed me and then you also lost, which I remember specifically.
Rym: That was the night when we all took our shirts off because we were at a friend's house playing the game.
Rym: We were sitting at the table by the heater.
Rym: The heater was way too hot, so one by one we all started getting more and more nude playing Illuminati in the corner.
Scott: Don't remember any of this.
Rym: I have a photo of it.
Rym: Frank took his shirt off first and I was like, you know what?
Rym: That's a good idea and I took my shirt off.
Scott: Okay, but the point is I recommend, you know, ringing in the New Year's.
Scott: A lot of people ring in the New Year by like, you know, watching a thing, right?
Scott: Or like waiting for a thing to happen.
Scott: I recommend ringing in the New Year by doing a thing.
Rym: Yeah, like break a glass or like throw a rock out a window.
Rym: Like, yeah.
Scott: I guess those are really simple versions, but yeah, you know, do a thing, right?
Scott: And that's, you know, anyway.
Rym: It was a pretty good thing though.
Rym: Fortnite did a cool thing.
Rym: Last year, Scojo kept yelling at me to like join Fortnite, but I was busy on New Year's.
Rym: But on New Year's Day, they do the Snowpiercer thing.
Rym: So every hour when it's the New Year somewhere on Earth, every Fortnite match, no matter what's happened, no matter how competitive it is, fireworks happen.
Rym: And your character starts dancing uncontrollably and you can't shoot at each other for about 30 seconds.
Rym: And then the game just starts again.
Scott: So if you were in a close range firefight at that moment.
Rym: Oh, it happened.
Rym: So literally at 10 o'clock or 9 o'clock that night, it happened.
Rym: We're playing a match.
Rym: There's like eight people left.
Rym: I'm in this like really desperate shotgun fight with what I assume is a 13 year old and our characters start dancing.
Scott: And, you know, I bet they were an adult who assumed you were a 13 year old.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: While they might assume I'm a 13 year old, I know they're a 13 year old.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: But yeah.
Rym: So we're kind of just circling each other because we both know that at some point our shotguns are going to reappear.
Rym: And it was actually a moderately fun, tense moment.
Rym: And I totally shotgunned that kid in the face when the dancing stopped.
Scott: That's enough Tuesday talk on Monday.
Scott: Let's go to the Monday.
Rym: But I thought you were all about the cross-pollination.
Rym: There is big news, though.
Rym: There's so much news and we've already forgotten 99 percent of it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, let's go to this Monday news.
Scott: that's also not really a tech news other than the involvement of YouTube, which is a tech company kind of.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, this could be a Tuesday news.
Rym: This could be a Thursday news.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, there's this thing in the United States called the National Football League.
Scott: It's a sport that other countries don't have.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And we're such.
Rym: we're so inward looking in our own sports and our own sports are so big within our country that we just named one of our sports the same name as what you all call the actually biggest sport in the world.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But anyway, so this sport is broadcast differently from every other sport because there are.
Scott: it's so violent and so hard on the human body.
Scott: There are so few games of it per season.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Like baseball, basketball.
Rym: How many games do they play?
Scott: Constantly.
Rym: There's like games like every single American football game matters a lot unless you're eliminated.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then once you're in the playoffs, you basically stop trying because you don't want to get hurt.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So what happens is that every football game is a big deal.
Scott: And there are a few football games.
Scott: There's a Monday is one game on Monday night during the season, at least.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which is only a few months.
Scott: It runs from like, you know, September, like the autumn through, you know, February, basically.
Scott: And then that's it.
Scott: Um, so it's, it's a pretty short season and it's only your teams play once a week.
Scott: And then, except they have each team gets one week off for recovery, right?
Scott: Somewhere in the season.
Scott: Some, you know, who knows when it's going to be depends on the schedule.
Scott: And then if you make the playoffs, you keep going for a few more games in a little single elimination tournament, which ends in the superb owl.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if you're eliminated, obviously no playoffs.
Scott: So if you're, you're playing once a week, there's one game on Monday night, right?
Scott: Just one, one, two teams play on Monday night.
Scott: And every team is going to play on Monday night, like once a season, usually right.
Scott: There's a Thursday night game.
Scott: And obviously if you play on Monday or Thursday that week, you're not playing on any of the other nights that week.
Rym: Right.
Scott: I don't know if they have a Saturday one or not.
Scott: And I don't know if that was a thing at some, there was a thing at some points in time.
Scott: I don't know if it's a thing right now, whatever.
Rym: I mean, I used to watch more football, but for the last few years, I watch an average of three football games a year.
Rym: I watch the Super Bowl and I watch like the Thanksgiving Lions game.
Rym: And I like accidentally watch one more game.
Scott: On Thanksgiving specifically, on US Thanksgiving specifically, there are three games, right?
Scott: An early afternoon, late afternoon, night game, right?
Scott: Time zone varying.
Scott: There's one Sunday night game a week, and that is like the big game.
Scott: You know, NBC Sunday Night Football is actually the number one primetime television show in the United States.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Like look at this, there's a stereotype of American football fans where like they prepare for the game.
Rym: Like the game is a big event and that's kind of like a pop culture thing.
Rym: And there are problems with American football fan culture.
Rym: Like don't think I'm defending it deeply.
Rym: But there's a reason why people treat like the big game like a big game.
Rym: Like we don't do that when we watch a hockey game unless it's a playoff game.
Scott: So all those games I just mentioned, those individual games are like these nationally broadcast or cable broadcast, like special games, right?
Scott: That, you know, you have to have whatever thing to be able to watch them, right?
Scott: You know, either regular TV or for NBC, it's just nationally broadcast, right?
Scott: Or to think to watch them.
Scott: I don't know what channel Monday Night Football is on.
Scott: It used to be on ESPN.
Rym: I'm not sure, but I think we could get football OTA in New York pretty easily.
Scott: Well, I mean, oh yeah, if it's on one of the major networks, yeah.
Scott: But that's the point is that, so the rest of the football games, all the other games that aren't the special game of the week in one of those special slots is on Sunday afternoon.
Scott: And there's one o'clock games and there's four o'clock games.
Scott: And at the four o'clock games, there's very few four o'clock games.
Scott: Those are the games that are hot and they are, uh, like special better games, but they're not hot enough to be the Sunday night game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And there's only a few of the after those four o'clock games, at least Eastern time.
Scott: And those games have like a bit national broadcast, right?
Scott: There's so few of them that you're probably, you know, you got one on Fox and one on CBS.
Scott: It's like you got two to choose from.
Scott: You're going to see them if, and if you just have over the air broadcast television, no cable, no nothing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, and you know, if there's more, if there's like three or four of them, you're going to be able to see the two that are like closer to where you live, right.
Scott: Based on which teams are playing.
Scott: And then one o'clock is every other game.
Scott: Every other game is a one o'clock and you're one o'clock again, you only have two TV channels, Fox and CBS.
Scott: So you're only going to see the two one o'clock games, depending on where you live and all the other one o'clock games, you can't see them.
Scott: There's no way to see them.
Scott: You could buy all the cable TV in the world.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you're not going to be able to watch those games that are the one o'clock games that are, or that are not where you live and have teams involved that are not near you.
Scott: And there's maybe a couple four o'clock games that you also won't be able to see.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And so they sell a thing.
Scott: They sell a thing called the NFL Sunday ticket.
Scott: And if you buy the NFL Sunday ticket with that, you can watch every NFL game that is at one o'clock or four o'clock on Sunday.
Scott: That would not be available where you live.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it costs $300 a year, give or take.
Scott: It's very expensive.
Scott: And for the past very long period of time, DirecTV owned it.
Scott: So if you wanted the NFL Sunday ticket, you had to buy it from DirecTV because no one else had it.
Rym: Now, it says here that to buy it, you want you have to have a DirecTV subscription.
Rym: if you don't use the rest of DirecTV, which is 80 bucks a month.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: And then you have to pay for a package that apparently cost $150 a month.
Scott: It's a lot of money.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the idea is that, you know, who would buy this?
Scott: Someone who really cares about a football team and doesn't live near that football team.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Which is funny because the opposite, like in the NHL, it's really easy to watch a hockey game if you don't live in the town where that team plays.
Rym: But if you live there, you can't fucking see it.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So whereas in the NFL, it's like if you live near a team, you can just turn on a TV and watch it on Fox CBS with an antenna.
Scott: It's just broadcast.
Scott: So this deal, right, that DirecTV made also spawned the birth of perhaps the greatest invention in sports broadcasting, the red zone.
Scott: The red zone is basically one channel where there's someone hosting it and they're constantly flipping between all the exciting parts of the one o'clock and four o'clock games.
Scott: So you can't like see the whole game, but you can see the good bits live.
Scott: ish, slightly delayed ish, like curated for you.
Rym: It's good.
Rym: It's like watching the best of an F1 race.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you don't have the Sunday ticket necessarily.
Scott: You might because there's two different red zones, actually.
Scott: The original red zone was a DirecTV red zone hosted by this one guy.
Scott: I forget his name.
Scott: And that red zone was part of the ticket.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that was the only way to see that red zone.
Scott: But two years later, after that original red zone began, the NFL made its own separate red zone with this different guy named Scott, which is I only know him because his name is Scott.
Scott: So and that different red zone that the NFL official one, you can get that one with just cable TV.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or you could even watch it on the Internet if you have cable or you don't need to have the ticket to see that other red zone.
Scott: But obviously it doesn't let you watch the whole games.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's this guy curating for you.
Scott: The hot parts like someone's about to score a touchdown.
Scott: Let's go to that game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it does cover every game that's happening at one and four o'clock.
Scott: So YouTube is the big news.
Scott: DirecTV was paying one and a half billion billion dollars a year for the rights, the exclusive right to offer this Sunday ticket package since nineteen ninety four.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: For a long time.
Scott: They were losing its estimated five hundred million dollars a year on it.
Scott: So they were only.
Scott: they're spending three X and making back two X. They were losing a third of the money they spent.
Rym: I don't think there was any time where DirecTV was doing well based on memory alone.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But this is why the first this is the first point to get into to really think about this is why sports.
Scott: You know, leagues don't want to just sell some direct to consumer streaming deal.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because they're going to lose a third of the money.
Scott: By having this in between deal that they sign for a set amount.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They can lock in their revenues like a guaranteed number, not have to lose a lot of risk.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Making someone else's problem.
Scott: The league ends up getting way more money than the TV broadcaster gets.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you add up all the money, they make selling ads and doing and subscription fees and all the other money that the TV networks get from the customers and advertisers and subtract the cost of broadcasting.
Scott: They the NFL is getting more money than they're actually making.
Rym: And there is a broader problem where when cable TV and advertising start to collapse for real, like when people actually don't pay for cable, but there's deals locked in for a long time.
Scott: So the NFL, the sports league is insulated completely from that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's basically at the TV broadcasters, the Fox's, the CBS's, the NBC's, the direct TV's, the YouTube's.
Scott: They're taking the hit.
Scott: They're basically just spending their money to keep the sport going.
Scott: Now, why?
Rym: Why would they keep spending completely subsidizing?
Rym: You're probably all thinking, why are they spending that money?
Rym: And really, the answer is partly that it feels like you should be able to make money off of sports.
Rym: Like it seems like it'd be a really easy thing to do.
Rym: But historically, that's actually not super true.
Rym: And I think a lot of cultural traditions and expectations drive it more than the reality of how the money comes in, coupled with various bubbles and things like advertising.
Rym: It is possible that American sports as we know it could not exist once this subsidy disappears.
Scott: Or at least could not exist at the budgets that they have now.
Rym: Like budgets are going to contract and play might get worse.
Scott: I mean, like you look at European hockey.
Scott: Look how many ads just all over the ice.
Scott: You know, European soccer.
Scott: Look at the ads are all over the NHL.
Rym: They got fucking ads on the jerseys now.
Scott: Only one, though.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's not like it's only some team.
Rym: Once you let one in.
Scott: It's well, you know, it's anyway.
Scott: So YouTube has purchased the Sunday ticket and that which means now from starting, I guess, next season, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you want to watch the Sunday ticket deal, you're going to have to buy it from YouTube.
Scott: And they haven't given out details of what it's going to cost or anything.
Rym: But it's not just free with YouTube.
Scott: No, presumably what it's going to be is that you can either a just buy it outright, which is probably going to cost hundreds of dollars and then watch it on YouTube or B, you'll get YouTube TV.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which is an existing service they have.
Scott: And then you will pay an extra fee to add it on to YouTube TV.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So YouTube is definitely hoping that the fact this exists will bring in YouTube TV subscribers doesn't have, you know, and YouTube is spending more money on it than direct TV did.
Scott: So I don't know how they're going to make.
Scott: also direct TV didn't even drag TV was losing a third of the money they spent.
Scott: Is YouTube going to lose half the money they spent on this deal?
Rym: Direct TV did not even bid on a renewal at any price.
Scott: No.
Scott: Why would they?
Scott: They're like, we're going to get out.
Rym: There's other bidders like Apple.
Scott: Apple was going in on it and all the everyone was going in on it.
Scott: But then they all pulled out.
Scott: And I guess Google ended up being the winner winner.
Rym: We'll see how this goes, because I think there has been a decline in interest in NFL football.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But I think, you know, the point is a right.
Scott: that original red zone, you know, with the with the guy, I can't remember his name, the direct TV red zone that what it's gone now.
Scott: It's going to well, it's going to finish out the season.
Scott: But after this season, that's it.
Scott: It's over that, you know, the really revolutionary television innovation is just going to the end.
Scott: And the other one, the other red zone with the Scott guy, that one's going to be the only red zone.
Scott: And I guess you'll be able to see it if you get the YouTube deal.
Rym: No, you won't.
Rym: So NFL media is not included, quote, the deal with YouTube TV does not include a stake in NFL media, which includes the linear cable channels, NFL Network and Red Zone, as well as NFL dot com.
Rym: All the ancillary stuff is not part of this.
Rym: Like it is just the games, from what I can tell.
Scott: OK, well, I guess you're still.
Scott: the point is that other red zone, the Scott one is going to keep going and it'll exist for someone to see somewhere.
Rym: Apparently the NFL is still looking for a partner for NFL media and no one's taking him up on it.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But.
Scott: Yes, it's all fascinating because there's definitely there might be a fascinating because it's like, you know, some of it applies to, you know, all of you know, it's like there's lessons to see here for all these other people.
Scott: But it's also a unique situation because the NFL is different from all the other sports in the way it's broadcast.
Rym: It also shines a light on a long term conversation around.
Rym: should a platform like YouTube really embrace just being the technology platform for people who provide content but don't actually stream themselves?
Rym: Because we've seen most of the streaming services are not making money and they've all started to collapse like really rapidly.
Rym: And two, most of the other streaming services suck.
Rym: Like Apple TV, when we try to watch it on our TV, like on a Windows computer, every third time we start a video, it just doesn't load.
Rym: We have to keep refreshing like.
Scott: it only works nice if you have Apple device.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: And Paramount Plus, like if you skip the intro to a show, like you don't want to watch the opening, it also skips like the first 10 minutes of the show.
Rym: And the UX is just garbage.
Rym: And also sometimes the things don't load.
Rym: And if something's airing live, you can't watch like you can't rewind until after the live is complete.
Rym: There's all these just really bad UX and platform decisions.
Rym: Very few of the streaming platforms work that well.
Scott: But YouTube, the Google ones and the Amazons work well.
Scott: And then the Apple, the Apple one works well if you have Apple devices.
Rym: It's just amazing how poorly Apple TV works on a Windows PC and a browser.
Scott: I mean, all Apple things work poorly on Windows.
Rym: We only have Apple TV to watch Ted Lasso anyway.
Scott: The Windows iCloud stuff is so bad that Microsoft had to work with Apple and Microsoft made the best iCloud photo thing for Windows.
Scott: It's like because Apple just doesn't try and they don't care about it.
Scott: They just keep it like at the bare minimum investment and existence because it's intentional.
Scott: Right.
Scott: As they want you to be able to, you know, it's like, yes, you know, if you have iPhones, if you have iPads, you want and you don't have Macs, we still want you to be able to do that because and have the minimum functionality.
Scott: Otherwise, you'll switch to Android because it just doesn't work.
Scott: But B, we don't want to make it too good because you really want to encourage you to get a Mac.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So they just keep it at that bare minimum level.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And in general, I think we're going to see sports just try to milk as much money out of the previous system as they can, because over the next five to 10 years, that old ecosystem is going to collapse.
Rym: And they got to put feelers out for how to continue to do their sports in an era where like cable TV disappears.
Scott: I mean, the you know, the prevailing thing that I see is that people who want to watch sports, they want to pay and they want to pay for something high quality.
Rym: And I really pay a lot if it works.
Rym: But like NHL, you want to watch hockey?
Rym: There's really nothing you can pay for except cable TV.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the problem is, even if the leagues provided something that was good.
Scott: And they charged money for it.
Scott: It's like the price that they would have to charge right to meet the revenues that they have now.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, look, the direct that we're just talking about this friggin Sunday ticket to get it from DirecTV costs hundreds of dollars per month or whatever year.
Rym: Oh, damn.
Rym: YouTube doesn't even have the advertising rights.
Rym: YouTube won't make money.
Rym: I like that.
Rym: YouTube is not going to sell the ad inventory.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But the point is, it seems like a terrible deal for YouTube.
Scott: They're just trying to get by YouTube TV subscribers, I guess.
Rym: I think YouTube is trying to buy eyeballs and be one of the last players standing.
Rym: I think YouTube, Netflix, Amazon are trying to like be the last ones to survive.
Rym: Disney plus might go away.
Rym: Paramount's not doing well.
Rym: Nothing's doing well except those three.
Scott: But yeah, it's like the amount that you have to pay for the services as they exist, which are being subsidized by the broadcaster.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if you were to get a really good streaming service and that was the only way the broadcasting was gone, the price you would have to pay.
Scott: That one and a half to two billion dollars that Apple is that YouTube is paying divided amongst all.
Scott: take two billion and divide it amongst all the people who want to watch football.
Scott: It's like how much was that each person going to have to pay a year?
Scott: A thousand dollars?
Rym: Almost like most good, complex things only exist with heavy subsidy.
Rym: And that subsidy can either come from the capital markets or governments or individual wealthy people.
Scott: And also the causality goes in the reverse direction, which is like if something is subsidized, it has a high chance of success.
Rym: Speaking of things that are subsidized.
Rym: So this is actually a really good segue.
Rym: There is a project that is kicking off near New York on the New Jersey Turnpike, which we don't know if you drive anywhere near New York City.
Scott: Like if you're not going to New Jersey, Turnpike is I-95.
Scott: Right.
Scott: A major the major north south interstate that can take you from the top of the U.S.
Scott: to the bottom along the East Coast.
Scott: It is an enormous, important road.
Rym: It's a nightmare.
Scott: It's a gristmill of only officially 100 percent completed somewhat recently.
Rym: So, of course, it's completely clogged with cars and has been forever.
Scott: And it's mostly cars.
Scott: actually try to avoid 95 whenever possible because it's filled with trucks.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But there's no way even to get through.
Rym: because if you drive, if you've ever never driven near New York City, I didn't even know this was a thing until I moved out this way.
Rym: So like in most places, you'll have a highway that goes by a tap by a city.
Rym: And there's probably like another highway that splits off and goes into the downtown.
Rym: Another city like loops around the city near New York City.
Rym: It's almost like a black hole.
Rym: Like it has so much gravity that every highway and freeway in the area kind of bends toward it.
Rym: And there's no way to just drive around New York City without going like 100 miles out of your way.
Rym: Like you're going to be stuck in New York City traffic even if you're not going to touch New York City.
Rym: So the New Jersey Turnpike, they are planning to widen it and extend it significantly.
Scott: Which, as we know, because of induced demand, will not improve the situation.
Rym: It will literally make traffic worse and not make drive times better.
Rym: Like it will not cause any positive outcome at all.
Rym: And even if it could, it doesn't matter because a big part of that traffic is people don't get into like the tunnels.
Rym: They can't wind the tunnels.
Rym: So what are you going to do?
Rym: But this project is now officially going to cost $1.1 billion per mile.
Scott: So they could take two miles of this.
Scott: Instead, it could decrease this project by two miles.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Just take two miles that you were going to add a lane to.
Scott: Just don't.
Scott: Take that money and give everyone in the whole country free NFL football.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: If you did that, you would never lose an election.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: People are so stupid.
Rym: The Romans do this.
Rym: Bread circuses.
Rym: That's the circus right there.
Scott: Instead of increasing the width of this one highway by two miles of the highway, you could give free NFL football to the entire country with no ads.
Scott: That's the amount of money that they're spending.
Rym: So again, we are subsidizing expanding this road to solve no problems.
Scott: Well, they believe they're solving a problem, but I don't know.
Scott: Is there something we don't know?
Scott: Because we're just.
Scott: we're not civil engineers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like everything I see online from other people who are civil engineers and experts and books and YouTube videos all about roads and engineering and city design and urbanism, they all talk about induced demand and how.
Scott: it's a fact and his studies that prove it.
Scott: And it's like, did no Department of Transportation in the world get the message?
Scott: Like, what is up with that?
Scott: Aren't those people also experts?
Rym: If you don't create induced demand as population grows, people cannot travel and things start to break down in other ways because our country will never have the conversation of instead of building X road, build Y literally fucking anything.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: A train, a train that carries cars like I don't even care that literally build anything.
Rym: But that's that this project's probably going to happen.
Rym: It's going to solve almost no problems.
Rym: It's going to cost a ton of money.
Rym: And if the cable companies subsidize football for no good reason, because apparently they don't make any money, taxpayers are going to subsidize this stupid road to no end.
Scott: At least it's New Jersey taxpayers.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Actually, I don't know.
Scott: Is it New Jersey taxes or federal taxes?
Scott: Pretty sure.
Scott: a lot of I-95 is an interstate.
Rym: Well, interstates get funded by the states by and large.
Rym: That's a gross.
Scott: The states also get money from the Federal Highway, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, but they get that money based on whether or not they follow certain rules because the Supreme Court is stupid.
Rym: So as a result, there are some rules that the feds have stated, but they can't actually enforce.
Rym: so they can enforce them indirectly by withholding funding.
Rym: It's all stupid.
Rym: It's like.
Rym: anyway, the more you read about it, the stupider it is.
Scott: Well, nothing I could do about it, but sigh.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And complain and demand trains.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So I think this is cool.
Rym: And it's sad that so many people are terrified of this.
Rym: A dude in Australia, a Huntsman spider got into his house and he just kept it like a pet.
Rym: He just let it live in his house.
Rym: This giant foot like foot wide spider.
Scott: Well, it's not a dangerous one.
Rym: No, they're not dangerous.
Rym: And people are like, why did you do this?
Rym: It's crazy.
Rym: He's like, look, I named it Charlotte's.
Rym: My kid's not afraid of it anymore.
Rym: And it eats the cockroaches.
Rym: It's actually saving me a ton of money.
Rym: This spider is great.
Rym: I hope this spider stays in my house for the rest of its life.
Scott: And when it dies, an Australian person, of course, they have this attitude.
Rym: I mean, that's a good attitude to have, though.
Rym: Kind of like if you don't like, I still wouldn't.
Scott: The thing is, even if you know, I know it's not a dangerous spider, but it's real big.
Scott: It's like crab.
Scott: It's a crab big.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like a crab isn't really going to hurt me.
Scott: What can they do?
Scott: Pinch me.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, but I'm still not going to let it.
Rym: You know, you might be pooping and he's just like up on the ceiling, just looking at you, just hanging out.
Scott: I'm not going to have a crab in my house.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Even if it even if it eats cockroaches or whatever, because here's another question.
Rym: What if you had cockroaches like lots of them move, move, move?
Scott: That's another.
Rym: Where's that Jon Stewart thing?
Rym: If you live in New York City at some point, you'll have cockroaches.
Rym: I'm rich and I have cockroaches.
Rym: There's no amount of money that will avoid cockroaches in the places that I have lived.
Rym: I've never had a cockroach, though.
Scott: So I have only ever encountered already dead cockroaches.
Scott: We've there when we first like in the toilet, like, you know, they go to the water.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then they die when our buildings.
Scott: I've never seen a live one skittering.
Rym: I saw a dead one in the building once and that was the only one I've ever seen.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: Oh, so what do I got?
Scott: All right.
Scott: So there's this, you know, different CPUs out in the world.
Scott: Go back to Monday here.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Have different assembly languages, different instruction set architectures.
Scott: And there's a recent ish one.
Scott: You know, I mean, recent, at least as far as CPU instructions that architectures go.
Scott: 2010, I think, is when they first revealed it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it was designed by professors at Berkeley.
Scott: It's called RISC-V.
Scott: Right.
Scott: A RISC-V.
Scott: And so what happened?
Scott: over time, over the past decade, decade plus, RISC-V actually became kind of the hotness.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, in terms of the commercial world, x86 and ARM are the hotness.
Scott: ARM even more so.
Scott: But basically, RISC-V is like really coming up and making waves.
Scott: Like, and it seems like every other day I'm seeing more and more RISC-V hotness.
Scott: We got RISC-V laptops coming out.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And we got all kinds.
Scott: So it's like and it's an open, you know, it's an open architecture, like, you know, licensing wise.
Scott: So this I think if there's anything that has a chance of like challenging ARM, it's RISC-V.
Scott: And so I discovered this thing of the day, just project on GitHub called Ripes, which is basically this amazing like RISC simulator sort of thing.
Scott: And like, like I've never I've seen simulators before, but like this one is like showing you like what's like literally the the the schematic of the CPU, like lighting up in real time while your instructions run.
Rym: This is nuts.
Rym: There was software I used when I went to community college in like early high school.
Rym: I took a class on systems architecture just for funsies and they made us use a simulator of like a really simple microcontroller.
Rym: We could write instructions and it would do this kind of animation.
Rym: But this was a microcontroller that had like eight registers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And this is showing you all like, you know, the stuff that, you know, would be the stuff that's usually invisible to a programmer.
Scott: Things like, you know, the cache lookups and the instructions being executed ahead of time.
Scott: And, you know, all the optimist compiler optimizations, you can put in some C code and it shows you the assembly code it goes with.
Scott: And it's like, you know, this is really.
Scott: this is really something.
Scott: And this is the kind of thing that you can get when you have an open source instruction set architecture.
Scott: It's cool stuff.
Scott: So, yeah, if you are looking to get into systems programming, either you're still young and you want it to be a career or you're just a nerd, you must be right.
Scott: RISC-V is definitely what I would recommend getting into.
Rym: In the meantime, the GeekNights Book Club book, Alif the Unseen, probably right after.
Rym: I have not finished it, but I will shortly.
Rym: As soon as I get back from that Colorado ski trip to Vail, so probably the last week of January, we'll do the show.
Rym: Because next week I'm going to be in Frankfurt for work and then we'll do another week of shows.
Rym: And then I'm going to disappear again to go skiing at Vail for a week and then we'll be back.
Rym: And then I don't know what else we got going on.
Scott: I think I've seen all there is to see in Alif the Unseen.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So you're going to read the other book by this author?
Scott: Probably.
Rym: I got to make time to read The World We Make.
Scott: I'm reading The World We Make and it's going along much quicker than I think it's.
Scott: Since I have the e-book, I don't actually know how thick the real book is, but I feel like it's not a thick book because I'm moving right along percentage wise, according to the Kindel.
Rym: I'm pretty sure I'm going to finish Alif the Unseen on my flight home from Frankfurt.
Rym: So maybe we'll even do the show that week.
Rym: Unless something really gets in my way.
Scott: Is there a Thursday episode that week?
Rym: No, I think that's another Monday, Wednesday.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Otherwise, we'll likely be at PAX East doing like a panel or two, but don't expect us to be like hanging out at the con.
Rym: Still a little early for that.
Rym: And otherwise, all our plans are up in the air and we don't know what conventions will look like.
Rym: It's very early in twenty twenty three and we just got to play this all by ear for the time being.
Rym: Websites coming along.
Rym: You might have noticed I finally updated our streaming template to remove Twitter IDs and make them just our names and sort of simplify it.
Rym: I am working on a better streaming pipeline and it's kind of an aside, but I'll mention it to all of you now.
Rym: If you make podcasts and you use Adobe like we do, you know, our whole pipeline is an audition and OBS.
Rym: You should check out the Adobe podcast.
Rym: It's not in production yet, like it's not live, but I've poked at some of the beta features.
Rym: Holy shit, is it good?
Rym: Like it solves the few problems we have with GeekNights, like the annoyance of recording over discord and synchronizing audio or having like guests call into the show.
Rym: And it does something that I'm going to review in a future Monday episode.
Rym: It has a an AI driven, make your podcast sound better filter.
Rym: And I tried it.
Rym: I tried testing it with a bunch of old GeekNights episodes.
Rym: And for someone who does good recording, like if you have real professional equipment, it doesn't really do anything for you.
Rym: Like GeekNights won't sound different if we use it because we have really expensive, nice equipment and I have a really good pipeline.
Rym: But if you say don't have three hundred dollar microphones, it'll make you sound like a pro on the radio.
Rym: It is it is nuts.
Scott: And it's literally just like upload your MP3 and push, maybe push one button and then push you back.
Scott: I made a podcast.
Rym: It makes a transcript of all the people on the podcast, all the words they said.
Rym: you can edit it like by changing text and it'll like try to fill in up to a point.
Rym: It is really not.
Rym: So GeekNights, once this goes live, will probably start publishing like full transcripts and text of the show, which is something I always wanted to do.
Rym: But the not so test is I took an extremely fucked up audio sample, like something that would take me a whole day to like make sound really good.
Rym: And I spent.
Scott: I let it.
Rym: I let it do the process.
Rym: It took it 11 minutes to do it.
Rym: And then I spent 11 minutes trying to clean it up using my professional audio engineering knowledge.
Rym: It did better than me in those 11 minutes by a wide margin.
Scott: 11 minutes isn't that long, right?
Rym: Yeah, but 11 minutes is like.
Rym: it doesn't take me that long to do this.
Rym: It would have to make to do it as well as the A.I.
Rym: did.
Rym: It would have taken me I would estimate eight to 10 hours on that on that file to do what the A.I.
Scott: I wonder how long it would have taken like a professional audio engineer, like the music studio.
Rym: My gut feeling is four ish hours because you would had to do the equivalent of some audio rotoscoping.
Rym: You would have had to like applied filters to different parts of the audio at different times.
Rym: What the A.I.
Rym: is good at is handling like transient, weird effects that you don't.
Rym: Anyway, I don't want to derail the whole show with that.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So Microsoft Windows, the world's number one desktop operating system isn't the world's number one computer operating system.
Scott: It's just the one that people use mostly for desktop computers, something like 70 percent of desktop computers in the world still use Windows.
Scott: And although the the so the slice of the pie that Microsoft has has always been enormous, but the pie is shrinking.
Scott: That's a topic for another day.
Scott: And also we've talked about that in the past.
Scott: Regardless, we've never done a show on Windows itself.
Scott: So let's begin.
Scott: Let's go through the history of Windows briefly.
Rym: I never encountered or touched Windows until Windows three point one.
Scott: Me, I encountered Windows three point.
Rym: Oh, I didn't.
Scott: Oh, not three point one.
Rym: We had three point one and then we bought.
Scott: I didn't have three point.
Scott: oh at home, but I did use computers that had three point.
Scott: oh at school and other people's houses.
Scott: I never.
Scott: Oh, one and two.
Scott: I only saw because I intentionally went out to see them.
Rym: We did buy the upgrade of Windows three one one for work groups because we needed some of the network features that had.
Scott: So what Windows originally was, was just not even an operating system.
Scott: DOS was the operating system.
Scott: And Windows was a shell, right?
Scott: Because DOS was not a graphical operating system.
Scott: It was just a command line.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So the original versions of Windows, what they would do is you would turn on your computer and you would see the DOS command prompt and you would run.
Scott: You type win and press enter and it would run windows that exe a program and it would open up right windows.
Scott: But DOS was still the operating system, right?
Scott: All the drivers were.
Scott: your mouse driver was still the DOS driver.
Scott: Your sound blaster was still the DOS driver.
Scott: All these every all the interfacing with the hardware, the reading and writing files to the file system.
Scott: DOS was taking care of all that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Windows was just making a GUI and it was providing an interface for some other programs to run on Windows, like within the shell.
Scott: That had their own windows in windows.
Scott: But it was anything that those programs did.
Scott: was either going through like some Windows library, which was then going to DOS or was just going to DOS.
Rym: This is why, like even up through the Windows three one one era, if you were, say, playing a game, you never wanted to launch a game in Windows because Windows was using some of your extremely limited CPU cycles and memory.
Scott: So a lot of games you just couldn't.
Scott: You could only launch a Windows game in Windows.
Rym: So really, like you would start your computer and sometimes you type win because you wanted to use Windows and sometimes you just type the name of the VXE you wanted to run and it would just run.
Rym: Sometimes you'd even run a boot disk that just loaded the program you wanted to run directly.
Scott: So Windows didn't become an operating system until Windows NT.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And Windows NT came out and it wasn't something that any people bought at their homes.
Rym: I wanted to.
Rym: My uncle had it because he worked at IBM.
Scott: Well, it wasn't very useful for you at home because it's not like your favorite games would run on it yet.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was, you know, the earliest Windows NTs only ran like these business applications that were made for Windows NT.
Rym: Right.
Rym: As a kid, I was obsessed with Windows NT partly because it supported Alpha chips.
Rym: And I remember reading that an Alpha chip could run at 500 megahertz.
Rym: And that was a ludicrous fucking number back then.
Rym: And as a nerd kid, I was like, I want the fast computer.
Rym: And I went to a computer store with my parents and my parents were like, tell the person what you want.
Rym: And I was like, I want a computer with two Alpha processors so I can have multi processor support of Windows NT.
Rym: I think I was like, nobody sells that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's you saw that in a computer magazine.
Scott: No, we don't sell that at CompUSA.
Rym: It's like, yeah, if you have ten thousand dollars, go talk to this distributor.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But yeah, Windows NT was the first Windows that was like its own kernel, its own everything.
Scott: There were some ways compatibility layers to run some apps from, you know, other windows, but not really.
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Rym: It was also it was.
Rym: it was the first time Windows was actually 32 bit like.
Rym: even Windows 95 was like a 16 bit, 32 bit hybrid.
Rym: I used to be a lot of nonsense.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Sorry.
Scott: So Windows NT started, but then Windows 95, what Windows 95 was was it was.
Scott: basically it's like, oh, you think DOS is still there.
Scott: People thought it was just a shell like Windows 3.1 was.
Scott: No, it wasn't.
Scott: With the way Windows 95 worked is very interesting and that your computer would turn on with DOS.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you wanted it to.
Scott: But as soon as you launch Windows 95, Windows 95 would sort of push DOS out of the way and sort of take over its own deal.
Scott: And but DOS was still there, kind of as like this 16 bit sort of layer.
Scott: It's like if you were so like.
Scott: if you wanted to run a Windows 3.1 app on Windows 95, well, it's going to be expecting to talk, you know, to use some DOS APIs to, you know, and it's going to be able to.
Scott: DOS is still there right in the corner.
Scott: So apps that what needs a DOS can still DOS, but the actual operating system is Windows 95.
Scott: If you open the Explorer in Windows 95 and make a file, Windows 95 is making the file.
Scott: It's not like telling DOS to make a file the way Windows 3.1 did.
Rym: And I think it's worth stepping back a little bit about Windows 95, because that was one of the most important changes in consumer computing technology up to that point.
Rym: Like Windows 95 introduced so many things that you take for granted today that did not exist before.
Rym: Things like plug and play.
Rym: You don't think about that.
Rym: You plug in hardware to your computer.
Rym: It just works.
Rym: That was not how hardware worked for all of computing.
Scott: Not having to do IRQs for your sound card.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: File names like having file names longer than eight characters plus an extension.
Rym: Not a thing in the Windows and DOS world until Windows 95.
Scott: Spaces in the file names.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Real multitasking.
Rym: Mostly like.
Rym: there's a big asterisk there.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Windows 3.1.1 had like you could call what it did multitasking.
Rym: Windows 95 had something that was effectively multitasking, but we're still not there yet.
Rym: But you can have multiple applications running at the same time.
Rym: And for a normal person, that was fine.
Rym: That was not necessarily the case on Windows 3.1.1.
Scott: When Windows 95 came out, it was like a hysteria.
Scott: Like, you know, people there were ads.
Rym: I waited in line to buy Windows fucking 95 A and install it on a computer because it was up like there was a paradigm shift.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So Windows 95 spawned this sort of heritage that went to 98, which is just really much better.
Scott: Windows 95.
Scott: Then there was 98 like B. That was like there was 95 B also.
Scott: But there was like a 98 SE or whatever.
Scott: I think that was even better.
Scott: Windows 98.
Rym: I had A and we never upgraded.
Scott: I think I only had Windows 95 B and I only had Windows 98 SE like the better.
Scott: Would you believe we had the better one?
Rym: Would you believe I never, ever in my life owned a computer running any version of Windows 98?
Scott: Well, I think the Windows 95, the original one didn't have support for USB.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: You had to install this like extension pack.
Scott: The better one, Windows 95 B like had the USB support and that's the one I have.
Scott: And then 98, I forget what the the better edition had, but whatever.
Scott: And then that chain of history went down to Windows ME, which is a complete disaster.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It completely failed.
Scott: I never had a computer that ran Windows ME either because in the freshman year of RIT, there were people who had Windows ME because that's when it came out.
Scott: And I saw it on other people's computers very rarely, but I did see it.
Rym: But it was not popular because there was sort of a split.
Rym: There was an interesting split.
Rym: Like it was actually kind of complicated back then because the what was Windows 95, that lineage moving into Windows, Windows ME ended up.
Rym: Microsoft's almost tried to position it as that's the windows for regular people.
Rym: And what was NT?
Rym: basically became Windows 2000.
Scott: And they marketed that as Windows 2000 is basically Windows NT five, right?
Scott: They just renamed it instead of calling it Windows NT five.
Scott: They called it Windows 2000.
Scott: And because of that marketing, not calling it NT anymore because NT was brand new technology.
Rym: I forget what it stood for.
Scott: I forget what NT actually stands for, but brand wise, NT was viewed as only for businesses.
Scott: You couldn't really use that for your home computer.
Rym: Good luck playing games with that was backronymed formally to new technology later.
Scott: OK, but yes, but when they went to Windows 2000, the fact that it was called 2000 sort of suggested to people like, hey, you could actually run that yourself.
Scott: It's not a business only, even though it was just Windows NT five and they had business users.
Rym: But what happened was if you were a nerd and you had a computer, Windows NT had a lot of powerful capabilities that the windows did not by the time they got.
Scott: because remember, the first Windows NT was three.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So this is like, you know, two or three versions of Windows NT.
Scott: later, it was called Windows 2000.
Scott: And by that time it had the capabilities to run your software's your games.
Scott: You could play Counter Strike on that shit.
Scott: No problem.
Rym: Windows NT had effectively real multitasking.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And it was basically just vastly superior and vastly more stable and better than Windows 98 or ME.
Scott: And so anyone who knew anything about computers and was running Windows was using Windows 2000.
Rym: And I remember this fascinating divide.
Rym: Everyone I knew who knew anything about computers at Windows 2000 and everyone else had Windows ME and had constant problems that weren't even their fault.
Scott: Yeah, I don't remember that.
Scott: I'm telling you not.
Scott: I don't know that many people at ME.
Scott: It was people still stuck on 98 and people in 2000.
Scott: But anyway, when that happened, ME and 2000 are sort of out at the same time.
Scott: Well, 2000 came first, actually, and then ME came out after and flopped.
Scott: And I guess they saw that.
Scott: so enough consumers and not just businesses were using 2000 and they made the wise decision to just fucking go with it.
Scott: And then they went to Windows XP and Windows XP was like, OK, it's it's literally Windows NT six.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But we're going to make it like this is the only Windows.
Scott: Everyone use this Windows.
Scott: They intentionally marketed it to everybody, whether you're a business or not.
Scott: And that was the new better.
Rym: As it turns out, having a just a shittier operating system for the masses is not actually a good idea.
Scott: You don't say.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So Windows XP, even though, you know, the look of it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: People always think of like the way it looks and judge the whole thing by that.
Scott: But it's like, yeah, it looked a little bit Fisher pricey.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The way they the default looks.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: Who cares?
Rym: It worked.
Rym: Windows XP was rock solid.
Scott: Windows XP was just great.
Scott: There was nothing.
Scott: It was just better.
Scott: Windows 2000 updated, you know, everyone.
Scott: When Windows XP came out, everyone eventually got on board the Windows XP train.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that was good to go.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: One last weird sort of aside that happened was after that, we had the infamous Windows Vista, which I had a weird moment and work a while ago and some training.
Rym: And there's this instructor teaching us about some data science stuff.
Rym: And he just they asked the class on the Zoom call kind of as part of the lesson.
Rym: So I don't know how many of you are old enough to have ever heard of an operating system called Windows Vista.
Scott: It's from 2006.
Scott: It's not that.
Rym: 2006 was a long time ago, 17 years ago.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So the deal with Windows Vista is that they had Windows XP.
Scott: It was successful.
Scott: It took over the world.
Scott: And like, what do we do next?
Rym: Yeah, because the problem was Windows XP was fine.
Rym: It did everything anyone needed, like not counting bit like super professionals doing like complex networking and enterprise environment.
Rym: Windows XP was fine.
Rym: Like as long as they kept getting security updates and people kept making drivers, your software just worked.
Rym: And people's focus was really on the software, not the operating system.
Rym: Operating systems still were just the thing that ran your stuff.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So Windows Vista, Microsoft had all these grandiose plans and they tried to do too much with it.
Scott: The big plan for Windows Vista was like this new like database based file system and all that really file system stuff was a big one.
Scott: And they sort of failed to pull that off.
Scott: They didn't succeed in the thing they were trying to do too much with.
Scott: But because capitalism, they had to still release an update and get people to buy something.
Rym: Remember this whole time, even leading into the modern era, you buy an operating system for a couple of hundred bucks and Microsoft never gets money from you again.
Rym: So who pays for security updates?
Scott: Yeah, so but yeah, so people, you know, were just sticking with XP.
Scott: They were happy with it.
Scott: And Microsoft is like, shit, how do we make more money?
Scott: So they ended up putting together Windows Vista and this is they.
Scott: they started making a big mess.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The UI got like janky.
Rym: It was kind of unstable.
Rym: I had a laptop that came with Vista and I I actually installed Windows 7 over it as soon as Windows 7 came out.
Scott: Yeah, they had all sorts of different versions of Vista.
Scott: Like it was an ultimate one that included everything in a home.
Scott: It was confusing to people which version they had to get different RAM limits for different versions.
Rym: Now, there's another weird thing that happened.
Rym: The Windows Vista era was right around like the nadir of PC gaming, like PC gaming, Windows gaming, like people playing games on PCs had been just continuously a huge market.
Scott: Well, this Windows Vista came out like basically when GeekNights started.
Scott: So like when PC gaming is also when iPhones were about like a year before iPhones appeared.
Rym: So right around then was when a lot of nerds like us, like when Vista came out was when I said, you know what, fuck it.
Rym: I'm not playing games.
Rym: Windows sucks now.
Rym: And that's when I ran Linux on the desktop.
Rym: Like I skipped that generation for the most part.
Scott: So, yeah, Windows Vista and it's like the thing is your apps, you know, people recognized in the software companies, recognize that not everyone was going to get Windows Vista.
Scott: So they in that era, people kept making things and making sure they would work on Windows XP because that was still most of the user base.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So there was no really pressure to go to Vista and it got a bad reputation deserved entirely or not.
Scott: It was really mostly bad business problems by Microsoft and also failure to deliver on these their their plans that they had for it.
Scott: If they had been able to deliver on those plans, Vista would have been some sort of revolutionary deal.
Scott: They just weren't able to pull that off.
Scott: And it was just sort of some incremental mess that didn't know what it wanted to be.
Scott: So anyway, then they're like, well, Vista was a debacle.
Scott: We're going to have to clean this up.
Scott: So they put out Windows seven and clean that up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The same kind of deal that happened when they had a mess with Windows ME and they saw that 2000 was the way to go and they cleaned it up with Windows XP.
Scott: They're like, well, let's do what we did in the past.
Scott: Windows seven, we cleaned everything up.
Scott: Everybody, here you go.
Rym: Windows seven, though, also they kind of backed away that there had been some UX trends around like how start menus worked and how you launch stuff and how you interacted with the operating system.
Rym: But I'm not trying.
Rym: a lot of people complain too much about the UIs and UXs of operating systems.
Scott: But I think that's the thing is for most people, that's the only like when they think about upgrading Windows, they don't understand.
Scott: They're not thinking about like the ninety nine percent of what's going on.
Rym: They're thinking like, wait, what's this file system?
Rym: Like, what's the test scheduler?
Rym: Like, how's how's this thing working?
Scott: The one percent of things that they that are different are the things that they can see and they focus entirely on that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they're like, if there's like.
Scott: if they don't like to look at the icons, like this is garbage.
Scott: It's like you can make the best operating system with the most amazing kernel.
Scott: that's 20 percent faster and more reliable and more secure.
Scott: And if they don't if it's ugly, they'd be like, no, I'm staying with the old one.
Rym: But I will say Windows Vista, like elements and menus started to get big and a little weird and they were ugly like Windows Vista is pretty fugly in my opinion.
Rym: Windows seven like settled on this really clean aesthetic that I really like.
Scott: Well, you also have to consider, right, the time period in what became available in terms of GPU power monitors that the hardware technology that Microsoft had no control over.
Scott: They just had to play to write, whereas Apple controls the hardware and buy the windows.
Rym: I remember Windows seven had options to turn on or turn off the nice UX that they had, whether or not you had a video card, because, you know, not everyone had video cards.
Rym: Windows seven came out right as PC gaming was starting to come again.
Rym: Not that many people had dedicated GPUs on their Windows PCs up until Windows seven.
Scott: You know, just like Windows 10 and Windows 11.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They got all these options for HDR.
Scott: It's really the same kind of deal.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But so, yeah.
Rym: And since then, Windows, honestly, like the only changes that are happening are changes you don't notice in the back end on like how it works or honestly, more and more features that I don't think many people use now.
Scott: So I get Windows eight was sort of like.
Scott: why again, it was it wasn't nothing wrong with it, but it was like, why should I upgrade to Windows eight?
Scott: Windows seven works just fine.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's no reason for me to do so.
Scott: I never upgraded.
Scott: Windows 10 came out and it's like, well, you know, now at this point, right, there have been so many advancements in hardware, I kind of need to upgrade Windows 10.
Scott: Windows seven isn't supported really fully anymore.
Scott: And it's not all the hardware.
Scott: I see upgraded Windows 10 sort of add a necessity.
Rym: And then Windows 11 really is not, you know, I would say there is no material difference between 10 and 11.
Rym: You just upgrade when you upgrade.
Scott: Yeah, they're so.
Scott: Windows 10 and 11 are so similar, architecturally speaking, it's like there is not a significant difference.
Scott: Like anything that runs is going to run in either one of them just fine.
Scott: You know, it's like why would you know?
Rym: Well, you know why I'm not upgrading?
Rym: Because I'm still you know, I build my computers to fucking last.
Rym: So this workstation was a supercomputer when I built it now in the year twenty twenty three.
Rym: It's an.
Rym: it's a sixth generation for gigahertz.
Rym: I seven.
Rym: Windows 11 will not run on sixth generation Intel chips.
Scott: I see the CPU I have is like the oldest one that Windows 11 will run on.
Scott: So I have I do like you have like an eighth generation.
Scott: I want to say it's eighty seven hundred.
Rym: Yeah, I have a sixty seven hundred.
Rym: No, it's not like five grand on this computer.
Scott: What I think they're currently on like twelve, you know, the twelve.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: I think next year, twenty twenty four is the year it builds a new computer.
Scott: Yeah, that Windows 11 is just, you know, I were Windows 10, you know, people are, you know, again, people heavily focus on the UI, but it's like it's just the same freaking thing as Windows 10.
Rym: Now, there's also the.
Rym: there was the Windows Mobile, which, well, like that didn't go anywhere.
Scott: So well, there was Windows, there's Windows CE and Windows Phone.
Scott: They're two different things.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So Windows CE was actually started out as like a fork of Windows 95 to run on Palm Pilot like devices.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And they upgraded that for many, many years, I think all the way up to like twenty thirteen.
Scott: But that wasn't just running Palm Pilot devices at those times.
Scott: Windows CE was used for lots and lots of embedded like ATMs or the dream tasks.
Scott: Right.
Scott: All sorts of small devices where Windows was running and people who are going to make applications for those platforms were writing Windows applications.
Scott: But the users of those devices never saw Microsoft Windows.
Scott: Only the developers did.
Scott: And that was Windows CE.
Scott: It started out as a Palm Pilot thing.
Scott: It became an embedded thing.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Windows Phone was basically just and also ran like, you know, now we know how phones work.
Scott: But Windows Fan was like Windows Phone was like.
Scott: they made that almost like it's.
Scott: it's not like part of the other Windows architectures.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like it's its own platform they tried to make to compete with iOS and Android and they failed.
Rym: Well, iOS, Android, like WebOS, free the Palm Pre like that OS.
Rym: There was a bunch of OS's because the smartphone world was new and early and there's a big OS.
Scott: They were smart.
Scott: Microsoft knew they had to get in on that.
Scott: They just failed to get in on that.
Rym: Yeah, they all know.
Rym: So apparently they the last release was less long ago than I thought.
Rym: It was twenty twenty.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: God damn.
Scott: I'm sure someone out there has a Windows Phone.
Rym: I've got my Palm Pre laying around somewhere.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's also Windows Server.
Scott: But Windows Server is basically just regular Windows with some software that's like included.
Rym: You know, I've heavily used Windows software, Windows Server Active Directory and shit like that.
Rym: You know, well, the other thing which is not really true anymore in the old days, like when I worked at IBM, if you had a like workstation with a capital W, like the kind of thing where you're putting a weird raid in a server like this is already everything I'm describing does not exist anymore.
Rym: We do things very differently in server rooms today.
Rym: But like if you were putting eight CPUs in a weird workstation for a weird use case in the year 2005, Windows Server was necessary.
Rym: Like regular windows could not address that hardware.
Scott: There weren't.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Regular windows had, you know, limits both artificial and real in terms of how much hardware it could use.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like you could have a computer with like 32 gigs of RAM in it, you know, if you could afford one and get one.
Scott: And, you know, you would only be at, let's see, Windows XP RAM limit.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you had Windows XP and you had a x86 CPU, you could only use four gigs of RAM.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So meanwhile, Windows 2003 server, the one I use the most, I actually administered the DNS server for IBM's fab on a bunch of Windows servers that I built myself physically.
Rym: And that thing could have up to sixty four gigabytes of RAM by default.
Rym: But you could get it up to five hundred and twelve gigabytes if you did fancy stuff.
Scott: And some of this is because you had, you know, 32 bit operating systems and they weren't 64 bit yet.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But some of it was also because, you know, they baked in there like, hey, we're not going to.
Scott: we want you to buy the pro edition and then we'll let you use more RAM.
Scott: I actually had.
Scott: there have been I think Windows seven.
Scott: I had Windows seven home and I had to pay to upgrade to Windows seven pro because I didn't know about the RAM limit.
Scott: And I was like, I had thirty two gigs of RAM and I could.
Scott: I turned my computer and it's like you got 16 or something.
Scott: I'm like, what the fuck is this?
Scott: And I had to switch to Windows seven pro and then I could use all thirty two gigs of my RAM.
Scott: Right now, in terms of purely an artificial limit by Microsoft to make money.
Rym: So in terms of like the OS itself, like these days, really, there are two of you're a horrible person using a computer for almost anything.
Rym: There are.
Rym: you either run iOS or you're on Windows.
Rym: And honestly, you know what it comes down to?
Rym: Not even preference.
Rym: It comes down to are you a gamer?
Rym: You got to run Windows like that's it.
Rym: Full stop for now.
Scott: Well, you can also you know, I think that's that's what games you're playing, right?
Scott: It's only.
Scott: you only really need Windows if you want to play the games that run on Windows, which, you know, which is a lot a lot of small indie games only run on Windows.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Well, I'm saying is like the thing about Windows is that it you could.
Scott: with a Windows computer, you can run basically everything ever, either by emulation or for real.
Scott: It's like whereas if you get some other devices, right, you're going to have to either hope there's a port or you can use some cloud streaming or you could use maybe emulating.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like your library of game.
Scott: choices, though, will still be enormous.
Scott: Like you could be a gamer that only plays iOS games.
Scott: And it's like that's still an enormous shit ton of games.
Rym: What you'll find?
Rym: because you're taught that enormous library spans decades in terms of like.
Rym: go look at Steam and look at a game someone wants to play today that your friends are playing.
Rym: Odds are it doesn't run on a Mac.
Scott: Oh, you go on.
Scott: There's a lot.
Scott: But yeah, it's.
Scott: it's not.
Scott: there's enough.
Rym: Partly because in our Discord, one of our friends is on iOS and doesn't have any Windows PCs.
Rym: And a bunch of times this year has said, hey, I want to play X game.
Rym: And it turns out it doesn't run on their Mac.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, that's the thing.
Scott: It's like, number one, if you look at a Mac or Linux and you look at the list of games that can run on there, it's like it's surprisingly larger than you think, especially with some of the emulation layers.
Scott: It's like, oh, you can play all those games on there.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: I had no idea.
Scott: But if you take your Steam library and you have a large one like I do and you and you filter it and you say, all right, Mac only, it'll still get cut in half.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, so it's like, oh, you know.
Scott: All these games still are on the list.
Scott: But oh, there's the half that aren't.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You know, but Windows just works.
Rym: It's easy.
Rym: Like there's a reason why it's the most like it's the OS people use on computers.
Rym: I think the only reason that might change is over time.
Rym: I think people just don't have computers.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I think that it's really the only reason Windows has been so successful, right, is that, you know, it was that first GUI in there and it was up.
Scott: the only other GUI it was really up against.
Scott: There were some other ones, but they didn't have a chance.
Scott: business wise was the Mac.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And so people, you know, business wise, we're already using, you know, Windows and the software was coming out for DOS.
Scott: And, you know, the games are coming out for DOS and, you know, that beat the Mac, at least until, you know, the return of jobs in the G3, G4 days later.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So and then people made software for Windows.
Scott: And it's like this.
Scott: People weren't coming for Windows.
Scott: People came for the software.
Rym: And pretty much the reason all OS's ever rose and fell was people went to them for the software.
Rym: they ran.
Scott: And nowadays, not only did the phone, you know, provide a new platform to where there could be a new war over what people, but nowadays people come for just the web.
Scott: So it's like it doesn't even matter that much.
Scott: It's like, you know, we joked about Windows phone, like, haha, who's using Windows phone?
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, you know, honestly, if you got a Windows phone, it definitely has probably some Microsoft Edge web browser on it.
Scott: Like you could probably just use a Windows phone and be mostly just fine.
Scott: if you're not expecting to get like, you know, a native like app for TikTok or something.
Scott: But you can go to TikTok.com on it.
Scott: Probably just just fine.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that's what's, you know, taken away from Windows's power is that the web is the platform now, but there is so much Windows software that already exists and games and some business apps continue to be these sort of.
Scott: you need Windows to run these things that you actually care about.
Scott: Therefore, Windows can still get a stranglehold on the world.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I did Linux on the desktop for a while, but as soon as I wanted to do any PC gaming, I started dual booting Windows again.
Rym: And now I'm back on Windows, probably effectively permanently.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I guess there's also the one other thing being that, you know, there's certain hardware you might want to use for some reason and a lot of hardware, I guess, you know, USB-C is, you know, putting another nail in this to drive even more away from Windows, get, you know, controlling everything.
Scott: But there's plenty of hardware in the world that will only work with a Windows computer or maybe a Linux computer if someone wrote an open source driver and reverse engineered it or something.
Scott: So and even then, it won't work 100 percent perfectly.
Scott: Maybe, maybe it will.
Scott: Maybe it won't.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But if you got a Windows computer, it's going to work.
Scott: So if you are using any kind of hardware, right, that, you know, doesn't have like an official Mac support or something or official Linux support, it's going to have official Windows support 100 percent of the time.
Rym: What I find funny is when I think about how I've engaged with Windows pretty much from the Windows 7 era onward, I don't really use anything in the OS like my interactions with every Windows since 7 is always the same.
Rym: I hit the Windows key.
Rym: I took the name of the program I'm going to run.
Rym: And that's the extent of my interaction with Windows directly.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, I might have to use Windows Explorer to run some, you know, browse some files or something.
Rym: But even then, I hit the Windows key.
Rym: I took the name of the folder I'm looking for and then I navigate from there in the Windows Explorer.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like in the in the earlier Windows days from, you know, three point one through two thousand through even up to, you know, seven close to seven, you had to do.
Scott: you know, you had Windows and like you would do a lot of Windows kind of stuff, right?
Scott: You know, configuring settings, even it was just Microsoft Solitaire.
Rym: It's like running applications that came with the operating system and ran within the operating system.
Rym: It's nuts to think that as a kid, I would spend a lot of time sitting in front of a computer that was not networked to anything and I was amusing myself just fine.
Rym: Nowadays, the Internet goes down.
Rym: I don't really launch, like I don't go to my computer.
Scott: No, not really, yeah, but yeah, Windows, we'll see how long Windows, you know, because it's Windows isn't growing, right?
Scott: It's just going to remain dominant in the desktop space, which is a shrinking space.
Scott: But it's the king of that space, right?
Scott: That's the fish that takes up this whole pond.
Scott: The pond is drying up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: How long will Windows rule?
Scott: And if Windows doesn't rule, that's like that will be like a catastrophe because all this history of software that will only run on Windows, we will need some way to run that software.
Rym: So according to I tried to look up stats, they all are about the same, supposedly generalizing in terms of devices that have operating systems running on them that we could extrapolate or get data about like the websites or things.
Rym: The top operating system in the world is Android with 44 percent of the market Windows of all computing devices, including servers and it looks like consumer devices.
Rym: I'm going through a bunch of different stats sites and I'm not I haven't read all the caveats on this page, but 40 percent, 40 to 45 percent Android, 30 percent Windows, 17 percent iOS, five percent OS X, one percent unknown point, one percent Linux.
Scott: Yeah, Android is crushing it because they've got, you know, like a lot of the phones, obviously.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Especially, you know, Apple is like, you know, the the.
Scott: even in countries where iOS is the king, like the US, it's like Android still has a sizable chunk.
Scott: And in some places, Android is just the only game in town.
Scott: iOS hasn't really gotten in here.
Rym: I can pull it also.
Rym: I can pull it.
Rym: I can pull it to just does just desktops, windows, 75 percent, OS X, 15 percent.
Rym: Nothing else registers.
Rym: Linux, three percent.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But Android is so dominant because there are so many embedded devices.
Scott: The Windows CE category.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Where Android is things run Android that you don't realize.
Scott: It's like cars running Android, smart TVs running Android, refrigerator running Android.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In the year twenty twenty two, twenty three, if it's some kind of embedded device like Android is like you can't install iOS on it, they don't sell that.
Scott: What are you going to do?
Scott: Windows CE?
Scott: No.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Your choices are Linux and Android and Android is kind of Linux.
Scott: So and it's like you got Android developers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's more than you have Linux developers.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So an Android can run on a phone.
Scott: It can run on any other small things.
Scott: So Android is like the go to for any small device and it's running, you know, it's running.
Scott: That's what's running there.
Rym: You don't realize in terms of websites being hit where they can figure out the OS.
Rym: It's the same.
Rym: It's almost the same numbers.
Rym: It's the same ratios.
Rym: Androids far away.
Rym: The best Windows is right behind iOS is almost nothing and nothing else registers.
Scott: Yep, pretty much.
Rym: Yeah, because it doesn't matter that much.
Rym: In fact, the biggest danger to Windows, if they start trying to monetize it and move to an app ecosystem, the fact that Microsoft Windows just lets you fucking run any EXE you want is a big part of why it still exists today.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for the first episode of GeekNights of the Year 2023 are Alan Joyce, Likithi, Dreda, Lily, Tenderbride, Case, Care, Makes, Music, Chris, Dodd, Chris, Rymer, Clinton, Walton, Dex, Finn, Joel Hayes, Rebecca, Dunn, Sam, Erickson, Shervin, Von Harle.
Rym: Stop all the downloading and many, many people who have wisely moved their pledge to one dollar so they can subscribe.
Rym: But I just won't say their names.
Rym: So, yeah, we're back.
Rym: We're going to miss about half the episodes in January, but then things will calm down.
Rym: So, yeah, for now, I just leave you with.
Rym: Have you ever jacked in?
Rym: Have you ever wire tripped?
Rym: Ready?
Rym: This is not like TV only better.
Scott: This is life.
Rym: Piece of somebody's life.
Scott: It's about the stuff that you can't have, right?
Rym: The forbidden fruit straight from the cerebral cortex.
Scott: I mean, you're there.
Scott: You're doing it.
Scott: You're feeling it.
Scott: Are you beginning to see the possibilities here?
Scott: I am your main connection to the switchboard of souls.
Scott: I'm the magic man.
Scott: This has got something to do with water.
Rym: Sooner or later, it washes up on your beach.
Rym: Fan mail from some flounder.