Rym: It's Thursday, October 19th, 2023.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We've got the website up and then immediately couldn't do shows for like two weeks for literally No exaggeration unrelated reasons and now we're back.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So, uh, yeah, see if the.
Scott: we'll see.
Scott: we haven't uploaded an episode the news site yet.
Scott: Let's see if it even fucking works exactly.
Rym: I was actually about to open with so this episode might be up like way late because we can't get the website in order on YouTube because it's already on YouTube.
Rym: It'll appear on patreon Probably about 20 minutes after I eat dinner after the show and then it'll probably automate that eventually.
Rym: Yeah, we will but well, I want to wait cuz looks like patreon is making too much changes.
Rym: So I don't waste our time implementing against their existing kind of.
Scott: yeah Change the whole bunch of shit going on.
Rym: Yeah The main reason I'm sticking with patreon right now.
Rym: Is that I'm Unless they go away.
Rym: It is a free publicly available archive of GeekNights.
Rym: regardless of if anyone donates money And that's the main we could go to archive that org also probably well where we should go everywhere.
Rym: but yeah, so that aside I was a biking home from work today like you do and it was Really windy when I got to that bridge.
Rym: like I like to bike in extreme weather and I don't mind wind and like Scott kind of makes fun of me for that like I will Bike in weather where Scott would absolutely not bike under any circumstances.
Rym: But even I had to pause my biking on the Queensborough bridge for fear of the wind blowing me into the side.
Scott: I've definitely had to stop biking at times in my life because I thought the wind would blow me away.
Scott: Yeah, and knock knock me over in a dangerous fashion.
Rym: and I was thinking about the wind and the name of the wind and I remember the Patrick Rothfuss existed and I went to see if that if there was ever a third book to that series that we read two of above the Kingkiller Chronicle, you know the Captain.
Rym: one of them you read - I read - and the second one was Definitely.
Scott: You said there were sex ninjas.
Rym: Now there were not.
Rym: there were sex ninjas, okay I remembered that correctly that and he accidentally out sexes the goddess of sex and she falls in love with him and That happens.
Rym: That's an odd one plus of the sex ninjas.
Rym: Okay, and those are the least noteworthy things that happen in that book that are worth making fun of.
Rym: I But yeah, they're.
Rym: there still is no third book and there's no indication there ever will be a third book.
Rym: It seems like it's radio silence.
Rym: So it is a race between Patrick Rothfuss The Game of Thrones guy and our Scott backer to see whoever finishes what they started.
Scott: Does he have a D?
Scott: I mean, you know All right, I couldn't find like oh, I thought you're saying George RR Martin He also none of them are gonna finish these series.
Scott: a lot of our names in there.
Rym: Yeah I feel like you know, uh, jr Sold the mojo from all the other our people.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is I feel like you know, if our Martin actually finishes a book that'll get published no matter what.
Scott: Yeah But I don't there's no guarantee that like if backer or Rothfuss finish yet another book that some low backer is writing another book But it's not a prince of nothing book.
Scott: Okay, but I mean there's no guarantee that it'll be published.
Rym: I think it is.
Rym: I'm pretty based up from.
Rym: I'm pretty sure he is Under contract still for that third book.
Scott: Yeah What happens to authors when they sign like a five book deal and don't write?
Scott: they just stop and they don't make.
Scott: get the next Book, I don't know.
Rym: cuz the same thing happened.
Scott: I get back your advance or anything.
Scott: It's like you're the local.
Rym: every guy like signed up for what like six books and then that just went nowhere And he had a bunch of person.
Scott: I mean, I guess that the publisher has the option to stop early But it's like.
Scott: but if you if they want another one, they're like, hey We want another one and you don't cough up and you or you don't get it done What hat do you get in trouble?
Scott: Like I mean, I imagine anyone out there an expert on book deals I don't know.
Rym: I bet it depends a lot on the contract you signed and I bet But I'm saying it's like there's probably a standard.
Scott: the big publishers probably have a pretty standard set of terms.
Rym: Yeah Then I also I imagine those terms very primarily based on how wealthy successful and famous you already are as an author up to That point.
Scott: Yeah, I know that There's definitely a difference between Fantasy author who's writing a series deal and I'm a famous person writing a one-book thing.
Scott: you're gonna sell copies because I'm a separate famous person from Politics sports etc.
Scott: as showbiz.
Scott: Yeah, and I'm not even writing them most of the book.
Scott: Someone else is helping me, right?
Rym: I wonder if they get into publishers numbers get insurance Like I want insurance on this nerd who said he can write me 12 fantasy novels in case he doesn't make it past seven.
Rym: All right, so there's so much news that There's.
Rym: there's no way we can talk about all of it.
Scott: So much of it is gaming news tech news Political news.
Scott: like it's like there's like a hundred relevant nerd companies have laid people off Never mind.
Rym: There are like multiple earth-shattering breaking news's that happen between when we put up that website and stop doing GeekNights.
Rym: And now I'm not gonna talk about all of them But I think we're pointedly not going to address the ongoing Extremely rapidly escalating war in Israel partly because you should not be coming to a podcast by us To learn about that conflict.
Scott: No, I learned about it in school, which is you know where you should learn about it.
Scott: I will say this right.
Scott: Is that not about the war itself?
Scott: Yeah, right, but about the the worldwide discourse right relating to the you know, the Israeli-palestinian conflict.
Scott: whenever it comes up not a healthy bring it again.
Scott: No, is that basically the situation is that you know you have in the air in the geographic area?
Scott: Right, you got Israelis.
Scott: Yeah, Palestinian people, right.
Scott: and In those right in each of those two groups, right?
Scott: There are violent people who kill innocent people.
Scott: Yeah, and there are the majority of each of those two groups are Normal people who just don't want to die.
Scott: They want to live their life and not die.
Rym: You know what just like everyone else people in Russia people in Ukraine everywhere Everywhere, right?
Scott: And so what happens is you know, you end up with people Right who take sides in right.
Scott: it's like most.
Scott: a lot of wars, you know and a lot of our media We try to you know view everything is like try to identify good guys and bad guys right like with Russia.
Scott: It's like Ukraine Never attacked Russia, Russia.
Rym: Russia as a nation-state Clear aggressor clear bad guy.
Rym: Ukraine as a nation-states Clear defender clearly in the right in this conflict.
Rym: But a nation-state is not even necessarily the sum of its people like America is kind of a democracy But kinda there's a lot of discourse we could have there about how it's not a great one.
Rym: Germany is more of a democracy.
Rym: Russia is basically an entire nation-state at the behest of one angry guy full of grievances.
Rym: and the
Scott: point is Right, you have these two sides both of which are simultaneously, right and perhaps close to equally evil heinous evil and Good, right and you know, depending on how you slice it up, right and People and you know look and see one evil or the other and take a side right and end up You know going some people, you know people go too far into the realms of either, you know anti-semitism or Islamophobia right and everything all this stuff because nobody can think subtly or You know with any level of even worse complexity beyond just two sides.
Rym: I am not defending politicians like but it is in science to recognize that Politicians.
Rym: in many countries this conflict and democratic countries.
Rym: in democratic countries this conflict is not voting happens a geopolitical issue.
Rym: it also for really fucked up in bad reasons is a domestic issue and It is impossible to say anything even remotely nuanced and still get reelected in any context related to this.
Scott: Yeah, it's like even if you're a politician right who understands, you know the situation you've been briefed by experts And yeah, you know you you understand what's going on, right and have a complex nuanced opinion.
Scott: If you go out and and try to say right that like hey This is two evil people fighting each other and killing good people on the other sides Right, and it's not just you know Some black and white kind of deal.
Scott: then one of those two groups or both Will just hate you now because you're either on their side or they're not they right And then they won't vote for you and then you lose your elected position perhaps to a crazy person.
Scott: Yeah, so you feel like it's better up.
Scott: a lot of politicians will actually just straight-up lie pretend or whatever and Look at their constituents and say what they have to say on the issue to get reelected Regard and hide what they truly believe.
Rym: and that's not saying that's right You know, it's just take a line from that monkey video that I use Me.
Scott: I would say what I believed and that I would be unelected.
Scott: but also You know Why should something anyone who's in like?
Scott: if you're the president of the United States what you have to say on this matter probably matters Especially
Rym: because every word you say could Literally cause the conflict to get worse and more people to die, of
Scott: course, but if you're like the mayor of podunk Whatever city somewhere right not New York City That's like some whatever city and it's like your constituents are gonna vote on that issue when even though nothing you do in the position Has anything to do with it.
Rym: and it is very telling that in the United States the intent of Our two houses of our Congress not to get all into deep politics The intention was the house represents the people primarily on domestic issues and taxation.
Rym: the Senate represents the states and the Senate is what does treaties?
Rym: because the idea was experts in the Senate should be making geopolitical decisions and Domestic voters should not be directly interfering in foreign affairs.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: That was the.
Scott: that was the intent that we were taught in some studies class All of them.
Rym: all this political just we're not justifying.
Rym: but to use that line that I use a lot because it's a very useful Line from that monkey video.
Rym: I'm not saying this is good.
Rym: I'm simply saying this is what happened.
Scott: Yeah, I think if you want to you know All I would tell the listener right is that if you're gonna open your mouth on this issue, right?
Scott: I'm not imagining many of the listener because I wasn't.
Scott: We're alive as far back as the early 20th century nevermind 1947 when this core conflict began, right?
Scott: So you didn't see any of this happen, right?
Scott: So you should at least study read more than one book Perhaps even more than two books.
Rym: I'm gonna read I'm gonna link to because it's pretty well done and it's shorts Just in the news.
Rym: for any of you who?
Rym: Maybe think you want to say something about this out loud in public.
Rym: it is an old crash course video that is 12 minutes long that just explains the context of the region between 1947 and About eight years ago.
Scott: Yeah but regardless, you know if you You know can't tell the difference right between like the six-day war and the Yom Kippur War and which one happened first Between who yeah, right.
Scott: Then you should just not say anything about anything that's happening there because you don't know what the fuck you're talking about.
Scott: Alright, and if you do really want to say something so bad well go Learn what happened there first, right?
Scott: Because it's one of the rare cases actually where I mean obviously history is connected to everything that's happening today, right?
Scott: Yeah, but this is one of those ones where it's still like, you know It's not one of those cases where like people are saying and sort of like, you know drawing connections like oh This is still the same Like continuous conflict about the same fundamental issues since 1947. ish, right?
Rym: It's it's right.
Scott: So it's still.
Scott: it's actually 3.
Rym: I think would be a better year to say that this all properly began.
Scott: I mean, you know, you could say it goes back thousands of years if you could.
Scott: only you know correctly Any of those old.
Scott: so they actually happened.
Rym: the one that this SciShow video gets to this.
Rym: it makes a very strong point that this conflict is not fundamentally about religion, which is a Facile at all.
Rym: thing that a lot of people believe has not much to do with it at all.
Rym: And the conflict as we know it today did really begin as a result of what happened in World War two.
Rym: So and the thousands of years like in the region are not it's a lot of it's the UK's.
Rym: for The UK like directly.
Rym: like you there are names of individual people we can blame and yet They have no responsibility for it now whatsoever.
Rym: Yep, and most of them are dead of old age.
Rym: Anyway in news that we can at least make fun of a little bit though.
Rym: It is going to be a crisis soon.
Rym: so last we left.
Rym: the US House of Representatives had failed to elect a speaker in a historic ridiculous shit show and eventually elected a guy who sucked and That guy failed and one of the can.
Rym: one of the things he agreed to to even get the speakership in the first place.
Rym: Now bear in mind the speaker of the house.
Scott: It was that he could be kicked out easily.
Rym: He could be kicked out.
Rym: Basically it would one person He's like.
Scott: he's like vote for me and put me in the job And if I suck at it You can basically breathe on me and I'll leave.
Rym: any one person in the entire house Can immediately force a vote to kick him out and all they need is a majority.
Rym: That was the what he agreed to.
Scott: and guess what the Democrats went all that whole time without breathing.
Scott: They could have done it any one of them.
Scott: Yeah, none of them did.
Rym: the reason the Democrats didn't is that I mean politically tactically.
Rym: if The house is going to be broken It has to be the Republicans fault in a way that even a stupid person is not going to disagree with.
Rym: But to the Democrats couldn't elect a good speaker regardless.
Rym: They voted every time for Hakeem Jeffries.
Scott: They have not changed.
Rym: that which I like Would be a fantastic speaker of the house for everyone in America Republican and Democrat like.
Rym: he's just a good person.
Rym: best ever question Mark, uh, you know what?
Rym: I think he might be the best ever and a big personal best and best in my living memory.
Rym: You know what a big part of that is?
Rym: He's not white.
Rym: the ones that the ones that I can remember I will take a name and name a non-white speaker of the house in all of American history?
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: But so, of course the dipshit caucus did this because the Republicans basically have such a thin majority That they have to vote a hundred percent to elect a new speaker or they can't.
Rym: they either have to give up and let the Democrats have the speakership or they have to all agree.
Rym: and There's between six and twenty people who political people are kind of legit.
Rym: it like this is a phrase I am seeing in a lot of places.
Rym: They're calling them the dipshit caucus.
Rym: It's basically 20 or so dipshits who were elected from Extremely gerrymandered districts that go like 80% Republican So they are unaccountable to anyone like.
Rym: they will get reelected no matter what they do.
Rym: There can never be consequences for them unless they commit a crime and go to jail.
Rym: One of them might go to jail.
Rym: So stay tuned on that.
Rym: He's so bad.
Rym: Even the Republicans are talking about actually kicking him out.
Rym: They can't elect a speaker they like.
Rym: this is Literally never happened before.
Rym: this is the longest the house has ever been without a speaker.
Rym: they have been trying for two weeks to elect a speaker and it's just failing and failing and Failing.
Rym: and there are updates every day.
Rym: I can't even begin to summarize the ridiculous own goal.
Rym: shit show that is happening.
Rym: the American House right now.
Rym: the latest update Jim Jordan who by the way has one never passed a bill and two Directly, it's like it's like the worst person anytime you watch.
Scott: anytime you watch a congressional hearing And that guy's there.
Scott: It's like up mute button.
Scott: It's like it's like there are other Republicans not to say that they're good people, right?
Scott: But that you can listen to and they'll say something maybe possibly coherent.
Scott: Occasionally.
Rym: this would be like if one of the corrupt King this in the Lord of the Rings gave a speech and then God Oh this guy of a speed out.
Scott: Jim Jordan is like, you know the person you would ban from your forum after the first time.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it's like.
Scott: he's like the worst person Right, it's like, you know, just a terror like the internet troll Horrible conspiracy nut job awful human being.
Rym: he directly supported the January 6 coup attempt and he voted against Certifying the 2020 election.
Rym: So that tells you all you really need to know.
Rym: He's the only candidate they've got to be speaker right now.
Rym: and even he can't get the votes.
Scott: and like 20 Republicans They have like hundred something members.
Scott: They can't just pick on any any.
Scott: none of them want to try.
Rym: No one who wants to try can get 100% of the votes necessary.
Rym: You need a majority of the house.
Rym: They only have a margin of like four.
Rym: So the dipshit caucus the smallest most dipshitty core of the dipshit caucus is six people.
Rym: That is more people.
Rym: Then you can have a defection one and still select a speaker unless the Democrats let you select a speaker and the Democrats are Saying we will only accept Hakeem Jeffries.
Rym: So this is an Unprecedented and I mean that literally crisis in American politics and it is noteworthy that right now America can't even pass bills to send aid to Israel or Palestine or Ukraine or anything like.
Rym: Not only is this an unprecedented crisis that has literally paralyzed the American government.
Rym: it's gonna shut down again in a few weeks if they don't pick a speaker and We can't do anything during an unrelated unprecedented set of multiple major wars starting simultaneously, so fun times in DC and the world.
Scott: I Wonder if you know you want to talk about conspiracy theories.
Scott: Let me make up some.
Scott: obviously not true.
Scott: I don't want anyone spreading these.
Scott: I guess You know conspiracy theories that I just made up.
Scott: I literally just made up both of these ideas.
Scott: do not Pretend that I believe these or spread them as truth, right?
Scott: Conspiracy theory number one other countries do their bullshit with timing because they see this happening, right?
Scott: Even worse conspiracy theory to go even further.
Scott: Right that some people in the house are agents of the other countries making this happen on purpose to disable the US government And then the countries do those things.
Rym: what bothers me the most is that that's not a conspiracy.
Rym: some parts of that are Pretty well proven in that there are a number of members of the American House and Senate who are Republicans who?
Rym: Directly advocate for transforming American democracy into something more like Hungary or Russia and they say this out loud.
Scott: The point is if somebody is actually proven to be worked, you know That's I mean you're allowed to believe things like that, right?
Scott: That's not against the law, right?
Rym: But if anyone was shown You know A Democrat from New Jersey who if the Democrats are aggressively trying to force out of the Senate.
Rym: He's got about to be charged with being a foreign agent of Egypt like right now Right.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: Is that if you're if you're clearly a foreign agent of another country of that nature, right?
Scott: But you know, we're not like at war with Egypt.
Rym: Yeah, in fact, actually it has been as a nation in this entire conflict Pretty reasonable and pragmatic relative to the history of that country in regard to this conflict.
Scott: that was a very guarded statement for a reason but sure but if somebody was an Agent of an evil place.
Scott: All right, we'd have real treason.
Rym: Yep, but It's very hard to prosecute treason as we're seeing with the literal former president.
Scott: Well, that's you know, that's the the king's problem right?
Scott: is the stupid, you know the king who cried treason?
Scott: Yeah, I can 17 whatever.
Scott: it was just treasoning everybody in the UK.
Scott: It's like off with their head treason I don't you said but you don't like the color of my shoes.
Scott: treason head off.
Scott: So in 17, whatever right Ben Franklin was like, all right We can't let it be anyone be swinging around these treason so easily.
Scott: We got to make it real hard to do the treason because that fucking King over there He was just treasoning every fuck every to say I mean granted about half the states treason not too long later And we had the Civil War.
Rym: so I'm just saying okay All right, one last little news before we get into everything else.
Rym: So I have to institute a rule that we haven't had to use on gig nights in a long time.
Rym: The Jack Thompson rule is back Weird after this news.
Rym: We're no longer going to talk about Twitter in any context Unless the news about Twitter is somehow Bigger and crazier than any news that has ever happened up to this point about Twitter.
Rym: Because Twitter's dead like buried done nails so many nails in the coffin.
Rym: They can't even write.
Scott: It's like is Twitter literally out of business and closed and gone forever.
Scott: No, you can log in you can tweet.
Scott: Yeah, I can see tweets right?
Scott: It's it's still there.
Scott: It's actually you know, if you haven't been on it recently, which I hope you haven't it is more Like, you know.
Scott: together then you might realize yeah, like.
Scott: but you know, how many people are there that you follow?
Scott: your timeline might be a little ghost town II but It's still there, but effectively it might as well just be turned off at this point.
Scott: Yeah, effectively speaking.
Scott: so it will talk about it again.
Scott: if like a it literally turns off or I don't know what it would have to be something of that nature for us to discuss it.
Rym: So if the theme of the last news in this news are is a punching yourself in the dick Twitter has put the final nail in their dick.
Rym: They are now going to charge money to tweet.
Scott: Well, I think they're.
Scott: you know, they're discussing doing it.
Rym: They rolled it out in New Zealand and the Philippines.
Scott: Yeah Now, you know, this is an idea that has been brought up for many Oh web platforms many times.
Rym: the idea of Retweet in the era before Twitter was completely ruined by everything else Probably would have solved a lot of Twitter's problems.
Scott: But it also right.
Scott: we also don't like this idea for many obvious problems, right?
Scott: It keeps out everybody who even if they have a dollar to spare right doesn't have a credit card to actually perform online transactions.
Scott: you'd have to sell like You'd have to sell gift cards in the store that are like one dollar and we see how healthy that ecosystem is with you GameStop and Nintendo points over the years.
Rym: It also as you bring up there is a big difference between the ideological reality of paying for a service is superior if you pay with dollars Intentionally as opposed to paying with spying and advertising.
Rym: but the practical reality of having people pay with dollars Causes a lot of externalities that are hard to address under capitalism.
Scott: Yeah, also when you have an audience that is entirely paying with dollars advertisers want to advertise to it more.
Scott: right because they know right it's.
Scott: it's this weird thing that happens right where It's like, you know in the ad world We've talked about this so many times right?
Scott: all numbers in the ad world even before the internet are full of bullshit, right?
Scott: and that's sort of the standard for how it always bid right.
Scott: the You know radio ratings TV ratings, it's like no one ever counted those super precisely, you know Nielsen has methods that are not actually awful, but it's like they're imprecise, right?
Scott: They don't really know how many people watch the Super Bowl every year.
Scott: Yeah, they just think it's a lot of people and they're not wrong, but Regardless.
Scott: and so what ends up happening is someone who's in a position of selling ads.
Scott: Every bot pretty much everybody almost everyone who sells ads Inflates the numbers to some degree right that like it'll be something as small as like.
Scott: I have an email newsletter and I don't Subtract the people who unsubscribed until like, you know, some period of time has passed after they've unsubscribed.
Scott: That's like the smallest amount of number fudging, right?
Scott: But then so other people straight-up lie, like I'll round up to the nearest thousand right?
Scott: or you know, it's like They just count to get the biggest number they can.
Scott: and people who buy ads Right, sometimes don't even give a shit and they're just happy to believe lies And they don't really care about their ad performance.
Scott: and some people who really are buying ads and do really care about performance Right Have trust want to get real numbers, but have a hard time doing so and we'll use various methods.
Scott: But nothing even on the internet is is really accurate at all.
Scott: Now here's the thing.
Scott: if you go down this road that Twitter is going down of charging money Getting rid of bots, right?
Scott: You are going to bring the numbers down.
Scott: Yeah way way down.
Rym: But meanwhile the number of dollars coming in even if every human being who has ever used Twitter Paid a dollar a year.
Rym: That is not the amount of money the advertisers were paying Twitter.
Scott: nope So the dollars that come in are basically just blot blocking bot blocking.
Scott: Those are not.
Scott: Those are not dollars that actually gonna be your good revenues, right?
Scott: It's like but you're hoping that advertisers would rather pay More money if they know that their ads are being seen only by real people.
Scott: but a smaller number, right?
Scott: Or would the advertisers rather pay for the big number?
Scott: But they're not all real people and the fact is right.
Scott: It was the same number of people either way.
Scott: Yep It's it right.
Scott: It's just right.
Scott: It's the same number of real humans are gonna see the ad either way whether you block the bots or not It's the same number of real humans that are there right.
Scott: So why right?
Scott: but yet you're gonna you know mess with the your advertisers perception by messing with your number, right?
Scott: So it's not.
Scott: this is why big platforms have never right taken the strongest measures To actually block all the bots and duplicate accounts and fake accounts.
Scott: because when you do that People see the reality which is that the number is small.
Scott: The number is small now if you are running on that many people that char really using these platforms really active on these platforms Right there never really have been.
Scott: the number has always been mega inflated.
Rym: now Meanwhile, look at a service you pay money for like Netflix.
Rym: They know how many people are paying money And all they really care about is how many people are paying money because that money goes directly to them.
Rym: and then they figure out What is the minimum level of content and effort?
Rym: We need to put in to make sure the money that people pay us is Significantly more than the money we spent like that.
Rym: and they keep raising there and they're raising the prices again And they're probably right to do so because they kind of won the streaming war.
Scott: Maybe we'll see.
Rym: I mean all the other platforms are on the verge of bankruptcy like no one's doing well.
Scott: Yeah So in the related tiniest news right Apple in the new iOS has updated the podcast app Which most people don't use I guess because people hate that app for some reason I didn't.
Scott: I never really needed it.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know why people hate it so much but it there's nothing wrong with it.
Scott: They updated it a bunch whatever They.
Scott: I actually been using Spotify more because the people who complain about it.
Rym: They use like they have like really fiddly particular Fussy things they want to do with podcasts that I just don't understand.
Rym: like they're like.
Scott: I just want the newest episodes to be there so I can listen to.
Rym: they're like no But I want to be able to set a rule where it keeps the most the most recent five episodes of these shows.
Rym: But I want to keep the whole archive of this other show and I want like they have all these fiddly Requirements.
Rym: like I don't care.
Scott: I just listen to episodes and they come out otherwise.
Scott: I'm not listening to it, so I don't want it anyway.
Scott: The D it used to be that the Apple podcast app.
Scott: Apple is no longer the number one podcast client anyway.
Scott: they're like number three or four or something.
Scott: but the Apple podcast app used to just keep downloading all the episodes.
Scott: So if you subscribe to GeekNights in that app it would just download every GeekNights episode, right?
Rym: Even if you weren't listening to GeekNights Scribes far more popular than it actually is.
Scott: just like there's a lot of people If you're looking at downloads as if you're looking at downloads of mp3s as your metric because obviously you can't track plays.
Scott: You don't know if someone's playing it or not.
Scott: They might play it ten times.
Scott: you might right, but if you're looking at downloads Numbers were inflated and now the newest iOS doesn't do that.
Scott: if you don't listen to that podcast it stops automatically Downloading all the episodes.
Rym: so that's I think this is great.
Scott: Yeah I don't think that's good, too.
Scott: But it's a similar story to Twitter where the number you can show the advertisers is going to be smaller Right.
Scott: and so even though the true number of listeners is unchanged.
Scott: Yeah unchanged our Advertisers going to pay less money because it's harder to lie to them with a bigger number Even though their true number was the same before as it is now if it was worth it to them before.
Scott: Nothing is different now other than the person who is lying to you can is forced to lie less.
Rym: Well, especially because the downloads Represent someone actually listening for real.
Rym: so you have this hard number, but the podcasters there are a lot of people I get the impression who are fans of podcasts and They throw a subscribe over there because they're asked to by the person they're a fan of because that helps the advertiser metrics.
Rym: So you can support a podcaster you like by being a subscriber because it juices their metrics a little bit even if you never listen.
Rym: I think there's a lot of people who subscribe to things on YouTube on all these platforms Because they're trying to do a solid for the person they like but they don't actually engage with that person's content.
Rym: Mmm, I think that's a thing and you know what we're about to find out how much of a thing that is.
Scott: Well, you know, we'll see.
Scott: anyway, that's that's just going back.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so full disclosure.
Rym: This video does have a sponsored ad in it.
Rym: I'm just gonna tell you straight up It's it's actually pretty cool software.
Rym: I think so I don't feel that bad about it.
Rym: But also it's on a channel that does a very very good content normally.
Rym: So I'm okay linking to this because the video.
Rym: you're not familiar with how music works.
Rym: You know about minor scales and major scales I'm sure most people at least know.
Rym: like Minor scale music sounds a little bit sadder and darker and major scale music sounds happier If you know a little more about music.
Rym: you know about the modes like the Lydian mode and the mix of Lydian mode and the Phrygian mode and different kinds of minor scales and songs are written in all sorts of complicated scales.
Rym: this Video takes a song that you might have heard of.
Rym: it's called.
Rym: It's called Bohemian Rhapsody by an artist known as Queen and they play a snippet from the song and then they Alter the song to be very well done in a bunch of different Musical modes as an exercise in showing you how different
Scott: song already has like four or five modes.
Rym: Yeah But it takes basically just killed a man like that little bit and plays just that bit in a bunch of nine different Distinctive modes and it's very well done It.
Rym: if you ever wondered like how these different scales work This is a really good demonstration of it.
Rym: If you heard about harmonic minor and melodic minor and wondered why there's all these different minor scales well, yeah, there's a reason.
Rym: one of these sounds way better than the others for a reason and what I'll leave on is a lot of people talk about how the locrian mode is Impossible nonsense garbage that should never be used for any purpose.
Rym: The locrian mode would be if you're sitting at a piano you start at C and you play all the way up to the top.
Rym: It makes a nice major scale.
Rym: Move your fingers one white key to the left Start on B and play whatever scale that is B to B. It's gonna sound like shit.
Rym: That's the locrian mode.
Rym: You're gonna find out what Bohemian Rhapsody would sound like if someone earnestly tried to make the locrian mode work For this song at the end of the video.
Scott: So, what do you got?
Scott: so I mean, I guess I could have saved a speedrun thing of the day for a Tuesday, but whatever.
Rym: So I thought you're gonna open with a joke about how we finally discovered nuclear fusion.
Scott: Well, no, it's So on a Monday, there's a Game Boy Advance Castlevania game.
Scott: There's a few of them, but there's one called circle of the moon, which I've never actually played.
Rym: I kind of want to know I never beat any of those.
Scott: I've tried anyway, they're good.
Scott: But anyway speedrunners play those games obviously and you know speedrunning.
Scott: I think I still enjoy it as a spectator of it.
Scott: But lately it's like you haven't really seen.
Scott: you know, you see people beating times Right, but you're not seeing too many incredible techniques developed and known games like in big games people have sort of pushed things to the limit yeah and this to the point where they have things like the Simpsons people putting out a
Rym: One where humans have achieved Within like a couple of frames of Taz near Taz.
Rym: perfection like yeah.
Scott: But you know in terms of like something a new development that dramatically changes something in an entertaining for the spectator fashion is rare.
Scott: But here we obviously have a case of that.
Scott: Otherwise, it wouldn't be mentioning it.
Scott: So the circle of the moon They discovered a technique called nuclear.
Scott: They call it nuclear fusion.
Scott: It's a good name is the bit the greatest thing ever when you activate this trick and you don't fuck it up.
Scott: Basically, it does Maximum infinite damage to every enemy as soon as the enemies appear on screen.
Scott: So you like walk into a boss room boss dies As soon as like enemies die before they get on screen you barely even get to see the nine nine nine nine nine nine that appears That's it's just nine nine nine nine nine covering the screen.
Scott: Yeah And it's really fun and awesome and she completely changes how people speedrun this game.
Scott: obviously that to make separate categories Yeah with and without this glitch, but it's super fun to see it And I really wish I had.
Scott: there's a lot of games that I wish I had that and I Mean games a lot of game.
Scott: There are a lot of games that are that are fun games Except they have really shitty fighting and I would love to just auto win all battles Eliminate the combat from the game and have an otherwise good.
Scott: so
Rym: when I was a kid I played bionic commando once with a game genie because I'd never beaten it before like this when I was pretty young and I put in the code that made you invincible And I got all the way to the game and it was super fun.
Rym: And then I got to the bit where you got to shoot Hitler and if you fall you get shot by that gun and you Have to try again.
Rym: and I missed because it's actually a hard shot Especially if you're a kid.
Rym: and then I fell and the gun didn't kill me because I was invincible Invincible and I softlocked the whole run was ruined and it was over and I was fucked.
Scott: But I'm gonna say, you know playing doom with IDD QD and IDK FA is not unfun.
Rym: It is definitely fun.
Rym: I've I've done that a couple.
Rym: I do.
Scott: I'm not good.
Scott: You know, it's not obviously not you know, impressive Yeah, but it can be fun.
Scott: I mean I Still even though your can't die and there's no skill involved in fighting the monsters You still have the fun of finding secrets and exploring mazes?
Scott: And just shooting monsters is can be enjoyable even if there's no risk.
Scott: it's only reward, right?
Scott: It's like it's like buying a bag of candy and eating it.
Scott: No risk all reward.
Scott: It's like there's still enjoyment to be had because it's entertainment software.
Scott: Yeah, but you won't see me playing doom that way very often.
Rym: Yeah You know thinking about playing doom 2 again With IDD QD.
Rym: Yeah, just kind of straight up Just actually I have beat doom to a couple times in high school on hurt me planning And that's the best I ever did and that was that took a lot of attempts on some of those later levels.
Scott: I just don't.
Scott: it's shocking even today how few of the secrets I know where they are.
Rym: It's like I know where they are in doom - because I was obsessed with that game and modded it'll pass the early levels Like I have no fucking clue I find I don't.
Rym: I spent more time in wadded and Dehacked fucking with doom and like digging into how maps were set up than I ever did playing the game.
Rym: Yeah, anyway anyway in the meta moment I'm gonna skip the normal meta because one we've already gone on for like 45 minutes and two.
Rym: The most important meta is the new GeekNights website is live.
Scott: Yeah, we don't need to talk about it every meta moment anymore.
Rym: Yeah, it's live.
Rym: It's up.
Rym: We're gonna in.
Scott: it seems to be functioning.
Scott: We nobody's said that like hey, we can't get your podcast anymore.
Rym: We've had aesthetic and UX complaints, but that's expected.
Rym: We just wanted to get it live because you know What sucks more than making a website better making a legacy website better simultaneous to making a new website.
Scott: Right, you know, I didn't wait until the new website was perfect before putting it up, right?
Scott: I said hey as soon as the new website is as good as or even slightly better than the old website I'm gonna put it up Even if there's still more work to be done.
Scott: because a I did a whole bunch of work making it really easy to work on the new website.
Scott: So I or anyone else because it's now just open on github.
Scott: there If you send pull requests and they get merged they are automatically and instantly deployed to the new website.
Scott: No, no effort required which is awesome and makes it easy.
Scott: Like I said easy to work on and improve.
Scott: So it's just a matter of finding time identifying what to fix and fixing it adding new features Whatever.
Scott: if you have ideas for features Send them in as github issues or make a pull request or you know, yeah I'm still gonna be working on it.
Rym: any ideas anything throw them at us.
Rym: worst case We just don't do it because it's hard or we don't like it like you got nothing to lose.
Scott: You could take the code and make your own website if you want.
Scott: Yeah, that's similar, you know podcast II features, I guess and We're gonna keep evolving from there.
Rym: The the biggest thing is that It was literally unrelated reasons.
Rym: It was a combination of like I got sick with a minor cold and then we had some like life fun stuff that we went to Do like events and then there was a hockey game and our schedules just like it was a perfect storm.
Scott: It's like 15 20 minutes.
Rym: Yeah There that's why I'm not gonna try to upload the episode until after dinner because I want to eat and at least be able to watch This hockey game, but we'll get it uploaded.
Rym: So but I guess Totally unrelated.
Rym: it is literally the only reason we have not used this website for a new episode Solely because of life nonsense.
Rym: tonight just happen to be a good night to do a show.
Scott: so We'll see if the technology for that part functions or not.
Scott: and be a sting
Rym: this episode That you might be watching on YouTube because you're wondering why it's not on our website Or you might be listening to it on patreon because you're wondering why it's not on our website if this episode is not up tonight Do Give us some time because that means that we got to fix something and I'm not gonna stay up late to fix something Together with.
Scott: I'll just do it tomorrow's Friday and I got a whole weekend.
Scott: It's gonna rain again.
Rym: So yeah, this weekend's fucked anyway, so it's not like I can go hiking.
Rym: So yeah, if the episode does not get up tonight Blame the fact that this is our first production test of uploading an episode of fully.
Scott: I did test it many times on production But well, you also haven't tested with now Rym's uploading episode and I haven't tested actually uploading to lips And I uploaded to fake FTP places.
Scott: Yeah, so lips in is obviously weird.
Rym: Yeah, so there might be a kink or two and the episode might not appear right away.
Rym: But then we got a long rainy weekend until next week when we do a show on our normal schedule again And then we're back to normal.
Rym: So this episode is kind of just a test.
Rym: We were gonna do a hello world test last week like a short episode But then I got sick and the worst thing was I wasn't like too sick to do stuff, but the sickness involved Sneezing constantly like to the point that I couldn't record anything like.
Rym: it was super gross and really annoying.
Rym: You know, I think it was the most annoying sickness I've ever had in my life.
Rym: that's sneezing like I cannot express how irritating it is.
Rym: Do you just sneeze?
Rym: Several times a minute and not be able to stop?
Scott: Alright, so let's talk about some of the I guess the features on this new website, right?
Scott: So we have a. the search function is way better.
Scott: Like it's using a postgres text-based search.
Scott: It should be lightning fast.
Rym: I just searched for Jack Thompson and it says search results page 101 for Jack Thompson and didn't have anything.
Scott: I have four results.
Rym: Oh, I spelled his name wrong.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: Oh, but that is a bug.
Scott: It should say no results found or something.
Rym: Yeah, it says page 101.
Rym: So there's nothing.
Rym: so there we go.
Scott: I can put it All right, so I can put something.
Rym: get up if you if you don't yeah, a Geek fable a myriad of topics a Stratego.
Scott: Yeah, there is a Player built into the website that uses the standard HTML audio tag.
Scott: So that's you know, we don't have any weird player tracking you or anything.
Scott: We don't even have Google Analytics.
Scott: I have no idea who's visiting this website.
Scott: We've removed all If you know, I guess I removed it actually what quite a while ago from the old website.
Scott: But there is no tracking or any Nonsense of any kind on this website.
Rym: Yep, the player just works.
Rym: It just works on mobile.
Rym: It just works in weird browsers like.
Scott: it's just HTML audio thing.
Scott: You know, we have we updated the various links on the website so they go to the right places.
Scott: That's you know, there's.
Scott: there isn't a bunch of garbage left over I don't know.
Scott: it's a website with links to podcast episodes.
Scott: Yeah, like the podcast the main yeah, the main feature is that it produces an RSS feed.
Scott: then the RSS feed is Like as every possible RSS thing that you can have for a podcast.
Scott: it's like I looked at like the RSS feeds of like the top podcast like NPR podcast shit like that and We're doing everything that they're not doing.
Scott: Yeah, if Rym actually bothers to enter it Like we even have like chapter data in there We gotta start doing like I.
Rym: so It was a nice confluence that I made a pipeline to crank out thumbnails for videos Because of Adobe Express which is actually like it works pretty well like it kind of just works.
Scott: Yeah, you can put images on the episodes now.
Rym: So I'm gonna start you.
Rym: I'm gonna leverage these capabilities with increasing fervor as time goes on as we ramp this up.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, why does the website actually exist?
Scott: it exists mostly to produce an RSS feed right and So that if people search they can find us, right?
Scott: Yeah, they can find our pot and and you know just so that you know, we don't want to be beholden to various platforms.
Scott: It's like we can have our own place.
Scott: That's why it exists and You know, it serves that function.
Scott: I imagine most listeners don't need the website don't have a use for it, right?
Scott: You know, it's.
Scott: it's.
Scott: they're just using their podcast app or YouTube or whatever it is that they're using.
Scott: Yeah, and that's perfectly fine.
Scott: I don't care if you use the website or not, right?
Scott: I I have it because we have to have one not be.
Scott: But the search function I hope is actually, you know, the most useful thing.
Scott: so if there's like a old GeekNights you're looking for or you know you You want to know if we ever talked about a particular thing?
Scott: You can go and use that search function and it should be faster and hopefully more helpful than like doing a Google site search or something like yeah,
Rym: and we do have one feature that we have to bring back later around related content and we'll talk about that if and when we have a better implementation
Scott: The one that.
Scott: well, there's actually a few things that are already on the list to do right.
Scott: one thing Is that you know to make it so that when we post episodes they automatically get shared.
Scott: You know all around right?
Scott: we talked about the posse model.
Scott: publish on your own site syndicate everywhere elsewhere.
Scott: We have to do a lot more syndicate elsewhere, right?
Scott: so I can right.
Scott: so I've already done the thing to where if you like post a link to our one of our Episodes say on discord or somewhere like that you'll get or our forum you'll get sort of the automatic Fancy embedded thing right with like the logo and all that stuff appearing.
Scott: But I have to make it so that when Rym uploads an episode it automatically posts on discord without us having to do that by hand.
Scott: Yeah Automatically.
Scott: make a post on patreon without us having to do it by hand.
Rym: I'm a big fan.
Rym: we were talking about privately among some friends the why not just syndicate on every fucking possible thing Anywhere like why not have up a pop three that just will email you a podcast like it Point outlook at GeekNights and you'll get your pot.
Scott: We could gather email addresses and set up a thing to where people subscribe to eat nights by email and it emails everybody when there's a new.
Scott: you know Yeah, I.
Rym: so I was poking around on the search and I found a gem already.
Rym: I found something we uploaded on July 30th 2012. it was me appearing on episode 57 of Friday night party line and in the forum There is video of the live stream of the podcast and all the people on it And the video is also embedded in the website because of how good Scott is at his job.
Rym: It looks like we talked about the possible discovery of the Higgs boson.
Rym: So there's been a lot of movement since that episode and I think I see Timo was on this episode.
Rym: I see his face.
Scott: You see the vid there it is.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Yeah, okay found a little gem.
Rym: So, yeah I feel like we could adjourn now because I really want to eat and then start watching some hockey and then I will start to go through the upload process and
Scott: We'll see how
Rym: this goes,
Scott: you know, if you're gonna do the upload process, you know, contact me and then like share your screen.
Rym: Yeah, I will do that.
Rym: We will do.
Rym: step through that together.
Scott: Maybe I can watch the computer while it's doing whatever it does.
Rym: They will do it during a period break in the hockey game.
Scott: during the first day or second intermission I also have to eat.
Rym: so TBD worst worst case.
Rym: if we don't get to it, we'll do it tomorrow or something.
Rym: It's not like I have anything to do this weekend.
Rym: It's gonna rain.
Scott: Yeah, also, you know, hey in addition to us not doing episodes for reasons We also don't have a lot of episode ideas.
Scott: So yeah, you know come to our forum, which you'll find a link to on our website.
Scott: Yep, front row crew comm you can click on community and then click on Forum.
Rym: there is also I note or eat or you can even click on email or discord I put but we have not had a link to our fucking discord for so long and our discords actually got a lot of cool People in it.
Rym: I've been starting to try to pay more attention to it.
Rym: So occasionally you'll figure out if I'm like pooping at work because suddenly I will reply to like 15 threads in the gig nice Discord all at once and then disappear again for two weeks.
Scott: Yeah But yes send us, you know show ideas.
Rym: Yeah, so I'd suggest anything except We will not talk about Twitter and we will not talk about Jack Thompson unless they have somehow topped themselves.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this momentous episode of GeekNights are The Allen Joyce linkage.
Rym: you dread lily Tenebrae case care makes music Chris a Dodd Christopher or Clinton Walton and death Mac Finn Joel Hayes penny Reimer Rebecca Dunn Sam Erickson Shervin Von Harl and a ton of people who are given like a dollar Which is a fine amount to give.
Rym: Yeah, let us know anything.
Rym: any thoughts you have?
Rym: in the new website There's a lot of little bugs a lot of minor issues some usability concerns some aesthetic concerns.
Rym: It's all out there.
Rym: Submit them let us know because we're gonna be making a lot of improvements for the foreseeable future.
Rym: But for now, I leave you with something incredibly fresh Like how are you?
Rym: You're three.
Rym: Yeah god, that's see.
Rym: I envy you I envy your youth.
Rym: I'd give anything to be three again.
Rym: You see these pigtails.
Rym: Yeah, I regret it.
Rym: Oh don't live like me.
Rym: Okay, enjoy your youth shady cuz it goes by fast one minute.
Rym: You're three next year eight and you'll be like god.
Rym: What have I been doing with my life?
Rym: Yeah, almost three times your age.
Rym: don't see me crying.
Rym: you ever been to the third grade?
Rym: Oh, it sucks.
Rym: Your life's basically over by that point.
Rym: Oh, I've wasted my entire life.
Rym: Finger painting.
Rym: you ever finger paint shady?