Rym: It's Tuesday, August 22nd, 2023.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are talking about the quake 2 remaster.
Rym: Kind of just quick - Let's do this.
Rym: yeah, mr.
Rym: Shows last week cuz I caught kovat for the second time and Yep, so it seems Moderately hard to avoid if you continue to live your life.
Rym: at this point though Scott has continued to still avoid it.
Scott: So hopefully I mean, I don't know that I've avoided it.
Scott: I just Don't know that I haven't avoided it, right?
Scott: That's why it's possible that I've had it with no symptoms and no positive test.
Rym: That's the hardest part because I didn't actually get that sick.
Rym: like I was being extra cautious because a lot of the evidence says that a big cause of long kovat is pushing yourself or like Exerting while you have kovat and I given yourself enough time to recover.
Rym: so Precautionarily, I was super super careful.
Rym: I was going to bed early like not working out like isolating but Before kovat if I had felt that sick I won.
Rym: I would have gone to work - I wouldn't have even thought I was sick.
Rym: I would have thought I was just tired and that would have been the end of it.
Rym: Like I would not have even thought of the possibility that I am sick.
Rym: The only reason I even knew it was kovat is because Emily came home from Michigan where she definitely caught it like traveling around like at an airport in upstate, Michigan, but She came home and she's like I got a slight tickle in my throat.
Rym: I should take a kovat test and there was the faintest little line.
Scott: Well, yeah, I mean that a faintest line means you've got it.
Scott: Every time I've done the test there has been Absolutely, no line whatsoever like not even a little bit of line.
Scott: Any amount of line makes me think up.
Scott: there must be some kovat in there.
Rym: But had Emily not felt a tickle in her throat and decided to take a test I literally would not have known and would not have changed anything Like I would have kept going to work and I would have nothing in my life would have changed.
Scott: So well good for the.
Scott: you know, the little free home tests good a good thing.
Scott: They exist.
Scott: Maybe we should have those for more things, right?
Scott: Yeah, maybe we sure know would be cool.
Scott: Why can't we you know, what if they made one?
Scott: I don't know if this would be possible, right?
Rym: Where you it tests for like five different com right?
Scott: It's like the litter, right?
Scott: So you do the swabbing.
Scott: you put it in the liquid you squeeze it out and there's like a long Test strip that's got like seven lines on it.
Scott: It's like if you're sick you put it on and which line lights up tells you which sickness you have.
Scott: I am it's a pretty sure.
Scott: it's a kovat.
Rym: only reason we can't have something like that Is the combination of capitalism and conservatism and it may be.
Scott: I'm just wondering scientifically if that's not possible.
Scott: Like does the liquid part have to be different for each one?
Scott: Probably like it would be pointless because you'd have to swab and liquid five times.
Scott: So you'd be sitting there doing this like for an hour until you've figured out which one you've got.
Rym: I feel like the real important thing is just that.
Rym: I hope the mindset at least in the Blue parts of the country has indeed become if you feel sick Don't go out like don't go to the party you were going to just like normalize.
Rym: if you feel sick stay home.
Scott: Yeah, I mean that's good.
Scott: No matter what does.
Rym: yeah, that's something we people should I mean.
Rym: even before kovat?
Rym: nothing annoyed me more than Being it like a pax and like getting into a line for something and then the person in front of you is like clearly like dying of the flu Like What are you doing buddy?
Rym: like?
Scott: I know it's like that should be like a crime.
Scott: Yeah, like if you know that you are ill Right with it with a virus of ordinance some kind of it, right?
Scott: It's like obviously if you're ill with something else like you have cancer.
Scott: It's like yeah, you can go outside It's not the same right, but if you have some sort of viral Bacterial infection, you know MRSA something something nasty and contagious or could be contagious coffee sneezy Right.
Scott: Yeah, you should be required to basically house arrest yourself.
Scott: And if you don't Then you should get in trouble.
Rym: Fever is a good line.
Rym: If you got a fever definitely don't go anywhere.
Scott: There's a reason why a lot of well unless you're going to the doctor or the hospital or the pharmacy or I don't know.
Scott: It's What you know some another person in your family's home to take care of you, you know something reasonable, right?
Scott: But not any public place where there are.
Rym: now there's one.
Rym: There's the capitalist problem of some people are forced to go to work or they'll starve no matter how sick they are And that's a big big problem.
Scott: We need to fix that heart, right?
Rym: Nobody needs to go to a PAX as an attendee if they've got a fever.
Rym: I don't care how much you like packs.
Scott: That's correct.
Rym: So, uh, yep, otherwise, so get right into it again.
Scott: when I would hear a katsu con and I was sick I just stayed in the hotel room.
Rym: That what we did come out to do our like late show panel on stage.
Rym: And what do we do after we finish it?
Rym: We went straight back to the room.
Scott: That's right And I was far away from the people.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I still can't believe we made it through that show.
Rym: That was that was like top 10 sickest I've ever felt Near the bottom of that list, but it's on that list.
Scott: I Guess I was.
Rym: number one is pretty poisoning.
Rym: Number two is Lyme disease.
Rym: Number three is actually a sinus infection I got recently.
Rym: Covid was like seven I think on that list.
Rym: Anyway tons of news.
Rym: we're gonna forget most of it.
Rym: These are just the three that stood out from when we decided to do a show today.
Rym: but first and foremost I. I had Atari 2600 that was gifted to us by our good friend the cold guy that Had.
Scott: I had.
Scott: well I had one when I was young and my family has like five of them.
Rym: like both Grandparents had an Atari 2600.
Rym: We also had an Atari 2600 as did our aunt and uncles.
Scott: You guys had a lot of money my family.
Rym: No, we didn't Like my I come from and I cannot like I talk about this occasionally.
Rym: I know what I'm talking about my deep past that much on GeekNights.
Rym: I come from a family of gamers.
Rym: like gaming was Central to my entire extended family's lives video gaming games role-playing D&D just gaming.
Scott: Yeah But you know, we didn't go spending money on shit.
Scott: We couldn't afford.
Scott: but we had an Atari 2600 that was like collectively purchased but ended up in our home.
Rym: Yeah Well, we partly we got more and more 2600s over time as they became of zero costs because they were.
Rym: we did not do that But I got a 7800 before I got an NES and they were out around the same time because the 7800 Cost an order of magnitude less than an NES back then it did not function very reliably.
Scott: So it was not.
Scott: eventually just stopped being used because it's like it's was such a pain in the ass to try to.
Rym: But I also had the same.
Scott: I didn't know.
Scott: but much better cuz what was I five was if I was my age?
Scott: Yeah, I could have done something about it.
Rym: So, uh, I had of course a gigantic pile of Atari games like Nearly a hundred actual cartridges all functional times.
Rym: We had games.
Scott: we had a handful.
Rym: Well because by the time I break out pac-man combat I don't know if we even had anything else besides that when I was a little kid We had like 20 or 30 total across the family and we'd pass him around.
Rym: but as I get older like remember we'd go to we'd go to the gaming store and we were at RIT and Sometimes we I would just buy like an Atari game for 25 cents.
Rym: Like they were not expensive.
Rym: That wasn't beacon I'm pretty sure because I had the Atari 2600 in the 7800 at RIT not the 2600.
Scott: Where would you buy an Atari cartridge in there?
Rym: The hippie mall.
Scott: I Don't remember any place in there that had an Atari car.
Rym: I do but I can't be sure.
Scott: I remember I debt the Dragons didn't be in.
Scott: pkipsy definitely had a few.
Rym: Yeah, they did but I know we were buying them before then because they the average Atari cartridge cost about a nickel even in the 90s.
Rym: Anyway, so I just recently gave all of my Atari away and every Atari console every controller every game everything.
Rym: I gave them all away.
Rym: and Now there is a brand new Atari 7800 in a Atari 2600 case that is full-featured and has HDMI and USB-c and just works.
Rym: that was released by Atari Officially legit that I could have used for all those games for 130 bucks.
Scott: Yeah, I mean.
Scott: so what's happening is there are plenty of people out there who you can buy consoles from that are not official in any way shape or form But will play cartridges for all kinds of other, you know, and they're totally legal the vast majority of them, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, you can't get a top loading NES.
Scott: You can just buy this other thing that plays NES cartridges perfectly.
Scott: it's not an NES, but it might as well be and They're out there, right, but this is the first time You know that I've seen a company come out and say, all right.
Scott: Well, we'll just make one of those but official.
Scott: Yep And I mean you've had the NES mini the Genesis mini the PlayStation mini But those are just like, you know little computers with some memory and a bunch of ROMs installed.
Scott: right an emulator.
Rym: This is play the old cartridges Which is totally a difference the equivalent of buying a modern record player turntable or a modern VHS tape player.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: I don't know why Nintendo doesn't you know, could they make money if they just made some super Nintendo's?
Rym: You know what I would do if I were Nintendo.
Rym: I'd make those brand them as a special edition limited run and charge an insane amount of money for them and If a critical mass of people would definitely buy them.
Scott: It's like you can already buy one of those effectively maybe even better than the official one for cheap.
Scott: But it's like yeah an official Nintendo one might go for more.
Rym: Also, if I were Nintendo, I Would invest in making the re-released NES and SNES consoles start with those two Effectively As legitimate as on the original consoles could be.
Rym: that would be a huge not only a huge selling point.
Rym: That would actually I think be important to video game preservation.
Scott: I think it would also be you know, the portable consoles would be better right because it's like you could.
Scott: you know Right now like I'm upgrading GBAs, right?
Scott: Yeah, they could just sell official, you know GBAs that are upgraded and but they could probably do much better than Anyone in the upgrading modding scene does.
Rym: Plus I can emulate a game and they could get the real.
Scott: they get the real buttons and not like these crappier buttons that I'm Getting.
Rym: yeah, but also I can emulate a Gameboy But I don't really want to sit at my computer or my TV playing an og Gameboy game Like I want to play that on the go.
Scott: Anyway, so it's a new Atari did it and maybe some other people will follow suit.
Rym: Yeah, I think it's really cool And also they they confirmed it is fully compatible with the original 267800 controllers as well.
Rym: like it is legit It's exactly the same thing effectively speaking Yep, just whereas the you even has the old ports on the back in addition to the HDMI USB C.
Scott: Oh does it?
Rym: Yeah So cool, if I hadn't literally just given away every Atari game I owned I would definitely have bought one of these.
Rym: But since I gave it away I'm sticking to my policy of trying to keep less fewer atoms in my house.
Scott: Yeah, that's right fewer baryons.
Rym: So in some other news Surprised it didn't happen sooner.
Rym: Anyone who's mad about this I mean, come on dudes awesome.
Rym: But he should also have the ability to retire and move on to a new role.
Rym: Charles Martinette the voice of Mario is No longer going to be playing Mario and is moving on to being the Mario ambassador which sounds like The perfect best possible retirement job for someone like that.
Scott: I could imagine Yeah, I mean, this is what a lot of athletes do right?
Scott: It's like they retire and then their team like if especially an athlete that was with one team the whole time or a majority Of the time will get some sort of you know job with the team Like they get paid some nominal amount.
Rym: They got a tanner glass or a gurney They had.
Scott: well tanner glass is an actual job but like You know, it's like but they'll you know, just had to appear at some functions right?
Scott: some fundraisers Some promotional events, right?
Scott: They don't really shake hands.
Scott: do some signings do some outreach.
Scott: you know really, you know, you really like to do like hard office work or 40 day a week work or anything like that.
Scott: You just sort of you're.
Scott: you're getting paid.
Scott: You're holding on to you.
Scott: We're maintaining our good relationship with you, but you don't need to actually do your actual job anymore because the time has come.
Rym: now what'll be interesting is They Nintendo's already confirmed that the new Super Mario Brothers wonder and onward will not involve Charles Martinet And these games definitely have Mario voices.
Rym: I've heard them.
Rym: So the question is going to be is Nintendo going to announce the name of the new person?
Scott: Are they going to be in the credits right?
Rym: will they or will they keep it secret?
Scott: I don't can't not put it in the credits.
Rym: If it's if it's a person, uh So the old video games a lot of people who don't get credited despite doing for real work Video games voice act in a video game then, you know You're a lot a lot a lot A lot of people don't?
Rym: they sign bad contracts because the work doesn't pay much.
Scott: show me a Nintendo game.
Scott: That doesn't I don't think.
Rym: does that other companies definitely do?
Rym: I'm just saying What I'm surprised what I would have expected.
Rym: I would bet that the voice of Mario will be a Machine learning generated at some point in the future and remain that way in perpetuity.
Scott: Well, I mean you could do a whole 10 GeekNights episodes about you know, AI replacing, you know actors but Type of voice like they're basically sound effects in a video game.
Rym: That's the lowest hanging fruit.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty low hanging.
Rym: So on some final news because we were dunking on this a little while ago and Scott has Admitted that you've got a what a twitch stream open in the background while we're doing GeekNights muted that you're not watching?
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Rym: Yeah, so anything there is one of all the of all the many toxic influences of capitalism and games one that just annoys me personally.
Rym: and there's a lot going on and we're not gonna have time to get Into all the factors about this especially because we'll repeat ourselves from previous episodes quite a bit.
Rym: but I've always particularly disgusted and annoyed by Companies, especially twitch like twitch is all over this and has been for a long time Trying to give people direct rewards like drops or loot basically paying people to watch Twitch streams to drive up viewership.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know think about the whole thing is all about, you know There's the we People right users customers audience, right?
Scott: We are perfect world would be we can see what.
Scott: whatever would we want to see?
Scott: Right and nothing.
Scott: we don't want to see whenever we want to see it, right and no one tells us what to see.
Scott: and the people who make things to see their perfect world is.
Scott: We decide what you see when you see it how much you see it who sees it?
Scott: And nobody gets to choose what they see when they see and this is the battle right.
Scott: and so The people on the producing side, you know, it's like they're basically in a war with each other as well for attention Right.
Scott: It's like I'm sitting here with two eyeballs and there's ten people who all want me to see their thing to the exclusion of The nine other things right.
Scott: so anything that they can do To get me to watch their thing instead.
Scott: They're gonna do it, right?
Scott: So, you know there have been throughout history right people so many every iteration on this right.
Rym: There are sweepstakes where they would announce Numbers or pieces or a phone number to call at some point in the last third of the broadcast.
Rym: Make sure you don't miss it.
Rym: It's only gonna be on the screen for ten seconds Probably in the middle of like five minutes of ads.
Scott: Yeah, every single trick in the book has already been done.
Scott: We'll pay you to watch the ads.
Scott: Please watch them.
Scott: You know you the content itself is so good right theoretically and then we just put ads on.
Scott: you have to deal.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: That is basic.
Scott: That's the basic.
Rym: That's NHL hockey.
Rym: Like I I still watch hockey despite the fact that there are physical ads on the ice that I can't not see Sure, it's like that's.
Scott: that's the you know, the tried and true method.
Scott: Yeah, you know, they're the.
Scott: they're taking this to the next level here.
Scott: So this is Rym's first inner.
Scott: I think this is just the first time.
Scott: you know, this is an old Talked about this on GeekNights before.
Scott: yeah But this is the first time like it's hit a game that Rym was playing while he was playing it.
Scott: So Marvel snap had its piece.
Scott: games comm is starting in Europe.
Scott: So there's a bunch of gaming news, but we don't care about most of that triple-a nonsense here.
Scott: geek guys, you know that.
Scott: But Marvel snap, which we still play Has is doing if their PC game, which is the only one I've ever really used mostly I only use the mobile one a little bit, but it's finally out of early access as of today.
Scott: they upgraded it a whole bunch and they have.
Scott: they're doing a big promotional thing for that release and The promotion includes twitch drops and the way that works is you have to connect your twitch account and your snap account together.
Scott: So now twitch note might get some data from snap and vice versa, right?
Scott: Who knows what kind of data?
Scott: They're sharing and have to read the privacy agreement.
Scott: But also when you watch Snap on twitch for a certain amount of time on certain streams, right?
Scott: For example, there's one person over here who is being lit there.
Scott: They're open about it that they're being sponsored by snap.
Scott: So snap is paying this person to stream snap And if I watch them long enough with my connected accounts, I'll eventually get snap currencies.
Scott: So I'm just minimized and muted them And it's like alright, I will just spend some CPU cycles and get some free snap credits Right eventually and that person I'm watching they'll benefit.
Rym: I guess well, cuz they'll get a fake eyeball watching 30.1 minutes of their stream, right?
Scott: But yeah, this is the fun, you know, I'm still waiting for the.
Scott: you know The final straw to break.
Scott: with regards to you know advertising people love their numbers to be fake.
Scott: so much Right.
Scott: It's like they don't.
Scott: they don't want to report the real numbers of things like the number of people actually Watching for real and paying attention is so small.
Scott: Like if those numbers got out the ad buyers would be like hell.
Scott: no Why am I?
Scott: I'm not paying you nearly as much or as often.
Rym: so I paid you to have 10,000 people Not watch this stream for a half hour and then log out the millisecond.
Rym: We gave them some pings in an app, right?
Scott: And then but on the other hand, they've got this competing thing Where it's like.
Scott: we need to root out fraud and fake number.
Rym: We need to.
Rym: we need to Performatively show that we have put a nominal effort into rooting out fraud, right?
Scott: So this is the this this battle that's always happening between get the real numbers Or get fake numbers that are inflated But not too fake that no one will believe them.
Scott: and you can see the extreme end of this by looking at what's going on Right now.
Scott: we're like, you know, Ellen has got like, you know, mostly bots following him.
Scott: It's like he doesn't want the real follower account to get out but other interested parties Want to know the number of real users not get all these bots out of here.
Rym: So it's funny because overwatch League tried to do something similar and from all the articles Like I just I talk about overwatch a lot because I play it a lot still.
Rym: so I didn't want this just never made the cut.
Rym: Their problem was people who didn't even like.
Rym: even the drops weren't enough to get people to watch the league matches on Twitch Like people just didn't even go for them didn't even bother with them That they have to be something that people are willing.
Rym: and there's one thing that people want They want spider-man pictures of spider-man.
Rym: literal textures of spider-man is what you get.
Scott: who doesn't?
Scott: who doesn't want a picture?
Rym: Oh They must hire JJJ as a consultant here.
Scott: I mean listen, you know, JJJ wants pictures of spider-man.
Scott: But guess what?
Scott: He wants them because if he puts them on the newspaper, everyone buys the newspaper.
Scott: They want to see pictures of spider-man.
Scott: He pays because he'll know you'll pay.
Rym: Yep And now we're cutting out the middleman.
Scott: if you if you let me tell you if the real if the real newspaper Had pictures of spider-man on it.
Scott: I bought it.
Rym: Yeah, the first though for at least the first newspaper that had a real spider-man on it New York Times cover was like, you know had spider-man I'd be like.
Rym: well get that thing is, you know humans Two weeks after the existence of a real spider-man Like was acknowledged it would just be in the background.
Rym: We wouldn't even think about it again.
Rym: It's like oh if spider-man did something interesting.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway cookies out on the balcony Spider-sense but anyway things of the day.
Rym: so So a listener and a friend both sent this to me after I had already queued it up as my thing of the day and The thing of the day is very short.
Rym: It's a two minute 30 second video that will walk you through a legitimately plausible chess opening.
Rym: But it is in the style and framed not the way chess people Traditionally frame these kinds of conversations but more the way Modern gamers frame these kinds of conversations.
Rym: because if you haven't paid attention There's the like weed.
Rym: when we talk about chess on GeekNights We tend to talk about the top top tier and the drama around that and how everything's a draw and AI is messing stuff up and like the stalemate.
Rym: rules need to change and there's all that sort of space.
Rym: but If you talk about counter-strike that way that's the equivalent of yes It's the it's the counter-strike Intergalactic championship for the game is literally just who clicks on whose heads first around the corners and everything's memorable I like it's.
Rym: it's a totally different game from how the vast majority of people play it.
Rym: So all the people who aren't grandmasters at chess who play chess for fun and have not Exhausted the possibilities of chess where chess is a really fun game that community is growing Rapidly and has been growing for many years now.
Scott: Still hot still hot.
Rym: So now there's lots of YouTube channels and streamers and people who are playing chess who are not the Stereotypical very old white man who seems gruff like it's just gamers talking about this like gamers.
Rym: So this this video will walk you through something that is Actually kind of close to the opening I used to always play when I learned that openings existed in chess and that was how I beat my friends because if you play chess with an opening you will beat like 70% of people who don't know what an opening is.
Scott: even if you're bad at chess I've never bothered to memorize any kind of.
Rym: I've memorized the Polish opening and a variant on this one and Like a couple others.
Rym: I don't do I remember them fully?
Rym: Yes, I think I do.
Rym: Anyway, this Opening gambit is titled the intercontinental Ballistic missile gambit and it basically involves making a few moves because unless your opponent is like Kasparov They're not gonna see it coming like unless they know chess and then you basically launch your queen it into their back line Like a flanker in overwatch and fuck them up.
Rym: And it's really funny as an opening to a chess person.
Scott: The thing is if you're playing against some amateur They're gonna make moves that are way outside what this video Thinks they'll make and I don't know if it'll work.
Rym: if they make moves outside of that though It's almost easier to pull this stuff off Maybe.
Rym: but what I like about this video too is It actually does assume that you're gonna play basically competent chess and it just points out the few Dangers.
Rym: that wouldn't be obvious.
Rym: and it points out this one specific danger of if the if the opponent does this Don't be a fool.
Rym: Don't take the bishop and you know what?
Rym: Well, I immediately before they said don't do this.
Rym: I saw the move and I thought oh, I'll take the bishop and they're like.
Rym: No, don't you're a fool.
Rym: I Taken that bishop so hard and so fast in that situation.
Rym: So yeah, that's what I got.
Rym: play chess.
Rym: It's actually a pretty okay game unless you're really good at it or really bad at it or anyone's memorized anything.
Scott: Yeah All right, so this videos.
Scott: maybe this video is quite old, but it was uploaded to YouTube quite a while ago.
Scott: But I only saw it during the Tour de France, which is already a while ago But didn't have until now to make a thing of the day.
Scott: But basically, you know when you look at the Tour de France our marathon or something.
Scott: It's like there's official people who are like, you know on teams driving support vehicles Supplying food beverages snacks equipment support etc.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Well back in the olden days Apparently that was not always the case And here we see a perfect example of it.
Scott: I didn't realize it was this extreme until I saw this video But apparently back in the olden days for these long bike races the people would just sort of the Cyclists, which is sort of when they were hungry or thirsty and there was a cafe They would just get off and loot the cafe like they would run in steel Shoplift put shit in there in their pockets.
Rym: They're like walking around like cramming food into their mouths putting like bottles of wine in the back of their Jersey.
Scott: Yeah It's like what it's like.
Scott: and then basically the people with the cafes would send you know an invoice to the to the tour.
Scott: be Like hey, this is what you guys shoplifted.
Rym: It was a culturally cherished tradition.
Scott: from watching this video I don't know how cherished it was by the cafe owner, but I get.
Scott: I assume they got.
Scott: the invoice was paid But still it's like, you know It's.
Scott: it's pretty funny to see just somebody get off and loot a cafe Like it's like it's like they're supposed to but especially the videos like.
Rym: one of the most important moments of the tour are the drinking Raids and I made it like what the fuck is the drinking raid?
Rym: Yeah you know, it's funny because
Scott: one idea
Rym: what it starts to illustrate is a thing that we talked about occasionally where and actually we talked about a little while ago where the extreme optimization of any game any sport like any system tends to become Very different from the thing it was intended to be.
Rym: up to that point Like baseball has the very small number of true outcomes.
Rym: The number might increase or reduce slightly based on the rules But most of the parts of baseball don't matter anymore.
Rym: And as people professionalize also, a lot of fun aspects of sports and fun aspects of games become less and less prominent.
Rym: and think about what this looks like if you watch this video of like the way the racing was like they're like Eating ice cream sandwiches and like popsicles while they're riding they got bottles of wine And these are.
Rym: these are the pros racing in the for real tour.
Rym: nowadays.
Rym: it is Extremely scientifically driven riders with an infinite line of cars giving them Highly tuned food that they can and highly food that tuned beverages that they consume on a very strict schedule.
Rym: It's like he almost took most of this fun out of it But you made it.
Scott: that could be fun from a certain perspective.
Scott: It can.
Rym: yeah, I Feel like I would enjoy the older Tour de France more than the current one But we should.
Scott: we should hold it, you know old Tour de France, right?
Scott: No one's allowed.
Scott: no support cars allowed No support vehicles.
Rym: We stock cafe.
Rym: You have to.
Scott: you can only eat and drink if you loot.
Scott: You didn't loot it.
Scott: you can't drink it.
Rym: In the meta moment the GeekNights book club book is the murder bot diaries.
Rym: I picked this one.
Rym: We're good at what we're gonna do.
Rym: I have read 1.5 of the murder bot diary.
Scott: I have read 3.9 murder effectively for murder bot diaries.
Scott: so far Each of them has taken literally one sitting.
Scott: the first one.
Scott: I finished eating dinner.
Scott: I went to the park.
Scott: I laid down on the bench in the park I started reading and then I finished reading and the Sun went down and I went home.
Scott: That's how long one book takes like two to three hours.
Rym: Yeah, we went to Queensbridge Park.
Scott: I went to the beach.
Scott: I read 1.9 books at the beach.
Rym: Yeah Yep, so these are pretty quick read.
Rym: So what we're gonna do is we're just gonna keep reading them and see how far we get.
Rym: cuz there's a bunch of murder bot Diaries.
Rym: we're reading them in Publication order.
Rym: cuz why not doesn't really matter the order.
Scott: the internet says to read them in.
Scott: Yeah, I don't have numbers on them, which is annoying.
Scott: I had to look up what the order is based.
Scott: Yeah, I went to Martha Wells website which had a handy list in order And that's what you do have to read them in order Like they literally that they pick up right where the previous one left off like immediately.
Scott: There is no gap and it's cereal.
Scott: so yes, you figure out the order even if the volumes don't have numbers.
Rym: and what I'll say so far is that the Deepest vibe is think about the alien aliens universe the kind of capitalism the kinds of companies the kinds of situations and it's that world as seen through the eyes of a Low rent security bot who doesn't want to do its job.
Scott: Yeah, the security bot is like I thought it was.
Scott: it said murder bot Diaries and I was expecting when Rym explained it originally That it was gonna be like an assassin right like all it like some military.
Scott: It's like man.
Rym: I wish I was an assassin.
Rym: I'm just like a rent a cop.
Scott: right like all it does is kill right.
Scott: so then it has to contend with like you know All these issues.
Scott: like my only only thing I know how to do is kill these clients.
Scott: right, but it's not.
Scott: It's a security bot You know which is like.
Scott: you know its its purpose was to protect people although it has many capabilities for violence And that sort of on the one hand brings it in right to make more sense, but on the other hand loses some of that.
Rym: Anyway, yep, but so far.
Rym: I'm enjoying it.
Rym: so at some point after packs We'll do the book club show on it, and we'll warn you how far we get.
Rym: I'm probably gonna read them all regardless, but we'll see if I read them all before we do the show.
Rym: But with two flights to Seattle I feel like I might just read them all.
Scott: How many how many of you read listener?
Scott: Where are you?
Rym: Considering I just put up the post now So the only listener who knew we were talking doing this book was someone who listened to the previous book club book on.
Rym: this is How you lose the time war.
Rym: the GeekNights book club has done Actually a lot of books over the years not because we do them quickly But because GeekNights has been going has a lot of years.
Rym: 2005 was a long goddamn time ago.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Also, we will be live at PAX West 2023 with an all-new panel.
Rym: and well sometimes if we have a panel That's a variation on a previous theme Scott will call me out and say it's not at all new panel.
Rym: It's like 20% new.
Rym: this one actually is an entirely new talk.
Rym: the problem is we already came up with an even better talk that we want to do after this one, but Games you can't play Sunday 3 30 p.m.
Rym: Eastern time not Eastern time.
Rym: I just that's a typo.
Rym: I got a fix.
Rym: soon as we finish the show a Seattle time in the blue morpho theater I guess.
Rym: I guess will it be what the daily savings won't be over yet, so it'll be PDT Yeah or just PT and that way that whether or not daylight saving time is applied is Implied and doesn't need to be explicitly stated thus avoiding confusion.
Rym: I also was reminded again recently because I was trying to set up a meeting across a bunch of time zones And I knew this, but I forgot that I knew it.
Rym: I learned it again that China is one big time zone What I didn't know that.
Rym: oh, I feel like we talked about this.
Scott: we should go to the far western China.
Rym: So you know that's.
Scott: uh cuz Emily was in Michigan and while she was gone we talked about that all right But about far western China is gonna be.
Scott: wait Yeah, cuz think about that.
Rym: where Emily was is like a eight to twelve hour drive from here.
Rym: How far could you drive across China at eight to twelve hours?
Scott: I don't know measured I Imagine not all the way All right, so uh Weirdly we have never talked about quake quake one quake to the only talks about quake live Yep, talked about death matches.
Scott: We've talked about these things, but we never did an episode directly on Quake.
Rym: one two three yep, so this episode at least will be about the quake to remaster that just came out.
Rym: but it is by extension a Review our discussion of just quake - because it is it's the same damn game.
Rym: It's just a patch.
Rym: It's like if what if Super Mario 1 got an official patch from Nintendo today?
Scott: We talked about that in the news when the quake one remaster came out.
Scott: right and this is this is what I'm talking about Right.
Scott: so many other companies for example Capcom.
Scott: They do these Resident Evil remasters right which I'm played some of them Yeah, and it's like yes those original games are have much much merit and are worth playing for certain reasons But they're software implementations the user interfaces not ideal right it's inaccessible annoying ugly.
Scott: Dated Control is bad right.
Rym: people put up with it back then, but now by modern standards not pleasant But also those those tend to be when they remit when they remaster them re-implemented.
Scott: Yeah, sometimes sometimes the Resident Evil ones are basically the same damn game And it's like and then they charge money for it.
Scott: Right because it's like they put a lot to put a lot of work into that because they basically rebuilt a new game that just Happens to be the same as some other game, right?
Scott: it's like you know and So there's that kind of remake that happens, then you've got like Nintendo Which does like sort of like a HD remaster which almost feels like they didn't put too much work into it.
Scott: not like the Resident Evil ones where it's just like they're basically just taking like a Wii game or a GameCube game and making it HD and Recompiling it and just getting it to run on a switch and upping the resolution And it's still the same damn game basically
Rym: of course.
Rym: then they have things like the Link's Awakening remaster Which was like that was a work of art.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, that's a. that's a complete redo, right?
Scott: So here what the what they've been doing?
Scott: down, I guess but the company is Bethesda.
Scott: now Right is with Quake 1. they're just like on Steam.
Scott: if you got Quake 1 We're right.
Scott: there already been fans doing this.
Scott: fans have made like custom engines that you know will run.
Scott: You know your doom or your quake or your tie fighter or whatever game You know but only better and modern.
Scott: you just have to have a few data files from the original game and you take it the new engine and Boom you've got an upgraded game, right?
Scott: It's suitable for the modern times, but here they're like.
Scott: you know what if you already own the game on Steam?
Rym: boom It's upgrade cuz it's just a patch.
Rym: It's just up version.
Rym: I forget what version number is.
Rym: it just has a version number.
Scott: Yeah, they did it for Quake 1 and then they for quake they.
Scott: it was rumors cuz quake on kit happened Right that it was gonna come out, you know quake quake on that.
Scott: They would announce it.
Scott: Not only did they announce it?
Scott: They released.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: it's just like.
Scott: hey guys if you have quake 2 on Steam It's upgraded now, and if you don't well you can buy it.
Scott: It's discounted now y'all and now you can enjoy quake 2. and not only did we upgrade it to be you know Basically better than all the fan-made engines out there and everything But we're also gonna throw in a whole new You know campaign and we're gonna throw in the.
Scott: you know the the quake 64 campaign also.
Scott: Yeah, right cuz that if you way back in the day There was quake - quake and quake - for an instead of 64 and those had different maps and and you know I think it doesn't different enemies.
Scott: basically they were different.
Scott: You know the game part was different.
Scott: It wasn't just the same game.
Scott: you know sort of Water down to work on an n64.
Scott: it actually changed the game.
Rym: So yep now full disclosure.
Rym: I will admit this I have never played through even a materially a material amount of the single-player quake 1 or quake - I Mean it's basically just you know, it's 3d.
Scott: you aim up and down unlike doom, right?
Scott: Yeah, and it's fast and full of enemies everywhere and there's some dis of.
Scott: you know Get the key find the door find the secret stuff going on.
Scott: And then one thing a lot of players a lot of annoying platforming parts where you fall in lava.
Scott: that kind of sucks.
Rym: Yeah, well partly because it's fascinating to play these again because I was poking at the single-player both quick one and quick - just you know.
Rym: Just wanted to see These games on one hand.
Rym: They have a lot of annoyances like game design like level design as a science.
Rym: It's better now than it was back then.
Scott: they added a compass to this one Which at least if that which is draws like these great you enable it It turns these green arrows to show you where the hell to go.
Scott: Yeah, it would be very somewhat unplayable without it.
Scott: There'd be parts we'd be like running around in circles like not knowing where the hell to go.
Scott: Yeah, I'll be not for that.
Rym: So but when these games came out like that there weren't games like these before and that is something you need to Internalize if you play these games, yes, we're the ones.
Scott: Yeah, people don't remember who weren't around then but basically 3d cards for your computer became a thing and so the Two games that were like the big-time games that came out where it was a battle between quake one and Duke Nukem 3d Which is and you know how that Duke Nukem forever right.
Scott: the sequel to do a Google 3.
Scott: You know how that went right but the sequel to quake.
Scott: Well that actually happened.
Scott: Yeah We know who won that battle.
Scott: it wasn't in the video game magazines.
Scott: They made it out to be like, you know, it was.
Scott: it was a SNES first Genesis battle.
Scott: It wasn't quick just one.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: but also there was you need to understand to how fast the iteration cycle was between when Doom 2 came out and Quake 2 came out was not that long like quake 1 came out in like summer of 1996.
Rym: Duke Nukem came out a few months before that.
Rym: in 96 quake 2 came out in.
Rym: Quake 1 was already obsolete within a year of quake 2 coming out, right?
Scott: So wait quake 1 came out when right to Doom 2 is 94.
Rym: So in just two years we went from doom 2 to quake 1 And in less than a year we went to Duke Nukem 3d which was actually really impressive for like what it was Which was predating quake 1. and then quake 2 just comes in Less than a year after quake 2. after what month did quick to come out?
Rym: About a year after and quake 2 just destroys the entire landscape.
Rym: Yeah, quake 2 was like one of the biggest revolutions in video games up to that point.
Scott: Yeah, quake 1 was like, okay, you can aim up and down now.
Scott: It's really 3d for real this time Yeah, but there wasn't like the first, you know descent also was like that But descent was a flying game though and not a you know descent was like a free, you know, six degrees of freedom whatever, right?
Scott: Yeah, when did descent?
Scott: 1 came out?
Scott: 95 so same time as like doom 2. so we already had the 3d games, right?
Scott: But you know descent was a lot more like quake 1 and sort of.
Scott: you know, yeah Right, and then quake 2 was like, alright now we're gonna.
Scott: you know, we was the polishing right?
Scott: It's like they didn't polish the quake 1.
Rym: It's like they had it and they got it out when it was enough and you know why it was a groundbreaking game Because we'd never seen anything like that before.
Scott: no, yeah I mean, you know like other than descent.
Scott: right but it wasn't an FPS and you know Is not easy to play even today not because it's hard to get the software to run but because six degrees of freedom.
Scott: Flying is just difficult.
Scott: Yeah, no matter what your controls are.
Scott: I mean, even if you have a VR helmet, it's it's difficult.
Rym: Not only was it just polished quake 2 had things like cutscenes NPCs that would interact with you like a kind of for real story like the single-player mode is big.
Rym: I only didn't play it for other reasons.
Scott: We'll get into the story isn't that much?
Scott: The story is aliens invaded and now we're gonna invade them back.
Rym: Yeah, but compare that to the story of doom.
Rym: There's no NPCs in doom Even any NPCs in quake 1.
Scott: But yeah, just you know the polish and of quake 2 right.
Scott: it just polished quake 1 in in so many so many ways And it's partly because this was an era where you mentioned the 3d cars.
Rym: but a few other things were happening in around.
Rym: when quake 2 came out is also when a bunch of Neighborhoods across the United States got access to some of the earliest broadband.
Rym: like there were cable modem deployments all over America in random towns and also modems were getting like the 56k era was fully there.
Rym: So and computers not even 3d cards were just getting faster and more people had them.
Rym: So we had this confluence of.
Rym: the technology was evolving So fast and a game came out that took advantage of that evolving technology Over the course of the quake doom quake quake 2 iterations and it was the perfect storm that changed everything.
Rym: Well, yeah there is.
Rym: I never played the single-player.
Rym: was that?
Rym: that was an error in my life where because I had a cable modem and Because I was already deep into quick one like and doom Online play all I wanted with death was deathmatch.
Rym: All I wanted was multiplayer and mods.
Rym: I Literally did not care that there was a single-player game in quake 2 Mmm, I bought it solely to play online with my friends.
Scott: That's you know.
Scott: if you could if that was a thing you could do right when that wasn't a thing that Existed before then really easily with that.
Scott: What other game was there that you know?
Rym: It's like doom and quake and command and conquer all those.
Rym: you could do that and I did it.
Scott: You could but it was not everyone good.
Rym: I in high in middle school in high school I knew like four or five other people who were capable of doing it with me.
Rym: Yeah, but my quick to like everyone in the neighborhood had quick to like people would be playing quake with each other after school.
Scott: No, it was for some reason.
Scott: It was you know, it was easier to play, you know quake one It's like, you know people had to like upgrade quake one with all sorts of mods to like get it to do.
Scott: You know, there's GL.
Scott: quake was like an extra thing, right?
Scott: It wasn't the default, right?
Scott: Whereas quake 2 was basically all those things from quake one that we know were you know need you need to add to quake one?
Scott: You didn't need to add them to quake to quake to had them built in because it was quick to.
Rym: So the other that I guess in terms of gameplay that because the I have the most experience with the multiplayer And I think it's worth pointing out that quake one is interesting to play Multiplayer like deathmatch in particular capture the flag or all the things you can play But it really is limited like it really doesn't hold up to a significant amount of play Even if you double down and try to get good the variety and the polish of quake to make it So much more of a game like.
Rym: it is such a compelling multiplayer experience compared to quake one that if you haven't played either I Almost wouldn't bother with quake one.
Rym: unless you're interested in the history.
Rym: quake two is the revolution, right?
Scott: Well quake two also, it's like yeah, there were plenty of mods for quake one But quake two that's where the mods ready counter-strike Effectively came out of the lineage of people modding quake two and then modding half-life action right to me.
Scott: Well half-life one was basically right like quake engine.
Scott: then they modified that a whole, you know.
Scott: But it's like half-life one has a lot in common with quake.
Scott: to write you open the console You got a lot of same commands going on there and stuff right.
Scott: software technology wise.
Scott: Half-life warning as you know, it comes straight from quake two almost.
Scott: and then you know counter-strike obviously is right on top of half-life.
Scott: What it's like all that's.
Scott: and then the separate branch.
Scott: at this point cuz Duke Duke and 3d died Right was the separate branch was the unreal branch.
Scott: Yeah real tournament.
Scott: That was the other.
Scott: Yeah, that was the you know, the the distant unrelated software, right?
Scott: But all the half-lives and the counter-strikes in the quakes.
Scott: Those are all like in the same Family of the FPS.
Scott: is that still control the world.
Rym: Yep, but like Yes, I played quick one online a bunch like with our friends and then nobody really wanted to play it much anymore Cuz we kind of got everything.
Rym: we're gonna get out of it.
Rym: I've been playing quick to online kind of often with people and I'm not good Like.
Rym: don't don't don't mistake that.
Rym: I'm good relative to like all the people out there who are great at quake, too But I'm about as good as I remember being.
Rym: It's way fun.
Rym: Like it is it is.
Rym: I would say quake to multiplayer deathmatch is Fun enough to be competitive with current modern online FPS's.
Rym: It's also really really fast right good, especially compared to any FPS you're playing today Fortnight or quake 3 and you go play quake - Doug I don't know how you're gonna cope with it and then go play.
Rym: quake 1 is like faster than that.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of like driving, you know an f1 car.
Scott: It's like you could bet be a professional race car driver.
Scott: You've driven all kinds of fast cars, right and then you try to drive an f1 car and it's like oh fuck It's like step on the pedal a little and goes too fast, right?
Scott: Oh shit, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, it's yet to handle it right and quake - you start running and you do a rocket jump.
Scott: It's like ha ha ha.
Scott: It's it's you know, your guys moving too fast and then you die before you see anybody.
Scott: It's like yeah, you know.
Rym: or you just run you out of the hallway and then you're in the lava and you died.
Scott: It's like what?
Scott: what happened?
Rym: It's just the.
Rym: the gameplay is so fast and furious that there aren't a lot of games that captured.
Rym: well There's a lot of games that have tried But honestly, I don't think a lot of them have really reached the level of gameplay polish that quake 2 had.
Rym: So, what did they change in the remaster?
Rym: because they did make changes like this is a new version of the graphics are Dramatically improved.
Rym: Yep wide screen just works.
Rym: I got a modern thing.
Rym: high resolution just works.
Scott: You can even do local You know local split-screen.
Scott: Yeah, if you want to do something like that You can works.
Rym: now you can turn on and turn off whether if you had a video card with glide that could support the color Matt like the fancy color mapping or didn't.
Rym: you can turn that on or off because most people had video cards that didn't show all The colors quake had or all the lighting that quake had.
Rym: It looks like you can get mods working.
Rym: I haven't tried yet.
Rym: that's something I'm gonna look at later.
Rym: They also made gameplay changes.
Rym: they changed the recoil on the machine gun.
Scott: They tweaked some of the recall on the machine gun in the original.
Scott: quake was really made it hard to use.
Scott: Yeah, now the machine gun is significantly better.
Scott: It's like now.
Scott: it's what it should have been which was a weaker chain gun But it uses less ammo because you use the chain gun.
Scott: chain gun is amazing But you run out of ammo because it's a chain gun.
Rym: they fixed quote Hundreds of level and gameplay bugs like they just fixed bugs.
Rym: Imagine a game like quake how it came out in 1997 the year 2023.
Rym: Hundred bugs just get fixed.
Scott: that were you can up the resolution to 4k.
Scott: I don't know if you could do that on the old one.
Rym: Oh, you definitely could not right.
Scott: If you have a high refresh rate monitor, you could run it at a higher rate.
Rym: They fix the AI on a bunch of the enemies now to make them behave better in game.
Rym: The berserker even has a new leap attack and there's like.
Rym: they're like some of the monsters.
Scott: Yeah, it's really dangerous.
Rym: Yeah, but the best part is the things that they added that I some some insufferable nerds are complaining that It's not the quake.
Rym: They remember It.
Rym: I guess Bethesda straight-up said no these were things we tried to do in quake 2.
Rym: We just ran out of time and had to release it like we couldn't get him done.
Rym: This was the quake to remastered.
Rym: is our vision of what quake 2 was supposed to be?
Scott: Yeah, I love.
Scott: I love the fact that it's like it's.
Scott: it's not treated as like some separate game.
Scott: It's literally just like they.
Scott: you know after all that time you did another version.
Scott: I would love to see not just games but like lots of software out there Right that you know just like.
Scott: that's been old and un-updated for a long time But maybe someone is still using it somewhere like just have a new version right be like, you know What?
Scott: What's what's?
Scott: an old software that you know, I guess, you know Winamp has failed at this.
Scott: It's not always gonna succeed You know, I don't know if there's currently a word perfect out there, but I know a lot of people using old word.
Scott: Perfect.
Rym: It also ties into our panel in.
Rym: that Was what was one of the first things we bought on that on steam when steam was not just the counter-strike updater But had things to buy.
Rym: we bought with both of us bought a pack of every a game ever.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Well, that's what that's exactly That id pack of like the id toad all games id that had all the dooms and all the Wolfenstein's and all the quakes Right.
Scott: That was the first one of the first things I bought on steam and the early 2000s 2001 2 3.
Scott: I'm like that right.
Scott: and That quake that I got in that bundle on the same steam account is the quake that just got a patch.
Scott: So because I bought that then I have this now, right?
Scott: It's literally the same item in the same steam library that was just updated and this is partly why like so after all these after 20 years plus years of steam I'm still playing the first game I bought on steam
Rym: and beat between the history has got an update and the history of steam and the history of valve and the history of Bethesda and id give me a strong hope that Most games disappear or you have to struggle like you can't trust platforms to be around forever.
Rym: but the legacy of id and the legacy of valve Regardless of if they could fuck us over one day They have a multi decade history of not fucking us over.
Rym: that is all huge history.
Rym: That is a huge percentage of the entire history of the concept of video games.
Scott: Yeah now there is something funny to mention That we don't need to comment on much because you already know everything there is to know about this, right?
Scott: But they've added Cloud save which is really nice.
Scott: But they've also added cross play.
Scott: So somebody playing quake on not a PC can play against someone like on a PC.
Rym: I joined a cross play server a couple nights ago Mm-hmm, like lambs to the cosmic slaughter.
Scott: well did?
Scott: I don't wonder if you're lying because In fact, if you try to play cross play, right?
Scott: It will not allow you to use mouse and keyboard.
Rym: cuz I enabled cross play in the lobby in the one we were playing.
Scott: I check the bottle it.
Scott: from what I've heard if you play cross play everyone has to use a gamepad.
Rym: That's a really good idea.
Scott: Well, so we'll see.
Scott: That's what I heard.
Scott: I haven't actually attempted it.
Rym: So yeah, I will.
Rym: next time we play I'll check that box and see what happens.
Scott: Yeah, we'll have to experiment and verify.
Rym: I must just be good against most people.
Scott: Or who knows?
Scott: or maybe maybe that information is incorrect maybe Rym's lying who knows?
Rym: yeah Anyway, the the other thing they've added to the game that is very important And this is another like big checkbox in their favor and they did this with a quake one remaster as well And we talked about it like they added a huge number of accessibility features.
Scott: Oh, yeah Which like turning off flashing.
Rym: so you don't get yeah things that even if Early game developers had thoughts to try to do them were not easy to do with the technology at the time.
Rym: and the the fact That they committed to doing this along with the remaster is it's just a very important thing Like this is.
Rym: there's nothing but good on this release.
Rym: as far as I can see It looks better.
Rym: it plays better like everything about this is great.
Rym: if you don't own quake - I'd recommend getting quake - This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 License.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights RL enjoys the engage you dread.
Rym: Lily Tenebrae kiss care mix music.
Rym: Krista Dodd Clinton Walton decks Finn Joel Hayes Penny Reimer Rebecca Dunn Sam Erickson sure not all and a ton of people who give like a dollar or a pound or a Euro I assume just to get that sweet patreon RSS feed.
Rym: so uh Yeah, stay tuned for us at PAX and you might see our new website coming sometime after PAX.
Rym: We're getting real close there.
Rym: Don't expect too much.
Rym: We're focused on functionality not aesthetics cuz nobody goes to the website.
Rym: Anyway, we just need it to be crawlable and such and there's a lot going on, but we'll move from there bit by bit.
Rym: we just got to get off of our ancient ancient ancient platform and And yeah, so anyway, I'm hungry I'm gonna about to play blades in the dark, so I'll leave you with.
Media: I Had a more pleasant day.