Rym: It's Wednesday, May 10th, 2023.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are talking about Makoto Shinkai's latest Suzume.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh in New York City, we got the city bike, which is our like docked bike share program.
Rym: Like it's pretty good.
Rym: Like I use these bikes a lot in my day to day life.
Scott: It's like the biggest bike share thing ever and those and New York.
Scott: It's the biggest in the world.
Scott: it's the biggest in the u.s.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's the same system.
Rym: Basically.
Rym: that's in like Paris and all these other cities.
Rym: But in New York like I use this most of the time like I use my real bike to go on like a bike trip the weather is decent and I'm going pretty much anywhere that there are city bike docks and City bike will get me there fast enough.
Scott: It is the best choice.
Rym: Yeah In fact when I had to get my remember when my camcorder like the lens scratched itself internally at yeah So to do the RMA to get the replacement I box that giant thing up in this giant box.
Rym: I strapped it to a city bike and I biked to the FedEx store.
Rym: Yeah So, uh and we have regular bikes and about 20% of the system is e-bikes and you have to pay a little bit if you Use the e-bike compared to the even if you guys you can get an annual membership Which is like you can.
Scott: if you have an annual membership, you can ride non e-bikes normal bikes all you want Just for basically you.
Scott: just the thing is any Individual ride has to be under 45 minutes and then you dock it and you take it right back out and you can keep riding.
Scott: Yep, if you hold one over 45 minutes, then you get charged But an e-bike?
Scott: as soon as you take an e-bike out you start getting charged money.
Rym: And if you don't have an annual plan, they cost a lot.
Scott: But yeah but if you have an annual plan you get charged a little bit
Rym: if and basically if you're cuz I use them kind of often now partly because They are if you're biking from our apartment in Queens to pretty much anywhere Midtown between Midtown and like Astor place it is as fast as the subway or faster and it is cheaper than one swipe of the subway.
Scott: But it's not cheaper than a non e-bike, which is free.
Rym: But if you need to get there with the speed of the subway It is faster than the subway and cheaper than the subway.
Scott: I mean I bike on a city bike.
Scott: unless it's a really far ride.
Scott: It's you know Like any ride to Manhattan.
Scott: if I leave the house and get on the city bike right outside and someone else has to take a bus Or walk to the subway.
Scott: I'll get there basically at the same time they get.
Scott: Oh, yeah I can see that the non e-bike is gonna get you there faster than this.
Rym: my difference The e-bike is way faster than the city bike only because we live next to the subway station And I'm always going to places like my office next to the subway station and it is still faster.
Rym: but anyway We have regular e-bikes like the first ones they rolled out which are Little bit janky looking like they're they're a bit hinky and how they made them, but they work.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: But they made some new fancy ones that are big and white and they're more like an e-motorbike like they're legit.
Rym: They're way fast.
Rym: They're like.
Rym: I actually really like them.
Rym: But there was a phenomenon in New York City that had and still happening but less so than it used to Where you'll every now and then just see one of those things just like Laying on the ground somewhere random in the city like halfway across.
Scott: I've seen them way upstate and way far away from any city bike.
Rym: We saw one Right next to the bike path that goes off from the main bike path to Tarrytown.
Scott: Everyone saw that same one.
Scott: it was sitting.
Rym: I was gonna like post it on reddit and I saw someone had already posted it and a bunch of people were posting like their Photos of it.
Rym: It might still be there and it's there to this day.
Rym: It could be so, uh There were two there and I learned today of a second way that that can happen.
Rym: because the first way that it was happening people was people would get one of those bikes out and then they would like stop riding and park it somewhere.
Rym: and because those bikes Are extremely expensive if you leave them somewhere like not moving for long enough.
Rym: They assume that you abandon them They lock themselves so you can't even roll them and any time you start rolling them that a little siren goes like we we we We we we we you and they call for help.
Rym: So the city bike people can go get them Like.
Rym: I don't know why people were like taking these things out and just like parking them somewhere cuz they will don't?
Scott: I mean people Don't you know?
Scott: read the thing?
Scott: It's just they do what they you know, as soon as you get the bike out of the dock It's like you can ride it freely.
Rym: It's like there's nothing to stop you right from like all the people we see getting on like the Staten Island ferry with them.
Scott: It's not like the bike yells at you and says hey, if you don't bring me back to a dock in one minute Yeah, I'm gonna get charged this much money.
Scott: It's like people, you know, and especially if it's not on your card or anything, you know, or you got the bike somehow else.
Scott: It's like, you know, just go people just go wild.
Scott: and if the bike, you know ends up somewhere else Yeah.
Rym: So yesterday at my way home from work I come out of work and I look and there's one e-bike available like right next to my office and it's one of the white ones.
Rym: so I go over.
Rym: they put my little key in and Instead of just unlocking immediately, which is how this system works It sits there blinking the yellow light for like 90 seconds And I don't walk away because what I know you can't do.
Scott: that That's the way that'd be the worst possible thing because you gotta wait for the red light and then take a different one.
Rym: So then the red light comes on and the bike pops out of the dock.
Scott: Oh That's a that's it.
Scott: I've never seen that happen.
Scott: That's the craziest bug I've ever seen right?
Rym: So, uh I take the bike and it works.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it's e-biking like.
Rym: it's totally.
Rym: it's working fine And I should.
Rym: I would have slammed it back in and I look at my app and the app says I did not check it out.
Scott: So yeah, that's why I would slam it back in because I have stolen this e-bike if I wanted to correct.
Rym: So I decide to see.
Rym: I bet it's gonna lock up on me and I just start biking home with it.
Rym: And it totally works.
Scott: lock up while you're riding.
Scott: So I don't think it would because of safety did.
Rym: it did lock up while I was riding.
Rym: Wow, interesting if they're stolen they lock up.
Rym: but the way it worked.
Rym: so I'm biking.
Rym: I didn't make it far.
Rym: I made it like a couple blocks and I was biking along a path where I knew there were a lot of docks Because I was confident this would happen.
Rym: I was just curious about it.
Rym: so I bike a little bit and then the city bike just starts making the siren sound while I'm biking and then It feels like the brakes were just very slowly engaged until it comes to a halt and then it's just stuck.
Rym: And I was about I don't know 50 yards away from a dock.
Rym: like I could see the dock, but then I realized I Can't drag it.
Rym: I can't push it to the dock because the wheels are locked up.
Scott: So pick it up So heavy.
Rym: I messaged city bike and I was like, hey, I got this bike out and it locked up on me.
Rym: I just played dumb.
Rym: and they respond immediately like oh, yeah, don't worry about it.
Rym: That happens.
Rym: Just leave it there.
Rym: We'll find it.
Rym: Okay, and I was like you're sure just leave it here like on the side of Lexington Avenue.
Rym: and they're like, yeah Don't worry about it.
Rym: And I was like, this is official I can just leave it here.
Rym: I will not be charged.
Scott: I didn't have a recording of this conversation or you're all good.
Rym: Yep I took like four screenshots of this conversation I had with that and then I left.
Scott: and that's my story because I mean if you lose the normal bike that does no Thousand bucks or something twelve hundred bucks.
Scott: if you write it's on your account and I can't imagine if you lose the white ebike Like and you don't get it back into a dock and it's missing on your account.
Scott: Imagine what they charge you five thousand.
Scott: I don't know right?
Rym: I don't ever want to find out.
Rym: but So yeah, I stole any bike and that's what I'm spending.
Scott: five thousand on a bike.
Scott: At least I want to have the bike.
Rym: a five thousand dollars won't even buy you a good mountain bike.
Scott: $5,000 will buy you an excellent bike of any kind.
Rym: It'll buy you know, it'll buy you an okay mountain bike or an excellent literally any other bike.
Scott: That's nonsense.
Scott: You can buy an excellent bike for five thousand dollars.
Rym: I've wrote I've ridden four and five thousand dollar mountain bikes, but I did ride an $11,000 mountain bike once and holy fuck was that fun?
Scott: Imagine there'd be that much difference.
Rym: Well, you know what the difference was.
Rym: the entire thing was carbon.
Rym: So despite being a mountain bike with a full suspension, it didn't weigh anything.
Rym: It had electronic shifters And the suspension was like drop 20 feet and you don't even feel it.
Rym: Anyway in some anime news, I got a geek bite animation news.
Rym: I got a geek bite because the Owl House the Disney show the fantasy horror comedy Fantastic show and I've talked about a few times in GeekNights.
Rym: We all know it got cancelled because Disney didn't really feel like it was part of their brand.
Rym: They had an executive shakeup and there was some drama about the fact that it was hard to push this show in Certain markets like China because of the heavy LGBT content in it.
Scott: So it's something only you know.
Scott: nerds cared about a lot of nerds, but it wasn't a mass popular thing.
Scott: Yeah, it's not in the public consciousness.
Rym: So I got cancelled but they did let them.
Rym: they couldn't make their third and final big season.
Rym: So instead they actually got the budget to make three Basically made for TV movies with pretty high budgets surprisingly.
Rym: Yeah We discussed how this has become a trend of some sort and they actually did the thing that very few people do correctly in that situation the in those three movies.
Rym: they Successfully in my opinion and now that I've seen all of the Owl House Holy and completely wrapped up the entire show every open question every loose thread in a surprisingly satisfying and meaningful way like I Can't imagine they could have wrapped it up better And in fact, it might have ended up been being better than what it would have been if it hadn't been cancelled because what happened Was I'm gonna go all the way back to an anime that I hope GeekNights listeners have watched.
Rym: I don't think we've talked about this in over a decade on the show But eska flown a a B plus or a minus tier anime of all time.
Rym: I'm not gonna say S tier is.
Rym: it's S tier in my heart But I'm not gonna say it's S tier on any other scale, but it's a good show.
Rym: one thing that made eska flown a notable was that it was supposed to be 52 episodes and For a bunch of reasons mostly around budgets it got cut to 26 episodes.
Rym: So what did they do?
Rym: after 13 episodes the next 13 episodes they just cut Everything all the filler but told the same story.
Rym: so this show accelerates all thriller no filler like to a degree that is shocking.
Rym: you go from Typical fantasy story with robots to what the fuck?
Rym: Why is Isaac Newton here?
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: They have nukes.
Scott: what's going on?
Rym: Yeah Spoilers on eska flown a and if I don't think that's really a spoiler cuz you're gonna watch You could watch 13 episodes of this show and think back to everything.
Rym: I just said and have no Possible conception of how I say Newton and nuclear weapons are ready.
Scott: It's a spoiler because in the show right spoilers, I guess also additional spoilers, right?
Scott: They from early on in the show.
Scott: They're referring to this mysterious enemy.
Scott: Who's like the big boss, right?
Rym: Assuming it's like a wizard like the wizard, right?
Scott: They're like, right It's sort of like, you know, there's a big bad guy named Isaac sort of like in Star Wars You know, there's a big bad guy who's just the Emperor.
Scott: and then eventually finally you see the Emperor, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, it's like ah There's a bad guy named Isaac and you don't think for a second.
Scott: that is Isaac Newton.
Scott: and then towards the end of the show They reveal the Isaac that's been the bad guy.
Rym: the whole time is Isaac and the reveal is so great because they're like It's Isaac Newton and you're like.
Rym: what?
Rym: like the guy?
Rym: Gravity calculus Apple guy that one and the show is like.
Rym: yes Exactly the show like it's like.
Rym: they just put it in impact font to just put it on the front of the screen.
Rym: Yes, it's Isaac Newton and then everything goes off the fucking rails from there.
Rym: the gravity guy that one anyway So the olives kind of does the same thing.
Rym: it's there is zero filler at all and they just follow the plot to the ultimate end.
Rym: and surprisingly the actual meta plot like what was going on is a Surprisingly complex like high fantasy story that was way bigger than I expected and pretty good.
Rym: So the show was fantastic.
Rym: the way it ended and I guess the things I would say about it without spoiling much is that one.
Rym: It does not do it Like.
Rym: it doesn't do the thing that a lot of shows like this have done throughout all of history Where they don't let main characters fully power up and they don't let main characters say fuck it I live in the fantasy world or why do I go back home?
Rym: Like isn't this place way better?
Rym: it avoids all those old boring tropes and just goes full-on in the right direction - they put in as much gay content as possible and they clearly made it so that it would be Almost impossible to edit out of the show.
Rym: and I think they did that on purpose to make it hard For Disney to put this show in certain markets Like they even had.
Scott: Disney could have always, you know, not let them continue or you know put in so yep They already had the budget.
Rym: So they just made the show and three it has.
Rym: you know, it's a kids show and it has the the meta plot of or the meta story.
Rym: if you should forgive people like Someone who's a bad person obviously circumstance led them to this.
Rym: you can't like you've got to stop their actions But you also have to understand why they're this way.
Rym: But it also goes a step further to point out that you only give someone so many chances and then You just don't give them any more chances and maybe you got to kill him.
Rym: Like maybe they just can't be allowed to continue to do their thing.
Scott: Yeah, it seems they still work.
Scott: Yeah, the out allows kind of ends with long as people have necks.
Rym: Yeah, the out allows kind of ends.
Rym: on a note of there is a line beyond which yeah guillotine time like Nuremberg trials And I was surprised that the show went that far and it does it in a really really good way in my opinion All right.
Scott: I mean I can appreciate that to some extent right, you know I've been realizing more recently like the past few years like all the arts that I enjoy at least fictional stories are the ones that Are.
Scott: you know abstract, you know challenging not having answers right being ambiguous, you know, whatever You know only asking questions not giving answers, right?
Scott: But if you're gonna be the kind of story that you know is giving answers Then you should be exactly what you just said giving all the answers not Lazily forgetting plot threads so that the people are like what about X character?
Scott: They just we just never saw them again.
Scott: Oh, yeah, what happened?
Rym: zero open questions of any Importance.
Scott: that's that's tight writing to remember everything to keep it all together, right?
Rym: But also the fact that the answers were all Satisfying and didn't feel like heck down at the end.
Rym: That's Yeah, it didn't even feel like fanservice.
Scott: It's tough to be.
Scott: if that's really a skilled writing technique is how do you be satisfying without being fanservice?
Rym: Yep, Picard season 3 was moderately satisfying but it was too much fanservice.
Rym: This somehow got that line, right and I struggle to think of many more examples of something that I would say struck that balance.
Scott: Yeah, the key to being satisfying without being fanservice right is fan service is giving people what they want and what they And what they want is also what they think they want, right?
Scott: Whereas not fanservice is giving something someone they wanted but they didn't know they wanted it and they didn't even conceive that it existed Right, but they're there.
Scott: it pleases them once you deliver it.
Scott: Yeah, that's the correct way.
Rym: like like What's not like evangelical parts of evangelical like.
Rym: oh, this is what you want here.
Rym: I'm gonna give you exactly what you want.
Rym: That sucks.
Rym: Doesn't it?
Rym: Guess what?
Rym: All right, so you got some news.
Scott: Just a tiny news, right?
Scott: We had Shin Godzilla came to to the US a long time ago, right and then there was the shin Ultraman Which I did manage to see.
Scott: did I actually talk about that on this show?
Scott: and I didn't see it.
Rym: really sure you did But I'd have to go look through the archive to be a hundred percent.
Scott: I mean, it's not as good as Shin Godzilla and it's better.
Scott: It's really, you know more geared towards people actually know things about Ultraman and care about Ultraman.
Rym: I think it did a full bite of it.
Scott: It's still okay.
Scott: But yeah, Shin Kamen Rider is coming now to the US a one-night nationwide screening in fathom events.
Scott: Yep, so the way that works technologically is fathom events.
Scott: basically live streams it but you can only watch the live stream from a movie theater.
Scott: There's no way to watch it from your house without extreme hacking Decryption and whatnot.
Scott: So The premiere is gonna be at the Japan Society here in New York City.
Rym: I already bought a ticket So I have to confirm exactly because I got to go to Colorado for my cousin's wedding.
Rym: So I might be a bit home in time to see it.
Rym: But if I am I'll be like landing from Colorado that morning, but in that case in which case I'm gonna get a ticket.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is my knowledge of Kamen Rider is you know, very basic level knowledge, right?
Scott: So, you know hero guy on a motorcycle looks like a bug has like a watch or a belt or something that transforms him.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I don't even care.
Rym: I would go I would go see this and I think you should do.
Scott: if you're out there and you you have The opportunity and it's like even though, you know, Shin Ultraman was you know, okay, but not up to my I guess You know, I don't know what expectation I had.
Scott: But even if this is you know, if this is as good as Shin Ultraman I won't feel bad about going to see it.
Rym: Ah but anyway things of the day.
Rym: so, uh Scott and I are actually compared to the ad that what I assume is the mean age of the listener.
Rym: I Feel like we're pretty old.
Rym: so This is gonna definitely cement in anyone's mind exactly how old we are because this is a YouTube video.
Rym: it's only two minutes long and it steps through a Full example of what every type of modem sounded like from the 300 baud era up to the 56k era.
Rym: and if you don't know what a modem is then that's not even how badly we're gonna date ourselves, but This hit me so hard in the nostalgia.
Rym: So, uh, my first modem was a 2400 baud modem and I kind of forgot what it sounded like because in my head like in my mind, I realized I only remembered what 33 6 and 56 K modems sounded like to a 2400 baud sounds way different.
Rym: But as soon as I heard it You know that phenomenon.
Rym: we like you can't remember the name of something and someone says the first syllable of it and your brains like Oh, I remember now it was that Memories of childhood came flooding back and I he actually had the 14 for modem.
Scott: We didn't actually use it right away.
Scott: we had the computer we had the modem But we didn't have.
Scott: we weren't using it right and then eventually, you know, we got it.
Scott: We started using it.
Scott: We started using it when everyone else is buying 28 8 modems.
Scott: Yeah 14.
Rym: So 2400 baud was a v22.
Rym: that was like 1982. you're 14 for there was that.
Rym: that was the second like class v32.
Rym: That was 9.6 and 14 for they're basically the same kind of modem.
Scott: Yep But yeah, and then I bought a USB 56 K modem and like 1999 that was all cool and transparent.
Rym: I Never stick on it in my life had or used a 56 K modem because he's it's K Modem could play tribes to online with a bad Like a 300 ping but it worked.
Scott: it worked Tribes - is surprisingly resilient to bad things.
Scott: Yep, I bought an Ethernet card and went to college.
Rym: see so 3028 8 and 33 6 came out in 1994 and in 1994 we got a v34 modem to do that and I use that up until like 1996. and then we got a cable modem because the pilot program was in our neighborhood.
Rym: So never had 56 K. I had broadband in 19 late 1996.
Scott: So my thing of the day is a website called make it from comm right and let's say that you're some sort of engineer or Manufacturer or something and you you know, you need to.
Scott: you need to choose a material to make something out of right?
Scott: it's like well this website has a database of materials right and Publicly collected public data about the material property, you know the properties of those materials, right?
Scott: So for example, let's see magnesium alloys.
Scott: I'm clicking on magnesium alloy a z9 1d and we can see it's Brunel hardness.
Scott: It's compressive crushing strength.
Scott: It's Young's tensile modulus.
Scott: It's elongation at break its impact strength.
Scott: It's thermal properties electrical properties.
Scott: it's otherwise unclassified property is like it's base metal price and Etc, etc.
Scott: It's composition mostly magnesium with a little bit of aluminum and then some really tiny amounts of zinc manganese silicon, etc.
Scott: right and you can see this for a bunch of materials and you can compare the materials to each other and Make your choice about what you're gonna, you know Choose embodied energy.
Rym: embodied energy is a measure of the amount of electrical energy consumed.
Rym: It just tells you everything and it defines everything.
Scott: They collected all this data from public places and compiled it onto a text easy to use good UI website.
Scott: That is extremely useful if you do anything with metal ceramic plastic, etc.
Scott: I'm gonna say right now.
Rym: This is web 4.0 back to 1.0 but with modern technology.
Scott: just here's the This website plain text sports.
Scott: This is how this is the direct direction to go in.
Rym: I think I think it is the right direction.
Rym: Like I'm dead.
Rym: This is not a joke.
Scott: We're dead serious about this old but websites had it right from the beginning.
Rym: Yep Web 2.0 was an experiment.
Rym: odd If you don't know what web 2.0 is because that's actually a long time ago.
Rym: Look at the current gig nights website From 2020 from May 2023.
Rym: I got to clarify cuz that might change in the near future But I miss that wet internet.
Scott: If you ever ask yourself the question, what should I make it from?
Scott: go to make it from dot-com?
Rym: In the moment the geek dies book club book the satanic versus the next Thursday show.
Rym: we're just doing it.
Rym: We're done with the book.
Rym: It's a great finish reading every verse that Satan had to offer and I I thoroughly enjoyed the satanic verses.
Rym: And you know, I will admit Having not known a lot about the book.
Rym: when we came into this book club I thought I knew the meta around the book.
Rym: anything about the kind imagined it would be like reading any Classic important book in that I would enjoy it and I'd think a lot.
Rym: But I'd also have to approach it from like a. I am analyzing this as I read your perspective.
Rym: No, it's just a fucking fantasy book.
Rym: I just read it like a fantasy book and it was fantastic as a fantasy book.
Rym: It's just Just cry me the allegory is there.
Rym: it's deep.
Rym: It's dense.
Rym: But I think the thing that stood out the most And we'll get into the met.
Rym: you know the actual show when we do the book club episode was that it was one of those books and I like it when this happens to me where I'd be reading and I'm go Vibing going along and then the book would throw something at me and I get like half a paragraph past it.
Rym: Then I'd pause but wait a minute.
Rym: What the fuck just happened and I back up.
Rym: cuz something crazy just happened and I had to back up and like be ready for it.
Rym: Mm-hmm that happened a bunch of times in this book and it was great.
Scott: So I mean even chat like the first chapter is like what's happening.
Scott: Yeah, what that's what's happening.
Rym: What?
Rym: and then you dive into Movie star.
Rym: You do die die and then you dive again.
Rym: Just keep diving Let's make gods.
Rym: So, uh other met a bit.
Rym: so you're all aware I'm gonna link to a thread in the GeekNights forum which you should join partly because Twitter is a dying husk of its former self and I barely use social media anymore and I'm Diving back into forums and discords and you know all that other stuff.
Rym: So in the in this thread I have posted many examples of the new thumbnails that I've been creating for GeekNights stuff and I've got a lot of good feedback from the listener.
Rym: and I've been making them better and better Because it's literally driving traffic to our old lectures that people forgot about in a surprising way.
Rym: So I'm just gonna keep doing it.
Scott: All right GeekNights' website is a Polish.
Scott: at least there are some features we should.
Scott: you know how gonna have to do after releasing but I want to basically only narrow down to the things that are required for releasing only and we just got to do those and we can release and replace the old website and then We can go and do all those other things after and it'll be fine.
Rym: Yep And at some point around the launch of the new gig nights website I'm gonna do it even if Scott doesn't know how to do.
Rym: it Was gonna throw at probably a bar or restaurant or beer garden somewhere in Queens.
Rym: It's gonna throw a no-host party meeting.
Rym: We're gonna celebrate the new website and if anyone like open invite for anyone to show up.
Rym: you're paying for your own whatever's.
Rym: I'm just gonna be there.
Rym: I'm not coordinating anything other than I will be there.
Scott: I See, that's what you mean by no host.
Scott: Like you're not gonna call the place You're just gonna be like I am going to be at this place.
Scott: That is a public.
Rym: from this hour to this hour.
Rym: It is public.
Rym: It's open seating.
Rym: It's not gonna be like a restaurant.
Rym: We're like, oh, hey, I see you from the table that I got from the waiter.
Rym: get your own.
Scott: Why don't we go to since it's all warm place?
Rym: You're proud of the?
Scott: Well, you go there.
Scott: you can get like one of the big barbecue places They all have.
Rym: yeah John Brown's actually would be a good one.
Rym: with that huge outdoor area in the back.
Scott: the big beach is like three John Brown.
Rym: But but John Brown's isn't that crowded?
Rym: especially?
Rym: do this on like any day that's not a Friday night Saturday night.
Scott: Yeah, I mean Pig Beach is not crowded on a weekday.
Rym: Exactly So.
Rym: I'll post details as it comes but I'll make a thread because if you're interested, let me know.
Rym: I'm just curious.
Rym: It would be nice to see the listener who lives like somewhere in the area the one listening.
Rym: if If you're that's it.
Rym: that's our joke.
Rym: calling the listener for humble Gregory's all.
Scott: the joke though from some podcast.
Rym: Yes, I was about to say Because I there's a job is gonna steal a joke from the Simpsons about this or a crush.
Rym: He's like if your name's anyone but bad then I stole this.
Rym: then this is my bit.
Rym: But I stole that joke from it's all politics from NPR podcasts.
Scott: Does that podcast still exist?
Rym: It does but with different hosts and a slightly different name and they they got rid of the joke.
Rym: They don't make that joke anymore.
Scott: No, it's ours now.
Rym: It's ours now If we can get right into it.
Scott: so, uh, Susan may Alright, so background info right.
Scott: Makoto shinkai.
Scott: This is if you don't remember this person.
Scott: back in the early 2000s Makoto shinkai made short animations in his basement By himself possibly with his spouse partner.
Rym: Yep in the 90s There were a couple of really small short films But the one that you all know was voices of a distant star Hoshino Koei.
Rym: in The first time we ever saw anything by you know Makoto We were in college and there was this buzz about this short thing and someone fans up did.
Scott: it was like five minutes over ten.
Scott: I know how long.
Scott: it's not very long.
Scott: It's very short.
Scott: They played it at the anime club.
Scott: Everyone was blown away by this very short anime like people were like everybody was crying Yeah, and everyone was like someone made that in their basement by themselves and they even voice acted at themselves.
Scott: But then the voice acting got replaced by professionals later.
Scott: Yeah, it's like oh and it's like that was one person doing holy.
Scott: Everyone is losing their mind over this thing.
Scott: And then we waited to see what Makoto shinkai would do next and and it was a guy Ritchie situation.
Rym: Makoto shinkai is good at longing at Will they won't they?
Rym: at?
Rym: cherry blossoms falling at Spectacular clouds and sky scapes and rainbows and sparkles.
Rym: Yep, and maybe you cry.
Scott: the first time I saw another Makoto shinkai work after.
Rym: that was what plays Promised promised in her early days, which for a long time was my second favorite of his works.
Rym: I like it.
Rym: It's kind of weird, but it made me cry even harder than Hoshi no Koi.
Scott: I mean sure it's like, you know but he wasn't.
Scott: it wasn't like some of the other people.
Scott: where it's like everything he makes is like a Unmitigated hit right?
Scott: It's like you can you know, it's just like, you know, sometimes things were a bit off.
Scott: What's the?
Scott: was children to chase laws voices?
Scott: Was that the one that I saw in New York New York comic-con?
Rym: That was the one that was like, I don't know a low-rent.
Scott: I couldn't understand what the hell was going on with that one.
Rym: It was low-rent Laputa.
Scott: The plot didn't make much, but I remember the character New York comic-con.
Scott: It was enormous screening.
Scott: He was there.
Scott: It's the first time we saw him in person.
Scott: And yeah, that movie is like what the fuck it was beautiful.
Scott: Sure, everything he does is beautiful.
Scott: Yeah, is you know, the most beautiful Makoto shinkai works are his commercials.
Scott: Oh, all right Go look on YouTube from Makoto shinkai TV commercials.
Scott: They are unbelievable.
Rym: Yep Then there was enemies per second.
Scott: Yeah, the point is it?
Scott: no Makoto shinkai was sort of you know He was successful enough that he kept making movies, but he didn't really come until your name right.
Scott: your name?
Scott: Is it like the the still the most grossing animated thing ever or like it's enormous, right?
Scott: It has like some enormous record.
Rym: I'm looking to see what the Japanese box office.
Scott: for 12 non-consecutive weekends It grossed twenty five point seventeen billion yen The highest grossing non Hollywood film in China up until two Indian movies Displaced it right.
Scott: So your name was just absolutely.
Scott: Did we do an episode here?
Rym: We had to have.
Rym: it was number one in South Korea.
Rym: It was number one in Thailand.
Rym: like it.
Scott: This was like one of the biggest movies ever Now one of the biggest movies ever one of the biggest animated movies ever period.
Scott: so that's like boom.
Scott: then weathering with you We did an episode on that one.
Scott: I was disappointed in weathering with you mostly, you know for several reasons the message.
Rym: I don't.
Rym: I disagreed with what appeared to be the message of it honest.
Scott: Yes Like there are many good parts of it, but I agree Rym the biggest bad part was the message.
Scott: the message was Humans will find a way to survive.
Scott: don't bother trying to fix you.
Rym: don't sacrifice your own happiness to prevent climate change.
Scott: right because humans will find a way to survive even if this terrible climate disaster and it's like That's the wrong message by a lot.
Scott: So it comes up with another movie and all we know about this movie going in is it's another.
Scott: Makoto Shinkai joint and two It's one of the characters turns into a chair a literal chair made of wood.
Scott: the thing you sit on a Small one that a child would sit on like that would go at a child's desk like a tiny one.
Scott: Yeah right a character a human is transformed magically into a Piece of furniture that a child would sit on.
Scott: and that's the two things, you know about this movie going in.
Scott: And I'm like, well Makoto Shinkai is coming to the museum near me for the East Coast premiere.
Scott: Whatever, right?
Scott: I'll go see it and I'll see what he's got to say now.
Scott: I haven't seen this guy in ten years plus, right?
Scott: We'll see what's going on.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: Honestly, it was pretty great.
Rym: Like I think it's one of his best works.
Scott: Also, I get actually like it better than your name.
Rym: I also like it better than your name.
Rym: I see what like.
Rym: I see Why your name would probably be seen by many film people as a better constructed movie.
Scott: I think you might have just.
Scott: I also highly suspect it could have been a timing issue If this had come out when your name came out and your name came out Now would the would the box office grosses have just been reversed?
Rym: It's hard to say like I. actually I would struggle to take a strong stance on that question.
Rym: And also it's doing great.
Rym: It is already itself the fourth highest grossing Japanese film of all time.
Scott: Yep, I think the one thing that might keep it that might hurt it at the box office compared to your name Is that it's a little bit Japanese centric, right?
Scott: Your name is sort of universal.
Rym: So there's a lot going on here.
Rym: at the end We're gonna talk about some of the spoilery things.
Rym: cuz one just go see this movie like.
Scott: it's not really a spoilery kind of movie But it's not like.
Scott: there's nothing.
Scott: there's no surprise or a secret that's revealed or anything like that.
Scott: It's just you know, it's about character development.
Rym: Yeah, there's a few things.
Rym: I don't even any really any major events in the movie, but there are a few things I wouldn't really want.
Rym: I think it would be better for people to not know going in but we'll get to that at the end.
Rym: like but what I Would say is one.
Rym: it's great.
Rym: But - you know what it is.
Rym: It's a road trip movie.
Rym: This is about people going on a road trip to process trauma from their past.
Scott: That's correct.
Rym: That's what this movie is And it's it does it and it so well and the characters are To.
Rym: every single character in the show is a fantastic character.
Scott: Yeah, I think some of the characters were sort of thrown in not fully developed or necessary, but they were still.
Scott: I still enjoyed them.
Scott: So I guess they could.
Scott: they had purpose in that like for the best example, obviously is you know The show idle music right car, right?
Scott: It's like we did that like that guy sort of came in in The like way late in the movie to introduce a character with speaking lines, right?
Scott: Pretty much And it wasn't that significant and you probably could have had the movie without him.
Scott: like it sort of felt a little bit awkward like but at Sort of worked because he was not awkward just to the audience showing up late.
Scott: But that's his relationship with the main character is like an awkward guy who shows up late Yeah, and at a weird time.
Scott: and but he was a very enjoyable character, you know Cuz he was sort of you know, like that wacky side character almost right?
Scott: He was a lot of fun But you know, he could have not been there and it would have still been fine.
Rym: Yeah so and the I guess the other main thing that I think really made this stand out is that And Makoto Shinkai did this was your name too.
Rym: in that in your name, you know There's magic key stuff happening and it is literally happening.
Rym: The movie makes it quite abundant.
Rym: That's not like allegory.
Rym: I mean it is allegory, but it also literally directly happened.
Rym: like characters Remember the specifics of the magic that happened.
Rym: It is real.
Rym: this movie does the same thing.
Rym: There's a moment where the characters who have not been involved in the magic BS Encounter the magic BS and their response is whoa, there's some magic BS going on Mm-hmm, and I think the message of this one like unlike weathering with you was also good.
Rym: I think it was actually a new.
Scott: yes this had the message.
Scott: Yes good.
Rym: No, and it was multiple messages.
Rym: there were messages about unpacking trauma and facing trauma messages about like Talking to family and talking to people and making human connections.
Rym: But there was also messages about if there's a problem go deal with it, which was kind of the opposite message of weathering with you.
Rym: I'm comparing the two a lot because I do feel like this was.
Scott: I don't know if you With you that much you can't get away from.
Scott: yeah but I almost said that's a that's a Rym thing.
Scott: Rym find Rym will find a thing and have a have a Criticism of it and then just keep bringing it up cuz things get stuck in my craw and whether it's right It's in your craw and it never gets it bother.
Rym: it specially bothered me because since weathering with you came out Like a lot of things in the real world have gotten worse and worse and worse in a way that people need to make sacrifices to try to stop.
Scott: Yep, but it's like basically any time weathering with you comes up or any time something reminds Rym of weathering with you It'll pop out of his craw and have like oh the message of that movie.
Scott: I hated it for this.
Scott: Yeah, I forgot that was in my craw But it came back out and it's like everyone's already heard you say that the last time it popped out of the crock.
Rym: So what is this actually about?
Rym: like really like.
Rym: it's a road trip movie But basically this girl and it gets right to the point This movie does not belabor getting to the magic.
Scott: nice girl's only remaining family is her aunt and she lives with her aunt and goes To school as a teenage dish like young teen.
Scott: How old is she?
Scott: like 14 13 17 high school I don't know.
Scott: She's she's teenage aged right and she lives with her aunt only.
Rym: Yep And like in school cool meets a weird guy who's clearly up to something in a anime magical way Interacts with him briefly, but then just continues on to school and then at school and the guy has something weird He's like hey, is there any?
Rym: Abandoned ruins around here and she's like, yeah that way weird question to ask but whatever.
Rym: and then she goes to school And there's kind of an earthquake and then she sees a bunch of magical shit happening off in the distance in the direction of the ruin, she pointed the weird guy at and nobody else can see this biz and she's like Fuck school.
Rym: I'm gonna immediately go look into this.
Rym: which is the correct thing to do?
Scott: Yes, or unless you're actually hallucinating in which case would be the wrong thing to do?
Rym: Well, I would do one of two things.
Scott: I would either a good thing that within the world of the movie She wasn't hallucinating and the magic was real.
Rym: I'll tell you what.
Rym: I would go and check it out And if there was nothing weird going on there, I would immediately go straight to the doctor.
Scott: What if you went there and you were still hallucinating the shit?
Scott: How would you know it was real or not if the hallucination were that self-consistent?
Rym: I'm fucked anyway.
Scott: Yeah, the point is the moving chair sort of confirmed, right?
Rym: See the moving chair like people are basically like posting on Twitter Like I saw a fucking moving chair and like she sees it everywhere, right?
Scott: The guy was fighting the evils that are underneath the earth that are coming and causing disaster through these magic doors.
Rym: There's a whole like mad magical plot and he's got.
Scott: he's got to make sure the doors stay closed and whatnot, you know and sealed yeah, and He gets turned into a chair because she does something, you know She messes around with the keystone or whatever.
Scott: when she should have she.
Rym: basically she picks up a rock That's kind of shaped like a cat and she's like wonder what this is and then it thaws.
Rym: This all happens like the first six minutes of the movie.
Rym: Yeah, it like thaws and turns into a magic looking cat that says cryptic stuff and runs away and then all hell breaks loose.
Rym: and Then the magic guys like what the fuck did you do?
Scott: Yeah, you fucked up the magic and now the evils coming out.
Scott: It's your fault Oh, but I got turned into a chair.
Scott: So now you have to fix it.
Scott: I can't fix it.
Scott: I'm a chair.
Rym: So now it's a road trip.
Rym: try even though I'm a chair and then the the magic cat Runs off and gets on a ferry and then the chairs like we got to do something about this show.
Rym: She grabs the chair and the two of them run onto the ferry and then the ferry basically goes like Four hours away like it goes way where it becomes.
Scott: it's like in the one end is a road trip But on the other hand, it's a chase right?
Scott: It's like the.
Scott: you know her and the chair.
Scott: Well, she's chasing the cat and she's carrying the chair.
Scott: The chair is also chasing the out but it's a chair.
Rym: It's a guy It's and she very smartly is like you're a chair.
Rym: What the fuck are you gonna do?
Scott: Right.
Rym: So because she's not lucid she's going for and then the ant is worried Which is this is why it's such a road trip movie because she calls her on late at night on the ferry.
Rym: She's like, yeah, I'm like staying over at so-and-so's house.
Rym: I'll be back tomorrow.
Rym: And then the next day she wakes up like a hundred miles away from home like and then Doesn't make it home that night and she calls her on like that night's like yeah Not gonna make it home again.
Rym: and then it's like where are you?
Rym: and there's this great scene?
Rym: Where she like cuz this keeps happening to the point where the on acts like a normal adult and it's like you get your ass Home right now or like I'm coming after you.
Rym: What's wrong?
Rym: Yeah and then she like sends his long text to the aunt and then she's like turns the phone off.
Rym: like doesn't want to deal with it.
Rym: and later on like she opens the phone and there is like a 400 line text waiting for her and she's reading it like oh my god.
Rym: And before she could even begin to respond another 400 line text like appears from the aunt and she's just like oh shit And there's lots of just fun moments like that.
Rym: all the characters act like they live in the modern world where cell phones and reddit and Twitter and things exist and It's just a very like modern sense, but it's not.
Scott: yeah, it's not but it's not like, you know Bell where it's about the internet It's just it's a very much takes place like in the real world.
Scott: People have modern technology because it's taking place in 20 22 3 whatever year.
Rym: Yep so and yeah Yeah the movie just keeps going from there and it.
Rym: so the
Scott: Chair thing seems like so ridiculous from the trailer or from just hearing that that a guy turns into a chair But when you see the movie first of all He's not a chair actually for you know is a chair for a smaller portion of the movie than you think But
Rym: it is still like a good chunk of the movie.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's you know a big chunk, but it's less than he turns on chairs at some point, right?
Rym: Yeah, well cuz really it's not about him.
Rym: It's about the girl and her aunt's exactly But it's less.
Scott: It's a lot less silly in context.
Scott: Obviously.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: It's not it's not.
Scott: it don't go in thinking It's some nonsense thing.
Rym: It's yep.
Scott: And and what there has as a meaning?
Rym: there's a reason it's a chair the chair has a Literal plot reason that literally it has to be a chair and it also has a very profound allegorical reason that it's a chair and it's also a. Well, we talked about this when we were.
Rym: there was a news about how he said he made the director.
Rym: She think I said he made it news.
Scott: that news was slightly different from what he said when I saw y'all.
Rym: So it's and he said slightly different things every time he's talked about it And actually read a ton more interviews since then.
Rym: so I guess I'll address it now.
Rym: My personal best summary based on reading four different interviews where he explained this different ways through translation.
Rym: so like take this with a pretty good chunk of salt is The producer told him you've got to have a romantic interest.
Rym: You can't just make the other character a girl which obviously that's a can of worms.
Rym: But shinkai was like but I don't want to do a romance and the producer kind of forced him to.
Rym: So he was like I got to make it something else and he thought about making it like the guy gets turned into a monster Or the guy gets turned into like random objects as they move along.
Rym: anything to make him not a hot boy.
Rym: So there isn't romantic tension during the story because he didn't want that to happen.
Rym: He did not want to distract from the story of the girl and her aunt with a will.
Rym: they won't they romance?
Rym: and he?
Rym: Settled on a chair and then he came up with a really good reason why it had to be a chair.
Rym: and if you didn't Know that back story if you've never read one of those articles or heard any of those interviews You would think it was a chair from day one because the chair is crucial to everything This movie is about in profound Direct ways.
Rym: I would have been.
Rym: I would be surprised if I learned after seeing it that The chair was because of all these other reasons.
Scott: So the vibe I got when we saw him in person didn't they?
Scott: obviously through a translator?
Scott: He yeah, he spoke to us right was that you know he had all he has the signature thing He always does clouds romance lover separated by space and time.
Scott: every single one of these movies every single one of his works Except maybe some TV commercials even some of those have it right.
Scott: it's like and he like Didn't want to do what he's always done.
Rym: He wanted to do something you want to do clouds Family trauma and family like stop.
Scott: I don't know if you want.
Scott: I don't even know if you want to do the clouds But they want to do the clouds heat.
Scott: He said that the producer You know was like listen.
Scott: I know you want to do something different, but it's like.
Scott: this is what you're known for.
Scott: You're good at it.
Scott: That's what's successful.
Scott: This is still capitalism.
Rym: It's telling that every single movie poster shows the girl and the guy in non-chair form like standing next to each other in some fashion.
Scott: Yeah, he's like.
Scott: you still have to include that to some extent and so he included those his trademark things To basically this minimal extent to where you know his stamp is on it.
Scott: You can tell immediately that this is a shinkai work.
Scott: But you it is not the focus of the work the way it is in a lot of the others, right?
Scott: It's just sort of off to the side and is not center stage.
Scott: It's like side stage.
Scott: And the other things he interestingly said.
Scott: the biggest interesting thing he said when he spoke was that You know back that we talked about for Hokushino Koei.
Scott: He made it like in his basement by himself, right?
Scott: mostly He said that basic.
Scott: the way he made this is the way he makes everything.
Scott: is he?
Scott: Storyboarded the whole thing in his basement or wherever his studio in his house by himself, right?
Scott: He voice acted.
Scott: every character recorded it at home With his own microphone by himself, right?
Scott: And basically once he had a storyboard with everything voice acted for the whole movie and it was all done Which took like two years?
Scott: Then he brings in the whole animation studio Right with everyone else and they make the real movie from that.
Scott: so he still does it that way.
Scott: Nobody else does it that way.
Scott: that I'm aware of and at least not for movies not even not for TV episodes either.
Scott: so That's wild.
Scott: Yeah, that he still does that And somehow gets away with it, but I guess they don't want to mess with success.
Rym: So they let it keep going and What else could we say other than doing a very long like final thoughts style?
Rym: Like let's dive into all the allegory dude I feel.
Scott: the only other thing I would say is that compared to his other movies Which I think some of the other ones had parts that didn't make sense didn't fit together.
Scott: We're a little bit nonsensical We're a bit a little bit muddy and he could have used a lot of editing, right?
Scott: This one did not need as the editing so much.
Scott: It was very well put together, you know tightly structured Well paced except for maybe a little part when then towards the end, but not really.
Scott: so he's definitely his most well structured.
Rym: Uh, I mean the movie is a hundred and twenty two minutes like it's long But I had no point was I Only?
Rym: I looked at my watch once the movie just washed over me to the end and I didn't realize how long it was until Like we walked out of the theater and I was like, wait a minute.
Scott: It is long for an animated movie.
Rym: So yeah, thankfully we saw it at the Alamo Drafthouse in Manhattan, which I didn't realize was in the Sub sub sub basement of like 28 Liberty down there.
Rym: It's way deep.
Scott: I Gonna go to the movie theater.
Rym: I could walk to us but uh The I guess the last thing I would say is that what the movie is about cuz on one hand it is about The.
Rym: you know, it's about the magical stuff like that literally happens.
Scott: It's about the earthquake.
Rym: Yeah, it's about the the earthquake that caused the Fukushima disaster.
Rym: like Directly in the plot but allegorically it's.
Rym: it uses.
Rym: it almost uses the allegory of the girl and her aunt Dealing with their shared trauma but also society collectively dealing with its shared trauma of what happened.
Rym: because like where her childhood home that was destroyed was is Directly relevant.
Rym: and Ching Kai has talked a lot about how the 2011 earthquake Affected him and how it was a big part of the inspiration for this movie.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, well, that's I think that's the thing that all happens.
Scott: Is that anytime there's a major human event positive or negative but sadly especially the negative ones right that immediately?
Scott: Sort of causes, you know artists filmmakers writers, right?
Scott: It's like, you know You could go cause a disaster on purpose or or what happens by accident and if anything is significant If it's remembered if it makes the news there's gonna be books about it.
Scott: This might be a documentary.
Rym: I mean, there's still like World War two movies are still very very common in the year 20.
Scott: the bigger the bigger the event the bigger the the more art it spawns.
Scott: right World War two was so big that the art Will probably never stop coming As long as they're just still people alive who as long as the thing that got everyone to forget about World War one doesn't happen.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, it's like so that that earthquake, you know, it's like the timing of it, right It's like if you would have come out with this movie too soon after the earthquake.
Scott: You're in that sort of depending on the tone of your artwork that goes to a disaster.
Scott: You sort of have to work on your timing.
Scott: Yeah, so you can't.
Scott: you can't come out with an animated movie about an earthquake, you know immediately after the earthquake You got to put some space between it, right?
Rym: I think that space was extra important for this movie because the movie was also.
Rym: it wasn't just about unpacking trauma.
Rym: It was about unpacking Distant trauma like the main character.
Rym: She's unpacking trauma from.
Rym: you know, she's 17 from like 10 12 years ago.
Scott: Yep, well, I think that's the one thing he still kept in in, you know, the lovers in this movie They were not separated by space and time.
Scott: They were separated by one of them being a chair But the there was still a separation right between you know The the horrific events of the past and you know The main character.
Scott: time wise right a time separation and a space separation Which she closes and the time separation which you know is Expanding.
Scott: right.
Scott: and it's different where when you have the lovers who are separated They're trying to connect and reach out to each other right over a long distance Whereas here it's like when it's a trauma you're trying to get away from
Rym: And by trying to get away from it You end up heading straight toward it and then because magic stuff you get a little bit of a time a time loop type situation with the magic.
Scott: Yeah, I Thoroughly enjoyed this movie and of course, yeah, I wouldn't say I wouldn't say that this is like some s-tier anime, right?
Scott: But I would still say that like, you know, are you gonna see anime movies that came out this year?
Scott: It's like or you know, I guess within the past year.
Scott: It's or whatever.
Scott: I don't know when it actually came out in Japan, but You know, it's.
Scott: I guess it's the same.
Scott: as you know, is it better than Bell?
Scott: That's a close race.
Scott: That's okay, right?
Rym: It's like, you know, I think part of what's going on here is because Hosoda and Shinkai are both Younger creators who are creating more modern work younger.
Scott: They're like, they're still.
Rym: yeah they are but think about the vibe of both of them and their movies.
Rym: like technologies use the way young people actually use it.
Rym: the world and the plot exists in a modern like Setting and it's.
Rym: it's not like a lot of older.
Rym: older filmmakers will make a movie set in current day current time But like nobody has cell phones for some reason like that's still happening.
Rym: Shinkai Shinkai is 50 and Hosoda is 55 But the movies still speak to a younger more modern sensibility in a very direct way.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights Are Ellen Joyce when kiji dread lily tennifer case care makes music Kristin odd Clinton Walton decks Finn Joel Hayes Penny Reimer Rebecca Dunn Sam Erickson Sherman von Harl and a ton of people whose names I will not say at their request.
Rym: so, uh, you probably should have seen what's about to Assault your ears coming, but I'll be surprised if you didn't.
Rym: so This is your last chance to stop listening before I play the thing that you really should be expecting and now I Leave you with the sounds of my childhood.