Rym: It's Wednesday, April 6th, 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I am the Scott.
Rym: And this is The GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we're talking about the Phoenix Wright anime, Ace Attorney.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, I do not like people who vape or vape pens or any of that crap.
Rym: Like, I'm glad you're smoking that instead of a cigarette, but I still don't want you smoking it around me.
Scott: I still don't want you smoking.
Scott: I mean, I don't want you smoking anything because, I mean, perhaps it may be less poison than tobacco.
Rym: Oh, you know what?
Rym: I don't even care.
Rym: It smells just as bad as cigarettes.
Rym: It just takes longer to build up.
Scott: I also don't want anyone poisoning themselves to any degree of poisoning.
Scott: And, but, the one thing I am thankful for is that people who vape, people who smoke, it's like they're trying to let it go away and smoke.
Scott: At least that they're polite, right?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: But people who vape, like, they seem to, like, want to show off that they vape, so it's sort of...
Rym: I've only seen that at conventions and bars where, like, basically the shitlords who used to pick up girls by, like, "Hey, you wanna have a
Rym: smoke?".
Scott: Well, I think it's also partially because vaping is a newer thing, so it stands out just on its own even if you're not trying to make it stand out.
Scott: So, it's actually, whereas, like, someone smoking a cigarette could be more inconspicuous just because it's more common.
Rym: True, but in both cases, I've found that while there are people in the world who are not annoying and/or shitlords who smoke or vape, it's a pretty good, like, easy filter of which humans to talk to at any given event.
Scott: But that's what I'm saying, is that vaping at least is beneficial in that it is, like, "Well, there's a person that is a bad person.
Scott: I see him from a mile
Scott: away.".
Rym: So, anyway, I got a coworker who vapes, but, you know, he doesn't do it in the office because, of course, everyone complained.
Scott: He tried to do it in the office?
Rym: Yeah, he just did it.
Rym: He wasn't immediately fired?
Rym: No, HR was like, "No, you can't do that," and that was the end of that.
Scott: Well, it wasn't HR, like, "You're fired.
Scott: Don't come back
Scott: ever.".
Rym: But, I know he vapes in the bathroom because it smells like vape juice in there, and that's the building's responsibility.
Rym: So, a couple days ago, there's a no smoking sign because there's already, like, people smoke in every nook and cranny of this giant building.
Scott: No, but not in my building.
Scott: Yeah, well, this building is a multi-- I mean, and that's not a fair thing to say because the building I'm in now only has two tenants, one of which is us.
Scott: Yeah, the same multi-tenant building.
Scott: The building I was in previously had a bunch of tenants, didn't have all these empty floors.
Scott: So, Scott, this building has-- There was no smoking in that building.
Rym: One, this is a giant building.
Scott: It's really big.
Scott: How many floors?
Rym: Like, 30?
Scott: Okay, that's twice as big as the buildings I'm in.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, we're on the 16th floor, so I have to use the local elevator.
Scott: We're on the 8th and 9th floors.
Scott: Which sucks because some, like-- We're on the 8th and 9th floors, but there's only-- the 11th floor is the penthouse.
Rym: Some kind of media startup that they look and act like College Humor or Cracked or one of those kinds of places, but they took over, like, the entire 13th floor and a bunch of, like, the 17th and 19th floors.
Rym: So now, when I'm trying to use the elevator, it'll come to my floor already full of these, like, late 20s--.
Rym: Basically, they look like me, but they're all working for a thing that sounds like and acts like College Humor, going between all these floors, getting in my way as the elevators fall.
Rym: And they have the most vapid conversations possible, but I won't complain about that because that makes me an old man.
Rym: I don't care.
Rym: But they do have really vapid conversations, but I digress.
Rym: There's stairways all over, connecting all the floors and everything.
Scott: Which you use instead.
Rym: I do.
Rym: Well, I stopped using the stairways because they are so full of cigarette butts and ashes and, like, shitheads actually smoking in there.
Scott: And the building, like-- The stairwells in my buildings that I've been in, the previous one and the current one, have been completely empty except for the people who are basically fit enough or really want to use the stairs because-- I want
Rym: to use the stairs to go up, but everything's locked, so I can't.
Rym: I can only use them to go down.
Scott: We can use them to go every which way.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's about the bigger a building and the more tenants there are, the less access you actually have to the building.
Rym: So earlier this week, there's a no smoking sign in the bathroom, because there's no smoking sign fucking everywhere in this building, because they know it's a problem.
Rym: A paper sign appeared under that that was like, "No electronic cigarettes in the
Rym: bathroom.".
Rym: And I was like, "Huh, that's
Rym: funny.".
Rym: The next day, someone had ripped that sign down.
Rym: I wonder who ripped it down.
Rym: So I await with glee the passive aggressive war that's going to be waged on my floor of this building.
Scott: You just fire this employee and, I mean, if I owned a building and someone was breaking the no smoking in my building rule and it's my building, I would just call the cops on them.
Rym: So actually, the cops literally do not care about that.
Rym: They won't even come.
Rym: I mean, I can-- Scott, did you see the cops-- Fine, okay, fine.
Rym: In parks, right?
Rym: It's illegal to smoke in parks in New York.
Rym: I looked up how many citations they've written for that.
Rym: Like four?
Rym: And they only write them for black people.
Scott: See, here's your mistake.
Scott: Is that you're not calling the cops because you want them to arrest someone for smoking.
Scott: They don't give a shit about that.
Rym: Well, no, it's like a $50 ticket or whatever.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: You're calling the cops for these two other reasons.
Scott: Number one, if the person who's smoking in your building is not a tenant, you're calling from them for trespassing, which you can actually get some attention on, right?
Rym: No, because there's public businesses on various floors of this building.
Scott: Oh, well, you can still get them for something.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: If I go into a Walmart and start smoking-- If you go to Walmart and start vaping, no one gives a shit.
Rym: And if an employee tells you to stop and you don't, one, I doubt they'll call the police.
Rym: And two, if they do, the police will probably just hang up on them.
Scott: All right, so you know what?
Scott: Okay, so here's what we do, right?
Scott: Number one, the building's 30 floors.
Scott: Give or take.
Scott: Private security can take care of the people.
Rym: I'm not hiring private security for my own part of a floor of a building.
Scott: At least in your case, at least in your case, this person is a tenant in the building, or an employee of a tenant in the building.
Rym: Now, the other people think-- The building can come after-- Building gives zero fucks.
Scott: You as the tenant.
Scott: Well, I think building gives enough fucks to put a sign up.
Rym: Well, yeah, probably because someone complained, because it's not just our employee who I know is vaping in the bathroom, because the people who go-- Also, why don't you fire this employee?
Rym: I'm not in charge of any of that crap, and I don't really care.
Scott: Just fire him.
Rym: I run my own division.
Rym: I do not care about what anyone else does.
Rym: Remember, Scott, it's not like I work in a company with people who know or are into the things I'm into.
Rym: It's not like it's my video game company.
Rym: If I wanted to fire everyone I've ever worked with who annoyed me-- I mean, there's no one in my building I would fire.
Rym: Well, I mean, my old company was a bunch of stock market people.
Rym: Most of them were intolerable to deal with.
Rym: Most of the people in my industry are intolerant.
Scott: Stop working in that industry.
Rym: But that's where all the money is.
Scott: I got money.
Rym: I got more money, and I want to keep it that way for now.
Scott: I got plenty of money.
Scott: I don't need money more.
Rym: You don't want more money?
Scott: What am I going to do with it?
Rym: Well, I don't know.
Rym: Go to the beach eventually?
Scott: It has to be a lot more money to make a difference.
Rym: It was a little more money.
Rym: You could just go see the castles whenever you wanted.
Scott: No, money's not the thing keeping me from seeing the castles.
Rym: If you had a reasonable more money, you could just say like, "Yeah, I'm taking a
Rym: sabbatical.".
Scott: Then what do I do when I get back from the sabbatical?
Rym: Go back to work.
Rym: Sabbatical just means unpaid time off.
Scott: They're going to let me?
Rym: Are you that important to the organization?
Scott: This is great.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: It doesn't happen anyway.
Rym: So have you got any opening statements here?
Scott: Oh.
Rym: I was just trying to segue you into your inane story about your life.
Rym: Because as you know, the format of GeekNights is we have the opening bit.
Rym: that's unrelated.
Scott: I'm going to talk about something that absolutely nobody cares about.
Rym: You think anyone cares about me watching like-.
Scott: They care about this even less.
Rym: A slap fight between someone who put up a no vaping sign and someone who tore it down.
Scott: People who care the least about.
Scott: But I have absolutely no human beings to discuss this with.
Scott: So I'm going to just say it on the show because I want to.
Rym: All right, all right.
Rym: I'm really excited to see how I feel about this.
Scott: So I was watching some garbage Korean TV.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Which I watch a lot of.
Scott: And there was this show that was on recently called Produce 101.
Scott: And this is the most garbage show that has ever existed.
Rym: Is that the old ladies rapping?
Scott: No, that's a way cooler show.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So this is a show on Mnet.
Scott: And Mnet is sort of like MTV where it's supposed to be about music.
Scott: And it is.
Scott: But it's mostly like reality shows.
Rym: But all the reality shows- So it's just like MTV.
Scott: But all the reality shows, at least on Mnet, are music related.
Scott: They're not like completely.
Scott: just reality shows have nothing to do with music.
Scott: They're actually music related like competition shows usually.
Scott: Like for example, they have a show Show Me The Money, which is like a rap competition show.
Scott: And that grandma show is on a different channel.
Scott: It's basically grandma show me the money, right?
Rym: I'd watch grandma show me the money.
Scott: That's on JTBC.
Scott: It's a different channel.
Scott: But Show Me The Money is actually, you know, it's like the show is just like every other Mnet show.
Scott: Except there's good music comes out of these things.
Scott: If you go to Spotify, go on YouTube and search for turtle ship.
Scott: That is like the best song from Show Me The Money.
Scott: It's so good.
Scott: Anyway, so that Produce 101 was pretty much just like Show Me The Money, a competition music show.
Scott: Except what it was is 101 trainees, right?
Scott: Which is like teenage girls between the ages.
Scott: Well, some of them weren't teenage, but, you know, teenage girls competing in this elimination show over the course of 11 episodes.
Rym: You showed me some of this.
Scott: Yeah, it's the creepiest thing ever.
Rym: It's not the creepiest thing ever.
Scott: They're cutting them down to a group of 11 that will form a temporary idol group for one year.
Scott: Because I guess the they're from all like small, some not all.
Scott: they're from small agencies, but most of them it's like, for example, the one girl who's like the best, even though she's only 15, she's like the awesomest.
Scott: She actually lost on another competition show, right?
Scott: And now that's why it was so easy for her to like, she's already popular, right?
Scott: So she coming into this show.
Rym: I feel like that's cheating, but anyway.
Scott: Maybe, but she's the awesomest, so whatever.
Scott: So the big drama here, right, is that you know how at the beginning of these shows, like the American idols and whatever, like first episode, first couple episodes, they introduce everybody.
Scott: There's always those examples they show.
Scott: They always show you the best and the worst.
Scott: They don't show you all the average, boring people, right?
Scott: They show you the best people and they show you the garbage people who are like, aha, look, this person can't even sing and dance.
Rym: I'm awaiting your very specific complaint about some trashy TV you watch from Korea.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Scott: They always show those people who are just garbage, right?
Scott: As the example of like, aha, look at this funny person, right?
Scott: We just like the American Idol, whatever.
Scott: We have them here for episode one entertainment value, but then they're gonna go away.
Rym: Like the guy who comes out and I'm gonna do a like, ninja magic trick and then he just falls over and breaks his nose at the end.
Scott: Exactly, right?
Scott: So they had a girl who was like, Japanese and couldn't sing or dance and like, thought too much of herself who was like, comic relief.
Scott: They had a girl who was like, ridiculously incredible singer, but then they asked her to dance and she was like, um.
Scott: And they were like, you can't dance.
Scott: You know, this is an idol group.
Scott: You're gonna have to dance, right?
Scott: And she's like, yeah.
Scott: But they're like, you know you're the best singer, right?
Scott: Why don't you just become a solo singer and leave the show?
Scott: And then they had this girl where it's like, they were like, isn't your agency like, acting?
Scott: She's like, an acting agency?
Scott: And she's like, yeah.
Scott: They're like, so do you know how to sing or dance at all?
Scott: And she's like, I know acting.
Scott: They're like, why are you here?
Scott: And you didn't really get a clear answer on that, right?
Rym: So obviously it was set up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So all these things were set up, right?
Scott: All these people.
Scott: The mistake this show made, right?
Scott: They didn't rig it.
Scott: It was a hundred.
Scott: It was a hundred percent voting of the audience.
Scott: For real.
Scott: Not kidding.
Scott: Not pretending, right?
Scott: Other shows would like all these other competition shows have like judges and things like, right?
Scott: That would cut.
Scott: or they do like percentages like, oh, fan vote counts.
Scott: 20% judges vote counts.
Rym: They got super delegates like the Democrats.
Scott: This was a hundred percent pure democracy with various voting systems.
Rym: Did someone really dumb and bad get voted on just because?
Scott: The actress girl, basically after like the first couple episodes, she got a whole bunch of votes.
Scott: So then she stayed on the show after the first cut.
Scott: And then they started showing her more because she had, you know, fans, I guess.
Scott: And then, but every time they showed her, it's like, you could tell they were trying to show that this girl could not sing or dance.
Scott: And then they showed even scenes like the girl who like was in second place and was like so good was helping her out and being nice.
Scott: Trying to make that girl look good and the other one look bad.
Rym: That's like the vote for what to name that British ship.
Rym: And the winning vote from the public was like Bodie McBeth face.
Scott: And they tried to like show that like she was crying because she couldn't do anything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then somehow at the very end of the show, like they unceremoniously were like, all right, you won.
Scott: You're like fourth place.
Rym: That's awesome.
Rym: No, it's not 100% awesome.
Rym: That is brilliant.
Scott: You think it's awesome.
Scott: But now this group.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, imagine if I, if you had to go work with 10 other people at a job.
Scott: And they were voting on, uh, you know, programmers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they voted for the one person who obviously couldn't program.
Scott: But now that person is on your team and you have to deal with them.
Rym: You would have to use what attributes they have to make something amazing happen.
Scott: So there's like this huge internet, like hate storm of like, oh my God, this girl, why is she, she's going to ruin everything.
Scott: So there, there's some internet drama from a corner of the world that I know not, not even one listener has ever seen.
Scott: So I can't imagine.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Let me bring it back.
Scott: The super thing, the super narrow thing that you've never even heard of.
Scott: Right.
Scott: As this kind of drama, imagine how many dramas like that are in the world simultaneously every day and all the corners of all the geekery.
Rym: It's a beautiful thing to see.
Scott: If you could somehow add all those up.
Scott: Or like get a picture of all of them at once.
Scott: Like the drama map of, you know, April 6, 2016.
Rym: Huh?
Rym: I feel like you could make a social media account or website that collected all these stories and provided context.
Rym: Like, uh, call it drama bomb.com.
Rym: What if that exists?
Scott: I'll just call it now.
Scott: Isn't it just called a newspaper?
Rym: I guess it'd be encyclopedia dramatica.
Scott: Isn't it just a newspaper?
Rym: Drama bomb.com does not exist.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Buy it then.
Rym: I think I will wait.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: Now it turned into a blank page.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I'll get into that.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's no one to talk about that with on earth.
Rym: So we were two weeks ago at anime Boston and then I was a Zenkai con and Scott was not.
Scott: And I don't have a, I made the right move.
Scott: Didn't I?
Rym: I had a good time.
Rym: In fact, the only thing that marred my Zenkai con at all, because actually Lancaster's way more rocking than it was last year.
Rym: The only thing that marred it was that my Amtrak train fucking hit some dude on the tracks on the way home, but he lived, but you know, I learned a lot about Amtrak nonsense, but anyway, uh, so at Zenkai con, one of the panels I did was like how to run an anime club and I did it with the other Scott Scott Johnson who ran the RIT anime club with me.
Rym: We also did a how to run an anime club panel at anime Boston between both of them.
Scott: They were well attended for some reason.
Rym: And I actually took a bunch of questions as Zenkai con too.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: These kids know what's up.
Rym: Anime clubs are having this huge resurgence, but none of these kids at either con have any idea of why they want to have an anime club.
Rym: Like they don't know why they just seem to assume that they need, they need to have an anime club or that they should have an anime club, but they couldn't, none of them, no could articulate why they wanted to run an anime club except one kid who was like, I kind of just want to like be popular and like be the gatekeeper of animate all my friends and to everyone else in the area
Scott: gatekeeper
Rym: or not say it in so many words, but he, he was, he wanted to be that he wanted to be the guy, the, the, there's
Scott: a difference between the guy who stands at the front of the granary with a spear and says no.
Scott: And the Jesus guy who goes around handing out fishes, you want to be the second, the Jesus guy, you don't want to be the guy with the spear.
Rym: But with a fandoms, there's often the Jesus guy who's going around handing out just one kind of fish because that's the kind of fish he wants everyone to be into.
Scott: It's Lord of the flies, man.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You read this book when you were the age to run an anime club.
Rym: And I realized between doing these two panels, especially doing the second one, that the only content that actually matters is how to deal with drama and how to deal with that guy.
Rym: Like none of the other advice we give actually matters because it all just comes around to guy, all that structure, all the constitution, all that shit only exists to deal with the drama.
Rym: And then that guy, and actually, I think we convinced a few people to make private anime clubs, invite only anime clubs because a lot of people were real uncomfortable with the advice that we were giving.
Rym: And it was just very interesting to see this simultaneous, like widespread desire.
Rym: Like these kids want to start anime clubs enough to where they go to a convention and go to a panel on it instead of doing all the other anime con stuff.
Rym: And yet they literally cannot articulate why they want to run an anime club.
Scott: Most people can't articulate why they do anything that they do or why they want anything they want.
Scott: That is a sign of like a higher, you know, thinking.
Rym: Now, why do you watch this trashy Korean TV?
Scott: I will tell you exactly why.
Rym: I'm really curious, like nothing against it, but why?
Scott: I will explain very well why I watch the Korean TV.
Scott: When you watch American TV, that is equally trashy, right?
Rym: But I don't.
Rym: I watch good American TV.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Anyway, the American trashy TV has this sort of cynical outlook, right?
Scott: And it also has this sort of feeling like we can't show the truth, right?
Scott: It's dishonest, right?
Scott: It's super highly like overproduced and they hide the fact that it's produced in fake, right?
Scott: So not only it's dishonest and it also is like, you know, viewing the world in a dim light, right?
Scott: And it's sort of like when you see like someone brightly shining on, say, American Idol, it's like, oh my God, finally we found one good person.
Scott: Like the whole world is shit, but we found someone good, right?
Scott: The Korean TV is basically the same exact formula, except for those two things, right?
Scott: Number one, they show they basically are completely honest that this is just fucking garbage television, right?
Scott: They show cameramen, they just they break the fourth wall and they talk to the directors and the camera people all the fucking time, right?
Scott: They're not lying about the fact that, like, this is so fucking fake.
Scott: Look at us make fake TV for you.
Scott: TV people are constantly talking about TV the way the podcasters talk about podcasting all the time, right?
Scott: And the outlook is sincere and optimistic, right?
Scott: It's like, look at all these.
Scott: It's not like the world is shit.
Scott: It's like everyone work hard.
Scott: We'll do this.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it's like, you know, it's like feeling good.
Scott: It's like we're dancing and singing.
Scott: Woo.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like when someone loses their right.
Scott: It's they're not like you suck.
Scott: You lost because you suck.
Scott: They're like, well, you're famous now.
Scott: You'll be able to achieve your dream.
Scott: Work hard.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It gives a totally different kind of feel when you watch it than when watching the same exact car.
Scott: And those feels that you get from watching these shows, if you watch too much of them are dangerously addicting.
Scott: So don't start.
Rym: All right.
Rym: You got any anime news?
Scott: I do have an anime news.
Scott: It's sort of not really the big news, but.
Rym: Yeah, because my news of I guess anime comes are getting popular again.
Rym: That was news.
Scott: So you might recall a while ago we talked about.
Scott: I talked about how I had canceled the Crunchyroll paying and started at the Hulu paying because there wasn't anything left to watch in Crunchyroll that I want to watch.
Rym: It was funny.
Rym: We just went in to log into the Crunchyroll account that we just had.
Scott: Stop stealing my news.
Rym: Someone else's password for.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And they had also stopped paying canceled Crunchyroll.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And I paid for Hulu instead.
Scott: So I watched a whole bunch of stuff on Hulu.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Still watching a bunch of stuff.
Scott: There is a bunch of stuff to watch on there still.
Scott: But it's stuff like Sailor Moon where it's like, am I really going to go back to it now?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Scott's Virgin Go Mina.
Scott: Am I really going to go back to it now?
Scott: You have to.
Scott: Anyway, it's so good.
Scott: But this season, there's actually quite a few shows to watch this season.
Scott: Some of them this anime season.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: This season.
Scott: And some of them are maybe shows.
Scott: Some of them are shows I have to see before I know.
Scott: But one of them is Sakamoto Tezuka.
Rym: Sakamoto Tezuka.
Scott: Which is the best anime show.
Scott: I don't even need to see anything but the trailer to know.
Scott: That is the show of the season.
Scott: That is the... I don't know if it'll be One Punch Man good, but it's at least one step under that.
Rym: It's just kind of a show where, like, if it's bad, it'll be amusing like a Zai-zan Jotaro.
Scott: At worst, it's Zai-zan Jotaro with way better animation.
Scott: At worst, right?
Scott: It's worth... It can't... A show with that trailer can't be not worth watching.
Scott: And apparently every single show this season that I want to watch is on the crunchy roll.
Scott: And I haven't seen these shows on the Hulu yet.
Scott: So I'm going to pay for the crunchy roll again and maybe, maybe cancel the Hulu and, you know, do a little switchback for this anime season and then switch for, you know, who knows.
Rym: Because I need you to have the Hulu... Well, I guess I need you to be able to watch all this Lupin because I want to review all this Lupin.
Scott: I'm feeling Lupin season coming soon, maybe.
Scott: But I mean, if there's a Sakamoto desu ka, I'm going to watch that first.
Scott: You know, so that's that.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: So Crunchyroll right now has, like, all the shows you want to watch this season.
Scott: That's the news.
Scott: They've been announcing, like, the things that they're streaming, like, every day.
Scott: There's, like, another announcement and it's like, "Show you wanted to watch is streaming on...".
Scott: And it's always Crunchyroll.
Scott: It's been Crunchyroll, like, three or four times this week.
Rym: So it's basically Crunchyroll if you want to see the brand new anime.
Rym: Hulu if you want to watch all the rest of anime.
Scott: That you haven't seen already.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: For some mistake that you made.
Rym: And Crunchyroll for free if you want to watch the cool, weird stuff like Yamashibai or folk tales from Japan.
Scott: Oh, man, that thumbnail on the new folk tale looked really good.
Rym: Oh, man.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: Got a thing of the day?
Scott: I do.
Scott: So there's a store online called Vat19, right?
Scott: And it's a store, it's sort of like Spencer Gifs of the internet.
Scott: They sell all sorts of weird, you know, tchotchkes that do funky stuff, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The front part of the Spencer Gifs, not the Hot Topic back part.
Scott: And, you know, if you need something like that, I mean, you can go here, you can go to ThinkGeek.
Scott: But Vat19, as their name might imply, specializes in these putties, right?
Scott: That are, like, magical putties that do interesting things.
Scott: And not just the things that Silly Putty does, like, absorbing newspaper comic strips and stretching and bouncing, but many other interesting things, right?
Scott: So one putty they have is, like, this liquid glass putty.
Scott: And what happens with it is if you put it in a container, it will fit the form of the container, but also become, over time, ridiculously transparent to the point at which you look at the container and it would look like nothing is in there.
Scott: Ooh.
Scott: Right?
Scott: All right.
Scott: But if you grab it and start messing with it, it, like, gets cloudy and sort of looks like a crushed rock almost, but then you let it sit and it kind of, and it basically never runs out of its magic powers and is, like, you know, whatever.
Rym: Oh, man.
Rym: Material science.
Scott: And on their website, they have a video of a dude getting into a bathtub full of this stuff.
Scott: What?
Rym: I would not trust that that's necessarily safe.
Scott: He forgot he removed his hair in advance, smartly, and did not remove his armpit hair in advance, unsmartly.
Scott: But there's one putty in particular I want to put, so my thing of the day is basically this whole website, all their videos and everything, but the one putty I'm most interested in is one, I'm hoping that I can use this to mystify people who didn't listen right now, is this magical sort of, like, UV sensitive putty, and it comes with, like, a little keychain UV light.
Rym: I have a bunch of little keychain UV lights.
Scott: So what you can do with this is it's sensitive to the UV, so you put the putty in, like, a container, and then you can sort of draw on the container with the UV light, like, say, like, draw a smiley face.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then open it up and there'll be a smiley face on the putty purple and it's white putty.
Scott: And then it'll fade over time.
Scott: But you could just draw on it again.
Scott: So, like, that's a crazy magic trick.
Scott: If you can hide that keychain somehow in your hand with some sleight of hand, and you could be like, all right, play with this putty.
Scott: You see it's just white goop?
Scott: All right, put it in this container.
Scott: Ooh, let's say the magic words.
Scott: Ooh, you know, is this the number you were thinking of?
Rym: Oh, my God, it is.
Rym: You could go one step further and add another element.
Rym: So if you take tonic water, just, like, basic tonic water, it will glow, like, it'll look like it's glowing if you shine ultraviolet light on it.
Rym: As long as it's real.
Rym: I have to have, like, an equine in it to do that.
Scott: So splash it on someone's shirt?
Rym: Eh, that will be enough.
Rym: Like, but a glass of it.
Rym: Like, if you point it at a glass of it, you'll see, like, this effervescence kind of happening.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: It's cool.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So my thing is, I don't know if the show is good at all, but not that long ago, I suddenly saw a bunch of recommendations in my YouTube and some other people's YouTubes for that Wander Over Yonder show that didn't get a lot of attention.
Scott: I've heard of something called Wander Over Yonder.
Scott: As had I. I know nothing about it, but I know there's something called that.
Scott: That's all I know.
Rym: So suddenly I see, and I see clips of this show all over my YouTube.
Scott: Was it on TV?
Rym: So here's the deal.
Rym: I clicked on one of these, and it was a musical number, like a cabaret-style thing in the show.
Rym: And I was like, all right, because remember, I kind of got into ponies because, oh, they're singing.
Rym: There's music.
Scott: Oh, pony season started again, but I haven't watched any.
Rym: Yeah, I'll watch it soon.
Rym: Caught up on Adventure Time, though.
Rym: Damn.
Scott: I did, unless there's something newer than what I've seen.
Rym: Damn, still goes.
Rym: So then I click on the related next video, and it's another Wander Over Yonder, and it's also a cabaret-style song.
Rym: And all these clips are songs like that.
Rym: One of them is a straight-up meatloaf homage.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So I don't know if this show focuses on the music to that degree.
Scott: Or should I say Rym's Meat Locker?
Rym: But I'm going to give the show a watch based solely on these clips, and the times that I've gotten into a show because YouTube was like, hey, here's a bunch of clips from it.
Rym: I've almost never been led astray.
Scott: That's a pretty good indicator.
Scott: If you like a clip on YouTube, you're going to like the show it came from.
Rym: What I'm curious about, though, is why suddenly I saw these all over the place, because the videos have been uploaded relatively recently.
Rym: I wonder, this is a crazy speculation.
Scott: They're being uploaded to market the show?
Rym: Yeah, because I feel like Teen Titans Go, The Amazing World of Gumball, even My Little Pony, to a degree.
Rym: They didn't hit this certain level of mass appeal, except from people who were kind of in the know, until people were sharing clips from them on YouTube.
Rym: And that's a really low-effort entry point into a show.
Rym: But you have to have self-contained clips.
Rym: that sort of will draw someone in.
Rym: Musical numbers seem to be the primary successful way to do that.
Rym: I've seen it happen a bunch of times.
Rym: I'm curious if this is on purpose, if they dialed back.
Rym: the YouTube copyright claims to let that happen.
Scott: Let me just say, if you really like musical numbers, you can watch the show called Produce 101.
Scott: It's nothing but musical numbers.
Rym: But seriously, cabaret-style meatloaf homage.
Rym: One of these keeps getting stuck in my head, and it's just these two people, this dragon and this eyeball guy.
Scott: I can see this still frame on your screen there.
Rym: Well, Scott, look at this eyeball guy and this dragon.
Scott: But the screenshot you just had before...
Rym: Oh, the sexy dominator woman?
Scott: I mean, just that one still shot gave me a Samurai Jack kind of vibe.
Scott: Yep, this is a villain.
Scott: I lost that vibe now.
Rym: No, really, this villain is... Anyway.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: We'll see if the show is good, but the music is good.
Rym: In the meta moment, the booklet book will be Margaret Atwood's Orcs and Craig, but Scott, something real bad happened.
Scott: By the way, because I didn't realize this, I just want people to understand.
Scott: When I first heard the name of that book, I thought it was Orcs and Cake, like O-R-C-S and C-A-K-E.
Scott: So just because you said the name pretty quickly, I want people to know the way to spell the name of this book.
Scott: is O-R-Y-X, right?
Scott: O-R-Y-X and Ampersand, Crake, C-R-A-K-E.
Scott: Like a rake plus a cake?
Rym: This is like when we were talking about the Prince of Nothing on the show a long time ago, and we kept saying crow demons, and we meant literal birds.
Rym: Like the crow, crows.
Scott: Not like...
Rym: C-R-O dash demon.
Scott: Right, not like crow magnin man, right?
Scott: Crow, C-R-O-W, like, dash demon, pointy horns.
Rym: But Scott, I'm near the end of a very late book in The Wheel of Time.
Scott: Oh, you know what I saw at the bookstore?
Scott: Because I had time to kill.
Rym: The Wheel of Time?
Scott: There was a Wheel of Time companion book that was just 100% glossary.
Scott: It was this giant glossary book that was just a glossary.
Rym: The Wikia is populated primarily from that book.
Rym: So one of the power levels of all the individual Aes Sedai, ranked 1 through 31, there they are.
Scott: It also had illustrations and maps, and it was a giant hardcover book.
Scott: I think it's actually newish.
Rym: So the Wikia even points out that that book actually contradicts things that are said in the actual Wheel of Time books.
Rym: Your mileage may vary.
Rym: But I was literally about to peter out, I'm gonna stop The Wheel of Time right here, start Oryx and
Rym: Craig.".
Scott: Something happened.
Rym: And then I finished the chapter I was in, and basically a character you hadn't seen in a long time appeared and said, "Yo, you wanna know what's up with the fucking dragons?
Rym: The Alefin and the Illfin?
Rym: Remember that tower?
Rym: They're fucking in there.
Rym: Here's the door.
Rym: That's where all the shit's gonna go
Rym: down.".
Scott: Wait, but I thought they were like, "Dragons?
Scott: I thought it was snake people and skin people or
Scott: whatever.".
Rym: Yeah, so... They're dragons?
Rym: Well, I'm pretty sure the dragons are in there.
Scott: Dragons are the snake people?
Rym: Basically, someone comes up to a character and is like, "Hey, you know the Alefin and the Illfin and all the snake people
Rym: nonsense?".
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: The shit I wanted to know about them more than anything.
Rym: And then it's like, "Hey, remember the tower that people keep bumping into where wise old wolves and wise old people keep saying you're too low level to go into that
Rym: tower?".
Scott: Yeah, that's the tower I most want to go into.
Rym: Everyone's high enough level to go into the tower, and everyone knows where the tower is, and they know how to...
Scott: Well, isn't it just in the northwest?
Scott: I mean...
Rym: Yeah, it's because they see it on that boat.
Scott: Right, yeah, I saw it.
Rym: Yeah, so at one point...
Scott: It's not a mystery where... It's not a hidden tower.
Scott: It's like, "Oh, there it
Scott: is.".
Rym: This character's talking to Matt, and they're like, "The Alefin and the Illfin, he knows the shit about them for obvious
Rym: reasons.".
Rym: Like, he knows.
Scott: And it's like in Zelda 1, you bomb, you know, you go into level 9, and it's like, "You need a whole Triforce to come in
Scott: here.".
Rym: No, it's more like the Tower of Babel in Final Fantasy IV, where you see it there, but there's literally no way to get into it.
Rym: And then later, some character's like, "I heard that all the final stuff at the end of the game is in that giant tower, but we don't know what's in
Rym: there.".
Rym: And then you actually do know, and then you go into it.
Rym: That all just happened, like, on the subway over here.
Rym: So, we'll see.
Rym: Maybe I'll just blitz through the rest of these books real quick.
Rym: We will be!
Rym: We finally have a break in Conventions for a little bit, and then, before you know it, PAX East 2016.
Scott: The break in Conventions is after PAX East, right?
Scott: Not before.
Rym: Yeah, but PAX East, on Sunday at 3.30pm in the Arachnid Theater...
Scott: Wait, what time is the Omegathon finale?
Rym: Sometime after that.
Rym: We will get into the Omegathon finale.
Rym: I have the utmost confidence.
Scott: As long as they get the tabletop night shift.
Rym: The only... So, basically, when I filled out my Enforcer form, I was like, "You pretty much want to give me a night shift, because I have a panel that blocks both other shifts, effectively, on
Rym: Sunday.".
Rym: Because I need an hour or two to get ready for the panel, and all that crap, and then time to tear it down afterward.
Rym: So, yeah.
Rym: Anyway, 3.30pm, Sunday, Arachnid Theater, Atari Game Design.
Rym: And I'm telling you, that is the kind of title of panel that is guaranteed to fill a room, and it's also a panel that I can't guarantee we'll put on YouTube, because it's kind of hard to, like, make that all work out.
Rym: There's a lot of stuff I have to do.
Scott: It's also... Oh, the other panel's better.
Rym: Well, the thing is, the other panel, we did really well, and it's already on YouTube, so you can just watch that one.
Rym: Like, if we did...
Scott: Do we have to do the shitty panels more until you get a good one?
Rym: It's more that this panel has a lot more ad-libbing, and a lot more, like, emergent behavior that comes up, so we can't script it 100%.
Scott: Anyway, go to PAX East, or sorry.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, it might appear on YouTube, but I can't promise it.
Rym: Otherwise, stay tuned for news about other conventions, and...
Scott: So, I just talked about how all the new animes this season that you want to watch are on Crunchyroll, and one of those shows that is on Crunchyroll this season, and apparently still not anywhere else, I don't know if it will be anywhere else, is the new anime adaptation of Phoenix Wright, Ace Attorney.
Rym: It's just called Ace Attorney, or...
Scott: Yeah, it's weird.
Scott: I tried to search for Phoenix Wright, and I didn't find it, and then I realized, "Oh, right, this is like a subtitled Japanese show, it's just gonna be called, like, Yakuten Saiban, which is the original name of the game, which is Turnabout
Scott: Courtrooms.".
Scott: I searched for that, and I didn't find it, so I just browsed for it, because I knew it was on there, and it showed up as Ace Attorney just by itself, and I'm like, "Huh,
Scott: okay.".
Rym: So, the genres.
Rym: Comedy, mystery, themes, future, lawyers, murder.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: What fucking shows have the theme lawyers?
Scott: I don't know, but we watched...
Rym: It's the only one!
Scott: It's the only anime with the theme lawyers, according to Anime News Network and Slavery.
Scott: So, we watched episode one today, which is pretty short and easy to watch, and let me tell you this.
Scott: First of all, what was my expectation level for this show, right?
Scott: Pretty low.
Scott: Right?
Scott: I mean, well, I don't know.
Scott: I didn't have a low expectation, I basically had a no expectation.
Scott: I was like, "Because I didn't know what they were gonna do with
Scott: it.".
Rym: Well, Scott, we know exactly what our specific expectation was, because we reviewed this show at Anime Boston, and there's video that I'm gonna edit this weekend.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like, I didn't know.
Scott: I was like, are they going to redo the video games in anime form?
Scott: Are they going to tell something new with these characters?
Scott: Are they, you know, what is actually gonna be here, right?
Scott: It's like, it's been so long since that first game, right?
Scott: But clearly, you wanna use the main characters from that first game, because people care about them way more than the other characters from the other games, right?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: But what story are you gonna tell with those characters, and how are you gonna tell it?
Scott: And this is not the first time that a Capcom thing has been made into anime.
Scott: There are Mega Man anime, and Street Fighter anime, and I think there might be Darkstalkers anime, if I'm not mistaken.
Scott: No.
Scott: There's a lot of Capcom things that have become anime.
Scott: How is this one gonna be?
Rym: If it had been the lowest possible rate of animation, like just the video game even, but it had just been new stories forever, like just, let's just make a bunch of Phoenix Wright stories.
Scott: Yeah, that could be good, because you're basically saving the person the trouble of having to play the game, and giving them the same story, plus voice acting, plus actual animation.
Scott: that's a little, you know.
Rym: Yeah, like I could've lived with that, but I, this show is hot garbage.
Scott: Yeah, so first of all, the animation is bad.
Scott: It's not even like, if they would've just taken GBA animation directly, or DS animation directly, it actually would've been better, right?
Rym: Like, everything's drawn poorly.
Scott: The CG courtroom is like initial D quality.
Rym: Oh my god, the jurors in the courtroom are the worst CG.
Rym: Like, they stand out real bad.
Scott: This seems like a mad rush job by not good animators who are not putting in a strong effort, right?
Rym: And you think, like the opener of a show like this, you know, like we talk about in all our panels, Sailor Moon, like the budget on the opener was more than multiple episodes combined.
Scott: Yeah, it's so weird, the closer to the show is actually the best part of the show.
Scott: It's like well animated and has good song, goodish song, even though it's not really that memorable, right?
Rym: Well, 'cause it's not that animated, it's stylistic.
Scott: Right, but the opener is like, wow, this opener might even look worse than the actual show.
Scott: It definitely doesn't look better than the show.
Rym: Emily, when you start watching, she's like, "What the fuck with this run
Rym: cycle?".
Scott: Dude, I could tell the run cycle was bad even before she said something.
Rym: The run cycle had like three frames in it.
Scott: She beat me to that, she just beat me to that comment, 'cause like it was obviously, he was like running with only his lower leg.
Rym: Also, guys, it's 2016, your anime opener is generic song, protagonist running sideways across the screen, then later all the other characters running sideways across the screen together.
Rym: Like really?
Rym: Is this just like El Hazzard?
Scott: So, the episode one basically directly retells almost exactly what happens in the very first court case of Phoenix Wright, but it tells it in like 20 minutes.
Scott: Dude, if you play that game, right, on your GBA, even if you know all the right answers to everything, it takes a little bit of time.
Scott: It takes longer than that.
Scott: It's rushed, because they've taken out the gameplay, but kept everything else without adjusting the pacing or anything like that, or adding new material, or slowing anything down.
Scott: Everything feels like mad rushed, and it's just like, "Oh my god, everything,".
Scott: and--.
Rym: Now, they lampshaded a little, like it could have been funny if they did this just for this episode, then the show was like, you know, deviated or something, because they even like, whenever there's title cards, it shows like a video game text box.
Scott: Yeah, it's literally, like when they show the evidence on the table, it's like you get the shot of like the piece of evidence by itself.
Scott: It's like literally, like it's like really frame for frame, almost from the video game.
Rym: But one, it is just the game.
Rym: There is no reason.
Scott: If you have played the game, it's like, for example, the Death Note.
Scott: anime is almost exactly the same as the manga, right?
Scott: You know, it's telling the same story basically, right?
Rym: But it's got bitchin' music, the voice acting's really good.
Scott: But there are reasons to watch it, even if you have already read the manga.
Rym: Like Nodame Kontable, if you read the manga, the anime is the same, except you get all the music in it.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, there are reasons to watch adaptation.
Rym: I should say the same thing about Initial D.
Scott: Right, and often, for a video game, like if they made Final Fantasy VI, the anime, it's like, there are reasons to watch that as an anime, because like, wow, I can get the whole story without random encounters.
Rym: I would watch the hell out of a Final Fantasy VI anime.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: However, here is a case in which there is absolutely nothing to be gained by spending time in your life watching the Phoenix Wright anime, compared to playing the video game.
Scott: The video, and even if you've never done either, the video game is a vastly better experience, even though you have to spend time solving the puzzles and stuff.
Rym: Like you think it'd be a joke, like in this episode, they literally give Phoenix Wright the tutorial on how to play the anime.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And it's, it would be funny, except the preview of Episode 2 implies that it just plays that straight forever.
Scott: There are even like images in the preview that were exact images from the second part of the game, right?
Scott: So it, the main problem I had, bigger than all the other problems, is that in the game, there are spacey scenes in which characters are basically emoting ridiculously, like super hyperbolic, you know, emotion, like the witnesses will explode when Phoenix Wright like, exposes their contradictions, right, and have ridiculous expressions and start slamming on stuff and banging their head against the wall.
Scott: All this kind of stuff, right?
Scott: And in the video game, that works.
Scott: And the reason it works is because those animations are kind of slow a little bit, right?
Scott: Like the person slamming the head against the wall is like, "Slam, slam,
Scott: slam."
Scott: And they are kind of beyond the typical animation.
Rym: So you're watching a static game, and when the guy blows up, it's like, "Oh
Rym: shit.".
Scott: Right, and it's like this tension build, and then like a pause, and then explode, and then the music is like, "Do, do, do, do, do, do, do,
Scott: do.".
Scott: All right, and then you have to read through the text while the person is stuck, and it's like, so it sort of spreads that out a bit.
Scott: When you have that whole thing sort of non-stop at this, almost without the text, you know, pressing A and going through it at video game speed, right?
Scott: When you just pull it at full real-time speed, it's like everyone is super annoying, and with voice acting too, right?
Scott: It's like, "Oh my God, everyone shut the fuck up and die.
Scott: Oh my
Scott: God.".
Scott: It's like what used to be like a hilarious joke, that same thing now because the pacing is sped up, is like annoying and makes you want to kill this character.
Scott: And that really makes it unpleasant to watch, where something that was humorous is now painful.
Rym: But also, they miss their mark, so like when he does objection, it just uses the video game thing, like objection.
Scott: It does like a little triple super animation, you know?
Rym: But it's not, like him and Edgeworth slamming their hands down, like looks kind of weak.
Scott: They didn't do that a lot, right?
Rym: There wasn't a lot of that.
Rym: But they show it in the opener and it looks weak sauce.
Scott: Yeah, you didn't get that sort of slam, pause, finger, finger, thinking, thinking.
Scott: It was like, "Doom, ah, but I got you on the..." Right?
Scott: It's like, you got to, you know, the reason that animation worked and had impact in the game is because of that sort of those pauses, like, "Boom, I got you on
Scott: this."
Scott: Or, "Objection, what?
Scott: Ah, let me tell
Scott: you.".
Scott: His name is Naruhodou, right?
Scott: Because he goes, "Ah,
Scott: Naruhodou.".
Scott: And then he explains that, right?
Scott: This, everything was just, you know, it's fast.
Scott: And it's got too much excitement.
Scott: It's like they're on freaking, you know, some kind of drug and everyone's like made way too much sugar before they went to court.
Rym: Also, let's assume you've never heard of these games.
Scott: Or if you've never heard of Phoenix Wright and never seen any, this is not what you want.
Rym: Or let's say that you've, like, you know the deal, but you never played the first one.
Rym: They start by showing you who the murderer is.
Rym: And then the episode starts.
Rym: You can't even have that Poirot of like, "Oh, I wonder what's going to
Rym: happen.".
Rym: Like, it's just, "All right, here it
Rym: is.".
Scott: Yeah, in the game, you don't know who the murderers are until, you know, you actually solve the case.
Rym: I wonder if episode two will also be like, "Hey, guess who the murderer is?
Rym: Like, this person right
Rym: here.".
Rym: Because it starts, it's like, it literally shows you, "Here's the
Rym: murder.".
Rym: And then the episode starts.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So, I don't think the game did that.
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: I don't know if it did it for the first one.
Rym: Maybe it did in the first one?
Scott: I mean, the reason it's hard to remember that is because A, it was a long time ago I played it.
Scott: And B, it was so obvious who it was that it didn't matter if they told you or not because you'd have to be a moron not to realize it.
Scott: So, you don't remember if they gave it away or if you just knew it.
Scott: Because I definitely knew it before the end of the case, right?
Scott: So, I guess, like-- It's sort of always, if you don't know who the guilty party is in a Phoenix Wright case, it's like,
Scott: "Wow.".
Scott: I mean, wow.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: I could make more fun of this episode, but everything I would make fun of are things that are just jokes or I would be making fun of the game itself, like the Japanese court system.
Rym: Or there's literally, like, "Well, I guess that's the murderer instead of that
Rym: person."
Rym: Like, "Oh, unless you can prove what time it was, we're just gonna hang this other guy because that's how Japan works, I
Rym: guess.".
Rym: Right.
Scott: I mean, it's also, you know, even if, you know, regardless of the fact that it's bad, it's too late.
Scott: Phoenix Wright is already-- That's like something we played so long ago.
Scott: Like, in fact, I remember-- Right, this anime should have been out, like, five to ten years ago in the GBA days, right?
Scott: You should have struck while that iron was hot, right?
Scott: When that thing came out in the US, like, when the second game came out in the US, that was, like, the timing for this, right?
Rym: Yeah, who cares about Phoenix Wright in 2016?
Scott: People do still care about it.
Rym: But they care about, like, Godot and all that shit that happened way later, like, all these other games.
Scott: Yeah, and that shit is way better, too.
Scott: And it also petered-- You know, it's not at its full strength that it once was.
Scott: And also, this is, like, the weakest-- It might be the worst officially licensed Phoenix Wright thing there is.
Rym: In fact, if you want to watch a Phoenix Wright thing, just watch that old turntable turnabout to that Mystery Skull song.
Scott: If you want to see Phoenix Wright without having to spend the time playing through it-- Let's Plays.
Scott: Go on YouTube and find a Let's Play of someone who knows all the answers and goes through it really fast.
Rym: Oh, maybe I should do that for all the games I didn't play.
Scott: You can.
Scott: Sure, why not?
Scott: I will.
Scott: Playing them is also just fine, right?
Scott: They actually don't take that long.
Scott: It's not like a Final Fantasy with random encounters.
Scott: They're worth playing most of these games.
Rym: But for real, guys, this anime is not worth watching at all.
Scott: No, watch Sakamoto Desu Ga.
Scott: Don't watch this.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: The Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Rebecca Dunn, Nicholas Brandau, Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Amanda Duchette, James David White, Christian, At Least I'm Not Named After My Dad, Coops, Jess, MyStady.com, Mechanical Mind, William Eisenbros, Jeremy Miner, Spartacus, Spartacus, Spartacus, Joshiro Jostar, Tyler Eller, Sean Yeager, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Robert Lee, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Rare Lavell, Brian Cedroni, Rochelle Montanona, Finn, Eric Silveron, Can't Melt, Steel Beams,
Scott: Kinetic
Rym: Man, Eric Cerise, Chris Midcave, Chris Knox, Flame Darkfire, Sam Grodery, Daniel Redman, Chris Haddad, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: It is getting really hard to say that all in one go, you guys, you have no idea.
Rym: That is why I set the threshold for me doing that at $5.
Rym: So, anyway, the updates I got for you on GeekNights is we're gonna do the Q&A from the last month real soon, and then we're gonna immediately open questions for the next Q&A with a pretty good theme, I think.
Rym: So we're getting back on a regular schedule for that.
Rym: I got some Rimmle reviews coming up.
Rym: I got a bunch of Rym's Rants that I'm gonna trickle out.
Rym: And, as I promised, I am, this weekend, at least by the weekend, I'm gonna put up the first beta ever of GeekNights ever, for you guys only, only the Patreons, so you can see what we were like before October 31st, 2005.
Rym: And if we hit that goal, I'm gonna put up all the rest of the beta episodes, some of which I discovered were never published and are not anywhere on the internet.
Rym: So those of you who have found them, there are at least three that you have never found as far as I can tell.
Rym: I hope we didn't say anything weird or bad in them.
Rym: I guess I have to listen to them.
Rym: Also, I should have Judge Anime by its cover, since we reviewed this terrible Phoenix Wright anime.
Rym: we just reviewed, for real, on that, and you'll be able to see what we said about it before we saw the first episode.
Rym: I should have that up before the end of the weekend, unless something goes horribly awry.
Rym: And if you're waiting to submit things to ConnectiCon, honestly, I don't know what to tell you, the back end, like I'm not gonna lie, is kind of a disaster.
Rym: They switched it on me without consulting me, and I'm not sure what to do about it, 'cause it just doesn't work for panel submissions, and I know we're getting really late in the game.
Rym: If I had my druthers, I would have opened panel submissions in like January, or hell, if I could, I'd just open them literally on Sunday at the previous ConnectiCon.
Rym: So stay tuned, as soon as I know anything, I'll let you guys know, and now I leave you with something weird.