Rym: it's Tuesday April 12th 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym I am Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: me Tomo cuz that's technically a game.
Scott: let's do this.
Rym: so Scott I got a concern.
Rym: I got.
Scott: I got a real concern a concern or this is it that Korean TV show I stopped watching about people with concerns?
Rym: so my concern is that in our long-form Civ 5 game with all of our friends you shared a continent with a dangerous AI and a dangerous Lisa.
Scott: uh-huh she disposed of that dangerous AI.
Scott: apparently it wasn't so dangerous.
Rym: our concern is that she's about to dispose of you and then the rest of us gonna have to deal with this like existential threat to our being.
Scott: that's somewhat likely.
Scott: she's got like four military units next to what my second city.
Scott: I don't even have four military units total.
Scott: Scott.
Rym: do not go quietly into that night.
Scott: what am I supposed to do?
Scott: resist just make my spearmen poke the archer once before it dies.
Scott: I mean what?
Rym: what just archer?
Rym: did you have catapults hanging out?
Rym: what did you have catapults like?
Scott: I haven't seen a catapult.
Scott: I've seen there's like four chariot archers next to my city so you need to have a few.
Rym: make like a horseman or something okay so I do have a horse?
Rym: yeah make it make it a horseman right.
Scott: but uh no I have horses the resource.
Scott: oh so by the time I make a horseman if I stop doing what I'm doing now I will already be dead.
Rym: what are you doing now?
Rym: that's more important than making a military unit.
Scott: I think I'm making a military.
Rym: okay as long as you're making a military you just don't don't go too easy.
Scott: what am I?
Scott: there's no point though like what's.
Rym: what's the point if you give me the city?
Rym: I'll resist.
Scott: if you know how to resist better than I do I think I do.
Rym: I'm good at advanced wars.
Rym: the thing is we can buff you too.
Rym: like if you make enough contacts with us and you're still alive if every one of us gives you like a hundred gold you can start buying military units.
Scott: oh yeah everyone give me a hundred gold.
Scott: that'd be awesome.
Rym: well I'll I will fund your war to prevent the aggression of this toxic empire.
Rym: I'm expanding.
Scott: I'm totally okay with that.
Scott: yeah.
Rym: so just make contact with us.
Rym: diplomacy.
Scott: well I finally saw my trireme finally saw someone.
Scott: that's the other thing.
Scott: it's like I always.
Scott: I built this trireme.
Scott: that could have been a military unit that would have defended me but instead.
Scott: oh I know what I'm building.
Scott: I'm one turn away from finishing a wall.
Scott: that's actually in my capital but the other city that she's going after doesn't have a wall.
Rym: you know what.
Rym: I'm one turn away from finishing the Great Wall because I'm actually.
Rym: I'm not gonna betray anyone in this game.
Rym: you're just gonna have put up a great one but I am terrified that Germany will betray me.
Rym: so just in case I want the Great Wall yeah after I finish the wall I'm gonna build a military.
Rym: yeah finish the wall.
Scott: that is advisable but that's in my capital the city that is surrounded.
Scott: it has no wall but it does have a spear man in it which is okay I guess.
Rym: the other thing is if you get if she takes your city and someone takes it back we can liberate it and bring you back into the game.
Rym: okay which I often do because a lot of that.
Scott: how does that work with GMI?
Rym: fuck if I know I'll look into it if it comes to that.
Rym: so that aside I do have not a news but a geek bite.
Rym: so I played a game.
Rym: Chris and Anthony really wanted me to play this game and they kept snickering about chicken.
Rym: surprise and this game is called fast food franchise.
Rym: you heard of this game.
Scott: I've heard something about it.
Rym: so if I describe this game this game is to monopoly what Madoka Magica is to Sailor Moon.
Rym: okay this game is the ugliest like black and white like it just has these paper cards.
Rym: it's monopoly.
Rym: but it was really interesting to play and I like you roll dice move around the board buy stuff yeah but yeah but what this game?
Rym: I gotta play it again.
Scott: what rule is different and it's complicated.
Rym: so basically this is like cutthroat age of just kicks players out of the game and it converges on someone winning real quick.
Rym: like it takes less than an hour to play.
Scott: and what decisions do you make?
Rym: so when you land on a spot there's all this other bullshit like crazy.
Rym: there's words all over this crazy black and white board.
Rym: Natalie took one look at this board.
Rym: she was like that game is too ugly for me to even read the rules.
Rym: but so you land on a place right you can open a franchise and there's a limited number of franchises like chicken surprise or I don't remember any of them other than chicken surprise.
Rym: the art is real awesome in this.
Rym: it's almost like kingdom of loathing like it's just a little chicken bucket with a dollar sign on it and some like chicky nubs sticking out of the top.
Rym: and if you buy a franchise you then can put it on that monopoly space and then you can start building out franchises of that that franchise because you own it.
Rym: no one else can have it throughout the rest of the country.
Rym: so if someone lands on it they owe you based on the number of franchises connected to it.
Rym: if you then open another of these like somewhere else in a monopoly space and you connect all the franchises in the middle of the board then they owe you a fuck ton of money.
Rym: and there's all this other crazy nonsense going on.
Rym: I don't know if it's good I don't know if I necessarily like it but it's much like apocalypse zero is something that is neither good nor likable but is memorable for how how how it it was.
Rym: this thing is the apocalypse zero of monopoly like board games.
Rym: okay I will play it again.
Rym: I think I actually zero again.
Rym: I think I. I can see a situation where I would watch apocalypse zero again.
Rym: okay but it would have to be showing it to someone else to see their reactions to it.
Rym: so I want to play this game with you because I really want to see you experiencing this game.
Scott: we could just play monopoly.
Rym: no I will never play monopoly again but I would.
Scott: I have millennia monopoly.
Rym: I saw that ponyopoly.
Rym: I would play fast food franchise again and I don't know what else I can say about it other than that it could.
Rym: that made me question what it is that I seek when I play games.
Rym: mmm interesting situation here.
Rym: so you gotta got a gaming news.
Scott: it's sort of a news.
Scott: really got three things of the day and one of them is passable as news.
Scott: so it was revealed or discovered recently like within the past.
Scott: Oh week right there is something in punch out that people did not know or at least I guess I'm sure someone on earth knows the person who might like a technique or something.
Scott: no so you know how.
Scott: again certain guys there's a moment where you can punch them and they will go down.
Scott: just do the one punch.
Scott: yeah right right so did you know?
Scott: usually you sort of get the feel of like.
Scott: okay it's on some bald bulls third bounce like do to do to do to punch right you just you get and that's how most people play now.
Scott: it was revealed in 2009 by Iwata of all people right that there is a part.
Scott: in the first time you fight bald bull the time that you're supposed to punch him a camera flash goes off in the on the crowd.
Scott: whoa this is in 2009. this is revealed.
Rym: I I guess I'm not up on the current state of the art and Mike Tyson's in 2009 they revealed this that there's a camera flash.
Rym: oh my god it's.
Rym: that tells you beard right there.
Scott: it tells you when to punch a ball bowl.
Scott: so the thing that was just discovered was that for piston Honda right first piston Honda.
Rym: second piston Honda.
Scott: I think it's the second piston.
Scott: second Honda right and also the second ball bowl.
Scott: there's a guy in the crowd where the looks like he has a beard.
Scott: he's just a few pixels.
Rym: I see him beard definitely a bit at the moment you're supposed to punch.
Scott: he sort of like nods his head like mmm or like or shakes his head or does he doesn't?
Scott: some kind of animation to signal the exact moment you should punch either second ball bowlers or a second piston Honda to get the one hit knocked out on them.
Scott: wow this was just discovered.
Scott: I haven't.
Scott: I didn't know it before and I don't know anyone who knew it before.
Rym: and holy shit.
Rym: does that read that?
Rym: it means that the em because remember Mike Tyson's punch-out uses that mmc2 chip?
Rym: I think is the only game that used it.
Rym: because so and it was because it had to be able to have that crowd and the two giant dudes.
Rym: this could only have been done with the mmc2 chip.
Rym: well yeah the whole game can only be yeah but like the fact that they used the crowd for something beyond this this is kind of messing with me.
Scott: well I mean the flash was known this the nodding guy was unknown.
Rym: what else don't we know?
Scott: what else don't we know?
Scott: so now I'm gonna get some videos of some fights against.
Scott: you know Tyson himself and see.
Scott: is there perhaps some sort of signal in the back?
Scott: I'm sure people are already investigating that you could use to perhaps take him down more reliably because even the best people have some hard times.
Rym: I've watched a few failed even though every every speed run.
Scott: I've seen blindfold speed runs beating him now.
Scott: so that just shows how bad I I mean.
Scott: I could beat everyone up to Sandman and super macho man.
Scott: that's about it.
Scott: I can't have a hard time with them.
Rym: I could play a Mike Tyson's punch-out again.
Rym: it's been a while.
Scott: it's a good game.
Rym: it's got one more weird news because this is this is I don't know what to make of this except that it's gamergate esque but it's not the gamergate people doing it.
Scott: okay so people are harassing someone for a reason other than sexism or what.
Rym: so there's that slash tabletop game which is like slash two characters together.
Rym: some some people we know made it.
Rym: that's a good game for that sort of thing.
Rym: yeah but apparently some of the cards mention characters from a particular franchise and have a little bit of description about them.
Scott: well I mean a lot of games have that.
Scott: like you know this is like the super fight game and they got.
Scott: yeah they got a new game.
Scott: the
Rym: franchise they mention happens to be a franchise filled with nothing but ridiculous shithead fans who are so butter about the slightly biased and they get real into the ethics and the bias that this game presents about these characters that they have organized a massive down review bad review reporting campaign against this game trying to get as many people as possible and they're success.
Rym: not that popular a game yeah but the number of people who are trying to destroy this game now is ridiculous.
Scott: it's five people who are way more than 100 internet accounts?
Rym: no so what does the franchise?
Rym: is this dumb TV show called supernatural which I'm not I don't even know much about it okay but it's fans are the most butthurt people I've ever seen on earth and the reviews that they're writing are all and there's lots of them here are all basically the same.
Rym: they're mad that the people who made the game so unprofessionally talked about the characters that they like in a way that they don't like.
Rym: okay and this is like.
Rym: you should see how many of these reviews there are.
Rym: they're still growing like they're organized in their attempt to destroy this game because they're so butter about the fact that a little bit of text in the middle of this obscure indie game says something about a character dating another character in this relatively unpopular franchise TV show.
Rym: and they're.
Rym: this is the result.
Rym: this is like gamergate but supernatural fans only.
Scott: whatever I mean this is every day on the internet.
Scott: what's the big deal?
Rym: uh this is.
Rym: this is an example of this happening.
Scott: I don't think people really like 30 of these every day.
Rym: name one instance of this.
Rym: that isn't gamergate.
Scott: they're all kpop related ones.
Scott: okay so-and-so posted pictures on their Instagram kissing their boyfriend and everyone's mad.
Rym: so and so there's a difference between mad general like this.
Rym: is the because this happens on reddit the downvote brigades.
Rym: this is organized people trying to destroy the reviews of something like a restaurant just to make it go away because they're mad about the contents.
Scott: should I tell you the time that people went to the girls generation concert and everyone turned off their light sticks and turn their backs to the stage that's actually amazing because they were talking to dude idols.
Rym: oh yeah the people are horrible people.
Rym: but that that level of organization is amazing yeah I'm just saying so.
Scott: yeah this shit happens every day in every single right.
Scott: that's just one fandom right every single fandom that involves at people under the age of 30.
Rym: so the reason I bring this up is that you can actually go to the Amazon reviews and report these reviews as being fraudulent and Amazon will do something about it.
Rym: so it's kind of helping out some friends here.
Rym: you can go help them with this.
Scott: what's the I mean?
Scott: what's the current rating of the game on Amazon?
Rym: four stars for now very effective.
Rym: well because it takes a while to get the momentum up.
Rym: also it looks like the reviews are starting to be deleted because people are trying to undo the tide but this is related to this was something I was going to talk about on a Monday but it's relevant to this.
Rym: this same thing just happens well has been happening and someone did a news article about it to some random-ass farm in the middle of Kansas a farm.
Scott: yeah.
Rym: so the story is way back in 2002 there was some service that I guess would tell you like hey based on an IP address here's where the shithead you're mad about lives or you know.
Rym: look up where an IP address is now.
Rym: back then that information was not like.
Rym: there was no good people dynamic IPS and shit - oh so basically what this guy did what the service did is if it couldn't tell where you were other than that you're in the US.
Rym: it just put a dot in the geographic center of the country give or take and it hard-coded where that dot was and it just happens that that dot is the front yard of some farm.
Scott: just that some people lives in the exact center of the United States.
Rym: yeah so remember how an American God saw the center of the United States is the worst place in the world.
Rym: yes the internet for the last two decades has made this the worst place in the world.
Rym: death threats harassment IRS collectors basically all the shit and debris of the internet has coalesced around this one farm and it's ruined it for these people.
Scott: hey I mean it would be one thing if like they can't like a cute sign put there or like.
Rym: no this is like someone get like someone gets ripped off on the internet and they try to look up the IP address person who ripped him off and they see oh it's that farm.
Rym: hmm that scam farm.
Rym: people were starting to think that there was like a scam operation running out of that farm and they're like doing investigative journalism except they don't know shit about shit and it's just literally someone's family farm.
Rym: people.
Rym: a lot of debt collectors would come around police would come around.
Rym: this shit is ridiculous.
Scott: the moral of all of this don't leave the farm is that in the modern era move the farm like you got.
Scott: probably have a ton of fucking land.
Scott: you live in a farm.
Scott: pick your house up.
Scott: move it to the other end of the farm.
Rym: yeah but that's not the correct solution.
Rym: the problem is that in the modern era if you call attention to anything at all slightly more so than the things around it people will put literal poop all over that thing and gamergate is just the sort of recent iteration of that.
Scott: so like I think it's the one.
Scott: I think it's one that is perhaps doing more damage and also one that is being fought against more and it's also longer lasting.
Rym: well it's also like surprisingly organized but it's interesting because the gamergate nonsense is very like very tightly organized by shitheads like we will get together in anonymous forums to coordinate being shitheads together.
Rym: but this is literally random.
Rym: there's no worry.
Rym: this is just because some GPS coordinates showed up in a database with no other context and that the same gamer giddy shit happened by a collective group of people who don't know each other and are not organized in any way.
Scott: I mean standalone complex is already like way old.
Rym: yeah wait oh I get in the forum who has kept posting gamergate shit and finally got caught.
Scott: I don't really pay that much time.
Rym: oh so basically someone posted like an article that was kind of bullshitty and everyone was like dude that's some gamergate bullshit.
Rym: he's like oh shit I didn't.
Rym: I just linked to it because I'm sorry and then basically I realized that this person kept posting things that were that gamergate nonsense but then when called out on it and actually did some investigative journalism.
Rym: the response was always oh I guess I should check my sources better.
Rym: whoops so can't pull that trick more than once in the same forum dude.
Rym: but anyway things of the day.
Rym: what yeah for me.
Scott: I forget what.
Scott: I sent you two links.
Scott: I forget which one I'm gonna use on this episode.
Scott: let's figure it out.
Rym: first one all right all right you got anything cuz I got.
Scott: the first one is ah yes somebody went into I guess the supermarket or something and they left the dog in the car with the window cracked open.
Rym: but you can't that's still not safe yeah but the actually crack in the window has almost no effect on the temperature window the windows significantly open.
Rym: even then it doesn't have a significant impact and if it's open enough to make an impact the dog and probably just jump out.
Scott: what I'm saying is though that part doesn't matter.
Scott: the part that matters is the dog clearly knows that this isn't a good situation and it you know it decides to try to get the owners attention to for the great benefit of YouTube.
Rym: oh I actually have not watched this.
Rym: it's well it's just called.
Rym: I'll click on it later.
Rym: it's just called impatient pups left alone in car for their owners.
Rym: oh I see what happens.
Rym: smart dogs.
Scott: it's way cute this dog.
Rym: I'm into this cute dog so I don't link to these all the time.
Rym: but I'm actually deeply impressed with the people who are taking the music to undertale which is already great music and just doing like amazing covers of it like taking the song and remixing it doing stuff to it just covering it.
Scott: someone posted covers of the you know me me Tomo songs.
Scott: yeah.
Scott: so I mean if you make a song someone will cover.
Rym: yeah this is one of my favorite things about modern internet culture but this one goes above and beyond.
Rym: so there's a song in Undertale called bone trousel which is the bone guys the skeleton bros and it's a great song.
Rym: someone uploaded and it's on YouTube now.
Rym: bone klezmer.
Rym: okay it's a klezmer cover of this song.
Rym: it is so perfect and so wonderful that I can't get it out of my head.
Scott: I mean klezmer is skeletons second favorite kind of music genre.
Rym: yeah and in fact they posted it on Halloween.
Rym: good job.
Rym: yeah in the meta moment the booklet book will be oryx and crake by Margaret Atwood.
Rym: oryx with a Y not orcs like grar hitting you with a club or whatever.
Rym: I guess it works mostly your swords axes.
Rym: yeah axes swords spanking clubs.
Rym: they're not trollex and I'm probably gonna stop reading the real-time temporarily now that I'm finishing up book 12 and stuff stopped happening.
Rym: they were.
Rym: it got to this point where they're like hey remember that tower the tower that has all the obvious cool shit in where.
Scott: that's the only thing I want to know about good character.
Rym: all but literally said to another character you can't go there yet dude you're not high enough level.
Rym: and now they're finally high enough level.
Rym: that got mentioned.
Rym: and then a whole book later no one's going over to the tower.
Rym: so pause we're gonna pause.
Rym: but another interesting thing happened.
Scott: so we were watch book 13 is nothing but the tower.
Rym: yeah I'll get back to it I think when you read oryx and crake first though because that is the actual book club book the patreon the next patreon actually jumped way ahead.
Rym: suddenly what's wrong with you people on a new patreon jet?
Scott: listen instead of doing some patreon nonsense just send your money to me and then I will spend it on chocolate.
Rym: why don't you make a competing patreon for that?
Rym: no cuz then people can send you the money directly.
Scott: yeah my patreon will say every money you give to me you will get nothing in return.
Rym: you could say that just put up a video saying I'm gonna spend all this money on chocolate.
Scott: oh that would be giving them a video.
Rym: see at least they're getting something with my pit.
Rym: well our patreon.
Rym: so anyway it jumped way up and it was a dollar short of the goal to actually do something.
Rym: so no jump past the goal and it's done.
Rym: and even if it drops below the goal I'm fucked and I have to do it.
Rym: so over the next few weeks I'm going to remaster listen to make commentary for and publish on the patreon all eight or possibly nine of the beta episodes of GeekNights.
Rym: that we did in October of 2005 before we officially launched.
Scott: how do you commentary?
Scott: an audio track.
Scott: it's just like listening to an extra person talk at the hope.
Rym: so what I'm actually gonna do is one I'm remastering them which is actually really fucking hard.
Rym: I posted a thing yesterday about how hard it is to fix these audio files because they're so old and busted.
Rym: we didn't know shit back then but and we had terrible equipment especially for the beta episodes.
Rym: we actually bought a lot of equipment before we went live.
Rym: legit guys.
Rym: so but I'm gonna listen to them and then I'm going to basically preface them with an explanation and commentary on Park style.
Rym: yeah because I don't have an hour's worth of things to say about us haltingly talking about what we're gonna do.
Rym: GeekNights sound for an hour in 2005. so the heart the weird thing is I listen to the whole first episode just to kind of like see what I was getting into and it was really interesting because I don't remember being like that nor do I remember that era of my life that well 2005 is further ago than you think.
Rym: I remember Scott's a lot more enthusiastic and I'm a lot more blase.
Rym: it was my idea yeah and with.
Rym: but no you're more enthusiastic about life back then.
Rym: you're into shit.
Rym: we talked about politics and you talked about politics a lot.
Rym: yeah what's it?
Rym: what happened?
Rym: what changed?
Scott: I became smarter.
Scott: so uh yeah how much how much how much affected my talking happened in ten years?
Scott: none.
Rym: so over the next few weeks if you're a patreon subscriber and it's gonna be amazing.
Rym: but I have to warn you guys these are beta episodes.
Rym: I want to be very clear about that.
Rym: if you like GeekNights today or you've liked the last decade of GeekNights these are the precursor to it.
Rym: they are not it.
Rym: they are shockingly poorly done in some situations.
Scott: I mean see have you ever read the first penny arcade comic?
Rym: yeah it's actually not funny.
Scott: I mean they are.
Scott: granted.
Rym: the third one was really funny.
Rym: and then have you looked at it?
Scott: yeah yeah.
Rym: and penny arcade yeah.
Rym: so think of these.
Rym: think of it this way.
Rym: the.
Rym: the audio quality and commentary quality of early GeekNights is similar to the artistic quality of the drawings in the early penny arcades.
Scott: so last but not least you mean the most important thing.
Scott: you were about to forget and continue on to the.
Rym: No one has any proof of that.
Rym: I could edit this whole thing out but I won't.
Rym: PAX East is not this weekend but it is motherfucking next weekend and we are gonna be there.
Rym: I'm actually really pumped about this PAX East because one it's the one PAX we enforce that and actually enforcing is really fun like it's the one thing that makes PAX East really stand out from all the other.
Rym: PAX is just as us going because it's the only PAX we do.
Rym: that it's like this whole extra dimension to a PAX because otherwise it's got less going on.
Rym: yeah it's.
Rym: I'm not gonna lie PAX East is my least favorite PAX cuz it's the most expensive.
Scott: it's a pain in the ass.
Rym: well it's the second most expensive.
Rym: packs.
Rym: Australia is the most expensive.
Rym: sure right it's the most pain in the ass by far.
Scott: it's because I get to Boston.
Scott: it sucks to get a hotel room.
Scott: the building is not comfortable.
Rym: yep Boston forces packs have bag checks and while they're not nearly as horrific as the ones at the Heinz that anime Boston has to deal with they're not pleasant.
Rym: and in fact if I didn't enforce and have a way to literally not go through those security checks I might stop going to PAX East.
Rym: but it is a pax and let me tell you you know we talked about how it's the worst pax.
Rym: that's like saying it's the worst of the scallops.
Rym: at the fancy scallop this is the least tasty.
Scott: filet mignon.
Scott: yeah this restaurant.
Rym: yeah of this of this amazing shellfish sushi from the greatest sushi chef in Japan.
Rym: this is his least inspired one.
Rym: so we're gonna be there.
Rym: we're doing a tari game design on Sunday at 3 30 p.m.
Rym: in the arachnid theater.
Rym: also the omega-thon at this pax east might be the greatest omega-thon lineup I have ever seen.
Rym: mm-hmm it's knit hog but it's not just knit hog.
Scott: wait how isn't pax?
Scott: he's supposed to be the co-op omega-thon.
Rym: it's co-op knit hog.
Scott: that's not possible.
Rym: two players one controller.
Scott: is that what it says?
Rym: that's what I was told.
Scott: I don't believe that.
Scott: I thought that was just someone making an offhand comment.
Rym: I heard that's what it's gonna be.
Scott: I heard that was basically just somebody being like.
Scott: I said that it's co-op and someone was like oh maybe to p1c.
Rym: someone posted that in a different place.
Rym: so we'll see.
Scott: I think I was looking at a different forum.
Rym: might have been the same person.
Rym: that person's in both forums.
Scott: but that's how rumors start.
Scott: someone just has an idea like that a plausible explanation for actually so I heard and then someone believes it as if it's some true thing.
Rym: so I heard that the omega-thon finale finale is going to be first video ball and then the literal agro crag and then Megumi Hashibara is gonna perform.
Scott: I'm buying the video ball.
Scott: video ball is actually so here's some other pax east news.
Scott: the pax east news number one video ball is gonna be there as they have been at every pax for a few years now.
Scott: but video balls very close to being released.
Scott: he's been like writing descriptions for like to be posted on steam with the game and stuff like that and you might think why does the 2d?
Scott: I heard that he's bringing a ginormous television for video ball larger than any before and also has video ball shirts now.
Scott: so video ball is like imminent.
Scott: also other very important pax east news on Thursday before pax begins usually you want to play some games.
Scott: that's how pax goes.
Scott: any pax anywhere on earth.
Scott: before pax starts you play games but it's kind of hard to play games at pax east beforehand because the only place you can go is like this little circle tables that are sort of on this mezzanine in the in the hotel the Westin and it's not a lot of space and it's usually crowded.
Scott: and actually this year there's some kind of event taking up all the tables and the tables down in the bar area aren't comfortable and you gotta buy a drink or whatever it sucks.
Scott: so somebody arranged with the hotel somehow that there is some very large space some ballroom in the Westin that is unused and it will be opened with many tables specifically for gaming.
Scott: so much so in fact that if they see you gaming elsewhere they're gonna tell you to go there and that's gonna probably make it the best pre packs gaming that there is.
Scott: yep and because there's some like manager at the hotel like arrange this.
Scott: they want to like thank this person because it's like a miracle of odd miracles that like a very expensive hotel event space is being given for free.
Scott: so they made an indie go-go thing to collect money to buy a gift for this hotel version is amazing and hopefully that will make the hotel person be even nicer in the future and maybe give us some free catering to go with our free table now
Rym: if only any pecs attendees were staying at the Westin.
Rym: but the omegathon lineup round one is lifted.
Scott: I don't know what that is.
Rym: that's that board game where you wear that the hat with the crane sticking out of the front.
Rym: I've got a movement manipulate stuff on the board.
Scott: I've never seen this.
Rym: you've really never seen lifted.
Scott: I've never seen.
Rym: it's an amazing looking game.
Rym: around.
Rym: two is star wall.
Rym: round three is the knit hog.
Rym: so this is the one omegathon that I could have made it to the end like legit like without anyone stopping.
Scott: it's not bionic commando kaboom.
Rym: yeah the final round is advanced wars.
Rym: that's the Rym.
Scott: the Rym a thon.
Rym: yeah the Rym a thon.
Rym: DDR could be mixed in there.
Rym: sure I'm so almost.
Rym: I can almost do max 300 again.
Rym: I actually been practicing it like every day to try to prove that I'm not so old that I'm dead.
Rym: and I've gotten back to the point.
Rym: so the first half of the song you know it has like the first half and then there's like that pause and then it just kills you.
Rym: I can do the entire first half without missing a step reliably despite being thirty fucking four years old.
Rym: mm-hmm I cannot make it more than halfway through the second half without literally like almost like almost passing out like falling off breathing so heavily.
Rym: it sounds like I'm gonna die.
Rym: I might just be too old.
Rym: it might be that shit might have sailed.
Rym: so we actually debated what.
Rym: do you could make an argument a shitty argument in some cases but an argument on the last that the meat of Nintendo's me Tomo could be talked about in any of the four days.
Rym: sure and it technically does have a game in it.
Rym: it has me drop where you throw the knees down to get stuff and it is at least as much of a game as candy box sure.
Rym: so I guess Tuesday is the best day to talk about it.
Rym: it's a Nintendo thing.
Scott: I think the gaming audience cares the most about the me Tomo more than the tech audience of the anime audience?
Rym: yeah so but also I mean yeah Monday show people.
Rym: they don't care about it.
Rym: it's basically like Nintendo snapchat plus candy box Thursday people.
Rym: I guess we can really use Thursday shows.
Scott: so if I were to work there better for us maybe all right let me tell them oh it's Nintendo's first.
Scott: it's the first ever official mobile app made by Nintendo that is free for everyone to get.
Scott: and you know they had that puzzle dragons Mario thing but I think that was actually on 3ds.
Scott: I don't know if it was ever on phones or anything but anyway.
Scott: so what is me?
Scott: Tomo?
Scott: me Tomo is the social networks or like Twitter but it doesn't work that way.
Scott: here's how it works.
Scott: first you make a me obviously if you don't already have me
Rym: and it appears that this is now like your me to be to end all me's
Scott: maybe anyway you make a me and your me is hanging out in this room that you can't customize at all which I think they're definitely gonna let you customize that room.
Scott: it's yeah they are.
Rym: it's a really ugly room.
Scott: right now though you can customize the clothes on your me but you need to buy clothes with money.
Scott: you start off with enough money to buy the clothes you want.
Scott: but if you want to change clothes you need more money which means you basically just needed to play me Tomo a bunch and you just keep getting money all the fucking time.
Rym: yeah we talk about candy boxes game rewards you like.
Rym: if you listen to someone's answer it's like here's five me moneys.
Scott: yep you just get moneys all the time.
Rym: it's like oh you got 300 me moneys because whatever.
Rym: oh here's another 500 because fuck you.
Scott: yeah just get tons of tons of moneys all the time.
Scott: I don't think you have to pay real.
Scott: I think you can pay real money you can.
Rym: so I actually was you know I was fucking around on a couple days ago and I was like Oh butterfly wings I could buy that and I just click buy and it was like oh you don't have enough money for that is it?
Scott: there hasn't been a single thing I don't have enough money for you.
Rym: and then it was and I was like oh well then it was like you could put your credit card in.
Rym: and I was like nope nope nope you're never.
Rym: my credit card will ever go anywhere near you anyway.
Scott: so yeah the only real thing to use money on I guess is clothing.
Scott: but anyway so you dress your me up or not as in Rym's case and then you go into your room.
Rym: I dress up just only from the ways down.
Scott: sure you go in your room and basically you either a just sort of hear what people are talking about or people come visit you or basically it's all about questions and answers.
Scott: you can't just say whatever you want like on Twitter.
Scott: there's a question and you answer.
Scott: you can write whatever answer you want but you're supposed to answer the question or otherwise.
Scott: what's the point now?
Rym: what's?
Scott: and you see other people's answers and then you can comment on their answers or heart their answers.
Rym: now only friends.
Rym: this is 100% friends only right.
Scott: see this is what makes it different from other things is that it's super friends only like.
Scott: basically you use Twitter and Facebook to connect and find your friends and then you choose who you're gonna friend and you choose who you're not gonna friend and I'm only choosing people that like.
Scott: I know like I've met them.
Scott: there are people there in my like want to be friends list and it's like.
Scott: I've seen their names on the internet.
Scott: I know that they're like a listener or something you know but I don't like.
Rym: no then I'm gonna be even more judicious like now.
Rym: I pretty much don't accept friend requests unless it's someone I know in person right and then so I don't friend them.
Scott: and then because me Tomo is asking you some serious questions some of the questions are so serious I don't even answer them.
Scott: I'm like I'm not answering.
Rym: I joked about that like when it first came out.
Rym: I tweeted and I was something like me Tomo 2016 what's your favorite food?
Rym: me Tomo 2020. what is your darkest shame that you don't want anyone else in the world to ever know and it's basically asking stuff like that.
Scott: yeah it's like oh what do you regret?
Scott: yeah what are three things you look for in a part?
Rym: where did you hide the body right?
Scott: it's like.
Scott: it's really what it is is just not.
Scott: it's not so much a Twitter like what are you doing even though one of the questions is what are you doing lately or what you do last weekend?
Scott: oh it's more like a really highly detailed profile that you share one piece at a time
Rym: which from a design perspective is very interesting because I got to admit if all those questions existed in a social network I would never ever in my life click on anyone I knew to actually read all that crap.
Rym: but here it sort of feeds it to you in the serotonin boosting trickle feed.
Rym: so you're like oh I'm sitting here and I'm bored for three seconds.
Rym: oh hey I guess Scott really is into Oreos lately or whatever.
Scott: all right cool it helps you.
Scott: it actually is nice because it helps you learn about your friends and things you didn't know about them or confirm things you already knew about.
Scott: because I at least I hope you knew about them because you're their friends.
Scott: if it's all new information to you probably unfriend that person.
Scott: it's not someone you're very close with.
Rym: but the design is brilliant because a lot of times platforms like this will overwhelm you with like a million notifications or whatever.
Rym: so when you log back in one day it's like the people who get afraid of their email inbox like they see a thousand unread emails and they kind of just stop checking their email.
Rym: that like that happens more often than you think.
Rym: this game goes out of its way to be like oh you don't want to answer a question right now.
Rym: it's cool.
Rym: it's cool bro I got you.
Rym: we'll deal with it later.
Scott: just and it's like there is technically a feed you can go to the bottom of but you're never gonna get to the bottom of now.
Scott: so you just sort of like poke and listen to a few answers and then stop poking.
Scott: but the serotonin you sat there and kept poking until there were no more answers to here.
Scott: you would be there literally all day.
Scott: I did that when I've only got like 10-15 friends.
Rym: I did that when I had three friends.
Scott: I did that day the first two times I opened the app and then I was never able to do it again in a reasonable amount of time.
Scott: so I never did yep but I did it now.
Scott: it'd probably take hours.
Rym: the design behind this is frighteningly well thought out.
Rym: so you're answering questions right and it just.
Rym: it always helps you two options more or stop.
Rym: so it's like I want to hear more.
Rym: I don't hear on it and as soon as you get bored you hit stop like I'm done with this shit like I gotta go live my real life.
Rym: then it asks you a question yeah as soon as you say you're bored it reinjects novelty.
Scott: it's like oh you don't want to listen to answers anymore.
Rym: make an answer of your own yeah and then you'll stop and then but as soon as you do that then it pops you back out into more novelty and it is really designed to keep you using it for as long as it can.
Rym: it's it borders on kampu gacha style psychology evil.
Scott: there's no complete collecting butts though right yeah so anyway.
Scott: so it also has the clothing.
Scott: so the clothing you can just buy with coins that you earn by listening and listening to answers.
Scott: but also you can get clothing with this game called me drop which is like a dumb.
Scott: it's basically like dropping me and it bounces around.
Rym: it's Plinko.
Rym: it's bad Plinko it's just Plinko.
Scott: there's different.
Rym: Plinko says I don't do it I'm hoarding tickets cuz eventually there'll be some other game I can play.
Scott: eventually there'll be a clothing worth Plinko ing for yep but yeah all the clothes I need me too.
Scott: so yeah right now there's not really a clothing worth.
Rym: so I'm actually using it right now and someone just gave an answer to a question that is real personal.
Scott: okay like people are given law I wish it had the character limit cuz people give like these essay answers and ignore that nonsense.
Scott: sometimes it's funny though it's just like oh my god shut up.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: give the same answer shorter.
Scott: I would have cared but I don't because you wrote an essay.
Scott: deal with it.
Scott: so the other thing has is me photo right.
Scott: so that's another thing you might want the clothes for even if you don't want them permanently on your me is to take good me photos and me photo basically lets you pick any background you want even like photos from your phone or images you do.
Scott: any image you can get onto your phone.
Scott: yeah you can use it background and then you can position up to so many me's in the picture in a lot of different poses and write on it and do all and you can create some pretty creative images using this.
Scott: my favorite thing is to take a movie poster and then replace the people on the movie poster with me's.
Rym: yeah you sent me a really good one.
Rym: you made today.
Scott: I made.
Scott: I made three good ones.
Scott: I'm holding one back though but what does there?
Scott: one on Twitter I sent one to Rym and a holding one back.
Rym: what's real interesting about that is it lets you use anything and you can type anything.
Rym: like if you type fuck a whole bunch.
Scott: it doesn't care at all cuz if you're only doing it to friends exactly.
Rym: Nintendo has finally found a way around its ridiculous fear of people saying inappropriate things unless you're unless you do something that offends your specific friend and your friends can just unfriend you yeah or they can report you or whatever.
Rym: as long as you don't offend your own friends you can do whatever you want which is extra fun because those photos you can put whatever.
Rym: your guy could be hanging out and go to see if that's what your friend group likes and - it has a voice thing where it'll read in all the me's voices and you can customize the voice and it's actually really good.
Rym: the voices remind me of Tokimeki right for the old yeah except way better because I remember in Tokimeki you got to name your character and we were real excited about it and I believe we eventually made the name.
Rym: but I spent forever tweaking the voice until I got it as close as I possibly could and I feel like almost everyone else did that too except our friend cat who made hers this creaky old lady scary voice.
Rym: Chris Rob's actually doing something fun with this thing.
Rym: so if you friend him he made this scary-looking alien monster me and it says that's who that is that's Chris Rob.
Rym: chainsaw suit hollow I didn't.
Rym: it's just a visitor.
Rym: so it comes.
Rym: you have my favorite answer he gave ever.
Rym: it's like for one like he made it with this like scary open mouth and all this nonsense and the voice is like really disturbing but he basically tried to make it a creepypasta.
Rym: so sometimes like it just shows up in your house and it's a little unnerving because it's just like stalking around behind your me but one like one of the questions a while that one of the early questions was.
Rym: so what's the thing that you've been noticing a lot lately and are really into and his answer is your breathing.
Rym: it's fun stuff.
Rym: that's been.
Rym: I've noticed more and more people making clever accounts like that.
Rym: that is it is interesting to be friends with.
Rym: hmm and I'm actually in general impressed with the creativity people are putting into the only of one account.
Scott: it's like if I can make a second account I would totally do that.
Rym: yeah the other thing it's doing that I think is great is that you pick a gender for your guy or your me but none of the functionality in the game appears to be tied to that in any way.
Scott: it only chooses the shape of the body of your me and that's pretty much it and it doesn't even change the shape that much.
Scott: the only real difference is like and you can choose like all the aspects of your me.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: you can use the you know supposedly girl hair or supposedly guy hair on no matter what you know whatever you can.
Scott: any clothing clothing is the same way.
Scott: all options are available to all people.
Rym: I can buy skirts and whatever I bought.
Rym: a kimono was the only one in the game and happens to be a woman's kimono.
Rym: but whatever that's what I got.
Rym: that's what I use.
Scott: yeah I can wear a dress if I want.
Rym: the only difference is if you're a female in the game.
Rym: if you pick that as your gender it looks like you just swap back and forth whenever you want to.
Rym: it doesn't even like.
Rym: it seems to avoid pronouns which is nice but it puts a little like sort of sweatshirt II bra over your bits at the top.
Scott: oh you can't take your shirt.
Rym: oh yeah you can't be shirtless if you're female.
Rym: hmm but you could just be male choose all female characteristics and be as shirtless as you want.
Scott: oh baby yeah flat nipple is chest yeah but I'm.
Rym: I feel like that is fine.
Rym: like Nintendo gets it after the uproar over some poor choices they made in previous things like this they've done.
Scott: yes I think me Tomo is it's a candy box.
Scott: so if you need another candy box you can get this one and stop playing Neko Atsume or whatever.
Scott: yeah and then too if you've got some friends and you like you know you know you use Twitter and things like talk about specific things or you know post links to stuff you know it's like.
Scott: if you if you have a goal of actually wanting to like learn things about your friends or perhaps even go closer with them through a digital means this is I mean it's still just sort of like an app.
Scott: it's not like it's gonna help you grow closer.
Rym: actually the kinds of questions that unless you're still in college and it's four in the morning and you're all sitting in a lounge somewhere you're not gonna ask people these questions in your day-to-day adult life.
Scott: no but you know you can learn more about your friends and they can learn about you and it'll actually it actually works to some extent greater than zero which is pretty amazing for an app.
Scott: no app has achieved that before I check it one and especially not something you would expect from the intent.
Scott: I check it on the sorry Narosh Max.
Rym: yeah well pretty much now it's gonna be this and Pokemon go will be my only candy boxes.
Rym: this is 100% replaced.
Rym: all that 3ds but nonsense I'm just never gonna touch that stuff again.
Rym: I will never ever share a puzzle piece.
Rym: I will never ever ever do anything.
Scott: I'm just gonna.
Scott: I'm gonna keep making sure I have all the puzzle pieces and the gate and then on the 3ds is nice because I can try to get people from all the countries.
Rym: I've got a lot of countries like way more than you and I just don't care.
Rym: I just I'm not gonna do it.
Rym: I've.
Scott: I wonder if anything happens you get all the countries on earth.
Rym: uh you know what.
Rym: if something does there'll be a YouTube video of it.
Scott: I wonder if I got a second 3ds like about a new 3ds and I kept like changing the country on it and kept street passing it.
Rym: would I eventually is all that someone's already done that?
Scott: if it's possible maybe I'll check YouTube.
Rym: yeah but uh we'll see where this goes because it's I mean it.
Rym: it's a game by any reasonable definition of a game.
Rym: it's just.
Rym: it's not an ortho game it's not.
Rym: it's just basically a social network with a few game elements.
Scott: it's as much of a game as cookie cutter.
Scott: yeah right only this one helps you learn about your friends instead of just hurting your hand.
Rym: but it will be interesting to see.
Rym: I suspect Nintendo is going to use this as a like core linchpin in expanding into mobile and into getting everyone to have a Nintendo account to link all the Nintendo things they do together into one thing.
Rym: I think it's most.
Scott: I think it transcends consoles.
Scott: that's the main goal.
Scott: is they finally made Nintendo accounts properly that you know?
Scott: like the same way Xbox Live has accounts and Sony has accounts.
Scott: they should have done that earlier but basically to get people to adopt these new accounts that also go with the new you know Nintendo Club replacement thing they made me Tomo to encourage you to get the Nintendo account because if you don't get the account then you can't really friend people unless you meet them in person and you can't save your me Tomo stuff to the internet.
Scott: yeah don't lose your phone if you lose your phone.
Scott: so you basically really need the account to hook up your stuff.
Rym: so now in the future when they want to eventually stop selling consoles entirely and just have like some simple device that goes the cloud stream whatever and then all the games are on phones which I think is the far future of Nintendo.
Rym: they're setting up for that.
Rym: they're setting up to be not tied to Nintendo hardware.
Rym: I don't know if they'll jump ship on hardware.
Scott: I don't know you're setting up for that.
Scott: they're just setting up for get people to get Nintendo account.
Rym: I think they're setting up to be able to jump ship from hardware down the road if they need to.
Scott: no I don't think Nintendo has never wanted a different hardware and I don't think they will.
Rym: yeah but this and now Pokemon go.
Scott: just stay tuned come on go is a third party thing.
Scott: yeah but Nintendo's letting it happen and Pokemon companies letting it.
Rym: yeah Pokemon is one of the main reasons.
Rym: a lot of people we know even still pay attention to Nintendo.
Scott: Pokemon the Pokemon company is not entirely a hundred percent part of Nintendo.
Rym: yeah what if they go entirely?
Scott: it's just basically attached at the hip.
Rym: yeah what if they and suddenly decided to go entirely phone online?
Scott: I don't know who what kind of contracts exist exactly?
Rym: it's all.
Rym: we'll see what happens.
Scott: but I know that is possible to be an employee of the Pokemon company without being an employee of Nintendo.
Rym: I'll put it this way Nintendo with me Tomo and the Nintendo account is setting up a scaffolding that they could use in a number of ways.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night on the patreon.
Rym: guys you did it.
Rym: you hit the first goal.
Rym: you actually made a lot of work for me.
Rym: that now I actually have to go do over the next few weeks but I am releasing all of the beta episodes of GeekNights on the patreon as soon as I can remaster them listen to them and give you guys some commentary.
Rym: so special thanks now that this is the first episode since.
Rym: women over the line to Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette James David White Christian.
Rym: my dad's name is Richard goops Jess Sean Hayworth my state e.com mechanical mind William Eisen rose Jeremy minor Spartacus.
Rym: Spartacus Kimberly bachelor jar Tava Shan Jonathan shout out to dick Kunstmann a roamer.
Rym: Joe Shiro Joe star Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Clinton Walton.
Rym: run from New.
Rym: Zealand.
Rym: Ryan Robert Lee Ryan parent drew open lender Ray Lavelle Brian citroni Rochelle Montanona Finn Eric Silvera can't melt steel beams.
Rym: kinetic men Aaron Cerise Chris midkiff Chris Knox.
Rym: give me an a colon TLA or give me as SC RYM yowie Sam Gordon Daniel Redmond Chris Adad Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on and also dozens of additional people who do not give more than five dot four dollars and 99 cents a month or who do give a lot but choose not to have the names read.
Rym: you guys made this happen and you guys are all amazing and I will continue to stick to my promise from long ago I will never edit this ending bit.
Rym: I will never rerecord it.
Rym: so if I fuck up trying to say all of your names that is something that you're going to get to experience every time that it happens.
Rym: so stay tuned.
Rym: there's gonna be a whole bunch of crap in the patreon as I remaster those eight or possibly nine beta episodes of GeekNights.
Rym: they're amusing in their own way and that's all I'm gonna say about it for now and I'll leave you with something odd my lair deep dark cave.
Rym: it's a fungus right in the heart of devil's reef a foul abode of pestilent coral walls the ram you lo send their a best floriation spiraling so far beyond belief with a core seeping from my chamber halls.