Rym: It's Monday September 19th 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym, I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: technology books Like the ones with animals on them and the ones without animals on them, but mostly the animal ones I think Was the best one?
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: so some guy a bad guy In New York yep of New Jersey, New Jersey.
Scott: well from New Jersey from New Jersey cuz he you know That's how people do in New Jersey.
Rym: Well, I mean Philly fans.
Scott: he came over and he tried to bomb us shitty like yeah I'll do a very good job.
Rym: like thieves stole two of his bags, and then we're like oh shit.
Rym: There's a ball.
Scott: Okay, we don't know.
Scott: is this dude right, but you know well It's.
Scott: so why did he have a gunfight with the cops when they when they chase after?
Scott: well not to get into the details of It but from what I get I mean if he doesn't if he wasn't guilty of bombing he's guilty of gunfights.
Rym: This shit these aren't Hollywood bombs.
Rym: So it was like a pressure cooker with a flip phone taped to the outside with wires coming out of it.
Rym: So the thieves like accidentally knocked.
Scott: don't you still plug it in somewhere?
Rym: So what do you mean?
Rym: plug it in.
Scott: you got a pressure cooker.
Scott: right it needs to be like.
Rym: no the pressure cook is just A vessel it's just a nice like form container.
Scott: Oh, I thought you were using the pressure aspect of it.
Rym: Do we need to do a money show on bombs?
Rym: I know a lot of our bombs.
Scott: I always thought when you made you want to make a pressure your bomb you need to plug it in.
Scott: so no it works.
Rym: This is why you would be.
Scott: You could just put the bomb in a pot.
Scott: Why do you need to put it in a pressure?
Rym: pressure cookers have much thicker walls and?
Rym: Nicely sealed to compress the blood.
Rym: a lot of reasons.
Rym: use a pressure cooker.
Scott: okay.
Rym: anyway the moral is Real-life.
Rym: bombs by non-professionals are not Hollywood bombs.
Rym: apparently the way to disable these bombs It's just to pull the cell phone off, and then they won't go off
Scott: pretty much, so
Rym: yeah I had this guy you know bombed us and
Scott: meanwhile But when the cops tried to use their robot they fucked up and it blew up.
Rym: Yeah, that one might have been a pipe bomb like.
Scott: it might be different, but some thieves Accidentally designed.
Rym: yeah thieves stole two of the bombs Which says a lot about New York.
Scott: right?
Scott: the point is we're still lucky that no terrorist ever at least very few have actually been smart people who could do a lot of damage.
Scott: yep and So because of that We're not really afraid of them They're not a concern.
Rym: and I finally lived in New York long enough to where I can be that New Yorker.
Rym: He says shut the fuck up and leave us alone.
Rym: We're fine.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: people messaging us and well I am I am like.
Scott: it's nice to know that somebody cares about me.
Rym: Yeah, like.
Rym: I do appreciate when someone's like okay.
Rym: Oh look.
Scott: I'm not a person that is hated.
Scott: No one said oh, I hope Scott died in that bombing.
Scott: Yeah, you didn't get it.
Rym: I am that's like you dead.
Scott: That's nice because I'm not the most likable person.
Rym: so that's good, but you say that but on the grand scale of actual humans You're still way above even like the median.
Scott: I guess I'm not.
Scott: I try hard not to be that guy But yeah only what?
Scott: like how many people do even one person dying?
Scott: I think about like 21 people got hurt.
Rym: so what I gather?
Rym: one person was injured enough to go to the hospital and apparently they Were released mm-hmm.
Rym: the other 28 people didn't even go to the doctor.
Rym: They had cut scrapes abrasions or they put a band-aid on it.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: So maybe some ear damage, but that's fine.
Scott: people messaging us.
Scott: a you do not understand How big New York is.
Scott: B now where it was the bombing?
Scott: like in Chelsea or something?
Scott: So if you knew my apartment was in Chelsea and you knew the radius of like a pipe bomb is like less than a block and you knew that I lived on that Block maybe you should message.
Rym: Yeah, like Nate Silver lives apparently right there, right?
Rym: He tweeted right away.
Rym: He was like guys I'm fine right.
Scott: also like the restaurants are all still open right like if you know That like I live right there.
Scott: like if you heard Bombing in Astoria on the corner Scott lives on.
Scott: then if you message me that would make sense But I would probably message you first.
Scott: Well, if you hear even bombing in like LIC by rims apartment, you don't need to message me.
Scott: You know how far away that is, you know big LIC is.
Scott: Yeah, and do you know how many people are in New York?
Scott: If a hundred people get killed by a bomb the odds of it being me are so small.
Scott: I mean if this one car accident in the town Bumblefuck town you live in that kills like point one.
Rym: There's no population kills one person.
Scott: There's a greater odds of that being you then a hundred people dying in New York City the odds of that being me Math.
Scott: so if shit goes down in New York do not message us also the harm caused by that bomb.
Scott: You know itself and this crazy guy is bad But it's so small compared to the harm caused by the fear that suburban people have.
Rym: Well because it's telling no one in New York was tweeting like oh my god.
Scott: The harm caused by the existence of the TSA alone is like that guy times 100,000. and the reason the TSA exists is because you suburban people are cowards unlike us New Yorkers.
Scott: So stop being fucking afraid.
Scott: stop watching the goddamn news Right.
Scott: learn something about to New York.
Scott: or if you want us to respect you as a human being move to New York.
Rym: not to say Don't consume news.
Rym: Don't watch news.
Rym: Don't watch watching news.
Rym: You're watching CNN.
Scott: Don't consume the typical fear-mongering nonsense news That's making you think that way.
Scott: now.
Rym: now to get back to your actual point because you know There's a story because you know the anniversary of 9/11 was recently.
Scott: Oh, thank you New Yorkers for all the funny tweets about how we don't give a fuck.
Rym: Oh my god I saw FARC was pretty great about that.
Scott: I mean, that's one good thing about the suburban people being so afraid.
Scott: is that us New Yorkers get to be like Well, look how brave we are.
Scott: Why?
Scott: yes, we aren't as cowardly as you suburban folk.
Rym: Thanks for reminding us on September 11th when the attacks happen the real attacks Scott and I were in Rochester at RIT, right?
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: and they happened.
Rym: and then every relative I had tried to call me on the phone That day and in the days to come to find out if I was okay.
Rym: And if I was there.
Rym: and I want to point out that home was Detroit Going to school in Rochester and the 9/11 attacks happened in New York City a six mile drive.
Rym: New York City is further away from where I was in college than where I was in college was from Detroit.
Scott: Yeah, New York City is a six mile drive from Rochester.
Scott: six Seven maybe mile.
Scott: No sick hour hour drive You know what.
Scott: even six miles away from the World Trade Center you would have been just fine.
Rym: It is a five and a half hour drive if you are insane.
Rym: Yeah but and even now the other thing is I guess it's more people just like the common thing you're expected to say is like hey, are you okay?
Rym: But everyone who said that to me knew I was okay because one I don't stop tweeting Like.
Rym: you'll know something's wrong if you hear about a bombing and then rims not tweeting because I'm tweeting all the time And I'm just doing shit on the internet all the time.
Rym: So I think it's more that people say hey, are you okay?
Rym: But really they mean hey, sorry that happened near you, but that sounds kind of weird.
Scott: to say to someone what you should say is Nothing.
Scott: and also well, I'll make it much more in If say also suburban people, are you okay?
Scott: I mean you're driving that really dangerous car every day.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I'm worried about you, dude.
Rym: We should message scojo every day and be like, oh my god.
Rym: Are you okay?
Rym: I heard you had to drive to work.
Scott: Yeah, it's Cuz they like.
Scott: in all seriousness driving is fucking dangerous.
Scott: Like I am scared things.
Scott: I'm scared of getting in a car being near a car cars.
Rym: I'm less afraid of a car than biking nice to car.
Rym: I mean if I list the things that I'm literally actually not joking scared of Leases cars are like the top of the list.
Scott: terrorist bombing me is so even though it just fucking happened is So far down the list.
Scott: I'm more scared of like an animal in Bed bugs.
Rym: Yeah, I was about to say my list is number one I'm afraid of being hit by a car while riding my bike.
Rym: number two Being hit by a car while walking on the sidewalk.
Rym: number three car four car five car truck.
Rym: six bedbugs.
Rym: seven stabbin hobo ATSA.
Rym: nine regular cops.
Scott: Terrorist is so not something I'm afraid of.
Rym: if terrorists bombed New York and killed a person Every single day of the year in order to move I would still be more afraid of cars than a bomb.
Scott: in order to move Up the list terrorist would have to like be so smart and be so much more frequent Than they have ever been.
Rym: and at that point then, you know, that's when weird stuff happens and things change.
Rym: I mean, I've I've spent a lot of time in places where that sort of thing happens and it sucks And I don't want America to get to that point.
Rym: Yeah I don't want to go through a metal detector to go to the mall and you know what we won't have to if you suburban People aren't so afraid.
Scott: if you stop being afraid Then you won't want to put up a metal detector because you'd be.
Scott: I'm ready to get on a plane with no security whatsoever.
Scott: Yeah, I will walk onto a plane the way you walk onto the subway.
Scott: I don't give a fuck.
Rym: So it's like that in Singapore Scott.
Rym: when you go to the airport to Singapore You'll you'll just like you check in and then you're walking and you're walking and you're walking and then you realize you never hit a security Line, you're just literally at your gate.
Scott: That's how airplanes were in the US and then you know what they do.
Rym: There's one metal detector at the door to the jetway and you just go through that metal detector.
Scott: getting on the plane I'll go in without the metal detect.
Scott: I mean, I'm okay with it.
Rym: I don't give a shit, but Like bang for your buck and bang for your inconvenience metal detector is like one of the greatest.
Scott: yeah No, I mean, I'm not gonna say get rid of the metal detector But I'm saying if it wasn't there I would still get on the plane except when the TSA They actually did get rid of the metal detector.
Rym: They did.
Rym: Yeah anyway We're fine guys.
Rym: You got any news?
Scott: I do have a news For people who don't know.
Scott: right now and I think it's in Germany There's an event called photo Kina and photo Kina is basically it's like the packs of cameras Right.
Scott: This is where all the camera companies announced.
Rym: So what's the Photokina thon finale.
Scott: I don't know But there were mad tons of camera announcement type things, right?
Scott: So there's the GoPro Hero 5. we knew was coming.
Scott: It's out to be it's good.
Scott: It's mad waterproof without any case on it.
Scott: All the other GoPro did to put like a plastic thing around this one you can just throw in the fucking ocean.
Scott: I might get one because I have a GoPro - I'm Bob and it's so busted and old.
Rym: I'm gonna go like I use my GoPro - a few times.
Scott: I use it a lot.
Rym: when it came out the video quality was amazing.
Rym: But by modern standards, it looks like shit.
Scott: It does look like shit.
Rym: So and like.
Rym: it's so bad that I can't use it as like a backup camera at our panels.
Rym: But the new GoPro like that's better than the camcorder.
Scott: I mean I can use it.
Scott: I mean it the new ones gonna be better, but if I use for what it costs, right?
Scott: It's like 400 bucks to get the top of the line one.
Scott: Yeah It's like it's a deal right.
Scott: and then they also announced the GoPro's official drone Which looks to be like as far as drones go a really fucking good drone, but what am I gonna do with the drone?
Scott: Get it confiscated.
Rym: Here's what I would do with the drone and it's the most compelling use case I have is I would have it follow me skiing.
Scott: I don't think this one can follow you on its own.
Scott: It's a remote control by hand.
Rym: Yeah Well in that case to get a friend to do it.
Rym: But I actually I would just buy one of the fancy ones that follows you because those exist.
Rym: The problem is every ski resort in the world is banned drones.
Scott: Yeah, it'll fucking kill somebody.
Rym: Probably not.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: So So here's the problem little gust of wind blows someone skiing real fast up spinning blade in the face.
Rym: Well one the drones fly real high like, you know, they're not like be right behind you.
Scott: Well, it's a GoPro camera.
Scott: It's got a wide-angle lens.
Scott: You want to get it close?
Scott: Yeah Anyway, because we use it to spy on other announcements that they announced the Panasonic gh5 will be out early next year.
Rym: It's meaning if you want a badass camera wait until that time and buy the gh4.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it's better than the gh4 but it's not better in a way that'll matter to most people.
Scott: It's like do you really need your 4k at 60 FPS instead of 30?
Scott: Maybe you know, do you really need for two to?
Scott: 10-bit color instead of four to oh eight bit color Recorded to the SD card.
Rym: I mean most people who need the extra two bits of color are using external recorders anyway Actually, so if we were doing a lot more green-screen compositing stuff, that would be real fucking useful Maybe but we don't like I don't care Green screen back there.
Rym: I'm not gonna.
Scott: yeah, it can do like there's a 4k photo mode or two gh4.
Scott: Oh, it's like, you know, this is stuff like that.
Scott: Yeah There's a lot of in things happening in the world of like Polaroid type cameras.
Scott: Fuji makes this instax film which is basically Polaroid.
Scott: You take a photo the thing goes and comes out and it's been around for a while.
Scott: But they've got like a new camera and they I think Like is also making a more expensive version of the same exact camera.
Scott: that but it cost more money.
Scott: cuz there's like on it.
Scott: Oh, yeah, right.
Rym: So so totally the side but I was looking at the G if I got the gh4 and a decent lens For only a little bit more money.
Rym: There's this Sony like for real studio camcorder.
Scott: That is just like a studio camera Tons of studio camcorders that are really great.
Rym: But there's this one Sony one that's real great and cost about the same as a gh4 plus a good lens.
Scott: I mean if you really need a quality camera the Sony a7s is still like the king of.
Scott: yeah It's like the best you can see in the darts amazing.
Scott: It costs $4,000.
Rym: Yeah, then we don't how often you need to see us in the.
Rym: actually the panel rooms are pretty dark.
Rym: That would be useful.
Scott: but would you announced a mirrorless camera that has like an enormous almost, you know Like medium format sensor, it's like huge.
Scott: I guess Hasselblad already has a mirrorless camera with a giant sensor on it.
Scott: So people are making big old sensors.
Scott: There's all kinds of real interesting stuff is happening and it's interesting to see how like Even though like CP cuz cuz camera making these days digital camera making is really closely tied to like Moore's law Cuz you're making sensors or this basically the same as CPUs, right?
Scott: It's like we're printing on silica.
Scott: It's the same kind of process similar right and you know How come we're still managing to make huge advancements in camera land and we're not making this huge advancements in CPU land?
Rym: Well, they're not general purpose.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: I mean, it's kind of like good like, you know video cards and CUDA processing and all that.
Rym: because you're not general purpose You can be real efficient.
Scott: Well, I don't think they're being.
Scott: I don't think video cards are efficient.
Scott: I thought video cards are more like monster, you know, like What's it called well the old voodoo cards like that, yeah, it's like, you know, it's like a. You know, it's like a Hot Wheels, right?
Scott: It's like you.
Scott: just I just you know, put the biggest fucking engine in there.
Scott: Who cares how fuel-efficient it is.
Scott: Just go as fast as possible.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Whereas the CPU is actually trying to be like efficient with the electricity usage It's like GPUs got its own like power cables coming into it.
Rym: So in other actually semi-related news Netflix has this meridian test footage.
Rym: That is like a benchmark video to be used to test things like end-to-end processing or video pipelines or 4k TVs or whatever and They're releasing it Apparently Creative Commons so that anyone can use it to make it like this super official Standard for testing video pipelines.
Scott: So it's basically just a video.
Rym: It's there's a little more to it.
Scott: the same way everyone uses that picture of the the lady with the hat for photo.
Rym: Yeah, our testing it's kind of like that.
Rym: But there's a lot more supporting data and stuff behind it and they're basically releasing the whole thing just to make everyone's lives better.
Rym: So everyone can use it for all their testing and codex.
Rym: So just like an AVI file or something I don't know what format it actually comes in because the problem with the article I'm looking at is that I click through all The sub articles.
Rym: they still don't get me - oh there it is here I can download it.
Rym: It's a bunch of XML files and MXF files.
Rym: I'm sure which are UHD format.
Scott: I'm sure premiere knows what to do with it meridian shrc and xx us and nr.
Rym: 51 LTRT UHD Ovie, oh my god.
Rym: So this video is 89 gigabytes.
Rym: Sure Maybe I'll.
Rym: uh, I guess it's creative Commons.
Rym: I'll just stream it every day and make a channel.
Rym: That's what I do.
Scott: How are you gonna store this thing?
Rym: Any of my hard drives?
Scott: And you're on a terabyte hard drive that will take up 10%.
Rym: I've got ish that much space but the NAS does not have that much space, you know You don't need.
Scott: you don't need this video though.
Rym: No, I'm not gonna download.
Rym: What am I gonna?
Rym: what about what?
Rym: Our video pipeline is so babies first as it is.
Rym: So in other news, this is just kind of cool so I just want to highlight it real quick.
Rym: but if you have an Apple - There's no s update you can download.
Rym: perhaps an Apple - you can download protoss 2.4 Yes, and install it.
Scott: Yes, and it actually adds a lot of functionality to the Apple - yes I know there's no an Apple - really doesn't have an operating system so much.
Scott: It just sort of boots off, you know ROM or disk drive the old days.
Rym: We had a game.
Scott: You'd basically boot the game right anyway But you put a floppy disk in there and you turn it on.
Scott: it automatically starts loading the disk into the RAM And then it runs it.
Scott: that's how it works, right?
Scott: Yeah, if you want to switch you get to flip the disk over.
Scott: it unloads most of the first disk from the RAM mostly You know.
Scott: you put the second disk in it loads that off the disk and then you're good to go.
Scott: So so the best the biggest on the disk.
Scott: you would put protoss Right that - as like the thing that you put on the disk along with all your software.
Scott: So if you put a disk in your Apple - and you turn your Apple - on it says do protoss and then your game starts Loading.
Rym: so the main feature they add in this release is bitsy by which is a menu driven program Launcher that allows for navigation through files across multiple floppy disks and then someone added or hack USB floppy disks.
Rym: The way actually, you know the runs in less than a kilobyte of RAM leaving plenty of room to actually run.
Scott: I have a RAM expansion in my Apple - GS which already has more RAM than your average Apple - you know I load software.
Scott: I'm Apple - there's two really clever ways.
Scott: I do it because I have I have five and a quarter inch floppy disk drives now, but they're they work.
Scott: Okay, they don't work great.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I can't get the three and a half inch one.
Scott: They're actually hard to come by the drives and the disks for that even though that's the best way.
Scott: There's two other methods.
Scott: I use method number one I take my iPhone or something and I take a headphone cable and I go out of my iPhone and into the back of the Apple - and then I Find a WAV file of the software and press play and it's like a cassette tape.
Scott: They used to be able to load software from cassette tapes, right?
Scott: So I can set tape can be turned into a WAV file and I just play the WAV file at full volume on my phone.
Scott: The Apple listens to it thinks it's a cassette tape and then you have software.
Scott: the other way I do it is I have a cable a fancy cable and one end is USB on my real computer and on the other end is The thing that you would.
Scott: that would the cable that would come out of a modem if you got a modem for your Apple - GS.
Scott: so then I type some stuff on the Apple - and press enter and then I run some software on my computer and point it at a file and I say computer that file send it and it sends that file over the USB and the Apple - thinks it's getting a file from the modem over the telephone.
Scott: It has no idea that this is a modern computer.
Scott: And then boom Oregon trails on the Apple - screen.
Scott: so those are my two methods of loading software.
Rym: I'm Apple - the other cool thing.
Rym: It's got is a boot utility.
Rym: That's under 400 bytes.
Rym: So it'll fit on one block of storage and Yeah, that's it.
Rym: This is just super cool.
Scott: I don't know that.
Scott: maybe I'll load this up.
Rym: You probably should.
Rym: now if you don't happen to have an Apple - laying around.
Rym: There's a link on this.
Rym: the thing I'm linking to where there's an online full web emulator where you can just pretend you've got an Apple - and run whatever arbitrary applications on it all in your browser.
Scott: Yeah, I think the thing that you want if you're the software if anyone's wondering I think it's called ADT Is the thing that you use to load, you know?
Scott: Connect between a modern computer and an Apple computer.
Scott: an old Apple - I also have a Mac plus but that is harder to interface.
Scott: Even though it's a newer better computer than Apple - actually think it might well.
Scott: the one I have is has one megabyte of RAM It's not a 512 K. It's basically the same computer as a Mac.
Scott: 512 K only has a megabyte of RAM and a better screen and it looks better.
Scott: But that's harder to interface with modern computers.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so it's computer buying season.
Rym: I mean Scott bought a new HD PC.
Rym: a bunch of our friends bought new computers.
Scott: I mean way CPC is so fast like every game is a Pam.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Emily's upgrading the hard drives in her PC.
Rym: I bought a bunch of PCs for work.
Rym: I'm real close to upgrading my PC and it's it's time.
Scott: Does anyone want my old HD PC?
Scott: It's like it's not bad.
Scott: It just isn't fast.
Scott: Yeah If you just want to watch videos on your TV and play games that aren't super fancy 3d like it can play rocket league at Low frames my HDPC performs worse playing rocket league than my laptop does.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, it's it's not bad, you know.
Scott: as an HD PC My old one is still great.
Scott: In fact, if you took out the magnetic drive and put an SSD or just add an SSD It would probably.
Scott: that's probably most of the slowness right there.
Scott: Is that Drive?
Scott: You know so and you could get a newer low.
Scott: It can only take low profile video cards because of the case but it has an old Radeon like something garbage II.
Scott: you could put in I think a Nvidia 740 because those come in low profile mine at least and it would be 460. it would be a little better if you did that, you know, it wouldn't be much better, but it would be better.
Rym: Anyway, well the reason I haven't you know, we've talked about like what computer I would buy.
Rym: We've done bunch of shows on that recently, but this is just a YouTube channel.
Rym: It's kind of generic YouTube YouTube channel with all the YouTube YouTube stuff in it.
Rym: But if you don't know the stuff like what's this?
Rym: What good CPU should I buy?
Rym: or what the hell is a PCI Express lane?
Rym: And why does this motherboard have 20 and this has 16 and all that kind of crap.
Rym: Ah You should just go to this channel and watch these videos because the reason we're not gonna do videos like this Is that I was gonna do a few but these guys much better more production value.
Rym: well The thing is this is a level of knowledge that you only have if you're basically constantly currently building computers Like they have.
Rym: like that's your thing Yeah, or you're literally going through the process right now and then your information is obsolete almost immediately.
Rym: Like if you ask me in 2001 I could make every one of these videos for the technology in 2001 but in 2003 Fuck if I know I'm gonna watch a video like this, right?
Scott: But yeah, if you need to know about what's going on in the hobby the nerdy hobby of computer building This.
Scott: these are.
Scott: this is a really good YouTube channel.
Scott: I watch their video on thermal paste cuz like.
Scott: should I get some?
Scott: do I need some?
Rym: Yes, you do need some.
Scott: Well, apparently if you get the if you use the Intel stock cooler the built-in stuff that's on the bottom is just fine.
Scott: You don't need any more.
Rym: So the one I'm linking to is what CPU should I buy?
Rym: Because the thing is There's a lot of CPUs out there and with every generation There's only a couple that are worth buying and most of them are literally like worthless.
Rym: And the video does a really good job of explaining why?
Rym: So you got a thing of the day.
Scott: I do so.
Scott: it's just.
Scott: you know It's a typical internet kind of nice good feeling video.
Scott: somebody This person has a YouTube channel where they do the domino projects.
Scott: You set up a bunch of dominoes and knock them down and if you in a beautiful fashion, that's a hobby.
Scott: I do not have the patience and I think she said this at the end of the video.
Scott: I didn't watch it again.
Scott: So I don't remember.
Scott: I think she said this is a third biggest project ever Third biggest thousands and thousands of dominoes and in this crazy awesome spiral.
Scott: So it was really fun to watch this and mesmerizing and took a lot of effort set it up.
Scott: I'm sure I would not have the patience and I would not do it.
Scott: I'm sure I would knock it over like a thousand times.
Rym: as a kid I did not have the patience for domino rally.
Rym: We had domino rally and there is a machine that would even like lay your dominoes down for you And I still could not deal with that crap, right?
Scott: So You know what?
Scott: You just get all the benefits without the work by watching on YouTube.
Scott: Yeah, here you go.
Rym: I guess the only benefit you don't get is being in the room and hearing that like clicking live locally Yeah, but I mean you don't get the benefit of being the person who knocks it over.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah It's like how satisfying must it be to hit that first domino with your hand?
Rym: Oh, has someone ever kick-started that?
Rym: just kick-start like I'm gonna make a big fucking domino and whoever gives the most money gets to start It.
Rym: yeah, and just keep doing that over and over again and just live your life being the domino guy Back back if someone hasn't done that yet.
Rym: I think there's room in the world for one person doing that Maybe.
Rym: so if it doesn't already exist and you don't want to go to college There's your life In The better moment.
Rym: we got no conventions till magfest which is coming up in January.
Rym: good.
Rym: We'll be there.
Rym: We're mages again.
Rym: We'll be on all those like gaming magic missile.
Rym: Yeah 1d4 plus your level or whatever.
Scott: egg fest attacks darkness.
Rym: I'm really looking forward to magfest because I love packs.
Rym: we go to.
Rym: a lot of packs is but Magfest is the con that has I don't know.
Rym: There's something about.
Rym: just for him dig-dug.
Rym: Yeah I got a Scott beat me pretty hard and dig-dug a pack.
Rym: So I got a reclaim.
Rym: I played dig-dug recently I had not and it showed real bad.
Rym: I got ready.
Scott: I'll play a little dig-dug on my new HD PC.
Rym: Oh, I think my HD PC can run dig-dug.
Scott: So I think it can go to magfest.
Rym: We'll be there.
Rym: Otherwise, uh, Nothing, we're just doing our stuff again.
Rym: So I'll check out Scott's YouTube channel.
Rym: Check out my youtube channel.
Rym: Check out all our stuff.
Rym: Scott.
Rym: rate and subscribe.
Rym: Yeah, got a rate and subscribe.
Scott: Don't do any of those things.
Rym: sign up for the GeekNights loot crate.
Scott: No, we don't have one.
Scott: Thank God Scott.
Rym: No, that's the test genius.
Rym: Let's make a GeekNights loot crate.
Scott: It's all the shit.
Scott: We want to get rid of in our apartment.
Rym: Yeah, you'll get like all my old tech books over there one week.
Scott: Oh my god, we should do this.
Scott: This is actually a good idea.
Rym: My sign up for it, too.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: I have so much.
Scott: It's mostly comic books You're gonna get.
Scott: you're gonna get comic books But you're gonna get like a GTX for you know What one person's gonna get initially volume one and someone else is gonna get initially volume three, dude Someone's gonna be the same person.
Rym: Someone's gonna get a whole bunch of batteries.
Rym: I don't need anymore.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: The rule would be it won't actually be garbage and have to be something that has some actual value.
Scott: I will we should.
Scott: I mean the price.
Scott: the subscription would basically be like the price of shipping plus a dollar per month.
Scott: Yep, and I would send you like two things per person because it doesn't cause more to ship two things than one thing.
Scott: Yeah, anything that you know what we do?
Scott: The stuff would always fit in a UPS flat rate whatever.
Scott: so the price doesn't change.
Scott: Yeah, and us only.
Rym: I think that I think we could do this.
Scott: I can get rid of all my garbage.
Rym: Yeah, but it's garbage.
Rym: That's what has a non zero monitor.
Scott: Otherwise, it would just go in the garbage.
Scott: Literally this stuff I don't want anymore.
Scott: That's probably nerdy.
Rym: I got a lot of like plastic figures and that kind of stuff books.
Rym: Yeah a lot of books, you know stuff Looking around this room.
Rym: I see like a hundred things that would immediately go in there.
Scott: Oh my god, maybe we should do this.
Rym: What do you might get a parsec award?
Rym: So in typical fashion we looked around the room until we came up with a show topic for today.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and what's in that bookshelf way over there?
Rym: a whole bunch of O'Reilly books.
Scott: I hope we haven't done this show already.
Rym: Well tech books in general, you know, those sort of like any book.
Rym: I think I think we're gonna qualify this.
Rym: are we just talking like computer technology?
Rym: because I have other Techno like I have electronics books.
Scott: I mean, let's just do what we can right and get the show over with.
Rym: yeah but the books that are technical references to things typically O'Reilly books or like the books you get to pass your CCNA or whatever anything in the section of the bookstore where those books are The kind of book that your company like even die.
Scott: even dummy books like the air the dummy book At least the ones that are by technology.
Rym: I've always been kind of deeply bothered by the existence of the dummy books Because they basically say I am a person who self identifies as a moron.
Rym: Who wants someone else to treat me like I'm an idiot and teach me superficial things about something.
Scott: Yeah, but you know what?
Scott: I only ever bought one of those in like 1996 I don't know how to make do mods about JavaScript for dummies cuz you know what?
Scott: It was the only JavaScript book in the bookstore.
Rym: It's not like I could go to Amazon and buy a book But then I bought this other do mod book that was way better and way more technical.
Rym: and then I made do mods so Back in the day.
Scott: We used to have to used to have to buy these right because even though you know for certain things You were working on there were references you could get online.
Scott: even in the slow crappy dial-up internet days Those references often were not complete.
Scott: They didn't tell you everything.
Rym: they were out of date.
Scott: They were added or they were just API documentation, but not actually teaching you anything.
Scott: Right, like you can go.
Rym: list of all the functions.
Scott: great Yeah, you can get the job Java API docs, but that won't teach you Java.
Scott: You need to know Java to make use of that, right?
Scott: So you'd need another book to teach you Java and there was nowhere to just learn Java.
Scott: Yeah out of nothing.
Rym: and back then there weren't like videos online.
Rym: It wasn't.
Scott: it was no YouTube.
Rym: yet Academy there was no just no just.
Rym: hey you want to learn Python.
Rym: Here's an emulator in a browser.
Rym: Let's go.
Scott: Yeah, so nowadays you don't really need these books because books are nowadays.
Scott: even if you get the books They're out of date and they're useless and the internet has much better reference and there's nothing in the book that the internet won't have.
Rym: Well, you've already hit on.
Rym: I think we need to separate.
Scott: already in the olden days The book was the best and the internet was kind of not helpful.
Rym: So, you know how?
Rym: with board games like in that game rules panel We talked specifically about how they're.
Rym: the rules of a game serve two functions the teaching of the game and the reference during the game.
Rym: Teaching and reference are two very different use cases.
Rym: even here I still think there are cases for the teaching side in books But the reference side I don't think there is anymore at all.
Scott: well, the thing is for the reference side.
Scott: the online reference is going to get always gonna be more up-to-date and better.
Scott: but You know, sometimes for certain kind of things if you're looking stuff up a lot constantly a book could actually be a well-indexed book Could actually be faster and more efficient.
Rym: So based on the quality of the there was a time in my life when I did a lot of DNS DHCP Samba like IT network admin crap because I managed this data center like back at IBM.
Rym: So even if there had been online references where I could look this stuff up Having a book on all that stuff like locally even with little bookmarks in it cuz I wouldn't remember all the weird syntax of setting up like some nonsense Samba whatever.
Rym: all the time, you know and Even if online references were good, I looked this stuff up regularly.
Rym: So I just had the book sitting on my desk and if I were doing a job like that today I'd actually just go to Stack Overflow every time.
Rym: but the better solution would be to have that book.
Scott: on my dad There is one small case but that applies to a not insignificant number of people.
Scott: Where when you have to do technical work without any internet access for his military Contractor right like you're stuck in a place.
Scott: So there's no internet like in a secret base or a boat hedge funds space.
Scott: It's like suddenly you need to program something in like some language and you need documentation.
Scott: If you don't get a book, you're gonna have something printed out because you don't got anything else.
Scott: Yeah Well, you might have downloaded the documentation beforehand and brought it with you on a USB sticker.
Rym: Is that the online references which are objectively superior in pretty much every way almost never have an actually useful Form that's downloadable.
Rym: Mm-hmm, especially if it's like like even the Python documentation.
Rym: Like you're better off bringing a book on the plane.
Rym: Well, at least on your kindle.
Scott: something people don't know is at least if you have a Linux machine most Linux distributions You know even most Unix is when you install something.
Scott: Let's say you go app get install Apache on a Debian machine, right by default I'm pretty sure it installs the documentation.
Scott: you go into user local share doc Apache and the Apache documentation is actually there in HTML form waiting for you.
Scott: And if you look at the default Apache Configuration that comes on a lot of Linux distributions if you app get install Apache and then in your browser go to localhost slash doc you'll actually get the index of all the documentation that's been installed locally because it actually By default, that's one of the folders.
Scott: It's like a web folder.
Rym: there was a time when I did that sort of thing all the time because I was always fucking around with like NTP and the best patchy crowd.
Scott: and if your Linux machine is set up in this way and you actually use that It's actually really useful because that Documentation will always exactly match the version that you have installed.
Scott: if you app get installed memcache, let's say I don't even know if memcache has documentation, but let's say it does and It installs memcache Documentation.
Scott: that memcache documentation will be for the version of memcache that you have just installed.
Scott: and if you go online There might be some newer memcache and that documentation might mess you up because your machine has an older one.
Scott: that is Every time you go to the memcache website to look at the documentation We'd have to click through to say show me the old version.
Scott: This is the version I have.
Scott: But if you go to the localhost documentation, well, it's the right version.
Rym: That is a particularly important if you're working on a project where there's a fixed version of the thing you're using Like web frameworks they change all the time or
Scott: even if you use like a you know a stable version a Linux distribution It won't upgrade the software that you have.
Scott: It will give you that newer like.
Scott: vim8 just came out But I don't have vim8 because if I app get install vim I get vim7.
Scott: It won't give me vim8 until there's like a newer OS.
Rym: like I remember my last job.
Rym: I was working on this project.
Rym: I was making this big like soap server to do a bunch of soap nonsense and I got this Python library and I wanted to use it.
Rym: So I install everything and I go through the tutorial just like let's see how this thing works because I wasn't super up on soap either.
Rym: so I was learning soap and this library and None of the tutorial shit worked at all.
Rym: And I eventually realized that I was using the tutorial online Was the current version and the only version available in my distro was an old version.
Rym: so I upgraded to the newer version.
Rym: But then the version I upgraded to was newer than the docs on the website And if I went to the newer version of the docs on the website, there were no tutorials.
Rym: Yeah, all right now the other than I gave up and I used a different library.
Scott: The other thing is that you know people who tend to be really good at writing tend to write books, right?
Scott: so there are a few really famous really historic computer books and The tutorials that are in those books are way better than anything that you're gonna find online.
Scott: If you want to learn from a book and not from say a teacher or a class or anything.
Scott: They're pretty much the best way to learn certain topics that you're not going to find Anything online because and you know, I mean you could pirate these books online.
Scott: That's what you know.
Rym: It's like.
Rym: it's like finding historical event and reading the Wikipedia page about it as opposed to reading like a particular Book research and written by a historian.
Scott: Yeah, and yeah, they both have That book online, but you're still reading that book.
Scott: Yeah, so here's the important books that I am aware of that I have read right.
Scott: So the first book is the structure and interpretation of computer programs By Gerald Sussman and Hal Evelson and this book basically has actually been rewritten many times.
Scott: You'll you'll see it referred to as s ICP and I think the original one was written for the language called scheme But which is really similar to lisp.
Scott: It's a functional language But this book has been rewritten using different programming languages over and over again.
Scott: So you can find s ICP for CS IP CP for Python.
Scott: you can find all these books The original ones the best and this book even though it teaches you scheme a useless computer language effectively.
Scott: If you learn the shit in this book You will learn the fundamental concepts of functional computer programming which applies to all programming.
Scott: So if you can do the shit in this book, you can program in anything.
Scott: Yeah, so it's a really good book.
Scott: Other books right?
Scott: There's the C book the C book That started C and if you program the way they program in the C book, you know Which teaches like the standards of the C language?
Scott: That's not what modern C looks like.
Scott: so it really won't help you in a practical sense that way But it will help you be good at understanding how C works, right?
Scott: So like, you know, it's it's mechanisms in its design, which is a beautiful thing.
Scott: So that's an important book to read even if you don't do it.
Scott: There's a book called Oh What's the name of this book?
Scott: I forget.
Scott: let me let me look at you talk about some other book.
Rym: So you think I can't think of any in particular because most of the things I've learned About just computing in general.
Rym: I've learned by reading a specific technical reference and then implementing something.
Rym: Yeah Okay.
Scott: So here's the book.
Scott: So this book is code complete by Steve McConnell.
Scott: This is actually like a Microsoft book and it's written mostly from the perspective like Microsoft C++ programming.
Scott: But it doesn't matter because it's not about the language.
Scott: you're learning a language.
Scott: This is a book about coding style like how to name variables and how to organize code and it applies to all programming ever.
Scott: and Like this book is like it's big and you're like, whoa How can I read this giant textbook?
Scott: and it's like no this might be like the most important book You can read as a programming person.
Scott: It's it's like if you read this your code will change in the code that people can actually fucking read Without wanting without wanting to kill you.
Scott: There's one other book that was written by an RIT professor and was never Acquired in a class that I took but was recommended in a lot of classes I took and it was somewhat expensive and I was always like, oh, why should I buy the professor's book?
Scott: That's optional and expensive.
Scott: It's not even my professor this guy.
Rym: at least he made it optional.
Scott: Well, I wasn't in his class.
Scott: other other CS professors in the department were telling us to optionally buy the other professor's book and I. it's really hard to get this book and even more expensive now than it was when I bought it because I think it Hasn't been printed in forever, but it's called pointers on C and this book.
Scott: I Mean, you know not to shill for the RIT professor But if you don't understand pointers this helps you understand pointers better than any other book That has ever been like.
Rym: it's what it comes down to is, you know in anything you want to read Like.
Rym: I've read books that are like that about audio production and those sorts of things.
Rym: Or like using premiere like either go to like do like.
Rym: you can go to a place like digital tutors and watch like a tutorial.
Rym: But tutorials that seems how most people teach and learn technology stuff today.
Rym: They sort of give you a very narrow path Which is very useful if you have a goal and your goal is to complete the goal as opposed to generally learn the thing
Scott: Yeah, but
Rym: as opposed to computers like a lot of people can set up a DNS server if they need to.
Rym: But like I studied DNS to where I know the history and the context and like the broad Way the DNS works that does not necessarily help me achieve that particular goal.
Rym: In fact, it slows me down.
Rym: Yeah, if you try to learn like why AAA records are different from a records that's gonna slow you down.
Rym: I actually don't set up your go daddy.
Scott: I actually don't know the difference in a AAA is just an IPv6.
Scott: I thought I was about here.
Scott: I was about to guess that I Run into that problem a lot.
Scott: actually with the Photoshop tutorials, right because like I'm not very good at photoshopping.
Rym: Oh, and you're like, I just want to do this thing with this layer right now.
Scott: No, I want to like learn Photoshop so I could be like those people who can beat Photoshop.
Scott: Well, right.
Scott: So I go online looking for tutorial and every tutorial is either like here's how to use the brush tool and I'm like I know this.
Scott: move on and then they're like Here's how to make.
Scott: I see look in text and they're like do this now set this at exactly 53 and set this Like, all right.
Scott: I made icy looking text, but I didn't learn how to use any of those things that you just did.
Scott: Like how did you come up with that?
Scott: Right?
Scott: Well, how did you and I can't it's hard to find something that teaches me How to understand.
Scott: actually, you know what how to work the thing, right?
Scott: so that I can not just follow these set steps and I feel like a lot of people.
Scott: I try to teach people.
Scott: when I try To teach someone something I want to teach them the way I want to be taught.
Scott: All right Is.
Scott: I want them to understand the fundamental concept that you can then once you learn that you can do anything.
Scott: But people always want to learn from me.
Scott: do a do B do C and they don't even want to know what's happening.
Scott: They just want to remember a set of steps.
Scott: type this exact string in.
Scott: don't care what the string means Don't want to learn that.
Scott: just want to know exactly what things to type in.
Scott: and I'm like I don't want to tell you the exact thing to type in because I know that you're not learning anything Right.
Scott: I want you to be able to understand how it works to be able to come up with.
Rym: well Here's the thing.
Scott: type in on your own.
Rym: There are definitely places for both.
Scott: people don't want to learn that.
Rym: I mean there are times when like I'm in the middle of a project like I'm trying to get some guys video up or something or I'm trying to get like a server to work and I just got To get the thing done.
Rym: and there's other times where I want to add a life skill to my toolkit.
Rym: So that's why I know there's shit out of Premiere.
Scott: I only want to ever add a life skill because then I can get things done.
Rym: Yeah, but there's stuff I don't care about.
Rym: like I don't really want to learn how to do color grading I just don't care that much.
Rym: but like the same thing you said if Premiere I don't learn it I don't do it.
Scott: if you're
Rym: trying to like edit some complex video and you like you can find a tutorial on Here is how to do multi-cam But that tutorial assumes that you have already got the rest of your production pipeline sorted out Mm-hmm, and if you just follow that tutorial you're gonna do something really really really Complicated and it's gonna really slow you down and you're frustrated and then you're probably ruin your project.
Scott: The point is the kind of learning I like right where I learn how a thing really works is best is still to today Best found in books.
Scott: so pirate them or get the e-book version.
Scott: Yeah, you don't want a big stack of paper lying around your house that you then need to get rid of a loot crate.
Rym: Yeah, be a pick and choose like.
Rym: pick the things that you want to be.
Rym: You don't want to just be like good at them.
Rym: You want to be good enough at them to where you could teach someone else that you could explain what you do It.
Scott: yeah, that's right.
Scott: And but pick and choose like some things most good enough at it that you could write a book about it.
Rym: Yeah, but like Scott does not need to know the dinner workings of DHCP.
Rym: He'll go to stack overflow and figure the shit out.
Rym: I know another DHCP.
Scott: I don't need to know how it works internally, but I understand exactly what it does.
Scott: So what would you do if like I don't just know the steps to follow to go?
Rym: Do you make DHCP work if you have a switch?
Scott: I mean just put a router next to the switch.
Scott: Okay The router does the DHCP.
Rym: DHCP requires some art broadcast stuff.
Scott: I would just have a computer.
Scott: This is DHCP server.
Rym: What if you want a DHCP server to work on two different networks?
Scott: I'd have to like bridge the networks together so that one network sends its DHCP broadcasting to the other.
Rym: You don't want to bridge the networks together.
Rym: You want to use the DHCP relay?
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I didn't know that.
Scott: That's the thing.
Rym: Yeah, cuz you know what you're never gonna do the head Even do that you well all around.
Rym: but almost all good routers have to use to be really capability.
Rym: I'm saying does anyone actually set those up like yeah, if you have one corporate DNS or a one corporate DHCP Across like your networks, but you have like a production network that's isolated from you know, that kind of stuff It's.
Rym: but that's the kind of thing that you will never do in your daily life.
Rym: So there's literally no point in you knowing how off hand or even learning the stupid details of why it's the way it is.
Scott: Anything else to say about books?
Rym: This Has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the patrons for this episode of GeekNights in order the amount of money they give us on a continuing basis as long as that amount of money is at least $5 are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette James David White Christian coops construction noises.
Rym: my stated I'm Sean Hayworth William isomers Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas on Rochelle Montanona superboy the rainbow in the dark and Cerise Brian Fisher sailor visitor jail fried pork Iggy Smith Matthews Matthew Smith Don't like shark television.
Rym: Joshua just our Tyler Eller Shawn Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton run for New Zealand.
Rym: Ryan parent drew open letter.
Rym: Rilla Vell branches Roni Finn Eric Silver on the rural juror Chris mid give Chris Knox Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: so you might have noticed that we stream this episode live just because fuck it might as well start doing stuff like that.
Rym: This is the kind of stuff I said we're gonna try to do more and more now that we're back and we don't have anything going on.
Rym: however I might be flying to stupid Chicago on Wednesday morning and flying back Thursday morning meaning Probably won't be a Wednesday show this week, so not quite regular schedule yet, and then starting in mid-october I'm gonna be in Australia with Emily for two weeks But we're gonna get as much content out as we can in between all this travel.
Rym: and now I leave you with something weird.
Rym: I'm just lost.
Rym: see what we're trying to get to.
Rym: The highwayman.
Rym: Okay good to know.
Rym: well, so you see I'm the highwayman.
Rym: I make ends meet Just like any man.
Rym: I work with my hands.
Rym: if you cross my path I'll knock you out.
Scott: Do your shoes from off your feet You.