Rym: It's Thursday June 9th 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Twitter plays GeekNights.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So Over the weekend, you know, sometimes the toilet just starts running a little bit.
Rym: You know like juggle a handle like it makes noise that thing that a lot of people's houses we visit just do constantly.
Rym: So I replace the bit that causes that problem and I read the rubbery ring on the inside.
Rym: Yeah, a little rubber thing that the flap that comes up the flapper.
Scott: Yeah I need to replace my flap too because mine also has a tiny tiny leak and yeah constantly makes noise.
Rym: It started doing it over the weekend and I was like well, nope, and I just I went to Amazon.
Rym: I immediately ordered it and the funny thing was I was likes your own.
Scott: you didn't get the super to fix it Why would I?
Rym: but the super would take like a week and then they'd come in and track some like.
Rym: it's a pain in the ass.
Scott: Put the old home back out like a showerhead, but I paid like a dollar for it.
Rym: It took 30 seconds.
Scott: How did you get one?
Scott: That's the right one for your toilet?
Rym: So well the how I did it this time is I sat down.
Rym: I said fuck what kind did I get?
Scott: so I searched and did you like empty the tank by like turning the water off and then flushing and So.
Rym: so I guess I've done a lot of handyman stuff a lot.
Rym: He's tell us so basically I Go to wear gloves and reach your hand in the tub.
Rym: why even wear gloves?
Rym: it's clean in there.
Scott: Mine mine actually has.
Rym: I have a problem a separate problem and that not only do I have to wait wait What problem could cause that water to be unclean poop coming back up?
Scott: No, why?
Scott: nobody did an upper decker in there?
Scott: that I know of but there's some sort of like.
Rym: there's some sort of silty residue Up there and I told it as the same thing.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know how to clean it out.
Rym: That's a New York thing.
Scott: Oh, is it a New York thing?
Rym: There's silt in a lot of our water Especially because it'll happen anytime they lie, but it's only in my toilet not in any of my water sources.
Scott: Yeah, cuz it's pretty diffuse and I don't know and it keeps dirtying up my bowl.
Scott: Yeah, so how do I clean it out of there?
Rym: Uh empty it and just clean it out with like paper towel and a scrubber.
Scott: That sucks.
Rym: Yeah, or just leave it There doesn't hurt anything.
Scott: It makes my toilet bowl.
Scott: I had to clean my toilet bowl more often because it keeps getting brown.
Rym: Oh, it doesn't get into the toilet bowl.
Scott: mine does.
Rym: Usually when that happens it's because there was recent construction and they shut off your water at some point.
Rym: You don't know if they did because the New York they pretty much always do it because it'll happen in a neighborhood and if you Don't have a doorman like they won't even tell you.
Rym: between like noon and 3 on a Wednesday The water will just be off and then it'll be on again and most people have no idea this happened.
Scott: I guess that could have happened.
Rym: It's actually pretty common.
Rym: The only reason I know when it happens here having to work a lot.
Rym: Yeah, it happens all over in New York.
Rym: But because we have a doorman Whenever it happens the doorman puts a sign in the elevator that says yo water's not gonna work for this one hour period on Thursday.
Rym: So I just know every time that happens.
Rym: It happens like once every couple months.
Scott: I mean maybe like a Little less than a year ago.
Scott: the water main way down the street broke, but that was like six or seven blocks away.
Scott: I don't think it was affecting me.
Scott: My water worked fine during that period.
Rym: But anyway, so I go to.
Rym: I sit down at Amazon and I'm like, oh wait What the shit for tying up?
Rym: There's a Kohler toilet I think.
Rym: so I just type flapper valve and the first result that shows up help replace mine too is one that says you Purchased this on this date.
Rym: When did you know?
Rym: when did you buy one?
Rym: I bought one about three years ago because Emily's toilet has started running.
Rym: So I just clicked rebuy.
Rym: It came the next day.
Rym: I spent 30 seconds.
Scott: So there's a recent song called rebuy that just came out.
Rym: But yeah, basically all you got to do is just look up like the name of your toilet and There's probably doesn't have like a model number written on it.
Rym: I didn't even.
Rym: I just looked up the name The maker of the toilet.
Scott: cuz my toilet is made by I guess I have to look at the flap and then look You know what?
Rym: You'll have a Bemis Kohler like.
Rym: I don't even know any other names of toilet brands.
Scott: I Got a white the most plain gennaro white porcelain potty you ever seen and it's New York modern building.
Rym: I will bet you a dollar.
Rym: It's a Kohler koh le are or something like that.
Rym: I'll take a look at it but yeah, so I replaced the thing.
Rym: and Then I was thinking because I know a lot of people some of these people I still know Where they will say things to me like oh, you've got a jiggle the toilet to make sure it stops.
Scott: That means it's broken.
Rym: fix it And they've been.
Scott: mine is mine doesn't have the jiggle problem, but so mine started up.
Scott: the jiggle Just makes noise, but there's.
Scott: no there's no point in jiggling.
Scott: It just constantly makes noise.
Rym: So when I will usually the jiggling will like reseat the flap a little bit and then it'll like stop it temporarily But once you flush it's gone again.
Scott: No, I mean mine.
Scott: Well, if you no matter what if you jiggle it'll just keep making noise.
Scott: cuz like there's this tiny leak in the thing.
Rym: Oh mine would just like get kind of like weak so it would fall into the hole a little bit.
Rym: But if you jiggle it right it would get a better seal that it wouldn't run.
Rym: But the the flapper was a little loose too.
Rym: So I fixed that.
Rym: that took I don't know eight seconds.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: There are a lot of people out there who seem to like when something minor happens to them in a house, especially houses.
Rym: It's not even apartments because at least some lazy people will call the super in an apartment.
Rym: But like people who own houses will not fix Obviously annoying things for ever like they'll just never fix them.
Rym: It's just like well, there's a hole in this wall.
Rym: I guess this is my life now.
Rym: This hole is just here.
Scott: I mean if something is not broken to the point where it actually like, you know, like people have a computer that's all slow But it's like they're still getting their work done.
Scott: They'll just suffer through the slowness.
Rym: Yeah But why.
Rym: but it like suffering through your toilet making an annoying noise basically all the time wasting water Constantly when you can spend a dollar and 30 seconds to fix it.
Rym: Like you just not know.
Scott: they just don't.
Rym: you just think toilets work that way cuz your parents never replaced your flapper.
Rym: I don't even think It's kind of like how a lot of people we know have really nice houses and yet they have the default like shit-ass Showerhead up there.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Like guys 20 bucks.
Rym: You get a real showerhead Like I don't understand.
Rym: people don't upgrade their software or the people because today I noticed this.
Rym: I was biking and I'm not complaining about fixies, but this other class of people.
Rym: they have bikes with gears Usually don't use them, but well, I'm not even talking about that.
Rym: But I'll see him biking because I pass them and their bikes are squeaking So loud squeaking and clanking and rattling like you've probably never Sprayed anything on those gears.
Rym: that chain is probably dry as my best bones in the desert.
Rym: Surprise, the changes doesn't snap and you fall over like the bike is screaming to you to end its misery Like if you never maintained a bike before.
Rym: at least the stupid fixie people, you know They make a big deal about.
Rym: oh I got my simple bike and I care a lot about simplicity for some stupid reason even though it's objectively inferior.
Rym: But these are the people who have a more complex bike Obviously maintain it less than the simple bike and the bike still goes and they complain about it being like it's low maintenance.
Rym: Yeah Like you can take a bike with gears Literally never maintain it and while it'll squeak and squeal and scream at you constantly and rattle and be slow It seems like 80% of New Yorkers ride bikes like that everywhere.
Rym: So still works.
Scott: Toilet still removes the poop so they don't.
Scott: you know, that's it Why don't?
Rym: here's a YouTube video.
Rym: go around the city buy like one thing of lube and Go around the city to bikes that are chained up on the street and just lubricate them all just like lubricated.
Rym: make a video about it.
Rym: Mm-hmm Go for it public service.
Rym: Like you're a superhero.
Rym: I'm gonna lube.
Scott: you have extra lube.
Scott: You can go do that.
Rym: I actually do have extra lube.
Rym: I got a I accidentally bought.
Rym: I thought I was buying one, you know Actually buying a four-pack one of those things that last me like a decade.
Rym: so Anyone need some bike lube?
Rym: So you got any news?
Scott: I Couldn't really find any normal GeekNights news.
Scott: So I guess we'll just go with the serious news, right?
Scott: So I'm sure anyone who is a person who knows information knows that Muhammad Ali One of the greatest people to ever live has passed away and that is not usually.
Scott: we don't usually talk about celebrities dying On GeekNights, right?
Scott: Usually because most of the time we don't care.
Scott: That's just people mean there's millions of people dying all the time.
Scott: Yeah, and why?
Scott: just cuz you're a celebrity doesn't make you any more important than anyone else But mom and Ali is more important than everyone else.
Rym: Muhammad Ali, I mean one if you don't know like we're not right.
Scott: It's not even the fact that he died.
Scott: that is notable because to be honest it was like he was dead.
Scott: He said Parkinson's disease and been like basically not able to do much for quite a significant period of time.
Scott: So it's like he's been dead, right?
Scott: What's notable I think is, you know, the fact that he has died obviously brings out You know everybody who you know never knew who he was and you can see the typical internet reactions.
Scott: But mostly, you know the the yeah, we expected it.
Scott: But when you act, you know, there's the reaction that you expected.
Scott: But once you actually see it you still shake your head Which is the punk kids who didn't know who he was because they're too young.
Rym: So yeah, like I'm gonna link to it.
Rym: It's kind of my thing of the day, but I'll just talk about it now.
Rym: So there's a famous famous monologue that Billy Crystal and already half you were thinking.
Rym: Who's Billy Crystal?
Rym: Did and basically he recounted Muhammad Ali's life up to that point as a Monologue and it was funny but serious because Muhammad Ali's life so amazing that people haven't seen this.
Rym: yeah, like this is this was a staple like I just like everyone saw this.
Rym: everyone knew about this and Apparently Billy Crystal is gonna do.
Scott: or did the eulogy for Muhammad Ali's funeral like he was Considering the Howard Cosell who also people listen to this don't know who that is Yeah is died in like 1990 something but most of Twitter was left.
Rym: They were like who the hell is this Billy Crystal and why?
Rym: what the hell does he have to do with Muhammad?
Rym: I leave and who's this Cassius Clay guy?
Rym: Like?
Rym: was it his brother?
Rym: Like I found some shit poking around on the internet The thing that I saw the moat the thing.
Scott: Well, I shake my head at the people who don't know who he was, right?
Scott: And I think I think the 90s is like the cutoff right because like I was born in the 80s Which is still after the end of his career.
Scott: pretty much Yeah, right.
Scott: But I still knew everything there was to know about him and saw all his fights before YouTube and then saw his fights again When YouTube came out, he was the last great hero of boxing And he was also just kind of a hero as a person.
Scott: there weren't I mean there aren't really if you think about you know True like actual heroic human beings that were real people and weren't fictional.
Scott: There really aren't many right who alive Could you say is like at the superhero level.
Rym: if Muhammad Ali?
Rym: Person can you even think of the guys level the guy that they made Hotel Rwanda about the NATO guy who saved all those people?
Rym: Sure, he was great UN guy UN UN, right?
Scott: But he's not.
Scott: he's not even like half Muhammad Ali love.
Rym: There's the thing if you took if Muhammad Ali had not existed and you wrote a movie script about a guy like Muhammad Ali with that level of Just humor and presence and record and everything It seems like a fictional person like people would say that dialogues unrealistic.
Rym: No human is that clever in Conversations?
Rym: no humans that funny.
Rym: No humans that real and no one could be that good of a boxer.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: so.
Scott: here's the things that people still don't understand right if you're a punk kid, right?
Scott: First of all, people don't understand that between the year up until like the 80s and 90s Right actually up until the 90s pretty much Boxing was the number one sport, right?
Scott: Football was not the real football is.
Scott: in the United States football is number one and in the whole world soccer was always one Right, but before the 90s before like the end of Mike Tyson's career Right like Tyson Holyfield era from that going backwards all the way back to like, you know Joe Louis times right in the ancient days like 40s 50s, right?
Scott: Whatever, you know max Fleming, whatever, right?
Scott: Boxing was the number one sport in the entire world.
Scott: It was the most important thing There was in sports right horse racing was like number two.
Scott: Yeah, you know baseball was bigger than you know, but it's like football ice hockey basketball.
Scott: Those are all like sideshows right the way that all these other sports aren't, you know, and if you were the heavyweight champion of the world You were like the most dangerous man on earth, right?
Scott: You were like the most famous but it's like You know.
Scott: You look today like some of like the biggest like standalone individual sport athletes like like Novak Djokovic He's like the champion of tennis right now or like Tiger Woods, right?
Scott: Muhammad Ali was like 10 times as famous and big compared to Tiger Woods.
Rym: It's very important.
Rym: Is that he had a voice?
Rym: that?
Rym: Would have otherwise been ignored had he not had that fame that the position he held.
Rym: his skill at boxing made him so powerful in Society that the shitty white people couldn't ignore him.
Scott: No, you couldn't ignore him.
Scott: He's the most.
Scott: That's like you.
Rym: look at this Wikipedia.
Rym: Look at this record.
Rym: It's just like this crazy sea of winds The years where he wasn't allowed to box because he refused to fight Vietnam because he refused to go kill brown people overseas.
Rym: Well, you know when they never called him nigger they never did anything to him.
Scott: He didn't say that he said something like that.
Rym: He said I don't.
Scott: you said I ain't got no quarrel.
Scott: No Viet Cong.
Rym: There was another longer quote that he gave in an interview that I pulled up a little while ago.
Scott: I'll find it cuz I really good right but that's another thing right is so, you know, he was right a Muslim, right?
Scott: And we are here at GeekNights.
Scott: Very anti Skyman, right?
Scott: Yeah So you think why are you so in love with Muhammad Ali who is as pretty much as pro Skyman as you can be?
Scott: Well, the fact is is that even though he was pro Skyman He was Malcolm X Skyman style, right?
Scott: And the fact is that type of Islam that he believes in right?
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: He believes in a ridiculous Skyman that doesn't exist which is not good, right?
Scott: But that imaginary Skyman's Imaginary teachings happen to be the same thing that my complete lack of Skyman also teaches me, right?
Scott: It's like he was you know, he wasn't uh, you know, like a terrorist Muslim right like killing everybody.
Scott: He's like, yeah, he refused to go to the war and kill Vietnamese people.
Scott: I would have done the same exact thing yeah for a different reason and they suspended him from boxing in basically his prime years.
Rym: and When he finally won his court case because again, he was so famous and powerful that he couldn't be ignored He finally won he started boxing again And he was still an unbeatable powerhouse.
Rym: Nate silver wrote an article a little while ago on 538 that said that his greatness defied Statistics.
Scott: Yeah, I mean basically you had this like invincible human being right?
Scott: There was a comic book.
Scott: That's famous like Muhammad Ali vs Superman.
Scott: it's like yet and that made sense because he was the closest thing to Superman that ever existed.
Scott: Right, this isn't like, you know, like even Wayne Gretzky isn't even half as great right Wayne Gretzky?
Scott: His name is the great one.
Scott: Not even you could combine like Wayne Gretzky Babe Ruth and Michael Jordan and you still wouldn't have one Muhammad Ali, right?
Scott: He's like a historical figure like Alexander the Great, right?
Scott: This is this is like, you know, the supreme Amazing human being right people don't understand because they weren't alive when he was still a person that you would see You know walking around and talking whatever.
Scott: so I guess is that big.
Rym: I guess what I should say to you guys that he was a hero to multiple generations of people.
Rym: like we grew up at the end of the era where kids looked up to this guy and like really Understood and remembered him and here we were probably like the last generation to understand who he was and his message.
Rym: You know everything that he stood for as a person for the most part is not only relevant today, but it's sort of starkly relevant.
Rym: Like really wish Parkinson's hadn't taken him out cuz we could kind of use him.
Scott: I mean, you know, he got punched in the head a lot.
Scott: Yeah, but he punched Right, I mean basically and the thing is right, you know is the other major thing, right?
Scott: So when he started his career, he was gonna fight Sonny listed right after winning the gold medal the Olympics, right?
Scott: And nobody gave him a chance.
Scott: Of course Nobody gave him a fucking chance.
Scott: As little as people know about Hamad Ali people don't know anything about Sonny listed.
Scott: at the time Sonny listed was the scariest Mother fucker to ever walk the earth because if you were the heavyweight champion in the world You were the scariest most dangerous most famous athlete on the face of the earth, right?
Scott: Like if Sonny listed you heard he was that he was gonna be in your town soon.
Scott: You would run away Right.
Scott: This is like the most dangerous human being there ever was and some punk kid who's like 20 something.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like so incredibly confident that he's gonna beat the shit out of him.
Scott: Like imagine if you saw me right coming up like I'm gonna beat up Superman.
Scott: Yeah, I can take him I can take him I'm gonna take him down in eight eight rounds.
Scott: No seven.
Scott: No, I'll make it six I'll take him.
Scott: right.
Scott: you and you see me with like not looking very scary at all Right, like I'm this beautiful, you know human being.
Scott: right, you know, I'm look kind of strong, but I don't look scary Like I can take Right and I'm acting like I'm gonna do it.
Scott: Right, first of all, everyone's gonna hate you and think you're a moron and bet against you, right?
Scott: Which is why it was such a humongous deal anyway, so people just don't get it.
Scott: It's like you weren't there.
Scott: I wasn't there and I get it.
Scott: How come you weren't there?
Scott: But you also don't get it.
Scott: I guess if you don't you don't have to be there to understand.
Rym: if you don't know anything about Muhammad Ali Yeah, you're still curious why.
Rym: who this Cassius Clay guy as we talked about earlier, too.
Rym: Watch the Billy Crystal thing because it's inspiring and the most beautiful thing about it I watched it again because I hadn't seen this since I was a kid is that it has this little insert of Muhammad Ali Watching Billy Crystal like Asian TV.
Rym: Yeah, and it's just.
Rym: it's.
Rym: it's really inspiring and it's it's a good thing to watch.
Scott: You mean you should just actually watch Muhammad Ali fight.
Rym: also, you should also read all the things he wrote and said because I mean this thing is boxing is boxing gave him The platform to be right, you know, he saw unlike other people right?
Scott: He sought out the camera at all times, right?
Scott: He was a person who tried on purpose to like go out there.
Scott: He wasn't someone who was like, you know, you know, like you look at say some current athletes like, you know, no comment You know like I got nothing like Marshawn Lynch would be like the example of someone just like avoids the media at all costs or like when Pete went at even athletes that don't avoid the media.
Scott: It's like they only talk to it as much as they have to and they always make politically correct non comments.
Scott: They don't say anything right.
Scott: and it's like man I really wish one of these athletes who just say whatever they really wanted to say all the time.
Rym: It's like whenever they do it's always like ridiculous racist nonsense, right?
Scott: But it's like we already had that and you really know in a way not doing it is sort of like, you know You know sort of like saying look I can't do it as well as Muhammad Ali did.
Scott: Oh, I'm not even gonna bother.
Rym: in his Wikipedia article.
Rym: There's an entire section about his trash talk.
Rym: Why not like a big separate section?
Rym: all le le regularly taunted and baited his opponents Before the fight and often during the bout itself.
Rym: He told Frazier in the match.
Rym: He was too dumb to be champion.
Rym: This is good stuff.
Rym: So another kind of interesting news, you know AlphaGo like Humans have no input and go anymore.
Rym: Ai's got it.
Rym: There's something really fascinating going on now and I'll just link to one of these.
Rym: but basically they're pointing the same AI Google's deep mind at Atari 2600 games.
Scott: that should be pretty good.
Scott: I mean pong should be real easy, right?
Rym: The rationale.
Rym: but they're not seeding it with the historical information or historical games.
Scott: Right because they wanted to do AlphaGo just like self-trained 100% instead of training it on previous games, which they did.
Scott: Yep, well, they did both but right but I'm saying did it with their goal?
Rym: history of go?
Scott: Yeah, but their goal was to be able to do it with only self practice.
Rym: So this is interesting because the AI is give it.
Rym: basically this AI is learning to play Atari games the way me and Scott Literally don't play Atari games.
Rym: We were little.
Rym: we sat down in front of an Atari.
Rym: We could see the screens We could hit the buttons We didn't have the instruction books and we would just sort of do stuff until we eventually figured the game out.
Scott: I mean, but are they telling it things for example, like, you know The score going up is better because usually if you have like a normal old genetic algorithm You would say like a score up better score down worse and then it would figure things out.
Scott: Are they doing that or they just so they did a bunch of different things?
Scott: or are they letting it figure out that score to?
Scott: Go up.
Rym: So get this.
Rym: This is where it gets crazy.
Rym: They did a bunch of different things, but they're trying something.
Rym: The goal is they're calling it intrinsic motivation.
Rym: Basically, they want the AI to get addicted to finding novelty Because the only way to find novelty in a game is to progress through the game mm-hmm and Basically, like if they don't give it that Sense that goal of try to make things happen that I've never seen
Scott: right?
Scott: They doesn't know how to value one thing over another right?
Scott: Could play pong and decide that losing is good.
Rym: It basically went back and forth between these two screens and never really progressed anywhere.
Rym: as soon as they told it with no other Thing to seek novelty then it's explored already more than half of Montezuma's revenge, which is one.
Scott: Oh, it's not.
Scott: it's not playing versus games.
Scott: It's playing a single-player game.
Rym: It has all the buttons of an Atari and it can see the screen and that's always gonna put it on lowest difficulty maybe.
Scott: So I'd like to I'd rather it play outlaw watch itself.
Rym: watching this is Fascinating.
Rym: It's a lot like watching an AGD Q and I look forward to the day when AGD cues will basically just no one has to manually make a tool assisted speed run.
Scott: You just have an alpha.
Scott: go does the speed run and there it is.
Rym: Yep I mean alpha go.
Rym: they think about all the human effort and now I'm not saying it was wasted in the sense that the people Doing it enjoyed it like the Final Fantasy 4 run where the dude fucking like memorized random Right, but imagine if we can just have a computer just like.
Scott: make the perfect run.
Scott: It would discover things you didn't even discover doing frame by frame.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So this is just really fascinating stuff.
Rym: But again, I stress the reason I bring them up is new.
Rym: this up is news.
Rym: AI is moving so much faster than you realize and Like you saw Google's making their own chips now Just for AI.
Rym: like they're not even selling them to other people.
Rym: They're making their own chips to use themselves to do That.
Scott: I know of they are.
Rym: they are either acquiring or building one.
Rym: I don't know the four did.
Scott: they just buy like one of each machine and make a tiny fab so that they could make like One chip at a time.
Rym: It's not quite how it works.
Rym: Yeah But it was so.
Rym: actually I know there's an FPGAs.
Rym: the reason I know they're not so the reason I didn't read Like I don't know all the details of that is that that's my Monday news and we skip skip to Monday shows I'm doing the next Monday, but they're making the tensor chips tensor flow stuff.
Rym: So basically they're chips that only do the stuff they need for neural networks and nothing else.
Scott: is making a hardware version of?
Rym: Yes So they can.
Scott: basically they're just taking their software and making a hardware chip that does of the software does to make it go fast.
Scott: Cuz if you cuz think of it this way a general-purpose computer has to the calculations Like if I made a counter-strike chip and I think there's a computer that just like.
Scott: It's just like.
Scott: yeah, there we go.
Rym: but it's a little more unique than that because this tensor flow stuff is kind of fuzzy logic or like it's not like the.
Rym: you Know the old days where Pentiums if you multiplied certain numbers would get the wrong answer.
Rym: and how that that was.
Scott: That was one Pentium chip and it was like one specific.
Rym: Well, it was the first run of Pentium and it was.
Rym: it was that they were not accurate beyond a certain point in Floating point calculations.
Scott: Yeah, there was some register.
Scott: So those busted I forget.
Rym: now It was a logic error from what I read.
Rym: Anyway, I could go look it up again.
Rym: I I looked it up to do a talk on it like ten years ago.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, I digress it never mattered.
Rym: keep an eye It mattered to a few people.
Rym: you keep an eye out for this AI stuff like I bring it up on Thursday because Monday is like check out what it's doing and Tuesday would be AGD cues.
Rym: but Thursday is the shit's gonna affect your life in a real way way sooner than you realize.
Rym: Probably something that was funny today is You know that the president like the nomination process in America is over.
Rym: It's Trump and Clinton.
Rym: They're running like that's it.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: but What's interesting is that nothing the crazy candidate from all reports actually like reads his own Twitter Himself and like type shit into it Which is crazy because like any professional politician hires someone to do that for them also doesn't have time to do that.
Rym: Yeah, so and it appears that the crazy one also takes it all really personally like literally just responds to random people And it's just like that sort of thing is happening.
Rym: So the Hillary account tweeted something that was you know The delete your account like Trump's have something dumb and it was like delete your account and it went crazy viral What was interesting and I didn't even think about this until I found these compilations.
Rym: This is one of them.
Rym: Anyone older than like 35 has no fucking idea what that means.
Rym: It means It means what you said is so egregious that you should just delete your account and literally go away from this social network forever.
Scott: Right as in you know, you have a Twitter account.
Scott: Delete it so that you don't see your tweets anymore and you stop tweeting.
Rym: Yeah, like you shouldn't be on this.
Scott: What at me I mean, it's pretty and there's no jargon there.
Scott: It's delete your account.
Rym: What's the main?
Scott: like regular old media like and it's like say it's like say like if someone says something stupid to you and you Say kill yourself.
Rym: Yeah, so this is a video and there are many of these Of all the sort of mainstream news outlets around the world who don't understand what this means Trying to explain it badly to the people who watch TV news meaning the people who also don't understand what it means.
Rym: It is amazing to watch the generational divide so starkly and clearly demonstrated.
Scott: Well, you know what as you know, you might be laughing at those people, but hey the people who know what delete your account means They don't know who Muhammad Ali is but the people watching the news do.
Rym: yeah Of course.
Rym: at the same time the people are watching the news Also have their hands on the money and power and at least currently because they're old and also I'm sure some of the people watching The news are those racist types who were like they know who?
Scott: Like use a slave name because they hate him they hate him or they're like, you know die Muslim whatever right?
Scott: There's that kind of people.
Rym: Yeah, fuck them Things of the day.
Rym: I already talked about the Billy Crystal thing.
Rym: Just watch it like seriously.
Scott: So he's using your news as a team.
Rym: Okay, that was my thing of the day, but it was relevant I guess.
Rym: so, I guess I got another thing here.
Rym: this is a video of a guy who is playing around with the steady cam like a for-real one and he's got a $70,000 fancy camera on the steady cam the steady cam that like you wear with like a vest and she up and he's like Holy shit.
Rym: this is amazing.
Rym: and he's like check out stable does this?
Rym: and he starts jumping around and acting the fool.
Scott: and uh So if you've never used a steady cam before you got to be first of all to use a steady cam in the first place.
Scott: You got to be jacked right?
Scott: Like I couldn't wear one because it's too heavy.
Scott: I'm just like follow could wear.
Rym: you could wear this one.
Scott: I've seen like every time I ever see someone with the kind where there's a they look way bulky.
Rym: They're not that heavy.
Scott: No, no, but every time I see someone wearing one it they're always a buff, dude Like, you know, you ever see cameraman cameraman are always huge.
Scott: You never see like a little skinny.
Rym: Yeah, but a lot of them aren't buff.
Rym: They're fat.
Scott: There's still us and underneath that if you took all the fat off me and all the fat off them They would be jacked and I would not.
Scott: I still wouldn't be able to do a push-up.
Scott: If I had less to push it's because I lack in the pushing power not in me.
Rym: So I'll put it this way
Scott: not that the pushing is
Rym: steady cam type things like these camera stabilization things are amazing technology but they're the kind of technology that will fail on you in Crazy ways if you're not trained and you don't know how they actually work
Scott: like tempered glass.
Rym: Yeah, so this guy Let's the arm extend a little too far because it'll like.
Rym: you can jump up You can let go of it and jump up and down and it'll be perfectly steady.
Rym: But if that arm extends a little bit too far like beyond its safety Then now you've got this long thin skinny arm with a lot of like Mechanical logic in it and you've got a really heavy camera on the end of it.
Rym: It hits the safety threshold and it just collapses.
Scott: Why don't they change the hinge so it can't extend farther than it should?
Rym: Well No one who's ever used one of these things would make that stupid mistake.
Rym: is one to put it that far away from your body?
Scott: To get even close to that you have to like let go of it.
Rym: Yeah You already have to be.
Scott: no one has an arm that long.
Rym: Try to give an equivalent.
Rym: like to get to the point you'd have to like run away from it.
Scott: Like leave it there and run.
Rym: Like to turn.
Rym: like imagine you're riding a bike and you just suddenly turn your front wheel 90 degrees to the left as hard as you can.
Rym: like yeah, the bike will let you do that.
Rym: You know not to do that.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: So this guy basically turned the wheel 90 degrees to the right and it is a sublime moment.
Scott: Alright, so here's a video that I saw a long time ago like in the RIT days.
Scott: It went around.
Scott: I think This was uploaded to YouTube when that'd be interesting information if I could see.
Rym: That's not on the front page of a YouTube video anymore Like it used to be a lot more prominent when it was uploaded.
Rym: I think YouTube pulled that away.
Scott: I don't know anyway, so This video is from 1998 right and basically what happened here is there was a hacking group.
Rym: Oh, it's still there.
Rym: I see it.
Scott: Well, it doesn't say it in the app.
Scott: What does it say other?
Rym: Oh, I'm not on that video.
Rym: Let me go to that video now.
Rym: I picked a random video.
Scott: I had YouTube open anyway, so this video is 14th 2011. it's a long time ago.
Rym: the videos from March May 19th 1998.
Scott: so this is there was a hacking group called loft heavy industries.
Scott: Obviously the O was a zero and F in loft was a pH And it was a big deal because these dudes with their hacker names like Brian oblivion kingpin space rogue Mudge weld pond Stefan one
Rym: Right
Scott: these dudes who are like the most stereotypical hackers you've ever seen testified before Congress And when the news reported on this in 1998. basically all the news said was Hackers testified before Congress and say they could take down the internet in 30 minutes.
Scott: But really there's a lot more than they testified to Congress.
Scott: and this was in a day when?
Scott: Congress was a little bit better than it is now Interviewing people and Getting you know asking them questions and trying to actually learn from them instead of you know being real dumb.
Scott: it was a little bit less corrupt than it is now and This is a really interesting congressional testimony.
Scott: if you're a nerd of any kind especially one who cares about technologies and You know it informs a lot of you know what our government thinks about technology these days.
Rym: Yeah, and I feel like the Gulf between.
Rym: I saw this a long time ago.
Rym: I haven't seen it recently, but if I it's think it just came back up again.
Rym: So I had it like well like my thing of the day on Monday is gonna be that elevator hacking thing from Defcon.
Rym: That thing's way old, but I came up in my feet.
Rym: I was like all right that thing.
Rym: fun fact they gave that lecture at the end of Defcon.
Rym: because imagine if you gave a lecture on how to hack elevators at the Beginning of a long convention of hackers.
Scott: I mean they could have fixed the elevators in that hotel.
Rym: and now The gist of that video is an Elevator is just an unsecured stairwell.
Scott: yes Also, if I was the person doing that presentation I would have during the presentation triggered the elevators in that hotel to do what I say.
Scott: yeah I've been like oh and as I'm speaking the elevators in this hotel are all going to the basement.
Rym: the elevators of this hotel have all Exited their shafts and our arms.
Scott: They're all going up to the roof with the doors open.
Rym: But what this video?
Rym: The as much as there's this wide gulf between the people testifying and the old men who don't know better interviewing them That Gulf is like four times wider today than it was back in 1998.
Scott: Mm-hmm pretty much so.
Rym: in the moment the book club book will be Oryx and Craig by Margaret Atwood Even though the handmade sale would probably be more relevant to the current state of America possibly.
Rym: But I got to finish the last wheel of time book first so I can do that last special podcast with Kehil White at PAX Prime.
Rym: I'm halfway through the last book of the wheel of time.
Scott: tell me about the snake thief.
Rym: I know what's in that tower.
Rym: I know what the deal is for that tower.
Rym: I know what's up with Mazram tame that motherfucker.
Rym: I learned something interesting.
Rym: You know how the SNI can make up and bond a man as a water.
Rym: So the male wizards later they learn that they can bond a woman the same way.
Scott: What a tubule.
Scott: bond each other at the same time.
Rym: so someone just did that and it's like Don't if that's bad idea.
Rym: Okay, that that that causes prop.
Rym: basically that happens by accident and It's it.
Rym: It's like if you see a script that was written poorly starts looping It's stuff goes down.
Rym: So yeah, I'm gonna know a lot about the wheel of time real soon.
Rym: The patreon is going strong.
Rym: I just uploaded and I'm gonna rapid-fire the rest of these now The second of the beta episodes of GeekNights.
Rym: and the craziest thing is that as I upload these people who apparently have still been listening to GeekNights and hanging out in the forum who haven't posted or said anything for Five plus years are all coming out of the woodwork.
Rym: Some people who remember these episodes.
Scott: How could you remember some beta episode?
Rym: No, because our friends listened to all of them and gave us feedback.
Rym: Yeah Yeah What's great about this?
Rym: Is that the first one was pretty entertaining like the first thing we ever did just for various reasons.
Rym: You can hear my commentary.
Rym: the commentary that I did when I remastered them will be free for everyone not just patrons.
Rym: I'll update that.
Rym: I'll upload that over the weekend as a public update.
Rym: So you guys can hear the commentary.
Rym: What I'll say is this if listening to that first beta episode you were somehow under the misapprehension That we figured out what we were doing and made a good show like right away The second episode will disavow you of that illusion, I think it's.
Scott: you know, it's like penny arcade, right?
Scott: It's like yeah, first one's bad.
Scott: The only difference is that the current penny arcade is real good and the current GeekNights is still bad Just less bad.
Rym: We decided that we needed to argue more so than when we did this one.
Rym: like we start some bullshit arguments and then we get really mad at each other and just keep arguing and keep arguing and then At the end that this beautiful like don't listen to it.
Rym: It's actually really bad.
Rym: Just listen to the commentary.
Rym: but in the very very end of the file I Interrupt Scott and I'm like, you know what this episode got stupid Just cut it off and then Scott says you're the one who made it stupid.
Rym: You started one of your arguments and literally I say what do you mean?
Rym: What?
Rym: and then the audio cuts out?
Rym: Like I Imagine we must have argued for another hour or two after that.
Rym: I can't imagine that we didn't and we didn't record it, but it was tough to listen to this one.
Rym: We don't know shit because we're arguing about shit.
Rym: We don't know shit about.
Scott: what did we argue about?
Rym: You argued that there is no culture of anti-intellectualism in the United States, that's wrong.
Rym: Yeah, and I made it all up and in credit.
Scott: That's what I said.
Scott: Are you not putting words?
Scott: Yeah Why would I say that?
Scott: Yeah, so the United States is nothing.
Rym: but you and I also talk and argue about politics a lot but we Like we get way out of the shit We know and we clearly do not know a lot.
Rym: at one point We both start talking about what language or languages might be spoken in India.
Rym: Let me tell you we're real dumb in 2005.
Scott: Listen, people don't learn things by being young.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: This is what it's relevant.
Scott: I was watching Simpsons clips the other day, whatever the age I am is the age you are when you're the smartest.
Rym: This is one clip where like the producer for itchy and scratchy just comes in to a focus group.
Rym: But he's like you.
Rym: kids are all stupid Stupid.
Rym: you don't know what you want.
Rym: That's why you're young because you're stupid.
Rym: So we'd had some ideas.
Rym: what did the show on?
Rym: we actually considered just doing a whole show on Muhammad Ali But I figured you're better.
Rym: you're better served by reading his Wikipedia page.
Scott: You're better served by just YouTube for like until the crack of dawn.
Scott: I mean, yep, once you start watching, you know Muhammad Ali do anything you're gonna be watching for like days.
Rym: Yeah, like.
Rym: I really wish I could have met him or hung out with him or just talk to him.
Scott: I'd have been happy to talk to you.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: So I tweeted earlier today at 1151 a.m What should we do the show on tonight?
Rym: I got a lot of Suggestions.
Rym: I'm just gonna go through these.
Rym: we're gonna pick one if all of them are bad.
Rym: This is your fault.
Rym: internet.
Rym: Andrew Milim said Syria.
Rym: Oh, I don't think so.
Rym: My response to him was quote.
Rym: if I had to make a list of things God is least willing to talk about either on GeekNights or in real life I'll talk about Syria.
Rym: See oh you want to not tell that the Assyrians came down like the wolf on the fold.
Rym: the courts are gleaming in purple and Gold.
Rym: Yes that guy Real like current Assyria like that region politics.
Rym: or do you actually know about old ancient Assyria?
Scott: I know about fictional ancient Assyria.
Scott: All right That fought that fought with fictional Jews.
Rym: I'd be interested.
Scott: show on ham radio, but I don't know much about ham radio.
Scott: I can tell you that in summer camp There was you could you know where they had every nerdy thing.
Scott: ham radio was one of the nerdy thing And it's pretty much only the old grog nard types to do ham radio.
Scott: Not a lot of young people.
Rym: It's the kind of thing where I hope that a few people I know Are into it enough cuz it's like say Mad Max or something crazy happens.
Rym: that shit gets really useful real quick.
Rym: Yeah, otherwise I was actually really into radio as a kid But I didn't have the money or the time or the inclination to do ham.
Scott: just use like CB radios the truckers use.
Rym: I was about to say I actually I was a CB radio hobbyist Like.
Rym: I had all these different crystals and I had a base station with a fucking big antenna.
Rym: There's probably illegal.
Scott: I mean if I see the apocalypse corners buy some on Amazon or bust into a truck and take it.
Rym: I had random just conversations with truckers driving by like.
Rym: I learned a whole bunch of stuff I used to know more about like radio etiquette back then.
Scott: because yeah, no one cares.
Rym: Yeah, but I don't have enough.
Scott: go watch contact next.
Rym: Conspiracy theories.
Scott: don't believe in the next.
Rym: Terminator 1 vs.
Rym: Terminator 2.
Scott: Terminator 2 is a better movie next.
Rym: Terminator 1 was a good movie though.
Scott: Yeah, it was not bad.
Scott: I know we could do wasn't even half as good.
Rym: We ever actually do a show on Terminator 2.
Rym: I watched it in a couple years up Sometime down the road like when it's bad outside.
Rym: Let's watch the two Terminator movies and then review them as Thursday episodes.
Rym: We do a lot in Jurassic Park.
Scott: We can do a Terminator show on all things Terminator.
Rym: You have the two movies.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah exactly Ah.
Scott: Also the Terminator 2 video game.
Rym: Matt offered to do a guest episode and do a review of the state of New Jersey.
Rym: Call him we could review the state of New York.
Scott: call him right now.
Rym: He said he's busy playing overwatch.
Scott: I think that means he can call him right now.
Rym: Luke's Bert Luke Burge suggested driving just driving.
Rym: I don't think we ever did a show on that.
Scott: It's fun, but don't do it.
Rym: If you don't have to don't have anything to say about I could tell you I do a whole show on driving.
Rym: I had anecdotes about like we've done this already.
Rym: We might have I don't know and also future transport like the future of transportation and driving Car will drive itself and hopefully so.
Rym: actually that presents some problems though I was thinking about this a couple weeks ago.
Rym: self-driving cars are great, right?
Rym: Yeah here There's one drawback to them right now.
Rym: If you're if you're one of those terrible people who insists on living in the suburbs and driving an hour to work every day At least you're punished for it with a horrible commute.
Rym: If you have self-driving cars will probably quadruple the traffic and all those shitty like suburban towns Will be full of commuters driving to work like riding to work in their pods and will probably actually make Closer in mass transit and like city infrastructure worse in the short term.
Scott: I don't think so.
Rym: Why not?
Rym: I mean, I don't know like this is something I've thought about but I haven't really formed Just concrete opinion on it.
Scott: I mean just cuz you're not driving the car It's still gonna be.
Scott: if it's still being to be traffic.
Scott: if there's too many of them more than the road can handle Right, yeah, but will it self-driving cars?
Rym: will they just increase the like?
Rym: will they overload the road?
Scott: Also people are gonna like get in those cars together because you're not gonna like want to own one because that's that defeats the point.
Scott: You're not gonna have right old cars, right?
Scott: So you just got a car will be on your street somewhere You'll get in it.
Rym: But I guess there's a wider battle.
Scott: improve society by making people socialize with each other like.
Rym: will it reduce the need for mass bulk local transport?
Rym: or will it cause an explosion of Towns like beacon that are kind of sleeper communities?
Scott: Well, I mean just come here even if people stop getting on the Metro North first of all Right, the thing could just take you to the Metro North because then what the fuck is the difference?
Scott: whether it takes you to?
Scott: The train or not, right?
Scott: But also the cars used to all hook up to each other and make a train in which case it's just a fucking train.
Scott: It just has a lot more wheels.
Scott: What's the difference?
Rym: Yeah, and actually what one thing, you know the my counterpoint like my counter argument to that idea and Is that think about what happened in a lot of the developing world where they never had phone infrastructure and Then they leapt to cell phones.
Rym: So they skipped like one generation of bullshit.
Rym: It's like in Civ 5 when like I build a bunch of bullshit spearmen.
Rym: But what if you just don't build spearmen you get to the point of making pike men?
Rym: You skip a whole generation save a ton of money and just make like the good stuff, you know That's what I would have done.
Scott: Yeah, you know if I had money right now I could have like a knight but I instead I have a horseman.
Scott: because not cuz I don't know how.
Scott: to night I haven't played.
Scott: I've always armor sitting around but the armorsmith one I know how to make it you don't and I'm like, dude Listen, your whole blacksmith shop this whole town's gonna get burnt to the ground.
Scott: If you don't just give me some free armor.
Scott: We have so much iron.
Scott: Just give me free armor.
Scott: No, you got to pay.
Rym: You don't have that many humans living in your cities because I I have my one city.
Rym: I have three cities.
Rym: I'm gonna have a fourth reel soon and all three of them have more population than your capital.
Scott: Yeah, I couldn't get because I basically lived in a desert place.
Scott: There's not.
Scott: there wasn't enough food.
Rym: Yeah, you think I started in a good place?
Scott: I had.
Scott: no I still have like so low food, even though I got the tradition plus food capital.
Rym: I feel like we should start the fourth game.
Rym: I feel like that also but we can let this one go until like it's over we could start the fourth game.
Scott: because if we start thinking I'm thinking someone who Was war based and duels only war matters.
Rym: Uh, I was not going to war you at any point.
Rym: I had never planned on actually invading you.
Rym: The only reason I'm going to is to end this.
Rym: I Was planning almost.
Rym: I made all those videos.
Rym: you could have left my caravans alone then that was a like 2007 era GeekNights tangent.
Rym: I Posit that.
Rym: possibly the fact that the u.s.
Rym: Never had mass transit anywhere except New York City pretty much Might and we built all these highways.
Rym: if we jump to self-driving cars Suddenly skip over bullet train every single highway We built becomes mass transit and America has this explosion.
Rym: We have this amazing infrastructure Except for all the bridges that are collapsing But suddenly it turns into mass transit like there might be a renaissance in America if we survive the next 20 years of our infrastructure Collapsing.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: We'll see.
Scott: That's it's very optimistic.
Scott: It doesn't matter because it's here's the problem even if that if what you say is true.
Scott: Right, the self-driving car doesn't go 500 miles an hour.
Scott: Like the bullet train.
Scott: does you need the bullet train?
Scott: You can't.
Rym: why do you need the bullet train?
Scott: for so I can get somewhere in less than fucking 10 hours?
Rym: Yeah, where are you gonna go?
Rym: Where do we go?
Scott: We go to Boston in a self-driving cars takes for fuck ever.
Rym: So there should be bullet trains along the Northeast corridor and along the west coast, but nowhere else.
Scott: I mean there should be one that just goes across the whole goddamn country.
Scott: Why can't I take the train to California?
Rym: who would ride that?
Rym: flying is actually way better at that?
Scott: I mean the train is used less energy and goes just as fast.
Scott: How fast does the plane fly?
Scott: about 500 miles an hour?
Scott: How fast does the bullet train go?
Scott: You know if the bullet train was going through like the middle of the nowhere that is the middle of America It could go probably even faster than 500.
Scott: It could probably go six or seven hundred.
Rym: I'm not even gonna touch that one.
Rym: I'm just gonna let that stand.
Scott: You don't think that the really long train uses less energy than the plane that has to not only go forward but also go up?
Rym: I don't think bullet trains are the solution to Transcontinental.
Scott: You think that like a nuclear power plant hooked up to like maglev rail is less efficient than a jet engine?
Rym: I think planes are still better at that.
Rym: Also, you never saw the train movie right?
Rym: which one the truth.
Rym: There's only one train movie Galaxy Express 9 9 9. there's only one train movie.
Rym: That's not animated Trains planes automobiles That's also planes and automobiles and actually that that movie is mostly cars.
Scott: so the general with Buster Keaton.
Rym: Yeah, I guess that is also a train movie.
Rym: anyway That's the only train movies.
Scott: I know deciding what restaurant to eat at The one we're deciding what to do the show on.
Rym: that's Chris Reimer suggested.
Scott: You've done that already did we?
Scott: yes We've done that like a hundred times.
Scott: we've done this exact episode.
Scott: We're doing now 100 times.
Scott: No this episode.
Rym: We're actually doing.
Rym: we're doing though.
Rym: We're I don't think we've done one That was stated goal.
Rym: We're just going to do a show on how we decide what to do the show on.
Rym: I think we've ever done that.
Scott: This is what it sounds like to decide what to do the show on.
Rym: we we do a bring up.
Scott: we bring up crab people.
Rym: We do a one to two minute show.
Scott: I reject most of them.
Scott: Oh We find the least the the most tolerable crab people and then we settle on it.
Rym: the threshold for what's tolerable Continues to drop the hungrier.
Rym: we are Deciding what restaurant to eat that actually could be a good show to do.
Rym: not.
Scott: now I don't think we could do 20 minutes.
Rym: I think we could.
Rym: So here's the topics.
Rym: all right, so here's how I'll give you guys this cuz we're not gonna Do this show on this cuz this show is actually almost done.
Rym: We've been going for like 50 minutes.
Rym: There's the one the problem of like conventions like deciding where to eat forming the group of people to eat splitting up the group's reservations how everyone just fucking sucks at that and You know there's a lot to say.
Rym: there's probably like eight minutes of stuff on that.
Rym: There's us ourselves and how much easier that got.
Rym: we moved to New York And there's literally like 30 restaurants within a 15-minute travel of our apartment plus grow up hub.
Rym: But you could grow up from multiple places.
Rym: deal with the picky people.
Rym: We could talk about the picky people and how you just need to cut them out of your group.
Scott: or don't be don't be picky Babies.
Scott: if you're gonna be picky then look I don't like certain things right?
Scott: you know everyone doesn't like certain things.
Scott: But if like if I go to a restaurant for example like I'm not really into Radish and like you know radishes.
Rym: There's a restaurant that has just radish.
Scott: I mean radish is okay, but like I will never buy a radish.
Scott: I'll never intentionally put a radish in my food, right?
Scott: I won't order a radish focused dish at a restaurant But if I get a salad if I get a salad and there's mad radish on it or even moderate radish on it You know what I fucking eat it cuz I'm not a child Right.
Scott: so when you so when you go to a restaurant if you have like celiac disease or an allergy and you say no Bread, please that's absolutely acceptable, but if you say no radish You're a fucking baby.
Scott: Just fucking eat it or order something else now.
Rym: It is one thing.
Rym: Let's say the Like.
Rym: the menu listed the things in it, and it didn't list radish and yet radish was a significant component.
Rym: I Even asked like hey, what's in this?
Rym: and they still like didn't mention radish even once and then it's just like covered in radishes.
Scott: That's a little weird and bad restaurant.
Scott: Don't go there again.
Rym: I've run into those situations before but it hasn't happened since I moved to New York.
Rym: There's also so there's a side topic there.
Rym: I noticed something.
Rym: This is a problem that I never considered specifically in this context until the last Pac South Because remember we needed to find a place to eat and everyone was crowded and had a long wait.
Rym: And pass like San Antonio is one of those weird places where despite being crowded Restaurants will take reservations, which I think is ludicrous.
Rym: like if you're a good restaurant, and you're like filling reliably You should never take reservations.
Scott: No need to take a reservation like in New York.
Rym: No good restaurant except the super super upper-end places that are so expensive.
Rym: They don't fail.
Rym: like no one takes reservations You're just like stand outside for an hour if you want to eat a salt and fat Yep, or go it like the worst possible time.
Scott: It's like they're gonna fill all their seats.
Rym: They don't need your reservation And we had a constraint of.
Rym: we had a pretty large group of like 12 people and we all want to eat together.
Scott: now in The old days like I think everyone else always wants to everyone eat together I'm happy to just eat and it's like just split up guys.
Scott: make it easy.
Rym: Well.
Rym: That's it in the old days.
Scott: Just go ever.
Rym: we would like put great effort into being able to all eat together and I've decided that that is always a wasted effort especially at like a convention or whatever.
Rym: right.
Rym: But there's a side thing.
Rym: we found a place that would seat all of us immediately and We got a giant table and that seemed fine and in fact I noticed this happen a bunch of times.
Rym: in San Antonio.
Rym: There were restaurants that had the seating to accommodate a giant group of people.
Rym: However Places like that places that aren't like New York or Chicago that have a huge population of people doing that sort of thing all the time They have slow kitchens.
Rym: They're never going to have a kitchen that could actually deliver that much food in time.
Rym: So you run in the situation in San Antonio where you'll find a restaurant that will seat all 20 of you right now And then it'll take them literally an hour and a half to bring out your food.
Rym: So that's a further no new argument.
Rym: one don't go to places in cities that aren't New York.
Scott: Oh, you got 12 people right.
Scott: don't even go up and be like we got 12, and we can split up.
Scott: No, just say we got fo table four.
Scott: We got three tables before.
Scott: now.
Rym: the drama problem is that usually in any in any large towns You don't know each other.
Scott: fo fo fo.
Scott: Well in any large group, you know you didn't get my fo fo fo.
Rym: I got your fo fo fo.
Scott: yo you get that reference.
Scott: I think so.
Scott: What is that reference from?
Rym: There's nothing with Ross's.
Rym: got it a Ross right?
Rym: no no I got nothing.
Scott: then it's a basketball right?
Rym: I don't know what the fuck that is that I don't watch basketball.
Rym: I don't like basketball I don't know anything about basketball.
Rym: and I go ahead.
Rym: I'm bad at basketball - like real bad at it like Preternaturally bad at basketball if you watch me try to play like it's awful.
Rym: continue Right.
Rym: if you have it like sometimes like the front row crew like when like in the old days like when we'd all get together We all want to go to the same restaurant.
Rym: Everyone wanted to sit with everyone else like we were all chills.
Rym: if we split up it literally didn't matter who sat with who?
Rym: but Usually if you out there or are at a convention Or you have a large group of friends, and you all decide you want to get out together There are definitely a lot of people who don't actually want to share the table with certain other people Like there's the newer friends Stuck with like the second tier people like they want to sit with the prime people.
Rym: They want to sit at the cool table.
Rym: It always ends up being the hierarchy of like.
Rym: there's two tables were like cool crafts happening.
Rym: Then there's the table with all the people who aren't like super in the group.
Rym: And then there's the table with like the super annoying CPM who somehow is in your group.
Rym: You couldn't get rid of them.
Rym: and There I think we could do a whole show on how to file like how to decide where to eat How to deal with small and large groups, I think we do a whole show Thursday.
Scott: Hmm what I wasn't listening.
Rym: I think people would listen.
Rym: I think you would like it.
Scott: I wasn't listening to you.
Rym: Okay, what were you doing?
Scott: reading some internet?
Rym: Okay?
Rym: Uh?
Rym: Indy car.
Rym: It's car racing.
Rym: I don't know enough about it.
Rym: That's mostly died frequent flyer programs And like.
Rym: so like the jet blue stuff or the I guess the bolt bus thing.
Rym: I'm member of that.
Scott: I get free rides from all the time you do it a lot, and then you get free shit.
Scott: What's there today?
Rym: I mean The airplane stuff kind of matters because that's how I get like upgrades.
Scott: yeah You can get a lot of you can get more value you get a large amount of values worth and a lot of people do It.
Scott: I don't understand why companies Allow their individual employees to keep those benefits.
Rym: I would not fucking fly anywhere ever if my company didn't let me keep my air miles.
Rym: I would refuse mm-hmm.
Scott: That's why yeah like if I'm a company.
Scott: I'm like fly here, or you're fired.
Scott: It's your job to fly there.
Rym: no except literally no no one would do it.
Rym: pretty much Partly the accounts are usually tied to individuals like the corporate there.
Rym: usually they'll be like a corporate pool and weird stuff.
Rym: But generally no you you use your own air miles But at the same time your company might say you're not like you can't buy that ticket.
Rym: That's I know you want to fly Delta or whatever, but that ticket cost twice as much.
Rym: fuck you you're flying jet blue whatever.
Rym: uh One thing I can say is that I've seen people who?
Rym: Try to min max it and spend a lot of time like trying to game those systems.
Scott: Spent that time working.
Rym: yeah, don't bother.
Rym: the only the only time it is worth your while to like buy air miles There's some nonsense like that is if you're already in the wealthy class because then like it actually is cheaper than buying business class.
Rym: You're already wealthy though.
Scott: Does why do you even need to save fucking money?
Rym: I'm not.
Rym: I didn't get rich by wasting money.
Scott: Scrooge McDuck would do that kind of shit.
Rym: I would do that.
Rym: I mean I do that a little bit like I have all my frequent flyers stuff and I might buy a bunch of miles on Cathey for next year so that Emily and I can just fly business class.
Rym: if we go to Australia like something like that Do whatever you want be way cheaper than buying a business class ticket.
Rym: Vaporwave I'm not gonna talk about vaporwave for if it doesn't exist Comixology changing subscription model, I just don't use Comixology.
Scott: I don't use that either.
Rym: I would but I Read books on my Kindle instead.
Scott: I read comic books on paper not because I'm obviously not anti Digital read things.
Scott: I would much rather read things digitally.
Scott: but comics at least, you know most of the ones I read were made with paper in mind.
Scott: and Unlike say reading a book digitally, which there's not really any fucking difference If a comic book was made for paper and then you read it digitally That's like watching a widescreen movie on a 4/3 TV.
Scott: It doesn't work.
Rym: Ah All right home organization systems.
Rym: I get a lot of thoughts to unpack on that one.
Rym: So get it.
Scott: It's not funny.
Rym: That was real funny.
Rym: No music Talked about music.
Scott: It's too general music.
Rym: We like Almost all of it music.
Scott: We particularly like almost all of it.
Rym: you gotta have something like if you like if you're like a B test like it's in a Monomart song and Pretty good, like a Beatles song pretty good.
Rym: Like what if you had to pick one like prioritize which song is it?
Rym: Yeah It's got to be somebody's like.
Rym: I don't like a lot of modern R&B.
Rym: that much Depends.
Scott: but they see like that's a very narrow any any any genre that you pick out and you And you try to tell me I don't like that genre.
Scott: I'll find you like some songs in that genre that are so awesome because I think what I really like like What about country or Western?
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: I like some country songs.
Scott: I like songs with a strong melodic hook regardless of sound like, you know what?
Rym: I think Garth Brooks like Thunder rolls.
Rym: That's just like a twangy country kind of cliche song.
Rym: It's not a bad song.
Rym: I like it.
Scott: like you could take the same exact song and have some you know like Dolly Parton sing it and then have say I don't know I used to earth sing it and I'll probably if it's a good song.
Scott: I'll like it both ways.
Scott: It was a bad song.
Scott: I'll hate it both ways.
Rym: I Don't like the subject matter Like if it's the same like.
Scott: yeah, I tend to listen to more foreign or non lyrical music.
Scott: Cuz then you can't hear the awful lyrics right because I won't hear awful lyrics Right.
Scott: and awful lyrics include things that are just like, you know awful.
Scott: You know gangster rap that I run into that pretty often.
Rym: I like a lot of rap and hip-hop and yet the lyrics to the some of the songs that I really enjoy are Fucking awful, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's one thing.
Scott: if you're sir mix a lot and you're like, I like big butts.
Scott: It's like I. everyone like big butts.
Scott: That's great.
Scott: And then if someone's like, you know, I'm gonna kill people and rape all the ladies.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: no nobody like like.
Rym: There's a simpson wave song I like and it samples just takes to the big butts and at one point the guys like if life's A game inches then my dick something.
Rym: something's like really?
Rym: I'm Wish I hadn't picked out that one part of the song.
Rym: is there?
Scott: is there a karaoke version of this song?
Scott: because I've done.
Rym: Are you looking what the song is?
Rym: Cuz I actually didn't recognize it at first.
Scott: and it's like.
Scott: it's pretty.
Scott: you know What you can make some some badass hippin and hoppin.
Scott: Yeah, right without having nasty lyrics.
Scott: you for example a recent example Turn down for what.
Scott: what's wrong?
Scott: All right, you could just say turn down for what.
Scott: you could have a crazy ridiculous video.
Scott: That's like a modern.
Scott: I like big butts, right?
Rym: I Unabashedly like turned down for Will Smith's bubblegum rap.
Rym: I like Will Smith Like that shit way more than you would expect me to.
Scott: we live it in the will any of you.
Rym: If only he'd make good movies again, uh You don't need to if I was.
Scott: Will Smith is one of the smart people who's like I'm done.
Scott: Yeah, I'm so rich.
Rym: Fuck y'all Music me if I didn't say what I'm listening to the most right now, though.
Rym: It's actually legit.
Scott: Simpson wave Right now today.
Scott: I listened to so low-end Entertainment which is like one of the major kpop labels made a deal with Spotify So all of these past albums and things that were never on there.
Scott: It was like a huge dump of like new whatever, right?
Scott: So but right now I think XO just came back and as usual They have one good song and an album full of crap songs and one good song but they're like the biggest deal in the world at least for other people.
Scott: and then I listened to like The vorjax 9 6 or 9.
Rym: symphony is probably the one you're thinking of.
Scott: I'd bow but I think they put on Spotify.
Scott: There might have been this.
Scott: I forget which one that went on Spotify.
Rym: Yeah, if you really like him, you should.
Scott: he's my number one guy.
Rym: You should go back.
Rym: Do you like piano concertos?
Rym: Do you want like the big orchestra there?
Scott: I don't really care.
Rym: go listen to a bunch of Franz Liszt.
Scott: I already listened to Franz Liszt.
Scott: Okay teaching me anything new here.
Rym: Uh You have you ever gone deep into the Rachmaninoff?
Rym: I don't like Rachmaninoff as much But how do you like Liszt?
Rym: but knock rock not Rachmaninoff?
Rym: It's different.
Rym: What what did you describe?
Rym: how they're different at least?
Rym: Is more superficial like tone-poem nonsense.
Rym: Like this is a song about a painting I'm looking at at least Rachmaninoff has the crazy skill depth of the piano part The ones I.
Scott: the one I really don't like the most is Vivaldi.
Scott: That's my.
Rym: it's my not Vivaldi's good background music, I guess.
Scott: Yeah, whatever I'm really into lately the kind of music they play in the clothing store.
Scott: Like I'll go into a clothing store and put on Shazam and then go home and listen to that.
Scott: So it's funny not buy clothes.
Rym: I said I'm listening to Simpson wave and like I'm not joking look, I literally am listening to Simpson wave.
Rym: but That is very aesthetically similar to the kind of music.
Rym: They tend to play late at night in the rock climbing gym I go to and I'm digging that aesthetic a lot.
Rym: It's this is sort of The Muzak got to you.
Rym: Yeah, but it's a step up from Muzak because it's a little more.
Rym: It's more sparse than Muzak and yet more punctuated at the same time Mm-hmm, like sparser more punctuated melodic and rhythmic elements Basic income.
Rym: so that's been coming up a lot and I'd love we could do a whole show on that probably basic guaranteed income.
Scott: What's there to say other than we're just waiting for it?
Rym: I think I could say a lot about like cool.
Rym: Where could it succeed?
Rym: Where could it fail?
Rym: What would it do?
Rym: What would we do?
Rym: What's the threshold where we wouldn't work anymore?
Rym: Like that kind of stuff.
Rym: if I can just live my life comfortably Comfortably you mean comfortably like our New York high-fluent lifestyle or like living in like a shack outside of Albany somewhere.
Scott: No, I'm not living in a shack.
Scott: What the fuck.
Rym: a warm shack though, like you don't have to do anything Got internet.
Scott: Yeah, can I still buy comic books every month?
Rym: Oh, yeah, but you can't afford to go to Pax's.
Scott: fuck that Why live?
Rym: the problem is everyone was talking about basic income because they're like all Switzerland's doing it.
Rym: No, Switzerland's not.
Rym: they're voting on it and no one in Switzerland wants it to happen.
Rym: They're almost everyone in Switzerland is like crazily Violently opposed to the idea of basic income.
Rym: Also, they have mad money Need the basic income like the places where this is being put forth for referendums or debate The the tide is overwhelmingly against it.
Rym: Like this is not moving forward.
Scott: They don't need it.
Rym: Yeah, they do.
Rym: There's poor people there.
Scott: Yeah, but there's not.
Scott: it's not mostly poor people like other countries.
Rym: Uh ride-sharing like lyft and uber those aren't ride-sharing.
Rym: Those are just like evil subcontractor like slave wage slave nonsense companies.
Rym: That should be banned.
Rym: ride-sharing is not what either of those things actually does.
Scott: Well, they are doing some ride-sharing.
Scott: Yeah, that's you can get an uber and it might pull up with someone else in it already who's going somewhere close to where?
Rym: You're yeah, you know what?
Scott: No one wants that and like people do it because it's a cheaper ride.
Rym: It's only slightly cheaper and from everyone I've heard who talks about it It is Russian roulette with what crazy motherfuckers sitting next to you in that car.
Rym: Sure It is bad news bears and also forget that the ride the people who do drive those cars are just exploited Subcontractors.
Scott: Well, sure.
Rym: Yeah Zombies, no, we're not doing part four of zombies.
Rym: It's never gonna rise from the dead.
Rym: I Got there's nothing more I could say about zombies There.
Rym: their time has passed.
Rym: All right, guess we did a show about that.
Scott: we've done this show before Where we go through a bunch of topics people suggest and shoot them all down and yet somehow we went longer than we do for An average show.
Scott: Yeah, cuz it takes a long time to do a bunch of things for five minutes instead of one thing for Do we do more than four things?
Scott: It's worth it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brand ok for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com For show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows Sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: The patrons for this episode of GeekNights in the amount of money that they give us on a continuing basis are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brandau Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette James David white Christian open parenthesis cones Mystati.com Sean Hayworth, William Eisen rose Jeremy minor Spartacus Spartacus.
Rym: Spartacus Iggy kid Matthew Smith char tavish and Joshua Joe star Tyler Eller down Schleich Sean Yeager Clinton Walton and Ren from New Zealand.
Rym: Robert Lee Ryan parent drew open letter.
Rym: Rilla Val Brian said Ronnie Rochelle, Monta No, no Finn Eric silver on and the infinite sadness kinetic man Aaron series Chris midkiff Chris Knox flame dark fire Sam Cordray Daniel Redmond Chris a dot Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Yeah, we literally did just do a show on us trying to figure out what to do the show on.
Rym: so yo dog I hope you like the show.
Rym: I Think some of those topics have merit and Scott never listens to any of this stuff.
Rym: so if you actually want us to do one of those topics just Posting the forum and tweet at us and talk about how good of an idea you think it is.
Rym: now you really want to hear our opinions because That'll give me a little more ammo to trick Scott into doing a show on one of these things.
Rym: But anyway now I leave you with something odd.
Scott: Who are you America's in America's in?