Rym: It's Thursday, March 17th, 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: preparation Let's do this.
Rym: So my company like changed all its insurance II stuff and I finally sorted all that out.
Rym: So, you know like new insurance and my insurance now is actually way better.
Rym: So I started doing all that dance of.
Rym: I don't really have a good PCP's.
Rym: I was looking for a new like main doctor to be my doctor and I Was.
Scott: you find one not yet actually.
Rym: Yeah It's not easy.
Rym: every good doctor that my insurance takes.
Rym: that I've looked.
Rym: I went to Zoc Docs and I was like Who are the best?
Rym: like 40 doctors in Manhattan?
Rym: And as I go down the list, none of them are taking patients.
Rym: They're all like now we don't.
Rym: we don't need anyone like.
Scott: I had an awesome doctor who moved away I think I've said this in the show a long time ago and then so I eventually last year I went to a doctor that was at the same office, but was good obviously and he was okay.
Scott: It wasn't like a bad doctor, you know, it was definitely a sciency doctor and not a woo doctor, which is good But it wasn't someone who like really, you know took time to chill out like the other guy did.
Scott: the other guy like wanted me to come back for like a second appointment and Spent a lot of time like discussing everything and didn't care like what level of This guy was just sort of like.
Scott: he seemed like he was in a hurry and was just sort of like.
Scott: yep All right, there's nothing wrong with you.
Scott: And I know that you haven't been to a doctor and like, you know, it's like.
Scott: listen I know there's nothing wrong with me.
Scott: I haven't been to a doctor in like a zillion years, but I'm in my 30s and I just want to make sure Just oldening.
Scott: so I'd like you to like at least make it appear that you're spending a little bit of time examining my situation.
Rym: So yeah, so my last primary care practitioner I visited once.
Rym: every time I get a primary care practitioner I get it because there's a reason I need to go to the doctor and I don't have a doctor and every time I go I'm fine.
Rym: like.
Rym: the thing is never a problem and the doctors always met.
Rym: so I never go back to them and then usually my insurance changes or Something and then I don't start all over.
Scott: why couldn't that awesome doctor just stay?
Scott: Why do you have to go take a much better position in Florida?
Scott: I've decided.
Rym: my metric now is do they have modern stuff in their office?
Scott: That's always my measuring.
Scott: everyone I mean every baby real really any business.
Scott: I'm measuring by how modern the shit is in their office.
Rym: Yep I'm gonna be really real.
Rym: here is are the people the Socio-economic class of people in the waiting room within a couple of bounds of me?
Rym: Are they way above or below me?
Rym: because if they're way above me I probably like.
Rym: I probably can't actually afford that doctor like my insurance really won't cover it that well.
Rym: And if it's way below me It's probably not the best place to be for obvious reasons because American healthcare is kind of terrible.
Scott: How do you know that it's not Iron Monkey?
Scott: if with all those I am confident I would not I would bet Iron Monkey was serving the rich people and also the low-class people and he was the best doctor.
Scott: You know what.
Rym: if Iron Monkey came out and was the doctor I would continue to go to that doc.
Scott: But no one knew that it was Iron Monkey.
Scott: They thought he was doctor whatever his name was.
Rym: they didn't know it was a secret like spider-man unless they ever saw him and his Wife clean up the house.
Rym: They closed the doors before they clean the house, but I Actually, I don't need to go to a doctor.
Rym: So I'm still looking for a doctor.
Rym: either No one will take me or the people that will take me.
Scott: if anyone knows a good doctor in Manhattan I mean all the other thing.
Rym: all the doctors that are flagged as definitely taking patients are the ones who are paying to run ads In things like Zoc Doc, so I didn't check Zoc Doc.
Scott: I checked I checked.
Scott: I know it's like a cool way better than the insurance sites my insurance site But it's not great, but that's right now because I switched to Aetna.
Scott: I have United something so I used to have United.
Rym: They're the second worst.
Scott: Yeah, they have an app now that I use.
Scott: Yeah works.
Rym: Oxford was worse than them.
Scott: I never had that though.
Rym: They're not good.
Rym: I kind of miss the while.
Rym: Obamacare is definitely a positive thing 100%.
Rym: if you disagree you're wrong.
Rym: Because I was young and healthy and because insurance sucked so bad.
Rym: It was kind of cool back when I had my weird FSA HSA combo health insurance Like that was actually the best insurance I ever had.
Rym: But anyway, I had to go to the dentist and I had to go urgently because I was fine.
Rym: I was a little overdue.
Scott: you could have gone to the awesome dentist I found.
Scott: Dennis seems to be easier to find than doc.
Rym: yeah They do so.
Rym: I was overdue getting a cleaning like it been a little over a year.
Scott: That's a problem.
Rym: Well the thing is actually if your teeth are in good health you only have to go every year.
Scott: right sure But you know what the insurance pays for me to go every six months.
Scott: so why the fuck not?
Rym: but I had switched dentists a bunch of times and My teeth were fine Like I have zero tooth complaints.
Rym: and then suddenly a few days ago my jaw started hurting real bad Like way in the back here and saw that skiing.
Rym: So, of course, I got Google and I'm like jaw pain and of course, it's like T.
Scott: Okay Jock ends.
Rym: It's like jaw cancer and I'm like, well, I'm just gonna assume that's not true.
Rym: And then it's like Dental abscess and I'm like, is it possible that I have one of the?
Rym: because a lot of tooth problems are painless Until they're bad.
Rym: A lot of people don't realize that like cavities if they start to hurt they're already really bad.
Scott: that yeah It's like root canal territory.
Rym: Yeah Like that like dental stuff will basically not hurt and you'll feel fine.
Scott: and those teeth are bones most or they're not.
Scott: You know unless it gets down to the nerve you don't feel right?
Rym: Yeah, there's a lot of stuff going on there.
Rym: So I'm like, is it possible that I have like a hidden dental abscess?
Rym: So I'm like fucking around in my mouth with a flashlight and there's nothing like I can find not even a Swelling nothing.
Rym: There's nothing pus coming out of your mouth Nope, and of course, I made the fucking mistake of looking online for pictures of what a dental abscess.
Scott: No, don't do that.
Scott: Also fun fact Your mouth didn't look.
Scott: if your mouth didn't make you want to vomit.
Scott: You're probably okay.
Rym: Yeah, also in general googling for dental stuff What I found was that because I was worried like, you know My gums aren't a hundred percent grade and I got a few dental problems cuz I'm in my 30s and I had braces a kid.
Rym: But yeah looking online tells me that I take better care of my teeth and almost every American by far You're basically looking at only at the horror pictures and then assuming everyone's like no So I was looking at dental sites that are like do you have gingivitis?
Rym: This is what gingivitis looks like and I'm like, whoa, holy shit.
Rym: My teeth are way better than that.
Rym: But so I don't have anything.
Rym: so I'm wondering like what the hell could it be?
Rym: and I read up all the stuff on like TMJ mandibular issues and Mandibles.
Rym: Yeah, cuz it's in the mandible area and all the websites pretty much said it's cancer It's a hidden abscess It's like cellulitis or like bone inflection.
Scott: It's a random pain for being an old person.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: No, nothing said that.
Rym: Well, that's they all said you go to a doctor immediately.
Rym: Holy shit.
Scott: Yeah, sure.
Rym: So I try to find a dentist and I find I looked up and according to a bunch of websites I found what might be the best dentist in New York.
Scott: My dentist is real good.
Scott: I don't know how much better it could be.
Scott: who takes my insurance unless they're like giving blowjobs in the waiting room.
Rym: I mean But so I went in and they get.
Rym: I was like so I need an appointment now.
Rym: Usually I was like so I expected for a new patient It'd be like a week or two and they were like you want to come in right now And I was like, what do you mean right now?
Rym: They're like, can you get here in the next hour?
Rym: And I was like actually no and they're like pick your time and I showed up on time.
Rym: They took me in on time Zero delay, they did the thing like immediately all modern technology.
Rym: So long story short my teeth are fine and the dentist was like, I don't know on your jaw There's nothing wrong with it.
Rym: So maybe it's just oldening.
Rym: come back to me if it still hurts.
Rym: in like a month Even did an x-ray and he's like, yeah, there's nothing back there.
Rym: So But if you go to a new dentist and they do an x-ray and they use film Don't go to that dentist anymore.
Rym: They can.
Rym: why would you what?
Scott: Dennis still uses film?
Rym: Most dentists in New York.
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: I haven't seen a dentist with film and like my previous dentist used film for the x-rays But they didn't use the big old like plate film.
Rym: They use the like they put the film on the thing in your mouth and then they put the gun up to your mouth.
Scott: Yeah, I've even even so the thing with film right and I know this cuz my uncle's dentist.
Scott: Yeah, and he told me this when he got his like because I went to him right when I was like a long time in My life.
Scott: he got like digital like x-rays like a long time ago And he's like look when you use the film x-ray machine and you turn the x-ray machine on you got to turn it on like.
Scott: But if you use the digital one, it's like.
Scott: it's like it's like the exposure time.
Scott: due to this you know the ISO of the you know, I guess sensor the x-ray sensor versus you know, the The the eyes the x-ray ISO of the x-ray film right is way But Drastic, right?
Scott: So you have a lot less x-rays hitting your teeth and your face.
Rym: Yeah, which is a good thing.
Rym: Yeah But most dentists have a lot of old busted crap.
Rym: So the fact that they had modern x-ray machines and actually the machine was way tiny like way tinier than I expected And I did the dentist I go to the machines actually in the closet like you can't even it's like yeah.
Rym: They had a modern like ultrasonic cleaning instead of the old cleaning methods and everything was just great.
Rym: And then at the end he was you know, he was asking me about.
Rym: he was like, yeah your teeth are fine You take great care of him.
Rym: He's like you flossed at least once a day and I was like actually I flossed twice a day and he was like I don't really much.
Rym: He's like.
Rym: actually he was like.
Rym: that's actually what I recommend and No one has ever said that they did it twice a day where I've believed them.
Rym: Yeah Yeah He was basically telling me how Generally, the more someone talks about how often they floss the more likely it is They're lying at that is true.
Scott: and he's like I can tell See your teeth it's like I clean my bathroom five times a day go.
Rym: It's like I floss every day and he's like I looked at your gums and they started bleeding.
Rym: But Yeah, so I got a new dentist and while I'm there he was looking up because I have two teeth that were kind of like Chipped like the top of the tooth where it goes into.
Rym: the gum was like cracked off like old old injuries.
Scott: Whoa, it's fine.
Rym: That's just something that happens and like.
Rym: the only danger with that is that there's.
Rym: no, actually the danger is there's less distance before.
Rym: if you got a cavity there it get all the way in and Brushing your teeth does a braid your teeth away a little bit.
Rym: So theoretically you'll braid through the tooth and eventually have problems.
Rym: So he was like you want me to just bond him and I was like, I guess I can make an appointment Like no, let's do it right now like 10 minutes.
Scott: What is what is bonding?
Scott: do bonding?
Rym: It's just a what it's it's.
Rym: so it's a filling.
Rym: but instead of drilling and going in they just put filling stuff on the outside to Cover up like there's a busted bit.
Scott: No And that usually called a sealant.
Rym: Uh sealants a little bit different.
Rym: That was a. this is a bond Mm-hmm, and I was like really right now and he was like, yeah, and I haven't gotten a bondings in like he's looking.
Scott: He's just looking to get some money's right.
Scott: the more he procedures He does the more the insurance got to pay.
Rym: so he charged me like actually a really low rate for the bonding and he did A really good job in the bonding like it worked.
Rym: Great.
Scott: He's not gonna do a bad job.
Scott: He wants you to come back so you get more money from you.
Scott: not maybe.
Rym: but The final thing is I learned something that I didn't know.
Rym: cuz I have that old HSA Like for my old Obama Obamacare stuff, you can still use that money.
Rym: Yeah Back then when I was getting it for free I was saving it one for retirement because that's a loophole.
Rym: you can use that shit to retire And you can invest it and there's all this tax stuff.
Rym: It's great.
Rym: But - I was gonna use it if I ever had like a serious medical thing that happened to me like beyond my insurance.
Rym: But I didn't know.
Rym: you could also use it for dental stuff and use it for anything.
Scott: You can use it to just buy town all Dwayne Reed.
Scott: Uh, actually no.
Rym: Yeah That's dodgy.
Scott: use the HSA debit card.
Scott: Wait, just poop.
Rym: That's HSA or FSA.
Scott: Oh FSA.
Scott: yet the FSA we have at our work you can use for that too.
Rym: You can to a degree but FSA has got really clamped down on about two years ago.
Rym: So some stuff has changed.
Scott: Well the FSA at our work.
Scott: They specifically said you can use it for things at Dwayne Reed.
Rym: Have you used it for those things?
Scott: I don't put any money in the FSA.
Rym: Oh, you should put like ten bucks in it and get like the one drug you'll ever need.
Scott: I mean, I'm pretty sure I can buy mucinix once a year.
Scott: I don't need that to be tax-free.
Scott: It's a lot of effort to save five bucks.
Rym: So because I have all this HSA money.
Rym: You know how people who are rich have those perfect perfect teeth that you get if you basically get rich person teeth their fake teeth.
Rym: Yeah, they're not a hundred percent fake.
Rym: I mean, yeah, but I mean but they basically shape your teeth and gums to be a hundred percent on the movie set.
Scott: Perfect Right.
Rym: I basically have enough money in there to get that if I wanted to.
Rym: why would you want that when I'm 50 and my teeth are not great anymore?
Scott: because I'm dentures get some dentures.
Rym: I don't want dentures.
Rym: dentures suck.
Scott: Well dentures are the worst like fake teeth is the greatest.
Scott: You don't to worry about cavities.
Scott: You just chew anything.
Scott: Just get the movie star teeth.
Rym: They're just as good.
Rym: You don't have to take them out at night.
Scott: I Don't want any kind of implant action, you know, sometimes that's necessary.
Rym: You only need the implants if you're getting movie star teeth to replace broken teeth.
Scott: Hey, listen, don't play I hot I suck.
Rym: So, yeah, if you can't tell I was just trying to kill a bunch of time because I don't know.
Scott: I don't even have any News, so we have any news.
Scott: So I got some news.
Scott: There's nothing happening.
Rym: It's politics No, but it doesn't involve Trump or any of the stuff that Scott would get super mad about.
Rym: It's the kind of like Political science politics that is at least more relevant to real real world and more long-standing and not so ephemeral.
Rym: So Scott, you know about what's going on with the Supreme Court right now, right?
Scott: Someone died and they got to pick someone new.
Rym: So, do you know what's going on now?
Rym: Like why is?
Rym: why would I talk about this?
Rym: because shouldn't it already be taken care of?
Scott: you died a while ago Because I mean it takes as long as it takes.
Scott: right the president can pretty much wait as long as they want to appoint Someone or never appoint someone or appoint a bunch of people.
Scott: you can ever present it.
Scott: You can just appoint people whenever the fuck you want.
Rym: FDR did it.
Scott: I was just like I'm gonna point a hundred people right and then Once you appoint someone the Senate has to approve your appointment and they can take however
Rym: the fuck long they want
Scott: and they can Deny or they can say yes, they can say no they can do whatever.
Scott: so that is true.
Scott: It takes as long.
Rym: as however in practice that Basically never happened.
Scott: Yeah, historically the president usually Doesn't appoint a bunch of people if they're not FDR.
Scott: They appoint people only when someone dies and Congress might.
Scott: usually when they appoint someone Congress moves that to the top of the to-do list and they vote yes or no.
Rym: now They might vote no and make a few people The vast majority of the time they vote.
Scott: Yes, it's pretty rare that they vote.
Scott: No because usually, you know the president Takes pretty long time and pick someone who's not like way Obviously gonna get node.
Scott: if they want to pick someone who's gonna get a yes because the sooner they get in there You know, they'd rather have someone who's more moderate and acceptable get in and handle some cases and vote the way that they want earlier.
Scott: There's a little rather than have the tied court while they're waiting to get like some extreme Person like on the left or right.
Scott: that's not gonna get in anyway, right?
Rym: There's a little more nuance to it though because the Supreme Court has such prestige with the American people.
Rym: I mean it has more prestige than any other part of the government.
Rym: Basically.
Scott: It's the least hated part of the government though.
Rym: Actually that is turned around just recently.
Rym: the Supreme Court is as a Surprisingly high on favorability right now.
Rym: You want to know why it's not more unfavorable than Congress.
Rym: No, no Congress is less popular.
Scott: I mean like no part of the government is popular, right?
Scott: But I'm sure the Supreme Court is more popular than like the DMV, right?
Rym: No, but yeah Congress right now I think is less popular than cat piss man.
Rym: I think Well, that's about Congress.
Rym: Congress is less popular than cat piss man, sure.
Rym: So because cap his men's definition is 80% of your friends hate him and more than 80% of Americans hate Congress.
Rym: but so Traditionally they move the process along and they give it the proper level of respect and decorum.
Rym: Like if they're not gonna approve someone they just say no.
Rym: Yeah, they'll go through the motions.
Rym: They'll then do the formal vote.
Scott: I don't think they even do the for a lot of times like the president just does enough research in advance and consults with them In advance, right.
Scott: and they're like, yeah, that person's gonna get the no don't even send them.
Rym: Oh, that doesn't always work out.
Scott: I mean, I remember and I assume you might do some posturing for some other reasons and send someone over.
Scott: You know who's gonna get a nose?
Scott: Bill you want through instead.
Rym: that actually pretty much never happened either.
Rym: So that the what the notable exception of one of the strange ones.
Rym: This is something that I don't think any of you listeners will remember because you have to be at least as old as us.
Rym: But the whole Robert Bork thing that was like that was the.
Scott: I know that name.
Rym: Did you know anything about Bork?
Scott: He was appointed to the Supreme Court and didn't make it.
Rym: Basically, yeah, do you know the whole?
Rym: it's it there's.
Scott: that's the extent of my knowledge.
Rym: That is the earliest political memories I have.
Rym: is Someone talking about Bork and it being referenced by Bloom County?
Rym: and that's how I started learning about politics.
Scott: I know a lot more about Ray Bork the hockey player.
Rym: Yeah But do you know why I'm bringing this up now?
Rym: Really like, you know what's going on with Supreme Court if you paid attention at all.
Scott: No, I don't give a fuck really.
Scott: So really shocking.
Rym: No, so this is a big deal because it actually foretells a possible long-term constitutional problem.
Rym: what happened was Scalia died, yeah, and Obama, you know has to nominate someone to replace.
Scott: He doesn't have to but he did.
Rym: well He'd know.
Rym: so he don't.
Rym: he only did a little while ago.
Scott: Yeah, but he doesn't have to.
Scott: uh, He has the power to Whenever he wants decorum and precedent says he has to.
Scott: you're saying it was a constitutional issue.
Rym: I'm getting to that.
Rym: Okay, so before anyone said anything Before Obama even said oh my god Scalia's dead The entire Republican Party came out and said we will make sure that no one under any circumstances Gets even talked about no hearings.
Rym: Nothing.
Rym: We will refuse to let Obama appoint anyone because He's in the last term of his presidency and the voters should get to pick.
Scott: Well, I mean the reason is stupid, but they can just vote no all they want.
Scott: No, they're not gonna vote.
Rym: No, there's not gonna have a hearing.
Scott: They don't have to do that either.
Rym: Yeah, they don't have to.
Rym: technically it's a it is a. it's a glaring fault in the Constitution That has basically never been invoked.
Rym: It's like what it's like a broken rule in a game where Everyone even people are playing to win mutually agreed.
Rym: Let's follow that rule because otherwise the game sucks like it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the way the Constitution is written.
Scott: It says the president has the power to appoint people and the Senate has the power to say yes or no.
Scott: So it doesn't say you have to appoint people Doesn't say when it doesn't say under what circumstances.
Rym: But so they can do what they want other than basically like Civil War bullshit Something this has never happened before.
Scott: well I mean nobody had spent more than two terms in office until FDR.
Scott: then they made a rule about it.
Scott: But I'm saying kind of deal.
Rym: know so that the deal is different here because it isn't.
Scott: listen There wasn't a lot of play testing done on the Constitution, right?
Rym: You remember the beta?
Rym: it was the Articles of Confederation.
Scott: No, that was a different game.
Scott: Game wasn't funny alpha.
Scott: Yeah, they played it.
Scott: They said man this quake sucks.
Scott: Let's play counter-strike.
Rym: All right, there was no there was the time when they when they forked it There was the south in the north, right?
Rym: The south is just the north plus savory slavery and a bunch of typos.
Scott: See we're now at a point where it's like we'd really like to go to like counter-strike.
Scott: go.
Scott: But you know, we got a whole country full of cs1.6 purists and it's never gonna happen.
Rym: But here's the deal.
Scott: No one's gonna play Starcraft 2.
Rym: Starcraft 1 is gonna remain the competitive Eastport When the country was literally about to go to war with itself.
Rym: The partisan politics has never gotten to that level with the Supreme Court ever.
Rym: Hmm until now.
Rym: and basically the Republican said we won't let Obama appoint anyone because it's in the end of his term and The the interesting because doesn't matter there doesn't matter right?
Scott: Why even say because you're just open saying that?
Rym: because which is a really stupid because Scott so, you know why there's because you ever heard of the Thurman rule.
Scott: There's a strong third.
Rym: It is so the way our Congress actually works.
Rym: and this you know.
Rym: These are things that aren't in the Constitution The hidden rules the Congress makes for itself that actually matter a lot.
Rym: those rules matter a lot.
Scott: Those are the most important rules.
Scott: Congress just makes its own rules.
Scott: They have rules committee.
Scott: Yeah It makes the rules.
Rym: Congress has a rule about that.
Scott: basically you have to have a reason.
Rym: don't appoint anyone in the last and months Of that their term.
Rym: wait for the next person to come in.
Rym: Okay, but Scalia died so early that we would have a date person Supreme Court for well over a year Way beyond the bounds of the Thurman rule.
Rym: It's also interesting that the Republicans who all are spearheading this don't let anyone get in no matter what every one of them Basically last time there was any sort of court stuff were vocal on video on record.
Rym: You're adamantly saying that you have to let people appoint even at the end of their terms because that's what the Constitution I mean, this is not.
Scott: I mean what see.
Scott: you're acting like you're.
Scott: so it's like this is Daily Show.
Scott: every day Someone says a thing and then later they say a different thing.
Scott: That's something about their self-serving.
Scott: They don't actually care about political reasons for things.
Scott: They care about just their own agenda.
Scott: So this is not news.
Scott: Saying this like oh my god, somebody doesn't actually care about political principle.
Scott: They just want to do what they want to do and we'll use any That's in the moment.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: That's just.
Scott: It's not interesting at all.
Rym: I think it is.
Scott: it's every day that you might as well be saying Oh my god, there's water coming out of this cloud.
Rym: What's going on really happened before?
Scott: who gives a fuck?
Rym: So but the problem is that because they said this now they're worried that the next president will be either Hillary or Trump and They don't want either one of those people to appoint the Supreme Court either.
Scott: Someone's going to appoint you can just vote.
Rym: no No, they're never gonna vote again.
Rym: That's what's happening.
Rym: Basically.
Scott: You don't have to do that.
Rym: They said they won't let any hearings happen.
Rym: So don't till a Republican is in office effectively.
Scott: So well if you lose the control the Congress then that won't happen.
Rym: They're not likely to for 20 or 30 years.
Rym: so it is entirely possible unless the Republican Party literally splits in two that we will in the next four to eight to twelve years have a seven person and then possibly a six person Supreme Court and We will literally never appoint someone to the court again unless either we change the Constitution or the rules to force them to have votes or The Congress gets controlled entirely by one party that also has the presidency.
Rym: Mmm.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: That's an entirely new and very destabilizing element of American politics.
Rym: Never happened before other than during the Civil War.
Scott: I don't really see the problem.
Scott: All right Okay, there's nothing I can do about it and it doesn't matter.
Rym: so you don't find any of this interesting.
Rym: You don't care about school.
Rym: You didn't learn anything about social studies.
Scott: I mean, it's not interesting.
Rym: It's not interesting.
Scott: It's not surprising or new in any way.
Rym: It actually is surprising.
Rym: No one really expected this to happen.
Rym: It's basically never happened.
Scott: Okay, not surprised.
Rym: Okay, probably just cuz you don't know anything about the Supreme Court.
Scott: I know about Congress.
Scott: Do you really?
Rym: Anyway Things of the day.
Scott: my thing of the day is excellent much better than anything you've said so far.
Scott: In fact, if you listen to this episode of GeekNights You can just fast forward to this thing of the day and rather this thing of days.
Rym: So they won't hear your advice until they've already listened to that big mistake.
Scott: So and then immediately after this thing of the day is done Rims thing today is probably crappy.
Scott: remember now just stop listening to this episode.
Rym: not everyone can live the purely hedonistic lifestyle that Scott does.
Scott: Hedonistic these drugs I'm taking and these grapes drugs of anything.
Scott: with Edenism all these grapes I mean.
Scott: So if you're in the Russian military or if you're in any military right and you do something bad Usually they punish you right?
Scott: It could be some push-ups or maybe beetle Bailey style peeling some taters.
Rym: I figured they just hang you or like send you to Siberia their militaries where that happens.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: It might be like labor might be jail, right?
Scott: A lot of punishments are doled out in militaries right even killing pew even if you're by your own military.
Scott: But if you're in the Russian military, they have sense of humor.
Scott: I'm red.
Scott: So In Russian military right punishment get you.
Rym: that's it.
Rym: punishments always get you.
Rym: that's how punishments work I know.
Scott: so they're very creative as you would imagine if you were to say, I don't know Forget to bring your gun where you're supposed to bring it.
Scott: They punish you by giving you a replacement gun that you have to carry.
Rym: Oh, it's gonna be one of those like the devil ironic punishments.
Scott: It's a punishment that fits the crime and that punishment tends to be Carry a big heavy wooden thing around with you everywhere.
Rym: like those are amazing.
Scott: This guy who forgot who was looking at his phone when he was supposed to be military ing and doing something serious Was made to carry around a giant heavy wooden phone everywhere with him.
Rym: I like the guy huffing around the gigantic heavy wooden cigarette.
Scott: Yeah, so check this out and don't join the Russian military.
Scott: and if you do don't miss behave.
Scott: if you join any military of your own free will Or in fact if you're forced into military if you're conscripted at any point in your life into anything Whether you like it or not, I highly suggest following all orders Like if I'm just like, you know,
Rym: oh, yeah, you know, you're in the Nazi German army and you get ordered to do Genocide.
Rym: just follow the orders.
Scott: I'm just saying don't look at your phone If you're on the Navy boat with Horatio, don't do anything.
Scott: That's gonna get you any lashes.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So we we've had several things the day in the past Of like Richard Feynman doing something great because he's just one of the greatest people who have ever lived.
Scott: Yeah problems, but we do a lot about physics.
Rym: Yeah, but All the times we've ever had a Richard Feynman thing on the show It's always been like a thing he did like.
Rym: that is the entertaining thing of the day.
Scott: Well, it's usually.
Scott: I mean usually it's a video of him explaining something like the one where he talks about.
Scott: like.
Rym: You know, my favorite one is the one where he talks about magnets.
Rym: cuz the guys like.
Scott: so when I pushed I think I saw one where he talked about fire.
Scott: I don't remember the magnet.
Rym: one is good because I remember he was like that, you know Cuz there's always the quote-unquote idiot who's asking the questions.
Rym: the guys like so when I push two magnets against each other Like you feel something there like it's repelling and Feynman's like.
Rym: that's really a stupid question Like any and it's just.
Rym: it's one of my favorite videos of him ever.
Rym: but this is not a video of Feynman doing Feynman.
Rym: This is a video talking about Feynman and like actually is sort of a really short biography of why He was the way he was and who he was and I mean you can read.
Scott: there's a comic about this.
Scott: you can read.
Rym: Yeah, but if you've enjoyed like the Feynman-y things, I'm sure this biography is available.
Rym: This is a very short and succinct 10-minute video Explaining the why of Richard Feynman.
Scott: Not as good as my thing as a.
Rym: I think this is pretty good It.
Rym: it goes into great lengths about how many tell you know how he kept getting arrested for pranking people during the Manhattan Project.
Rym: Why wouldn't you all the strip club bongo stuff while he was doing physics.
Scott: I said he wasn't the greatest person.
Rym: It was a different time.
Rym: you understand Basically, what's funny is that the the word best used to describe him in this video is that while he was brilliant He was very annoying.
Rym: You don't say In the meta moment, um, I don't know if I'll peter out on the wheel of time, but I'm pushing into book 12.
Scott: So that like the last book.
Scott: No, there's like 14.
Scott: Oh, wow.
Scott: You're real close.
Scott: You can just tell me everything.
Rym: They're not hard reads.
Scott: No, they're not Anime, Boston's way soon.
Rym: Anime, Boston is not this weekend, but next weekend and we're doing five panels and lectures Friday and Saturday only and probably leave early on Sunday and not actually go to the con Anime, Boston's being weird and they're making us buy badges this show.
Scott: Do I have to actually do that?
Rym: Yeah before the 20th.
Scott: So I have to go to the anime Boston website and buy this.
Rym: the first time I have bought a badge To a fan can better get my fucking money back.
Scott: Yeah in like when do I get the money back?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: whenever they mail is a check after the con Screw you and you're.
Scott: you know, I'm not giving my money to the charity this time.
Rym: Yeah, I'm taking my money.
Rym: You're taking my money.
Rym: This is literally the first time since like 2002 I've gone to a website for a fan convention and Pre-registered like.
Rym: that's not something.
Scott: what if it's sold out?
Scott: I can't be panelist.
Rym: Well, then I'm gonna email him and be like, hey guys.
Rym: So, yeah if you really want us to be at anime Boston after this year You should probably let anime Boston know cuz we're going.
Rym: you know, we were doing five panels.
Rym: But if they make us buy badges and get reimbursed, we're not going back after this year.
Rym: So this be our last anime boss.
Scott: Yeah, it's kind of pain in the ass.
Rym: Yeah, all right after anime Boston the next weekend in Lancaster, Pennsylvania a convention that is not making us buy badges Zenkai con.
Scott: I think the chances me going to that are pretty low.
Rym: You're bailing on Zenkai con now.
Scott: I mean, it's a pain in the ass Scott.
Rym: if you go it'll be you me Chris and Anthony sharing a hotel playing board games the entire time.
Scott: Why don't we just not go and play board games in New York for some panels?
Rym: It's like close-up magic.
Rym: is that?
Rym: can we get a lot of fans out of?
Scott: and I got.
Scott: I gotta take a stupid train to Lancaster.
Scott: ruin my whole weekend.
Scott: have a. you know, it's a good weekend.
Scott: I'm losing.
Scott: I can go to the great yet I don't care about the good weather.
Scott: I'm just saying I'm losing the whole weekend.
Rym: You can go or not go.
Rym: I can do all those panels on my own pain.
Scott: It's really not worth the effort to go there.
Rym: Will you go next year if we if we do end up bailing on anime Boston forever more?
Rym: Is it gonna be in a much easier place to get no Lancaster's easier to get to them Boston the Amtrak's cheaper and you know It goes.
Rym: that lamb track goes directly to the convention.
Rym: It's not like you have to then take a $50 cab or some nonsense.
Scott: It's really not a pleasant trip.
Rym: Also, you can eat Amish food for one day and then there's nothing to eat on Sunday.
Scott: Yeah, that's another good reason not to go there.
Rym: We'll be doing a whole bunch of panels.
Rym: at least I'll be doing a whole bunch of panels.
Rym: and one of the panels.
Scott: Why do you want me to go there?
Scott: So then you don't have to.
Rym: I'm just saying fourth player for board games I don't need to go there.
Rym: Uh, one of the panels about.
Scott: you don't go there.
Scott: How about you?
Rym: just don't you want me to bail on a convention that we are listed guests at?
Scott: I think that'll go made a mistake already.
Scott: You already went in plus.
Rym: One of the panels is gonna be rimming Scott.
Rym: even if Scott doesn't go it's gonna be me and Scott Johnson.
Rym: Okay?
Scott: Yeah, go ahead.
Rym: I'll allow you like them apples.
Rym: Okay Shortly after that is PAX East in Boston where we'll be doing Atari game design one of our best recent lectures.
Rym: Also our video.
Rym: one of the many panels we did actually two now from PAX South are on YouTube.
Rym: The scary games panel is up and the designing game rules panel is up and the design design game rules panel is one of our better Lectures.
Scott: Why did they let us do that one at PAX East instead of Atari?
Rym: Whatever I'm pretty sure it's because the Atari one was a bigger draw.
Scott: I don't know about.
Rym: so they bully at PAX South.
Rym: They both filled the room packs out everything fills the room.
Rym: No, the panel both before and after us that every one of our slots far from filled the room.
Scott: I feel like the panel we went into before us was filling the.
Rym: no I wasn't I actually I was.
Rym: I was talking to some people a lot of those that our panels filled and not all the panels Filled by far.
Scott: Okay, that's good.
Scott: I guess.
Rym: Yeah, we're Actually kind of tell me how many rooms you filled zinc.
Rym: I can I feel we mostly.
Rym: the only time I didn't fill a room as thank icon was either going at a weird time or one They put me in main events.
Rym: I'm not gonna fill main events at any time.
Rym: I guess derpy Kong's they're made events.
Rym: It's like six people.
Rym: But where was I going with that?
Rym: right so designing game rules filled the room but Atari game design filled the room Way before the panel was gonna.
Scott: has I mean it has it.
Scott: they're judging based on that.
Scott: You should judge based on the quality of the panel not based on the.
Rym: you know People go to panels based on one thing The title and what time it's at?
Rym: Yeah, it was at four o'clock on a Saturday and it's called like and what else is at the same time as it?
Rym: Yeah, and the panel is called like.
Rym: hey free video cards fucking come here.
Scott: Why do we give away some video?
Rym: guys?
Rym: give away what it.
Rym: what if we could do a whole panel?
Rym: It's just why you shouldn't give shit away at your panel and then we'll give away like.
Rym: oh my god.
Scott: No, no, no, no.
Scott: go on let's go on eBay.
Scott: Oh, let's buy a whole bunch of old video card creative graphics blaster extreme.
Scott: I mean those are you.
Scott: we got to get ones that like those ones are probably actually more money.
Scott: We want to get like these in-between ones right like ones like like GTX for six.
Scott: Yes I'm like, yeah, right like knowing no one in the world wants that because it's completely useless.
Scott: get a bunch of them.
Scott: Be like video cards for free.
Scott: at this pan of like.
Scott: we're not lying.
Scott: There's video cards video cards.
Scott: You came for swag, well, this is what you get.
Scott: Greedy people teach you a lesson.
Scott: Now.
Scott: You got to take this useless shit home.
Rym: Then you got to do a whole actual lecture of reminding telling them all the reasons why what they're doing is bad.
Rym: They just feel bad.
Scott: We're not see.
Scott: they think we're dispensing video cards.
Rym: when a really dispensing Everyone you will find a video card taped to the bottom of your chair And We'll probably be at PAX Prime and then the next PAX out and we're definitely gonna be at PAX Prime.
Rym: I will very likely be at PAX Australia.
Rym: So stay tuned.
Scott: I might go to Europe instead.
Rym: I'll do both.
Rym: I'm going to Hong Kong.
Rym: I was just in Europe.
Rym: I'm just gonna go to Europe again kind of soon.
Scott: So I'll go to Essen.
Rym: Maybe we should go to Essen sometime.
Scott: I think it's at the same time think I had to choose between that and packs out.
Scott: They're both in October.
Scott: The problem is Essen would just be fun if they're not in the same exact time in October, they're pretty close, right?
Rym: So that'd be difficult as a conundrum because Essen would be fun to go to like just objectively.
Rym: But PAX South is a very fruitful convention for us as performing in Australia and entertainers PAX Australia is also fruitful because yeah, you think our panels fill at PAX South or PAX East our panels fucking fill.
Scott: Thanks, Australia.
Scott: The country is desperate for nerdery.
Rym: Yeah I mean remember when I first started the patreon.
Scott: So you get for living far away from everything.
Scott: the mayor.
Scott: and the thing is I when I went there I thought there would be so much better nerdery because they're so close to Japan, which is the fountain of nerdery, but no Japan's still pretty far away from Australia.
Rym: I started researching to start our patreon literally because when I said that we probably wouldn't go to that pad the last PAX Australia Meaning you're skipping our first packs ever as GeekNights More than a dozen people like 14 or 15 people Independently reached out to me and we're like, so how much would it take?
Rym: like what if we donate money?
Rym: Like what if we do a collection sure?
Scott: Listen don't give money to the patreon.
Scott: But if you want to give me $1400 to buy a plane ticket to Australia, that's okay at the current patreon levels.
Rym: We could just use that to fund a trip to Australia for packs.
Rym: We just have to.
Scott: you're making $1400 a year.
Rym: Yeah, we're making like 250 a month.
Rym: 250 times 12 is Yeah, all right As soon as we use the patreon money for something then we're obligated to make like.
Rym: You know how we did those videos and that they look we're gonna spend the whole con making videos.
Scott: Why I can't just buy a plane ticket to Australia and go to the coral reef.
Rym: I Don't you hate I don't think that's what the patrons expect.
Scott: They've gave their money.
Scott: That's not their money anymore.
Scott: I told them they're stupid.
Scott: They don't listen.
Rym: We could do a show live underwater.
Scott: They're upset.
Scott: I'm gonna say I told you.
Scott: so Come on.
Scott: so Preparation.
Scott: Yeah, so we didn't have a show idea for today.
Rym: But I know I know the worst thing is we came up with a bunch of show ideas But they all required at least 15 minutes worth of research.
Scott: That's every show idea.
Scott: But anyway, so I realized you know lately, you know, there's those certain things that you like you notice more lately, right?
Scott: So like you learn you learn a new word.
Scott: I forget the name for this thing is but you learn a new word Bears everywhere exactly.
Scott: so lately I've noticed a lot more preppers or at least prepper attitudes.
Scott: You know people saying like oh man gotta have your grab bag, you know your go bag in case something happens.
Rym: I don't think it is more common more talk more.
Scott: No, I'm just saying and lately I've noticed more talk of things like shelters or Survivalist attitude.
Scott: I will say I've noticed less people saying they would move away from the city.
Rym: so that you know I think that peaked in terms of me running into it in the early 2000s like 2002 2003.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I'm just no I'm not saying it's peaked I'm saying I'm noticing it more lately than I did a little while ago.
Scott: It's increasing right now in my in my perspective of anecdotal living.
Rym: now on the side Fun fact my mom basically bought a house that was kind of built and owned by preppers like that.
Scott: But your mom is not a prepper.
Rym: No, but she has a prepper compound basically.
Scott: I mean, it doesn't hurt It's like.
Rym: it's like she has a well when Arizona is a dried desert husk with no people living in it You mean my mom's.
Scott: well, isn't that what Arizona is?
Rym: It's a dried house, but there's still people in it.
Rym: Sure, but when there's no people because all the water is gone My mom's well, but I mean still there's no water there either is if you dig deep enough There's really water under there.
Rym: Yeah you so I did the well on this property is Ridiculous like Ridiculous.
Rym: how much of a well they put on.
Rym: this is the kind of well you would put on a secret government facility That needed to survive the atomic.
Scott: but I mean, I don't understand how there's water under there.
Scott: if I go to the Sahara Desert I mean sure there are spots where you can dig and there will be water but not every spot.
Rym: How deep do you think a well is?
Scott: Now you're already thinking you got to go basically under the bedrock to where the water table is.
Rym: The water table is under the bedrock.
Rym: I'm pretty sure it is, you know about as much about hydrology as you do out the Supreme Court.
Scott: It sounds like I know know much about hydrology or geology, but you got to dig through rocks.
Scott: It's not just like under the dirt.
Rym: So my mom deals.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: it's not dirt water rocks.
Scott: Anyway, dirt rocks water rocks.
Rym: My mom lives in a place Where the people around like an example.
Rym: if you go to the feed store because you just pick up feed like the horses and everything The people there doesn't grow it.
Rym: It's the desert.
Rym: all right You could grow it in other parts of Arizona, but not that.
Scott: well, you can't irrigate with that.
Rym: Well, I guess you could but you don't want to dry the well.
Scott: I don't get some sand.
Rym: Anyway, the they're like people at the feed store Literally think that Obama is gonna get a third term and literally come with European troops and literally take their guns.
Scott: Well, I mean that's a person who lives in the desert.
Scott: Yeah, who gives a fuck those people?
Rym: so my mom lives in a place where there's a lot of prep.
Scott: I mean, I would give more credit to the scorpion living in the desert and the Gila monster Not a Scorpio then to the person like Scorpio right like a Gila monster.
Scott: The desert is a native environment.
Scott: a person living in the desert is dumb.
Rym: People went into environments that weren't native to them and then just made bent them to their will with technology.
Scott: Yes, that's Adventuring.
Scott: it's also dumb.
Rym: venturing is amazing.
Scott: live in a comfortable place.
Rym: So here's the extent of what I have prepared for.
Rym: Let's start with that like what we've each prepared for because I've prepared for Problems money can solve by getting money.
Rym: Yeah, but that's easy.
Rym: I can't so.
Rym: but how do you per so like when I try and money don't use it all?
Scott: Well, here's a very specific example.
Rym: So I travel to a lot of foreign countries very often Mm-hmm, and I've traveled to places that are not the safest places pretty often.
Scott: Hmm, and I might actually are we talking Somalia unsafe or are we talking like New York City?
Rym: I'm talking like Istanbul current situation unsafe.
Scott: Well, I mean if you stay in the city is mostly okay.
Rym: More that's the problem.
Scott: Are you worried about like protests getting?
Rym: No, there was a terror attack in Istanbul not that long ago.
Scott: Oh, I mean, that's I mean that's anywhere right?
Scott: No, but it was a terror attack in New York not long ago.
Rym: No No, I'm talking like very recently.
Rym: Also, there hadn't been attacks like that before yet.
Rym: There are attacks in other parts of Turkey all the time And there are terror attacks in Paris Specifically targeted foreigners like me attacking the kind of place.
Rym: I would be mmm Like it's.
Rym: that's like.
Rym: I'm not saying I'm a coward like.
Rym: I'll still go to Istanbul again probably soon But I will not go hang out.
Scott: I mean, there's a much worse attack in Paris.
Scott: Would you go there?
Rym: Yeah, actually that attack was real near where I stay.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know.
Rym: But when I travel to those places, I do a few things.
Rym: if I'm not in my hotel room I always have my passport with me.
Scott: Yeah, no matter what.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But if someone stops you and it's like papers, please most places aren't like that actually.
Scott: and actually if someone says papers Please they don't fucking get my passport Obviously, but what if you need to like run to the consulate or something you in your passports in your hotel room?
Scott: That's not a good situation.
Rym: that would actually Usually be fine because if you get to the consulate they can issue an emergency passport to get you the hell out of you.
Scott: But it's much easier if you just have one.
Rym: I keep my passport with me just because I don't want.
Rym: I want to be able to if something goes wrong leave the country normally without having to go back to my hotel.
Rym: Yeah, also, I don't want to have to go to the console if someone finds your dead body.
Scott: They'll know who you were.
Rym: No, I'm pretty sure the American passports are valuable enough.
Rym: They just take it.
Scott: if they even were thinking about that Maybe they just think about murdering you.
Rym: I don't think anyone thinks.
Rym: Hey, let's just murder that guy.
Scott: Well, I don't think anyone thinks let's make a terror attack and then steal all the Americans passports.
Scott: They think let's make a terror attack and get on the news.
Rym: It's a random mugging.
Rym: They're gonna take my passport.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yes They will.
Rym: but in the hotel room, you know that safe that no one uses.
Rym: I use that safe You know, I put in that safe if I'm in a country like that.
Scott: I use that.
Rym: So I do that in any kind pretty much anywhere.
Rym: I travel I don't use it going to PAX what I put in.
Rym: Sometimes I do in facts, but usually instead of putting the safe I just put what I'm about to tell you.
Rym: I put in the safe.
Rym: just in the room somewhere I put my backup credit card.
Rym: I Put like 50 bucks Mm-hmm and one of my IDs like a driver's license or something.
Scott: I would put anything valuable electronically that I wasn't going to bring around with me.
Scott: like my camera I'm probably carrying but like if I wasn't carrying every lens with me Even if I brought I wouldn't even bring them to a country like that.
Scott: probably cuz you only need to bring a few travel Photography.
Scott: you don't bring a lot of lenses, right?
Scott: Yeah, but like laptop, you know iPad, I'm not carrying around all day.
Scott: That's going in the safe.
Rym: See no no So you're that's that's.
Rym: I think that's orthogonal to our point cuz that's just like avoid theft comment.
Scott: None of this is talking about the prepper type people who worried about like the flood or you know, any, you know nuclear.
Rym: well I'll make it relevant that we can go back to the nuclear war nonsense, but I basically I do when I travel Put a stay cash of ID credit card and some cash Separate from my regular supply of credit card ID and cash.
Rym: So say like someone steals my bag that has my passport and my wallet in it Well, as long as I can somehow get back to my hotel room, but if you don't have the keys to your hotel I just stole those.
Rym: I'm pretty sure I would be able to talk to the front desk without an ID.
Scott: They'll give you keys to a room.
Rym: I could probably make that happen.
Scott: It's I mean, yeah, it's not too hard But that's tough.
Rym: I could make that happen.
Scott: Yeah, but also actually I think it is a pain in the ass.
Rym: my hotel key I always put in a pocket separate from all my other stuff obviously But I have enough stuff to be able to afford to like take a cab to the airport Enough ID to at least convince them who I am like all that stuff.
Rym: So in my real life like outside of travel.
Rym: the amount of preparation I do is if there's a huge huge storm coming I don't buy anything different at all But I do fill the tub with water if it's like a hurricane.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: It's all I do If the storm is coming and I only do that.
Rym: so one emergency I guess I give the rabbits water but two so I can flush the toilet if Water pressure goes away for a few days.
Scott: if the storm is coming I close the windows.
Scott: and if it's what?
Scott: if there's like there was a travel ban, I think in the winter this year I just stay home, right?
Scott: I stay obviously but I don't buy anything.
Scott: I couldn't get delivery with the travel ban.
Rym: So I made yeah, you could actually the grub hub was working fine during the travel ban.
Rym: Really?
Scott: Yeah, I did not.
Scott: I was not able to grow up up.
Rym: delivery guys were biking walking there.
Scott: I kept looking out the window to see if there was any and there weren't.
Rym: so there are pictures on guy delivery men literally wearing snowshoes.
Scott: Well, I wish I would have known that but basically my preparation was given like a $20 tip if someone delivered some pizza.
Rym: Yeah, I bought.
Scott: I bought a box of macaroni and cheese so I would have something to eat and you know.
Rym: But I if like say civilization like civil order broke down.
Rym: There's only like a week's worth of food in my apartment.
Scott: Like I don't have enough food I usually only have like two days of food.
Rym: Well when I say a week's worth, I mean like there's pasta.
Rym: We haven't eaten that I guess we could cook.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay, plain pasta.
Scott: That'll be delicious.
Rym: Yeah, but it's food.
Scott: I guess I'm frozen food.
Scott: I can make a lot of banana breads.
Rym: I've got a bunch of rice.
Rym: I got enough rice to keep me going for maybe a couple weeks.
Scott: Yeah, I got plenty of rice.
Rym: I could rice it up, but my philosophy in terms of by rice in bulk actually an Amazon is that I live in New York.
Rym: Any disaster that is big enough?
Rym: Such that by the power of walking alone I cannot within 24 hours get to a place where civil order still remains.
Rym: I was fucked anyway And there's literally nothing I could have ever done to help myself.
Scott: Yeah, you could have not lived in New York.
Scott: Which preppers do that's?
Scott: the first thing they do is they move and live in the middle of nowhere because they think the society Collapses if there's riots or there's nuclear war There's fires or floods they will be far away from all that stuff and there's farms near them.
Scott: But I've spent time that they live in can be a self-sustaining Human you know nurturing place even if all other society is destroyed.
Rym: I've lived or spent time or had family members who do live in very remote areas.
Scott: You know what, you know, but they're ridiculously deep.
Rym: well if you're not a if you're not a prepper you still need to do a lot of preparation because like in New York a Mundane disaster like the power goes out.
Rym: I can just deal with it.
Rym: You know stuff happens the water.
Scott: they got generators.
Scott: They're good.
Rym: say the Water supply stops like say my buildings water break.
Scott: They have wells.
Scott: They don't need.
Rym: they don't have that problem yeah, but so if here's the here's the difference in New York.
Rym: if the well pump system like the distribution water system for my local part of the city like my building or my block breaks down I Can go to the bodega and buy water.
Rym: if you live out in the middle of nowhere stop delivering it Yeah, but in the short term like in the immediate term.
Scott: Yes, if you live in the middle of no preppers are not worried about a short-term problem They're worried about the big one.
Rym: No But I'm saying short term problems become a much bigger deal if you live in a remote place.
Rym: if the well Pump system breaks on your well, and you live in like Northern Michigan It's actually like you've got a travel significant distance to get water let alone get the parts to fix your well.
Scott: Usually you just call someone who would come and fix your well.
Scott: Yeah, but if civil orders breaking down you think that well person is gonna come and fix your fucking well I guess he better know how to fix your own well, but the preppers are not really rational.
Rym: Yeah I'm just talking about the rational amount of preparation I do like when I when we like when I was a kid we lived in places where there wasn't an exotic animal hospital within walking distance.
Rym: We kept a bunch of medical supplies in case like there was a medical emergency like dog gets hurt or something like we had medical supplies we could do sutures and stitches and things.
Rym: and Actually if I lived like in upstate, New York like the top part in New York like I guess Oh the real upstate New York north of Albany, New.
Rym: actually someone gave me some terminology I'm gonna start using.
Rym: I just remembered this.
Rym: they said that Canada.
Rym: No they said there are.
Rym: here are the regions of New York.
Rym: There's New York City, which is New York.
Rym: yes, there's upstate which means anywhere along the New York State Thruway There's outstate which means north of the New York State Thruway.
Scott: What about the Elmira Corning area?
Scott: That's south of the Thruway.
Rym: That's Penn State Penn State in upstate Downstate outstate.
Rym: those are the four parts of New York.
Rym: I'm gonna use this terminology.
Scott: if it's on 87 or 90 Upstate but 87. what about the part where 87 keeps going into outstate?
Scott: That's not the Thruway, but it's still 87 the Thruway.
Scott: Originally you're the one who said only it's only 87 and 90 and not say 90. so 90 east of 87 doesn't count and 87 north of 90.
Rym: You can just say the New York State Thruway.
Rym: That's a designated road.
Rym: I'm just saying unless you're within a feel like some small number of miles of the New York State Thruway and Yonkers.
Rym: but now you're upstate.
Scott: the thing is 90 east of 87 really isn't?
Scott: it's a lot like upstate.
Scott: It's not like outstate.
Rym: You know what there's a let's say.
Rym: There's a buffer anywhere.
Rym: There's a big city like you're on Albany or Syracuse.
Rym: That's upstate.
Rym: Like the area around Albany is upstate.
Rym: you get north of Albany.
Rym: That's outstate.
Rym: Yeah Preppers yeah, this is your idea.
Rym: you got more to say other than those.
Scott: people are dumb Dumb and crazy, and they're worried about some like disaster.
Scott: And it's not gonna happen.
Scott: and even if it does happen their preparation isn't really gonna help them.
Scott: It's not gonna be like some zombie attack movie where you escape the city And you find some guy who still lives at his house And he's got all the canned goods and you're safe now for at least a while until you until you know you have Interhuman troubles.
Rym: well, that's getting it.
Scott: you go out there, and that guy's dead already and maybe this canned food there.
Scott: Yeah Like that's what always Amazing about the preppers and you didn't even make it out there because you're dead.
Rym: to people who prudently prepare for things like.
Rym: Here's the difference.
Rym: a prepper spends a lot of time and money on like learning how to do basic farming and like learning how to smelt iron and learning how to start fires from nothing.
Rym: a Real prepper as in someone who is preparing for something lit that could happen.
Rym: Matches and lighters will still exist for decades after the breakdown of civil order.
Rym: There are so many lighters in the world.
Rym: I don't think you need to be able to start a fire with Flint I think you'll be able to find a lighter.
Scott: so If the fuel in the lighter is decomposed or leaked out you can get a match or just find another light.
Scott: I mean the bodega next to me.
Scott: Do you know how many matches they have?
Scott: if I'm like the only one left alive in Astoria?
Rym: I will have so many matches, but like there is no scenario ever Where the prepper guy out the middle of nowhere?
Rym: Knowing how to sew wheats and run a farm Like his own farm to rebuild society is actually gonna matter appreciably doesn't even have the manpower.
Scott: Even if he could sew the wheat, you can't harvest the wheat and mill it and do the baking.
Scott: It is not enough people.
Rym: That's almost like you'll need to recreate society.
Rym: I just I don't think any situation.
Scott: how many babies are they gonna make?
Rym: any situation where?
Rym: Some of the cities don't survive is a situation where don't worry about it.
Rym: That's Mad Max.
Rym: That's that's such a different paradigm of existence that all that preparation was literally meaningless.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I just imagine the guy like you know Everyone's like the even the city people tend to have like the go bag like if something happens I can grab this and run.
Scott: now We are like, all right.
Scott: So what situation happened?
Scott: We have to grab this and run newt goes off in downtown, Manhattan Okay, we're disintegrated.
Rym: Anyway, that's not that big Didn't?
Scott: we just do an episode about how thermonuclear weapons are so enormous.
Rym: You didn't really pay attention that thermonuclear weapons did exist.
Rym: that are that enormous Modern thermonuclear weapons let alone the kind of device that would let if it was likely to happen what happened in New York Would not touch us where we are in Queen.
Scott: I mean, we're still not gonna make it.
Rym: Oh, why not?
Rym: Actually, that's a very survival thing for us Really?
Scott: Yeah, how what are you gonna do?
Scott: So you go outside?
Scott: You're all radiate.
Rym: Actually a an air burst of a thermonuke like a modern one that would take out lower Manhattan.
Rym: The radiation exposure here would not be significant.
Scott: All right, good.
Rym: If it was a ground burst it would become very significant over the course of days.
Scott: How do you know?
Scott: they're not gonna.
Scott: you know, you think they're gonna shoot just one in New York.
Scott: They're not gonna like hit Queens - yeah.
Rym: So again, I'm not talking about global thermonuclear war is again a scenario where fuck it you're fine But you don't think it.
Scott: regular bombs that's gonna land on you, but imagine the much you're gonna lucky.
Scott: You're the building.
Scott: that's not gonna be a ball.
Rym: regular bombs gonna get here.
Rym: What countries have capabilities to bomb the United States?
Scott: not many.
Rym: but here's a plausible but unrealistic scenario.
Rym: Scott a Terrorist sets off a nuke in downtown Manhattan destroying like a job.
Scott: It's some if it's one that can be set off right carried.
Scott: It's not really gonna hurt us over here.
Rym: Uh a There are bombs that could be carried.
Scott: let's say let's make it let's get let's get worse though, right?
Scott: The nuke in Manhattan doesn't matter what kind.
Scott: you're at work.
Scott: You're in Manhattan.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: You're not a home.
Rym: So what would I do?
Scott: In fact, you're on the street walking a lunch.
Rym: You're not even in a building Yep, so the new goes off in downtown, Tribeca, right?
Scott: There's a flash you can't see now.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: You're on the street Yep, so it happened.
Scott: Well, you got a few seconds.
Rym: No, cuz it wouldn't I wouldn't do within the kind of bomb that would actually be likely in that not improbable scenario.
Rym: is Not the kind of bomb that would disintegrate me even at that radius?
Rym: Probably be okay.
Scott: Just days Yeah, no one's gonna die when the new goes off near them.
Scott: Yeah, how near You're in downtown Manhattan.
Rym: Let's say let's say we're both in Midtown doing something and a new goes off in downtown.
Scott: I'm saying it goes off near you.
Rym: Well, if it's close enough to vaporize me It didn't matter.
Rym: if I'm outside of these significant blast radius, then I'm probably gonna survive.
Rym: and I actually have a plan.
Scott: What's your plan?
Scott: run away?
Rym: So I would basically head northeast and I'd have to get over the river into Queens Long Island as fast as possible.
Scott: However, I do it because we're gonna swim over the East River.
Rym: that that's a pretty easy swim It's.
Scott: it's not the distance isn't the problem.
Rym: Well, then what's the problem?
Scott: The water is probably more deadly than the radiation.
Rym: Not in the short term.
Rym: that slightly increased risk of cancer down the road.
Rym: Maybe some gastrointestinal distress I can do.
Scott: also fish.
Rym: That's not the foot of the fish gonna eat me.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: No, yes.
Rym: so what I actually probably do is Walk over what.
Scott: also you're gonna hit by a boat cuz you might probably not.
Scott: You don't think the boats are gonna.
Scott: you think everyone who's got a boat isn't gonna be using it to go.
Rym: Actually, the boats will probably be clogging the waters.
Rym: I'm gonna jump from boat to boat And also you can't get.
Rym: the boats are so high you I would probably head to The area of next to Roosevelt Island and go across that little bit and then take the bridge in Roosevelt Island to my house.
Scott: Good strategy, but another good strategy.
Scott: See I'm so much smarter than you.
Rym: I what's your strategy?
Scott: steal a boat?
Rym: You Scott, you know how to start a boat if it's a boat with a steering wheel.
Rym: Do you know how to steer a boat?
Rym: Cuz at all.
Scott: with the steering wheel.
Rym: if you ever sailboat I got fucked.
Scott: But if it's a powered boat with a steering wheel, I'm good.
Rym: How big is this boat?
Scott: Doesn't matter.
Rym: Yeah, it does because it's really small.
Rym: So and you know what and you know if I get out Have you ever piloted a boat?
Scott: Yeah with a steering wheel.
Rym: It wasn't a swan boat.
Scott: Also swan boat Boat.
Rym: you're fucked.
Rym: like you said the water is will be clogged because remember the danger of a new going up.
Scott: so much water You can just move.
Scott: you're on roads that get jammed with traffic.
Scott: I just go Scott air helicopters even better.
Rym: a couple of boats bumping into each other fuck everything forever Only if they're real big.
Scott: no Do the circle line and probably make an escape you get your boat.
Rym: Now.
Rym: What were you gonna go?
Rym: up or down?
Scott: Depends where the boat is.
Rym: All right, you get a boat of the East River up or down.
Scott: where in the East River?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: next to Roosevelt Island you go to the ferry dock and you steal the ferry.
Scott: Yeah Oh, oh the like the water tax.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh water tax we can go up to where Long Island Sound Connecticut.
Rym: All right.
Rym: That's your plan.
Rym: Just bail that way.
Rym: Yeah, why not?
Rym: So I have more pressing concerns of Emily's.
Rym: probably at home somewhere and I got rabbits that I want to save.
Scott: No Well, I don't know how to need to save anybody here except me.
Rym: Yeah, so I actually plus you pretty much want to get away.
Scott: if you go back for people That's always a bad news every time in any sort of zombie movie.
Scott: when you go back for people all you find is dead people.
Scott: No, but it's not a good deal.
Scott: You don't want to see the main character then you find the people and then you have to deal with them and then they die Later and it wasn't worrying.
Scott: you were doing better off.
Rym: going west would actually be difficult probably because that's where everyone else is trying to Definitely not going west and while East is a dead end, but Long Island is pretty big It's not a dead end.
Scott: You got to see and you go to some other country.
Rym: Well, how are you gonna go out to see?
Scott: those boats are not seaworthy At least in the Hudson River.
Scott: There's cruise ships you can get on.
Rym: You're gonna pilot.
Rym: occurs you're gonna steal a cruise ship.
Scott: No, but there's a captain on there.
Rym: Yeah, that cruise ship is already teaming with refugees like streaming onto it falling off freaking out.
Rym: You didn't get anywhere near that thing.
Scott: Not if it's just like in-between voyages.
Scott: Basically my real plan my literal like not even joking plan is I know how to pronounce voyage by the way I just wanted to say voyage Cuz.
Scott: you know people say bon voyage, right?
Scott: Yeah, that's they're not saying bond voyage.
Rym: If shit ever went down in New York, and I had to get away my actual plan is to Basically put the rabbits in backpacks with like a cliff bar or something cuz I've always got those around.
Scott: Yes, I'm sure the effort of saving the rabbits.
Rym: It's worth it.
Rym: Okay, I'll save pets.
Rym: I would save pets in nuclear disaster.
Scott: Listen, the dog can you gotta have dog dog can save itself But just follow you but rabbit is probably okay.
Rym: Let's put them back back.
Rym: We're good.
Scott: I mean, I probably die going back to the river.
Rym: Bring this back around Preparing to like hunker down and live here through this temporary societal breakdown not worth it.
Rym: I'm not gonna have like a month of food and hide in my apartment with like a water supply growing crops on the roof We and like barricading it waiting for civil order to get restored.
Scott: No, I could live in DMZ New York.
Scott: That'd be cool with that.
Rym: Yeah, I'd rather live in DMZ, New York than modern-day Rural, I only prepare enough to where by getting on my bike and or walking within a day I get to a place where there's still running water and food.
Scott: Yeah, I could bike away.
Rym: Yeah, actually biking away is really the best way to get out because the roads be clogged immediately.
Rym: But once a roads clogged, it's real easy to bike on that road.
Scott: Really and you know, even if the shoulders clogged it's like well, that's right.
Scott: Well occasionally when the cars are too close to each other you get off your bike and walk the biggest Over a car.
Rym: The only actual danger is shit heads who were stuck in their cars trying to steal your bike.
Rym: So you got to be willing to punch and or shoot a person along the way.
Scott: Well, I mean if there's a Mad Max You're gonna have to start shooting or punching people because you got fist of the North Star power.
Rym: Yeah, so I'd probably walk across the bridge.
Rym: you might think but Rym the bridge is especially like the Queensborough Bridge is gonna be completely Fuck.
Rym: Yes, that's true.
Scott: Well, you better hope it's structurally sound after depending what happened.
Rym: Well, if something happened that could a lot of these bridges.
Scott: bridges are not new.
Scott: They're not fancy modern bridges, right?
Rym: So I am a very capable boulderer.
Rym: I could easily because if if it got bad the cops aren't gonna come up on the bridge and stop me They don't give a fuck I would just climb over like the top of the bridge.
Rym: that actually be really easy to do Avoiding all the dangerous people all the cars all the bullshit that's going on in the regular part of the bridge.
Scott: Listen, you know what?
Scott: In fact something interesting right.
Scott: knowing stuff about the city helps right?
Scott: It's like the Hellgate bridge Which is right near me.
Scott: Yep That bridge has been way old.
Scott: That's like a multi super old bridge.
Scott: ridiculously old is also a rail bridge.
Scott: No one's gonna be on it and the trains aren't gonna be running either.
Scott: I just get up there and walk over.
Scott: people have done that.
Scott: It's not really a problem.
Rym: Yep, I actually I know about.
Rym: I actually know the routes of a lot of the subway tunnels that aren't used or at least aren't used for passenger service.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: So yeah, everything is gonna be safe down there.
Scott: So Scott Oh, it's not safe down there now.
Rym: So to go back to your other scenario if a significant if I was close to a nuke that went off that didn't kill me In New York, the most important thing to do Not is just to get away from the possible radiation effects.
Scott: Well as soon as there are buildings that have little fallout signs on them You just find one of those and go in.
Rym: the plebs are all gonna go into those.
Scott: I would probably I don't think the plebs even know to go into those.
Scott: they make plebs from the 50s No, but plebs modern-day plebs are never taught.
Rym: Plebs are in the street freaking out.
Rym: You got to get off the street into one of those nice buildings.
Rym: I would not do that.
Rym: I would actually go down into the subway tunnel.
Scott: Yeah, that's about it about a safe because the people aren't gonna go down there.
Rym: They're afraid of that shit and I let me tell you subways gonna stop running real quick.
Scott: No, you better hope the third rail turns off.
Rym: I am confident that I am capable of not touching the third rail.
Scott: You never know.
Rym: Also, I know where a lot of those like secret shafts and paths are down there.
Rym: I just go down there and walk along all those paths until I could get to Queens.
Rym: Sure, just staying underground out of the radiation.
Scott: I'd go more to the Bronx where it's safer.
Rym: The Bronx is gonna be clogged with refugees streaming north freaking out and killing each other.
Scott: I'm underground.
Scott: So they uh, the subway is above ground there Not the a-train.
Rym: Yeah, but the a-train doesn't go far enough.
Scott: I can get to Fort Tryon.
Rym: No, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, that's in Manhattan still.
Rym: then what?
Scott: That's a fort.
Rym: you're gonna you know barricade yourself in the fort with the tapestry preppers with the tapestries.
Rym: I've actually never gone in there and seen the tapestries.
Scott: You really haven't.
Rym: no in all these years I've never done.
Scott: I've been there like two or three times.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I kind of do.
Scott: It's really nice.
Scott: It's a nice park there too.
Rym: As soon as it's nice enough.
Rym: You mean Emily lives bike there and go in.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty safe to tie your bike up outside.
Rym: Also, I'll carry my crazy lock between.
Rym: the three of us will have three locks will lock all our bikes together It's so.
Rym: it'll take someone a while to get through all those chairs.
Scott: This is just a donation to see the tapestries, you know, I've never been there.
Rym: Maybe I'll give him a donation of some kind.
Rym: Yeah You had anything else you wanted to say about preppers?
Scott: No, I just that was the only idea I had those remotely viable.
Rym: cuz.
Rym: I basically don't prepare for anything except by having money.
Rym: Yep, but I do do common sense preparation.
Scott: money can't save you you're fucked.
Scott: Anyway, whatever.
Rym: but like I said If a serious storm is coming and I'm not evacuating like hurricanes coming to New York and I'm not Evacuation zone so everyone else in this
Scott: area if you look at them If you look at like the flooding map because I mean, I'm pretty close to the water right the East River Actually my it's like across the street.
Scott: It's like a not so good flooding but like my apartment building like I.
Rym: yeah My block is literally the go here if shit goes south like situation, but I'm just like one zoned different.
Scott: They're like in an ocean flood zone.
Rym: I'm gonna like me Reasonable preparation if there is.
Scott: also I'm on the third floor so I kind of hope that if there is a flood that it reaches the third floor because then I can just like get a Rowboat outside my you know balcony and start moving around.
Rym: You're gonna even have a rowboat.
Scott: I'll just get inflatable I got.
Rym: are you gonna buy one before the hurricane?
Scott: No an Amazon drone will deliver to me.
Scott: Yeah Exist.
Rym: yet This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brand.
Scott: ok for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row crew Com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: this episode of GeekNights is brought to you by the following patrons all of whom are giving us at least five dollars and Are listed in the order of the amount of money that they give us?
Rym: Rebecca Dunn Nicholas brand our man to do shed The dot-com mechanical mind.
Rym: William Eisen rose Jeremy minor you expected the next name to yours, but it was me do.
Rym: Scott John Harrison Sean Yeager Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Robert Lee Ryan parent drew open lander rare Lavelle Brian's Adroni Rochelle, Monta Nona Finn Eric silver odd can melt steel beams.
Rym: Kinetic man Aaron Cerise Chris mink.
Rym: if Chris Knox Renee from news we hand Sam Cordery Daniel Redmond Chris a dad Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: I'm getting near the end of the wheel of time so I might do a little special and Just review the entire wheel of time because I actually know that a good number of you Enjoy the wheel of time as you bring up.
Rym: every time I tweet something obscure like what we're at all tours up to today And I get a lot of like oh what bookie you wanted.
Rym: such as such happened yet, so we'll see.
Rym: I suspect Scott will not read past the fifth or sixth book so it's gonna be just me And I don't think I could ever give it to Emily to read these books And I kind of have to finish him before the next our Scott backer book comes out because I plan to read all Of the Prince of Nothing books again in order to anticipate that book's arrival.
Rym: Anyway, as I said we got a bunch of panels up.
Rym: We just put up the February Q&A.
Rym: the March Q&A question submission is gonna come up real soon.
Rym: tomorrow Rimly review.
Rym: I'll have the review of Zootopia that Emily and I did and I'm finally.
Rym: I said I was gonna do this before and I Got distracted.
Rym: I'm gonna put up something for the regular patrons everyone not just the $5 people but basically I'm gonna give a Google form and I want you to submit like a sentence or something and I'm just gonna read them in the order that they get submitted And I'm gonna open the thing for a while and then close it And I'm just gonna tell whatever story you guys ask me to tell and we'll see how that goes.
Rym: this might be a terrible Terrible mistake.
Rym: and now I leave you with something Interest.
Rym: who cares about brains of the people happy.
Rym: don't lower your luxury rate.
Rym: You can do anything but lay off my luxury rate noble leader.
Scott: I concur your majesty Know your majesty.
Rym: pay them though.
Rym: He your majesty.
Rym: a word your majesty I'm concerned majesty May oh Yeah, uh-huh, I Don't mean to be stubborn on your gilded sandals King, but the government will fall if we don't entertain the people Science and taxes be damaged on openness.
Rym: The people need luxuries to soothe their aching hearts.
Rym: a Cloud darkens our land noble leader and the people need entertaining quickly.
Scott: Wise men say it only fools run an empire without luxuries.