Rym: So, when Emily and I saw Star Wars, we went and saw it at the 84th Street AMC, which is the only theater in New York.
Rym: Of all the theaters I go to in New York, unless it's a weird movie, that's the only one I'll actually go to for a new movie.
Rym: because assigned seating, which I know you European listeners are like, "Why is that
Rym: special?".
Rym: That's not the usual way theaters work in the US.
Rym: We basically just showed up a minute before it was going to start, sat down in our recliners, and watched the movie.
Scott: The way movie theaters in the US have worked has changed many, many times over the course of history.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: If you want to go back to the old fantasy days.
Scott: I mean, not even the old days.
Scott: If we had gone in New York to see Return of the Jedi in the early '80s and we were zero, or less negative, whatever, we would have gone to see in Times Square.
Scott: Right now in Times Square, there's the AMC, I don't know how many theaters are in there, like a zillion.
Rym: The AMC Tourist Theater.
Scott: It's like a multiplex of a zillion theaters all in this one crazy maze above Dave & Buster's or whatever.
Scott: You know what used to be there?
Scott: One really big fucking theater, like Radio City Music Hall big, where they had thousands of seats.
Rym: That's the kind of place where there's a Panavision 70 millimeter screen going all the way across.
Scott: Radio City Music Hall is the only place that's still like that, where it's really long and has four tiers and it seats thousands of people in it.
Scott: They have a movie screen in there because I've seen them use it, but they don't really show movies there anymore.
Scott: I'm sure if you had enough money to rent the place out, you could watch Star Wars and Radio City Music Hall.
Scott: But that's how it used to be, right?
Scott: The multiplex is actually an invention early in our lives where you would have more than like two screens in one place.
Scott: It used to be the kind of theaters where there would be two movies showing.
Rym: Yeah, well because two movies came out.
Rym: Right.
Scott: There would be two movies at a time at the theater and you'd have one of those sort of big neon light kind of things out, marquees out front with two movies listed on one on each side, one for theater one and one for theater two.
Scott: And the multiplex is a new thing and now the multiplex is going away.
Scott: So it's like, yeah, every like 20 something years or so, the way, you know, movie theaters are, you know, designed and made is it changes drastically.
Scott: It's not, you know, people think like, oh my God, it's always been a multiplex.
Scott: It's like, no, it's not.
Scott: That's less old than me, the multiplex.
Rym: But there is.
Rym: so we said we said we sat down and there was an Italian family to the left of us.
Rym: I'm pretty sure they were Italian.
Rym: That's kind of what the language sounded like.
Scott: It's that they're
Rym: going back and forth between Italian and English and they're being
Scott: kind of rowdy, but I made it to meet the ball, but
Rym: it's during the trailers like it's fine because the Kung Fu Panda three trailer happened and at the end of it, you know, the guys like, I think I peed a little.
Rym: So the next trailer was shitty.
Rym: I forget what movie it was.
Rym: So the trailer like fades out and I just go, I think I peed a little and they laughed real hard at that.
Rym: So it was all cool.
Rym: But then right before the movie is actually about to start, one of the old ladies suddenly gets up and has to pee and then she stumbles back into the theater like just as Star Wars is starting and can't find her seat again and starts yelling for her relatives to find them.
Rym: And they start yelling back at her and then she walks over and they sit down and they just start yelling and talking for more than a minute before I, because apparently no one else had the balls to say, yeah, I turn around, I'm like, shut up.
Rym: And they look at me and they keep talking for a second and I kind of give them the stink eye again and then they got quiet.
Rym: But then like 10 minutes later, one of them was quietly explaining the plot of star Wars to one of the old people.
Rym: But then the movie got loud and I could drown them out and there was a family in front of us to the right.
Rym: They brought a kid who was too young to even understand.
Rym: he was at a movie and he basically spent the movie running up and down in the aisle and like rolling around on the floor.
Scott: It was such a great experience in that, uh, in that expensive assigned city movie theater.
Rym: That shit happens almost every theater, but at least I was in a recliner.
Scott: I saw it in a regular plex in Connecticut and on Christmas day and there was only normal people there, you know, and it was just fine.
Rym: I think it was, it might've been the Christmas factor.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: It cost me eight bucks.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Actually I think we only paid like 20 bucks.
Scott: So I paid eight bucks times for three, four people, right?
Scott: Versus 20 times three, four people.
Scott: That is a week.
Scott: I was with popcorn.
Scott: I paid less than you pay.
Rym: Whoa, you got popcorn.
Scott: It was so cheap busting it out.
Scott: It was so cheap.
Rym: You got a free refill, but I don't have much of a news.
Rym: So I guess to continue this opening that, you know, Scott decided I had a news in the thing of the day and Scott was like, no star Wars only.
Scott: I had a star Wars news and star Wars thing of the day.
Scott: So Rym has to do the same thing.
Scott: So at least it's star Wars.
Scott: It is the single biggest nerd thing in the universe.
Scott: And you should be able to do a news and thing of the day for star Wars every single day of the week.
Scott: There is that much star Wars out there, especially because there's a star Wars only podcast somewhere and they could record every goddamn day if they wanted to from now until the rest of our lives.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, we're only going to talk about Star Wars occasionally, right?
Scott: We can definitely do a full Star Wars episode anytime we need.
Rym: We only did, we only talked about Star Wars once ever on GeekNights and that was in 2005.
Scott: It's the biggest, most important nerd thing.
Scott: there is 2005 episode called Star Wars.
Scott: I guess we're not talking about Star Wars enough.
Scott: Uh, yeah, especially because, uh, I mean, I'm sure we've talked about like tie fighter and shit too many times.
Rym: Moderately fresh in my memory is how fucking pumped I was when I heard episode one was going to happen.
Rym: And I've like pirated that soundtrack that spoiled Qui-Gon's death like way before the movie.
Scott: I was just pumped by the, uh, you know, the, the original trailer, which is at the time or perhaps still the most downloaded thing ever.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: Cause I, it took me a minute to even grok the fact that, wait, they're going to make another star Wars movie.
Rym: That's the kind of thing that I just assumed was never going to happen in my life.
Scott: I assumed it was going to happen once they made those special edition, but they made special edition when I was a kid.
Rym: And one of my Christmas gifts, I remember my brother and I both got a reference copy of the star Wars trilogy because that one, the VHS and everyone had that one.
Scott: That's the real one.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The only people who don't have that one are rich people at laser disc, which is the real, real one.
Rym: I still have that one.
Rym: Uh, so does everyone else, I don't think it's even been open because we watched other copies of star.
Rym: We had like five copies of Star Wars.
Scott: Get a good VCR just still work.
Rym: But I, the, the graph of how excited I was about episode one was just an upward and ever upward line until about 10 minutes into the movie.
Rym: And then we all know what happened.
Rym: So I approached this new star Wars with cautious optimism.
Rym: But before we talk about the new star Wars, it's time to talk about star Wars news.
Rym: You got a star Wars news.
Scott: Yeah, I do.
Scott: So, uh, there's fantasy flight games.
Scott: They're the people who publish net runner and they're not the greatest game publisher on earth.
Scott: Uh, honestly speaking, if you look at the history of games that they have published games that they have published that are made by other people that they're just publishing tend to be pretty good.
Scott: Like they published T and E now, right?
Scott: They didn't originally publish it in English, but they do it now.
Scott: Uh, they published net runner also a game that they didn't make originally.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But games that they have made them, they'll publish citadels.
Scott: That's another good one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But games that they publish that they make, you know, that people at fantasy flight have made entirely employees have designed, have not been the kind of games that I enjoy.
Scott: They're usually not so good.
Scott: And this company also has the rights to make star Wars board games in the United States of America.
Scott: So that includes the X-wing miniatures game, Armada, the role play, star Wars role playing games.
Scott: Uh, they have this Imperial assault, which is like descent, the board game, but star Wars or hero quest, the board game, but star Wars, right?
Scott: You move, you know, your jetties around and you'd stab stormtroopers.
Rym: I mean, that's a real mixed bag, but a lot of star Wars in right.
Scott: They make every star Wars tabletop game, uh, since they got the license and currently, right, they have exclusive rights.
Scott: No one else is allowed to make a star Wars tabletop game in the United States, except for them.
Scott: They have an exclusive license.
Scott: So they are making a game that is called star Wars rebellion.
Scott: Now this game all week, this week, we've known this game has been coming for a while, but, uh, and we've known that it's a big box.
Scott: It's going to cost like a hundred bucks and we've known sort of what it looks like, but we didn't know anything about the game itself until this week.
Scott: They're publishing every day.
Scott: This week they published an update on their site talking about really specific details about how the game plays out.
Scott: And it sounds like a real fantasy flight kind of game, which means it probably won't like it, but it it's like the only game ever that sort of.
Scott: lets you play one V one sort of like the entire empire versus rebellion conflict across the galaxy.
Rym: I feel like I'm going to enjoy it as much as I liked battle lore as in, uh, no, I think it'll be better than battle lore for sure.
Rym: Well, I did like, I enjoyed a lot of battle lore, but I also could not deal with a lot of battle lore.
Rym: So it's like a real strong, positive, real strong, negative balancing zero.
Scott: This is a game where like, this is a game where you can expect to do things like play mission cards that say like, you know, find the plans for the death star.
Scott: So then you send Leia to a planet to search for the plans and roll some dice to see if you succeed or fail.
Scott: And then, you know, you just keep the plan, have a death star, like a weird, this is a game where you'll have a superstar destroyer with a bunch of tie fighters and ATATs in it and you'll move it to another planet and then land things on the planet.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And then you'll have a ground combat and then you'll have a space combat and you could win the space combat and lose the ground combat, you know, and then what happens?
Scott: You mean you can't, I guess there's no bombing, at least they didn't say any rules about bombing or anything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's basically, and it's a game, it's an asymmetric game, right?
Scott: The empire is trying to find the rebel base and blow it up.
Scott: The rebels are trying to complete a bunch of missions.
Scott: If you get the death star into a system, you can roll dice and just blow it the fuck up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, but you know, the rebels can like get a really risky role, but if they succeed, they blow up the death star because that's star wars, right?
Scott: You know, so it's, it's one of those games where the, the theme really, really, really matches the mechanics, but perhaps the mechanics may or may not make a good game.
Scott: I'm hoping to play this at a convention before I spend any money or time on it.
Rym: Luckily, that's the kind of thing we can do.
Rym: We have so many packs is that probably like right after it comes out the next pack.
Scott: Because the good aspect of this game is that a, it's star wars, B it's got lots of little star wars miniatures in it, right?
Scott: Like star destroyers and shit.
Scott: But it's a two player game that is like a, you know, big crunchy enough competitive game, but isn't like some sprawling war game that takes you a hundred years, right?
Scott: You could probably play this again, someone in a reasonable number of hours.
Rym: The danger might be, it's one of those games that you might play a little bit and then it's played out, but it was real fun while you were playing.
Scott: But I mean, for example, if I was in high school, you know, rather than playing two player risk with my brother, this would have been like 10 million times better no matter how bad it is.
Rym: You know, sort of thing with gamers.
Rym: This is more Tuesday talk for GeekNights, but there is a place for those games that are not great from the perspective of people like us who have played every game in the world because we grew up with, you know, X's and allies was as good as we could get and that is not a good game.
Rym: So if the level, if this kind of game is the level that kids like us get before they find out about real big boy games, yeah, high school kids are able to get this and play one on one with their siblings or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or, you know, parents can get this and play one on one with their kids who are like early teens or teenagers, whatever.
Scott: That's this could be, you know, this is good stuff.
Scott: Star Wars.
Scott: So you can get more, get people to play it more easily with you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You bring out your Krusty War game.
Scott: You know, it's like your kids not going to play advanced quad leader.
Scott: It's not happening.
Rym: The danger of that is there's those games like the Ghostbusters Kickstarter game.
Rym: that would turn kids off to both games and Ghostbusters forever.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: But I mean, you know, Imperial Assault is still better than Hero Quest.
Rym: So that gem movie didn't open very well, as you guys know.
Scott: You don't say.
Rym: I mean, I talked a lot about how poorly that movie opened, but it did so much worse.
Scott: They're making a gem.
Scott: comic book I heard is good.
Rym: Apparently it's great.
Scott: Better than that movie.
Rym: So, so this is relevant to Star Wars.
Rym: So Star Wars global, the release of Star Wars gross like 1.8 billion worldwide.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And that doesn't count merch.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: How much do you think the gem movie grossed in the international release?
Rym: Like after the U S release?
Rym: zero, not zero, a thousand, $142,000.
Scott: That's still more money than I have in previews.
Rym: in the U S it averaged $36 per theater, $36 per theater.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So star Wars had one, like the third or fourth biggest opening in cinematic history, the new star Wars episode seven.
Rym: And likely as a result of that success, because it was around Christmas, they have pushed episode eight from a summer blockbuster release to go out at about the same time as episode seven did around Christmas.
Scott: I was actually surprised.
Scott: I had assumed right without knowing that episode eight was going to be out of holidays, Christmas time, 2016.
Scott: And then someone told me, no, no, no, it's going to be like spring, summer, 2017.
Scott: And I'm like, why would they do that?
Scott: Why wouldn't you just make it always holidays?
Scott: That makes no sense to me.
Rym: And apparently they took a big risk.
Scott: But 2017 it's like, I guess they're taking time on it.
Scott: I guess, you know, I thought they'd be like editing and polishing at this point.
Rym: So the rumor mill at first like, Oh, there must be delays in production.
Rym: But then the more reliable rumor mill basically said, no, they just think the holidays is actually like a really good place to put star Wars going forward.
Scott: I thought that's what it was going to be.
Scott: So it's like it wasn't even delayed for me because I assumed it was delayed by exactly one year for me.
Rym: You know what this is?
Rym: This is an example of the cost of knowledge.
Rym: People who had more knowledge than us because they paid that much more attention just got real disappointed.
Scott: But I don't give a crap.
Scott: What's my hurry?
Scott: I would be disappointed if you're going to live to see it or you're not.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So what if when I'm like 89 years old, they announced like the culture movie trilogy and movie three is going to come out three years from now.
Rym: I don't know if I'm going to make it three years.
Scott: Well, you know, they're always doing stuff like showing a Pixar movies to kids who have like cancer and aren't going to make it.
Rym: I guess that's my only hope.
Scott: Your only hope.
Rym: So someone pointed out that this puts it right before Avatar two, to which I responded Avatar to the blue one with the blue people, the blue people are making a second blue.
Rym: I didn't know that was happening.
Rym: I still don't actually.
Scott: I didn't know that was happening.
Scott: And you know what I found?
Scott: I don't know if I might have mentioned this in the show before.
Scott: I found out recently that like my one of my newer co-workers, he said that like he was a huge fan of that movie.
Scott: I didn't realize anyone was a huge fan of that movie.
Rym: The thing is blockbuster fantasy sci-fi action movies.
Rym: A lot of people end up being really huge fans of those things.
Rym: But those are.
Rym: that's not the demographic that gets normal merchandising.
Rym: That's the demographic that buys special editions and goes to see the sequels.
Rym: They're super fans, but they're not buying like action figures.
Scott: I didn't think that movie was sequel worthy anyway.
Scott: Well, I mean, most things aren't, but they get sequels and trequels.
Rym: Robocop was sequel worthy.
Rym: And yet we know what happened to that.
Scott: Oh, you know, Frank Miller.
Scott: He's a guy.
Rym: Yeah, that's a person.
Rym: Last night.
Scott: That's human being.
Rym: Last night, I just found the trailer to Robocop three.
Rym: And then we watched the opening 10 minutes of Robocop two.
Scott: Oh, no, no, no.
Scott: Why do you have time in your life?
Scott: Why are you spending it on that?
Rym: This sort of came up.
Rym: In the evening.
Scott: OK, you could have spent your time on many other things.
Rym: So it's like the bluebird in over the over the garden wall.
Rym: I'm a bluebird.
Rym: We have short lifespans.
Rym: You are literally killing me right now.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: We're all the bluebird.
Rym: Scott, as a total aside, we watch that.
Scott: Why are you listening to this GeekNights?
Scott: Seriously, bluebirds?
Scott: All you bluebirds listening out there.
Scott: What does that?
Rym: we watch that show?
Rym: It's on Hulu.
Rym: It's only 10 episodes.
Scott: I've seen like four of them.
Rym: Watch the rest of it.
Rym: It's crazy.
Scott: I've seen the end and I've seen like the middle of the end.
Scott: I saw because I saw random episodes that I remember.
Scott: I didn't know what it was.
Scott: There's Connecticut where I saw someone cosplaying or the red pointy hat.
Scott: And I was like, what the fuck is that?
Scott: And they said the no.
Rym: And you're like, no, no.
Scott: Then they said, no, it's over the garden wall.
Scott: It's some cartoon thing.
Scott: I'm like, OK.
Scott: And then I watched like one episode and I was like, all right.
Scott: And then I was home in Connecticut at some point.
Scott: My sister was there and it was like any on demand.
Scott: There was like some random episodes.
Scott: So I watched like one where they were at the old ladies creepy house and then one where the end where there was like the football team and shit.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: OK, so.
Rym: So, you know, in the show, the football stuff that is never shown to you until the very end.
Scott: Yeah, I gathered that.
Scott: I'm not a moron.
Scott: Yeah, I could tell.
Rym: It's making sure.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So anyway, if you watch the show all the way through because it's short, it's basically like a movie.
Rym: But, uh, the bluebird is Scott, the girl bluebird.
Rym: Like that is you, the bluebird speaks the truth and is correct.
Rym: And yes, yeah, bluebird, bluebird, bluebird go.
Scott: I saw a bunch of bluebird stuff.
Scott: There's a lot when the bluebird trying to get her back to her nest and shit.
Scott: And she was like, oh, whatever.
Rym: But anyway, that was in Star Wars.
Rym: So things of the day, this might have been used at some point way in the past, but I don't think you've all seen it.
Rym: And I watched it again just now.
Rym: And it's way funny.
Scott: Rym thinks this is funnier than I do.
Scott: I mean, it's not bad, but it's like I'm not so laughing at this.
Rym: I'm still laughing at this.
Rym: Just thinking about it is funny to me because this is my, this is one of the kinds of humor that I really enjoy.
Rym: But the moment that does it for me is how they edited.
Rym: They reversed Luke's face, like moving a little bit to make it look like you reacted to something in a certain way.
Rym: And that sells it to me.
Rym: Darth Vader feels the blues.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: My thing of the day is this, I just saw this today.
Scott: is this guy who was quite talented at the singing and the guitar in, and he does an acoustic cover of one of the best songs in all of star wars.
Scott: You have nub.
Rym: Oh, who did you hate this song?
Scott: You have no soul.
Rym: Oh, so, so Scott, I have someone actually the first YouTube comment here on my thing.
Rym: Someone had an idea.
Rym: I never thought of, they, they claim they did this.
Rym: I don't know if they actually did, you know, YouTube tell your family, Hey, let's marathon star wars, edit the last file.
Rym: So that scene is this instead of what actually happens in that part of star wars.
Scott: Good luck with that.
Rym: That is a long time.
Scott: It's going to be problem because the, uh, that video file there on YouTube has a wrong aspect ratio.
Rym: You could fix that.
Scott: I'm just saying you're going to have to zoom in.
Scott: The resolution will be bad.
Rym: And you know, yeah, I think the resolution is going to be from a laser disc or VHS.
Rym: Anyway, maybe, well, you're going to watch the new ones.
Rym: No, I got my, uh, I got my, um, that one, uh, bit torrent that everyone got the, uh, the one that's the highest possible quality, the de-specialized it's the highest possible quality you can get of star wars from the available source.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: The real one.
Scott: Don't watch any other one in the meta moment.
Rym: Uh, we're going to be at PAX South, like next weekend.
Scott: Whoa, escape the snow.
Scott: If we're a week too late to escape the snow last year, we escaped in the snow and then out to Arizona this weekend.
Scott: And then you're gonna go straight from Arizona to tejas.
Rym: I'm going to, I'm going to come back here.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: And then go to take what a bad move that I'm going from tejas straight to new Hampshire instead of going home.
Scott: That's a bad move.
Rym: So packs Atari game design Saturday, 1130 scared yet a discussion of horror games moderated by Chris Straub of chainsaw suit and a bunch of other super smart people.
Rym: And then for some reason I'm on the panel Saturday, five 30.
Rym: Sunday, one PM designing game rules.
Rym: And then Sunday at a two Oh one PM I am running to the airport and flying in New Hampshire.
Scott: I'll be chilling in tejas.
Scott: I think until maybe the next day, let me check my, you're leaving in the morning and remember I'm leaving the next day.
Rym: This was, this is kind of an aside, but in the meta moment, I think I've booked more travel in hotels and car rentals.
Scott: Which day is February 1st?
Rym: I don't even know.
Rym: I think it's a Monday.
Scott: That's when I'm leaving.
Rym: I think you're leaving on the Monday.
Rym: Yeah, you're leaving on the Monday.
Scott: All right, good.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So I'll be chilling in tejas.
Rym: I'm going to fly.
Rym: I'm going to land in Boston at like 11 because there just aren't direct flights to or from anywhere in Texas.
Rym: that matters.
Scott: Oh, that's right.
Scott: I'm leaving it like from leaving Friday at like six in the morning.
Scott: That was nice.
Rym: Oh, that's the worst.
Scott: No, it's the best.
Scott: It means like it's in New York.
Scott: Like, I mean, Monday at six in the morning, I'll get, be able to actually spend my day in New York going.
Rym: Ah, it means you got to get up at like four in the morning though.
Scott: I did that last time.
Scott: It was actually pretty good.
Rym: Yeah, actually you mean Emily usually do that after pecs prime.
Rym: So what if, anyway, star Wars, uh, obviously, you know, we're going to just spoil it because you're a nerd.
Scott: You're a nerd and you're so nerdy.
Scott: You listen to the Ignite and you haven't seen, and there's a new star Wars movie.
Scott: The most important nerdy event that can possibly happen in the world of geeks.
Scott: And you still haven't seen it at this point.
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: Meanwhile, I didn't actually see it until last weekend.
Rym: And yet somehow I avoided any spoilers or anything.
Rym: And I didn't like sequester myself away from the internet, but guys, spoilers.
Rym: Uh, I knew Han Solo was going to die immediately because this movie had a lot of, shall we say cinematic homage to episode four, I don't think, I think it was beyond homage to the point at which it was the same movie, like 75%.
Rym: It was the same movie structurally, but it had enough deviation to where.
Rym: I was very pleased with the result.
Rym: It's kind of like you knew where the journey was going, but the journey itself was fun because you didn't know what rest stops.
Rym: you hit along the way.
Scott: And pleased is a strong word.
Rym: I liked it a lot.
Scott: Uh, it was okay.
Rym: I put it like a hair below the original trilogy in terms of quality.
Rym: It's like episode five, episode four, episode six.
Rym: This is right behind episode six.
Scott: And it is infinitely ahead of episodes one, two, and three, which, uh, I mean, it's way ahead of episodes one, two, and three, but there's still a gap that, you know, quite a significant gap between four or five.
Rym: So what did you not like?
Scott: I think the main problem with this movie, right?
Scott: Is the same problem that I have with a lot of like TV shows that everyone seems to really like, but specifically is that, you know, the events that occur in this movie don't seem to have weight, right?
Rym: That is a complaint.
Scott: I will see when an entire star system gets destroyed by star killer in star Wars episode four, which is the same exact movie, right?
Scott: They're approaching the death star and it's like, that's no moon.
Scott: And you're like, oh shit, son.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In this movie, it's like, oh, by the way, this is giant star killer.
Scott: Oh, by the way, there's the foot, right?
Scott: It's like, you can fucking move shit.
Scott: Holy crap.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like the, the events like matter.
Scott: It's like, you know, at the very beginning of the movie, right?
Scott: It's like the, what happens at the beginning of any star Wars movie, a giant spaceship comes overhead, right?
Scott: So every single one, even episodes one, two, and three did a better job of this than episode seven.
Rym: Watch those again.
Scott: in the beginning, when the spaceship comes across, it comes from like the bottom and it's not that big.
Scott: And it's like, what?
Scott: And then, you know, episode four is like Darth Vader comes onto the ship and the camera moves from his feet up and it's like, oh, who is this motherfucker though?
Rym: Right.
Rym: That at least for that aspect, the fact that Kylo Ren doesn't really have that weight really fits what he is because he's just a Darth Vader weeaboo.
Rym: That's exactly what he is, which makes him a great villain.
Rym: But it means that he is like Darth Vader's skull had more screen presence than him, which was great.
Rym: Well, sealed that character for me.
Scott: I mean, yeah, it's sealed the character as shitty.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: I don't like you.
Scott: I don't want to see you.
Rym: I like the character.
Scott: I don't like him as a character.
Scott: I think it's like it's an obvious, you know, it's like, yeah, OK, there's I can see what they're going for there.
Scott: It's the same thing that everyone else sees that they're going for.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Is it Darth Vader weeaboo?
Scott: He's got, you know, parent problems and he's got, you know, his most anger issues.
Scott: and it's like, yeah, OK, I don't like him.
Scott: I want to be fucking Darth Vader.
Scott: I want Kylo Ren to die in a fire and I wouldn't shed a single tear.
Scott: I'd probably dance a happy dance like Jar Jar Binks died.
Rym: Yeah, people want to be Darth Vader.
Rym: You are Kylo Ren.
Scott: I'd rather be the emperor.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Emperor is way better.
Rym: Yeah, but he goes down like a chump.
Scott: It's fine.
Scott: That's the other thing, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, in Star Wars, it's like you have all this this mystery.
Scott: And it's like there's a fucking emperor here.
Scott: It's like, oh, there's some dude.
Scott: We know nothing about him and he's not cool.
Rym: So I have a crazy like thinking about, you know, the Voldemort, like it's the hologram of that guy.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I don't think this is true.
Rym: But a younger me would be like, oh, I know what's going on.
Rym: If this is what's true, then these this trilogy is going to be amazing.
Rym: But I don't think it is.
Rym: The commander guy, the Grand Moff Tarkin replacement, who actually is competent.
Scott: Yeah, that's actually not a bad character.
Scott: I like that guy.
Rym: What if it's a Wizard of Oz and that guy is the Sith Lord and the hologram is just him fucking controlling everybody?
Scott: That would be fucking awesome.
Rym: Because it could it could work.
Rym: Nothing is said.
Rym: That is not what is happening.
Rym: And the fact that it's a hologram actually lends credence to it.
Rym: I don't think that's what they're going to do, because that's kind of crazy.
Rym: But at the same time, holy crap, if it is because I like that character a lot.
Rym: And Grand Moff Tarkin is actually one of my favorite characters in all of Star Wars, partly because the acting.
Rym: I mean, that guy.
Scott: I mean, the thing that, you know, one of the number one things that makes Star Wars so awesome is that the Emperor, despite being bad guys, that must lose is so bad ass.
Scott: Right in this Star Wars episodes, even in Star Wars episodes one, two and three.
Scott: The Empire was well, not one so much, but at least two and three.
Scott: The Empire was still bad ass.
Scott: Well, the Empire seven in episode seven.
Scott: They are chintzy garbage in episode seven.
Rym: It is clear that the Senate and the resistance are both chumps.
Rym: They both suck.
Rym: And guess what?
Rym: They both got basically destroyed immediately.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And the Empire is also chumps.
Scott: There's no because Darth Vader is gone and the Empire is gone.
Scott: There is no bad asses left.
Scott: You know, like Poe is the only bad ass left in the galaxy.
Scott: There is no one else.
Rym: Yeah, we even lost Han Solo.
Rym: So it's just it's Poe.
Scott: I know Chewbacca is still there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And R2D2 is still there.
Scott: I was real worried.
Scott: R2D2 is sleeping the whole time.
Scott: But he's still all right.
Rym: I both expected and assumed that Chewie was going to go kamikaze after Han bit it.
Rym: And I was real happy that he was like, nope, I'm just going to.
Rym: I'm going to get my revenge later.
Scott: So we only got four bad asses left.
Scott: Right.
Scott: By my account, you got Leia, R2, Poe and Rey.
Rym: Rey is going to be a bad ass.
Scott: Yeah, but she doesn't.
Scott: I mean, she has bad ass skills.
Scott: The only scene that had the weight you're talking about is when she picked up the lightsaber and had a vision.
Scott: Yeah, that's the only one.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: And it's you sort of implied that her reaction was partly because of, you know, she sensed the thing that Obi-Wan sensed.
Scott: Well, you heard the voice of Obi-Wan and Yoda while she was having that vision.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But maybe you can point out that in the old world, only Ben noticed that she like the old only had weight because Ben noticed it and it had weight because Leia watched it.
Rym: But here, no one knew it happened except her because she's the successor to the Jedi.
Rym: She's the only one who knew that the weight of that event didn't actually come crashing down on screen for anyone.
Rym: So it makes sense, even though stylistically you miss that, like, base drop of the moment, it hit a different way.
Rym: Yeah, I think where I want to go with the rest of this, I mean, could use a little more space combat, right?
Rym: Yeah, but the space combat was real satisfying because it looked good as opposed to an episode one where it looked like shit.
Rym: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: Like, is it the space fights in the like?
Scott: I like to me.
Scott: he was escaping the, you know, the Star Destroyer, the TIE fighter was stuck on the thing.
Rym: Yeah, I like how we got a lot more sort of like technical stuff, like because they had, you know, modern technology to do the effects, you got a lot more like real zoomed in technical stuff going on on those ships and the fights.
Rym: Porkins made his cinematic cameo, which I was very pleased with.
Scott: You got Captain Phasma, who is basically Boba Fett 2.0.
Scott: Yeah, you know, don't appear a lot.
Scott: Don't say a lot.
Rym: But pointedly, pointedly not dead.
Rym: Obviously not dead because, yeah, throw her in the trash compactor.
Rym: That was funny, but that means off screen death.
Rym: Boba Fett didn't die off screen until you see him dead.
Rym: He's not dead.
Scott: He fell in the Sarla.
Rym: Yeah, Phasma is coming back and it's going to be great.
Scott: Yeah, obviously, but that's the Boba Fett character.
Scott: But Boba Fett wasn't in episode four.
Scott: So that's part of your twenty five percent.
Scott: Not the same as episode four.
Rym: Was there a Boba Fett in?
Rym: No, I guess there was no.
Scott: Boba Fett appeared for the first time.
Rym: And I said, oh, Boba Fett, as in the faceless background character that everyone gets obsessed with.
Scott: Greedo.
Scott: Yeah, not Boba Fett.
Rym: I was very happy that J.J.
Rym: Abrams let that scene happen where Han Solo fucking murders those people.
Rym: I feel like that was just a middle finger to George Lucas, like, no, he shot first.
Rym: He shoots first every time.
Rym: That's all he does is shoot first.
Rym: You know, where the two factions are both like, hey, you owe us money, and then he murders them all the end.
Scott: Oh, with the monsters come out and shit?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, that was sort of like, I don't know, it's it felt like a formulaic modern movie kind of scene there.
Scott: I didn't really care too much.
Rym: I mean, similar stuff went down to a lesser scale when he was in the cantina dealing with all the people he owes money to.
Rym: And they turn that into a villain here.
Rym: They kind of just killed all those people off because then they killed Bonoff.
Rym: So it didn't matter.
Rym: It's just I feel.
Rym: I wonder if I wonder if Star Wars.
Scott: Yeah, it's watchable.
Scott: It's enjoyable, but it's not like I'm going to watch it ten thousand times the rest of my life, like real Star Wars.
Rym: I will watch it several more times.
Scott: I mean, I could watch it another time to see things I didn't see the first time, but I don't see myself like if it's on, I will watch it.
Scott: I will intentionally turn it on on purpose, no matter how old I am, a thousand times.
Rym: I think that, but I haven't it hasn't been tested yet because the original trilogy was tested by the fact that I was a kid who'd be sitting at home like fucking around on my computer and I turn on the TV and be flipping through cables and I come into like the middle of episode five and I'd always stop.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So the test will be if we're hanging out and someone puts on Star Wars, the new one, and everyone just sits there and watches it, not saying a word.
Rym: or if someone says, let's do something else.
Scott: I'll say let's do something else pretty quickly.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: But I guess what's important is that the the new movie gave me faith that the rest of the trilogy is probably going to be as good, if not better than it.
Scott: Yeah, it'll be serviceable.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, I say that I expect episode eight to be a remake of episode five.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I wonder if.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, the only difference is that they've already taken the beginning of episode five and put it episode eight and put it into episode seven because the beginning of Empire Strikes Back, right after the battle on Hoth, Luke goes to Dagobah.
Scott: Well, she already just went to Dagobah or the equivalent thereof to see Luke, who is now Yoda.
Rym: So Scott pointed out something, you know, would be the best possible way for episode eight to open a battle in the snow.
Rym: Luke pulls his cloak back to talk or whatever.
Scott: It's all a robot man.
Rym: No, he's the one who has C3PO's arm.
Scott: Why would he have C3PO's arm?
Rym: C3PO's arm is missing.
Scott: Yeah, it's true, but Luke already has a robot hand.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: What if you replace it with C3PO's and that just happens because what I was getting at is I doubt that the and this might sound dumb.
Rym: The main reason I have faith that J.J.
Rym: Abrams and the people making new Star Wars at least understand what Luke is fucked up in the, you know, the second trilogy and what made the first trilogy great is C3PO's red arm because it's so it's so C3PO comes out and he obviously has this really like weird.
Scott: They intentionally throughout this movie left a lot of things open as to what happened between Return of the Jedi and this movie so that they can fill them in with their sea of content that they are going to produce, especially since they threw all the cannon away.
Scott: They can do whatever the fuck they want now.
Rym: As long as they do not fill those gaps in the next two movies, because that's what George Lucas would do.
Scott: Well, there's also side movies, right, like Rogue One and such that are being made that could fill in a lot of those things, which this is Mad Max.
Rym: Fury Road did the same thing.
Rym: Fury Road is a masterpiece.
Rym: It was the best movie of 2015, but there is a video game that did and a comic that together give you a ton of really awesome back story.
Rym: But the fact that all that shit was not in the movie is one of the things that made the movie great.
Rym: Putting that crap in the movies would ruin them in this context.
Rym: So as long as they never explain why C3PO has a red arm, that means that they get it.
Rym: If at any point in episode eight you find out in the movie why C3PO has a red arm, I will not trust episode nine.
Scott: You're going to see I guarantee you're going to find out why.
Rym: I think you find out in a comic, or in a show, or in a tweet.
Scott: You're going to find out probably in a movie, because they're making a lot of movies.
Scott: And if you do find out in a book, comic, tweet,
Scott: etc.,
Scott: I don't think it'll be a tweet, right?
Scott: It will also be shown in movie as well, right?
Scott: They double up on a lot of these things, right?
Scott: For example, there's that guy who gets killed by Calleren in the village early in the movie.
Scott: And it's like he's some important rebel guy, but you don't know who he is.
Scott: But if you read the book, they tell you his name, and they give you some small...
Rym: Ah, but that's a big part of Star Wars, because everyone knew what a TIE fighter was, right?
Rym: No one says the words "TIE fighter" until episode six, at any point.
Rym: And yet, everyone knew they were called TIE fighters.
Scott: Do you know why?
Rym: No, I don't know the specific reason why.
Scott: The first way... As far as I know, I could be wrong, some Star Wars nerds would smack me on this.
Rym: Second-hand knowledge, but I don't actually know.
Rym: And this is one topic where our listener will fucking jump on us if we're wrong about anything.
Scott: Sure, jump on me, because I could be wrong.
Scott: The first way that I am aware that a human being not involved in the production of Star Wars could know that a TIE fighter was called a TIE fighter was if they went to the store to buy a toy that was a TIE fighter.
Scott: And it says "TIE fighter" on the package.
Rym: That's how I know.
Rym: I learned a lot about X-Wings and TIE fighters because of some promotional books that were made that were like, "Hey, here's the technical diagrams of
Rym: Y-Wings!".
Scott: Yes, there were lots of things like that.
Scott: But I think a lot of those things, like novels and such, came out after... I think the toy was the first thing that you could get.
Rym: But there is a history...
Scott: The same thing with names of a lot of characters, because they had toys.
Scott: Like, how did you know that that droid was our... Whatever, it's not R2-D2.
Scott: How do you know what kind of droid that is?
Scott: Because they sold a toy, and on the package, it said the name of the droid.
Rym: That's why every kid knew what an R... Like, they knew about R2 and R5 and all the different droids and all that nonsense.
Scott: The toy packages, as far as I know, were the first place any of that was printed.
Rym: Thus, there is a strong tradition in Star Wars, it is very true to the original trilogy, to have a bunch of that stuff explained in side media, but not in the movies.
Scott: Well, they threw all their side media in the garbage so they can redo all of it.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: And true to that form, I'm going to ignore most of that side media.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: You don't need to know.
Rym: Because the parts that matter, like names of things...
Scott: Well, this also means that the good side media was thrown in the garbage also, like TIE fighter.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And Admiral Thrawn, who, if they had used him, could have saved this movie.
Rym: So, Scott, there's two competing movies...
Scott: I don't know how to use the word
Scott: "saved."
Scott: I want to say "made a thousand times
Scott: better.".
Rym: I mean, Star Wars is not... So, Star Wars...
Scott: It wasn't so bad that it needed saving.
Rym: This movie saved the Star Wars franchise because the bad taste... The bad taste in my mouth from the episodes one, two, and three was so bad that until I saw this movie, cautious optimism was as high as my height meter could go.
Rym: Like, I could not go in with anything other than "please, please don't be
Rym: bad.".
Scott: Yeah, mine was pretty much "please don't suck, don't
Scott: suck.".
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And it is possible... The argument seems to be about 50/50 on the internet of people who are arguing about this.
Rym: between either episode eight is going to be a mirror of episode five...
Scott: Yeah, probably.
Rym: Or episode four and episode seven were mirrors just to reboot the franchise safely and to give that due homage and to set up the same beginning story, but the next one is free now because it succeeded to go batshit.
Rym: It could be Admiral Thrawn nonsense for all we know.
Scott: Hope so.
Rym: Yeah, I hope... You know, Admiral Thrawn... A lot of you kids care about Boba Fett.
Scott: We had the, you know, the generic general guy who you said is secretly the Wizard of Oz, right?
Scott: But imagine if he was Thrawn instead.
Scott: You could have just done that.
Scott: Just make him blue and make him smarter, more dangerous, more scary, right?
Scott: That's the thing.
Scott: is it wasn't scary, right?
Rym: That guy was scarier than Kylo Ren.
Scott: Of course, but old Star Wars, all of them, even when there's Ewoks, had scary shit and there was no scary shit in episode seven or one, two, and three.
Scott: That's really the key ingredient.
Scott: that the original trilogy was missing and this movie is still missing is scary shit, right?
Scott: The Empire is scary and badass.
Scott: Everything is black and evil and clean and a machine of death.
Scott: And here, even though they have a weapon more powerful than the Death Star, it ain't scary.
Scott: It's like you blow up the Senate like, "Eh,
Scott: whatever.".
Scott: Was that Senate on Coruscant, by the way?
Scott: Did they just blow up Coruscant and not even give a fuck?
Scott: Or is that Senate meeting somewhere else that wasn't Coruscant?
Rym: That, I don't know.
Rym: All we know is that now who's in charge?
Rym: I guess Leia is now in charge of everything because everyone else is dead.
Scott: I'm just saying, you know, the Empire is in charge, right?
Rym: I'm actually real happy that Carrie Fisher is going to be in the rest of these movies, even though we lost Han because a lot of people have been talking about her autobiography, which I think I'm going to read now.
Rym: She is a stone cold killer.
Scott: You didn't know that?
Scott: No, but to the extent- I mean, you've seen the Blues Brothers, right?
Rym: The extent to which she is a badass was elucidated for me in a few choice anecdotes about her not taking shit from George Lucas.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I didn't read her biography or anything or autobiography or whatever, but, you know, she was on Broadway at one point and when that book came out, I remember reading, you know, meta about it on the internet.
Scott: So I pretty much know all the- I knew even way before all the bits that were to be known, including those Lucas type stories.
Scott: So it was just, you know, when she started going on the media circuit, I was like, "Whoa, look, she's doing
Scott: stuff.".
Rym: But when I was a kid, like, you know, obsessed with Star Wars, like you were, and when I got TIE Fighter, you know, I got that game, and I played it, and that voice comes in, "Signal Vice Admiral Thrawn to launch his TIE Squadrons
Rym: immediately.".
Rym: That's right.
Rym: Cuts to the blue guy, and I was like, "Who is
Rym: that?".
Scott: And then I went on the- Yeah, there was nobody in Star Wars Episode 7 where I said, "Who's that there, the most
Scott: amazing?".
Rym: And then I went on the, you know, the proto-internet of the time, and I looked up "Thrawn" and I found out who that was, and I was obsessed with that motherfucker.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: I even read his books, and they weren't the greatest.
Scott: They're supposed to be the best Star Wars novels, and I've said this maybe before, but if those are the best Star Wars novels, I'm not reading any others.
Scott: But that doesn't make the character any less the best.
Rym: Imagine if the end of Episode 8 is, you know, the first order or whatever sucks, and they're kind of failing, and Thrawn shows up with that fleet that was sent to the outer Rym, and he's like, "What's going on
Rym: here?".
Scott: Oh my God, that would be- What have you been doing?
Scott: He just kills Carol Loren, the end.
Scott: He's like, "Now you have to deal with the square
Scott: boss.".
Scott: And I was like, "Thank God,
Scott: yes.".
Rym: I did like the moment.
Scott: And then they win, and they don't just- I hope they don't just win in Episode 8.
Scott: I hope the bad guys win Episode 9, too.
Scott: Kill all, yeah, just boom.
Rym: It becomes, yeah, so Scott, you wanna go crazy?
Rym: Yeah, Grand Admiral Thrawn and Leia get married, and then they rule the galaxy forever.
Scott: They don't need to get married, just kill everybody, and then Emperor wins, the end.
Scott: Thrawn is Emperor, the end.
Scott: We need to wait for another rebellion to come along.
Scott: That's a shame.
Rym: I kind of want Poe and Finn to get together.
Rym: So does the whole internet.
Rym: Yeah, no, half the internet wants Finn and Rey to get together, which I don't see.
Scott: Which half of the internet is that?
Rym: It's out there.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: But someone made a good gif where they pointed out- They weren't trading jackets.
Rym: Yeah, so when Poe sees him in the jacket, watch closely, right before he says it looks good on you, he bites his lip like,
Rym: "Mmm.".
Rym: He's checking it out.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: Either that was ad-libbed, Han Solo, Harrison Ford style, or that's canon.
Scott: It's canon.
Rym: This isn't- The plasma canon.
Scott: This isn't some shipping action, right?
Scott: This is real ship, like an X-wing.
Scott: It's a real ship.
Scott: It goes to other galaxies.
Rym: There was a moment, actually, so I was obsessed with the Tydarian shuttle, because that was another one of those things.
Rym: you see.
Scott: I love me.
Scott: a Tydarian shuttle.
Rym: What's going on with that thing, because Luke has the toy, and then you see it, and you're like, "Oh, man, what's that
Rym: thing?".
Rym: The transport that came down the few times they used one that had the two wings, that's the new Tydarian shuttle.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't need the top wing.
Scott: It's going in space.
Rym: So I feel like the- I'm going to watch the movie again the next time I watch it.
Rym: I want to actually pay attention to notes to really make sure I see every one of the- Not the plot point homage to episode four, but the cinematic homage.
Rym: There are a lot of scenes that are obviously just saying, like when Rey is climbing around inside, Ben climbing around inside.
Rym: There's all those little scenes.
Rym: I want to make sure I didn't miss any, because some of them were real subtle.
Rym: Some were not subtle.
Scott: I spotted so many.
Scott: I feel like if I missed any, I wouldn't be able to know if I missed them, or if I was just seeing them again.
Rym: Yeah, there's a few.
Rym: I, you know, at some point- And not remembering that I remembered them from the last time.
Rym: Cracked, or someone like that, you know, is going to put up a YouTube video of like, here's the 800 specific references.
Rym: We did the research for you.
Rym: Just watch this video.
Scott: Yeah, here we put side by side.
Scott: Here's Obi-Wan crawling on the side of the Death Star, and here's Rey crawling in the inside of the thing, and there's the exact same camera angle, and, you know.
Scott: Turning off the thing, you know.
Scott: Turning it back on with some Stormtroopers walkman.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Even the room with the trash compactor had like the same layout of like controls as the one in the Death Star, right?
Rym: So, overall, I mean, I don't know what we can- I mean, we're assuming you saw the movie.
Rym: You have your opinion on it.
Rym: Listen, it's not- Your opinion's not going to change because of us.
Scott: It's not the best movie ever, but it ain't bad.
Scott: Why, if you're a nerd, why aren't you watching this?
Rym: The thing is, coming out of the movie, like, halfway through the movie, like, you know when you start a movie, like, once you get like fully immersed in it, you kind of like completely zone out the theater?
Rym: I had that Star Wars feel that I have not had in a long time, and that counts for a lot.
Scott: I didn't have much of a Star Wars feel, but if it wasn't Star Wars, if this is just like some other generic sci-fi that, you know, is the same plot just without, you know, you change all the X-wings into some other ship you made up, et cetera, et cetera, right?
Scott: I don't think anyone would give any shits.
Rym: Thing is, I think half the audience for this movie never really saw or paid attention to other Star Wars movies.
Rym: A lot of people, this is their first Star Wars.
Scott: Right, but if this was like, you know, Gennaro Space Adventure that's not licensed in any way as a new property.
Rym: I'd probably be into it, because I'm fucking into Gennaro Space Adventure.
Rym: I mean Guardians of the Galaxy was great, and that could have been a Star Wars movie, but for like four scenes.
Rym: Yeah, I'm into Star Wars, I'm into space biz.
Rym: Now, what's interesting to me is, talk about J.J.
Rym: Abrams, because the Star Trek reboots, in my opinion, are garbage.
Scott: Well, I mean, I can think all Star Trek is garbage.
Rym: No, I like old Star Trek, but every one of these Star Trek reboots, they're not really even touching on the speculative fiction aspect, and they're just space nonsense and character drop.
Scott: But I mean, that's what Star Trek is.
Rym: Now, what Star Trek have you seen?
Scott: Quite a bit, more than I wish I had seen.
Scott: Have you seen any D-Space 9 or TNG?
Scott: Yeah, I've seen many episodes of both of those.
Rym: Any character other than Picard from either of them?
Scott: Okay, so in the next generation, you've got Data the android guy, you've got the beard guy, you've got Wil Wheaton.
Rym: Alright, we're already falling off to beard.
Rym: guy and name of the actor.
Scott: Reading rainbow guy.
Scott: And in D-Space 9, you've got short guy with big ears who serves at the bar.
Scott: Oh, isn't there like this guy with lumpy forehead in both of them?
Rym: Yes, a Klingon.
Rym: There are Klingons.
Scott: See?
Scott: I know stuff.
Rym: Alright, alright.
Rym: But I guess the new Star Trek movies are not very true to much of the legacy of Star Trek, and J.J.
Rym: Abrams is sort of using it for this like character-driven drama action movies, and the trailers are very action-y.
Rym: Star Wars, at least, J.J.
Rym: Abrams is all about worshipping the source material, and at least understands- Yeah, by redoing it.
Scott: It couldn't really work.
Rym: He understands what people liked in Star Wars and is doing proper homage to it, and in Star Trek, it's just- Well, he doesn't understand that I liked evil, badass Empire guys, and he's giving me lame pansy ones.
Rym: I think he did.
Rym: I think like, so I've read, there was a, I don't know how true this is, but I read an article pointing out that apparently the toy marketing people assumed that Kylo Ren was going to be the biggest selling toy because Darth Vader was, and they didn't realize that Kylo Ren is
Scott: literally
Rym: the opposite of Darth Vader.
Rym: You're supposed to hate him because he sucks.
Rym: I did love the scene where it's the Darth Vader whatever, and then she's like, blah, blah, blah, wearing a mask, and he's like, and he takes his mask off, and you expect it to be some, and it's just- A lame-o?
Rym: It's just lame-o emo guy who you expect his face to be covered in pimples.
Scott: See, you know what could have saved it there also?
Scott: Yeah?
Scott: Is if they could have, instead of making it, you don't have to make it evil like Darth Vader, right?
Scott: And you don't have to make him a pansy, right?
Scott: You have to do something that I don't think Americans would understand and make him sexy, right?
Rym: If he had a char asnival face- Scott, I got some real bad news for you.
Scott: If that was a char asnival face under there, it would have been like, oh my God.
Rym: That, so I got some real bad news.
Rym: I agree with you, but I got some real bad news for you.
Rym: Half the internet thinks he is super hot.
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: Partly because he's also evil and brooding.
Rym: I think there's a part of the internet, a big part that likes brooding more than any other character trait.
Scott: I mean, is this just like goth kids or what?
Rym: I don't even know.
Scott: I mean, who thinks that that's hot?
Rym: I don't want to go into that community too much to find out.
Scott: I mean, Darth Vader's mangled face is hotter than that.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Well, he's got harmonica skills, so.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Uh, if that's hot, man, I don't want to know what else you're going to do.
Rym: Yeah, if he had been like char hot.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I basically assume that phasma is char hot.
Rym: Uh, phasma is going to be the boat.
Rym: Like phasma is Boba Fett 1.5 times over a thing.
Scott: I mean, uh, you know, prequel trilogy Boba Fett was kind of hot.
Rym: The only question is there's three ways for phasma to go eventually fight for the good guys, but for the wrong reasons, not for the right reasons.
Rym: She's not going to be a good guy.
Scott: Boba Fett.
Scott: I'm telling you.
Rym: Yeah, but is it Boba Fett that helps Finn or power someone for bad reasons?
Rym: Is it just bad guy?
Scott: Who does things for her own reasons?
Rym: Which might be great.
Rym: I don't think Kylo Ren is going to be redeemed though.
Rym: I think that just, I think that's going to be a, uh, Saruman falling off of his tower to the death in episode nine or maybe episode eight.
Scott: Yeah, he's definitely a little Saruman going on there.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: Saruman that was way cooler than Kylo.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Except watch, you know, watch those movies again and watch the actor for Saruman is like 10,000 times better.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: For the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website@frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion, news, and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution.
Scott: 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the patrons for this episode in order of the amount of money they give us on a continuing basis are Nicholas Brandau, Rebecca Dunn, Amanda Duchette, James David White, Christian Koontz, Jess, Sam.
Rym: I budget for this Cordri mechanical mind, William Eisenroves.
Rym: You expected the next name to be yours, but it was me.
Rym: Dio Clinton Walton.
Rym: My Stady.com.
Rym: Phil Ulrich Renee from New Zealand.
Rym: Robert Lee.
Rym: Ryan Perrin.
Rym: Drew Openlander.
Rym: Rare Lavelle.
Rym: Brian Sidroni.
Rym: Rochelle Montanona.
Rym: Finn Eric Silveraude.
Rym: And then he placed a single finger upon his mustache.
Rym: Kinetic Man.
Rym: Aaron Cerise.
Rym: Chris Knox.
Rym: Shut Up Scott and Take My Money.
Rym: Daniel Redman.
Rym: Chris Haddad.
Rym: Doug Schneider.
Rym: Sean Klein.
Rym: Chris Reimer.
Rym: And Thomas Hahn.
Rym: You may have noticed a slowdown of episodes and a trickle of Rims Ranch recently, and we're also a little behind on doing the December Q&A.
Rym: That's partly because a lot of travel and just after the holidays, and we actually still have a lot of work to do for PAX South where we're doing three panels.
Rym: So there's going to be a whole bunch of videos and stuff in a hurry, basically about three weeks after PAX, and GeekNights will also resume in full force around that time.
Rym: But we're going to do the Q&A a little bit different because I kind of got late to start on actually putting up the forum.
Rym: So this is going to be a Q&A, but the direction I have for you is ask us for advice.
Rym: The question should all be you asking for our direct advice on something, whatever it might be.
Rym: I'm sure you'll get wonderful answers from Scott on this.
Rym: And now I leave you with something pretty weird, but it's actually by the same guy who made something else pretty weird that I used another time.
Media: [Singing] The snow glows white on the mountain tonight, not a footprint to be seen.
Media: A kingdom of isolation, and it looks like I'm the queen.
Media: The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside.
Media: Couldn't keep it in, even knows I've tried.
Media: Don't let them in, don't let them see.
Media: Be the good goof you always have to be.
Media: Conceal, don't feel, don't let them go.
Media: Well now they know.
Media: Let it go, let it go.
Media: Can't hold it back anymore.
Media: Turn away and slam the door.
Rym: I don't care what they're going to say.
Media: Let the storm rage on.
Media: The cold never bothered me anyway.