Rym: It's Wednesday, November 16th, 2016.
Scott: -Are you sure it's Wednesday?
Scott: -Huh?
Scott: -Uh, yeah.
Scott: -I just mess with you.
Rym: -It's 100% Wednesday.
Scott: [laughter] I know it's Wednesday, I'm just trying to hang in.
Rym: And tonight, we're talking about Squirrel Girl, the unbeatable.
Scott: -Squirrel Girl.
Rym: -Squirrel Girl.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: You know, I probably complain about this about twice a year, maybe once a year at the most.
Rym: But daylight saving time, kind of bullshit.
Rym: And it's dark out.
Scott: If I ever have a company, when the clock moves, I'm just going to move the work hours.
Scott: Everyone 8 to 4 now, because you'll leave, you know.
Rym: I feel like the weight around this is we should just go back, like two hours, and stay there forever.
Rym: I want to get up in the dark, and I don't want it to be light until like 11 o'clock in the summer.
Scott: You can just go back to using sundials.
Rym: Yeah, because then every hour is a different length of time.
Rym: That's not good.
Rym: Time matters.
Rym: Got to keep track of time.
Rym: Mustn't waste time.
Scott: I was cherishing.
Scott: But that would be awesome, because there would be a time of the year where like lunch is way long.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think it would work out that way.
Scott: It would be totally cool.
Scott: We got to hook up sundials to our computers so that they can tell time.
Rym: Cloud comes in, everything's fucked.
Rym: Why are you late to the meeting?
Rym: It was cloudy.
Rym: So I got any news, it being anime day, because I've been not watching a lot of anime.
Rym: I was watching Mob Psycho.
Scott: It's not anime season right now.
Rym: It was.
Rym: I was watching a bunch of stuff, but I haven't watched enough to review anything, really.
Scott: I think I watched, did I watch all of that Mob Psycho?
Rym: I didn't finish it, but I watched a bunch of it.
Scott: I think I did watch the whole thing, actually.
Rym: Yeah, but I got distracted, and I started watching other stuff instead.
Scott: You know, whatever.
Rym: Westworld is way good.
Scott: Yeah, Yul Brynner's the man.
Rym: Yeah, no, the new Westworld.
Scott: Fuck that noise.
Rym: Scott, Scott, Scott.
Rym: So you got any news?
Scott: Yeah, well there's a non-news, right, which is that Miyazaki's coming out of retirement, he's going to make another movie, but we said that when he retired for the fifth time.
Scott: So it's not a news, it's an old news.
Rym: You know what he actually announced?
Rym: I'm going to make another movie and hope I die during it so that I can die during my last movie's production.
Rym: I feel like that is his only goal at this point.
Scott: Someone beat you to that, but they weren't trying.
Rym: Yup, and that movie didn't get made.
Scott: So fuck that news.
Scott: Is it real news?
Scott: Is that the trailer for... That was my news!
Scott: Sorry, deal with it.
Rym: So yeah, your name is coming out, and there's the trailer.
Scott: That's not my trailer.
Rym: Oh, what's your trailer?
Scott: Well, you just keep going.
Rym: Alright, so the trailer for Makoto Shinkai's Kimi no Na Wa, which I haven't seen, but is based on numbers in his best movie.
Rym: So I clicked on this trailer, and look, it's a girl, I assume, might be a guy.
Scott: Nice clouds to get there.
Rym: Looking up at a cloudy sky with a bunch of colorful shit going on.
Scott: Sounds good.
Rym: Yeah, so I mean, I guess it's coming out.
Rym: I guess the news is actually...
Scott: We had Crazy Box Office in Japan and Crazy Box Office in other countries.
Scott: It's coming to the US, so...
Rym: Yeah, there's a dub cast, which I literally do not care about.
Scott: I don't think it's going to be the movie that suddenly has a top tier AAA box office number for an anime in the US, but people are going to go see this, including you.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm going to go see it at an ice theater in New York, probably with the subtitlies and not with this dub cast, which everyone's actually talking about the dub cast, and one, it's like the people you'd expect, and two, literally, why would you care who the dub cast is?
Scott: Because you're not watching the dub.
Rym: Yeah, the dubs are all the same in America.
Rym: Either it's a Disney dub or it's a non-Disney dub.
Rym: Those are your options.
Scott: It's even funnier nowadays.
Scott: I was scrolling through Anime News Network, and it was like dub cast announced for the anime with the big guy, My Love Story.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it was a good show.
Scott: It's like, I already watched that whole show on Crunchyroll with subtitles, months and months, possibly a year ago.
Scott: A long time ago, I watched the whole show, and now you're dubbing it?
Scott: It's like, why?
Rym: Well, I mean, there are reasons to dub things for mass market because there's a wide chunk of America is really afraid of subtitles.
Scott: Anyone who's interested in something that obscure has already seen it.
Rym: But you only dub it if you're putting it on legit TV, and you're trying to make normal people watch it.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: Meanwhile, for whatever reason, going through my Twittersphere and also coming up on my news feeds, apparently there's an interview with the dub cast of the Sailor Moon R movie, which is the one we didn't watch and review.
Scott: It's not the Candy Sky one?
Rym: Candy Sky one is the Super S movie, Space Snow Demon, and also it's mostly about Luna is the S movie, and R movie is the-- Luna the Cat?
Rym: Yeah, Luna the Cat is, that's actually the best Sailor Moon movie.
Scott: I should check that out.
Rym: We should watch and do a show on it.
Rym: It's short, and it's actually pretty good.
Scott: Does it stand alone?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All you need to know is, do you know that Sailor Moon exists?
Scott: She punishes people.
Rym: You know that Luna is her cat, and that Luna is kind of also a human form, alien, whatever, but that never comes up in the show.
Scott: Yes, I know all those things.
Rym: You know everything you need to know.
Rym: Sailor Scouts do fuck all in that movie.
Scott: I'm just saying.
Rym: Also, it's a Christmas movie, kind of.
Rym: So I feel like we should do it as our Christmas show.
Rym: And the R movie, which is the one that I guess, it's about a gay plant that comes from space and tries to kidnap Tuxedo Mask.
Scott: That sounds like a One Piece movie.
Rym: It actually is a lot like that One Piece movie with the plant that kills everybody.
Scott: All right, so that was your news.
Rym: So what trailer are you talking about?
Rym: I assume this is the trailer you were talking about.
Scott: The crappy live action Ghost in the Shell trailer.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I guess that's right.
Rym: Well, I clicked on this trailer, and all it did was put even more colors and clouds up.
Scott: Anyway, so it was whitewashed, as promised, and it's Ghost in the Shell, as promised, and it's visually good-looking, but everything that I can gather from the trailer.
Rym: One origin story.
Rym: The least interesting part of Ghost in the Shell.
Scott: Whoever wrote this did not try to adapt Ghost in the Shell.
Scott: All they did was take the characters and visuals and setting and made, at least, this is what I can gather from the trailer, but trailers these days, you can usually gather the whole movie from them.
Scott: They're done that way on purpose.
Scott: They basically took a generic action movie plot of someone with a mysterious past having to fight bad guys and just slapped it onto Ghost in the Shell characters and setting without actually bringing along the real Ghost in the Shell plot.
Rym: Now, granted, it's all fighting cyber crime.
Scott: Ghost in the Shell is tricky, because depending on-- Which is the only part of Ghost in the Shell that mattered.
Scott: It took the parts that didn't matter, and they got rid of the part that did.
Rym: I mean, the good parts of Ghost in the Shell barely involve the source material.
Rym: It's just you want stand-alone complex, you want stand-alone complex second gig, and you want the two movies.
Scott: Right, the best Ghost in the Shells are the ones where it's like-- The manga's all goon-y, and then it gets sexy.
Scott: It's like procedural cyber crime.
Scott: It's about the bad guy.
Scott: How do we catch this bad guy?
Scott: What are they up to?
Scott: Oh, they're brain-dubbing, or they're, you know, they're terrorists doing-- You know, it's always about the bad guy.
Rym: Or you want, like, Botto be at all philosophical, and like, "Oh, what does it mean for me to
Rym: live?".
Scott: Or, like, you know, they're hacking into policemen's eyeballs.
Scott: It's like, it's always about that, and then they happen-- Section 9 happens to be these people who just are really good at fighting crime, and they find the bad guy, stop them, learn from them.
Scott: Moral of the story.
Scott: That's what Ghost in the Shell is supposed to be.
Scott: This movie is gonna be about Section 9, and no one wants that garbage, right?
Rym: Well, you do, but you want it the way Stand Alone Complex did it in second gig.
Rym: Remember, they had those flashbacks like, "How did this guy join the
Rym: team?".
Rym: And they're like, "Well, here's an interesting segment from how this guy joined the
Rym: team.".
Scott: Yeah, that's two seconds long.
Rym: They each got an episode.
Rym: Barely.
Rym: It was a whole episode.
Rym: Remember the one where-- The sniper episode where you get that awesome sniper stand-off?
Rym: Yeah, but all you actually learn about-- Oh, they did something with the
Rym: U.N.?
Rym: ?
Rym: Something, something?
Rym: Okay, we're back in the present.
Scott: Right.
Scott: All you learn about it, you don't learn his past and his deep inner feelings.
Scott: All you learn is like, "Oh, yeah, he joined the team because they were in a sniper battle, and he was so good that the Major was like, 'Hey, join
Scott: me.'".
Scott: That's all you learn.
Rym: To push forward the ideas and the setting, and when there's serious long-term origin story-esque plot, it's like the stuff with the Major and Kuzi, which is mostly hinted at, as opposed to this movie, which looks like it's literally, "Oh, yeah, remember that Kuzi guy?
Rym: Let's just follow that plot, and she's a superhero.
Rym: She's basically
Rym: Spider-Man.".
Scott: I think the only positive thing is that Aramakis looks to be played by Takeshi Kitano.
Rym: Yes, that fits.
Scott: They did one good thing.
Scott: Congratulations.
Rym: All I want-- I don't even like Arise that much.
Rym: All I want is more Ushi movies, which he'll never do, or more stand-alone complex, which is literally at this point my favorite non-evangelian anime ever made.
Rym: That's all I want out of anime is more stand-alone complex.
Scott: Well, maybe if this movie's a way hit, then I'll make some more animes.
Rym: You need the people who are making the new Westworld to make a live-action procedural Ghost in the Shell stand-alone complex.
Scott: Well, maybe they'll make a TV show after the movie's--.
Rym: Yeah, depends.
Scott: That's why I think you don't whitewash the TV show, also.
Rym: Someone pointed out that in one of the trailers, only white people talk and only Asian people get shot.
Scott: Yeah, probably.
Scott: I believe it.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: When you think of a kaleidoscope, what do you think of?
Scott: A kaleidoscope?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: That's when you look inside and you spin it and you see,
Scott: "Whoa!".
Rym: Yeah, you see,
Rym: "Whoa!".
Rym: When do you think those were invented?
Scott: When were they invented?
Scott: Probably-- Well, I guess they needed optics, right?
Scott: So, after Galileo times.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But probably before the-- You know, earliest-- What action in Civ VI boosts the development of kaleidoscopes?
Scott: Probably something related to boats, because that's where they're making spy glasses and shit.
Rym: So, 1816.
Scott: That seems about it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But-- They had boats.
Rym: What do you think they were invented for?
Rym: What was their purpose?
Scott: They had a purpose?
Rym: Yeah, so-- Other than entertainment value?
Rym: Basically, kaleidoscopes were seen as this philosophical and scientific tool, and then the plebs were like, "Ooh,
Rym: pretty!".
Rym: And all the scientists and thinkers of the day thought that people were obsessed with kaleidoscopes, and they were a weird and surprisingly powerful pop culture phenomenon.
Rym: And this is an article going into the details of the kaleidoscomaniacs of the 1800s.
Scott: So, it was the "Tickle Me Elmo" of its day?
Rym: It was more like the iPhone of its day.
Rym: Like, thinkers would bitch about how young people don't pay attention to the real world anymore.
Scott: Or like, "Yeah, you got last year's kaleidoscope.
Scott: I got that
Scott: too.".
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: "I got that since this year's model is
Scott: better.".
Rym: In 1819, New Monthly magazine listed the kaleidoscope as the most important invention and discovery of our times.
Scott: Are you sure that this isn't fake and this is real?
Rym: No, so I was looking-- I read a lot more about this.
Rym: It's a pretty in-depth article.
Rym: Check Snopes on this.
Scott: This could be fake.
Rym: Basically-- oh, you want to talk about kaleidoscope piracy?
Rym: No, this is pretty legit.
Rym: I've read some primary sources on this, but basically-- I'm just saying "could be
Rym: fake.".
Scott: I didn't say "is
Scott: fake.".
Rym: I was not 100% convinced when I first encountered this article.
Rym: It's been sitting in my queue of things of the day for a long time.
Rym: But the history of the kaleidoscope is way weirder than you thought it was.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: So there's this quickdraw.withgoogle.com.
Scott: It's been around, but I guess not everyone's seen it.
Scott: So I cheated on it with my magic pencil.
Scott: And basically, it's an AI learning thing plus Google.
Scott: So you push "Let's
Scott: draw."
Scott: And then it says, "Hey, draw
Scott: something.".
Rym: And then you draw what, a dick?
Scott: It tells you what to draw.
Scott: So it's telling me to draw a mouse.
Scott: So I'm going to try to draw a mouse.
Rym: Draw a stereo.
Rym: All right, I'm going to do it right now.
Scott: And then it uses machine learning to try to figure out, you know, like what?
Scott: if you've, you know.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I'm drawing a stereo.
Rym: Oh, what?
Rym: You figured it out.
Scott: You have a time limit to draw, to basically convince the machine learning thing that you've drawn what it wants you to draw.
Scott: So it'll be like, you know, draw a mouse and you've got 20 seconds.
Rym: I got my cactus.
Scott: You can draw for 20 seconds until the, you know, AI recognize it as a cactus.
Scott: Duck?
Rym: I can't draw a duck for shit.
Rym: It's actually really hard.
Rym: I can't draw.
Rym: That's a duck.
Rym: I think that's a pretty good duck.
Scott: I'm just saying.
Scott: So this is, that's what this is.
Rym: It didn't think I drew a duck.
Rym: The fuck?
Scott: That's a duck.
Scott: It's pretty.
Rym: I see an aircraft, Harrier helicopter bird.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: That's pretty good.
Scott: It's pretty interesting.
Rym: I could, I could spend some time messing around with that.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: In the moment.
Rym: The book club book is Rebecca.
Scott: Once, once it's holidays, I'll be able to read a book.
Rym: So you didn't start reading yet?
Rym: That's good because I was going to read it.
Scott: I did start reading it and then I stopped and I haven't picked it up again.
Scott: Instead I read it because I'm doing other stuff.
Rym: I read the entire second book of the mad Adam trilogy after Oryx and Craig.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It's real good.
Rym: Like, I think the second and second book might be better than Oryx and Craig.
Rym: It just, it basically, it looks at other parts of the world during the same time period as the events of the book, the first book.
Rym: So it's like some people in the plea blends with the cheeky knobs and all that biz, and you learn about how the gardeners were set up.
Rym: It was pretty good.
Rym: I was digging it.
Rym: So I guess I can finish the third book before you start reading Rebecca.
Scott: I did start reading Rebecca, so you can't.
Rym: Uh, otherwise check out both our youtube channels cause we're doing stuff and now that it's the holidays and we're kind of home and quiet, a lot more stuff's going to be coming in.
Scott: I'm not home and quiet until after Thanksgiving.
Rym: What do you mean home?
Rym: What are we doing?
Rym: We have nothing.
Rym: Our next convention, our next convention is magfest, which I guess I got to write that fucking panel on quitting stuff like every goddamn day I got.
Scott: no, I can't even clean my apartment.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I'm catching up on stuff.
Rym: I've been working on a lot of things.
Rym: I got to think about cutting certain other things that are big responsibilities out of my life, which might affect a lot of people.
Rym: We'll see how that goes.
Rym: That sounds ominous to some of you and it should, but don't worry.
Rym: It doesn't affect GeekNights or any of the stuff you're looking at here.
Rym: Uh, I guess PAX South submissions closed for panels like just now because they extended the deadlines a bunch of times.
Rym: So if you submitted a panel back south, I guess maybe there's a better chance you'll get one than usual.
Scott: Cause they're desperate.
Rym: Uh, worries me a little.
Rym: Could be submitted three.
Rym: Let's see if they give us three.
Rym: That'd be like the old PAX East where we do three or four every year to be worth it considering it's a trip.
Scott: Right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, I already booked my flights.
Rym: Like I'm all set.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I booked everything.
Rym: And I'm not doing that weird thing.
Rym: I did last year where I ran from the panel to fly to New Hampshire to go skiing because the people who run that trip are like, turns out they're white supremacists.
Rym: So bailed on them and not going on that trip ever again.
Scott: Otherwise.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Follow our stuff.
Scott: I mean, if you go skiing, skiing is a really super white people thing.
Rym: You know, I have this anecdote from a long time ago where I was at Hunter mountain.
Rym: It's unlikely you're going to see, cause I have a basically in finance, you get Martin Luther King day off, which I learned when I became an adult, cause I grew up in Detroit where also you got Martin Luther King day off.
Rym: that and a lot of the South, you don't get Martin Luther King day off.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: So I tended to always go skiing and MLK day and it's always a great day cause like it's a holiday, but a lot of people don't actually have that day off, which is kind of fucked up.
Rym: But that's an aside.
Rym: And I just remember there's this dude who works on a mountain and he's just this cool dude and he is a black dude just happens to be.
Rym: And one year I came in and he's standing there and he's like greeting everyone to come in.
Rym: He's like celebrate the blackest day in history with the whitest sport on earth.
Rym: And he was just being really funny.
Rym: That is my anecdote, but yeah, we're not going on that trip anymore.
Scott: So squirrel girl, you actually read every page and every word of every page and every word of both of those started with the big book that has like the bad one.
Rym: Well, I wouldn't say bad, but it was a sampling of the history of this character throughout comics.
Scott: It's not a sampling.
Scott: That's pretty much is the history.
Rym: My thoughts on the origin of squirrel girl is that that was some ugly, ugly and like even for the day.
Rym: that was some ugly shit like Dr.
Rym: Doom, fine.
Rym: That Durfee old Iron Man, Iron Man, sure.
Rym: But the fuck if I was Iron Man, I might've killed her cause I was afraid of her.
Rym: I think she's some sort of demon.
Scott: Well, she's also like 14 years old technically at that point.
Rym: But what did that I make up?
Rym: Like who thought that was a thing?
Scott: So right.
Scott: So when I was a kid and I read superhero comics a ton, right, this was.
Scott: there was sort of this thing where it was like a tradition almost of, you know, you would make non serious parody comics like self parody, right?
Scott: There would be like Spider Ham or, uh, you know, the characters that were just complete nonsense.
Scott: Like there was a character called slapstick who was literally like a living cartoon or something.
Rym: So was Howard the duck on purpose or was he really part of that?
Scott: I'd ever read that.
Scott: So I don't know.
Rym: I did.
Rym: You ever see the movie?
Scott: Uh, yeah.
Scott: Super long time ago.
Rym: We should watch it again as adults and review it.
Scott: No.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But you know, so there'd be all these characters that like weren't like canon characters, right?
Scott: Even characters like Spiderman would have serious times and silly times.
Scott: You could buy a silly Spiderman comic and a serious one.
Rym: Like when I was a kid in like the eighties and nineties, there were the what if comics are like, what if they're all became zombies?
Scott: Right.
Scott: And some things are Canon and some things warrant, but there were certain characters where the entirety of the character was a joke in and of itself.
Scott: So squirrel girl actually was not that kind of character originally.
Scott: You saw the original appearance.
Scott: She was just like this side character, horrible demon, right?
Scott: The side character in one issue of iron man or something, right?
Scott: Just randomly.
Scott: She shows up and that's where pretty much all superhero, you know, side characters come from that sort of thing, right?
Scott: It used to be back in the day, there were only so many comics on the, you know, and the, not even on the shelf in the bookstore, it'd be the drug store, right?
Scott: You could get Spiderman, Superman, Fantastic Four, you know, there's only so many, it wasn't like today where there's 50 something titles.
Scott: So all those other characters started out as side characters in these other things.
Scott: Like the, in humans, there wasn't an in humans comic, it's just, you would read Fantastic Four and there'd be in humans all over the place, right?
Scott: That's where they came from.
Scott: So and nowadays, since it's been going on for so long, they keep running out of material.
Scott: They are constantly digging through old books to get, you know, new or old, you know, characters is like, oh, this character already exists.
Scott: It's already IP that we own.
Scott: I don't need to bother designing a new character.
Scott: I can just bring this old one back and the bed.
Rym: They're not in that many comics.
Scott: So if you're worried about your continuity, there's not that you can sort of do what you want with them, but you have something to work with.
Scott: And it also, you know, makes fanboys excited because, oh my God, I remember that, you know?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I mean, you know, you say that, but when you saw Boba Fett again, you were like, oh shit, that guy.
Rym: Oh, oh man.
Rym: Boba Fett.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: I mean, that's how it goes.
Rym: Boba Fett.
Scott: Anyway, so Squirrel Girl was in this like one Iron Man throwaway comic a super long time ago.
Rym: But she beat the shit out of Dr.
Rym: Doom.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was, it was just a silly comic.
Scott: And then what happened was, I guess in the nineties or eighties, nineties, right.
Rym: That second one.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So like that felt like if I, if I was going to make a comic that was like a parody of what nineties comics were like, that thing was like spot on.
Scott: So in the nineties, they would, they, the Avengers got split up into two different comic books.
Scott: There was the East Coast Avengers and the West Coast Avengers, like the East Coast Avengers was like Captain America, such and such in the West Coast, I think was Iron Man, such and such.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And so as a joke, they were like, lol, Great Lakes Avengers.
Scott: Oh my gosh.
Scott: You know, joke.
Scott: And it was all these silly characters like Deadpool was involved, which already means it's going to be stupid.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So Squirrel Girl was sort of like a really, you know, important character on the Great Lakes Avengers.
Rym: Well, because she was pretty much other than the immortal guy, the most powerful and competent one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because basically it was, you know, that's, that's the joke of Squirrel Girl.
Rym: Even though, what's that guy's name is the immortal guy.
Rym: I already lost track.
Rym: All their names.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Cause it's all dumb.
Scott: I don't remember anyone's name.
Rym: Cause he's friends with death urge.
Rym: I guess.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Who I kept confusing with the doorman cause they look the same.
Scott: So anyway, the joke of Squirrel Girl is that she's a girl with the power to talk to squirrels basically.
Rym: But she also has the proportional speed and strength of squirrels.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And she's basically Aquaman of squirrels.
Scott: Only a girl.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And that's usually a really stupid power.
Scott: What could you possibly do with that?
Scott: That's so great, but she's actually not like, you know, usually when someone has a stupid power, these stupid characters, they're, they're also dumb themselves, right?
Scott: Like there's a Spider-Man villain who's like the frog or something, I think frog.
Scott: And he's just like frog man or some shit.
Scott: He's just a dumb ass wearing a frog suit.
Scott: It's like a joke, but squirrel girl, isn't a joke.
Scott: Only her power is a joke, right?
Scott: She's like totally smart and knows how to, you know, fight stuff.
Rym: And it seems like the going theme with her is that she's the unbeatable squirrel girl because the situation she is up in are just like, man, the only thing that would save the day here is this oddly specific power.
Rym: Hey, squirrel girl.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Whoa.
Scott: So what happened was, is there squirrel girl was, you know, sort of made into, you know, brought back as a character in the nineties, two thousands, great lakes, Avengers kind of thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then even then it was still just a joke kind of thing for superhero nerds.
Scott: It wasn't anything anyone cared about.
Rym: I mean, that nineties squirrel girl stuff was very, I'm pretty sure it was nineties.
Rym: I did not check, but it was just so like, like it had all these self referential callback jokes to the superhero fandom that like Deadpool with his car.
Scott: That's what it was about.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was just a, you know, jokes for, it was, you know, inside jokes for inside superhero.
Rym: But it was also that like, we're going to be like edgy and hardcore, like comics tried to be for a while then.
Scott: Anyway, I only made Rym read that garbage so he could suffer through it.
Rym: But I, you know, maybe it's just because I have not consumed that like grim dark, like toilet joke nineties era comics in a long time, but I kind of enjoyed it even though like at one time I'm looking at it like this artifact from a bygone era.
Rym: And on the other hand, I'm sort of appreciating that it existed in its time and place.
Scott: There's plenty more where that came from because you could do nothing but read that shit for like the rest of your life.
Rym: I mean, you want like 80 pages of suicide jokes.
Rym: Well there you go.
Scott: There it was.
Scott: So anyway, uh, what happened more recently is they brought back squirrel girl in her own comic book and it's good.
Scott: And the writer is Ryan North, the dinosaur comics guy, right?
Scott: So you already know it's going to be good.
Scott: And of course it is good.
Scott: It's way good.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: And he totally stands alone.
Scott: You don't need to know any superhero shit.
Scott: And it's not just for superhero nerds, even though it still has the basic structure of a superhero comic where every issue you have to fight a bad guy somehow.
Rym: And it's interesting because the like nineties, middle era of squirrel girl would make these fairy comic book guy references to the old bullshit or they would do homage that you could not understand unless you'd read those old like weird golden age, silver age comics where you'd see like that character keeps explaining what he's doing while he does it.
Rym: And that's the joke.
Rym: But the new squirrel girl will still reference the old crap, but in a funny offhanded way that is not in Trent, like it's not.
Rym: like it's not funny if you haven't read that old stuff.
Rym: It's just like an Easter egg.
Scott: It's weird.
Scott: Like despite the, you know, who knows what's canon and what's not right.
Scott: But despite this being a brand new squirrel girl, that's not nothing like the old one at all.
Rym: It pointedly is like, yeah, she beat iron man and dr doom and all that business, right?
Scott: She acts like all those things totally happened.
Scott: And she's got Deadpool's trading cards to tell her about all the bad guys cause right.
Scott: Cause all that Deadpool stuff actually happened and you know, and all this stuff.
Scott: So, and also I want the Deadpool trading cards to tell you about all the villains.
Scott: Those are way better than the superhero cards I collected when I collected those X-Men ones and there were multiple series of them.
Scott: I got that.
Rym: I had a lot of, I also have a complete set of the second Wolverine series, including a bunch of the foils.
Scott: I got a, I got a bunch of cards in my closet.
Scott: I could dig them out.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Let's dig them out and I don't know, burn them or sell them or, but anyway, so the deal with the new squirrel girl, right?
Scott: Is that she's going to college.
Scott: So I guess when she was 14 when she met iron man, she's college age now.
Scott: that's, you can use that to measure all other time passing in the Marvel universe.
Scott: Good luck with that.
Rym: How do you even know she ages like a human.
Rym: squirrels live like 30 years.
Rym: So if she has the, oh shit, she's in trouble.
Rym: But if she has the proportional squirrel shit, then she's probably gonna live like 900 years or less.
Rym: No, because she's, cause squirrels are small and strong for their size.
Rym: She's bigger, but proportionally stronger.
Rym: So she's probably gonna live a really long time or, or a lot less time.
Rym: I think she's gonna live a really long time.
Rym: Anyway, isn't even a picture of frog man on the, I don't know if it's called fraud.
Scott: I don't know if his name is actually frog man.
Scott: search for like spider alter ego, Eugene Paul, but search for like spider man, frog villain or something and see what comes up.
Rym: Spider man, frog man.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: That's him.
Scott: That's the guy.
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: I never realized venture brothers making fun of this guy.
Rym: There's this dude who comes into to audition to join a super villain squad and he stands there in a frog suit that looks almost exactly like this and he throws a brick and he's like brick frog and they're like, nope.
Scott: Anyway, uh, so squirrel girls now in her twenties or something.
Scott: and she decides because she's so awesome.
Scott: She's going to go to college, which is difficult for someone who doesn't have parents, at least no parents that we know of doesn't have money that I don't know where she gets money from.
Scott: Uh, I, did she even go to school?
Scott: I guess she's intelligent.
Scott: Maybe she got a scholarship or I don't know, but she's going to college and she is going to stop living in the Avengers attic and I don't know.
Scott: And so they're off.
Rym: She goes, I like how tippy toes is all like you're not majoring in squirrels and she's like, ah, I already know everything about squirrels.
Scott: Except then she didn't sure, but I guess she's going to study computer science, which is cool except they never show any computer science stuff that she's learning because she's too distracted actually doing superhero crap.
Scott: I wish that she would, they would show some computer science action though.
Scott: Cool.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like what, you know, just saying that you're studying computer science is nice.
Scott: Actually doing computer science and showing it in the book would be nicer.
Rym: She should have tied his tongue in a whatever, not instead of a whatever, not sure.
Rym: I can't quote Simpsons verbatim like I used to.
Scott: Uh, and you know, there's a little bit of school drama going on, right?
Scott: There's like some cute boy and there's an awesome roommate.
Rym: The characters are all just pretty good.
Scott: Like if you didn't know, it's a lot like the old Spiderman comics where like there would be the high school drama to go with the Spiderman drama.
Rym: Like, you know, flash Thompson, was that who it is, but you know, and like Gwen and whatever and all, but like this comic would sit right alongside all those quote unquote indie comics that you just get it like the mocha fast and you wouldn't even blink.
Scott: Like if you didn't know this, it didn't happen to have all these Marvel heroes and villains in it.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But even then the way they are portrayed and presented and used is still like pretty secondary.
Rym: Like it's still like, it's just, it's set up like a modern comic and not like that old nonsense.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And all the dialogue and such is sort of adventure timey, right?
Scott: Where they're being, they're being serious, but they're not, you know, talking like normal people.
Scott: They're talking in a slightly silly way, but still saying real things, you know?
Rym: Yeah, I can see that.
Scott: Like like, whereas in adventure time we'll be like, man, it should be like nuts.
Rym: I don't know if I like the, like put a weird sentence at the bottom of every panel.
Rym: So it feels like a web comic when you do that.
Rym: That is the text.
Scott: The dude is a webcomic author.
Rym: In the hover over on a webcomic.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So I guess he's used to doing that.
Scott: And the thing is, it would be totally cool, but some of them aren't funny.
Scott: They just don't really add and let you know, it's like, it's like a cool Easter egg.
Scott: The fact that it's there.
Scott: So I in the meta sense, but the actual content of the words written down there usually don't add to what you just read.
Scott: And actually the kind of distracting cause like you're usually, I can read a comic book really fast.
Scott: Just going through the bubbles and the pictures.
Rym: Ah, young Padawan learned for the master.
Rym: I read the comic first and I went back and read all those stupid things separately.
Rym: And then I read all the non comic, the letter pages.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So it's like they're doing everything that old comics did.
Scott: You know, a lot of comics have letter pages even nowadays, but they don't put the letter pages in trades.
Scott: They usually only put the letter page in the floppy issues.
Rym: No.
Rym: As a kid, I hated the letter pages.
Rym: The letter page was, ah, the comic ended.
Rym: I only got like four pages of comic and I got this ad and a letter page.
Rym: Great.
Scott: Letter pages are good, positive and negative points.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you know, some of the letter page stuff in here is good and some of it's not so good.
Scott: You know, it's when they can do.
Scott: a funny answer is when it's good and I feel like they're printing too many of the letters.
Scott: I feel like they should print less of them.
Rym: Or just a hundred percent fake them.
Rym: I don't know if they're fake.
Rym: Are they real?
Scott: Uh, I mean, as far as I can tell, they're, they're, they're probably real, right?
Scott: I don't know if they, they've always been real throughout history, but letter pages are definitely mostly, if not completely real.
Scott: Uh, so anyway, so yeah, it's a, what else is there to say about it?
Rym: I mean, I liked it.
Scott: It's hot.
Scott: If you want to read a superhero comic, that's also quite humorous, but has a modern sensibility.
Rym: I guess if you've never read the weird old nineties, like kind of gross quote unquote edgy comics or read them, you can read the score girl trade because I was moderately entertained by it.
Rym: No, the thing is what it really struggled to finish.
Scott: It just, it felt like a chore.
Rym: Just what it really put into stark contrast.
Rym: Get it?
Rym: Stark Tony Stark is how unfunny Deadpool is except in the smallest of doses.
Rym: So Deadpool is pretty great if you get like one to three pages of Deadpool inside of something else, but just Deadpool, how could you?
Scott: So here's the thing, right?
Scott: It's like Deadpool himself is not funny or unfunny, right?
Scott: Is that when you have superhero comics, there's so many different writers out there and even though it's the same nominally still Deadpool, the Deadpool in the first Deadpool comic and the Deadpool in a different Deadpool comic written by someone else are basically completely different characters, right?
Scott: They have nothing to do with each other.
Scott: So if you read like, you know, the very first Deadpool, it's like he's actually way serious and not a joke.
Scott: And if you read a Deadpool written by like Dan Slott, who's really hilarious.
Scott: I don't know if he's ever written any Deadpools, but he's like way hilarious.
Scott: It would probably be way hilarious.
Scott: Like if you read, there's a comic from the early two thousands, like Cable and Deadpool, that comic is way funny.
Scott: At least it was way funny for a high school college brain of me.
Rym: Well, cause there was a weird mystique around cable when I was in like middle school.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's called Scott brain.
Scott: I don't know if it's still funny, but I've read a lot of Deadpool comics that are just crappy toilet humor and aren't funny at all and has nothing to do with the character himself.
Scott: It has to do with the author, right?
Scott: It's the same with anything.
Scott: Right?
Rym: If you read some, you know, even like look at my little pony, like look at who wrote each episode and you got a good sense how that episode is going to go, right?
Scott: So the squirrel girl that's written by Ryan North is the top tier squirrel girl.
Scott: And you know, if it's written by someone else, yep.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution, 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night and the Patreon patrons in order of the mountain.
Rym: When they give us on a continuing basis are Alan Joyce, Rebecca, dumb, Nicholas, Brando, Heidi McNichol, Amanda, Duchette, construction noises, Ivy, Faye, my state of the account, William, I suppose, Jeremy, a minor Chris Reimer and Thomas on Christian Coons, Han Thomas and Reimer, Chris, Sherman, Von Horley, he kid, rare Lavelle, James, David White, Rochelle, Monta, super boy, a playground with no kids, Aaron, serious, Brian Fisher, Sailor Vista.
Rym: You think you're all that Kim possible, but you're not.
Rym: Matthew Smith, Don Schleich, Jar, Thomas and Joshua, Joe Starr, Tyler Eller, Sean Yeager, Sam quarter Clinton, Walton run from New Zealand.
Rym: Ryan parent rope, Atlanta, Rayla, Brian Sidroni, Finn, Eric Silverado, redacted, Chris Minkoff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redmond, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Media: I speak tonight for the dignity of man and the destiny of democracy.
Media: I urge every member of both parties, Americans of all religions and of all colors, from every section of this country, to join me in that cause.
Media: At times, history and fate meet at a single time, in a single place, to shape a turning point in man's unending search for freedom.
Media: So it was at Lexington and Concord, so it was a century ago at Appomattox, so it was just last week in Selma, Alabama.
Media: There, long-suffering men and women peacefully protested the denial of their rights as Americans.
Media: Many were brutally assaulted.
Media: One good man, a man of God, was killed.
Media: There is no cause for pride in what has happened in Selma.
Media: There is no cause for self-satisfaction in the long denial of equal rights of millions of Americans.
Media: But there is cause for hope and for faith in our democracy.
Media: and what is happening here tonight.
Media: For the cries of pain and the hymns and protests of oppressed people have summoned into convocation all the majesty of this great government, the government of the greatest nation on earth.
Media: Our mission is at once the oldest and the most basic of this country--to right wrong, to do justice, to serve man.
Media: In our time we have come to live with the moments of great crisis.
Media: Our lives have been marked with debate about great issues--issues of war and peace, issues of prosperity and depression.
Media: But rarely in any time does an issue lay bare the secret heart of America itself.
Media: Rarely are we met with a challenge--not to our growth or abundance or our welfare or our security, but rather to the values and the purposes and the meaning of our beloved nation.
Media: The issue of equal rights for American Negroes is such an issue.
Media: And should we defeat every enemy, and should we double our wealth and conquer the stars and still be unequal to this issue, then we will have failed as a people and as a nation.
Media: For with a country as with a person, what is a man profiting?
Media: If he shall gain the whole world and lose his own soul.