Rym: It's Tuesday, May 24th, 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: It's a fast food fracas with fast food franchise and food chain magnate.
Scott: Food chain isn't necessarily fast food.
Rym: That is true, but I needed an alliteration with you.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So yeah, there wasn't GeekNights in a while because we were packs, and then I got the flu, and then I flew to Hong Kong, and then I lived in Australia for two weeks, and now I'm back like over the weekend, and I guess we're doing GeekNights again.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Anything happen while I was sick and then gone?
Scott: Yeah, something happened today.
Rym: Oh.
Scott: So over the weekend, I made some cookies, and I brought them to work yesterday like I always do.
Rym: That's nice.
Rym: I got our office springs cookies occasionally, and they're super high quality when he does.
Scott: That's how I always do, right?
Scott: So I left the jar there in the office, and I left work last night.
Rym: What, that giant jar?
Rym: Like the one that you always put?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It was more than half full.
Scott: People didn't eat a lot of cookies yesterday.
Scott: I mean, you can only eat so many cookies, right?
Rym: I mean, I was about to say, like you know me, right?
Rym: But even I have my limit.
Scott: So I've done this many times before, but this is I guess the first time doing it since we changed offices, but whatever.
Scott: So when I come in this morning, I go to get a morning cookie like you do, and the jar is just gone.
Scott: Like the whole jar has disappeared.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: And I'm just like- Wait, so like the jar was there empty, or the jar itself is missing?
Scott: The entire jar is missing.
Scott: It was in the spot where the jar was.
Scott: There was now nothing.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Someone steal your jar?
Scott: So I go around.
Scott: Look, it was still really early.
Scott: Hardly anyone was in the office.
Scott: So I go around looking for the jar, and I found it.
Scott: It was empty and perfectly clean in the kitchen.
Scott: So someone not only ate- So I start looking for all the cookies, and they're not there.
Scott: So I don't, I mean, you know, if people ate them all, that's fine.
Scott: I'm okay with that.
Scott: That's the point, is people would eat them.
Scott: But I can't imagine that anyone ate that many cookies between five yesterday and nine in the morning today.
Scott: Yeah, especially like- Most of the people were leaving the office already, right?
Scott: They weren't eating that many during the day when they were freely available at lunchtime.
Rym: Well, I mean, you know me.
Rym: The situations were like I'll eat literally all the cookies we own before Emily even comes home from work.
Scott: You couldn't have eaten that.
Scott: Even you could not have eaten that many cookies.
Rym: In that fugue state, in Wildwood, where Scojo says, "Hey, didn't I buy a whole dozen
Rym: donuts?"
Rym: And everyone looks at me, and they're like, "Rym, how many did you
Rym: eat?".
Rym: I only ate like seven donuts.
Scott: My suspicion is that the cleaning person just fucking threw them all out, in which case I'm going to find them and murder them in their sleep.
Rym: But that wouldn't make sense unless your building has a weird fucked up policy of like no food overnight.
Scott: No, we don't have any such policy.
Scott: Basically, when we changed offices, my job is the same as it always was.
Scott: But basically, since changing offices, there are some improvements, like better chair, even though it's still not a great chair, and modern office furniture, better internet setup, the Wi-Fi that actually works.
Scott: But the culture of the people in my department is the same, and all the people in general are the same.
Scott: But the people who run the management of this office, like office managing, is giving me some serious problems.
Rym: Well, I know you can't ride your bike easily.
Rym: You have to lock it up outside.
Scott: I was like, "The building has no problem letting me bring my bike into the building because I saw someone do
Scott: it.".
Scott: And so did my other coworker who bikes.
Scott: And I'm like, "Hey, can I just bring my bike in the
Scott: office?".
Scott: He's like, "There's no
Scott: room.".
Scott: I'm like, "There's room right behind my fucking
Scott: desk.".
Scott: And they're like, "Well, if we let you do it, we'll have to let everyone do
Scott: it.".
Scott: I'm like, "Well, let everyone do it.
Scott: What's the
Scott: problem?".
Scott: They're like, "It would be an aesthetic
Scott: concern.".
Scott: Whoa.
Rym: If someone ever said that to me, phrased that way, I would consider just immediately quitting.
Scott: I considered it, right?
Scott: So that pissed me the fuck off.
Scott: Because basically, you're telling me that you're that person who complains about the neighbor's car being too old.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Right?
Scott: And I'm working for you.
Scott: Why should I spend eight hours a day helping you out, right?
Rym: Yup.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: You got time to lean.
Rym: You got time to clean situation.
Rym: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, my coworkers is still the same.
Scott: The work is still the same.
Scott: Everything else is still great.
Scott: But I found out that I'm working for that kind of asshole.
Scott: Right?
Scott: It's like, you know.
Rym: You could engage in an elaborate gaslighting campaign between you and all your smart coworkers to get that person fired.
Scott: You're basically like the CEO.
Rym: Oh, so the office manager isn't the CEO?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Basically, right.
Scott: That's weird because my company-- No, the office manager isn't the CEO.
Scott: But basically, they're like, you know, the executive-- The letter, I think the email said something like, the executives would not approve something, something.
Rym: Right?
Scott: So basically, you know, at this company, right, we basically, you know, we don't really interact with these, you know, the executive level people, right, ever, right?
Scott: Since they bought us.
Scott: Like, we don't talk to them or know them or anything, right?
Scott: And only on like a couple of occasions, there have been like weird decisions handed down from mysterious unnamed individuals.
Rym: So, Scott, I can at least tell you, when I worked at IBM, it was like that.
Rym: Like, we did our thing and everything was fine.
Rym: But like at one point, one of the senior management people at IBM, like top, top people, ended up being in our building, like in the same area.
Rym: And a whole bunch of weird stuff started happening.
Rym: Like suddenly, like you weren't allowed to leave doors open at certain times and they had like rules about what could be left in public areas.
Rym: And like all this weird sort of just annoying stuff started intruding into my work.
Scott: Right, my tolerance for that is very low.
Scott: So, and also another thing that happens, right, is the fucking cleaning people, right?
Scott: It's like they go around every night and if you have like a coffee mug on your desk, they take it away and clean it.
Rym: So that's not that uncommon, Scott, corporate bullshit.
Scott: But it's like I have one on my desk and I don't drink any coffee.
Scott: It's just there.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And occasionally, it's just fucking gone.
Scott: And I'm like,
Scott: "Fuck.".
Scott: And then someone's drinking out of it and it's like, "Oh, Jesus
Scott: Christ.".
Scott: It's like, "Don't touch shit on my fucking
Scott: desk.".
Rym: But that's a specific thing that's come up in like the last four or five years.
Rym: It's like the clean desk policy where a comp- And I bring this up because the only companies that give a shit about that are the same kinds of companies who are worried about aesthetic concerns.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: They want the desks to be clean.
Scott: Right, so this whole, you know, the whole management of this new office, you know, with this executive influence is pissing me the fuck off.
Scott: See, as much as I complain about like- But the problem is, is I want to go, you know, it's like everything else is great, though.
Scott: But, you know, if I want to go somewhere else, the problem is, is I can't find anywhere else to fucking go, right?
Rym: What about that weird place that would have paid you money for like four days a week?
Scott: Are they even still in business, that place?
Rym: If they still are at this point, maybe call them back.
Scott: You know what the business they were doing, right?
Scott: This is the problem, right?
Scott: Okay, so I'd work four days a week.
Scott: That's terrific, right?
Scott: And they probably would have let- I got a bike ride into work.
Scott: None of those problems would have happened.
Rym: And Scott, in two years, they go out of business, and you just find another place that's the same and repeat.
Scott: I can't- there's no guarantee that there's a place that's the same.
Scott: And also- Scott, you're a- The work that that place was doing is they're basically hitting the YouTube API and scraping the entire thing every night.
Scott: I'm just- I know.
Scott: And also, they're going to expect me to do fucking work, right?
Scott: I don't do work.
Scott: I sit around and get paid and don't do anything.
Rym: That's how this works, okay?
Rym: But Scott, I'm just saying, for someone who is a good developer, like a real developer, like a New York developer, like the kinds of people who want to be paid in money and not lottery tickets, you can pretty much just get a job.
Scott: that's- Yes, but all those jobs fucking suck.
Scott: They want me to work.
Scott: Yeah, and you- They actually want me to develop something, and it's like, "Fuck you, no, just pay me to sit
Scott: here.".
Rym: See, Scott, the way- this is why I wouldn't necessarily hire you to do any work, because I know you won't do it.
Scott: No, because that's exactly the thing, is these people are expecting me to sit there for a long time working.
Scott: It's like, no, that's not how- Obviously, I don't do no work.
Scott: I get the work you're asking for done in 10 minutes, and then I want to fucking leave.
Scott: That's how it is.
Scott: And at least- no one will let me leave, but at least where I am now, I can watch YouTube after I do my 10 minutes of work.
Rym: See, I have sort of a different situation where I have more work than I could do.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and if your internet is filtered or monitored in any way, I'm not working for you.
Rym: That actually is a deal breaker, and I have said that openly, anywhere I've ever interviewed in the past, and that was always okay.
Scott: I mean, basically, I've tried both ways, right?
Scott: I've tried the, you know, be nice and try to convince you to hire me, and then come out negotiating at the end,
Rym: and
Scott: what happens when I do that is they want to hire me, and then I reject them because they won't agree, and then we just waste everyone's time, and then I've tried negotiating upfront, and what happens then is they don't want to hire me.
Rym: See, I always came in with a separate thing.
Rym: If I act like they already gave me the job and are just talking about how it's going to be when I'm there, that's how I treated every interview I've ever done.
Scott: I mean, that's, you know, the I want you to hire me mode.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time, those interviews are always for places I actually did want to work.
Rym: Like, I decided, like, I do want to work here.
Scott: There's no place I want to work.
Scott: I want to not work.
Rym: Well, there's really no place in modern society for you.
Scott: You don't say.
Rym: Yeah, we're not post-scarcity yet.
Scott: I want to work as little as possible, but every place that wants to hire me wants me to work more.
Rym: Now, just saying, what if our Patreon got to the point to where you could make the same money you make now, but we were paid just to do GeekNights four nights a week again, but we made the same money we make now?
Scott: Yeah, if you've given me that much money.
Rym: No, but I'm just saying, as a theoretical, if the Patreon were at that level, would you be willing to put the effort in to do GeekNights four nights a week like we used to?
Scott: Four nights a week?
Scott: No?
Scott: Well, I mean, we just do four nights one day in the week.
Rym: We're incapable of doing two nights in one day now without considerable bitching.
Scott: But I don't have to go to work.
Scott: I can just wake up on Monday, on Monday record four podcasts.
Rym: Yes, but I'm saying, is that an acceptable level of, like, required work and office work, everything all mixed in and money?
Rym: Would that work for you?
Scott: It's only four hours a week.
Scott: That's okay.
Rym: It's more like six hours because it takes us a while to actually figure out what to do the show on.
Scott: I think with six days of doing stuff, I could get up enough material to do four shows.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I gotta say, having basically three weeks off of GeekNights just because of sickness and travel.
Scott: We could even do eight shows in two days.
Rym: Holy shit, do I have stuff for, like, a month or two worth of GeekNights just, like, queued up now.
Scott: But you'll forget it all.
Rym: I put it all in Google Keep.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: 'Cause I'm real smart now.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: So, in the news... It's not happy times.
Rym: Meanwhile, I just went to my company.
Rym: I was like, "Hey, I just want a bunch more
Rym: money.".
Rym: And they were like, "Oh, shit.
Rym: Okay.".
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I could ask for money anytime also.
Scott: They give me money every year, and I'm like, "I want
Scott: days.".
Scott: And they're like,
Scott: "Eh.".
Rym: Well, if you know you're not going to take the days anyway, just start getting more and more money, and maybe you'll build up enough of a nest egg of money by doing that to be able to take a bit more risk later.
Scott: I mean, I could just, you know... I don't want to take any risks.
Scott: This doesn't work.
Scott: I need to stay in New York City.
Scott: If I was going to leave New York City, I could just not work for years.
Scott: Wait, Scott.
Rym: You just want to live in New York and not have to do really work.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Work for the city in some sort of union.
Scott: Like what union?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Work for the MTA.
Scott: That's not enough money.
Rym: Yeah, it's enough money to live here.
Scott: Not enough money to leave the apartment I have now.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: You'd be in a shitty apartment.
Scott: I could move to a shitty apartment now if I wanted to and save a bunch of money.
Rym: Just remember, we could go back to Beacon and live there for five years just on our savings.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not taking any trains.
Rym: No, but we wouldn't be working anymore.
Rym: We'd just be living up there.
Rym: Burning savings for five years.
Rym: And then, I don't know, crime.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, as you guys might have noticed, we've been playing a lot of Civ V suddenly.
Rym: Like, just that bell rang and we've been playing.
Rym: Like, I'm in five GMR games right now.
Scott: I'm in one.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: I don't know what you're doing with your life.
Scott: Do you have time for five?
Rym: It does not take a lot of time to play GMR games because the only game I'm putting serious effort into is the big game I'm playing with the rest of the FRC, which you and James were eliminated from and everyone else is dangerous.
Rym: So, it's funny and weird to me that we just, for whatever reason, doubled down on playing Civ V. Like, serious multiplayer Civ V. And then, they're just like, "Oh, yeah, guys.
Rym: Civ VI is coming out October next
Rym: year.".
Scott: Civ V is a lot older than you think.
Rym: I know.
Scott: We saw it at PAX once.
Scott: It was like when it came out.
Rym: Wasn't that the same PAX we brought John St.
Rym: John?
Rym: I'm pretty sure it was.
Rym: That was a long time ago.
Scott: It might have been.
Scott: The release date of Civ V was 2010.
Scott: September 2010.
Rym: Remember, Civ V was kind of a shit game that didn't really exist until Brave New World, the second major expansion.
Rym: Just like Civ IV was kind of a shit game until the final expansion.
Scott: I don't really remember too much the difference because I didn't play it so extensively.
Scott: I played it a lot.
Rym: When Civ V first came out, it was boring, unplayable bullshit.
Rym: I played through it twice, and I was literally done with it.
Rym: There was no reason to ever play it again.
Rym: It was that bad.
Rym: Gods and Kings gave me one more playthrough.
Rym: Brave New World made it a game that I'm willing to play.
Scott: I don't even know which stuff was added in which expansions because I played the original a little bit, you know, and then I didn't.
Scott: And then, there was some Steam sale.
Scott: The whole everything.
Scott: So, Scott, I'll give you an example.
Rym: Ideologies, that's new.
Rym: All that crazy endgame stuff is brand new.
Scott: What ideologies?
Rym: You don't know about ideologies?
Scott: What are you talking about?
Rym: The thing called ideology in Civ.
Scott: Where is it?
Rym: Once you hit the industrial era, someone picks fascism, order.
Rym: You'd pick autocracy, order, or democracy.
Scott: Oh, that thing on the left where it's like these three symbols for each one?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I didn't figure out what those really do.
Scott: Really?
Rym: That's the best part of Civ.
Scott: I don't really know what makes them appear or which ones to choose or what effects they have.
Rym: I'll tell you this.
Rym: It appears when, as soon as you build, three factories.
Scott: Oh, you know why?
Scott: That's why I don't see it too often because so many fucking times I play this goddamn game and there just happens to not be any coal near me and I can't get any fucking coal.
Scott: Yes, you can.
Rym: There's going to be like four city states that have got coal.
Scott: How did I get the city state to give me coal?
Rym: Just be allies with them.
Scott: I can't get them to be allies with me.
Rym: Give them money or do the quests.
Scott: Allies require so much influence with the city state.
Rym: Hey, it is so easy.
Rym: Scott, I'm already in the solo gamer plan right now.
Rym: I am allied with one city state and friends with two more.
Scott: Yeah, the two city states that I can see have quests that I cannot possibly fulfill in any near term period.
Rym: Scott, I know what those quests were.
Rym: You can go for them.
Scott: There is no chance of me succeeding at any of those quests.
Rym: How so?
Rym: Anyway, you might have some problems in that game soon.
Scott: I already have problems in that game.
Scott: Well... I have no money.
Rym: Part of that is because I got that trireme blockading your whales.
Scott: Well, I'm building a trireme to divide my whales.
Rym: Yeah, well, let's see what happens in that trireme because there's things you can't see just out of range.
Scott: All right, that's fine.
Rym: Hanging out.
Rym: Anyway, Civ 6 is coming next year and something amazing happened after they announced that.
Rym: Daryl Surratt pointed this out, but I went and confirmed it.
Rym: Civ 5 went from not being in the top 10 to being the number three game people were playing on Steam.
Scott: Over what time period?
Rym: Just overall.
Rym: If you went in there and it showed today...
Scott: I'm saying when was it not in the top 10?
Scott: and then when was it...
Rym: It hadn't been in the top 10 for six months or a year.
Rym: It just wasn't up there.
Scott: When did it hit the top three?
Rym: The day after they announced Civ 6 was coming out.
Scott: Oh, so you said... Oh, okay.
Scott: The announcement... I thought you were saying...
Rym: Civ 6 was announced immediately.
Rym: Everyone was like, "Oh, right," and started playing Civ 5 again.
Rym: I think giant multiplayer robots are actually kind of pushing that too.
Scott: How many people are really using that?
Rym: A lot.
Rym: Go in there and look at the games that are looking for players.
Rym: Holy shit are a lot of people using that.
Scott: I don't know how many people know about that.
Scott: I can't imagine the percentage of those people playing on Steam.
Scott: I imagine a very small number of them.
Rym: I would wager that at least a third of all the people who are playing Civ 5 right now are playing multiplayer with that.
Rym: Because you can't play multiplayer any other way, for one.
Rym: But anyway, Civ 6 is coming.
Rym: I don't know if it'll be good or not because...
Scott: There's not enough info.
Rym: Either they're going to release it and it'll suck and then they'll have their expansion.
Rym: that makes it good later.
Scott: It's always good to assume that history will repeat.
Rym: Yeah, Civ 5 taught me that.
Scott: It's usually true.
Rym: Civ taught me that.
Rym: Every Civ.
Rym: If someone builds an owner's workshop...
Scott: I'm pretty safe betting.
Scott: a new iPhone is coming in September.
Scott: Pretty safe bet, right?
Rym: Yeah, there's going to be an iPhone 7 SE in December.
Scott: It's a pretty safe bet.
Scott: Civ 6 will be a lot like Civ 5.
Rym: But, if they're smart, and I don't want to impinge upon their game designers or whatever, but for real, they need to take the stuff that they added in Brave New World, like the current state of Civ 5, because it is the best Civ has ever been, and iterate from that and skip the phase where they make a stripped-down bullshit version like they do it in every other release and then add expansions to it later.
Rym: And I think that's what they're actually going to do because here are the things that they're adding.
Rym: One, cities will take multiple tiles and those tiles can be specialized in some fashion.
Scott: So now I've got to defend a million hexes when my city gets all big?
Rym: Well, it means maybe I take over your industrial district but the rest of the city is still resisting.
Scott: Yeah, well, if my industrial district is taking over, how can I build a military unit to fight?
Rym: I don't know, we'll see.
Rym: Two, active research.
Rym: So research is going to be more than just the tree.
Rym: You can do stuff in-game, like build units and do things that boost certain types of technology.
Rym: So, like, go into the jungle and do some bullshit and get a certain kind of technology faster.
Scott: So manual labor.
Scott: My manual labor and not my worker's manual labor.
Rym: Well, no, because you can probably automate that.
Scott: I mean, I feel like that's something that's abstracted by having a worker work.
Rym: Yeah, so basically worker work can now also specialize toward particular technology things.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Dynamic diplomacy.
Rym: So diplomacy will be... It'll change a lot more era to era.
Scott: The diplomacy with the AI, even in Civ V, is so bad.
Scott: I don't understand how it works.
Scott: I don't care.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Scott, one, it's really straightforward.
Rym: Two, I can tell you exactly how it works.
Rym: I know exactly how the AI will act.
Scott: The AI just randomly pesters me with things, and they're either bad or not, and I just either say yes or no.
Rym: One, it's not random.
Rym: And two, there's just a mathematical model.
Scott: If I try to propose anything to the AI of any kind, they basically say, "Oh, you want my luxury good?
Scott: Yeah, give me your whole empire and a
Scott: city.".
Scott: And I'm like, "No, how about I give you one of my luxury
Scott: goods?".
Scott: And they're like, "No, fuck
Scott: you.".
Rym: If I propose things to the AIs, they usually just say, "Yes, awesome, Rym.
Rym: Thank you for doing
Rym: business.".
Scott: That does not happen with me.
Rym: Because you don't know how diplomacy works.
Scott: Even the AI that I keep trying to be friends with, like, "Yes, let's be friends.
Scott: Yes, friendship declaration.
Scott: Yes.".
Scott: And then I propose something to them, and they're like, "Oh, you want one luxury good?
Scott: All right, give me 10 gold a turn for 30 turns, and give me a city, and give me a luxury
Scott: good.".
Scott: I'm like, "How about I just give you one luxury
Scott: good?".
Rym: Are you asking for a luxury good that they have multiple copies of, or one that they only have one copy of?
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: If I ever ask them for anything, they say no.
Rym: Scott, no one else has these problems.
Scott: I don't know how to manipulate that into giving me a fair deal.
Rym: But the diplomacy against humans and multiplayer can be real intense and real useful, but it's pretty limited.
Rym: It looks like they're going to give you a lot more options.
Rym: Like, alliances can be more later in the game.
Rym: There are hints at things like negotiation mechanics, and there's even a hint, a vague hint, that there might be ways to make alliances for joint victory.
Rym: That's a game changer.
Rym: Combined arms, so actually, this is something you're going to like.
Rym: So right now, the one unit per hex thing is good, right?
Rym: Because it reduces the -- I have 400 military units to move around the map.
Scott: Yeah, it's more -- it makes it an advance wars aspect, and not just a, "I built more units.
Scott: I don't care about advance
Scott: wars.".
Rym: But the con was, if you want to do something like send a land unit over the water, you have to manually make sure it's protected by sea units.
Scott: That's a pain in the ass.
Scott: And you have to manually manage all your aircraft, so now -- Well, at least the aircraft, you don't have to move around hex by hex.
Scott: You just say, "Bomb
Scott: that."
Scott: Boom.
Rym: Yeah, but you have to manage what cities have which types of air units and what are they doing in their downtime.
Scott: I wish they would just abstract away all the military stuff entirely towards just, "I have more military than
Scott: someone.".
Scott: I say, "I wore
Scott: Rym.".
Scott: It says, "Boom, Rym city explodes," because you have more stuff.
Rym: That exists.
Rym: It's called Europa Universalis.
Scott: That's too much -- that doesn't abstract anything.
Rym: Plus, I don't want to abstract it, because I love the shit out of that advance wars nonsense.
Rym: But, Scott, the new feature, combined arms, here's the exact thing.
Rym: For example, if you have an anti-tank unit and an infantry unit, you can merge them into a combined arms unit.
Rym: You only have one unit to manage, and they support each other.
Rym: Or you can link a warrior to some settlers, and it's just one unit.
Rym: Move it out there, treat it like one unit.
Scott: Oh, well, then when the settlers build, do I lose this warrior?
Rym: No, then the warrior's just in the city.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: And you can make -- basically, you can link a bunch of units together into an army, at least for movement purposes.
Rym: So you can say, "Hey, army, go that way," instead of -- Yeah, that's good.
Scott: I need that.
Scott: They claim -- All that stuff is stuff I need.
Rym: There's one lie item that just says, "enhanced multiplayer," which I hope means, finally, multiplayer will work, because it's never worked in any Civ ever.
Rym: I mean, giant multiplayer robot exists, because multiplayer literally does not work in Civ V.
Scott: I don't understand why it's so hard for them.
Rym: Yeah, it's like, I could design it for you, and the backend can't be that hard to set up, guys.
Rym: If FPSs can do it, Civ can do it.
Rym: Seriously.
Scott: Civ isn't even real-time.
Rym: Yeah, you can have one-day latency.
Rym: I'd be fine with that.
Rym: And there is an ominous one, however.
Rym: So everything up until this point that I've mentioned seems like really good news, because they basically imply that the game is going to be the current state of Civ V with stuff added.
Rym: It's almost like an expansion of Civ V with all of its existing expansions and a little bit of cleanup and consolidation.
Rym: But the last lie item -- and this is from the Civ website -- "A Civ for all
Rym: players.".
Rym: And they talk about how veteran players will have new ways to tune, but new players will have easy ways to play.
Rym: And coupled with that is the fact that they're changing the aesthetic to look like Civ Revolutions.
Rym: Remember Civ Revolution?
Rym: That game was garbage ass.
Scott: It was really fast to play.
Rym: Yeah, it was fast to play, but it acted like a free-to-play, nonsense Farmville kind of game.
Rym: There was no decision-making.
Scott: No, it didn't play like a Farmville game.
Rym: There was no decision at any point in that game.
Scott: Did you play that game?
Rym: Yeah, it was so baby that I just immediately gave up on it.
Scott: It was just a very much simpler Civ.
Rym: Yeah, it was so simple that there was never a non-obvious decision to make at any point ever in any situation.
Rym: So it's interesting that they're taking that art aesthetic and applying it to regular old Civ, and we'll see where that goes.
Rym: I mean, we have almost no information to go on.
Rym: What I told you is literally all we know.
Rym: And even what I told you was peppered with speculation based on vague things that they said about what Civ VI will be.
Rym: So time will tell, but I'm not going to pre-order it because if it's a Civ V or a Civ IV or a Civ III situation...
Scott: Well, I mean, Civ V lasted six years, so...
Rym: Minus the time before Brave New World was unplayable.
Scott: Why do I need to get Civ VI as soon as it comes out?
Rym: Yup, the only reason to get it if it comes out is if it basically is the Civ V. Brave New World's just better.
Scott: Like Doom just came out, and I played the multiplayer in the alpha and the beta, and it was meh.
Scott: It was just, basically, I could just play Quake Live.
Scott: Why do I need to play that?
Rym: Doom looks super fun.
Scott: But I want to play the single player, but I'm not paying 50 bucks.
Scott: I'll wait for it to be 10 bucks.
Rym: I'll pay 20 or 30.
Rym: It looks that good.
Rym: I got money.
Scott: Yeah, I got money, but I get spent on other better things.
Rym: Yeah, the only reason to buy a game immediately is if you have infinite money and infinite free time, or it's a multiplayer game that might have either a short shelf life or a short window to get good at it before you can never be good at it.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: -Got any news?
Rym: -I do.
Scott: So the spiel des Jahres nominees came out.
Rym: -Woo, exciting.
Rym: -Yeah.
Rym: I, for once, didn't look at that.
Rym: So if you tell me what they are, this is actually me learning for the first time.
Scott: Well, remember, there's the spiel des Jahres, right, which is the main award, right?
Scott: There's the Kenner spiel des Jahres, which is like the connoisseurs, right, award.
Scott: Those are like the fancy games, right?
Scott: And then there's the Kinderspiel, which is the kids' games.
Scott: So the Kinderspiel, the kids' games, was a game called Leo muss zum frissur, which is Leo goes to the barber, never heard of it.
Rym: I've heard of that because I heard people talking about it.
Rym: -Okay, sure.
Rym: -I don't know anything about it.
Scott: There's a Reiner Knizia game called Mmm, which I assume is about food.
Scott: And there's Stone Age
Scott: Jr.,
Scott: which is, I guess, a kids' version of Stone Age.
Scott: -There's a bunch of honorable mentions.
Rym: -I didn't like Stone Age, though.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Anyway, the connoisseurs Kenner spiel des Jahres, there's Isle of Skye, which I've seen around but haven't played.
Scott: There's Pandemic Legacy, which I haven't played.
Rym: Pandemic Legacy seems like it's actually probably a pretty good game for what it is.
Scott: And then there's Time Stories, which I've never heard of.
Rym: No, I actually have not heard of that either.
Scott: There's three honorable mentions, Seven Wonders Duel, which I'm kind of interested in trying.
Rym: I've heard mixed things about it, though.
Scott: Blood Rage, which I've never heard of, and Mombasa, which I've never heard of.
Rym: I've seen people play Mombasa.
Rym: I've never played it myself, but I saw some people playing it.
Scott: Anyway, the regular spiel des Jahres, three nominees.
Scott: Imhotep, never heard of.
Rym: I've heard of that.
Rym: In fact, I almost bought it because I saw it on sale.
Scott: Karuba, never heard of.
Scott: And Codenames, which I actually played.
Rym: Codenames?
Scott: Because everyone's playing Codenames nonstop.
Rym: Codenames is actually a really good game for the type of game that it is.
Rym: In that space of semi-casual, but also for serious trying to win social games.
Rym: It's way fun.
Scott: At least it's unique.
Scott: And it's like, yeah, it's cool.
Scott: I just don't really ever want to play it.
Rym: I bought it, and I actually do often feel the urge to play it.
Scott: I have no desire to play it.
Rym: At PAX, when you disappeared with TableTop and never came back to go to dinner with us or anything, we just played Codenames all night.
Rym: It was fun.
Scott: After dinner and everything else.
Scott: There's a bunch of other games here.
Scott: The honorable mentions for the regular spiel des Jahres, Agent Undercover (Spyfall), Animals on Board, Die Fiesen 7, Crazy Words, -Quinto...
Rym: -It's kind of an aside.
Scott: I don't know what these are.
Scott: But Codenames and Digs- Usually I know a lot more of the games that are on these things.
Rym: Well, because we've actually been kind of distracted.
Rym: It's been sort of video game and anime season lately.
Rym: For a whole year?
Rym: I haven't been super keeping up on new TableTop.
Rym: Partly because the feed of my social media isn't half people talking about new regular TableTop games and half people talking about Kickstarter TableTop games, which are almost universally awful.
Scott: Yeah, notice how none of those Kickstarter games got nominated for any spiels.
Rym: Because they're almost all bad.
Rym: Sorry, guys.
Rym: Sumer is the best TableTop Kickstarter game, -and it's a video game.
Scott: -It's a video game.
Rym: I think there's like one day left on that, so back it, guys.
Scott: They got enough moneys, I don't care.
Rym: Oh, as long as they made it, because it's really good.
Scott: It's good, but, you know.
Rym: It's good for- No one's made a game like that successfully in a while, and it scratches that mule itch in a big way.
Scott: Yeah, I just don't see myself actually playing it.
Rym: I do, though, because I did some playtesting, and I got, like, Judith and Natalie to play it.
Scott: I also playtested it, but then I, you know, while I, you know, evaluated it and it wasn't bad, I wasn't gonna- -But here's the thing.
Scott: -I didn't want to play it.
Rym: Most people have never experienced mules, so I got Judith and Natalie to play it, and they were like, "Uh, this game looks complicated," or whatever, "We'll start
Rym: playing.".
Rym: But as soon as that bidding happened, like, Natalie starts pushing forward on the bidding, and I pushed past her, and she was like, "Oh,".
Rym: and she pushed past, and, "Uh," and then I backed off at the last second, and then she was like, "Oh, shit, I was gonna do that to you,".
Rym: and then she bought the overpriced item, and, like, everyone immediately realizes how cutthroat that bidding is.
Scott: Mule bidding is a real deal.
Rym: Like, mule bidding is one of my favorite mechanics in games, full stop.
Scott: It's a good mechanic, but we can just play mule.
Rym: But a friend of ours had a good idea, 'cause Dixit's in the same space as codenames in a lot of ways.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: Just play codenames, but put Dixit cards out instead.
Scott: So you have to flip over the right cards?
Rym: Yeah, like, we came up with some rules for it, and I gotta tweak it a little bit, but there is a way to combine those two games into something- There's not enough Dixit cards, even if you buy 'em all.
Scott: Yeah, but you can combine those two games- And you need to make all the stupid little, like, boards that, you know, tell you.
Rym: You could combine them into something that was, like, a super dangerous, like, for real game with some amount of effort.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: I have two videos here, and it's very- They have to be two, and that is why it's my thing of the day.
Rym: So this is a pretty crazy lock.
Rym: Now, they call it the forever lock.
Rym: This thing, they sell it as, like, a bike lock, like a U-lock, and they also sell it as a lock you can use for, like, your house, like a for real lock, like the deadbolt.
Rym: And it's got this crazy key that is- They talk about how it's effectively unpickable because it's a traveling keyway.
Rym: Do you know a lot about locks?
Scott: Like, you ever- I know as much as any nerd does.
Rym: So the idea of a traveling keyway is you have this crazy, like, weird lock and key.
Rym: So you stick the key in the lock, then you twist a thing, so the key is in the lock and you can't see it.
Rym: Then you twist another thing, and now the key goes into a part of the lock that can literally never be accessed from the outside, and that is how you unlock it, so there's no way to pick it.
Rym: There's literally no way to get a pick in there.
Rym: And this video is like a six-minute video of a lock nerd going into extreme detail as to, like, why this lock is so for serious and hard to pick.
Scott: All right, and then someone just smashes it.
Rym: Uh, no.
Scott: I mean, if you use it as a bike lock, it's like, dude, no one picks bike locks unless you have a really shitty one.
Scott: They just cut them with a giant, giant claw.
Rym: Yeah, now, actually, I have another video, it's not my thing of the day, where someone points out that if you use the right kinds of tempered alloy chains and things, unless you use a powered grinder, like a powered Dremel, or a five-foot or longer bolt cutter, there's actually no way to open those.
Scott: Did you read that thing about the confessed bike thief, and he talked about how he used to steal bikes back in the day?
Rym: Yep, I think you've sent me a link to that.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Because we were talking about bike theft on GeekNights.
Scott: He basically had a gigantic bolt cutter, they would ride around on a motorcycle, the guy would get off the motorcycle, right, clip the bolts, give the bolt cutter to the guy on the motorcycle, then ride your bike away.
Rym: But, I mean, this lock, like, you can use it as the deadbolt in your house, which at least that seems like a more reasonable thing, because, like...
Scott: If I had my own house and I could put my own lock on it, I'd just get some sort of digital lock.
Rym: Yeah, but that might be jackable in all much easier ways.
Scott: Not if I made it myself.
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: That's like the people who roll their own encryption, like, maybe it's better.
Scott: The encryption part, I would just get from some safe, open-source, trusted place.
Rym: But anyway, at least it makes sense, like, any lock in any apartment building, I could just bumpkey it open, like, if I wanted to.
Rym: Like, bumpkeys, like, I could teach any of you how to use a bumpkey in, like, two minutes.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: They just work.
Rym: Just open any apartment.
Rym: But it would at least make sense, like, here's a weird lock, like, basically can't pick it from the outside, except my follow-up video is a lock nerd who knows a lot more than that other lock nerd, who throws a lot of shade at that lock nerd and similar lock nerd.
Scott: He says this lock is kind of nonsense?
Rym: He is like, whoa, guys, one, this lock is, like, really hard to use as a lock, like, fuck this UX, because it's got the weird key, and two, watch me pick it in literally a minute.
Rym: [laughter] And how he picks it is an attack that I'd heard of, but I'm not really a lock nerd, so I didn't know what a foil attack actually was, and watching this video, I now know exactly...
Scott: Tin foil?
Rym: Basically, it's foil tape.
Rym: It's tin foil that's sticky on one side.
Scott: I've seen locksmiths use that.
Rym: Yeah, so this video is great, because this guy knows way more about locks.
Rym: He's just like, yo, dog, this lock sucks.
Rym: Check it out.
Rym: And at one point, he's like, all right, so it's a dimple lock, and it's got two sets of dimples, and that's complicated, so actually, and then he starts looking at it, so this one's probably, like, a three, three, three, wait, are these all, are there really only three levels of depth here?
Rym: Uh, wait, there might only be two levels of depth.
Rym: Whoa, that's, let's not get into that.
Rym: Let's assume that there's three.
Rym: Now, a real lock will have, like, seven or nine, and this guy's great.
Rym: This guy reminds me of that other guy.
Rym: we watch the videos of, where he takes dodgy electronics, and he's like, wow, this'll just kill you.
Scott: Speaking of locks, how safe do you think your stuff is if you put it in the safe deposit box at the bank?
Rym: Uh, well, because I read FARC, I know, not safe at all, is that your thing of the day, those guys?
Scott: No, I just, I just thought of it just now.
Rym: Oh, some guys, literally, the article came out today.
Scott: It's in Historia, anywhere I live.
Rym: They broke into a bank from the top, like, they just cut a hole in the roof, and just opened every safe deposit box.
Scott: They didn't open all of them, but they took a bunch of them.
Rym: They opened as many as they could and just took everything.
Scott: Anything valuable.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, I guess the vault in the bank isn't really a vault, it's just basically a vault door with a room behind it, and you can just break into that room from the ceiling or through the drywall.
Rym: Yeah, I suspect the only banks that have actual vaults are, like, pre-war banks.
Scott: Well, someone pointed out that if you go through, like, the desert, there's old Wild West banks, and the vaults are still there, and nothing else in the town is there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Also, in Manhattan, you can go and find safe deposit boxes in old banks.
Rym: Yeah, you go to the places that, like, the ultra-rich people use.
Scott: Yeah, we can go there.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's not really expensive right now.
Rym: The thing is, if I busted into a safe deposit box, the only things I would take would be SD cards and USB sticks.
Rym: 'Cause you know that that's, like, passwords to backends of dangerous shit.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: Anyway, so here's my thing of the day.
Scott: Back in 1994, when we were, like, 12, '94?
Scott: At the Consumer Electronics Show.
Rym: I was in, what, sixth, seventh grade anyway.
Scott: Right, there wasn't, like, an E3.
Scott: Maybe there was an E3 then, but there was, you know, there were a lot of video games at the Consumer Electronics Show, 'cause it's not like there was a PAX.
Rym: Yeah, back then, like, there were gaming coms, but they were, like, Grognard old D&D style gaming coms.
Scott: And this was the 16-bit era.
Scott: So they were showing off at this 1994 Consumer Electronics Show a game for the Genesis/Super Nintendo.
Scott: that never came out.
Scott: But somebody recorded a video of this game with what I assume must have been a VHS camcorder or maybe Betamax camcorder.
Scott: And that video is on YouTube here for you to watch.
Scott: Here is the cancelled, never officially released, never found in any form except for this video.
Scott: I guess all the code must be deleted.
Scott: or who knows?
Scott: The officially licensed 16-bit Akira video game.
Scott: Whoa.
Scott: Could have been a real thing.
Scott: Never was.
Scott: But you can see pretty impressive the parts that they made, mostly the cutscene parts.
Rym: Yeah, Genesis games tended to have really good cutscenes.
Scott: The game parts look real bad, but the cutscene parts look real good.
Scott: And I guess we don't know even, like, if the code for this is out there anywhere.
Scott: I'm sure if you found it, you would be mad, you know, popular.
Rym: In the meta moment, the Book Club book is gonna be Oryx and Crake by Margaret Atwood.
Rym: Did you start it yet?
Scott: I read comics instead.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: I was sitting there in my bed and I look over to the side and it was sitting there and right next to it was, like, you know, some comics.
Scott: And I'm like,
Scott: "Hmm.".
Rym: We can start it sometime before PAX Prime.
Scott: It doesn't look like... I got the book.
Scott: I don't think it's that large.
Scott: If I started reading it, I'd probably finish it in, like, a week.
Rym: So, I was gonna just stop The Wheel of Time and just move on to other stuff, but in the 13th book, suddenly it was like, "Oh, shit, let's wrap up every single thread and tell you
Rym: everything.".
Scott: Did they go to the Tower of the Snake People?
Rym: They're on their way there, so basically...
Scott: That's all I want to know.
Rym: So, you know, I remember way back, a character is like, "Hey, what's the deal with this
Rym: tower?".
Rym: And someone from the tower is like, "Uh, you're way too low level for
Rym: this.".
Scott: Yes, I read that part.
Rym: Yeah, so now, someone was like, "Guys, you're high enough level now.
Rym: Go into that tower.
Rym: Here's what that tower is.
Rym: Here's the deal.
Rym: Here's the deal with the doorways.
Rym: Everything's explained.
Rym: Go.".
Scott: Tell me what it is, then.
Rym: No, read the books.
Scott: I'm not reading 13 books.
Scott: Fuck you.
Rym: Or listen to the podcast because Kahlil White and I are going to do a podcast special on the entire Wheel of Time.
Scott: I only care about the tower part.
Scott: Just tell me that part.
Rym: Uh, no, because it's real interesting what's going on, actually.
Scott: Oh, fuck you.
Rym: Yeah, you can read the books and find out, or you can wait until PAX and listen to the panel.
Rym: It's either going to be a panel or...
Scott: If there's a listener out there who's read all these stupid books, tell me what the fucking tower is.
Scott: Also, if I wouldn't mind, just tell me what the deal with the dark one is, and then I don't need to know anything else.
Scott: I don't know the deal with the dark one yet.
Scott: I don't give a shit about anything else.
Rym: But I know the deal of almost everything now.
Scott: I don't care about those other things.
Scott: I don't care about the two things.
Scott: What's in the snake tower, and what's the deal with the dark one?
Rym: Yeah, you don't care about Slayer?
Rym: Like, what's his deal with that guy?
Scott: No, I don't even know who that is, and I don't give a fuck.
Rym: I thought you were under him.
Rym: Maybe you didn't run into him yet.
Rym: He's the one who went back into the tower, I guess.
Rym: I barely remember.
Scott: I don't know who that is.
Rym: But anyway, I'm going to finish the books, and then I'll read Orcs and Crake.
Rym: The Geek9's Patreon is going strong.
Rym: There's a bunch of stuff in there.
Rym: Emily and I have been reading a bunch of anime.
Rym: We're going to be at ConnectiCon.
Rym: Submit your panels, because I'm literally scheduling the whole con, like, right now.
Scott: Oh, why is this so soon?
Rym: So if you didn't submit a panel, the places in the schedule I could put your panel are rapidly filling up with what I've already had submitted.
Rym: Like, I'm not joking.
Rym: If you wait a week or two, even if you submit a good panel, you're just going to be SOL.
Rym: Pax Prime is coming up.
Rym: I think Pax South.
Rym: Badges are on sale.
Rym: Notice how they're not sold out.
Rym: You can totally buy them.
Rym: Pax Prime Badges will go on sale any day.
Rym: They will sell out within a second.
Rym: So buy them as soon as you can.
Rym: And don't even try to get the Sheraton.
Rym: Get some other hotel.
Rym: Yeah, Geek9's will be back on its regular schedule for the foreseeable future.
Scott: I bought a bunch of equipment that I needed to make live streaming actually work easily.
Scott: Because I tried to do it, and then I was like, "Oh, fuck, I don't have...".
Scott: And then I was like, "Oh, fuck...".
Scott: And then it's now.
Scott: I should have, by the end of the week, all the things I need.
Scott: And then Saturday is the Philadelphia Netrunner Regional Tournament.
Scott: So starting next week, I'm just going to make a bunch of YouTube videos that are probably all bad.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And you might have noticed, I've been uploading a ton of, like, CIV 5 videos.
Scott: Streaming and also not streaming.
Rym: And, like, panels we normally wouldn't upload, but fuck it.
Rym: We're basically just going to start cranking out a lot more content.
Scott: I'm going to make a bunch of garbage because there's nothing better to do.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But, frankly, a lot of content that's not 100% polished seems to do way better than a small amount of good content.
Scott: Yeah, YouTube seems to favor you when you do a lot of stuff.
Scott: So, fine, I'll do a lot of stuff.
Scott: Don't be sorry.
Rym: The floodgates are opening.
Rym: Looky-mighty.
Rym: It's Epax.
Rym: Our friends Chris and Anthony.
Rym: Chris has been bugging me in particular to play these two games for a long time.
Rym: Particularly the first one.
Rym: And we played them.
Rym: Scott, we both played them.
Rym: And now we can talk about them.
Rym: But I stress, we're reviewing games that we played one of them once.
Scott: And one of them less than once.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So that is the level of review you're about to get, at least for now.
Rym: I might revisit one of the two of these once.
Rym: I've played it a bunch of times.
Rym: And the other one, while I appreciate it, I'll probably never play it again.
Scott: I'm not playing either one of these again.
Rym: I could play the second one again.
Rym: So, fast food franchise and food chain magnate.
Scott: Which one are we talking about first?
Rym: I think we should talk about fast food franchise first.
Scott: So fast food franchise is a game that I won.
Scott: I got a full web.
Scott: And it's basically just Monopoly.
Scott: This game is Monopoly.
Scott: You roll the dice, you move around the board.
Scott: You buy stuff.
Scott: But instead of buying hotels, you sort of by this weird system put little squares of your fast food franchise in this grid in the middle of the board.
Scott: And if you were able to connect your grid and I was able to, I picked the ice cream which is the most possible squares.
Scott: Because it's not symmetrical, right?
Scott: If you choose the fancy one that pays out more you get less squares to work with.
Scott: I picked ice cream.
Scott: Just randomly I picked ice cream.
Scott: But it had the most squares.
Scott: So I was able to make a full 100% connection between all of my ice creams on the entire board with a full web.
Scott: So anyone who landed on my ice cream had to give me a million dollars.
Scott: And when I passed go, I got like a zillion dollars.
Scott: And the only thing that separates this from Monopoly is actually a pretty big deal is that number one, you get eliminated fast.
Scott: If you land on my ice cream.
Scott: when I'm set up like that you just die.
Rym: Yeah, that's the way I describe it.
Scott: Take Monopoly and you get a ton of money.
Scott: when you pass go if you've got stuff set up and if you get a million dollars you just win.
Scott: So imagine Monopoly ended after like 20 minutes, but it's basically the same game with a very small amount of decision making.
Rym: Well, the thing is, I would say that this is almost a deconstruction of Monopoly or a game like that.
Scott: Uh, no, a deconstruction of Monopoly would be Mad Magazine the board game.
Rym: Well, but what I was about to say if you deconstruct something, this is where you're trying to lose all your money.
Rym: No, but it's almost too close to Monopoly and too true to the feelings of Monopoly to, it's not like Monika where you took, you know, the magical girl genre and said, wait a minute, look at it from another angle.
Scott: I should watch that.
Rym: This is more like Monopoly, look at it from this like pure distilled angle where it'll give you a lot of the feels that Monopoly would give you but in a much more streamlined elegant, fast failure model where it has the snowball of Monopoly, but then just as the snowball crests the peak game over, it's done.
Rym: Like, uh, in both games that I played of this, I got eliminated.
Rym: I was just out and you know what?
Rym: In Monopoly, you're eventually just out eventually, but eventually in this game, like you're eliminated the second you can't come back anymore.
Rym: Like within one more go around to the board, you're just out because you land on someone else's chicken surprise and everything's over and you just quit.
Scott: and it's.
Rym: it's oddly liberating because Monopoly is a game that I do not enjoy playing.
Scott: You get just trapped in Monopoly because you're, it's like you've already lost, but you have to keep playing because you're not eliminated, but you didn't officially lose yet.
Rym: But at the same time, but Monopoly at the same time it's, it's weird how it scratches a few itches around nostalgia and also like some of the gameplay, like it scratches a few itches, but then it punches you in the dick repeatedly while it's scratching.
Rym: Fast food franchise is just like fast food franchise pats you on the back.
Rym: Like it's fine.
Scott: Stop playing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Congratulations.
Scott: You won.
Scott: Stop playing.
Rym: Like faster franchise walks over and says, Hey, do you have that itch?
Rym: that says, Hey, maybe I should play Monopoly?
Rym: It scratches that itch really, really good.
Rym: And then it walks away.
Scott: I think the thing it's missing that Monopoly has is the sort of like dog boat, Mr.
Scott: Monopoly go to jail.
Rym: It has that because it's got chicken surprise.
Scott: Yeah, but chicken surprise isn't as good as like, Oh, go to jail.
Scott: Do not pass go.
Rym: Are you kidding?
Rym: Chicken surprise.
Rym: You're running a fast food franchise.
Rym: you don't have called chicken surprise.
Scott: And you don't have bank error in your face.
Rym: You have to click on the link and look at what this game looks like.
Scott: You don't have like when you don't win the beauty pageant.
Rym: This.
Rym: Yes, you do on those cars.
Scott: Isn't it?
Scott: Wasn't it second place in beauty pageants?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But the the aesthetic of this game be no railroad.
Rym: Take a ride, bitch, has been variously described by people I've shown it to as interesting minimalist.
Rym: What the fuck?
Rym: That is horrible.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, because this is a small press game from the nineties, right?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Oh, so if you think about like, you know, the the relative production value of like indie game, indie tabletop games today to, you know, the super professional ones.
Scott: Think about what an indie tabletop board game looked like in the 90s.
Rym: But Scott, the logo of chicken surprise is so wonderful that that is the equivalent of the top hat.
Scott: It's not a battleship blowing up a top hat.
Rym: I think it's on the same level.
Rym: I don't.
Rym: Maybe I'm just really into chicken surprise.
Rym: I want to make a T-shirt.
Rym: I'm also.
Scott: I'm also kind of into the, you know, monopoly characters.
Rym: No one remembers this game.
Rym: You know, I'm going to do because I've got Amazon merch.
Scott: Just print one.
Rym: The chicken surprise T-shirt is going to be that color and it's just going to be the chicken surprise logo blown up front and center.
Rym: And that's it.
Scott: Do it.
Rym: I'm going to make that shirt on Amazon just so I can buy myself a copy of it.
Scott: Shit talking is happening.
Rym: I don't think you understand how quickly I can make a T-shirt.
Rym: Remember that listener who made that ugly fan art of us that I'm, for whatever reason, like really obsessed with?
Scott: I don't know which ugly fan art that is.
Rym: The one that's like a stylized Ren and Stimpy looking versions of our faces?
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: There's a Dave and Joel one, too.
Rym: I made a poll in the Patreon of, hey, if I made this GeekNights T-shirt, would you buy it?
Rym: And the resounding answer was, what the fuck, Rym?
Scott: Everyone is already giving us money.
Scott: They definitely want the T-shirt.
Rym: No, they don't want the T-shirt because they hate the T-shirt.
Rym: Emily looks at the design.
Rym: She's like, no, no.
Scott: But it wasn't there a shirt where we were playing.
Scott: We were Dig Dug.
Scott: Why don't we make that shirt?
Rym: Oh, I don't remember that one.
Rym: Find me that one.
Rym: I'll make that T-shirt.
Scott: Someone made a fan art of us like a million years, like nine, ten years ago.
Scott: We were Dig Dug.
Rym: Find it for me and I'll make it.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I don't think it was high res enough to make a T-shirt.
Rym: I could get someone to redraw it.
Scott: I don't think the colors are good enough either.
Rym: Yeah, but I could get someone to redo it just in the concept.
Rym: But Scott, I can make two hundred and fifty T-shirts and just sell them on Amazon.
Scott: If you want to buy a T-shirt with Dig Dug, but it's me.
Rym: I'm making the Chicken Surprise shirt and then I'm going to email.
Rym: Oh, is this Tom Lehman?
Rym: Who made this game?
Rym: It was, I think it was Tom Lehman.
Scott: Lehman's brother?
Rym: No.
Rym: Yeah, Tom Lehman.
Rym: So, I'll email him and be like, yo, I made a Chicken Surprise shirt.
Rym: Do you want any money from it?
Rym: Can I be the official distributor of Chicken Surprise T-shirts?
Scott: As forgiveness instead of permission?
Rym: Well, I'll make one because I just want to buy it for myself.
Rym: So, I have to put it in the marketplace, order it for myself on Amazon and then I could just take it down.
Rym: But I want to go to it and be like, look, can I make one T-shirt for each of the franchises in this and be the official T-shirt?
Rym: franchisee of fast food franchise merchandise?
Rym: Fifty, fifty profits?
Rym: Let's go?
Rym: Because Ice Cream Scream is also a really good logo.
Rym: It's just like this minimalist guy yelling in an ice cream cone.
Rym: it's also like the graphic design is like really minimal and weird but at the same time it's kind of beautiful because you look at this map like this board and you're like, what the fuck?
Rym: But then you realize that it's actually a surprisingly accurate map of the United States.
Rym: In a grid.
Rym: And it is.
Rym: And it actually works out that way.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: But I mean I don't want to really get into the mechanics because we're kind of just talking about our impressions of these games, but fast food franchise is worth playing.
Rym: just get some people who are on your same wavelength, find a copy of this game somehow.
Scott: Good luck.
Rym: Find Chris Reimer at any convention.
Rym: if you live in Pennsylvania, just track this dude down, knock on his door and be like yo, Rym said I could play fast food franchise with you guys.
Scott: I think this might be useful game if you have a family that refuses to play a real game.
Scott: You couldn't even get them to play Ticket to Ride.
Scott: But you can get them to play Monopoly and that way you can play this and that's the compromises.
Scott: They'll play it and it won't take forever.
Rym: This is both simpler and more complicated than Monopoly though.
Rym: It's hard to...
Scott: But someone who refuses to play Ticket to Ride but will play Monopoly could possibly be convinced to play this instead.
Rym: But they might be scared away by the weird abstractness of it.
Scott: It would be an improvement.
Rym: But I think this is a good game to get like high rollers, Scott.
Rym: Like people like us or like Jared Sorensen or Chris Reimer and do a livestream.
Rym: let's play of this game like all in.
Scott: I think it's mostly a game of luck.
Scott: You should gamble on this game and it would be a lot more interesting than gambling on other games that people usually gamble on.
Rym: No, here's what we do.
Rym: We play the game and we all put up money and we do a livestream.
Scott: Play the game with real money.
Rym: But the YouTube livestream.
Rym: we do a separate thing where it's basically salty bet and everyone is betting on which one of us is going to win.
Scott: It's not exciting.
Scott: Salty bet works because you can get a lot of bets on a lot of fights real quick.
Scott: If this would be one long game, like 20 minutes no one wants to bet on that.
Rym: The kind of person who would be fascinated by this game is the kind of person who would be all in on that.
Scott: You're getting two people.
Rym: Anyway, seriously, if you care about game design at all if you're into this stuff, if you're into TableTop I'm not saying this is a good game.
Rym: I am saying you should play it once and just see what's going on in there.
Rym: Because I enjoyed my time with this game.
Scott: You can just read the board game and see what's going on in there.
Rym: I don't think you can.
Rym: I think you need to play it once and experience it.
Scott: You're never going to find a coffee so it doesn't matter.
Rym: And I guarantee at PAX Prime you're going to see me wearing a Chicken Surprise t-shirt.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So, the other game, which is a more traditional to the modern era of indie games game, is Food Chain Magnate.
Scott: I can see why.
Scott: I mean, this is a real game, right?
Scott: Like a quote-unquote real ortho game.
Scott: It has a kick-started aesthetic.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I don't think it was kick-started.
Scott: I don't even know.
Scott: The aesthetic is actually kind of cool retro kind of style.
Rym: The game is beautiful.
Scott: It's not beautiful.
Rym: Except for the board.
Rym: I think the board is kind of bad and I don't like the design of the board.
Scott: The board is bad and it's like slightly unpolished but it has that sort of retro 50s diner style.
Rym: I'll put it this way, Scott.
Rym: The issues that we have with the aesthetic design are down to the level of those four.
Rym: things should be colored differently.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: But, and I can see why people like this game a lot because it's like a real game.
Rym: It's a high skill game.
Rym: It's an ortho game.
Rym: There's very little randomness.
Rym: This is a Puerto Rico style.
Scott: There's like no luck whatsoever.
Rym: If you lose, you made bad decisions.
Scott: But, I don't like this game.
Scott: I don't want to play it ever again.
Rym: And remember, we played...
Scott: Just because it's a game of skill doesn't mean that I want to play it.
Rym: Full disclosure again, we played like ten turns of this game before I was so fed up.
Scott: we stopped.
Rym: Scott and I both hate this game but we have to be clear.
Rym: this game was brought to us by people who we trust who thought we'd like the game, which was interesting.
Rym: And I can see why they thought we'd like the game.
Rym: And I can see why they like the game.
Rym: I hate the game for very specific and narrow reasons.
Rym: And Scott hates the game to a degree that actually frightened me.
Scott: It was just so uninjured.
Scott: Like, you know, it was just so painful.
Rym: Like, we start playing the game and I'm like, alright, so I'm going to make a decision here but I take issue with the way this goes.
Rym: I feel like there's going to be a snowball that I can't come back from already.
Rym: I feel like the decision I made.
Rym: this turn round two literally ended the game for me and it's over.
Rym: Scott sits down and basically before I even got to that level now, he's like, "What the fuck is this bullshit?
Rym: What the fuck?
Rym: Fuck this
Rym: game!"
Rym: And starts going apeshit at the table at length about how much he hates this game to a degree to where bystanders came over to see what was wrong.
Scott: Right, so much like Age of Steam, right, this is a game that kicks your ass.
Scott: You fuck up one thing early, it's just like you're done.
Scott: Unlike Age of Steam and unlike Fast Food franchise, Food Chain Magnet, you don't get eliminated.
Scott: You gotta fucking sit there, right?
Scott: So, the main problem with this game is that on the right side of the board, there's all these bonuses, right, that let you upgrade your abilities.
Scott: Everyone starts off on even footing.
Rym: But, they're all crazy permanent powers.
Scott: There's crazy permanent powers that are super strong and you basically upgrade yourself for the rest of the game.
Scott: Like, I am better at this now than everyone else for the whole rest of the game because I got this thing.
Rym: And there's a million of them.
Scott: There's a ton of them, so obviously everyone's gonna get a different set of them and that's gonna guide their course through the rest of the game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, and that is a perfectly fine mechanic to have, right?
Scott: It's like aha, I will be the guy who's better at A and I'll be the guy who's better at B and we'll take different strategic routes to build our machines and build different machines and see who has the most money in the end.
Scott: That is perfectly fine.
Rym: Now, the way you get these things, and I'll let Scott go apeshit on why he's so mad about it, is that there's things you can do in the game, like a million things.
Rym: There's lots of options like what you're actually doing in the game.
Scott: You've got all these different actions.
Scott: you can choose on your turn and different employees.
Scott: you can basically choose which employees are going to work every turn that you've hired and you can also hire more employees and that, and you can increase your capacity of how many employees can work per turn.
Scott: and that sort of is what you do on each turn, right?
Rym: But this mechanic, full disclosure before Scott goes crazy, it is a very clever mechanic that in a vacuum I actually really like, but applied to this specific game, I dislike it.
Rym: But I want to make it clear, like this mechanic has merit.
Rym: So the way the mechanic works is if you do a thing, like every power has a condition.
Rym: So one of the powers gives you like a ton of pizza or whatever and its condition is if you are the first person to put a pizza billboard out on the board.
Scott: Something like that, like if you're the first person to hire a pizza boy, you get the super pizza upgrade and no one else gets it.
Rym: Yep, one of them is like if you're the first person to fuck up and throw away food, you get a fridge that lets you never have to throw away food again basically.
Rym: And the way this works is if you hit the milestone, everyone who hit that milestone, the turn that anyone hit the milestone...
Scott: Right, so that's a perfectly good mechanic, right?
Scott: Because now you don't have a turn order situation where like, "Oh, Rym went first and he snatched everything
Scott: up.".
Scott: They figured that out, that's great, right?
Scott: It's like, okay, we'll give it to whoever does the thing first, but if everyone does it on the same turn, everyone gets it.
Scott: And then after, if you do it on a turn after that, well you don't get it because...
Rym: Yep, so if you do the thing, if you and me and Scott get the thing, because we both like advertise on the first time, no one else can get those powers for the rest of the game when you flip them over.
Rym: Now that could be cool.
Scott: Right, that's fine, because obviously if someone didn't get those powers that we got, they're getting other powers, right?
Scott: Because basically every turn someone is going to be doing a thing that gets them one of these powers, especially early in the game, right?
Scott: Where everyone doing everything is the first person to do that thing, right?
Scott: And if you see, you know, you can sort of tell what other people are maybe going for based on different things and try to choose things that they don't choose, but obviously if you choose the same thing on the same turn, that's perfectly fine, because you're going to get it too, right?
Scott: So
Rym: it's like whatever direction you push in, you're going to be able to push harder in that direction, and the game among skilled players would be, very clearly, because there's no real luck in this game, Scott pushed in direction A, and I'm pushing in directions B and C, so the competition is the direction we're pushing enough to overcome each other, like you're specializing in the thing you're doing.
Scott: Right, and then, you know, the game will actually come down to more specific decisions, like which spot did you put your advertisement on the board, and, you know, you can really get.
Rym: Did you anticipate that Scott was going to push B three rounds and then swerve and push C a little bit, thus diversifying crazily?
Rym: Like, did you anticipate that?
Rym: Could you counter it?
Rym: Which is similar to what happens in non-luck games like Puerto Rico, where, did you anticipate that Scott was going the factory route, and set yourself up to capitalize on that, while you go the other route.
Scott: It's like, aha, you were planning to, you picked trade, you thought Scott was going to craft, but actually, nope, you didn't pick craft and now you're stuck trading nothing.
Scott: Good luck.
Rym: So Scott, regale me with why you don't like that mechanic in this game.
Scott: So the main problem is that if you fall a turn behind under any circumstance, you're basically just fucked, right?
Scott: So what happened was, is I misinterpreted some of the things in the game, partially?
Rym: Now I think Scott misinterpreted them because he's dumb.
Scott: Partially because I'm dumb, but also partially because there's some issues with the design of the thing.
Rym: There are a few cards that need, they really need to be a different color.
Scott: There are a few things that need to be a different color, and there's a few things that could be worded better, right?
Scott: But I still, I just messed up, I didn't realize something, so I made a decision where I thought I was going to get a thing, and I didn't get it.
Scott: And the result of that was, I could not be the first to do pretty much fucking anything for the rest of the game, so I couldn't get any more upgrade abilities, and I was pretty much just done.
Scott: There's no way, and there was no because everything is first come, and that's it, there's no other way to get stuff, I couldn't catch up.
Scott: So why was I still playing this game?
Scott: It didn't, the game is a long game, I would have had to keep playing it.
Rym: The game itself, what they say on the box, quote, "This game can be played by two to five serious gamers in two to four
Rym: hours.".
Scott: And it's like, well, I fucked up one thing on like turn two, because I didn't get it right, and now, and as soon as I was afterwards, I realized it within like, you know, immediately, like, oh, that's not the thing that I should have done because of that, but it was too late, and now I'm just fucked.
Scott: But I have to sit there for three hours, fuck this.
Scott: I'd rather complain and then leave the game.
Rym: It was a little more narrow in that the game's a snowball game.
Rym: The way I would describe this game is, everyone starts at the top of a mountain, and they make a snowball, and the snowballs are all the same size, and you pick what direction to roll that snowball off the map, and they just accelerate and accelerate and accelerate.
Rym: If you like, drop your snowball, if your snowball hits a rock or something, well, if it hits a rock, it was your fault.
Scott: Yeah, but it might split into, you know.
Rym: Yeah, but you might, there's all these, it's a snowball game.
Scott: If you make any mistake whatsoever, right, and the thing is, you know, I made a mistake of a beginner who didn't know the game early, right, you know, and early is, I guess, the worst time to make a mistake, but you can make a mistake in this game at any time.
Scott: You could be really good at this game, right, not, obviously, if you're incredible at the game, you're not gonna ever make a mistake, right, but you could be in a situation where like, you're good at the game, you understand it, but say midway through the game, like, after hour one, you make a mistake, and now you're just fucked, but you already invested an hour in the game, but you can't win, but you still have to keep playing, and it's not over.
Rym: Now, Power Grid, base Power Grid is an example of a game where if you, like, if you play the game a lot, and it's a bunch of skilled fucking players playing that game, it ends up being the same way, like, if Scott has three extra dollars left over at the end of a round, he fucked up and didn't optimize for the last five turns, and like, that's the fiddly tiny decision that means he loses.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: But that only happens after you've gotten to the point where you're all playing this game at like, ultra-pro mode.
Rym: In this game, that happens immediately.
Rym: So if I had to describe what this game is really like, and who it would appeal to, if you like Twilight Struggle, you like this game.
Rym: Because they are games where you have to commit to being very good at the game, and navigating the simple, because they're not complex, but highly divergent heuristics of the game.
Rym: They are not intuitive, you cannot play this game by gut.
Rym: It's like the difference between chess and Go.
Rym: If you just kind of feel your way through chess, You're gonna lose.
Rym: You're gonna lose, but you'll do okay.
Rym: Like, if you know the rules, and you have some basic knowledge of chess, and you watch the people play.
Scott: Yeah, you'll try to take more guys than the other guy takes, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But if you play the chess in the long, long run, the attractors in chess are slow defeat, or else a draw.
Rym: In Go, the attractors, as the game tree expands out into the void, are all losing.
Rym: If you go in semi-random directions, you just lose.
Scott: Yeah, and it's not like in Netrunner, this happens a lot too, where there's certain types of play, certain lines of play that your opponent can have, and it's like, "Okay, I see that I'm losing this game, but I'm still doing stuff,
Scott: right?".
Scott: It's like, you know, "I still got stuff going
Scott: on.".
Scott: You know, like in Rare or Tycoon, this is a big thing that happens, right?
Scott: Where it's like, "Okay, I see I've lost the game, but I'm still moving cubes, and I'm still building tracks, and I'm still putting trains and playing cards, so I'm still enjoying myself and doing things, even though I know the best I can do now is second place, because look what that guy did moving 10 cubes or something,
Scott: right?".
Scott: There's certain things that happen, and in this game, where it's like, not only did I know I was going to lose the game after making a one mistake on turn two, but I pretty much couldn't do anything effective.
Scott: I couldn't sell even one food, right?
Scott: It's like, I literally could not do anything meaningful on my turns anymore.
Scott: If I played the best I could play.
Scott: from that point on, it's like, literally, I've done nothing.
Scott: I've made no money.
Scott: I can't get any more stuff.
Scott: I can't do anything.
Scott: I'm just, like, locked, and I'm not even, even if I continue to play and try and enjoy it, it's like, I can't build trains or put cubes.
Scott: I'm just sitting here doing nothing, making meaningless decisions.
Scott: I can't move.
Rym: Now, I'm going to say something.
Rym: This is a good game.
Rym: It is a well-designed game.
Rym: But, and Twilight Struggle is a well-designed game for what it is, those kinds of games.
Rym: But, this is the kind of game that, because of these complex heuristics, well, not complex, because of these simple, but surprisingly divergent heuristics, and because of the harsh penalties for failure, and because all of the attractors in the game tree are ridiculous failure, the only way to enjoy this game, you have to be the kind of person who wants to pick a game like this, play it a million, million times, and become very good at this particular game.
Rym: If you are good at games in general, that will give you almost no assistance in being good at this game, unless you do what I was doing until Scott and Chris and Anthony yelled at me to stop.
Rym: This game also can suffer from extreme analysis paralysis.
Rym: I could have navigated that heuristic tree by sitting there for literally five or ten minutes of my turn.
Scott: You did take a fucking long time on your turn.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what?
Rym: I did better than you.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I'm not going to put in that kind of effort, especially if I'm convention, right?
Scott: I'm not looking to, you know, right?
Rym: But I'm saying this game, the only way to be good at this game is to play it a lot, to be good at it, or to study it and do a lot of analysis and calculation, slowing the game down, which explains why they say the game takes two to four hours to play.
Rym: Much like Twilight Struggle, you have to play it and be good at it, because it has a whole bunch of name cards that do very specific things, and the game's only interesting if you know what all those cards are and what they do, and your opponent also knows what they all are and knows what they do, or if neither of you knows.
Rym: So you can only play this game...
Scott: Yeah, if you play this with a bunch of people who've never played it before, you could all make mistakes and still maybe not have a problem because you all made mistakes.
Rym: But then you still have to force people to not spend a long time on their turn, because if someone does think longer, it's like a choir.
Rym: If you actually calculate out, you could play this game very well the first time, and it's going to take the full four hours to play the game.
Scott: And this game has another problem, which is one I've noticed in a lot of games before, one that always comes to mind when I think about this is Quarriers, which is the dice dominion.
Rym: Oh, that game feels like it should be so good, but it's not.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that problem is basically big stuff never used, right?
Scott: So it's like, there's these huge cards you can get if you upgrade all the way, like these ridiculous employees, like the CEOs and stuff, like these ridiculously powerful cards.
Scott: And from what I could tell is if you were to play this game to completion, right, you would maybe get one of those cards like on the final turn or second to last turn, maybe maybe you would get one of them and maybe use it like once and the game would be over at that point, right?
Scott: It's like in Quarriers, you get like one fancy, super powerful dice and maybe roll it once and the game will be over by that point.
Scott: It's like, dudes, if you're designing a game and you got big, powerful stuff in that game, at least let people use it.
Rym: Like in Civ 5, at least let me use the death robot for like 10 turns.
Scott: Hearthstone is actually a good example.
Scott: It's like in Hearthstone, you can play and put out big, amazing legendary creatures and actually use them a bit before the game ends, right?
Scott: You can actually, you know, get to use the heavy hitters and enjoy the fun of using them.
Rym: As opposed to Magic the Gathering, where if you got one of those like legends golden dragons of three colors out on the table, like good job.
Rym: Good job getting that dragon out there.
Scott: And then, yeah, you've probably lost the game before that happened.
Rym: Or you won a long time ago.
Scott: It's gonna die instantly.
Scott: You know, yeah, you've already won and you're just playing that because you've already, you know, because you can, because you're already controlling the game, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, it's like if you, the top level equipment in your, whatever game you make, right?
Scott: The top level, most powerful stuff, right?
Scott: The big buildings in Puerto Rico, right?
Scott: You know, whatever is the biggest, strongest stuff should be able to come into play, say, between 75 and 80% of the game's completion, right?
Scott: And then after that, there might be bigger stuff, but that stuff should be victory points only.
Scott: It shouldn't do anything.
Rym: And that way, you don't feel bad.
Rym: You didn't get to do it.
Scott: You buy a big building in Puerto Rico, all it does is give you points.
Scott: It's like it's not a big, you know, but you get a university, which is like the biggest building that can do something.
Scott: And you'll get, you can get that and use it.
Scott: You can get the wharf in Puerto Rico and use it.
Scott: You can get it, you know, 50, 60% of the way into the game.
Rym: Well, that little machine game we were playing, the game where you pump stuff through your factories.
Rym: The card game.
Rym: You played it at PAX.
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: You bought it, or I bought it, one of us bought it.
Scott: Oh, um, oh my goods.
Rym: Yes, that game has a good mechanic where when the game ends, you know, you've built your machine of like all your different buildings out there doing shit.
Rym: At the end of the game, you get to crank your whole machine a bunch of times.
Rym: So you've built the crazy building at the end, you get to use it like multiple times at the end of the game, rewarding you for having it.
Rym: Like, there's ways to get around that problem.
Scott: Whenever the biggest, the biggest, funnest, most awesome, powerful thing there is in your game, players should be able to get that thing, if they play well, obviously, right, with at least 20% of the game remaining, so that they can actually use it a bit and have a bunch of fun with it, and then the game should end.
Scott: not, you know, you don't want to give it to them too early.
Scott: If you get that stuff halfway through the game, then it's like, oh my god, why isn't it over yet, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But like, with 20% or less of the game remaining, you should be able to get the biggest, strongest, most fun thing, and use it three, two to four times.
Scott: Get some uses out of it as the finishing blow.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right?
Scott: That, you know, this game, it's like, you could never get the most powerful level stuff.
Scott: You know what they could have done to make that better?
Scott: Just remove that top level of powerful stuff.
Scott: Just not have it in the game, and that way, the funnest, most powerful stuff is stuff that's, you know, gettable, right?
Scott: It's like, just cut away your top level, and now make the second to top level the top level, and that will now become, simply because it's at the top of your tech tree, like, you play Civ V, you can't actually get and use XCOM dudes, right?
Rym: I have used them in long wars.
Scott: Only if you continue after the game ends.
Scott: No!
Rym: I've used them in long wars to win the game.
Scott: I've never gotten XCOM dudes before the timer was up.
Scott: I have, Scott,
Rym: I had a fleet once of a bunch of XCOM dudes, and not one, but two giant death robots, and I used those to take out a bunch of cities from a civilization that was close to a culture victory so that I could then get a science victory.
Scott: Well, obviously you were having a science victory already.
Rym: The thing is, I could have just taken out his capital and had the domination victory, but I was sick of always getting domination victory.
Scott: Right, but I mean, you know, whatever your top level of stuff is should come into play before the end of the game.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, I mean, we didn't play the game enough to give you, like, a deeper review than that, but suffice it to say...
Scott: Unless you like being punished, right?
Scott: Don't play this.
Rym: Or, if you like games like Twilight Struggle, that are serious, luck-free, long...
Scott: Twilight Struggle has some luck.
Rym: Yeah, but heavy analysis requires significant investment in that specific game, as opposed to games in general.
Rym: I can think of a lot of kinds of people who would really like this game.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: I am not one of those people.
Scott: No.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: The Patrons for this episode of GeekNights who are paying at least $5 a month in order of the amount of money they give us on a continuing basis are Finn, Eric, Silveron, and the Infinite Sadness, Kinetic Man, Aaron, Cerise, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, A Red Lion, Sam Corddry, Daniel Redman, Chris Hadad, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: I know we had a long outage between PAX and me having the flu, and then me being in Hong Kong and Australia.
Rym: I recorded a bunch of Rym's Rants, but I didn't have any bandwidth in Australia, and Patreon doesn't work so well in Australia.
Rym: So I'm going to be uploading those over the course of the next couple weeks.
Rym: You'll also get the March, or the April Q&A from me and Scott.
Rym: The May one is still taking questions for another week and a half or so.
Rym: And remember, the theme for May is something Scott will hate.
Rym: It's politics.
Rym: But we're back for bed, and now I leave you with something weird.
Rym: - My ding-a-ling!
Scott: - This act is over!