Rym: It's Tuesday, December 20th, 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we're talking about Doom.
Scott: 2016 Doom.
Rym: A new one.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, yeah.
Rym: I bought the new gaming PC.
Rym: I'm literally recording GeekNights on it now.
Rym: And my record of, since I switched to Intel chips, posting successfully the first time I touched the power button?
Scott: Yeah, you know, I think, you know, we were talking, I think, before about how right now is sort of a time to buy the PC.
Scott: because in the one hand, you know, the 1080 is a good time to buy that because it's so new.
Scott: And I know there's 1080 TI rumors, but the processor I bought now is the same processor.
Scott: I would have bought like a year ago, the same price, but I'm beginning to think maybe it is a good time because even though the CPU feels so old, like why are you buying the CPU now?
Scott: That's already so old.
Rym: They ain't going to get faster.
Scott: Is it so stably right now?
Scott: The, I, you know, I put an i5 in my HD PC with a 1070, the new one, and that's like, so spice.
Scott: It's like the most stably PC, you know, I'm mispronouncing stable on purpose and not the horse kind.
Scott: That's the most stable PC since I've had since the Pentium 3, not even counting the AMD ones, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And my current desktop that has like, is, you know, mad blue screening, which I think is because of the motherboard.
Rym: That has to be the motherboard.
Rym: That is, that is what caused my previous computer that replaced the one I just replaced.
Scott: So two years ago, I'm sticking with my next time for now and for the foreseeable future, right?
Scott: No more gigabyte motherboards, aces only.
Scott: I don't care if it costs more money, aces only.
Rym: I was going to get the aces 1080.
Scott: You think it's just brand loyalty.
Scott: Brands don't mean anything, right?
Scott: I don't care about brands on clothing and I don't care about the brand on the computer.
Scott: I need to show off the fact that it's aces or whatever.
Scott: It's just, I have had in my history of life when buying a bit and aces motherboards as a bit even still around.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Well, a bit used to be, so in the old days, well, the old days in like the AMD case, seven days, aces and a bit were pretty equivalent.
Rym: I think it's dead now, but it used to be better in terms of a bits would have like more USB headers, like more shit you could do on the motherboard, like raid built in and all this like overclocking nonsense.
Scott: But they were less stable point is over the course of like 20 years of my life.
Scott: Yeah, aces.
Scott: Mobos have never had any problems that I have bought.
Scott: I'm sure other people can disagree.
Scott: Just like I got some brand loyalty with Seagate, even though now Samsung is now the king of storage.
Scott: I'm talking about spinning magnet, spinning magnet disk.
Rym: You know what's fucked up if you went to Rym 10, 20 years ago and you were like, yo dog, check out this Western digital hard drive.
Scott: Get that not see shit in my face nowadays.
Rym: Actually, if you want a spinning disk, Western digital is really falling off the boat.
Rym: Get the Western digital black.
Rym: Holy shit.
Rym: Are those things fast?
Scott: Those cost more monies, though.
Rym: It's worth it.
Rym: So when I'm rocking in this thing, I'm going to post the exact, you know, I don't care about the speed of my magnet disk.
Rym: I do because, uh, because that's the raid.
Rym: So I have two Western digital black five terabyte drives in a raid.
Scott: One is such a bad number.
Rym: Yeah, I think it's fine.
Scott: Just, you know what I would do make four terabyte partitions on them and throw away that extra terabyte just because it feels weird.
Scott: So you could have a nice, but you're okay with six, six gigabyte.
Rym: Why is that?
Rym: Okay.
Scott: It's even, but it's not, it's not great, but at least it's not five.
Rym: I have 10 terabytes.
Rym: That's even.
Rym: No, it's not.
Rym: I just split it in two, rated it.
Rym: But, uh, when I'm recording, like Sam capturing video or like capturing, I like to capture directly to the raid.
Rym: because if anything goes wrong, now instead of like, if something crazy happens, then I like lose something.
Rym: I'm not losing shit with the raid.
Rym: It's a good feeling and all my media is there.
Rym: So I have this workflow now where I can put out, like if I'm editing 4k video, I can save it just to the raid.
Rym: So it's safe before I, you know, cause I got to back it up to the cloud or whatever.
Rym: Anyway, it was like $200 more total to have 10 terabytes of black instead of 10 terabytes.
Scott: Point is brand sometimes means something.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Sometimes.
Rym: But, uh, the other thing is that if I'd bought the computer a year ago, I would add the exact same processor I have now.
Rym: But motherboards got a lot better in the last year.
Rym: Like now you can get like six USB threes and a USB three one if you want it.
Scott: They've been revising the same motherboard layout for a long time.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Like the previous version of my motherboard, the PR version is great.
Rym: They are a version.
Rym: The only difference I can see is it's got some bullshit like bling LEDs on it that you can't really turn on.
Scott: That's what the aura means is that the LEDs change color and you can customize the color.
Rym: There's a couple other minor differences in the layout and you get, generally you get more USBs and that kind of stuff.
Rym: And the reviews, the eggs are better, way fewer RMAs cause.
Rym: it's like an incremental improvement.
Scott: Why did you put your computer under your feet and not in the computer hole?
Rym: So there's a lot of reasons for that, but mostly because I'm actually going to put another hard drive in early next year.
Rym: And I can just slide it in without having to unplug all the shit.
Rym: early next year is really soon because I ordered the Samsung nine 60 like M dot two crazy drive.
Rym: And the motherfuckers I ordered from sent me a nine 50 like I wouldn't notice.
Rym: So they're going to be a full refund because I was like, send me the nine 60. there were like, we don't have any nine sixties.
Scott: That's what I ordered.
Scott: But the, oh, it is the deal.
Rym: The, uh, the story with these SSDs right now is that the Samsung nine 60 pros are out in a five 12 gigabyte configuration for like 350 bucks.
Rym: That's insane.
Rym: But the five 12 in these nine 50 era was the like top tier in the nine 60 era.
Rym: It's the minimum and the one terabyte and two terabyte ones perform way better.
Rym: for reasons I don't want to get into right now.
Rym: That's more of a Monday time.
Scott: Whatever's game time.
Rym: So if you're going to be really gaming computer guys, wait until like February and you can buy a one terabyte crazy as fast M dot two SSD for your games for like 500, 600 bucks.
Rym: That's not overkill necessarily, but it's, it's not crazy.
Rym: It's just excessive.
Rym: So anyway, is there any news other than Mario runner?
Scott: No, it's the only game news.
Scott: Even if you go to a gaming news site, it's like the only thing that's on there.
Rym: Super Mario run is kind of a big deal for a lot of reasons because you know, me Tomo and all those things came out.
Rym: Have any of you launched me Tomo in the last four months?
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: I mean, maybe I don't remember what the day I stopped using it was.
Scott: It could have been four months, less than four months ago.
Rym: I actually uninstalled it a couple of weeks ago.
Scott: Do I still have it installed?
Scott: Nope.
Rym: Cause I was, I was, I was messing with some stuff in the app store and I was like, Oh right.
Rym: Me Tomo.
Rym: Haha.
Rym: And I installed it.
Rym: That was fun.
Scott: It's not installed right now.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Mario run is.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But that was a big deal because it was like Nintendo made a good app on a phone because Nintendo has always been kind of bad about using the world, the ecosystem of phone hardware.
Scott: Well, they just didn't want, you know, Nintendo is like, we make the games, you know, and we want to sell these hardwares and the games.
Scott: so that, you know, we're all, we're Nintendo.
Scott: You know, that's how we do.
Scott: That's all we've always done.
Scott: And we're mad stubborn in Japanese or the most Japanese and the most stubborn and they're still the most stubborn.
Scott: And even when they give a little bit, they don't give in all the way.
Scott: They just give in a little tiny bit.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: And, but they released, you know, the thing is surprisingly, and Miyamoto said this also, it was like Nintendo and Apple kind of similar keeping secrets, making their own hardware, being really controlling, polishing everything until it's the shiniest.
Scott: You know, being late to the party.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Right.
Rym: You know, sometimes being late to the party makes you the life of the party.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: But sometimes.
Scott: The point is Apple and Nintendo, it was obvious to everyone, get along really well.
Scott: Even Apple and Nintendo know this.
Scott: So they put out a real Mario game for iPhone, iPad.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's not like Pokemon go.
Rym: That's like kind of a bullshitty AR version of Pokemon.
Scott: This is an actual real like, no, you can't say, you know, even if you're one of those pet ants, like.
Scott: this is not a game.
Scott: It is a real video game.
Scott: that is a platforming game and requires skills.
Rym: Had this been released for like the Game Boy.
Scott: And is difficult.
Rym: It would have been fine.
Rym: Like I would have said great and probably bought it.
Scott: Uh, this is the game.
Scott: For 10 bucks?
Scott: Yeah, it would have to be a $10 like DS download game or something.
Rym: I would pay 10 bucks to play this on my DS.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: Like just if it didn't come out on mobile and they were like, Hey, here's a game we made.
Rym: And I would be like, sure, because the game design of this thing actually pretty slick and clever.
Rym: Like this game is not the simple like baby game you expect.
Scott: I mean, all you're doing literally is you have one control, which is tap the screen anywhere.
Scott: And if you tap Mario jumps, if he's already in the air, he does a little spin and slows down for a little bit.
Scott: And you know, it's, it's basically depending on the context of where Mario is on the screen, your tap does something different and you need to tap rapidly sometimes, but mostly with extreme precision timing to get Mario to do the things you want him to do.
Scott: And if, you know, mostly you just want to get Mario to the end of the level, which is ridiculously easy.
Scott: You only have to jump over the holes.
Scott: The bad guys really have a hard time hitting you unless it's like bullet bill or something.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Or is like you could run right up to a goomba and Mario will just like vault over it and keep walking.
Scott: If you don't touch jack shit, it's really hard to die.
Scott: Sometimes you want to die because that's the only way to go backwards and you can't like this.
Scott: No, I'm like, please let there be a piranha plant for me to run into and there isn't.
Scott: and this right because I want it.
Scott: There's no way to go backwards.
Scott: Mario just keeps running to the right almost no matter what.
Scott: So, you know, it's, it's quite difficult.
Scott: It just, you know, if you want to start doing fancy stuff like you'll see there's an obvious, you know, different path if you go up, but going up requires like three precision wall jumps and then like a precision jump off a bad guy and then another precision job of bad guy and then you can reach those clouds and get a bunch of bonus coins and it's like, all right, let's try to do that.
Scott: and a normal Mario game.
Scott: You try to do that and you would fail and you try again and you get it in this.
Scott: You fail and then Mario keeps running to the right.
Scott: It's like, fuck you.
Scott: You don't get a second shot.
Scott: You got one shot.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: Now keep going, Mario.
Scott: You got to restore.
Scott: You want to try again.
Scott: You want to restart the goddamn level.
Scott: It's like, it's like, it's actually hard.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Now there's some fascinating circumstances around this game.
Rym: So one, the game, and I'm not going to speculate specifically as to why, but it just so happens that right after the game was announced, it was launched and went live.
Rym: Nintendo stock basically collapsed like down 15% since December 12.
Scott: I don't know why people are buying and selling that much stock based on one mobile video game.
Rym: I'm not going to necessarily speculate as to whether or not that is the specific cause here, but a lot of people seem to be hinting at the fact that the fact that this game is very poorly rated is a factor because a lot of people might've been looking at this game and deciding that it's a bellwether and whether or not Nintendo is capable of existing in the modern phone app ecosystem and whether or not their ultra premium model, which that's the second part of this.
Rym: The fact that this is considered ultra premium was viable because Nintendo charges 10 bucks for this game.
Scott: Well, I think their mistake, right?
Scott: It was sort of a tough decision, right?
Scott: So obviously apple promoted them.
Scott: Apple and Nintendo both promoted this thing like crazy.
Scott: It's a big deal, right?
Scott: And if Nintendo is going to finally make a real game, that's mobile on someone else's platform.
Scott: It better do well.
Scott: or Nintendo's being like, well, that didn't work.
Scott: Fuck that noise.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, you know, apple did their best to make it do well because look, apple makes a big cut.
Scott: They wanted to sell a ton too.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you know, if Nintendo is going to make a lot more games for iOS, that would help apple out a ton.
Scott: Uh, so anyway, so what they did is they needed it to have a big lot of sales and downloads to get it up in the charts.
Scott: because if they do it and it doesn't go up in the charts, well, it looks like a failure.
Scott: So they made it free, but only world one is free.
Scott: World one, one, one, two, one, three, and one, four.
Scott: after world one, four, you got to pay 10 bucks.
Scott: So a lot of people downloaded it and then they were said 10 bucks.
Scott: That's a lot of money for compared to most of the games, not just a lot of money.
Rym: The average.
Rym: So this is where things get interesting in the mobile ecosystem.
Rym: Like two 99 is considered premium.
Scott: It's funny that people will like play hearthstone and buy $70 worth of packs of cards.
Rym: I know humans who have put hundreds of dollars into hearthstone, right?
Rym: There are people out there like, you know who you are, you, you, who I was talking to on Google about this like two days ago, not spend that much money on hearthstone.
Scott: I know it's good, but Jesus son, well, I mean, even the thing is hearthstone, even spending hundreds, it's cheaper than magic.
Scott: It's actually cheap as far as collectible games go.
Scott: But but anyway, yeah, there are two fundamental care people spending more money on free games for bonus shit than they're spending on Mario.
Scott: But then they're complaining that Mario is 10 bucks.
Scott: because psychologically you got this game for free and they got paid 10 bucks.
Scott: just made it 10 bucks up front.
Scott: Like if you want to play, you got to pay 10 bucks.
Scott: if nobody, the sales would have been low.
Scott: It wouldn't have gone up.
Rym: in the itunes top problem is that freedom.
Rym: So it's two, two problems.
Rym: One is now you've got this clash of worlds between, you
Scott: also got people who don't got 10 bucks as their kids, but
Rym: gamer people who would self describe as gamers who know about games in a general sense and have a vague basic understanding of the broad ecosystem of gaming as a whole.
Rym: And then you've got the masses, the smart, the app market on phones is pretty much the masses.
Rym: And the well for the masses has been poisoned by free to play.
Rym: The average person who is not a gamer, when you ask about games, they think about games on their phone and they assume that those games are all free.
Rym: That is it.
Rym: That is the ecosystem.
Rym: Getting them to pay more than zero is already a big ask.
Rym: And then they download the game that's top of the promotions like, oh, all right, some Mario game.
Rym: I've heard of Mario and they play it and it's fun.
Rym: And then it has for that $10 that is literally insane to them.
Rym: Like that is fucking nuts.
Rym: And they're pissed and they're reading the game one star.
Rym: And as a result, the game has 60,000 ratings as of Dateline, uh, 6 34 PM, December 20th.
Rym: And its average score is 2.5 and a five star rating system that is effectively zero.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: I mean, it's people giving a five stars cause they paid the 10 bucks, didn't care about paying 10 bucks.
Rym: Well, the five star people are the people who expected this to be an interesting Mario game and saw that $10 is pretty cheap for a real game.
Rym: I mean, it's the cheapest Mario game has ever been, but normal people who don't know about games, give it one star because what the fuck is this bullshit?
Rym: $10 WTF made, right?
Scott: They're not judging the game.
Scott: They're judging the $10, you know, for any iPhone game ever.
Scott: It also wants to get, you could make fucking like final fantasy.
Scott: What's the new one?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: You can make final fantasy 16 the whole game, the whole game, iPhone only exclusive, I iOS exclusive and charge 10 bucks for it and, but it's a full final fantasy, just as big as final fantasy 16 should be or will be when it comes out.
Scott: Cause it's definitely going to come out at some point, right?
Scott: For years.
Scott: Uh, and people would be like 10 bucks, what the fuck is this shit?
Scott: But the same game on PS four people be like game of years, $70.
Scott: don't give a fuck.
Rym: Now that also is interesting cause this gives us some data we never really had before.
Rym: The reviews are pretty much all one star or five star.
Scott: There's almost nothing in the middle, which there aren't a lot of one star reviews that say paid 10 bucks.
Scott: Don't like this game.
Scott: It's shitty.
Scott: Right?
Scott: However, there is a part of the game that is not so great, right?
Scott: So the good part of the game, at least as far as I'm concerned is the main solo part of the game.
Scott: You play these, it's got like six worlds of four levels each, right?
Scott: And in each world, you know, it's a little short levels, but the levels, each level has replayability times three because not only getting to the end of the level is a cake walk.
Scott: It's automatically running you there with very little things that will actually kill you and you can come back to life a bunch of times and it's, it's not difficult, right?
Scott: I beat the game like on my first shot, just like straight through, but in each level there's five coins to get and you got to get all five coins in one.
Scott: go for it to count.
Scott: So you get all the pink coins, then the level changes and now you get all the purple coins.
Scott: And then when you get all the purple coins in one shot, the level changes and there's the five black coins.
Scott: Fuck the five black coins.
Scott: Not to be racist against those coins because it's not the color that's the problem.
Scott: It is their location.
Scott: The level changes in a very devious fashion.
Scott: You think really how devious could it be a game where you only have to push a, you don't even got to push.
Rym: I was looking at some youtube videos and you're like, like it's a spot that you wouldn't even can.
Scott: I was able to get all five black coins in world one, one and world one, two and in world one dash three, there's some coins I'm seeing and I'm like, how the fuck do you get?
Scott: Like how do you even, and you to make it even worse, like I could maybe get up there if it was a regular Mario game and I could go backwards.
Scott: You can't go backwards.
Scott: You got one shot at each coin.
Scott: You miss it.
Scott: Restart the whole goddamn level.
Scott: Oh, I missed the first coin.
Scott: Well, it doesn't matter.
Scott: Restart the whole level.
Scott: Oh, you missed the fifth coin.
Scott: Restart again.
Scott: Go back and get the first guy.
Scott: And he's just like, you know, but that's the good part of the game.
Scott: The not so good part of the game is the mobile ish type part of the game where you get toads and coins to build your town like a kind of thing.
Scott: And basically this is toad rallies.
Scott: You get toad rally tickets to go in the toad rally and it basically makes you play a level and you're playing the level against someone else's ghost of that level, like sort of like Mario Kart.
Scott: There's a little like paper Mario that does the level in their place and you got to do the level better than they did it, which means getting more coins and more points, which means doing more fancy moves.
Scott: You do more fancy moves, you get coin rush, you get more coins, you get more points.
Scott: And if you do the level better than the person you chose to go against, you take some of their toads and you get more toads.
Scott: But if they do the level, if you don't do the level better than them, you lose toads and you try and just increase your total toad army to level up your town and also get coins to buy shit for your town.
Scott: And it's sort of love it or hate it kind of thing.
Rym: I see most people seem to love it, which is interesting.
Scott: It's kind of fun to do a toad rally kind of, but not as fun as trying to get all five coins and mastering the levels.
Scott: But I really don't give a shit about what my mushroom kingdom looks like.
Rym: So the five stars are basically the pool of people who are actually gamers who play games on their phones.
Rym: The pool of one stars are normal people who have heard of Mario and are pissed off that they have to pay any amount of money.
Scott: Mario is like, you know, the Mercedes of games.
Scott: You ain't going to give me for free.
Rym: So what, pray tell, is in the two, three, four reviews?
Rym: And there aren't that many.
Rym: So I poked around in them.
Rym: And what I learned is that the two reviews are mostly.
Rym: the game requires an Internet connection 100 percent of the time or it stops working.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: You can't actually play it on the go on the first.
Scott: Originally, I'm like, man, that sucks.
Scott: I would really like to play this game on the subway, but it's a good game, so I'll play it anyway.
Scott: But yeah, that's bullshit.
Scott: You should let me play on the subway.
Rym: That is insane.
Rym: Literally no game I own.
Rym: I have a lot of games on my phone won't work if I'm underground, however, or especially the solo part of the game, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: However, I realized a subway is kind of shaky.
Scott: You can't.
Scott: It's not good to play a game that even on my 3DS sitting on the subway, I can't play games that are like real time action because it's fucking shaking.
Scott: Well, dude, I remember I need absolute stillness and stability.
Rym: I was remastering those beta episodes of GeekNights in 2005 for the Patreon and one of them you're talking about playing the surgeon game on the DS and how you can't play it on the train.
Rym: You'll just kill it.
Rym: There's no way.
Scott: So I guess that's not an old van Scott problem.
Scott: That's also, you know, young Scott problem.
Rym: But here's all the problems.
Rym: Like I couldn't play it in the bathroom at work because there's just no data in there.
Scott: See, that's bull.
Scott: That's a problem.
Rym: I couldn't play it at PAX.
Rym: Like most taxes.
Rym: You can't get internet.
Rym: Like it just doesn't work.
Scott: The thing is you just need barely enough internet rather give any data at all.
Scott: It's going to work.
Scott: You don't need like real data.
Rym: You know, I can watch a Netflix movie with no internet on my phone now and yet I can't play Super Mario run.
Rym: That just seems.
Scott: Nintendo is, you know, that's who they are, but it still has friend codes and bullshit.
Scott: It doesn't just let you use game center or whatever.
Rym: And it seems like all the two and three star reviews are those kinds of complaints.
Scott: Like the complaints about the middling bits, right?
Scott: Like someone like a four star review might be someone who likes the game, didn't care about spending 10 bucks, but really doesn't like the toad rally, right?
Scott: Whereas I look at it and say, well, I don't like the toad rally part either, but they're being extra crap attached to a good game.
Scott: Doesn't diminish the good game.
Scott: That's already there.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Unless it gets in your way, right?
Scott: It's like if I buy Puerto Rico, the best board game there is, and there's 10 garbage expansions in the box and I just throw those out and the rest of the game is still good.
Scott: That doesn't make the existing Puerto Rico worse.
Rym: But imagine if the expansions were printed on the board and like you had to like ignore them, but they were always there in your way.
Scott: Toad rally's not in your way.
Scott: Just don't touch toad rally.
Scott: It's one button.
Scott: Don't touch it.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Scott: I got so many things of the day.
Scott: Which one shall I use?
Scott: This great bounty.
Scott: I
Rym: also have many partly because, well, lot of reasons partly because I also rebuilt the HTPC by cascading parts down and now it's running on an SSD and I was like watching a lot of YouTube videos and there's a bunch of stuff in the living room and I found this just pretty funny little comedy bit.
Rym: It's short and it's about, it's the, the workers and sieve and one of them is a worker from like sieve two, three, four and the sieve six guy is explaining to him how his job is different now and it was actually pretty funny.
Rym: Like it has a pretty good payoff.
Rym: It was good.
Rym: It's short.
Scott: All right, so this guy in the Netherlands, a good land.
Scott: It's in the nether places.
Rym: I got good stuff in my nether places.
Scott: He, his phone got stolen and he realized like, oh man, shit, if your phone is stolen, that's like the worst.
Scott: I guess he didn't realize that before his phone was stolen.
Scott: So then he got a new phone and on that new phone, he put spyware, the kind that lets you completely control the phone from anywhere as long as the phone has internets.
Scott: And then he let this new phone get stole on purpose.
Rym: That ain't bad.
Rym: He just like got it hanging like out of his pocket, got the phone stolen on purpose somehow.
Scott: And now he took the footage that was recorded from the spyware on that phone that he collected as much as he could and created this 20 plus minute long short film of the journey of the stolen phone.
Scott: It's a short film known as find my phone.
Scott: It is a good film.
Rym: Good stuff.
Rym: In the meta moment, the booklet book is Rebecca.
Rym: Rebecca.
Rym: Sounds like you're reading it, so I'm going to start reading it in earnest and finish it pretty quick.
Scott: I'm reading it quite a, you know, the timer on the Kindle says a number of hours and then it seems to that time it reports goes down faster than the actual clock does like.
Scott: I'll be reading it and I'll be reading it for 15 minutes.
Scott: But the estimated time to finishing went down by like an hour.
Scott: And it's like, OK, I guess you're really bad at estimating.
Scott: I'm going to finish this when I don't know.
Rym: Otherwise, we're going to be at Magfest doing six panels across four days of Magfest.
Rym: Oh, it's coming.
Rym: I'm feeling Magfest real hard.
Scott: Like I only have one and a half more days of work.
Rym: All right.
Scott: In 2016.
Scott: And then, you know, how many days of work I have before Magfest, zero, three and a half more days of work because I go back to work on like the Tuesday and then work on a Wednesday and then a Magfest on a Thursday.
Rym: Like Pax is super fun, but I go to between three and five Pax's a year.
Scott: So there's only one Magfest.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like Pax I'm excited about.
Rym: But but like right after Pax Prime, I'm not like, oh, man, I got to wait another year for this.
Rym: Like, oh, there's another Pax coming.
Rym: Like pretty soon, actually.
Rym: Pax out.
Scott: Let's go after Magfest is over.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Pax out.
Rym: Pax out is like right there.
Rym: So right after Magfest, we're going to Pax out.
Scott: And if you want to enforce it, Pax East.
Scott: If you are a previous Pax East enforcer, do stuff.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Stuff's happening.
Scott: Stuff is now.
Rym: Do your stuff.
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Rym: Otherwise, the Patreon for Geek Knights is going strong and I'm uploading more and more content.
Rym: I think Emily and I will be reviewing the new Doctor Strange movie pretty soon because actually Emily read all the Doctor Strange comics a long time ago and I never did.
Rym: So we had different perspectives on the movie, which is interesting.
Scott: You and me.
Scott: There's there are many various different Doctor Strange comics.
Rym: I feel like everyone, cause I haven't read any of them.
Scott: There's so many different ones.
Scott: is like, you know, you could almost like if you read some new ones and someone else read some old ones and someone else read some like nineties ones, but it's like everyone would think something different about, you know, Doctor Strange.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Like who he is.
Rym: So all that aside, Scott a while ago played the new 2016 doom and he told me I should play it.
Rym: I installed it on my previous computer and it was not a good enough experience to where I would be willing to play it all the way through the 770 and the Nehalem, uh, I seven and the 12 gigabytes of Ram.
Rym: Not enough.
Scott: I played it on my six 80 and originally it was running just fine.
Scott: I mean like it wasn't beautiful and amazing.
Scott: It was just, it was plenty good, uh, but it was crashy a bit and I thought this was related to the blue screens.
Scott: I mean I busted computer, but actually apparently it was cause of this crappy DRM that they included in it and that DRM in a patch that came out after I beat the game has been removed, but I was able to reduce the crashiness quite a bit also by lowering the settings.
Scott: So I use the settings suggested by the G force experience and not the settings suggested by the
Rym: G force experience on my seven 70, which is a way better is well faster than your six 80 and a lot of ways that are relevant for gaming, but my motherboards old.
Rym: So the seven 70 wasn't running at full potential.
Rym: So it's kind of like a wash game.
Rym: didn't look that great.
Scott: Like it was playable, but I mean I had it on low, I originally had it on the medium settings that were suggested and it looked just fine on the low settings.
Scott: It also looked just fine.
Scott: It wasn't like back in the day where you turn the settings down in tribes too and everything's just like gray rectangles on the new computer.
Rym: cause I got the 10 80, uh, I sure it looks better to the absolute 100% maximum like crazy.
Rym: Like I turned on the shit that you would not turn on on a 10 70.
Rym: Holy shit, does it look different and locked 60 FPS the entire time.
Rym: It is beautiful.
Rym: Even Emily, like I'm playing the game and even in the right in the beginning, you know when you're like inside the UAC facility,
Scott: the triple a game is new
Rym: and then you see that door and you can go outside and you see like the orange Mad Max dystopia of Mars out there.
Rym: You walk out.
Rym: Emily was standing behind me and she was like, holy shit, it looks great by the 10 80 guys like Jesus.
Rym: Oh my God.
Scott: Or I mean the other thing, right, is like, uh, it looks great, but I'm still the same mind I was in.
Scott: like the nineties where it's like, I don't care about graphics that much.
Scott: I care about the game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The game's just as good on the seven seventies.
Scott: You don't even notice the graphics while you're playing, right?
Rym: But the thing is when I was playing with the 10 80, like when I played that great, are they $600?
Scott: Great.
Scott: Is that really worth $600?
Rym: Well, here's the thing.
Scott: You can play the game with a video card that costs half as much.
Rym: It's not just that it looks crazy great.
Scott: Like you could get the 10 70 if you're, you can play this thing with like a nine something just fine.
Rym: Maybe like a nine 79 80.
Scott: Yeah, sure.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: You might get occasional frame dips unless you turn stuff down.
Scott: Oh no.
Rym: I, because I've been playing a lot of like semi serious FPS is again, frame dips are.
Rym: I will not tolerate a frame dip.
Rym: Like I cannot play with frame dips anymore.
Rym: Like I will turn down everything.
Rym: It will be gray models with no lighting in the background before I will take a frame dip.
Scott: And I was mostly just upset about crashing.
Scott: It wasn't crashing.
Scott: I was just, I was fine at 30 FPS.
Rym: So it was crashing until I turned the settings way down in the seven 70. but I think I was overheating the seven 70. but anyway, enough of that.
Rym: The game is a worthy successor to doom in a lot of ways.
Scott: It's not doom.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: part of it is doom and part of it's not doomed, but it's still a good fun single player FPS kind of thing.
Rym: Part of it's half life too.
Scott: Part of it is half life too, but pretty good half life too.
Scott: Like kinda like not as, it's not as good at half life too as half life too.
Rym: Like here's the thing that half life two does is real.
Rym: It's a good thing to bring up.
Rym: Half life two will have two.
Rym: There's two like hallmarks of half life too.
Rym: One of them is you're in a room, you can walk around, but there's kind of a cinematic happening around you and it won't let you leave until all the people stop talking.
Rym: Doom and half life two both do that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Doom does not have cut scenes really.
Scott: Oh, it has a few actually.
Rym: But even then, they're pretty insignificant.
Scott: That's not like it stops and shows you a fucking movie.
Rym: And two with the thing that half life two did brilliantly.
Rym: that like, like that is why that game is to this day, like such a brilliant game is.
Rym: it will get you into a mood where you do things that feel natural and are guided subtly into doing things that end up feeling very cinematic.
Rym: Like the best example of that is in the, in the like apartment tower in the early part of half life two, where like you're talking to some people and they're like barred guards are busting in in the basement and you're like trying to get away and like you jumped through the window and like the game doesn't necessarily railroad you into that, but it sort of guides you into doing this really cinematic thing.
Rym: Doom does that several times, not as well as half life two did, but way better than any game other than half life two has ever done it.
Scott: So here, I mean, mostly it's a single player FPS game with levels and you beat it eventually, right?
Scott: Now here's where, here's how the flow of it works and how it differs subtly and maybe not so subtly from other FPS.
Scott: is that are single player, right?
Scott: First of all, uh, you know, the maps are very doomish and that, you know, you even have, you can press tab to look at the map and you get the key to open the key door and then you get the other key to open the other key door, right?
Scott: And the weapon will be up on a pedestal and a real, it's like the level design, despite it being modern and 3d is very doom inspired.
Rym: It felt real close to like the levels in the second and third thirds of doom two in particular.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Uh, you know, the music and the music, the combat is very doom, right?
Scott: It's pretty much the doom soundtrack, but played with real guitars and not with a mini controller.
Rym: I'm going to tell you, I didn't think about it.
Rym: Like the game starts and this metal music starts.
Rym: I'm like, all right.
Rym: But then the metal music kind of like how the Wolverine versus the X-Men had the melody from the old nineties X-Men cartoon in it just like done modern and like changed up.
Rym: You hear the original doom melody, like come in and it's good.
Scott: The music is good.
Scott: However, it didn't get me as pumped as original doom music, but it got me like 80% of the 80% there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's not bad, but it's like the original doom music, like it's like, it's just like tribes too.
Scott: It's like, Oh man, you are ready to go.
Rym: But what it does differently is that it has semi dynamic music.
Rym: So doom would have like a pumping up song.
Rym: Like every, every level has a different music in the music.
Scott: I'm going to tell you a bad secret and that the music and doom isn't as dynamic as you think it is.
Rym: Uh, in this doom.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I know I have figured out the triggers already.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It's basically, did you find the thing that you have to do in the level that's causing the like more monsters to appear or not?
Scott: Oh, that's not how it works either, but okay.
Rym: Cause that's, that's the only thing I noticed so far is that, you know, when you find the thing and like pull the heart out and then a bunch of monsters appear and you gotta fight them.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: The music will like kick into high gear then until you beat them all.
Scott: So you didn't play the whole game.
Rym: Not yet.
Scott: But basically the structure of each level.
Scott: in regular doom, do one doom too, right?
Scott: It's just get to the fucking exit.
Scott: Holy shit.
Rym: Every level is its own thing and the music is just the level.
Scott: It's just get to the goddamn exit as quickly or as safely as you possibly can.
Scott: And if you're killing demons on the way, do that.
Scott: This doom is not like that.
Scott: What will happen in this doom is that you will go into areas and it will lock you in basically each level.
Scott: There's only like token bad guys around.
Scott: There aren't really a lot of demons around, right?
Scott: There's only a few here and there to sort of fill up the environment and they're usually the weak kind that really can't do anything to you and go down.
Scott: It's like one regular shotgun shot, but you'll get into an area that's either locks you in right with physically locking the doors behind you or locking the doors in front of you.
Scott: So you can't proceed or both.
Scott: or has one of the like an item that you interact with, like grab the key or push a button or the gory heart out of the gore thing.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Pull the gory heart of the gore thing.
Scott: And it's like, okay, now is combat time.
Scott: So it's like combat time in regular doom, do one, do two is always like do two.
Rym: level will start and there's like a siren even coming at you.
Scott: It's like, go, go, go, do not stop ever in this.
Scott: It's walk around and chill, then combat time.
Scott: Then you must kill every bad guy during combat time and then combat time ends and you can chill again and you, it's, it's, it's exploring time, combat time, exploring time, combat time.
Rym: I'm looking for the level because the entire game so far reminds me of one specific level in doom too.
Scott: I just got to remember which one it is, but the whole game is like this from beginning to end.
Rym: tricks and traps in doom to this entire game feels like that map, map eight in doom too.
Scott: It's just explore time, combat time.
Scott: One after another.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You explore as much as you can get as much goodies as you can.
Scott: There's a lot of secrets just like doom, right?
Scott: You know?
Scott: And then when you're ready for the combat, you start the combat and you have to kill all the demons.
Scott: If there's even one demon you failed to kill, the music will still be, you know, rocking on and you got to, you know, that's a bad guy somewhere.
Scott: You got to find the problem is half the time.
Rym: it's like one imp who's just like fucking around and you can't, there have been times.
Scott: there was a time, uh, one time where the music kept playing and I ran around for 10 minutes.
Scott: It couldn't find the guy.
Rym: that happened to me too.
Scott: So I quit and redid it.
Scott: And I, that second time was just fine.
Rym: I found the guy and luckily I leveled up the, uh, the, the assault rifle with all the zoom damage stuff.
Scott: I also, that was also my weapon of choice.
Scott: The zoomy assault rifle that I upgraded all the way, but it felt so undoomed like to use that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's not about zooming and sniping that I feel like you shouldn't even have zooming and sniping and doom, but the levels are designed in such a way that there were a lot of opportunities to use it with great effectiveness and it meant that I could stay far away from dangerous demons and not die.
Scott: So I used it.
Rym: So tricks and traps in doom two, one, if you use like doom editors, that was the default map.
Rym: They'd throw you in if you just launched the game.
Rym: So that's why a lot of people just like specifically remember it.
Rym: But the way that map started is you're in this room and it's octagonal.
Rym: There's eight doors.
Rym: Each door goes to like a tricky place with its own bullshit.
Rym: And that's literally what this game is like.
Rym: Like you go into a place and it's got some bullshit you have to deal with.
Rym: Then you go to another place that's separate, that has different bullshit, right?
Scott: It's almost like each, they had different people design map pieces and they just sort of stuck them together in a way.
Scott: But the thing is, a lot of those pieces are just like a big room.
Scott: You're locked in with a whole bunch of demons, kill them all.
Scott: Now it's interesting though, because one thing that doom and especially doom two and it forces you to kill them all, you can't just like run through to the exit.
Scott: Like you couldn't do doom two.
Rym: Actually this map did that a lot.
Rym: A lot of the rooms you went into would lock you in and now you're stuck and you have to kill all the monsters to trigger.
Rym: I think it was trigger six, six, six and anyway, there's a trigger in doom because that's how the game work.
Rym: You would have triggers that will cause events like do the thing and the door will open.
Rym: One of the triggers is when the last monster in this room dies, does do the thing or when this monster dies, do the thing.
Rym: The whole game is just map 08 of doom two anyway.
Scott: So, uh, the bad guys themselves though are a 90% of them are bad guys from old doom games that have been recreated in magnificent fashion.
Rym: Like the amps are great.
Scott: They're just amps only fancier in 3d and modern and kind of creepy throwing fireballs at you.
Scott: But you can tell they're an imp right away when you look at them.
Scott: There are certain bad guys that were not used very much in old doom that are now used a great deal.
Scott: What's the guy's name?
Scott: The big fat guy with like, he's all tech, mancubus.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Mancubus is like all over this game, even though he was not used very often at all in the old dooms.
Scott: Is there an arch vial?
Scott: Which one's that?
Rym: That's the guy who can resurrect people.
Rym: is the wizard with the yellow fire.
Scott: Uh, maybe there's, there's one thing is there's only one spider and one cyber demon, which is disappointing.
Rym: Is there a commander keen?
Scott: Uh, maybe there's, there are many barons of hell plant, you know, it's just, uh, the invisible, you know, that's the arch vial.
Scott: No, the invisible demons that just run up to you, right?
Scott: You actually don't see those till a bit later.
Scott: The pink guys, pinky, the regular old demon is like kind of a dangerous dude in this game.
Scott: Uh, and he doesn't show up till later.
Scott: You think he'd show up earlier, but yeah, it's all the guys, you know, uh, one of the thing is the old doom.
Scott: There was Caco demon and there was the other one that there were two different floating balls with eyeballs, right?
Scott: The red one and the fleshy colored one in old doom.
Scott: And now there's only one kind, the Caco demon, which is, I guess.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You're thinking of the, Oh, what's the, what's that guy called?
Rym: The, uh, there's the fleshy one and there's the red one shoots out the skull guys.
Scott: One of them is the Caco demon and one of them's not pain element, pain elemental is the one that shoots out.
Scott: Pain elemental is not in this game, but there are floating fire skulls that are just on their own.
Scott: Uh, but anyway, it's, you know, each bad guy was great about them is that each one has to be defeated in an interesting way.
Scott: It's like, sure.
Scott: You could beat any one of the guys just by shooting them a ton and the BFG will kill obviously anything, but each guy has a really efficient way of killing them.
Scott: So like to beat pinky, the best thing to do is get behind him and shoot him and he'll go down easy and other guys are going to easy.
Scott: We shoot him in the head and other guys would go down easy if you shoot him like, you know, in a certain spot with plasma and other guys would go down easy to a shotgun.
Scott: It's like each guy has an easy way to get them.
Scott: So it's like you have to really, you know, like recognize guys, switch weapons, move and fight each guy.
Scott: When there's a bunch of different guys coming at you all mixed up, you have to, you know, get some interesting strategies going on.
Scott: Like, well, just dodge that guy, kill that one first, that sort of thing.
Scott: It also has this mechanic where if a guy's hurt a bunch, but not dead yet, oh yeah, you can do the gore thing.
Scott: You can push a button to kill them in a gory and I guess melee fashion.
Scott: It's a weird jarring experience.
Rym: Like you sort of like shoot forward and have this weird gory squeaky like play experience and then you shoot back.
Scott: I got an upgrade that increased the range on it, which made it even weirder because like I'd be kind of far away from a guy and I'd push a button and suddenly I'd be like ripping his head off.
Rym: Like it's weirdly immersive and jarring, but not as just like, it doesn't mess you up.
Scott: Like you're like normally it's like, I'll just shoot all the guys, but hey, if you do that, you lose an ammo and be.
Scott: when you do this to a guy, you get health and stuff.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So it's like you want to do it if you can.
Scott: The other thing is they got the chainsaw, which is a doom classic, but the chainsaw works in a weird way.
Scott: It's not, it doesn't come up when you choose your weapons normally.
Scott: Neither does the BFG, I guess to prevent you from using it by accident.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And when you use the chainsaw, you use fuel.
Scott: And what happens?
Scott: if you use the chainsaw on a bad guy, you will kill it in an awesome chainsaw way, no matter what, as long as you have enough fuel for that bad guy.
Scott: You, I've even killed like Baron of Hell, a chainsaw, as long as I had a ton of fuel.
Scott: But once you kill a guy with the chainsaw, uh, you get, it just spills a fountain of ammo like everywhere.
Rym: So it's interesting.
Rym: I couldn't figure out how to use the stupid chainsaw.
Scott: It has a specific button to bring it out.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So I picked it up and I was like, oh, I can't select it.
Rym: So then I thought, oh, maybe it's an item like my frag grenade, but then it wasn't.
Scott: No.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I didn't use, I barely use a lot of the game.
Rym: And until Scott came over to the show tonight, I didn't know how to use the chainsaw.
Scott: It has its own button to bring it out.
Scott: It's not a regular weapon.
Scott: That's why same thing with doing a job of telling me that same thing with BFG.
Scott: No, I had to look it up in the options.
Rym: I pointedly, the way I played this game is I decided it's a doom game.
Rym: Fuck it balls out.
Scott: I'm just going and going and going and going and going and going and going.
Scott: That's what I did too.
Scott: Except I also, uh, lingered around and found secrets.
Rym: I found a lot of secrets because it does the thing that doom did.
Rym: That's why it's like the secrets.
Scott: The thing is doom was all about secrets, but the secrets in this doom or half-life two style secrets.
Scott: Yeah, but they're not doing that or told the way doom was.
Rym: Cause the way doom would have a lot of secrets would be like, you'd see like a glint of a blue armor.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And you'd be like, how the fuck do I get in there?
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: That's how it does.
Rym: But what it doesn't do, at least it hasn't done to me yet.
Rym: Is the classic thing that doom two would do all the time.
Rym: It was like a hallmark of game design would be.
Rym: you'd go through an area and that would set up triggers to where on your way back, like shit would happen behind you.
Scott: There's not a lot of backtracking.
Scott: There's maybe some, but not too much.
Rym: Like you do a thing and then like behind you, a door silently opens and like four bears out, come out.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: Like that stuff.
Scott: The game does a little bit of that, but not a lot.
Rym: Like I, because I'm doing like, I was obsessed with doom.
Rym: Like I got doomed to like memorize, uh, this game.
Rym: I expected a lot of terrifying things to happen.
Rym: that did not happen so far.
Scott: Well, have you gone to hell yet?
Rym: Well, no, I'm just on Mars still.
Scott: It's a little more terrifying in hell.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But like doom two, that shit started like in level four.
Scott: It's not, yeah, it doesn't happen as much.
Scott: Uh, also you play it on harder difficulties.
Scott: that happens more, but good luck getting there.
Rym: I'm laying it on a hurt me plenty right now.
Rym: I also was hurt plenty, but I'm going to try it in debt.
Rym: I think I'm going to like have a decent way through the game.
Rym: I might just start over on a ultra violence and see how it goes a little bit of the ultra violence.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Uh, the other thing that this game has, which other dooms did have, people just didn't pay attention is a plot.
Scott: It's a really thin plot, but it's a doom plot.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And it also presents the plot.
Scott: The thing is the plot of the original doom was just about as thin.
Scott: It just wasn't presented so overtly.
Scott: So you would miss it.
Rym: purely environmental storytelling, right?
Scott: It was environmental and also a little bit of text.
Scott: when you started one of the episodes, like the original doom, even do one had a plot.
Scott: It's just people didn't know it because they didn't read it and they didn't pay attention and they didn't sort of figure out like, oh, first he's in the base and then he gets overrun and then he goes to hell and then his way out of hell portal open.
Scott: It's like that plot was in the original doom.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: you couldn't, you had to like look for it to see it there and fully understand what a dude is like.
Rym: We have play God in this one.
Scott: This dude is just telling you the plot.
Scott: It's just like everything is just told to you, but it's basically the same plot as the original doom with the obvious exception of, uh, yeah, you're the doom guy brought back for more doom as opposed to you are.
Scott: now, you know, you're just a guy, a space Marine and you are become doom.
Scott: Guy,
Rym: but the way
Scott: it
Rym: does that is sort of interesting because it's a little bit deconstructive or a little bit parody in that it'll start to do a half life thing, but like a little casino start, but it'll do it in this almost like desultory fashion and like doom guys.
Rym: Response will be to punch the monitor halfway through the dialogue and ended and just continue like that kind of stuff happens a lot.
Scott: Doom guy doesn't give a fuck.
Scott: He just wants to shoot them demons.
Rym: Like the thing that like lets you upgrade your shit.
Rym: The way you interact with it is it starts to like do a thing and you just fucking punch it in the face and pull the upgrade out of it and keep going.
Scott: He's just, he's doomed guy.
Scott: I didn't give a fuck.
Scott: He's supposed to kill demons.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Also, it's got a lot of hell.
Scott: I'm going to shoot it.
Scott: It was a point at which I don't know if he got there.
Scott: I don't remember when it was in the game where the guy who's like the character who just tells you everything, the certain narrator, the cyborg guy, the guy who you're not sure if is good or bad and he's probably both or whatever.
Scott: He's like, Oh, you seem to like guns.
Rym: You'll find something to your liking over there, but like you only ever interact with the environment by hitting your use button.
Rym: Very doom style.
Scott: And it just does whatever it's going to do.
Scott: You don't, there's not a lot of choice.
Rym: It does it in kind of a funny way.
Rym: Like sometimes like here's the switch, it may look different and do a crazy thing, but it is just the switch to continue the plot
Scott: and you might kick it or just touch it or like early
Rym: on in the game you go to the control room and like you see a switch.
Rym: And you hit use on it and it like doesn't do anything, but then there's this dead body like laying next to it and the dead bodies highlighted.
Rym: Like you can use it and if you hit use on that doom guy reaches down, holds up the dead guy's arm, shoves it on the control panel and that activates the switch and you don't have to, it's no puzzle.
Rym: The puzzle, there's no puzzle to solve there, but it has the trappings of what in another Megaman, Megaman style FPS would have been a puzzle.
Scott: Yeah, it has.
Scott: It's like, it's not really a puzzle or a maze, but it's like joke.
Scott: It's, it's like there's a lot of parts that like would be amazed, but they didn't make it complex enough where you could actually get lost, right?
Scott: It's like, it's like, oh, I'm doing a maze just like original doom games, ha ha ha.
Scott: But it's like, no, actually it's just like two corners.
Scott: There it is.
Scott: It's not really a place you're going to get lost in like real doom.
Scott: Sorry.
Scott: It's, we didn't make a real maze cause that would take too long.
Rym: Yeah, but even then it's still closer to, cause dooms mazes were not really mazes either.
Rym: They were just funneling you through the monster fights.
Scott: Wolfenstein was a maze, right?
Scott: Everything got less mazy over time, but this newer doom is the least mazy.
Rym: I feel like the old, like Hexen was more mazy, but I don't really remember that clearly.
Scott: Not as mazy as Wolfenstein, which was a literal rectangular maze, you get fucking lost.
Rym: Well, the doom engines big, like big thing move forward other than the 2.5D was that walls could be at any angle, not just 90 degrees.
Scott: I mean, that is one nice part.
Rym: The side deaths or whatever the sectors, the line deaths.
Scott: This is real 3d.
Scott: So you got a lot of, you know, interesting ways to hide secrets and maze bits by going up and down.
Scott: And you think, well, it didn't quake do all that, but actually quake.
Scott: single players, garbage compared to old doom or new doom.
Rym: Cause quake and quake two single player were basically, we made a multiplayer game, but there is technically a single player game here.
Scott: Here's a bunch of garbage levels you never want to play.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I like this game though.
Rym: Like it's, it's, I don't know if you want to pay full price price for it necessarily.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I paid full price just because I really wanted to play a single player FPS and it was the best one around.
Rym: But like, it was very telling that I play Overwatch a lot.
Rym: It's and Counter-Strike again, it's very hard to pull me away from those like competitive modern games.
Rym: But then I sat down to play this game to do the show and I just kept playing it.
Rym: Like I just kept playing it the way I would when I was in high school.
Rym: I only stopped because I noticed it was like midnight and I had to go to bed.
Scott: So it's like, you know, I wouldn't pay the, you know, the 50 bucks or whatever because it's the kind of game where I play, I beat it and I put it on the shelf and I'm done.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: But if this comes down in the steam sale, like 20 or less, and you want to, you like single player FPSs and you like doom, you should get this game if your computer can play it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon Patrons for this episode of GeekNights, in order of the amount of money they give us on a continuing basis, are Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Nicholas Brando, Ida McNichol, Amanda Duchette, Construction Noises, Ivy Fain, MyStady.com, William Eisenraos, Jeremy Miner, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn, Christian Kuntz, You Can Use Regex, Parsaise, Shamal, It's True, Sherwin Von Horl, Iggy Kid, Rolivel, James David White, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy.
Rym: and then The Winged Hussars arrived, Erin Cerise, Brian Fisher, Sailor Vista, Carl Henrady's Famous Knock Knock Joke, Matthew Smith, Don Schleich, Char Thomas, Joe Shiro, Joe Starr, Tyler Eller, Sean Yeager, Sam Corddry, Clinton Walton, Renford, New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlanders, Brian Cedroni, Curie Eniff, Redacted, Chris Midgiff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: It is a testament to the pipeline I set up that this is the new computer.
Rym: I didn't have to change anything.
Rym: My mixer is digital.
Rym: The Firewire card worked.
Rym: I literally just took the template from the old computer and used it on the new computer and it seems like it worked.
Rym: I'm about to actually edit the episode together so you'll find out in the forum thread if things did not go according to plan.
Rym: Stay tuned for a lot of new content now that I can stream episodes live and I can do all sorts of cool nonsense, but now I leave you with something.