Rym: It's Tuesday, June 21st, 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight we talk about people who may or may not know a lot about games and How bad they might be but all in good fun?
Rym: Thanks to Reddit.
Rym: I Don't know what the fuck to call this episode.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So we like going to Wildwood like even though it's kind of in the bottom of New Jersey.
Rym: we have a long history of going to Wildwood and like friends and it's just.
Rym: it's a. it's a very nostalgic place and For the East Coast of the US.
Rym: It's one of the best beaches in terms of actual sand beach.
Scott: You know, even in Florida is technically still the East Coast.
Rym: Yeah, the Northeast Coast.
Scott: I mean, there's Virginia.
Scott: I guess it's below the Mason-Dixon line, but Virginia and a Virginia Beach.
Scott: I've seen pictures of it.
Rym: We've been to it.
Rym: It's usually crowded and kind of meh.
Scott: Oh, it looked nice in the picture.
Rym: I mean a lot of things I never been.
Rym: Rockaway looks real nice in the picture.
Scott: It is nice.
Rym: Yeah, I wouldn't swim there that long Mmm.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So anyway, I do worse, but I tend to don't go.
Rym: it like I'll bike to Rockaway, but then I don't like Change into swimsuits and swim or like spend.
Scott: it is where the fuck am I gonna put my bike?
Scott: Yeah, I'm in the water and then what I'm gonna bike back wet.
Scott: Yeah, how is that gonna work?
Rym: so Emily and I this Logistics are not there tipped off by Gothamis because apparently this seems like it's a relatively new thing and it's one of those things that Eventually like regular New Yorkers are gonna figure it out and ruin it for all of us.
Rym: But right now there's this express ferry that goes from 35th Street like that ferry terminal Yeah direct to Sandy Hook Beach Which I didn't actually even know existed.
Scott: It's just a North Jersey Beach it's at that.
Rym: so it's be.
Rym: it's north of North Jersey because there's Jersey kind of like goes up to that point and the Barrier Islands to the right and all the Jersey Shore places are in the barrier like islands the barrier peninsulas.
Rym: But to get to this beach driving you have to go all the way around Into North Jersey and then turn left and go up north to actually get to it like it's popping up over the top.
Rym: From the beach you can actually see Manhattan and like the Verrazano Narrows bridge and all that crap like it's it's.
Rym: it's like kind of like off the coast of Staten Island And I just never really thought about that place and from New York.
Rym: It would be a super pain in the ass to get there Like it's actually harder to get there than to get to other beaches that are further south Unless you take a boat.
Rym: So this boat is like 30 bucks round trip.
Rym: That's a lot of monies Yeah But it's way less money than car or any other way to get to this beach.
Rym: In fact, if you drive to the beach, it costs like 20 bucks just to park there.
Rym: So the ferry takes like 40 minutes gets us right to the beach.
Rym: There's bike pads Everywhere up there.
Rym: There's like no cars.
Rym: You can bike everywhere.
Rym: It's like great biking.
Rym: There's like four beaches and they're great beaches.
Rym: The water is super clean.
Rym: It's clearer and cleaner feeling than Wildwood's water Even though and apparently I was reading up about the beach.
Rym: It's because of where it's situated It's sort of shielded from the New York stuff.
Rym: So it's like very different water quality from all the other beaches in the New York area.
Rym: it's more like swimming way further south would be normally.
Rym: and the other interesting thing is There used to be a nuclear anti-aircraft battery on this island.
Rym: So there's museums and like all this nuclear anti-aircraft show It's trying to shoot nukes.
Scott: theoretically would shoot nukes at planes.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: The idea was that is a bad idea.
Rym: So this is in the 50s and I knew a little bit about this, but I didn't know they couldn't hit the plane.
Scott: So they figure well just shoot a big enough aoe it is way worse than that.
Rym: So we had the Nike missiles right like Nike Ajax.
Scott: Yeah, they weren't very good.
Rym: Well, they were.
Rym: so the original missile had a conventional explosive and it would shoot up.
Rym: It was the first like missile rocket artillery.
Rym: It would shoot up and hit a bomber Awesome.
Scott: Yeah bombers big and easy to hit.
Rym: and they had this because they were worried about a Soviet nuclear bomber coming in to nuke New York.
Scott: Yeah I mean that was a good plan.
Rym: and then the Cold War progressed a little bit and instead of the worry being One Soviet bomber it was squadron of Soviet bombers.
Rym: So the idea was why don't we just blow up a nuke over New York to blow up all the bombers?
Scott: Why don't you just use your fighters?
Scott: you can shoot the bombers down.
Scott: they're big and slow.
Rym: There's reasons for that and our fighters are better.
Rym: I'm not gonna turn the front of the show into why it was the way it was.
Rym: but I'll put it this way I thought we were looking at it cuz I didn't know a lot about like the Nike Ajax Nike Hercules.
Rym: I knew a little bit just cuz that's like basic war history.
Scott: So which?
Scott: which part of this is left at the beach?
Rym: So the whole fucking thing like the batteries are there dishes nukes there waiting.
Rym: So obviously the nuke payload is not in them anymore the fuel is not in them anymore.
Rym: but there's like.
Rym: they've got him there as like museum pieces for you to check out.
Scott: and They've got like whenever you go to the veterans place.
Scott: There's like a missile out in the front and it's empty.
Scott: It's a big metal.
Rym: Here's what's terrifying.
Rym: They're really small two-stage missiles and looking at him I was like can't be that big a yield.
Rym: I mean this would be used for air.
Rym: It was like.
Rym: what are these like?
Rym: maybe like.
Rym: are they a kiloton?
Rym: No, these things are fucking like.
Rym: I think it went up to 80 or 90 kilotons.
Rym: We're talking nine Hiroshima's.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, the radar array is there and apparently on special days I got the schedule.
Rym: I want to go back.
Rym: They do tours of the actual facility where all this shit is now.
Rym: They'd only do it.
Scott: They do it like pike your bike.
Rym: Yeah, I probably parked our bike outside everywhere.
Rym: There was totally safe now granted, but there was safety in numbers one.
Rym: Everyone bikes everywhere on this island.
Rym: There's bike racks everywhere.
Rym: You can't get cars near the bike racks.
Rym: So so like the kinds of bike theory they're going to Manhattan can't really happen there.
Rym: New York riffraff can't easily get there because the expensive ferry.
Rym: New Jersey riffraff can't easily get there because it's a long drive and you have to pay a lot of money to park there or bike in Bike.
Rym: that every seems a pretty uncommon.
Rym: there like most people weren't even locking their bikes up.
Rym: But no we fucking locked our bikes up.
Rym: No one stole them though, but partly because we both have beefy locks.
Rym: so we locked our bikes together Mutually to the pole.
Rym: So if the three of us went daddy three locks.
Rym: But yeah, so there's all these batteries there like old batteries from like early World War one and late Civil War.
Rym: There's so much cool history on the island and great beaches.
Rym: One of the beaches is special.
Rym: There's like a bunch of beaches at different places along the island but one of the beaches is Technically owned by the federal government and is not New Jersey state land.
Rym: So you can have alcohol on the beach.
Rym: There are basically no rules except federal rules on the beach and You can be naked on the beach.
Scott: So it's the new for tilden is the same way then.
Rym: Yeah but unlike this beach has a like all these beaches here also have a lot of Facilities and way better showers and changing rooms and things than a lot of beaches.
Rym: So it was just a great place.
Rym: I'm gonna go there a bunch of times, but not immediately cuz Kind of got a little bit sunburned.
Scott: Why did you bring lotions?
Rym: I went.
Rym: I did a lot of swim in and I rubbed it off and didn't correctly fully reapply.
Rym: So my sides where I like my arms rubbed it off.
Rym: Yeah, it's bad news bears another problem with swimming mid bike.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is what we did is we biked around for like a few hours.
Rym: Then we went.
Scott: it's also a problem with the nude beach.
Scott: right suddenly you got a lotion in all the places.
Rym: Honestly, if I'm in a nude beach I'm not gonna be super nude cuz I am NOT going to ever risk burning the young master and his merry man.
Rym: Holy shit Is that?
Rym: literally one of my biggest fears is a sunburn down.
Scott: all peeling off can't use it.
Scott: Okay, when every time you pee you got to touch it.
Rym: Yeah, especially because this we would not have been nearly so bad when I was the younger man Cuz I used to wear boxes all the time, but son as you get older, it's box of briefs time and Box of briefs plus the sunburn down there.
Rym: I feel like I just would call in sick.
Scott: I mean even just sun burning your ass is not good.
Scott: You sit down.
Scott: Ow.
Scott: Yeah It doesn't matter what you wear and I think I'd wear unless unless you're wearing like a freeze ice pack like a mushy gel one.
Rym: But yeah, I plan to go to this beach on a semi-regular imagine like rubbing cool aloe like all over your butt.
Rym: Yeah So I was just cool and you should check it out and I'm gonna find out when I can go see.
Rym: because apparently like I suspect There are still some sort of like anti-aircraft things there because there's a lot of military personnel who work there still.
Rym: So the tours of the nuclear shit are like tightly controlled on certain specific days gonna shoot somebody.
Rym: Also, the park service is like all over this place.
Rym: So like there's all these old gigantic gun batteries and abandoned forts and everything.
Rym: and There's park services.
Rym: people just stand in there and if you bike up They're like, hey you want to come inside and like check this shit out.
Rym: They give you a flashlight and a hardhat and they're like Let's go and they just tell you all the history and answer any questions and they're all a hundred percent chill.
Rym: That's what their job is is stand there and all day every day what I do in the winter In the winter, you can still go to this island.
Rym: There's a bunch of stuff there.
Scott: It's a pretty weird job.
Rym: Yeah, Park Service is kind of awesome.
Rym: I wish we had more of that.
Rym: So, yeah, that was my weekend.
Scott: hmm, I just biked to normal places.
Scott: now don't have to spend money in our in, New Jersey.
Rym: Well, I was on federal land for a part of it.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't go to the federal lands this weekend.
Rym: So, uh in the actual news you got any news cuz it's gaming day and such Fiasco people are talking about here right?
Rym: Oh a fiasco.
Scott: No sort of a fiasco.
Rym: the game fiasco.
Scott: So basic now.
Scott: So there was basically there's this company tiny bill.
Scott: is it called tiny build?
Scott: it's called something like that.
Scott: What happened?
Scott: I lost the link.
Rym: Oh Radio silence gig judges off the air.
Rym: I'm gonna fill it with patter until Scott comes back online with this link on his iPad I guess And I'm running out of steam.
Rym: So I'm playing a lot of overwatch.
Rym: I can start talking about overwatch.
Rym: I figured out how to deal with the situation where you're pushing and it's over time.
Scott: They took a link off the top of the page so I had to like scroll down to find it.
Scott: that is a tiny build Which made some games like speedrunners and games.
Scott: I never heard of whatever they.
Scott: basically here's what happened They set up a website to sell their game.
Scott: So you go to their website tiny build.
Scott: you buy the game and they give you a steam code.
Scott: Then you use the steam code and you have the game.
Scott: this way instead of buying the game on steam you buy the game from them.
Rym: Right, yep real common sure whatever.
Scott: so there's this other website G2a which is apparently the shadiest of shady fucks.
Scott: and what g2a does is basically let you resell game codes.
Scott: So you would buy a game code or maybe you have a game that you don't want or already.
Rym: That's the kind of thing that if I didn't know what I like what I know about the game industry I'd be thinking that sounds like a pretty cool side.
Scott: I mean in principle that's perfectly okay, right.
Scott: if I buy a humble bundle and there's a game I already got and I don't want to gift the game to anyone or whatever Why shouldn't I be able to sell that code right?
Scott: It's a writer for a sale And you know in that aspect g2a is fine, right?
Scott: So you go on g2a you put your code someone else buys it from you they get the code They use it on steam what and they get the big at the game, right?
Scott: It's that's nothing wrong with that in principle.
Scott: apparently though g2a is like shady as fuck and they really don't give a crap if like people are selling bullshit codes or Whatever.
Scott: so the scam is this people go out and they look for People selling game codes that have shitty web stores like tiny bills own personal store And they use fraudulent stolen credit cards to buy codes.
Scott: They resell the codes on g2a to basically money launder them and get tournaments like real money.
Scott: Then obviously the transaction gets cancelled.
Scott: So now the person with the original store has given away the game the code.
Scott: that's gonna work But now they don't get any money because it was a fraudulent credit card.
Scott: But meanwhile now it's the person who used the stolen credit card has the money because they resold the code I like a good price or even you know discount or whatever.
Scott: So the game got given to some legitimate gamer who bought the code who wants to play it.
Scott: So sometimes I think in certain cases what they've done is they've like, you know invalidated those codes And now someone paid money to a scammer and now doesn't even have a game.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Now granted.
Scott: I see ever still has the money.
Rym: Yeah, okay.
Scott: So the two I think that you know, everyone here is blaming g2a which yeah You should blame g2a because basically it appears they don't give a fuck about shit like this and they're like Okay, they're just so scammy and don't give a crap.
Scott: and they're like, hooray we're making so much money from these scammers.
Scott: Please continue selling shady shit.
Scott: Yeah, but also Some blame needs to be put on.
Scott: You know, I guess there it's sort of victim blaming.
Scott: It's sort of like oh you didn't lock your door and your house got robbed.
Scott: But at the same time you're really dumb if you don't even lock your door to your house and you have valuable shit in there.
Scott: Yeah, don't make your own fucking web store.
Scott: It's like everyone complains that like Apple or steam or whoever is taking a cut.
Rym: dude guys We tried to Scott and I like we were gonna do some e-commerce way back and I started setting them a magento server.
Rym: Yeah, fuck that never you pay someone else.
Scott: Someone else is taking a cut.
Scott: So they set up their own web store and Yeah, cuz you know what.
Scott: now they're like, I think they said they were so upset.
Scott: It's like we've spent more time developing Anti credit card fraud than developing games.
Scott: It's like why are you developing that?
Scott: you could have just bought it?
Scott: Yeah, or instead of bonding it you could have just paid someone else like Apple the cut they take which is going towards things like this.
Rym: That's you know Cuz I've.
Rym: you know.
Rym: I work on Wall Street like in my day job and one of the primary like arguments and discussions that always happens is build versus buy.
Rym: Do you build something or buy it?
Rym: The answer is almost never to build it unless it's your primary thing.
Rym: Yeah, so there right unless it's the thing making you money just buy someone else's right.
Scott: and it was even like I think like one or two weeks ago, John Oliver did a thing about.
Scott: do you let people know about you know?
Scott: Something we knew already which is like hey, yeah mutual funds and have mad fees on them Right, but it's like he wasn't.
Scott: even he wasn't like.
Scott: yeah find one with no fees.
Scott: It's like no because your fee is still buying you something which is a smart person buying stuff You don't have to right it's not?
Rym: you don't watch out for robo advisors because that's kind of making that less and less.
Scott: But yeah, no.
Scott: But the point is is right is it?
Scott: if you want to do something without having to work this fees to cover shit like this Yep, right, so kind of like if you're a tiny build and you lose apparently they say they've lost $450,000 right Because of this.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: that's what you get for opening up your own goddamn store and doing something that isn't your own deal.
Scott: You should have just sold your stuff on Amazon and Google and Apple and let them take the cut and steam whatever.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the primary blame still falls on the scammers.
Scott: Obviously if G that's the other thing.
Scott: if g2a didn't exist Right and wasn't doing this or it wasn't being shady there would be even if you bought these codes of stolen credit cards You'd have no way to turn those code to launder those codes into money and there would be no point in buying codes of stolen credit
Rym: card.
Rym: companies also are a little culpable because they have a lot of capacity to Recognize trends of fraudulent use and deal with that.
Scott: they do do some extent but they don't do it.
Scott: It's it's weird.
Scott: It's like if I use my card at like a store I never go to it won't work and I'll get a phone call.
Scott: Yeah, but if some legit stolen credit cards are used to buy game codes like a thousand times at the same store They don't do anything.
Scott: It's like I don't know what their anti-fraud system is.
Rym: But so actually my credit card number got stolen a bunch of times in rapid succession due to a breach I think with a bank or whatever.
Rym: like there's a credit card processing or there's some sort of big like super top-level breaches years ago and every time it got stolen and used for until like finally just stopped because The big high up person had fixed it It was always at the same Target store in like.
Rym: Tennessee.
Scott: wasn't target the place they had a breach.
Rym: I might have been but I haven't shopped at the target like ever.
Rym: Yeah So it wasn't.
Rym: it was my credit card number was not breached because of Target.
Rym: just Target was the store where people were using the fraudulent Credit cards that they cloned or whatever to make purchases.
Scott: But yeah, it's really.
Scott: it's also the law's fault Right because if I was the government I would just say credit card companies as in Visa MasterCard American Express You're responsible for all of the costs associated with not merchants not customers.
Scott: Not anyone else.
Scott: It's gonna be you no matter what and you what they would.
Rym: I would say then you can't use credit cards online at all Unless you have a chip reader in your house plugged into your computer.
Scott: and then I would say no You just have to fucking deal with it.
Scott: visa.
Scott: Fuck you because That's the law we passed.
Rym: This is why you're not president nor you're a member of Congress.
Scott: Why not deal with it?
Scott: Okay, you have your multi bajillion dollar international company like visa.
Scott: fucking deal with it.
Scott: If this loss is involved you eat him.
Scott: Fuck you.
Scott: Yeah, I can have plenty of fuck.
Rym: I'm gonna go that route.
Rym: There's a better way.
Scott: What's the better way?
Rym: You just fucking nationalize the credit card.
Scott: That's a great idea too.
Rym: You don't tell the private company.
Rym: Fuck you do what we want.
Rym: You say you're a public company now, that'd be fine, too.
Rym: I owned by the public as in the federal government.
Scott: that actually sounds great, too.
Scott: I'd be like, hey guess what Visa MasterCard and American Express relating all of you.
Scott: There's not one thing it's called US card system.
Rym: Yeah, listeners guys realize like we're pretty radically far left on a lot of issues.
Scott: I'm okay with that.
Rym: It sounds great But there's also like the.
Scott: there's a little bit and you know what?
Scott: You could also get rid of all those stupid things that you know, like you get your ATM card And there's all those weird symbols in the back.
Scott: Yeah, it's like rich ATM.
Scott: Can I you can get rid of all those two and join them in the same system?
Rym: So a little bit of blame goes on the people who buy stuff on g2a Because when you see a game for sale for like a penny or a dollar somewhere That's there's almost no way that's legit.
Scott: Yeah, sure, but you know also like I at least that person's a legit gamer.
Scott: They're probably a poor high school kid with no money.
Scott: Who's the only way they can get a game?
Rym: I looked at you to his website for the first time.
Rym: Yeah, I would have assumed it was a scam.
Scott: Yeah, that's the site I'm never gonna give like dude.
Rym: at the top it has a little money bag sign and it says g2a gold mine.
Rym: earn real money with us.
Rym: no Oh The site sets off all my fishing radar, yeah.
Rym: So g2a.
Scott: yeah, if you want to buy a game just but it's like dude the steam sale isn't cheap enough for you.
Rym: Yeah, how to go to cheetah you're bitching about paying, you know, five dollars instead of a dollar on a shady side.
Rym: Come on, guys.
Rym: I Mean, I bought overwatch like immediately a full price, but that game's not gonna get cheaper.
Scott: Yeah, I think there's also.
Scott: I think part of it is that with g2a you can you know?
Scott: If you don't have a credit card or some punk kid you can earn money doing g2a nonsense.
Rym: Yeah, and by games with you know, that's that's exactly I was about to get to that because that is the game store model as Well, I trade in your games.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like that business model of target kids You can't get credit cards should not be allowed and simultaneously There should be an easier way to give kids credit cards that their parents control.
Scott: You should be able to go into any bank Even if you're gonna give them cash and they should have to give you a card That is worth that amount of cash that can be.
Rym: well you can do that like any target or Rite Aid or whatever.
Scott: Yeah, you get a gift card.
Rym: No, you can buy like visa debit cards or whatever.
Scott: Yeah, sure But sometimes those don't work.
Rym: No, I'm saying like when I was a young kid, like I was a teenager I was like lucky because you know, my parents were internet and I was internet.
Rym: So they got me a credit card when I was really young that they were also on the account.
Rym: So even as a punk kid, I could use a credit card to do stuff online.
Rym: in the modern era It is ridiculous that 13 year olds can't have credit cards.
Rym: I mean I when I was 13 year old needs a credit card like they need a smartphone.
Scott: when I was in high school I bought stuff by buying it online and then mailing a check to the place.
Scott: Wow that worked It's real well.
Scott: And then when I was in college Rym was like I. the reason I didn't get a credit card was simply because I figured I Didn't have any credit.
Scott: They wouldn't send me one and Rym was like they'll totally send you one.
Scott: So I went to a website and he filled out the form and sure enough a credit card came in the mail.
Scott: I'm like, oh, okay.
Rym: We're good But like in the modern era it's ridiculous to expect a 12 year old to not have a cell phone And it's ridiculous to expect the 12 year old shouldn't have cards They can use to interact with the modern world of currency and commercial transactions.
Rym: So in other news, this is sort of an interesting thing.
Rym: So overwatch is getting you know patches and updates and everything.
Rym: but Jeff Kaplan who is the game director Actually posted a very long sort of discussion of The changes they're making and the rationale and basically everything around the matchmaking in overwatch and the matchmaking.
Rym: those are guys like the most advanced matchmaking on earth that they do and Overwatch is in the he even admitted is basically a special problem even more so than other games of its ilk.
Scott: Isn't it the same problem as tf2 or?
Rym: Tf2 didn't have that much of a skill cap and the characters weren't actually that much different?
Scott: I guess yeah.
Scott: If there's less skill then it doesn't matter as much who you're paired with because you can you'll you have much more leeway.
Scott: It's like if you miss pair people it won't make it won't ruin the game as much Whereas if you miss pair and a high skill cap game, right that one person is gonna kill everybody.
Rym: also the matches are very different.
Rym: like the matches function more like a sports game in terms of how they're structured than a Server of capture the flag or whatever like it.
Rym: I'm doing a review in the game So I'll kind of sidestep just explaining what I mean by all that.
Rym: But also because of the grouping like it's six on six and you can pick from all these different characters and the characters are So radically different and you can change characters mid-match And you're expected to like I'll run while like I'll run diva for half the match.
Rym: But then during a clutch moment I switch to Winston and they go back to diva like people do stuff like that.
Rym: So the matchmaking is crazy complicated, but the two really interesting things that you should just read this thing I'm not gonna paraphrase it all for you is one.
Rym: He said that if they broadly describe how it works they can summarize match results into five broad buckets.
Rym: My team won.
Rym: we beat the other team by a long shot To.
Rym: my team barely won.
Rym: My team barely lost.
Rym: my team lost and it wasn't even close.
Rym: And then the last category is this match was somehow fucked up or broken.
Scott: so I dropped out.
Rym: Yeah, like people dropped out.
Rym: It didn't have the max number.
Rym: Play the game like maybe the mat like the ping half of rocket league games.
Rym: But what's interesting is that if you ask the average gamer like what kind of game do you want to play?
Rym: They would say that the games they want the most are the two middle ones.
Rym: My team barely won or my team barely lost.
Scott: like that's bullshit the clothes fair.
Scott: I want to win.
Rym: quotes.
Rym: Most players will say they want a match to be either type 2 or type 3 as I described above.
Rym: those sound even barely win Or barely lose.
Rym: But I believe when psychology comes into play most players actually expect type 1 or type 2 to be the result.
Rym: Even amazingly a close type 3 the my team barely lost is generally is can turn into a quote.
Rym: Highly negative experience for a lot of players.
Scott: right people who don't have most gamers on earth Right do not have the competitive mindset.
Scott: They do not actually want to measure their skills against the skills of another person and have the result Declare one person more skilled.
Scott: that makes them upset especially if they lose.
Scott: if they win they don't care.
Rym: But if they lose it makes them very upset because they in that because they don't just want to win and have a closed game They prefer to win soundly.
Scott: to be like this is why games like pandemic and munchkin and all these things are very very popular Especially compared to game, you know, I'm the only people who play games like counter-strike or dota are like, you know hardcore time This is inside.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I I heard there's a munchkin CCG like.
Rym: I ignored it.
Rym: like I don't know.
Scott: Yep, I watched a video of that.
Rym: Okay, so if I were going to make that game I don't know what the real game is.
Rym: I've literally not looked at it.
Rym: I would make it.
Rym: I'll just keep selling cards forever and there's basically almost no rules of what you can put in your deck and Just the nerd who brings the most fucked up deck will win in any given group.
Rym: It's just like this ARG game almost No, whatever.
Rym: That's what I would do.
Rym: Just give.
Scott: it seems like they made a real game.
Scott: I see that's the problem, but it also.
Scott: but it includes silliness of munchkin For example dropping a card and seeing where it lands.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Yeah, I would go crazy.
Rym: I'd have cards that be like if you're at a penny arcade Expo.
Rym: This monster is worth plus ten levels or whatever.
Rym: Like I would go nuts.
Rym: I would make the game less of a game because that I'd make it more like we didn't play.
Rym: test this at all.
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: so he talks about that a lot like the matchmaking and how players Will say they want even matches, but really they just want to win.
Rym: but something really fascinating happened.
Rym: There's a feature that I've used that I really liked and it's interesting that I did not anticipate the problem with this feature and Blizzard apparently did not anticipate the problem either.
Rym: They're removing the feature now because of this problem.
Rym: I mean smart people might have come up with it if they really thought about it.
Rym: But the idea is in this matchmaking system, you know, this is a game you play in public So you can block other people from like your chats or whatever and you can report people for being shitty and Blizzard takes all that Super seriously, but you also have the option to avoid a player.
Rym: So if someone's a bitch like there's annoying little shit bird or you know whatever causes them to be annoying or not fun to have on your team or play with you can say avoid this player and It'll take that into account whenever it's matchmaking you.
Rym: What actually happened is that most people would click avoid on anyone who ever beat them.
Rym: they never wanted to play against people who were better than them of course,
Scott: right and
Rym: That started being a huge problem because basically good players could never find games and apparently the way they figured it out Was that one of the best players in the country like in the world?
Scott: He plays Widowmaker the sniper and he's the one that requires the most skill.
Rym: Yes this play Oh Widowmaker might be number two in terms of skill But anyway, this person I don't know if it's guy or girl.
Rym: I didn't fully read this but basically they were complaining that they could never get matched up Like they'd never find games.
Rym: it would take forever.
Rym: Let me see if I can find the actual quote because it was real interesting.
Scott: Even other really skilled people didn't want to play.
Rym: Well, you've got to find a match.
Rym: They could be it.
Rym: Here it is.
Rym: Read this whole thing.
Rym: We realized the avoid.
Rym: this player was wreaking havoc on matchmaking.
Rym: One of the best Widowmaker players in the world complained to us about long queue times We looked into it and found that hundreds of other players had avoided him quote.
Rym: He's a nice guy.
Rym: They avoided him because they did not want to play it against him because he's good not because of any misbehavior, right?
Scott: You don't play basketball against Michael Jordan.
Rym: Well, I do because that would be a fascinating you're not?
Rym: it's like see part of it Is like like I want to lose to ridiculous people just because that's what hell of an experience.
Scott: Well, yeah, so here's the problem.
Scott: right depending it depends a lot on the game right?
Scott: if I play basketball against Michael Jordan It's not fun because the skill difference is so big.
Scott: even old Michael Jordan.
Scott: today Michael Jordan the skill Oh, yeah, still so big I would never touch the ball.
Scott: I would never do anything meaningful.
Scott: I would net right and it would.
Scott: so it's like I'm not even playing basketball.
Scott: I'm literally just standing there maybe running around ineffectively.
Scott: I'm not even playing the game.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: even if I'm not upset by losing I don't get to do anything now.
Rym: Yeah, now I want to play that game.
Scott: It's like for example, though I would love to say go in a car race again, you know, like if I could drive an f1 car and not die Against you know, even Lewis Hamilton, right?
Scott: It'd be great because even though he's gonna lap me like ten times and I'm not maybe I'll stall and who knows what'll happen to Me I'm gonna hike still have the fun of driving the car.
Scott: I can still enjoy the experience of playing, right?
Scott: So if you it depends on the game in cat in a game like FPS say quake.
Scott: right if you're up against someone really really really good, especially like quake three that open map.
Scott: You know the one where it's just like you're about It's literally spawn railgun to the head spawn railgun to the heads.
Scott: Right, you won't even get to walk around or pick up items or even shoot a rocket.
Scott: so it won't be fun.
Scott: But if the game is such where even against a really good player, you can actually still do stuff You just won't win that and maybe even kill him once then it's okay at least by me.
Scott: but against other people They just don't.
Scott: they just can't deal with losing period Want a competitive game.
Rym: it appeared to be the better players.
Rym: They just want fun avoiding this guy because what the there was a secondary like that was that good.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, so I mean I used to play in clans like Ken.
Rym: He was one of our snipers like when we'd like I'd do skirmishes with them or like I'd play Mega TF or weapons factory in weapons factory.
Rym: He was good.
Rym: So if you want you if he was up in the battlements like a do for bad That was just a no-man's land.
Rym: in between.
Rym: the two would be like the snipers dueling and no one could even go out there.
Rym: Everyone had to go alter your roots, but there was a secondary effect.
Rym: It's even funnier because it could never find a match.
Rym: It would keep widening the net of who it would match this person up against.
Rym: so eventually It would open it up to the lower skill players.
Rym: So he went whenever he did find a game it would only ever be against noobs.
Rym: So it made it even worse.
Scott: and he's just they and then those noobs block him and he fights even newbie or newbie or people And eventually he's just by himself playing against like literally someone who logged in and then died at the controls, right?
Scott: so I think the solution one of the solutions to this that I advocate for that know that the game companies seem to hate is to literally Segregate the population right there.
Scott: So again segregating your player base into two, you know or more groups.
Scott: Well, you can't it like in lizards games, especially overwatch more than anything have so many players.
Scott: Yes I think that you could.
Scott: they could afford to do it.
Scott: You should have serious mode and not serious mode.
Rym: So that is coming.
Rym: that is actually one of the changes that is coming and in and serious mode should be completely different from.
Rym: serious Mode has different rules and it like like they talked about that like regular mode Just the way the game is.
Rym: you'll often.
Rym: the games will often go into overtime if the teams are well matched.
Rym: in Serious mode overtime is a lot more brutal and hopefully a lot more rare.
Scott: I also you know, I think that Syria, you know If it what I've been thinking of for serious mode is it should be a lot more serious in terms of the money You bring this up every time.
Scott: Should it be free to be in serious mode?
Scott: because if you're serious, you should be willing to pay money.
Rym: and what if you're good, but just poor?
Scott: I Then if you you know, if you have a bad skills Then you can play in serious mode and you you know As long as you don't decide whether or not you have to pay.
Rym: Hmm, is it gonna be like a vote or whatever and he gets the reverse scholarship or with all that stuff?
Scott: How does the NFL decide who to give fines to when they misbehave?
Rym: Yeah, but they're serious.
Rym: be those people are being paid.
Scott: Right, if you're so good that you're in serious mode and you've done and you've misbehaved then fuck you.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think that's gonna be a problem.
Rym: serious You could.
Scott: you can choose just not to play in serious mode if you can't and I don't think you go into serious mode for And then as long as you don't misbehave you won't have to pay anything.
Rym: I don't think there is enough of a problem of serious mode in games like this to warrant financial penalties.
Scott: I think there should be some real penalties not just like banning and kicking for people who misbehave in a game and then you could ensure that serious mode is Like this beautiful community of happiness because all the shitheads you're fucking kicked out All they do is all they see.
Rym: you're already doing a very good job.
Rym: Like they're bad people.
Scott: Yeah permanently banned Yes, they're permanently banning them, which is fine.
Scott: But but what I would much rather put a bigger hurt on those people.
Rym: Why does the goal?
Rym: I thought the goal of a justice system is one prevent harm To.
Rym: if harm happens or address it to the biggest extent possible punishment is not even a factor.
Rym: So why are you here?
Rym: So keen on punishment?
Rym: shouldn't the only goal being to prevent harm You prevent a lot more?
Rym: because oh, so you're saying that by punishing people by causing that kind of harm in a sanctioned way You're preventing more harm.
Scott: Threat of a fine versus the threat of a ban will dissuade people from doing it in.
Rym: the Band is actually going.
Rym: so the other day someone used a derogatory term in a match and I mess it up right away.
Rym: It's like I'm gonna report you and he was like what far and I was like you said and you and the player like actually Was like oh and like apologize and then was like super nice the whole rest of the match I'd still report him.
Rym: I did anyway, but But they did apologize and it was like then they were nice the whole rest of the match like.
Rym: that literally happened and That was kind of notable like it stood out in my mind.
Rym: but anyway things of the day Is a cute little blog I found and one of the it's and there's an article here Japanese things in video games and it's basically all these.
Scott: you mean everything cuz.
Scott: video games are Japanese Yeah, but like is it everything in video games Japanese?
Rym: It's in the event There are often sprites.
Scott: I guess they didn't invent video games.
Scott: We invented pong and stuff or particular ways of running real video game.
Rym: that like Japan like for example it points out that Japan in video games almost always depicts apples as Fuji apples was like right on top and yellow on the bottom and explains why.
Rym: that's just a way they happen to draw things.
Rym: Yeah, and apparently Most people in the US and much of the world have always thought that that was a pineapple in Pac-man, but it's actually a honeydew or just a melon.
Rym: because apparently Japan They just call all different melons melons and don't really specify the money.
Rym: melon from the other melons.
Scott: I know honeydew doesn't taste like a cantaloupe.
Rym: It's a different melon Yeah, but melons just a generic term as far as I can tell versus a canary melon is way different.
Rym: Everyone always assumed that was a pineapple in Pac-man.
Rym: Apparently it's actually a honeydew which they would call a melon and it just so happens the Japan.
Rym: They always leave this t-shaped stem on it and that's taken out of the top.
Rym: Everyone thought the sprite was either a grenade or a pineapple But now it's a honeydew melon.
Rym: And my favorite line of this entire thing is peaches are always depicted in this implausible upside-down pose.
Scott: Is this all food related?
Rym: Uh, just the top.
Rym: Here's the whole section on vegetables Okay, and Western foods and the association between fried chicken and Christmas.
Rym: So this is just very interesting.
Rym: if you play a lot of like NES games, especially like those weird Platformers that like you'd see for rental, but like you'd never really played that much You'll see a lot of these as sprites and now you'll know what the hell they are.
Rym: I would have never have guessed that this thing was a baby pacifier.
Scott: Okay Got a thing of the day I do so this dude I don't know how much time he spent on this.
Rym: I mean this baby rattle looks like a push pop.
Scott: Okay, it seems like this dude spent a lot of time on this.
Scott: this video was released today.
Scott: So this thing is brand new.
Scott: He made a doom mod a wad file.
Scott: That is a doom mod and it is a very small doom map But a very elaborate one.
Scott: that is Seinfeld's apartment.
Rym: Scott showed this to me.
Scott: It's it's real good and you don't need to actually download the wad and load it up.
Scott: You can just watch the YouTube video, but the one of the best YouTube comments says what's the deal with double-barreled shotguns?
Scott: And the best comment in reply to that is why not have three barrels to which I say why not?
Scott: That would be great and totally appropriate for a game like doom.
Rym: sometimes I love the internet.
Rym: In the meta moment the book club book a long time ago was the wheel of time.
Rym: I'm literally in the last like hundred pages of the last book of the wheel of time But for the book club, you only had to read the first book of the 14 of the wheel of time Not counting new spring, which is the 15th.
Scott: Wait, did we do the episode on wheel of time long time ago?
Scott: I was like, yeah, we did already.
Scott: Yeah, we did.
Rym: Okay, but the next book club book Which will start probably right after Connecticut is Oryx and Crick by Margaret Atwood.
Rym: I think that'll be fun.
Rym: Otherwise, we're gonna be a Connecticut.
Scott: When is Connecticut the week after the fourth of July?
Rym: Yeah, which is the July 8th 9th and 10th in Hartford Connecticut like three weeks for now.
Rym: Yeah, something like that.
Rym: We were on the panels department.
Rym: The panel schedule is mostly online.
Rym: I got a little bit of work to do to like get everything going.
Rym: but Connecticut's the con.
Rym: But I will warn you our gig nights listeners There's some things that have changed that while the website is being very clear about this.
Rym: I am 100% sure that at least 200 people who show up to Connecticut will not know that this change has occurred.
Rym: the con the Convention Center closes at 9 instead of midnight and then all the 9 p.m To midnight content and the overnight content is in the Marriott Hotel connected.
Rym: I think a lot of people do not know that and it'll be very interesting The people who are surprised when we kick them out of convention center at 855.
Rym: But Connecticut is always fun.
Rym: I would not say fly to Connecticut.
Rym: I'm not say travel multiple days.
Scott: You can get to Connecticut by use of a car or walking or bicycling.
Rym: Yeah, even a train Within the same day.
Scott: It's worth going to.
Scott: I know like if you live in like New York City Is it really worth attending Connecticut by Amtrak as an attendee?
Scott: Yes I don't know.
Rym: I would still go to Connecticut because one the price of the Connecticut ticket is so high.
Rym: Oh, well, I would get in for free.
Rym: Plus how higher all we don't pay for conventions.
Rym: I don't think you realize how expensive conventions.
Scott: I think only tax is more expensive than I mean Anime.
Scott: Boston is cheaper than Connecticut anime expos not cheap.
Rym: If you want to go to any you don't want to go to anime But I would go to Connecticut because I'll put it this way One it's the only con we can perform at that isn't gaming and anime.
Scott: That's not a reason to attend it.
Scott: What's the reason to attend it?
Rym: by buying a ticket other than Pax West Pax East Pax South and Pax Australia and magfest?
Rym: It's the best tabletop convention in America.
Scott: Sure in terms of just that's right.
Scott: Thank you Jen Khan and fuck you origins.
Rym: Also, it actually has really good panels and like the dealers room They're like all that stuff has all the accoutrement of a convention and I just found kind of go to.
Rym: I might even enjoy it more if I wasn't running everything.
Rym: so we'll be there doing some panels - but Yeah, well, we'll see you there.
Rym: Do not expect to hang out with us if you're there because we'll be busy Otherwise.
Rym: Pax Prime is coming up and Pax dev.
Rym: We will debt will definitely be a Pax Prime.
Rym: I assume and hopefully we'll be doing a panel or two at Pax Prime.
Rym: I'll be a Pax dev.
Rym: Maybe Scott will be a Pax day.
Rym: We haven't decided yet and otherwise See you on the internet.
Rym: check out our YouTube videos.
Rym: in particular check out our series on me and Scott playing Civ 5 two-player games because two-player Civ 5 is weird and only military matters.
Rym: Uh, I did not defeat you militarily in the last game.
Rym: I didn't do shit militarily you effectively.
Rym: Well, no, I just built a bunch of cities.
Scott: I did know if you didn't build any military then I could have caravanned all day I.
Rym: yeah Scott my huge military was like one unit that walked over and blocked like your transport.
Scott: Right, so I didn't have enough military to push your military out of the way.
Rym: You should have had a stronger economy.
Scott: So where that would but that was my economy was those caravans.
Rym: don't make your economy something so dependent on the military.
Scott: I don't know how.
Scott: well that's.
Scott: the thing is how do you?
Scott: there's no way to make an economy and Civ that isn't based on Caravans.
Rym: Yeah, there are ways.
Scott: How do you make a lot of money without caravans or cargo ships?
Rym: So I could so in the videos cuz I only put the videos up like once we finish a game I started putting the videos together.
Rym: in the next one You'll see a trick that I pulled where I do build orders and do some bullshit and you're gonna be real mad at what I did.
Scott: How do you make money without caravans a cargo ship?
Rym: There's a few ways.
Rym: one way that's real interesting Scott, especially in a game like this lose the race to build a wonder.
Rym: if You are building a wonder and someone beats you to it all the hammers you put into that turn into cash.
Scott: I didn't know that.
Scott: I thought you just lose everything up every Civ.
Rym: It's turned into cash.
Rym: It turned into cash in Civ 2. you like it was fine.
Rym: I would.
Rym: very often.
Rym: in fact in Civ 5 I have often gone for wonders because I was so desperate for cash that either.
Scott: Hey, I got a wonder I didn't expect but you know in no Civ ever has there been like a pop-up.
Scott: when that happens It says you get you lost X hammers and gained X gold.
Scott: So I never knew that.
Scott: I never knew that until just now.
Rym: Well, you didn't know about the demographics tab.
Scott: until you get in the one game that I put on YouTube All I do is I do I move my units and I click next turn and if a city needs to build something I choose it and I click next turn.
Rym: I move like individual workers.
Scott: I don't pay attention.
Scott: I never I never in my whole life actually paid attention.
Scott: like in Civ 2 in the back in the day I'd open up the city window and they've all these fucking numbers and pictures of barrels of grain and shit.
Scott: I just ignored all that, huh?
Rym: That explains how things are going in the current game.
Rym: then Good luck.
Rym: Have fun.
Rym: So six days ago Scott sent me a link to this reddit thread and It's a pretty amazing thread.
Rym: like I spent a while like.
Rym: I've read a bunch of this thread and it was enjoyable and The title of it is what is the strangest or most unusual strategy in a game?
Rym: you've seen that should never worked but worked but wound up actually working.
Rym: and We were thinking about this because there's you know We talked a lot about up like we just did in the opening and the overwatch news how a lot of people play games But kind of like how a lot of people watch sports But don't know like they don't follow sports that deeply or they have a hobby But they're kind of idly into it like people who say they're into movies or TV, but they don't really know much about them.
Rym: They kind of consume them and watch them, but that's about it.
Rym: games are the same way.
Rym: They're like any other hobby and it was interesting to see all these people right?
Scott: Think about how many people watch Star Wars most people who live in civilized society that have access to movies.
Scott: How many people know?
Scott: Who Mon Mothma is?
Scott: Okay, so how many people play board games?
Scott: tons of people.
Scott: board games are getting still.
Scott: even we've been playing them since like our lives.
Scott: But you know euro types.
Scott: since like 2000 It's only been getting more popular over the past 16 plus years.
Scott: right and still increasing in popularity.
Scott: But how many of those board game people right really?
Scott: Understand when you should craft and when you should captain in Puerto Rico and why?
Scott: no it's really the same The same percentages.
Scott: people know who.
Scott: you know John Dodonah is yeah I guess.
Rym: what's different about this though like what makes it kind of really interesting to me and again everything That's about to follow is all in good fun because reality is people know
Scott: rims basically just gonna insult all those people who don't know Who Mon Mothma is or what a both end looks like?
Scott: Saying that he's not insulting that like someone who says this isn't racist, but I'm not.
Scott: I'm not insulting you.
Rym: But but the thing is with games.
Rym: What's very interesting is that I think they're all stupid games I only half agree are a thing you play You're trying to win.
Rym: you'd assume You're at least trying to if there is a win or at least yeah.
Rym: Or you think you're trying to win or you're playing patty cake and you're just trying to complete patty cake successfully.
Rym: Or maybe you're not me.
Rym: you're trolling in patty cake.
Scott: Maybe it's mario paint.
Rym: it is very interesting to me.
Rym: How many people will say that board gaming is a significant hobby for them and play board games a lot?
Rym: Like to the point that it is the primary Identify.
Rym: it is the primary social currency they bandy about and yet they literally never get better at games.
Scott: They don't have an analytical mindset and they don't try.
Scott: they don't you know.
Scott: They're focused more on the drinking than the act than the gaming.
Scott: Yeah, you know they like the gaming, but they don't like.
Scott: you know they.
Scott: they don't like losing right.
Scott: They just like you know fooling around and moving pieces around.
Scott: They don't you know think about winning and care and even if they did care about winning.
Scott: They can't because they don't think the right way.
Rym: another thing I have noticed this kind of a side thing is there's a lot of people out there who?
Rym: Mostly play games with one group of people and that seems to be the source of most of the posts in this reddit.
Scott: Yeah, because it's basically like me and see I think most board game people are exactly that way.
Scott: They have one group especially if you're in the suburbs.
Scott: Yeah They have their group of players And that's the only people they ever play with.
Rym: ever so even if you're all smart and like super trying to win And like even trying to like analyze the games if your group sort of falls into this rhythm It's very likely that there will be a strategy that no one in your group happened to think of.
Rym: That's just how it goes in a small community like that.
Scott: You know the legend even if you're even if you're a really amazing player.
Scott: right you you need You know.
Scott: you need someone to play against to push you.
Scott: you know to get you know to find the optimal path.
Scott: Otherwise you'll find some path that like you know is really strong against the people.
Scott: you play again.
Rym: local maxima perhaps right?
Scott: But if you play that way against people.
Scott: actually any good You'll still get hosed But you would never find the way to play against those people and win until you play again.
Rym: What was the stories of the go masters going out to the right way province?
Scott: There was some go master who lived in the woods and no one ever beat him.
Scott: And then you know the Shogun was like oh my god.
Scott: I heard legends of this amazing go master Undefeated from the woods invite him to the capital.
Scott: so he comes to the capital and he just gets blitzed by all the actual go Masters who actually play against each other in the capital.
Rym: So what I kind of want to do is this certain experiment.
Scott: Here's a bunch of stories from go masters in the woods.
Rym: Yeah The top comment the 400 point most voted up thing is all sheep plus sheep poor.
Scott: so first of all that's not strange or unusual At all.
Rym: that's like if some way if the other players don't stop you.
Rym: Yeah like duh Right
Scott: also if so in settlers if there's a bunch of sheep tiles near the sheep port or a bunch of brick tiles near the Brick port so that you don't to build a lot of roads because if you have sheep you're not getting a lot of roads Right now you that you can actually set that up like especially if you can put one of yours.
Scott: if you don't go to place The first settlement I like the six and the eight.
Scott: if there's like a five or a ten or something reasonably Okay next to it that you can put your starting settlement on the sheep port and a sheep and put your other one on a Like.
Scott: you go forth in placement, and you can get cheap sheep, then yeah, okay sure other people are gonna Get resources more often, but you only need to get two sheep to get one of anything Automatically so you can basically catch up to them even though you have lower
Rym: odds and frankly the people who and
Scott: mathematically it could be About equal and then of course luck if swings your way if they're not rolling a lot of sixes and eighths which can happen.
Scott: Yeah, you can win really easily.
Scott: It's like just a couple rolls where you get two sheep.
Scott: It's just like whoo.
Rym: and what's even more interesting is if you don't like if you let this happen Like the kind of person who would let someone get a sheep port and a bunch of easy access to sheep Those are the kinds of people who are gonna lose to that person.
Scott: right if I see if I see Rym starting settlements are On my grain grain grain, and I see him put her his first road aiming towards the grain port.
Scott: I'm going to put on the grain port to prevent him from putting a settlement on the grain Settlers game is determined in.
Scott: but say someone who is not really good at settlers isn't going to see that a settlers.
Rym: I can see it from the first road.
Rym: in this order.
Rym: one.
Rym: Do you know how the game works?
Rym: You know yes, or no, and if that's tied go down to the next tier which is in fact I didn't even need to put a sediment.
Scott: I just need to put my longest road to black.
Rym: Number two now how the dice shake out.
Rym: number three who place their settlements where?
Rym: in the very beginning of the game The only way you will ever see sheep port plus sheep.
Rym: and actually of all the ports she poured plus sheep is by the best one Because then you're probably doing a sheep grain strategy if we're gonna do the tripods and go for you need rock to get stiffy Cards also right.
Scott: yeah, you can always get some rock with your sheep port But I feel like the brick wood port is actually the best because you can use roads from all you start on brick And woods that have good odds.
Scott: you get a lot of bricks and woods.
Scott: you can road your way over to a brick or a Wood port and put us put a settlement on it then Use that.
Scott: you keep getting bricks and woods But through the rest of the game without having to settle on the rocks grains and sheeps.
Scott: you can get them using the port.
Scott: so In the early game you get the roads And then you can upgrade to the cities and then the game is probably over by then.
Rym: the only way you'll ever see this happen In a game of skilled players is if the person who does it had to go forth.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: yeah cuz.
Scott: then you can guarantee Because I mean if you're not gonna get the good placement of going first or second on the high odds Spots of where the sixes and eights are you make a perfect?
Scott: You're gonna need to use a port in order to catch up with your bad odds spots.
Rym: so Here's what's real interesting.
Rym: Well.
Rym: Here's a comment on that one.
Rym: This is ready.
Rym: my first game.
Rym: I ruled sheep.
Rym: I started naming them and eventually played my monopoly dev card just to get more sheep in my sheep army.
Rym: I didn't win the game you don't say But I felt like a winner.
Scott: you're supposed to trade away all your sheep and then play your monopoly sheep card And then spend them all.
Rym: well, so someone else.
Rym: Here's a more fun way to use your monopoly card.
Rym: It'll make you end up with just as many friends as the game of Monopoly.
Scott: It's always like yeah That's baby's first settlers.
Rym: But to look at these these kinds of discussions because it's almost always People who like came up with a clever idea that they don't think anyone else has really come up with like it's.
Scott: like dude I've seen that it's 16 years old that move.
Rym: So Trade all the others and often the strategies are bad, too Like that monopoly thing that only works if it's kind of a noob game anyway, I guess Yeah, I mean if I see Rym is like hey anyone want sheep.
Scott: He starts trading sheep away.
Rym: I'm like Scott's like Rym never trades.
Scott: Yeah, well also.
Scott: I'm like no Rym.
Scott: I don't want your fucking she Give me them for free.
Scott: Maybe that's about it.
Scott: I see you trading away a big mountain of sheep But you just take your turn and we'll roll a seven.
Scott: you got that fist full of sheep there.
Scott: throw some of them out to the robber Pull this off once.
Rym: yeah a lot of people are obsessed with the sheep thing.
Rym: mmm whatever It's interesting to watching people explain like the situation they've run into now.
Rym: There's all these people talking about like fours and fives never get rolled and like nines never get rolled.
Scott: What are you talking about?
Scott: It's based on odds.
Scott: There's dots on the numbers that tell you how much they get rolled.
Rym: There's general disdain for Catan.
Rym: a lot of people myself included feel there's too much like involved.
Rym: I think there is exacerbated by many folk my family that think it's 100% strategy.
Scott: It's more strategy than games.
Scott: They're used to yeah.
Rym: Oh, here's a good one.
Rym: We have a friend who doesn't look at her cards and coo.
Rym: does that count?
Rym: She's had enough success To have fun and use it regularly.
Rym: It's a dumb game first of all but there's all these people who seemed like a really really trying to explain Whether or not this is a good or bad strategy and a lot of them seem really It doesn't even matter really.
Scott: and coo if you look at your cards or not Yeah, well you can do the same thing and you just use whichever power is most advantageous Yeah, and in fact against most people the intimidation of not ever having looked at your own cards is enough to scare them.
Rym: Oh, it makes it harder to read whether you're bluffing or not.
Rym: bluffing doesn't exist.
Rym: Yeah game like this.
Scott: Well, I mean you know there are people who try to like actually read.
Scott: other people like look at their eyes and whatever.
Scott: But if you didn't look at your own cards, yeah, you don't know if you're but you just do whatever ability you want to you.
Rym: Whoa, here's someone who sees through the gnosis.
Rym: This is a this is great.
Rym: It becomes Impossible to know if you're bluffing or not because you're not bluffing.
Rym: now you're gambling.
Rym: it changes the game to a game of probability.
Rym: But since it's usually only for one player blah blah blah.
Rym: It would utterly lose the nature of coo if the whole whole table played that way.
Rym: I think yep.
Rym: You're right, dude All the all games.
Rym: that's why we don't play settlers.
Rym: that game breaks down.
Scott: we don't play coo.
Rym: That's why you don't play citadels played.
Scott: So once I was done citadels became a game of literally.
Rym: everyone shuffles the cards and plays the round randomly every turn Not every turn.
Rym: but you know, I'd always make it look like I was yeah They well what I would do is I would usually I would narrow it down to two.
Rym: that would be advantageous to me.
Scott: Yeah, because there is some that you pick and it's like yeah if I pick this one, it's really just yeah Useless.
Rym: like if I want to pick the bishop, I'd shuffle the bishop and some random card.
Scott: So I got a 50/50 shot like if I have a whole bunch of red cards, you know, and I picked the merchant It's like it's not helping me.
Scott: I you know, I need.
Scott: I need to pick the warlord or like the assassin or the thief or something.
Rym: Lot of people talk about coup diplomacy where my friend Kyle didn't ever say a word.
Rym: We thought he was just being silly bringing Hubert a serious game.
Rym: It didn't think of his movements.
Rym: later He controlled most of Russia Turkey in the Balkans to retrieve him as a threat and we lost.
Scott: I mean you just couldn't you see after like the first turns orders that he took territory from you?
Rym: Well, I don't know.
Rym: I mean the problem with that game is that to Li with someone, you know Diplomacy is actually very difficult to parse the interactions Unless you've played it a lot and even then like it takes a while to chart it out.
Rym: So planning the interaction is very difficult.
Rym: So I suspect among most people who played diplomacy unless they play it like seriously and regularly Not coordinating with other people and only relying on yourself would probably do you really well for a really long time?
Scott: I mean at least not after the first turn.
Scott: after the second turn you see that this person who hasn't said anything has Only gained territory.
Scott: I would unite against them.
Rym: Well, what you got to do?
Rym: some bullshit diplomacy with people that I had a non cooperative game.
Scott: I diplomacy with the people who were all you know.
Scott: Obviously he lost that territory by getting that territory by taking it from someone right?
Scott: So and hopefully it wasn't me, but if it was me, I would be.
Scott: you know, I'm the person next to him, right?
Scott: So I picked the other person that lost territory to him.
Scott: I was like look this guy took land from both of us.
Scott: in the last two turns You and me were teaming up.
Scott: take him out and back you not talking person either to start talking or else we're coming for you Right, and then we go to a room with the other person.
Rym: we make a plan to get him and we get him But then I if I was in the plan to get him.
Rym: I just betray you.
Scott: Why now that you're gonna just get it?
Scott: you can just get killed in the back by the guy who's better than you.
Rym: Whoo, I had a friend who won a game of small world underground without declining his empire ever.
Scott: He didn't.
Scott: we must have had it.
Scott: Oh, he destroyed.
Scott: Well, I that must have been a an amazing Empire.
Scott: Yep be you didn't come into the board on to it.
Rym: Yeah, no one attacked him.
Rym: more importantly small world has a problem like Vinci was did he say which what match what?
Scott: Empire was.
Rym: let's see iron dwarves.
Scott: What do iron dwarves?
Rym: The underground version of small world immortal iron dwarves Mortally, oh another person.
Rym: I've seen immortal iron dwarves run an entire game.
Scott: Do they have like super defense?
Scott: You can't take them out easily.
Scott: Is that what it is?
Scott: You can.
Rym: just the best way to counter iron dwarves is too kind.
Rym: I think he's typing wrong.
Rym: kill off the dwarves set by the tip Wyatt.
Scott: I can't parse with this person typed Yeah, I mean if they can't beat a guy who hasn't declined to Empire.
Scott: but yeah, it's in Vinci small world if you can defend your empire and Because when you decline it you basically take a turn of losing points, right?
Scott: But then your new Empire gets you more points.
Scott: where you're declining one still gets you some points and it evens out Yep, so you gotta decline at least once.
Scott: but if you can if you can defend and the territory You've claimed is large enough and worth enough points every turn that you won't actually gain any and no one can it.
Scott: no one assaults You to decrease your point value or they can't because your defense is so strong.
Scott: You can just sit on it.
Scott: It's perfect.
Scott: What's wrong with that?
Scott: Now the prize is calculating point maximum points per turn.
Rym: the problem is that is you give up the opportunity cost of when you decline You.
Rym: the goal the point the purpose of declining is to come back on the board and fucking roll someone else.
Scott: But if you're in first place, you don't need to roll someone else.
Rym: Yep, unless someone's getting close.
Rym: So basically you only decline if you're in that winning strategy.
Rym: if there's a second place person who's close to you You pick an opportune turn and just decline all over them.
Rym: But otherwise, yeah Don't either.
Scott: you guys must have been sucking so much that a you didn't attack him Right B. There was never a better sieve to choose when he declined.
Rym: So why'd have been in like a Nash equilibria situation word like no individual player.
Rym: declining would actually be better off Right.
Scott: Also, they're just hanging out in first place.
Scott: if they were in last place.
Scott: Yeah, they're gonna decline.
Scott: They needed to catch up by doing something.
Rym: but now the iron I wonder because I haven't played small world underground.
Rym: But it's possible too that the iron dwarves might be slightly degenerate.
Rym: Maybe that's I don't know.
Scott: if I don't know what they do.
Scott: What it look up what they do.
Rym: Look up what they do.
Rym: iron is immortal.
Rym: iron dwarves, but Small world unlike Vinci has a set number of turns.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: Warves as opposed to Vinci where the game ends when someone gets to a certain number of points.
Rym: So with a fixed number of turns There's a lot more Determinism to how the game will get.
Scott: immortal mean they don't die like you just always have the same number of dudes Even if they get killed.
Rym: So all I found is all these threads of people saying immortal iron dwarves fucking win the game and they never decline.
Rym: There are multiple set people as threads on board game.
Scott: What do they do though?
Scott: silver hammers is immortal mean?
Scott: They don't die like you could get killed and you put them back on the board next turn.
Scott: Let's see That's the reason you decline is because your empire shrinking because people are killing it off.
Scott: if they're immortal as the word says Then yeah, you don't need to decline.
Scott: you all used to love the same number of dudes you had before.
Rym: Uh, it's there's mines.
Rym: There's some complicated shit.
Rym: So the rules don't make sense without the wider context of the additions in small world underground, I guess yeah I don't know.
Rym: But I suspect degenerate combos are a much bigger problem in the small world variant than in the original Vinci just because of the deterministic number of turns.
Rym: Yeah Cuz you can predict if there's only three turns then if I decline now Then I'll come in on the board next turn.
Rym: then I've got one more turn as opposed to Vinci of will the game end?
Rym: Let's figure it out.
Rym: I could make the game end like that kind of stuff.
Rym: Yep I won code words by randomly guessing words that were far away from the other words of my team's color Shouldn't have worked, but we won.
Scott: I mean, I guess you can win that by luck.
Rym: Sure Yeah, you can also win that by Clever innuendo Or just by the right was the right way to play it.
Rym: Yeah I've seen people win Sheriff of Nottingham by focusing almost exclusively on illegal goods.
Rym: lies bribes people at least 80% of the time.
Rym: People say playing honest is best.
Rym: I'm not sure.
Rym: Yeah, it's a lot game.
Rym: if you can play Sheriff of Nottingham and you happen to have like five apples in your hand That is the best possible thing you could do right because it's a win-win no matter what right.
Scott: and if someone if no one Calls you out you at least get them the minimum number of points or the five apples and if they open your bag You're just getting even more points and you get your five, you know, busy only benefit, right?
Scott: You can get this much or that much and more.
Scott: so that's you know with honesty.
Scott: But if you don't have a lot of legal goods, you know, why not try the illegal goods?
Scott: You can get you know negative a little bit Maybe not much.
Scott: you can maybe put in some legal ones to cancel it out And if you're get through super big money It's you know, there's not really any sort of weird strategy and Sheriff of Nottingham It's like any.
Scott: pretty much any move is valid.
Rym: I think most strategies people come up with rely on trying to second-guess other people.
Rym: poison cup situation.
Scott: Yeah, no, it's just put whatever the fuck you want in the bag and then go for it.
Scott: It's like, you know, yeah It's yeah, they're gonna work.
Scott: They open it or they're not right.
Rym: So there's a strategy I was gonna try at some point but I was thinking of always putting four goods in my bag no matter what and Always offering a two coin bribe no matter what.
Scott: I mean if I have five apples, why would I put four apples?
Rym: Well, it's for consistency to remove any human.
Scott: You're just losing a point if you do that.
Scott: Maybe more maybe more than a point.
Rym: This guy's favorite play and sheriff is stuffing a bag with five illegals to five crossbows.
Rym: and yeah in the offer I'll give you ten gold if you open everyone's bag including my own.
Rym: hmm That's a clever sort of gambit to scare the sheriff.
Scott: I guess I'd say okay Give me the ten and then I'll open all the bags including his.
Scott: yeah Yeah Just like you said.
Rym: cuz actually the the penalty to the sheriff of opening a bag that was legit is way less bad Than the penalty to you if the sheriff opens your bag and you were lying bad Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's real bad.
Rym: If you have five crossbows and the sheriff's like, let me open that bag.
Rym: What's going on in there?
Rym: Yeah But yeah, I mean I like sheriff of Nottingham looks like there's a lot of people talking about it, but The game is not a super good Like.
Scott: if you don't know how you put that in a thread of unusual strategy because the game has no unusual strategy.
Scott: Yeah, it's like there's no valid or invalid moves.
Rym: Oh, we played one game of Catan where I just went for dev cards.
Rym: I guess this guy Rediscovered the old stiffy card strategy.
Scott: You don't say you did that.
Rym: you only had you know Not the usual wheat and stone city and development card strat Just development cards because he couldn't build any settlements.
Rym: You know getting nine points.
Rym: Oh, he's talking about cities and nights.
Scott: Totally different game whatever.
Rym: Yeah, that's it.
Rym: That's not that.
Rym: Let's see take it to ride.
Rym: We discovered the best way to get points was to build one good distance route and then pick up tickets.
Rym: You can hopefully finish with a minimal number of branches off your main route.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: That's the base.
Scott: That's not unusual.
Scott: That's how you win ticket to ride.
Scott: every time I win ticket to ride which is most of the times I've played I have a Big ass long route and all of my smaller routes are contained within it.
Scott: So I get I put down a train is doing double duty and completing multiple routes.
Rym: Oh, this guy's a troll.
Rym: I ended up having an awful game one.
Rym: So I got pissed off and decided to screw everyone else by spending every turn picking up tickets and keeping them all.
Rym: I had no Intention trying to finish them.
Rym: I was just playing a material denial strategy to prevent my friends from doing well.
Rym: I ended with negative 143 points.
Rym: You're just a dick.
Scott: Yeah, fuck you.
Rym: Uh This guy claims to have won a paper rock scissors tournament by always picking rock.
Scott: Maybe it's not unusual though.
Scott: Yeah, it just I mean no one noticed.
Rym: Oh There's a bunch of people talking about in viticulture Winning the game by not making any wine.
Scott: wasn't there a situation where they changed the rules so you can do?
Rym: Yeah, they had to a rat of that which that's all separate situation.
Rym: That's viticulture when we first played it like it.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: that is necessarily that bad of a game like.
Rym: it's clever and I like a lot of what it's doing.
Rym: But if the part where the aging of the wines is a little messed up It was like the concepts were too muddled and it was very in elegant mechanically yeah, so I suspected that any deep analysis would find a bunch of either broken strategies or Degenerate stuff.
Rym: It looks like there was one.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I didn't winning didn't make anyone not one bottle and People are talking about it.
Scott: Just give wine tours.
Rym: Yeah, they had to make specific errata to say to fix that.
Scott: Mm-hmm The problem with any I mean, why did you award someone victory points in your rules for doing something?
Scott: That wasn't making wine in the winemaking game.
Rym: well, I mean in in Kayla's you can make money by pleasing the king and the giant castle is the whole focus of the game or Just by going after gold and other stuff.
Scott: That's not it.
Scott: It's not easy to do though.
Scott: And actually those tiles like expansion special tiles that weren't in the original Yeah, yeah, if you didn't have that there's really only one way to win Kayla's.
Rym: Yeah, unless everyone sucks There's a lot of talk about the rules of.
Rym: people are not sure what rules are in there's.
Rym: it's like these people look like They're arguing about how to score farmers in Carcassonne.
Scott: So these people are into board games enough that they're in the board game reddit subreddit and they're hanging out and commenting But they don't understand the actual games they're playing.
Rym: Well, you know it.
Rym: to be fair in this case Different rule books say different things like people don't know.
Rym: quote any link on this errata like they don't know about it.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm saying in general.
Rym: I would definitely like to shut this strategy down.
Scott: It's how about you?
Scott: just don't play that crappy game.
Rym: It's okay Yeah, it's kind of a side point.
Rym: but the games that come out of like their traditional like Eurogamer circuit Tend seem to have a lot of play testing and tend to be at least elegant or don't have degenerate strategies like that.
Rym: Like they'll break down in other more fundamental ways in the long run because all games break down.
Rym: But all these Kickstarter games and like a lot of the games that are coming out of the US or coming out of like newer game designers They seem to skimp on the play testing and like not notice these really bad degenerate strategies Like long after they publish the game.
Rym: Yeah, that seems like a trend.
Rym: hmm, oh My god people are talking about that a lot.
Rym: Friend tried a strategy where he chose prospector every time he chose a role in San Juan and beat us soundly.
Scott: You guys just sucked.
Rym: also San Juan is not a good game.
Rym: Yeah I could see prosper that working pretty well.
Scott: because the game is everyone keeps choosing everything else for you.
Scott: You know, well that games also prospector only benefits you and you take it, right?
Rym: It's just so reliant on the cards.
Rym: you get like if you happen to get silver and full of silver mines.
Rym: Just play the only building silver mine strategy.
Rym: You almost guaranteed win.
Scott: That's how we always won.
Rym: Yep, the only time I wouldn't win with that is if I didn't draw silver mines.
Scott: It's a.
Rym: uh My daughter who was five was playing love letter and discarded the countess.
Rym: on her first turn.
Rym: It turned out.
Rym: her other card was the priest.
Rym: I thought she was making a mistake.
Rym: She wasn't.
Rym: she was screwing with us.
Rym: I threw us off so bad round netted pretty quickly.
Rym: I kind of stuff just happens in really small short games.
Rym: I mean if there's only a few cards and you draw them the odds are weird.
Rym: combos come up pretty often.
Rym: Mm-hmm I also.
Rym: it's a Love letter is fun because it's quick, but it's not enjoyable.
Scott: It's also what you get for trying to play the player and not play the game.
Rym: Yeah Thing is most of these kinds of games will break down to trying to play the player or doing the poison cup thing Don't do that.
Rym: We were playing a ticket to ride game with a card hoarder who was a new person to our group.
Rym: Alright so someone came to.
Rym: it's.
Rym: a stranger came to town.
Rym: We were warned.
Rym: she claims routes only near the end of the game and wins every time.
Scott: So you even knew what the strategy was in advance?
Rym: Oh, apparently they crush her.
Rym: Nobody had ever tried to block her routes before.
Rym: Okay, so this was the stranger comes to town with the undefeated record and the weird strategy.
Rym: and she comes to town and in the Town, they're like, we just won't let you finish those routes.
Rym: Now.
Rym: What what?
Scott: Yeah, all the routes have been taken.
Scott: What are you gonna do?
Scott: card hoarding person?
Rym: Yeah I'll card hoard in Alhambra.
Rym: actually all the card organ Alhambra like ignore the first score.
Scott: Yeah That works a little bit.
Rym: or die hell out of those.
Rym: like if you can pick up like a 1 1 2 like little currency Go for it.
Rym: Just get a giant hand on ones and twos.
Scott: There's no limit on cards in your hand.
Rym: There is I'm pretty sure there's no limit on cards in your hand.
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: in a Splendor there's a limit of 10.
Rym: Yeah, that's real important or splendor wouldn't work.
Scott: I don't play in splendor lately Uh, I don't lose it splendor too much.
Rym: Uh, I was there was a pretty close game the other night.
Rym: it was lost in the girls and Natalie was like prime to win.
Rym: But the whole time Emily was building up this combo and then suddenly Emily was like but but but but points over game over.
Scott: Yeah I mean I've tried to do the both the get lots of small ones and then start getting free stuff.
Scott: machine Yeah, and I've also tried the big stuff one and I think the small stuff one is just better.
Scott: Yeah, yeah the cards come out.
Scott: it's on my turn I get a free card free car.
Scott: eventually I was like I only have to take tokens in the early game and pretty much every turn after that is just card card card And you'll end the game with like a few big ones.
Scott: and then I have two or three of the nobles.
Scott: Well, I have to get the nobles.
Scott: Yeah, so I usually get two or three nobles and I end the game.
Rym: I usually go for that if I see multiple novers nobles with a heavy overlap of what they want.
Scott: But it's real easy.
Rym: if there's something you could get for free that is not in the combo of the nobles You're gonna have the discipline to not take it.
Rym: Mmm, like don't take the freebie that literally doesn't help you spend that turn.
Rym: picking up gold or spend so many victory points is worth.
Scott: Sometimes there's a card worth like three points and the nobles were three.
Rym: I once won a three player seven wonders game by not building a single resource.
Rym: Yeah, that's like strategy number four.
Rym: Yeah, that's like.
Rym: that is like a game strategy Constrain stringing.
Scott: this isn't unusual.
Scott: Yeah, is there any strategies in the Strad that are actually meet what the title of the thread says?
Scott: Which is unusual.
Rym: Well, they might be unusual for that group.
Rym: Sure Founding fathers looking for game of mafia.
Rym: Oh mafia.
Rym: with three mafia and 12 town One of the mafia outed himself and offered himself to the chopping block.
Rym: No one believed him and the mafia won.
Rym: Okay, uh The only thing I say about mafia is I do still enjoy that game if played like once a year like Illuminati.
Scott: I just want to play it the original way but I have to communicate during the day.
Rym: probably the most poignant moment is sort of proving the breakdown of those like perfect strategies.
Rym: and It's a friend of ours.
Rym: It was Phil.
Rym: The game started.
Rym: He was obviously not mafia and he was like guys.
Rym: and he was like, let's just systematically eliminate everyone We're guaranteed to win.
Rym: and he's trying to outline the strategy and all the mafia just like played along with it but then acted confused and gay like started to mess stuff up and It like one round.
Rym: the strategy failed it misfired and then it was too late.
Rym: the mafia were guaranteed to win.
Rym: It was over.
Rym: you can disrupt those things socially pretty easily.
Rym: Mmm Dracula pirate lord of the high seas furry of Dracula.
Rym: that is a game strategy.
Rym: Once again I've played that round.
Rym: we like you start on an island you go ocean ocean double back ocean And just basically stay off the map for a while.
Scott: Yep It's too easy for them to find you on land.
Rym: Yeah Tragedy looper.
Rym: I don't know what that game is village.
Rym: Very smart moves.
Rym: as one of your family members beginning I'm promising new current town hall and have him die of a heart attack on his first day.
Rym: Yeah, that game is all about killing your people like as soon as possible like kill people early and often yeah, which is actually why I don't like the game because the the conceit of the game Sort of breaks like like what the fiction of the game world is and like the analogy of it kind of breaks down when the strategies Really break down to kill people all the time and push the clock.
Scott: I think that the problem in the game is simply the timing and pacing of it is.
Scott: It should be a game where you can get a lot more work out of people before they die And then you would get more stuff happening, right?
Rym: It seems like, you know, it'd be more fun That there are a bunch of people complaining about winning games of small world without ever declining.
Rym: This is regular small world Skeletons fortified kept putting fortresses down till I was maxed out.
Rym: Position myself for going after me would be costly.
Scott: just waited And it worked.
Scott: Yeah Cuz I mean anyone who goes after you to prevent you from winning will not be the winner and you won't.
Scott: you won't be the Winner either.
Scott: one of the other people who don't do who don't bite the bullet will be the winner But if no one does it you're gonna win.
Rym: risk taking over Asia first, uh What's unusual about that?
Scott: If you can take over Asia you can win the game.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, it's just dice.
Scott: You might get lucky score the highest point continent first.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: What's that?
Scott: Was that unusual?
Rym: Stone Age starvation strategy, uh Uh Grow a really large family ignore farming and food a hundred percent.
Rym: Apparently that's a winnable strategy not in Agricola though.
Rym: Nope that I kind of a problem with all the games that followed after Agricola that are like.
Rym: in that vein of like make a machine and then You got to feed your people because they all like the analogies start to break down It will lahav like doesn't fucking make any actual sense.
Rym: It's not a bad game.
Rym: It doesn't make any sense.
Rym: Yeah Two player block is.
Rym: I went first.
Rym: he mirrored every single move of mine for the entire game except the very last move.
Scott: They win.
Rym: he played a better piece and won.
Rym: we played it again.
Scott: Why didn't you play that same piece?
Scott: Also to play right she went first.
Scott: he went second in two-player block.
Scott: is it should be possible for you to play in such A way that they cannot marry you because you fucking block them?
Scott: Yep Why do you played a piece in every turn that which could just be mirrored so that you cut the exact same score?
Scott: and then?
Scott: The very final piece when you could only each play one more piece yet the exact same board You played a suboptimal piece that they can play a better one.
Scott: So you just stupid.
Rym: not sure if this is strange or the best but in camel up which he spelled wrong I never roll unless I am first to play on that leg.
Rym: other than that I always leg bet tiles or overall bets.
Scott: Ah Yes, you I only roll after a whole bunch of betting is happened.
Rym: No, but he never rolls unless he is the first to play on that leg.
Scott: If I'm going first why would you go first and give everyone else free information and just take a dollar for yourself?
Rym: It sounds like the opposite of what he should do.
Scott: Yes I should be betting first.
Scott: that or the first thing you want to do is put your oasis your desert out.
Rym: now It depends how many players there are because if you're playing with a small number of players you roll you're gonna get more actions.
Rym: Yeah, it'll come back around to you and all the things you could have taken more like.
Rym: I could see that working But in a full game no way.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Scott: winner of the thread.
Rym: Someone said someone asterix was like it's camel up.
Rym: Someone else said no, it's a mole cup.
Scott: You're the winner.
Rym: Con man out you.
Rym: that's the funniest thing I've seen all day.
Scott: Can I go eat now?
Rym: You want to be done?
Scott: I want to be done.
Rym: All right, let me see there.
Rym: I'm gonna skip through this caching guns.
Rym: I'm skipping through.
Rym: there's a lot of interesting stuff in this thread.
Rym: We'll just leave it at that good hungry.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night
Rym: And the patrons and the amount of money that they give us on a regular continuing basis are Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Nicholas Brando, Heidi McNichol, Amanda Duchette, James David White, Christian, close parentheses, Kuntz, MyStady.com, Sean Hayworth, William Isenrose, Jeremy Minor, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn, Israel, Iggy Kid, Matthew Smith, Kjartavishan, Joshua Joestar, Tyler Eller, Don Schleich, Sean Yeager, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Robert Lee, Ryan Perrin, Drew Oppenlander, Ray LaValle, Brian Citroni, Rochelle Montanota, Finn, Eric Silverrod, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn, Aaron Cerise, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, Flame Darkfire, Sam Cordery, Daniel Redman, Chris Adon, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Multiple of you conspired to make me laugh, and that credit points to.
Rym: But yeah, many of you have been playing Overwatch with me.
Rym: Many of you will be playing Overwatch with me.
Rym: Valhalla just came out.
Rym: I say everyone's playing that instead of Overwatch.
Rym: But, ConnectiCon's coming up.
Rym: We're basically done doing the schedule and a lot of the work I have to do before ConnectiCon.
Rym: So, hopefully this weekend I should get another remastered GeekNights up.
Rym: I got a whole queue of Rym's Rants, and more importantly, I should have the Utena episode, episode 15 up too.
Rym: It's mostly edited.
Rym: I just haven't had time to finish it, getting all the ConnectiCon work done.
Rym: But after ConnectiCon, I have nothing significant to do until PAX.
Rym: And PAX panels are a lot easier to write because I don't have to schedule the entirety of PAX.
Rym: I just have to do one or maybe two panels.
Rym: So anyway, now I leave you with something else.
Media: Here's the baby's bath.
Media: Here's the baby.
Media: I'm not even going to try and draw arms and legs.
Media: So, sad baby because quite frankly, yeah.
Media: Electricity.
Media: And just for the sake of completeness, let's put its Mr.
Media: Whippy in its head.
Media: Whippy.
Rym: Whippy.
Media: And here's the electrode.
Media: Plugged into the wall.
Media: Accidentally.
Media: There's the water.
Media: And this would act as a potential divider.
Media: It would be putting out if that was 220.
Media: This would be putting out 110.
Media: Roughly the midpoint of, well unless of course, actually how does that go?
Media: You know, it's quite complex.
Media: It's quite an odd resistor network.
Media: But other than that, the water would be forming another resistor from the midpoint of that.
Media: Oh, this is boiling quite ferociously now.
Media: The currents, the voltage, the power's going down.
Media: But yeah, so touching the baby, if it was dropped into that water, you would get a shock.
Media: But it would depend on the conductivity of the water, how far the baby was from the electrode, and how grounded you were at the time.
Media: So rubber gloves for baby handling in live water perhaps.