Rym: It's Monday, April 4th, 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight some specific hadoken.
Rym: no That's actually a weird inside joke.
Rym: the show is about HFS plus and case sensitivity.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So as you all know I was at Zenkai con this past weekend doing a bunch of panels.
Rym: It was really fun con, but mistakes are made.
Rym: Yes on the way home because Amtrak's the only way to get to Lancaster, Pennsylvania.
Rym: now if you get there with a car Amtrak's the only way to get to Lancaster, Pennsylvania.
Scott: get there with a helicopter.
Rym: I don't think there's a helipad anywhere in Lancaster.
Scott: You could just a big empty field.
Scott: I mean come on and you could.
Scott: you could walk and you could bike there You could motorcycle there.
Scott: so on the way home, and there must be a nearby river.
Scott: Can you boat that?
Rym: our only real complaints about Lancaster?
Rym: You know when we would go because this time Scott bailed was just me.
Rym: go to the convention.
Rym: good move One.
Rym: there's nothing open on Sunday, so you can't get any food and everything sucks.
Scott: Yeah, it's Jesus town.
Scott: Yeah, we're talking Amish Jesus not born-again Jesus, and that is no longer the case.
Rym: weirdly so last year on Sunday There was nothing to eat.
Rym: We went to the one restaurant that was open and just like drank beer and had crappy bar The thing only thing that was open on Sunday was like the donut place.
Rym: uh that donut place did not appear to be open I couldn't tell but that tap room was open.
Rym: you remember the tap room.
Scott: Yeah the one with the upstairs Yeah, there's two tap rooms now.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: There's two places called the tap room that are very similar.
Scott: Why don't you just call if it's not the same owner?
Scott: Why don't you call one of them like the keg room or something?
Rym: one's called the something tap room and someone the other is called The something else tap room.
Scott: uh-huh.
Rym: I just we just call it tap room, but anyway uncreative town.
Rym: so now There were like seven or eight restaurant.
Rym: basically every restaurant That's new is open on Sunday and every restaurant that was already there when we had last visited Lancaster Not open.
Scott: I'm surprised there isn't like an ordinance that they have to be closed on Sunday.
Scott: I was you who's in control all the places on Sunday.
Rym: We're super hipster.
Rym: They had basically the same kind of brunch food.
Rym: you get it like sage or LIC market here.
Scott: Just so basically even Lancaster could not escape shitty pot town.
Rym: Yeah And you know what shitty pot town is real great when you have to visit the town For two days and you want somewhere to eat on Sunday, so I actually had a really good brunch.
Rym: look Sunday was fun Sunday was a good day, but then I went home.
Rym: You know as you might have seen me tweeting Amtrak Hit somebody like my train hit somebody.
Scott: Now well it hit workers cuz.
Rym: no no no no you keep saying that that is not what I said yesterday.
Scott: No No The news is lying.
Rym: an Amtrak train like eight hours before that in the morning Hit a backhoe that was working on the wrong track.
Rym: It was just a bag.
Rym: someone just pulled a backhoe up onto an active Amtrak line and the next train that came hit it And killed everybody involved.
Rym: mm-hmm least everybody in the back up no one in the train.
Scott: So the Amtrak workers were killed.
Rym: I think it was just regular construction workers not Amtrak workers.
Rym: But so Amtrak's investigating why the fuck they were just like on the wrong track, but I was like oh crap Maybe I'll get a home.
Rym: Then I look online and Amtrak's like no your trains totally fine because you're coming from the Harrisburg line So we'll bypass the actual derailment.
Rym: all right cool.
Rym: I get on my train at the end of the day and suddenly the train emergency brakes.
Scott: Someone pulled the stupid thing.
Rym: no so the train just hit someone on the tracks totally unrelated to that other accident train.
Scott: You were on his train.
Rym: I was on just fucking hit somebody on the same day.
Rym: Yes So I learned a lot about what happens when an Amtrak train hits someone.
Scott: sits there for a while?
Rym: No, but I learned about why it sits there for a while because the conductor was a super chill dude.
Rym: And I was talking to him the conductor or the engineer.
Rym: the conductor the engineer was not Around to talk because he had to do something stupid.
Rym: He had to.
Rym: so the train hit a human being.
Scott: killed somebody the train?
Rym: no He did.
Rym: so the train hit a human being.
Rym: the guy survived who got hit?
Scott: apparently what stuff Amtrak's go away?
Rym: fat I mean there, but he was severely injured, but he was not dead at that moment, okay?
Rym: The train could have just kept gone on like and left this guy lying there like ambulance.
Rym: I came immediately like they took care of.
Rym: that was fine.
Scott: the train could have just kept going with this bloody smear on the front Pulling into Penn Station.
Rym: Uh yeah, actually they.
Rym: they pulled into Penn Station without cleaning it off,
Scott: okay,
Rym: but The rules that Amtrak has to follow from the federal level are so Ridiculous and overbearing that because the train was involved in any sort of incident at all Basically the engineer Himself had to get off the train and walk the entire length of the train on both sides Inspecting the entire train and sign off on all these pieces of bullshit information along the way Before they could continue.
Rym: the train is over a half mile long.
Rym: it took him a long time to walk all The way around the train and they weren't allowed to leave until he did it.
Scott: couldn't you just like improve this with some technology?
Rym: You can improve the cameras underneath the train.
Rym: improve this Scott in any number of ways.
Scott: a bunch of sensors.
Scott: So like you're on an airplane, right?
Rym: It's like yeah, Scott airplanes do manual inspections.
Rym: the same way.
Scott: I know airplanes do manual inspections, but in the cockpit.
Scott: There's a bunch of lights that show you what's working.
Rym: What's that?
Rym: - but because it struck something even though it was a soft human who was very unlikely to have caused any damage to To the mighty train could not be defeated by the squishy human.
Rym: Remember the rhinos the Rhino ads in Australia and Melbourne like don't fuck around with the tram you don't is a rhino six rhinos.
Rym: So, uh, yeah the three or whatever hour delay was 90% stupid Amtrak rules and the actual crisis was dealt with almost immediately.
Rym: and That was my night.
Scott: How did the ambulance get down into the train track?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It was right next to a road Like.
Rym: I guess it was easy.
Rym: People were walking up there people were walking up and down like going to the front like knock out the window and see what was going On.
Scott: and yeah, I don't want to go see dead bodies Severely injured bodies.
Rym: Yeah, but apparently this happens kind of often.
Rym: It's called.
Scott: they call you out of the person get it's like it's.
Scott: you know, you can get on to the Metro North tracks.
Scott: It's sometimes in most places hard to get on the Amtrak.
Rym: No, it's not.
Rym: No, no pretty much anywhere I'm they're just there.
Rym: Plus remember the other the step is usually a fence.
Rym: Remember when we were coming back from this go-to party and we saw two separate cars almost get hit by a step to try Is way like the it's on the road.
Scott: you can get near those tracks.
Rym: Yeah, so apparently they call you if you want to find out how often this happens.
Rym: It's called a trespasser strike Because one person was trespassing.
Rym: Yes, if you're on the track Truck and apparently trespasser strikes happen all the fuck time and a lot of times and abstract trains just get delayed for a long time It's because of that.
Rym: It's really good.
Scott: Why are people going on the tracks?
Rym: uh, so the speculation that I heard from people I will not name and imply who they were and seems to be corroborated by a little bit of Cursory follow investigation homeless people.
Scott: They just wander on a train.
Rym: It's like 80% homeless people.
Scott: Are they trying drunk people?
Scott: Are they trying to die?
Rym: No, they're just following the train tracks.
Rym: No, no better.
Rym: You don't know better than to not go near train tracks Scott because trains are not well known in America to most people.
Rym: You would be surprised how many people just walk on train tracks because they don't have no idea how trains work.
Rym: They assume train tracks they find are abandoned.
Rym: They just don't even think about it.
Scott: So, yeah, yeah, I assume train tracks I find are abandoned.
Rym: if like they're rusted and broken With Amtrak, maybe you might or if I have a map that says rail trail here But the picture the more the other 20% is drunk people who just like walk off an Amtrak platform.
Scott: How many taverns tap rooms are right near the train track?
Rym: Amtrak shares a lot of track.
Scott: I feel like you shouldn't give someone a liquor license if they're right near a change.
Rym: Amtrak shares a lot of Train-track area with New Jersey Transit Which you can drink on.
Rym: no, but there's towns near there and drunk drivers are like like when cars get struck.
Rym: It's usually a drunk driver who just like parks on the train tracks.
Rym: when people get by trains It's pretty much always homeless people or drunk people.
Scott: This is the ban.
Rym: alcohol suicides appear to be pretty rare actually compared to all those other ones.
Rym: So I learned all this last night and I didn't get home till like midnight.
Scott: Oh glad I didn't go there.
Scott: I stayed in New York where everything was good.
Scott: Nice mocha festival.
Scott: nice, you know, it's small but good stuff.
Rym: Yep I will return to Zen kai khan, but if Zen kai khan overlaps with mocha fest again I'm not skipping to mocha fest in a row because I really like mocha fest.
Rym: It's okay.
Rym: Yeah We'll talk about mocha fest.
Scott: spent a few hours there went home.
Rym: Yeah, did you get a haul?
Rym: some comics will talk about?
Scott: no I just bought one comic with your said this cat on the cover who had a knife in his mouth.
Scott: It was ready to kill.
Rym: Sounds like something you would buy.
Scott: It sounds like something we would both buying but I think I think it was just called like no kitty No, and it's like, you know, the cat just messing stuff up in their apartment.
Rym: So you got any news Technology news that doesn't involve trespasser.
Scott: Well, it's sort of a news.
Scott: It's not even a new news.
Scott: It's like a January news, but it's sort of like came to a head at least today for me personally.
Scott: So delicious, which is the site that I've been using.
Rym: Oh, yeah used to be de l that I see I owe us.
Scott: It still is de l that I see out of us, but it redirects you to delicious.
Scott: calm.
Scott: Yeah, this is a site that was made in 2003 by a super nerdy guy Joshua something.
Scott: I just remember his name was Josh.
Rym: I think we did a whole episode.
Rym: We use the shit out of this at RIT, right?
Scott: So basically what delicious is is cuz you know when you're using the web, right?
Scott: There's two kinds of bookmarks You need.
Scott: there's the bookmark of the site you go to every day, right?
Scott: You just need a fast way to get there.
Scott: It's faster than typing it in even or maybe it is a complicated URL and you don't want to type that in ever.
Scott: Right, like the Amazon Web Services console, right?
Scott: It's like you could be.
Scott: if you're working with Amazon Web Services You might be using that every day.
Scott: the login URL for that is like fuck you.
Scott: It's not like amazon.com slash console, right?
Scott: It's some nonsense, especially if you've got to put like your account number in there and shit.
Scott: Fuck that.
Scott: So you use the bookmarks in your browser for that, right?
Scott: But there are some times you just remember URL.
Scott: for example, I see a thing of the day on the internet.
Scott: That's not like a YouTube video.
Scott: So I can't just like it.
Scott: to remember it I have to like, you know save that URL somewhere and I don't want to use my browser bookmarks for that.
Scott: That's like a big mess.
Rym: and also browser bookmarks like.
Rym: no one has made a good UX for that in modern era Right, and it's not.
Scott: they're not searchable.
Scott: They're not saved anywhere.
Rym: So do I know you say that but I mean like Chrome.
Rym: syncs it across all my Chrome's like sure But it's not super like.
Scott: it's not convenient for that purpose, right?
Scott: 2003 delicious solved this problem with a really simple website where you could just use a bookmark lit Which you'd make a real bookmark out of and any website you're on.
Scott: you could just click that Regular bookmark and it would hit the delicious API and create, you know And save the URL of the page you were on and you could also put a title description and tags.
Scott: But it also man the.
Scott: it would automatically fill those in for you.
Rym: So think of this an old GeekNights days I had a tag to TD which was things of the day.
Rym: then I had a tag Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday.
Rym: So anytime we had to do a show I'd be like, ah, well I'm gonna talk on a Thursday and I'd go to the URL that was Thursday plus to TD Thursday plus GN news, right?
Scott: There was awesome.
Scott: That was the best.
Scott: one of the best features of delicious was that you could find things with multiple tags.
Scott: so like you could just go to like delicious comm slash like music plus Evangelion, right and you could search for things that way like anything has these two tags on it.
Scott: You could find stuff there that you couldn't find on Google easily because it was things that human being specifically like wrote down.
Rym: Like man, you did do an episode on delicious on November 14th 2005. yeah, so 2005 night on GeekNights we considered TV OSER over TCP IP Google Analytics.
Rym: Douglas rush coughs new book.
Scott: Yeah, that's a rush cough has another new book by the upcoming.
Scott: It's calling.
Rym: It's called throwing rocks The upcoming Xbox 360 launch lineup.
Rym: then we discuss slash shot FARC delicious and dig.
Rym: we called this episode Reading the web.
Scott: All right, so delicious, right?
Scott: We talked about it.
Scott: So I'm talking about lazy show.
Scott: This is was made in 2003.
Scott: It was bought by Yahoo.
Scott: then in like by in like 2005 or something, right?
Scott: And then in 2011, it was sold to some other company.
Scott: We I think that was a news.
Scott: then only in January of this year It was sold to yet another company.
Scott: that company Right, even the previous company didn't do as good a job as even Yahoo or you know, the original developer Yeah But the company that started in January has begun in like the past month or two, right?
Scott: They start, you know, they didn't actually get working until like February March, right?
Scott: Really making delicious bad like.
Scott: oh, sorry.
Rym: I'll go to the list.
Rym: It still does.
Rym: Hey, why do I see all this like?
Rym: Twitter trending bullshit.
Scott: No, I mean that's always bad.
Rym: You've been on the front page because I've never been to the front page of delicious before.
Scott: no, you never have.
Scott: it's always had stuff like that, but anyway the You know, they just redesigned it more and it's like it still does everything It always did technically speaking but it's been like broken at times or down at times Popular way more ads on it than ever before.
Scott: Yeah popular tags AARP Bible Real estate I mean the point is delicious is sort of like finally Jumped the shark for real like.
Rym: what's wrong with it now?
Scott: I mean you want to keep using that site now.
Rym: As far as you told me the site's been like this for a long time.
Scott: No, it's it's.
Scott: I mean this.
Scott: it was bad and now it's.
Scott: it's beyond the pale, right?
Scott: So I switched to the next most popular thing today this morning It only took me like 10 minutes, which is called pin board.
Scott: Now the problem with pin board is that a it doesn't look as nice on the website.
Scott: The website looks like a Craigslist styling, right?
Scott: successful for a reason but you don't have to go to the website because you can just get like an app on your iPhone or whatever.
Scott: that hits the API and does it that way.
Scott: so pin board is not free.
Scott: It costs money.
Scott: Ooh It's like $11 or whatever A year, it's got flicker style pricing.
Scott: but for $25 a year You can get this super pin board, which basically does everything delicious did.
Scott: only there's no ads ever.
Scott: And it's super fast like it's performance is like their goal.
Scott: It's way fast.
Rym: if there was a Twitter that just cost 25 bucks a year Yeah, I know right.
Scott: So anyway, it's super fast and it does everything delicious did.
Scott: but if you buy this super version for $25 a year, what could it possibly do for me?
Scott: It has this amazing feature that delicious did not have.
Rym: What does it find things of the day for me?
Rym: It tells me what to do.
Rym: GeekNights on.
Scott: no What it does is it's archive mode.
Scott: So anything anything you bookmark it will actually take a download a copy of that page and save it.
Scott: so if like you but if you make a pin of Some like article and then you delete that article or edit that article or mess with that article or becomes 404 you can go to your pin board and click on this button and see the permanently saved version of that site that you Bookmarked.
Scott: Whereas I'm delicious, you know, I loaded my delicious backup into pin board and it didn't take very long at all.
Scott: It totally worked perfect everything everything broken.
Scott: Yeah, all the old old links Most of them don't work but pin board even if you export from pin board like all the data They give you all those backups - it's like those are?
Scott: you know, those are yours you're paying.
Scott: So it's like if you want to leave pin board Well, you can download all those cached versions of web pages.
Scott: The only caveat is it's a 32 megabyte limit per bookmark.
Scott: So if you like bookmark a YouTube video You're not getting the YouTube video.
Scott: Yeah Okay, and if there's like a giant giant JPEG that's a whole bunch of them like a big photo gallery and they're all full-size.
Scott: You're not getting us warning 1.4 megabytes.
Rym: download with care.
Rym: Yeah So There is a fork.
Rym: This is just kind of a weird.
Rym: so in the road I've been thinking about this idea a lot because someone pointed out very very poignantly that Soylent is just ultra slim fast.
Rym: But tech bros pretend that they invented it and they market it at men pretty much.
Rym: Yeah Yeah Also, they make it in shoddy dangerous labs and with no oversight and it's sort of a we're surprised The FDA hasn't and looked into it yet.
Scott: I suspect selling it is food.
Rym: Yeah, I suspected so.
Scott: in the United States the FDA will look into it.
Scott: I'm surprised but why did they?
Scott: why were they able to Sell it before the FDA like tint.
Rym: I don't know we should.
Rym: we should find someone who can tell us how Soylent is not gone.
Scott: Do I know a person I could ask about?
Rym: we do perhaps What that person's opinion is but this
Scott: I never thought to ask that person about this particular
Rym: ideas like fake food or vet meat or everything, but when it comes to fake flavor Like Americans like to drink garbage soda the candy water But and they've ruined their sense of taste so much that they don't want to drink anything but candy water most of the time.
Scott: I don't drink any and they need to constantly drink candy water.
Scott: So actually even drinking less juice than I drink before Yeah, I drink mostly water and seltzer.
Rym: Well coffee.
Scott: I'm only getting the high cloud on drink coffee either.
Rym: Why coffee is good for you?
Scott: No, okay That's what they want you to believe.
Rym: actually pretty much every study says they paid for by coffee industry.
Rym: No, but there's a lot of evidence actually that moderate to high intake of coffee Has a pretty strong correlation with not getting Alzheimer's sure Or at least not getting dementia in a general sense.
Rym: I don't know if it's Alzheimer's specifically.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: Yeah Okay, and all the you know, just keep you know, justifying your poison.
Rym: What about water?
Rym: I mean with Flint, you know, you never know.
Scott: I'm drinking New York water.
Scott: Yeah We should test our water and see you can get a free water test to call through on one.
Scott: They'll send you one.
Rym: So but we invented to deal with this problem Fake sugar which you know, like people don't think a lot about diet soda.
Rym: But when you really think about it, we design chemicals that taste like things our body wants but yet are indigestible.
Rym: It's like we're drinking sawdust.
Scott: Oh, you can just use MSG, which is actually totally okay for you.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but it's a similar but that's a flavor that the body also will process.
Rym: It's just not super caloric or I don't know if it's even caloric at all.
Rym: I don't think it's cool might be a little caloric and you'd be surprised what things are at least moderately caloric.
Scott: It just makes things taste savory.
Rym: I just got.
Rym: uh, how many calories do you think are in like a shot of vodka?
Rym: Vodka yeah, or like grain.
Scott: Oh, I mean, there's no calories in the alcohol part.
Scott: Yeah, there are.
Scott: it's only the nutrition It's only the potato part.
Rym: No, it's the alcohol part.
Scott: Alcohol is nutrient is nutritive but that's not something that like you're what I mean, it's just your liver does that?
Scott: not your?
Scott: It's not something like you would digest and absorb in your intestines.
Scott: It's like it goes into the liver and then the liver enzymes break up the outer sky.
Scott: That's not giving you any calories.
Rym: one ounce of vodka 64 motherfucking calories.
Scott: That's all the potato part.
Scott: No It's not I don't understand.
Scott: This doesn't make any sense.
Scott: Anyway, chemically speaking so it can't be just the ethanol if you just drink how many shots.
Scott: so how many calories are in a shot?
Scott: Of like Everclear 200 proof.
Rym: I'll type it in around ethanol.
Scott: Yeah, it's got to be zero, right?
Scott: You get to tell you could spell it properly Seven calories per gram of pure ethanol.
Scott: Where does it come from?
Rym: The what is ethanol Scott?
Scott: It's just alcohol.
Rym: Yeah we anyway.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: so We're also the people who invented a Lester.
Rym: do you remember Alestra?
Scott: Yeah, didn't that make people like have diarrhea?
Rym: Yeah, so it wasn't.
Rym: so the deal with Alestra is that it was a fat But it was like it was just like.
Scott: it was a fad that didn't break down.
Scott: So it went straight through you.
Rym: It was a fat.
Rym: So you taste your nice fatty nonsense.
Rym: But it just went straight through right through your body like a tube and just come out the other end.
Scott: that is greasy.
Scott: So it made your shit mad greasy.
Rym: So I was reading actually about Alestra a couple days ago.
Scott: And also you didn't get your necessary intake of fat.
Scott: if you just ate that shit.
Rym: even worse it might have actually caused other nutrients to leach out of your body and oh, yeah, because other food is gonna slip right out like a.
Scott: It's like food that would have stayed in the intestine and gotten digested and absorbed instead right out.
Rym: so The only reason it caused all that like.
Scott: it's like you're not gonna get too much nutrition If even if you eat like a salads all day and like the most delicious best salads if you're also eating x-lax, right?
Scott: it's not gonna help.
Rym: so Basically Alestra wouldn't have been this problem that it ended up being Except for the fact that the people who were using Alestra chips like they'd eat Alestra chips because I don't want to get fat They would eat so many more chips than anyone even reasonably think the human would consume That.
Rym: that is why they're having such a problem.
Rym: They're busy ODing on a lot.
Scott: So that's how they got on the shelves to begin with.
Rym: cuz yeah people tested them tested a reason What human being will buy an entire extra large bag of chips and eat all of them in one sitting?
Scott: and apparently the ones that Are really fat, which are the ones that are Alestra, right?
Rym: Yep Exactly.
Rym: Here is a. I never imagined that this would be.
Rym: yet a third way to go.
Rym: This is edging into.
Rym: this is one step away from.
Rym: why don't we just put a chip in your brain that makes you taste?
Rym: Whatever we want you to taste?
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah, cuz you could do that.
Scott: Take that.
Scott: Yeah, then I could save a lot of fucking money.
Rym: I'll hack it and poop taste.
Rym: Send me a Bitcoin or poop taste.
Scott: Well, I mean you can make a great.
Scott: you can go to restaurant websites and taste their food before going to the restaurant.
Rym: Yeah, and then I hacked it.
Rym: you trust a restaurant's websites not get hacked with poop taste.
Scott: No, I'm gonna hack all the restaurants.
Rym: Remember the time at RIT when we printed goats eat all those printers just kind of randomly.
Rym: It's gonna be that but with poop in your mouth.
Scott: Did you see that the the asshole weave guy sent like he printed things?
Scott: are all that racist nonsense Nonsense around like every open printer he could find in the US or whatever?
Rym: Yeah, fun fact guys, uh, if you just use Google, right?
Rym: There are so many unencrypted public webcams of stuff You probably don't want to watch.
Scott: No, there's a. I think there's a site.
Scott: It's like a. it's like a roulette like you just click next and it finds a webcam and you watch it.
Rym: I was playing with a site like that at work the other day and you know what?
Rym: I mostly found video of.
Rym: it was cameras pointed at pumps in factories.
Scott: There's a lot of those.
Rym: so I guess there's a pump breaks.
Rym: you'd be like, well, I guess that's the one that's broken.
Scott: I've worked I've worked.
Scott: I'm like pump monitoring, you know stuff.
Scott: It's like that's a big deal because like in factories like the pumps are the things that need the most looking at right?
Scott: Yeah, they're constantly have a moving parts You know, they need to be lubricated and powered and that's all you know, if you're in a factory That's like mostly doing its own thing.
Scott: I think the one we were working for was like a corn syrup place, right and it's like.
Scott: that's the most important part.
Scott: Everything else is like tanks.
Scott: You don't really it's like there's a tank.
Scott: have a leak or not?
Scott: If it does we'll find out pretty quick.
Scott: So they needed all kinds of stuff like monitor the temperature and the vibration and all this.
Scott: You know all kinds of things on all pumps most of the IT work.
Rym: I was doing an IBM like on that factory and the fab was not to add to the things that are actually directly making the Chips.
Rym: it was monitoring all the parts of the process.
Rym: So you detect if like a pump broke or like something weird happened somewhere or or usually like yields go down like well Why and then you have to look into the whole system to figure out what changed?
Rym: This is a fork that uses varying frequency electric currents.
Rym: So when it touches your tongue, you can it can give you a a basically like a binary of salty tasting and sour tasting.
Scott: So the fork is pretty limited.
Scott: It can't be poop taste.
Scott: It's not poop taste yet It can't do any taste.
Scott: It can only do this all.
Rym: it's pretty much as current on off if you use it to and level I think frequency.
Rym: I didn't read the whole paper.
Rym: So it gives a salty taste because right like already think about how useful that is.
Rym: So people who have heart issues where maybe they need to really cut their salt intake As much as you should not eat a lot of salt You should still eat some salt.
Scott: Yeah, but a lot of people like try to avoid salt too much and that's also bad.
Rym: Well, you probably should because all our food is way too much salt in it.
Rym: So well, I mean if you try to avoid a hundred percent salt You'll probably take enough salt in to be okay anyway, right?
Scott: But I mean first of all, you got to get the IO died.
Scott: right.
Scott: the thing is people are always thinking about when they think about salt.
Scott: they think about the salt like when they're shaking salt on the Food and it's like that's actually like if you shake salt on the food as much as blue apron tells you to.
Scott: that's actually not That much salt, right?
Scott: But if you eat like a bag of potato chips, yeah, that's way too much salt.
Scott: Yeah, the salt that's like in food you buy that's already made is too much.
Rym: I think about this say you want to eat your awesome salty dish, but you're not allowed to eat salt because of medical condition.
Rym: This would basically make your food taste salty if you use this fork to eat it.
Scott: Sure, and it doesn't there's.
Scott: no it's not even like a Lester where you're taking in something into your body.
Scott: You're just not you're just tickling the tongue.
Rym: Oh, so that that's why I was.
Rym: the reason I brought this up is when it came to a Lester and diet cola.
Rym: They feel vaguely disgusting to me because it feels like we're like.
Rym: it feels like this weird subversion of our bodies Desires like we trained ourselves to like something bad and then we make a bad thing to consume so we can continue to experience that Sensation.
Rym: this is just VR This Thing this fork it's just VR.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it's not sight or sound it's just tongue Kinda, well, no, it's AR because you're not just gonna like carry it around in your mouth You're gonna use it to augment the food you're eating.
Rym: So this is AR not VR This topic here, but there's room for debate.
Scott: That whole point is I don't need the salt version.
Scott: eat the sugar version.
Scott: That would also a lot more people have diabetes.
Rym: no, I need these sugar cookie version.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: I put it in my mouth and I taste sugar cookie.
Scott: I'm hacking that with poop days.
Scott: Now, you know that'd be the greatest like if I could somehow get it to her like Like this cookies and if you steal them, they taste like poop, but if I eat them, it tastes like DRM on the cookies.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Wasn't there that company that's claiming they're gonna?
Rym: if you pirate stuff They're gonna hack into your computer and like take it for ransom.
Scott: cool.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see how that goes down.
Scott: Go for it.
Rym: It's like.
Rym: I want other news because this will affect Our listener more so than most people because this only affects insufferable pedants.
Rym: The AP style guide has decided that the word Internet and the word web and the World Wide Web No longer deserving of capitalization in modern usage.
Scott: Okay, I agree that World Wide Web should not be capitalized.
Scott: Well, because I don't.
Scott: the World Wide Web is not a thing.
Rym: I agree with that but I want to qualify that by saying that the World Wide Web was a thing and We killed it and it no longer exists.
Scott: It was never a thing right thing.
Rym: All you're doing right is it and there was a time when the internet was just a collection of static web pages that were hyperlinked To one another.
Scott: that's not true at all.
Scott: In fact, the web came way after the internet started.
Scott: Yeah the internet That's the problem as a consumer internet.
Rym: You want to get pedantic?
Rym: Let's go.
Scott: No, that's not true at all.
Scott: In fact the shit like prodigy for it came out for consumers way before the.
Rym: you know HTTP and the World Wide Web was a revolution beyond that.
Scott: No the World Wide Web is not even a thing is this?
Scott: and the problem is the fact that people created the term World Wide Web to Refer to.
Scott: you know web browsers and HTTP Made people think that the entire internet was HTTP and web browsers and that they don't realize like oh like.
Scott: well Well, it gives all these other protocols for communicating over the internet.
Rym: Most people thought that was that that was right as the growth of people accessing internet technology was skyrocketing.
Rym: So the like pretty much within a year of the World Wide Web existing in any practical sense Probably the majority of people using the internet in any way had only ever experienced it.
Scott: anyway I disagree that internet should not be capitalized.
Scott: See if the internet is a thing and if you want to give a like if you want to say that like Chicago should be capitalized with a capital C then Then the internet as in the one and only big internet that the whole world is connected to should be capitalized with a capital I.
Rym: so they pointed out that the reason for this is that very few people like.
Rym: the word internet is used most often without the Definite article.
Rym: it's used as a descriptor like an internet blah, then you should definitely lowercase it.
Rym: in that case Yeah, and I I will do that, but I agree with you I will continue to get right if you want to when you're referring to it as the place where my culture lives.
Scott: Right, if you want to talk about the internet as in the one then you need to use a capital I. But you know if you want to talk about yeah, you know on internet, right?
Scott: Well, I think internet has an adjective like, you know as something as we discussed before we started recording the show.
Rym: No, well actually no, you know No one ever you no one ever in the modern era like for decades has actually said internet to mean Networks that were connected.
Rym: okay there that are not on the internet the word intranet ended up encompassing everything that's not on the internet.
Scott: Yeah, people people use the word intranet to describe internets when they shouldn't.
Rym: yes, cuz intranet now just means private network.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: I'm gonna disagree.
Scott: I think if you're talking about say An internet protocol right for example, yeah Well, you wouldn't.
Rym: you don't capitalize highway system protocol the highway systems not capitalized That's true, but if you're over but interstate I think is well You're thinking about the wrong thing.
Scott: if someone writes New York bagel you don't Uncapitalized New York because it's being used as an adjective Chicago pizza, which isn't pizza.
Scott: Otherwise, it would just be called pizza and not Chicago pizza.
Scott: You still capitalize Chicago.
Scott: Whoo, there's a you want to write, you know Turkish citizen.
Scott: You don't Uncapitalized Turkish, ah, but what?
Rym: as much as I'd like this to be true We can't actually live in internet yet and it's not a sovereign nation.
Scott: It doesn't mean anything.
Scott: It's still a proper noun.
Scott: It is a specific one and only thing and not one of met.
Scott: You know, it's like when you talk about a pie.
Rym: so Scott as long as I can tell you style guides You have to capitalize the word interstate because it refers to the interstate road system in the United States.
Rym: So if interstates capitalize,
Scott: I think if you're talking about the interstate but not on Interstates, but
Rym: no one uses that terminology and if you refer to a specific road like i-10 you have to say interstate 10 Capitalized I
Scott: well, but if you were gonna talk about like a Rym right not the Rym But a Rym would you uncapitalized Rym in that case?
Rym: in that case?
Rym: Yeah, I would I don't know except there's no generic case For please.
Scott: I'm just saying the AP got it wrong.
Scott: That's all I'm saying.
Scott: They're trying to disrespect internet.
Scott: We should we should uncapitalize AP just be like app.
Rym: there are a lot of deleted Wikipedia articles and Arguments about the deletion of what.
Scott: could be someone trying to go around all of Wikipedia uncapitalizing internet?
Scott: now They're there.
Rym: So the category was interstate highways in Alabama and apparently there was there.
Rym: someone was trying to make a page interstate highways in every state.
Scott: Why don't they just make the interstate highway system page?
Scott: I just split up the states.
Rym: I just found a Fascinating world that I do not want to step too much deeper in because I'm gonna read these pages all night.
Scott: every Wikipedia Article has something like this if you just click on the discussion tab talk tab.
Scott: That's why I don't click on that shit.
Rym: Yeah, go for it.
Rym: There's clearly no consensus in the use of uppercase H. That's what H. Why are they talking for highway?
Rym: Yeah, yeah highway is not capitalized.
Rym: There's some people here really wanted to be capitalized.
Rym: their arguments are stupid.
Scott: well if I was talking about for example the Scott-rubin highway you would capitalize highway, but if you're talking about a highway like I'll take the highway Even though it's high road in that song, but you would You already undermine your own argument.
Scott: I'm just saying I'm gonna take a ride on the highway.
Rym: I would lowercase highway in that sense, but I guess the the useful categories today are intranet Internet is the Internet and then extranet is just basically like Basically replaced lands except they're private.
Rym: They're only really used by enterprise companies.
Scott: They're really just intranets.
Scott: when a company has multiple canvases or Between companies like a bunch of companies will like if you're in the Google office in New York You need to be able to connect on the same network to the Google office in California.
Rym: That's just a. when an extranet is more like say Google Amazon Yahoo!
Rym: And ten other companies said we need to all communicate with each other.
Scott: Yeah, you know what everyone uses for that.
Scott: just eat the Internet Yeah, but well no.
Rym: so finance and there are a bunch of other industries.
Rym: They use extranets where they sort of all agree and just directly connect infrastructure to each other and make their own internet.
Scott: I mean do they do this like in a single data center, or is like Verizon helping them out?
Rym: They do it across data centers, and they work with multiple vendors to make it happen.
Rym: But the idea is you can connect through these networks to other people in a semi-public fashion within the network With varying levels of security.
Scott: Does it have its own DNS?
Rym: It's basically an invite only private internet.
Scott: Does it use IP?
Scott: Basically, yeah.
Scott: Did they have their own DNS?
Rym: Yeah, actually cuz everyone's running their own DNS internally for all these basically a bunch of intro.
Scott: Yeah, it's like how do you fucking find that?
Rym: It's a bunch of intranets connected together.
Rym: So actually extranets are what the generic case of the word internet was but because we don't use the word for that anymore We call it extranets.
Rym: So extranets and intranets are lowercase I. The internet is uppercase I. All other uses of internet are lowercase I. That is my position Whatever.
Scott: I'm gonna keep up keep an internet uppercase.
Rym: Also, you're not allowed per the style guide to use the two-letter abbreviations of US state names anymore because it's confusing to people who don't Live in America and apparently it's confusing to a lot of people who live in America now.
Scott: Tell me what is the two-letter Abbreviation.
Rym: Montana or Maine?
Rym: Those are the ones that mess people up usually For Maine.
Rym: Maine is ME, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Are you sure?
Scott: I'm reasonably sure.
Scott: What's Missouri?
Rym: M.O.
Scott: I think you're right.
Rym: Yeah, I know my shit Because Montana is MT, I'm pretty sure.
Rym: Yeah, Maine is ME, so I'm good.
Scott: And then Mississippi.
Rym: I'm I Am I, cricket letter, cricket letter, I, cricket letter, cricket letter, I, humpback, humpback, I Things of the day.
Scott: Oh shit, what was my thing of the day?
Rym: So, all right, I'm gonna talk a little bit about Angola's Wikipedia pirates Mm-hmm.
Rym: This is a cool thing that's happening But there's a whole- This is too weird.
Scott: Angola, Wikipedia, pirate, those are three words that don't go together.
Rym: Oh, and it relates to digital colonialism.
Rym: So the article is fascinating because basically you're gonna hit a bunch of topics that are themselves fascinating by looking at this and This is sort of like a whole of stuff You probably have not encountered.
Rym: but the angle that the entry point of this whole article is that Wikipedia Wikimedia, so Wikipedia and you know, like all the other line.
Scott: Wikipedia is run by the Wikimedia Foundation, which does other things also.
Rym: Yeah, so it's not just Wikipedia.
Scott: Mostly they run Wikipedia.
Rym: Like they have hosting for like public domain stuff.
Scott: They do a lot of shit.
Rym: Yeah, and Facebook got together I think some other companies are involved too, to give Angola free access to their websites But not the rest of the internet, the whole net neutrality thing, but they did this.
Rym: No, yes, and I while I think that's shitty if you- India said no, India took the smart route But India has a lot more developed infrastructure than Angola In a lot of ways.
Scott: You should have said give me the whole internet.
Scott: So anyway, this exists.
Rym: So if you're in Angola, you have free access to Wikipedia, Facebook, and a few other things.
Rym: I'm just gonna quote the article.
Rym: So naturally Angolans have started hiding pirated movies and music in Wikipedia articles and linking to them on closed Facebook groups.
Rym: And The degree to which nerds in Angola have hacked Wikipedia to hide pirated material is amazing.
Rym: Like copy-pasting an entire novel into a rarely read Wikipedia article Telling other people and everyone just goes that article and copy-paste it out for as long as they can before someone fixes it.
Scott: Good job Angola.
Rym: Yeah, this is widespread and Amazing.
Scott: Maybe you should give people the whole internet next time.
Rym: Yeah, so never discount, you know, as much as you know stuff goes out around the world.
Rym: go Angola never That.
Rym: if there's a place with nerds and they have access to an internet It's your birthday.
Rym: nature finds a way.
Scott: go Angola.
Scott: You're my heroes.
Rym: You got a thing of the day like the 90s.
Scott: You got a thing of the day Yeah, so here is see.
Scott: I don't know how many people listening have used an Apple to computer.
Scott: I suspect all the old ones.
Scott: I have some in my closet.
Scott: I have one in my closet The Apple to computer the original one that cost like a zillion dollars.
Scott: I think it costs like over a thousand dollars originally and no one could afford that in 1980 something That was like a million dollars in 1980, whatever.
Scott: It had a problem and that you could only use cassette tapes with it Which is like the style of the times.
Scott: so you would like you would plug in a cassette tape rewind it press play and it would load the whole program into the Apple to and then you could use it right and that sucked.
Scott: They wanted to use discs with the Apple to and using this with the Apple to.
Scott: well They didn't have a disk drive originally.
Scott: now they have one, but they didn't originally have one.
Scott: So Steve Wozniak made the hardware for it and his hardware was like this genius hardware.
Scott: I have some of the boards that do this because I have extra floppy drives.
Scott: Yeah and I have the exact boards that like the Steve Wozniak design and Basically, it's a. it's the genius of that design.
Scott: people don't realize.
Scott: is that up until that point?
Scott: Floppy disk controllers are mad expensive.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: They were all hardware, right?
Scott: Everything was done in hardware.
Scott: He moved the complicated bits into software now put an IC on this on this board.
Rym: I just want to point out that similar things were done later to Dramatically opposite effect.
Rym: remember the wind tell modems, right?
Scott: And this is why like the Apple to like there are other computers that have floppy disk drives.
Scott: but the Apple to was like the first time where like everyone could have a floppy disk drive and have a bunch of floppy disk because The board that the floppy drive was actually, you know usable and cheap enough.
Scott: right the controller boards were cheap enough.
Scott: So but the problem was they had this thing, but they needed like they didn't need an OS But they needed like a file system kind of control.
Scott: You know, there's some sort of disk operating system some way to actually use floppy disk All right to make files to read and write from them.
Scott: And that didn't exist.
Scott: So actually no one at Apple wrote that.
Scott: I found out from this article here that They hired someone to do that from like another company in the same like, you know a little campus whatever.
Scott: And that was the Apple to disk operating system.
Scott: And if you've ever put like an Apple to game on a floppy disk into an Apple to and turn it on It'll say like Apple to DOS version something something and then the game will start.
Scott: Yep, right And that's.
Scott: it's not really an operating system.
Scott: It's just really like a disk controlling kind of thing.
Scott: But it also like has a basic interpreter and stuff like that and lets you read and write files and whatever.
Scott: and Finally the listing for that disk operating system is now publicly available for non-commercial use.
Scott: You can read it yourself.
Scott: And what's really fascinating is I've always wondered this like how did they write this to begin with?
Scott: It's like I can use an Apple to writing in basic once the disk operating system is loaded.
Scott: I don't wouldn't know how to write at least without a lot of help something like on a Blank Apple to like.
Scott: I don't know how to interface with that at all like an assembly like, okay I wrote.
Rym: what do you try?
Scott: It's like I wrote some assembly for Apple to.
Scott: how do I assemble it and get the Apple to to run it?
Scott: I have no fucking clue.
Scott: Apparently what they did Is they did it on a different computer with like punch cards?
Scott: Right, and then that computer asset did the assembly the Apple to couldn't assemble its own assembly, huh?
Scott: Right, they assembled it on a different more powerful computer and then print it out like I just you know You know a long tape right and then we're able to load it on the Apple to nice.
Scott: So here's the listing for that assembly that you have to assemble on a different not all man.
Rym: It's just PDF here.
Scott: Oh, man Yeah, check it out.
Scott: I mean it was the print.
Scott: it's a listing.
Scott: It's not the code in a file It's a listing of.
Scott: you know Like if they used to do that print out books of code and you would turn from page to page reading the code.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So here you go.
Rym: Enjoy in the minute moment.
Rym: We were just as thank.
Rym: I can't release.
Rym: I was at Zenka Khan.
Scott: I was wise enough not to go to.
Scott: thank God.
Rym: I went to the mocha festival Convention is PAX East which is coming up pretty soon a few weekends from April 22nd 23rd 24th on the 24th on Sunday We will be presenting sometime in the afternoon Atari game design and that's one of our panels.
Rym: That is definitely not on YouTube anywhere.
Rym: It's also a pretty good panel.
Rym: So stay tuned.
Rym: otherwise, uh, stay tuned for whatever news might come of.
Rym: other conventions were involved with.
Rym: and Yeah, the next book a book is Margaret Edwards Oryx and Craig.
Rym: I'm going to start reading it within a week.
Scott: I bought a copy already.
Rym: I'm gonna finish the 12th book of the Wheel of Time because I'm mostly through it and I did start reading it though.
Rym: Yeah, so I'll start reading in about a week.
Rym: So you got a little bit of buffer.
Scott: this Saturday April 9th is Netrunner regional championships in Massachusetts, which I bought a ticket to See if I go there as a who sits.
Scott: Yeah, it's in Cambridge and you're like MIT areas So I have at least possible ways of getting there.
Scott: But it'll be weird going to Massachusetts and Boston area like three times in one month.
Scott: Anime Boston net runner tournament packs.
Rym: It's just like oh my god I once went to London and then went to Hong Kong in a separate trip and then stopped in love.
Scott: Is the ninth then there's nothing the weekend after that and then packs is the weekend after that.
Scott: actually I could doable.
Rym: Yeah, they'll remember packs.
Rym: This is not the four-day packs like prime and Sunday is not always super hopping.
Rym: just because you know Boston is not the best venue for the outside of Khan hopping.
Rym: There'll be some hopping Thursday.
Rym: day and night is gonna be really hopping.
Rym: So if you want to expand your paxies scenario, you want to get there Thursday like early afternoon?
Scott: Yeah, I'm thinking actually I might go Thursday and like Sunday, you know try to go home late Sunday.
Rym: I was thinking about that too, but like real late on Sunday I might still take money off work.
Rym: Maybe I'll leave late Sunday.
Rym: But then again, it's nice to just go to bed after a packs.
Rym: We'll see like there's something, you know I go.
Rym: I've gone to a lot of conventions where I leave like Night, because I don't want to stay like through the whole thing.
Scott: But if it's a big con, especially a con that I do a lot The thing is for the cost of a hotel room, right for much less than the cost of one night in a hotel.
Scott: Yeah, I could take a cab from the bolt bus to my apartment and luxuriously get home at Sunday Or Scott for the price of another night in the room Which I would never something I would never do.
Rym: I could take the Acela home and actually be home like real early like way Earlier than you think.
Scott: it's not gonna save that much time.
Rym: It's gonna cost a lot of money.
Rym: compared it doesn't cost.
Rym: I take you sell all the time.
Scott: I'll probably buy tickets for tonight.
Scott: That's like 12 bucks.
Rym: I'm gonna buy those tonight too, but if I was gonna take the Acela home Yes, so it's gonna hit someone and I'm gonna be home first.
Rym: the Acela.
Rym: if it hits someone they might not notice.
Scott: Oh, it doesn't go that fast.
Scott: No, it goes pretty fast.
Scott: Not Shinkansen cells been going pretty good Not even 1/5 Shinkansen also Scott.
Rym: It's at least it's the money part of Amtrak.
Rym: it's not the Pennsylvania part.
Rym: All right, so Scott tells me he's been having trouble with HFS plus.
Scott: well, okay.
Scott: So, I don't know if people realize this but you know computers have different file systems that they use Right, like all your CD roms have like ISO 96 60 or whatever the fuck it.
Rym: Yeah, or like in the old days like on Linux.
Scott: It was xt like and all your floppy disk used fat fat 16 and all your USB sticks probably using fat 32.
Scott: Yeah, which is what Windows 98 used.
Rym: I'll remember the old days fat 32. and then when people started using, you know A lot of people were afraid to leave fat 32 Because the newer file systems on Windows were not accessible on Linux.
Rym: and those grognards they are now They are now.
Rym: NTFS just works.
Scott: fine NTFS is what your Windows computer uses and your Linux machines.
Scott: you could use anything the fuck you want But you're probably using ext4 if it's modern, which is pretty great.
Rym: I still see a lot of systems that default to ext3 and I don't know why.
Scott: well, they're just old.
Scott: Well, it's old kernels.
Rym: Yeah, it's always people in selling like some old version of arch somewhere.
Scott: stupid reason arch Usually just the newest.
Scott: everything old version from a thing is old version.
Scott: It's one of those rolling distros.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway
Scott: Some people use XFS some people use ZFS whatever but max OS X modern a brand new MacBook you buy today from the Apple Store Uses a file system known as HFS plus which is I guess slightly better than HFS and HFS Plus even even the plus one is garbage.
Scott: It is like though.
Scott: It's worse than fat.
Scott: Maybe it's not as worse as fat 32, but it's Like I don't know a lot about HFS cuz I've never really well really I mean there are many problems with it under the hood that like no one cares about or will notice, right?
Rym: Well, yeah I mean I could say this like I used to.
Scott: you know It's funny back when I cared a lot like it's not gonna give you the performance or the safety of like ext4 you know and all these kinds of things that no one cares about.
Rym: I used to be like.
Scott: I really like like when I made a Linux machine like I thought a lot about if you're a Linux user and you're not just doing defaults using ext4 for everything You have to think about file systems you like, you know what.
Scott: I'm gonna put all these giant videos on this drive So I'll use XFS.
Scott: Yeah, and I have to think about like what my block size is gonna be and stuff, right?
Scott: You know, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, I know you and you you thought it mattered.
Rym: It usually didn't actually matter that much.
Scott: the main problem with HFS plus is that it is not Case sensitive which means if you go to a directory and you make a file like readme.txt All lowercase readme.txt and you make another file all uppercase readme.txt.
Scott: Those are actually the same file on Every other file system that I've ever used that I. as far as I can remember.
Scott: That is not the case, right?
Scott: If I go to my Windows machine I can make a file that's Scott.txt with a capital S or internet.txt with a capital I and a totally separate file internet.txt with a lowercase I and those will be two Separate files that are not the same file in any way, which is pretty important.
Scott: Like when you're programming something right, you know If you're programming file names into your code or in your settings for your you know Code's gonna use you gotta put file names in there, right and they got to be the right file name.
Scott: Otherwise the wrong file is gonna get opened.
Scott: if there's two different files with you know Only thing differentiating their names being the case of the letters in there.
Scott: Now the counterpoint I usually see is people arguing that in practice You shouldn't be putting two files in the same directory with the same name.
Scott: We're only cases.
Rym: if you ever have a file called internet.txt with a lowercase I and Uppercase I and they're in the same directory fucked up.
Rym: Yeah, you there's.
Rym: there is a deep problem with you.
Scott: Maybe that's the case.
Rym: Yeah, but that was always the argument that they would assume that Users of computers would never want to do something like that.
Rym: So if you put if you have a bunch of characters that are a file name They assume that if you use a similar set of characters that differs only in case you meant that file.
Scott: Well, that's bullshit.
Scott: Everything should be case-sensitive pretty much always.
Rym: Actually I haven't thought about this a lot because I explicit is always better than implicit true but I have all I've.
Rym: I always think about this in terms of applications and keys and databases and that kind of stuff.
Rym: but here the fat fat 32 NTFS, HFS plus all case insensitive Apparently.
Rym: and what?
Rym: apparently NTFS if you mount it in Unix is case sensitive Yes, but it's not case sensitive normally anyway.
Rym: interesting yeah, I did some.
Rym: I just I found a Wikipedia article and I found some links that are telling me things I didn't know about NTFS.
Rym: So I got distracted right?
Scott: So the major problem here is that let's say somebody is working on a Mac.
Scott: They're you know developer at my work, right and they're writing some JavaScript or something, right and in their JavaScript code They write something like include my file dot JS and they in their code They write like all lowercase my file dot JS.
Scott: But actually when they make the file they make it like my file dot JS or some camel case uppercase M uppercase F.
Rym: See now I would already feel not talking about specific technology that if I'm referring to a name of a library It should never be case sensitive, right?
Scott: But so on their computer that totally works.
Scott: Right, they?
Scott: because my file dot JS is my file dot JS on a Mac with HFS plus.
Scott: And then you give that code to someone else to run on this Linux server in production.
Scott: and what happens?
Scott: File not found my file dot JS no such file.
Rym: Wait HFS plus is listed as both case sensitive and case insensitive.
Scott: That is correct because in fact if you are extremely wise You can actually flip a little blip and make it case sensitive and fix everything.
Rym: However, however, does that break other things?
Scott: it breaks two things.
Scott: number one every single OS X Application that you try to use that is because the default is case insensitive.
Scott: every OS X application that you try to use That is basically not ever thinking that the file system will be case sensitive is now going to break.
Scott: So anything that's not coded extremely well For your Mac will just not work.
Scott: So good luck changing that setting.
Rym: in any realistic scenario where you actually want to run software, right riser I forgot about that didn't kill his wife or something.
Scott: Yeah, something weird.
Scott: don't use that.
Scott: It's dead.
Scott: Because so whoever the other problem being Yeah, try to flip that before like before OS X installs and rewrites.
Scott: It's like you can't flip the switch early enough.
Scott: by the time you flip the switch OS X is already installed and all these case insensitive files are already there at least if that were an option in Unix.
Rym: like you have full control like you can bootstrap your own Stupid system if you want, right?
Scott: Yeah, so I'm not sure exactly how.
Scott: I'm sure you can flip it after the fact somehow but good luck with that.
Rym: So you want to have some extra fun this.
Rym: I think I mentioned this once the GeekNights before but this is I don't even know What would happen in the file system?
Rym: So what if I in HFS?
Rym: Made a file that used the Turkish I instead of a normal I?
Scott: yeah Unicode is another big reason that we shouldn't make things case insensitive, right?
Scott: You know, actually if you make so you make uppercase I and lowercase I are just two different Unicode characters.
Scott: What's what's uppercase?
Scott: There's no such thing right from the perspective of bits in a file name But there's a bunch of different uppercase.
Rym: So if I write code in Turkish, will it now not work if the libraries are named?
Scott: this is what I'm saying.
Scott: What is uppercase and lowercase is from a computer's perspective, right?
Scott: It's you're basically just saying apply this flag to any of these Unicode characters and they map to these other Unicode characters.
Scott: so for the purposes of looking at file names only Consider these 26 Unicode characters to be the same as these other 26 Unicode characters.
Scott: All of the Unicode characters are unique except these 26 are the same as those 26 with a one-to-one mapping.
Scott: and it's like Why are you putting that nonsense exception in there?
Scott: Just make it wait.
Scott: No file name is a string of Unicode characters that are unique.
Scott: the.
Rym: my file name has an uppercase one.
Rym: So I guess the exclamation point right exactly, right?
Scott: You wouldn't do that.
Scott: That's nonsense, right?
Rym: but at the same time so alright if because if you're doing the uppercase lowercase thing then again the Turkish I The dot I and not dot I are different.
Rym: So if I uppercase a dot I it's an uppercase I with a dot on it.
Scott: I mean of all people Linus Torvalds has like you can find he has many rants, right?
Scott: he has a rant about this.
Scott: basically talking about HFS plus is the worst piece of garbage on earth and As is often the case when he gives these kinds of technological rants He is a mostly right and B half the words are him saying stupid moron stupid You know, so
Rym: I think a little bit of by
Scott: cetera, etc.
Rym: Suspect.
Rym: there's an interesting the the tone of the words in the Wikipedia article about HFS plus which I'm looking at.
Rym: Cuz I don't know a lot about HFS.
Scott: Let's see who wrote quotes.
Rym: due to the age of HFS plus several features that are currently considered staples of modern file systems Like ZFS or riser FS are not present.
Scott: That's true, which is true.
Scott: Apparently Plus is a garbage.
Rym: Let's see nanosecond timestamps are not there.
Rym: Nope, which actually could be a problem actually like Concurrent access.
Rym: It's basically an old file check summing snap shotting.
Scott: Okay, imagine if Windows like barely updated like me instead of making NTFS They had made like fat 64 and then they just stuck with that.
Rym: Okay, so real until today It does not have proper hard linking.
Rym: but are there modern use cases for true hard links?
Rym: Really?
Scott: Yes, but the point is one.
Scott: is that Name one.
Rym: Yeah for a proper like fully compliant hard link like in the b-tree or whatever the file system uses.
Scott: because some Application I have a file right and I want to put the file in like someone's home folder for example.
Scott: But I also want the file to be in like var Www say for example so that a different application can look at it.
Scott: I don't want to just put a similar Because it may be a sim link isn't gonna work right cuz sim links aren't really.
Scott: they're not true links No, but a hard link will totally get the job done, yeah anyway The point is is that there is absolutely no reason I can see why they can't just ship like the next version of OS X with like ext4 or ZFS or any UNIX file.
Scott: It's just you.
Scott: OS X is just UNIX.
Scott: You can use any UNIX file system.
Scott: It's open source.
Scott: There's already a bunch of open source stuff in OS X. It probably would be like minimal labor to just ship OS X well with any
Rym: modern file
Scott: system Except for the issue of There's probably a lot of software out there that will break when the file system becomes case-sensitive
Rym: Makes it the opposite of a minor problem with trivial effort.
Scott: I think that you just.
Scott: you know everyone who has actually has a program that people still use bugs and they'll be done.
Rym: so.
Rym: Microsoft developers like dotnet people have to complain forever about the file path file name limitations Even though modern file systems can.
Rym: you can have very very very long paths and file names For all intents and purposes like any software you run in Windows or right in Windows Like you just won't work if your path gets too long.
Rym: Yeah, so shit'll break randomly.
Rym: Microsoft has said unequivocally They will never address it because the cost of figuring out all the things that'll break and dealing with that is not worth them even Considering they will never remove that limitation.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: So this is probably gonna be in that same boat.
Rym: Yeah Until I don't know until I guess until they switch until they pull a Windows and switch from you know HFS to some fundamentally different You know.
Scott: First of all, you could do it in iOS because right it doesn't even matter in iOS is no file.
Rym: They could make their own custom file system that had a way to handle legacy application.
Scott: Why write a file system?
Scott: someone already wrote like the best file systems ever for free.
Scott: Why would you write one?
Scott: That's the dumbest thing I've ever heard.
Rym: Yeah, they'll take it and fork it or something nonsense like that.
Rym: That's like I mean I'm saying what I think is gonna happen is The people who care about this will be mad and nothing will not change in the foreseeable future.
Scott: No, well, nothing's it change.
Scott: Yeah, I'm just saying is that this is a thing.
Scott: That's a big problem that people don't even know and The only people argue that file system should be case insensitive are bad.
Rym: And now you can argue that like certain key lines line is terrible.
Scott: to say They're stupid.
Rym: a key field in a database You might want to make case insensitive and you might have a good reason for that But that's not a file system.
Rym: file systems Like the underlying infrastructure of your storage that is you don't want to have implicit assumptions about that.
Scott: The only times you want things to be case insensitive is like up at the user interface level like someone searches for like dog.
Scott: it's like yeah, you want to return results if someone typed it if the you know, The article has a capital dog or like.
Scott: say you have a system below the user interface level.
Scott: You don't.
Scott: you want case sensitivity perfectly for everything because that's computers dealing with that.
Scott: They need to be.
Rym: Also anything that's human readable shouldn't be your key.
Rym: your key should be some UID or some nonsense on the back end Like it's not you.
Rym: So yeah, like say you want to make a report your system.
Rym: you're writing reports.
Rym: No one wants to name a report.
Rym: internet with an uppercase I and internet with the lower case on.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leaf for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the patreon patreon for this episode of GeekNights in order the amount of money that they give us.
Rym: The continuing basis as long as they give us at least more than five dollars is Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brandau Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette James David White Christian At least I'm not named after my dad coons Jess my state e.com mechanical mind William Eisen rose.
Rym: Jeremy minor Spartacus.
Rym: Spartacus.
Rym: Spartacus Joshiro Joe star Tyler Ellers Scott John Scott John Harrison Sean Yeager Clinton Walton running from New Zealand.
Rym: Robert Lee Ryan parent drew open lander rare.
Rym: Brian citroni Rochelle, Montana.
Rym: Finn.
Rym: Eric silver on can't melt steel themes.
Rym: kinetic man Aaron Cerise Chris mid give Chris Knox flame.
Rym: dark fire chef Sam Cordery Daniel Redmond Krista Dodd Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: and I will point out there is a surprising number of additional people who Choose not to have their name read at the end, but are donating above that threshold.
Rym: More than one.
Rym: who is donating 666 which I think is funny.
Rym: But yes, we're back from Zek icon back from anime Boston.
Rym: we got a few weeks before PAX East.
Rym: so The patreon content is going to expand mightily the next few weeks.
Rym: And I've decided because at least as I look right now if you look at the front-end number We're just shy of that first stretch goal of me remastering and re-releasing well, I guess releasing all of the Pre-GeekNights launch beta episode some of which none of you have ever heard.
Rym: for sure most of you never heard them, but I think what I'll do because The actual amount of money you're pledging is well above what that threshold was set to.
Rym: It's just that kick patreon changed the way they count the submission money and everything.
Rym: I think I'm just gonna take the first ever episode of GeekNights the one we did as a test the first time we ever Did anything before.
Rym: we did real GeekNights with the Logitech stick microphone?
Rym: I'm gonna take that remaster it and put it up on the patreon for you guys to hear and I'm sure I'll have some interesting commentary once I listen to that, so I'm gonna do that this week.
Rym: And now I leave you with something kind of weird.
Rym: Then he waddled away waddle waddle till the very next day.
Rym: bum bum bum bum bum bum.
Rym: When the duck walked up to the lemonade stand and he said to the man run in the stand hey Bum-bum-bum got any grapes The man said no.
Rym: like I said yesterday We just sell lemonade.
Rym: okay, why not give it a try?
Rym: the duck said goodbye.
Rym: Then he waddled away waddle waddle.
Rym: then he waddled away waddle waddle.
Rym: then he waddled away.
Rym: He waddle waddle till the very next day.
Rym: bum bum bum bum bum bum bum.