Rym: It's Tuesday, January 5th, 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we're back with games.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So we had our traditional New Year's party.
Rym: One of our friends, someone always kind of bites that bullet to host everyone we know at a giant party every year.
Rym: And in keeping with our sort of tradition, what we pretty much do at these parties is play games.
Rym: Eating.
Rym: At like 1145, 1150, someone's like, "Hey guys, it's almost the New
Rym: Year.".
Rym: And then at like 1158, we're like, "Oh, right,
Rym: yeah.".
Rym: And everyone kind of stands there looking at their cell phones.
Rym: It hits midnight.
Rym: We go,
Rym: "Woo!"
Rym: Arbitrary times.
Rym: And then we continue playing games.
Rym: It was a pretty much typical party though.
Rym: And we played a lot of games.
Rym: Actually, I think I played more games at this New Year's weekend than I even played at the last PAX.
Scott: I don't know about that, but I mean, it was mostly just games we've already played before.
Scott: We just played them.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Which is interesting because at PAXes, usually...
Scott: Which is bad for GeekNights because what the hell do we talk about now?
Rym: But usually I'm playing a game and I play it.
Rym: There's always like one or two people who haven't played the game before.
Rym: So we end up teaching the game and it's sort of like an experience.
Rym: But to get together with our crew, it's pretty much like we sit down.
Rym: A glory to Rome just opens on the table.
Rym: No one ever really consented to that being the game.
Rym: And then we just play it.
Rym: A bunch of steely-eyed experts staring each other the fuck down.
Rym: I miss that kind of gaming a lot.
Scott: That's why you should play Netrunner.
Scott: Because when you play Netrunner, you go and you sit down and everyone there knows how to play.
Scott: And you just bust it open.
Scott: That's why I stopped going to board game night and did Netrunner instead.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time Netrunner scratches different kinds of itches.
Rym: I'm not... I like the three to five player dynamic more than the one-on-one.
Scott: And my one-on-one game... You want some political game.
Scott: You don't want some skill game.
Rym: It's not necessarily political.
Rym: Puerto Rico is not significantly political.
Scott: It still is more political than zero.
Rym: Yes, that is technically true.
Rym: You are correct.
Rym: You win the semantic war.
Rym: Congratulations.
Rym: But partly too, my one player pure thought game is Advance Wars and I maxed it out.
Rym: And I don't know if I have it in me to max out another game.
Rym: And I'm not willing to play a one-on-one game that I'm not willing to max out anymore.
Rym: Either I'm going to be one of the best or I'm not going to bother.
Rym: I don't want to be middle of the road.
Scott: But being the best at Advance Wars doesn't get you anywhere.
Scott: If you're the best at Netrunner, sure, it's not like it gets you an Olympic gold medal.
Scott: But actually, that can get you quite a lot.
Rym: Yeah, but it'd be a similar amount of work to what it took me to be good at Advance Wars.
Scott: Maybe, maybe not.
Scott: It's not that hard a game.
Rym: No, it isn't.
Rym: But also, that ship sailed.
Rym: I'd have to go learn all the cards and pay attention.
Rym: I'd have to play it constantly and regularly.
Scott: You know, I'm doing it.
Scott: I got no problems.
Rym: Yeah, you are doing it.
Rym: I'll play every other game instead.
Rym: But anyway, there's some news.
Rym: But first, there's a rumor.
Rym: This isn't really Tuesday, but the rumor seems pretty legit.
Rym: Apple might have the 6C or the 7C in spring.
Scott: This has nothing to do with games.
Rym: No, but it's an iPhone that's tiny.
Rym: And if it happens, I'm switching to an iPhone.
Rym: Which means I'll start playing mobile games because most mobile games are iPhone only.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So you got any news?
Scott: I do have a news.
Rym: It's not about Netrunner, is it?
Scott: It is about Netrunner.
Scott: There's other game news out there like AGDQ is happening now.
Rym: I was going to talk about AGDQ in a little bit, but anyway.
Scott: You can do that if you want to.
Scott: But something big happened in Netrunner land.
Scott: And even if you don't care about Netrunner, this is relevant to all kinds of games that are the kind of games that change constantly over time.
Scott: Which includes every professional sport, Magic, Netrunner.
Rym: Hockey has changed so many times.
Rym: When I started watching hockey seriously again a few years ago, some things were different that really mattered.
Rym: It took me a while to notice even the jerseys had swapped.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: So the big change that made in Netrunner was basically, first of all, there was a card that they won't admit to it, but I'm pretty sure was misprinted.
Scott: Or at least they've told us that it had this property in playtesting.
Scott: It was unique in playtesting.
Scott: But for some reason, once it got to the real, the printed one wasn't unique.
Scott: So now they've ratted it to make it unique again because it was a big problem.
Scott: So that's fine.
Scott: The other thing they did is they made this restricted list of some sort.
Scott: It's not actually a restricted list because there are many different approaches that various card games have used to sort of, "Oops, we made a card that was too strong.
Scott: Let's fix
Scott: it.".
Rym: Yeah, well like Magic would either have you put it in the tier system.
Scott: Right, so Magic, what they did is they had different ways to play Magic and different cards were allowed in different types.
Rym: And even within that, you can only have four of a card, but there were some cards you could only have one of.
Scott: And there were some cards you could have zero of.
Scott: And once they found out a card was a problem, like Channel, they're just like, "Well, zero of
Scott: those.".
Scott: Not allowed to use that card anymore.
Rym: Channel Fireball, Mox Emerald, Black Lotus, Demonic Tutor, One Turn Win.
Scott: They would just ban, right?
Scott: So in other games, so for example in the Game of Thrones card game, which is the first LCG, which is what Netrunner is, what they did is they made a restricted list.
Scott: So I don't know exactly how it works, but the general gist is you can have this card in your deck, but if you do, you can't have any of those cards.
Scott: And if you have those cards, you can't have these.
Scott: So basically this broke up nasty combos.
Scott: Like there were broken combos, but the cards that made up the combos weren't individually broken.
Scott: They were just fine as long as you didn't combo them.
Scott: So it'd be like, "You can have Channel, as long as you don't have any of these disintegrates or fireballs or any X cost spell to go with it, you can have your
Scott: channel.".
Scott: And if you have any of these disintegrates, you can't have any channels.
Scott: It's like that.
Rym: Which I feel like that's unmaintainable in a card game.
Scott: Well, it worked for them.
Scott: Anyway, so in Netrunner, they were so proud that over a long period of time, since the Android Netrunner started, they didn't have to do any of that.
Scott: What they would do is they would just print new cards to sort of help counteract older cards.
Scott: And sometimes it worked and sometimes it didn't.
Scott: But it comes down to two things.
Scott: Number one, the person who's in charge of Netrunner or was the lead designer moved on to go do another game, and now we have a new lead designer.
Scott: So they're making different decisions.
Scott: And two, over the course of multiple years of Netrunner play and looking at the statistics, which the new lead designer and old lead designer both did, they've seen that for a living card game, the whole point of Netrunner, the reason I've been able to play it for so long, because they keep putting out new cards and the game keeps changing.
Scott: You don't see people having such this huge community and world championships around a game that doesn't freaking change ever.
Scott: It's like if we were playing Settlers.
Rym: Yeah, except chess.
Scott: And Scrabble.
Scott: But people are as obsessed with it.
Scott: But it's so boring.
Rym: Go has not changed since there was a time back in medieval times they had the rule to balance the fact that one color was more strong than the other color.
Scott: All right, so chess go.
Scott: What happens there is even though the game itself doesn't change over time, the game is so big that people still haven't figured it out yet.
Rym: Ah, true.
Rym: That is true.
Rym: I mean, Tic Tac Toe, the scene died once someone figured out the optimal opening.
Scott: It's like baseball hasn't changed that much, but people keep getting better at baseball.
Scott: If you just had the Netrunner core set, people would max it out and then it would come down to luck because the game isn't as big, there isn't as much to improve.
Scott: There's a limit to how, you know.
Scott: It's like, well, we've discovered the best possible deck and the best possible way to play and now it just comes down to shuffling the cards.
Scott: You need to keep adding more cards or changing the cards around to keep it interesting.
Rym: Or make a game like chess where it's so deep that people will continually come up with novel ways to play parts of the game.
Scott: There aren't that many novel ways to play because a lot of cards are just mathematically obviously less better than--.
Rym: Granted, arguably there aren't that many novel ways to play chess.
Rym: I've been reading studies of current strategy.
Rym: Front halves of chess games are not evolving in any significant way among human players.
Scott: Not now, but what if you were playing chess in the 40s or the 30s or the 1800s?
Rym: It seems like in the late 80s it started to solidify.
Rym: Right, so it took a long time, but maybe this will hurt chess, the fact that it's not-- I think it actually will because it's hit this point where it seems like games are getting longer because players get beyond the point.
Rym: a human could even have a reasonable state of the game.
Scott: So Netrunner, which is a big game but isn't quite as big as chess-- Not quite, not quite.
Scott: In terms of depth, room to grow as a player and advance over time, right?
Scott: You need new cards to come out, to shake things up, but despite new cards coming out, if you look, certain things are not changing over time.
Scott: There are certain cards that were in 100% of the top decks at the World Championship.
Rym: It's like fantasy football.
Rym: 100% of the teams have one of three quarterbacks.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: In other cards it was like 80% of decks, regardless of which deck they were playing, all had this card in it.
Scott: 100%, regardless of what, had this card in it.
Scott: And sometimes it's okay that they all have this card, right?
Scott: And there's a really basic card, like Sure Gamble, which is just the basic money card that's in the core set.
Scott: It makes sense that everyone has that in their deck.
Rym: Well, because it's a sure thing.
Scott: It makes sense that 90% of their decks would have this really basic thing in it, right?
Scott: But there are certain other cards that don't.
Scott: It's like, why is this same exact ice in every deck?
Scott: And because everyone's using that one, none of these other ice are getting made, getting used at all.
Scott: We printed all these cards and no one is using them ever because this one exists.
Scott: There are other problems where it's like, well, we'd really, you know, there's a card that lets you break any code gate.
Scott: that's three or less, you know, for free, for zero, free.
Scott: And it's a core set card.
Scott: It's like this key thing.
Scott: And it's even easy to break.
Scott: You can boost it a little bit and even break things that are four for free.
Scott: So this really hurts them because it's like they want to make all kinds of interesting code gate ice and nobody is using any of these.
Scott: Nobody who's winning is using any code gate ice.
Scott: It doesn't matter if there's zero, one, two or three, you know, or even four.
Scott: They're just not using any of these cards.
Scott: So it's like it's restricting their game design.
Scott: Like we can't print any new cards that do that fit in these holes because no one will use them because that card exists.
Rym: And you might think like, oh, maybe the meta would sort it out.
Rym: But no, because the cost to having that card in your deck is basically zero.
Rym: But the cost of having a bunch of ice that's really easily broken through by that card completely wrecks you if someone has the card.
Rym: So it only works out if someone happens to not play that card.
Scott: So imagine if like there's a card that will totally wreck you if you play is like totally wrecks like 20 different cards.
Scott: So people stop playing those 20 different cards because they'll just get wrecked.
Scott: And now people stop playing the card that wrecks those 20 cards also.
Scott: But people still won't play any of the cards.
Scott: Basically, none of those cards are getting played at all.
Scott: So what they did is they came up with this thing, which is the N.A.P.D.
Scott: most wanted list.
Scott: So any card that's on the list, basically, if you know the rules of Netrunner, cost basically reduces your influence by total influence, total by one, but not below one, even if it's in your faction already, which in which case it'd be like it.
Rym: for those of you who've never played.
Rym: If in Magic the Gathering, you can only have one color in your deck and then you could have up to 15 points worth of other colors.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But now there's your green deck.
Scott: But this really powerful OP green card is still going to cost you a point, even though you're green and normally it would cost you zero points.
Scott: So there's a bunch of cards on the list.
Scott: There's a bunch of cards that aren't on the list that maybe should or should not be.
Scott: But it's really going to shake things up in quite an interesting way.
Scott: That is.
Scott: And a lot of, you know, the stagnation, hopefully some people are just taking the decks that, like, were the top and just sort of removing a few cards, you know, so that they can basically get 90 percent of the power they had before with the same idea.
Scott: And maybe that's all that'll happen.
Scott: But, you know, the fact that they've shown that they're going to do this means that, well, if they don't see the statistics change, if they still see the same decks winning over and over, they're going to push it even further.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And, you know, they like they want the game to.
Scott: it's supposed to be a living game, like living Greyhawk.
Scott: They want it to constantly.
Scott: they want to see lots of changes over time.
Scott: They don't want to see the game stagnate.
Rym: And the interesting thing is, as much as we talk about analyzing games and game design with a game like this, it is feasible to figure out ahead of time, like if this will work or like what changes you make will affect the game.
Rym: But practically it is not.
Rym: It is not feasible for a company to put the resources required to do the kind of playtesting and analysis that would tell them whether or not these changes will affect the meta or not.
Rym: So you pretty much got to throw it out there with an educated guess and see what happens.
Rym: So in other news, an auspicious Kickstarter launched today on the 5th of January, the Burning Wheel Codex.
Scott: 2016.
Scott: That should have been 2015 to get an extra five in there.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, I guess you could have waited until May 5th, 2055.
Scott: So he loves those dicks.
Scott: They have a lot of the same number.
Rym: It already met its goal.
Rym: It met its goal immediately because it's Burning Wheel.
Rym: If you've listened to GeekNights for any amount of time and somehow haven't heard us talk about Burning Wheel.
Scott: Seriously?
Rym: I mean, it's not the best.
Scott: You must be a brand new listener.
Rym: It's not the best role-playing system in the world because that's an impossible question to answer.
Rym: But it is one of the best.
Scott: If you want to play a serious, hardcore fantasy role-playing game, this should be the first place you look.
Rym: It's the best medieval gritty fantasy role-playing system in the world, in my opinion.
Rym: If you want medieval gritty, if you want other kinds of medieval or other kinds of gritty, or you don't want medieval or gritty.
Scott: It's also fantasy.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Fantasy, medieval, gritty.
Rym: You want to have those three things.
Rym: Burning Wheel does it.
Rym: Also, if you want your uncle to hate you.
Rym: Burning Wheel's the game where you want your uncle to hate you.
Rym: But Burning Wheel went through, you know, there were a lot of editions of it.
Rym: And then there was the gold edition was the gold standard.
Rym: Like that was Burning Wheel.
Scott: Right.
Scott: First there was Burning Wheel, then there was revised, and then there was gold.
Scott: It's like, all right, we fixed most, you know, 90% of the problems.
Scott: We rejiggered, we streamlined.
Scott: Burning Wheel gold is the one you should play.
Scott: Burning Wheel gold is still the one you should play.
Rym: It is, but gold came out, but there was a lot of other material in Burning Wheel that came out in the revised era.
Scott: And even before, like the monster man, the monstrous compendium is pre-revised.
Scott: The adventure burner, the blossoms are falling, a lot of these extra books were in the revised era.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like the same thing with D&D.
Scott: It's like you have your second edition, you know, the complete paladin.
Scott: And then third edition comes out and like, well, I guess I'm throwing on my complete paladin also, because that's useless now.
Rym: So I didn't actually look at exactly what all is included in this, but basically the Kickstarter is, hey, if you want to buy the right, the Burning Wheel gold book, you can get it real cheap.
Rym: And you can get the codex, which is basically going to be the equivalent of you have your D&D books.
Rym: And then next to them, you have all those brown books, like the complete guide to elves.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So basically what happened was, you know, things like the adventure burner had very, and the magic burner had short print runs, weren't reprinted, weren't kept in print, and there was a high demand for them.
Scott: And, you know, Lucas has reasons for not printing them probably because they go with revised, you know, he thinks that they're flawed.
Scott: So in the Burning Wheel codex, which goes with Burning Wheel gold, you get rules for magic, rules for monsters, you know, commentary, all the things that were in Adventure Burner, monsters, you know, all the things.
Rym: A companion to the Burning Wheel gold system, including additional life has magic and rules commentary, because we know Luke.
Rym: And I'm sure that Luke, if he had his druthers, would be happy to rewrite the rules of Burning Wheel to make all the clarifications necessary.
Rym: But in reality, no one is going to do that.
Rym: It is easier to write commentary and errata than it is to rewrite rules.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So take it from someone who's been reading a lot of rules to games, because we're doing a panel on writing rules for games at PAX South.
Scott: If you want to play some Burning Wheel, this is something you probably want, especially if you already play some Burning Wheel.
Rym: Yeah, also, seriously, it's 50 bucks to get the codex hardcover and Burning Wheel gold hardcover.
Scott: Oh, if you already have Burning Wheel gold, how much does it cost to just get the codex?
Scott: That's real cheap.
Rym: Yeah, D&D costs more than 50 bucks, guys.
Scott: I know, right?
Scott: So this is your chance to buy some Burning Wheels if you don't have it already.
Rym: So the other thing, it's not really news.
Rym: You know AGDQ is happening, I assume.
Rym: If you don't, it's Games Done Quick.
Scott: And you know, when I first looked at the schedule, usually in the past two or three years when I've looked at the schedule, I've found games and things on the schedule that I definitely want to see that.
Scott: This time, I looked at the schedule and there was only a few things I wanted to see, but I'm bored at work, I tune in, and every time I tune in, it's something I want to see, even though I didn't saw it on the schedule.
Rym: Well, you're like, "Okay, Disney's Aladdin.
Rym: Why do I care about a 17-minute run of Disney's
Rym: Aladdin?".
Scott: When I saw that Aladdin run, I was like, "Damn,
Scott: son."
Scott: You see through the Matrix on that crap.
Scott: Plus, it was real funny watching all the cutscenes.
Rym: The craziest one that I watched so far was the NecroDancer one.
Rym: That, like, I can't even, like, I went back and watched sections again.
Rym: I can't imagine how he was making the decisions.
Rym: he was making that quickly.
Rym: He was doing APM shit like you do in an RTS.
Scott: The thing I don't understand is how someone could dedicate so much of their life to just playing NecroDancer and not get bored of it and, like, want to keep doing it and perfecting and honing, you know, their NecroDancer blade to be so freaking sharp.
Scott: It's like, really?
Scott: Wow, that's dedication that I do not have.
Scott: I couldn't even play the game for more than, like, a little while.
Rym: Like, I did that with Advance Wars.
Rym: We know people who have done that with Counter-Strike.
Rym: Most people pick a small number of games.
Scott: But that's not nearly as grueling in the physical taxing area as NecroDancer.
Scott: Yeah, NecroDancer is a hard- Especially on the mode he's playing.
Rym: Yeah, he's playing on a mode where, basically, one hit kills you, you can't touch gold or you die, you can only ever have a dagger.
Scott: You have to hit something on every single beat no matter what.
Rym: Yep, if you ever don't hit the button, dig the wrong way or anything, death, the game developers themselves, if you put the game in the mode that this dude played, they pop up a warning.
Scott: It says they're pretty sure this is impossible.
Rym: Yeah, they're like, there is no way.
Scott: They thought it was impossible.
Rym: And Spoody Biscuit, I don't know what to tell you, but good God.
Rym: The one I'm most looking forward to, actually, is the Secret of Mana one and the Final Fantasy IV one, those two.
Scott: So, the Secret of Mana one, I didn't realize- See, normally, I don't need to watch Secret of Mana being played, right?
Scott: I know what's gonna happen.
Scott: But what I found out is that this- I saw earlier in the AGDQ, during that Disney block with the Aladdin game, a guy was playing Goof Troop.
Scott: And I was like, what the fuck?
Scott: I don't give a shit, right?
Scott: It looks like some combination of Lolo and something else, only this Goofy and this Max.
Rym: I played that game.
Scott: Anyway, but the guy was playing with two SNES controllers and he was only one person playing a co-op game.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: That same guy is doing the Secret of Mana run.
Rym: Yeah, any percent, one P, two C.
Scott: One player, two controller.
Scott: That is why I have to see the Secret of Mana run.
Rym: And then, Scott, right after that, it's only 25 minutes, is Turtles in Time, one P, two C.
Scott: Whoa, one P, two C. Serious biz.
Scott: But anyway, yeah, that's gonna be exciting because of the one P, two C.
Rym: Yeah, and there's some classics here, like the Mario 2 in 15 minutes.
Scott: Well, you gotta see the Super Metroid every time, no matter what.
Rym: Yeah, 'cause that's always crazy.
Rym: But I'm kinda into the Final Fantasy IV one, 'cause I actually know a lot about the glitchy stuff you can do in that game, but- It says no 64 floor glitch, so I think that means that it's any percent, which means anything is on the table.
Scott: They can do all sorts of other glitches, but not that one, 'cause that one, I guess, is bullshit or something.
Rym: Yeah, but what's interesting- so here's why I'm interested in that.
Rym: The main set of glitches I know about are- they're kinda like that gunslinger thing, where you can sorta fuck with the game and make weird crap happen.
Rym: I think it's gonna be one of those situations where he's hitting buttons to program the RNG to make nonsense happen.
Scott: Yeah, I'm wondering, like, it's really hard, a game with random encounters like that can be really difficult to-.
Rym: Yeah, I thought that, but then I watched the Chrono Trigger, and the guy was like, "Oh, I gotta do this and this and this and this and this and this and this, so that when I get to this one random encounter, this one guy does this one thing that lets me beat it real
Rym: quick.".
Scott: I also watched them play D&D Shadow over Mystara today.
Scott: No deaths.
Rym: What?
Rym: No- Well, I guess, yeah, it's AGDQ.
Scott: He did not die.
Rym: You know what it is?
Rym: You know what you said?
Rym: How could someone dedicate their life to that?
Rym: AGDQ, if you are that person, if you have decided to dedicate your life to, like, Goof Troop or Super Monkey Ball, this is your time to shine.
Scott: And all of us who cannot do such a thing will watch upon you and honor you and heaps praise upon you.
Rym: The honor is deserved.
Rym: My field of fucks has overfloweth.
Rym: So, things of the day.
Rym: This is some text, and you just have to read it all, but I'm going to read for you the title of this article.
Rym: I did some cursory research to make sure this wasn't just an elaborate scam, and I found a lot of corroborating evidence.
Scott: The title is- It's an elaborate scam.
Rym: The true story of Roland the Farter and how the internet killed- As in?
Rym: Yes, professional flatulence.
Scott: Well, I think Rym is the most upset about this because he would become a professional flatulator if that was a possibility.
Rym: I was describing- I was telling Emily about this the other day, and she was like, "How would you fart on
Rym: command?".
Rym: And I was like, "Well, because I
Rym: can.".
Scott: And then you just went and farted?
Rym: Well, no, because I at least have to prime it, so I gotta go-.
Scott: Well, I guess Roland is a little better than you, huh?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Maybe before his performance, he'd do the thing to prime his butt to be able to fart.
Rym: So, I'm gonna read for you just the beginning few paragraphs of this.
Rym: It's short.
Rym: Roland, court minstrel to 12th century English king Henry II, probably had many talents, but history has recorded only one.
Rym: Referred to variously as Roland le Sausser, Roland le Farter, Roland le Petoy, and Roland the Farter, Roland really had one job in the court.
Rym: Every Christmas, during the court's riotous pageant, he performed a dance that ended with, quote, "One jump, one whistle, and one fart, executed
Rym: simultaneously.".
Rym: For this, Roland was gifted a manor house in Hemmingsdon, Suffolk, and more than 100 acres of land.
Scott: Listen, in the medieval times, they didn't have no Netflix, alright?
Rym: So, basically this article talks about the real talent of farting on command, which was part of the repertoire of the equivalent of Gleeman from ye olden times, leading up to this black and white photograph from the late 1800s of a man performing flatulence at the Moulin Rouge theater, and how actually this art continued until the early 1900s.
Rym: So, yeah, this is quite a wild ride, this article.
Rym: Oh, and there are people who still do this.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Methane, apparently, is the current sort of well-known world fart dude, and here's a picture of him farting on a birthday cake, I guess.
Scott: I guess he's trying to light those candles up.
Rym: But he's holding like a video game?
Rym: I don't know what he's doing.
Rym: There's something going on there.
Scott: Alright, well, I'm not really interested in Mr.
Scott: Methane.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm real interested in the history of Roland the Farter.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So, what do you got?
Scott: So, in Dubai, a place where there's mad people with mad monies, you know, they built a whole bunch of buildings there, most of which with evil slave labor, which is why people, you know, didn't want World Cup/Olympics or anything like that to ever be there.
Scott: So, it's pretty funny, I guess, in a, I don't know, in a haha kind of way, as in a haha-you-deserve-it kind of way.
Rym: In a cosmic justice irrespective of the local consequences way.
Scott: To see a ridiculous luxury hotel in Dubai go up in flames, and also a skyscraper in flames is not something you see every day.
Rym: Yeah, that does not really happen.
Scott: Usually, they're not flammable.
Scott: They're not really made of wood.
Scott: You couldn't set, like, you couldn't even set my apartment building on fire.
Scott: You know, it's like someone's, one person's apartment would, like, burn out, and the sprinklers would put it out.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So, it's like, yeah, I don't know how this got started.
Rym: Yep, I saw the stories about it, but other than noting that that happened, I didn't actually read any of the stories.
Scott: So, this, I think, is a Russian or Eastern European photographer, and he happened to be in Dubai, and he saw this out the window, and everyone's like, "Well, I'm gonna take some photos, some video, and I'm gonna make a
Scott: time-lapse.".
Scott: And he made this amazing time-lapse.
Rym: The fireballs coming out of the building are the most interesting part, because from the distance he's at, those things could not be small.
Scott: The shot he's got shows, like, you know, the Burj Dubai next to the, you know, this hotel, which is, like, in the center of town.
Scott: And it's like, "Well, it's pretty epic visuals that you will not see often, if
Scott: ever.".
Scott: So, in the meantime, we are going-- And the next time the fire alarm goes off in your hotel, will you think about actually leaving?
Scott: Nope.
Rym: I'm gonna, you know what, I'm gonna take that risk, because let me tell you, the day I decided-- If you were in that hotel, though, you would have stayed in.
Rym: Yeah, and I think, you know, I will stay in the hotel.
Rym: if the fire alarm goes off, unless I'm more than, I don't know, 50 stories up, then I might at least go out into the hallway and see if anyone else is leaving.
Rym: But if I'm at a convention, and some motherfucker pulls the fire alarm, I am not going outside.
Rym: I am just going back to sleep.
Scott: But don't go to a convention in Dubai.
Rym: I would not go to Dubai if I could avoid it.
Rym: I'm generally avoiding those places lately for a lot of reasons.
Scott: Yeah, good idea.
Rym: So, in a moment, we are going to be at Pac South 2016.
Rym: That shit's coming up real quick.
Scott: It's, like, two or three weeks away.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Saturday, 1pm, Atari Game Design.
Rym: Saturday, 5.30pm, Scared Yet?
Rym: A Discussion of Horror in Games.
Rym: Sunday, at 1pm, Designing Game Rules.
Rym: All three of these are in the Bobcat Theater.
Rym: All three of these can be yours.
Rym: Two of them involve Scott, and the third one involves a whole bunch of smart people, and I guess, somehow, I tricked my way to be on this thing, too.
Rym: It's Chris Straub, it's Susan Art from GamesRadar, Dave Allen from Penny Arcade, and me.
Scott: I'm going to find a way to play a ton of fucking games.
Rym: I feel like this is not the RPG packs.
Rym: I feel like I want to play mostly German Euro this time.
Scott: Also, I've somehow ended up with a Netrunner tournament kit, so maybe I'll run an unofficial, unlicensed, you know, unsanctioned Netrunner tournament, if there are enough people at PAX South who will come at the time of my choosing.
Rym: Or, you know, actually, I was about to say...
Scott: And judging by that panel schedule, probably Sunday morning.
Rym: Maybe it is the RPG con, because a lot of the RPG people we know tend to go to PAX South instead of the other PAXes.
Scott: We can do some RPG, perhaps some Burning Wheel plus Codex.
Rym: Ooh, I could bring the one-off that I mostly finish running for you guys.
Scott: Chris, I don't think the Codex is going to be here by the end of the month, right?
Rym: I'll go to Luke and be like, "Yo, can I have some design
Rym: files?".
Scott: But I've got a lot of RPGs that we have not yet played.
Rym: Yeah, I've got The Warren.
Rym: I haven't even read The Warren yet.
Scott: That's a good one.
Scott: I got Ryutama, which is like the JRPG of tabletop RPGs.
Rym: Yep, Emily has Night Witches, which we haven't played either.
Scott: Plenty RPGs to play.
Rym: So yeah, come to PAX South.
Rym: All of this can be yours.
Rym: Also, apparently Chris Straub is going to have an unofficial event somewhere Saturday night.
Rym: It's an ELO roundtable.
Rym: As in, ELO.
Rym: The ELO you're thinking of.
Scott: The ranking system?
Rym: No, Electra Like Orchestra.
Rym: He's making a big deal about how he wants to do this.
Rym: I don't know why.
Rym: All these people are tweeting like, "Wait, you mean...".
Rym: And he's like, "Yeah, so we'll
Rym: see.".
Scott: Which one, though?
Rym: All of them.
Rym: Everything that can be held under the banner of ELO.
Scott: So both rankings and awesome music?
Rym: No, all the music of ELO.
Rym: And all the iterations of EL and all the people related to it.
Scott: So the music.
Scott: He doesn't care about ranking chess players.
Rym: No, though it would be funny if enough of us showed up at the thing and only wanted to talk about ranking chess players.
Rym: Every year I play a game that I hate, and every year I either win or almost win.
Rym: And sure enough, this year again, I won like $400 in fantasy football at my company.
Scott: It's not a hard game to win.
Rym: Even though they all took it super seriously, and all I did was every day I logged in once, I looked at who had the best projection numbers, and I used my waivers and nonsense to get whatever players I could, made the statistically maximum team, and then didn't touch it again.
Rym: I made no trades, I made 29 acquisitions, and I won.
Rym: I got a pile of money.
Rym: The only thing that was interesting is that for all they're paying attention and not paying attention to the stats, I did way worse this year than I'd ever done because they changed the way the beginning worked.
Rym: Usually people just do the auction, but my company, I think they all caught on to the fact that I kind of manipulated them in the auction every year.
Rym: So they changed it to the snake so I couldn't mess with them.
Scott: How does the snake work?
Rym: So the snake works, it's Settlers of Catan.
Rym: So start with player one, just go back and forth.
Scott: That's why it's a snake.
Rym: Yes, back and forth, back and forth.
Scott: That's not bad.
Rym: But what it meant was instead of having all the good players because no one knows how to bid on things or value things in any degree in the real world, I actually had a pretty average team, as did everyone.
Scott: That's how a snake's gonna be.
Rym: Yeah, still won though.
Rym: But in the last game, because the Seahawks clinched a while ago, so they had two games left where- Who's gonna get put on the field in a game that doesn't matter?
Scott: Who's gonna try in a game that doesn't matter?
Scott: It's like you got a team that's clinched against a team that can't make the playoffs.
Scott: They have to play football, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, what's gonna happen?
Rym: The whole game is like the last three minutes of a hockey game where a team's down by five.
Rym: It's just, alright, what's gonna go on?
Rym: So almost my whole team was Seahawks, like four of my players.
Rym: And I was winning because of that.
Scott: You gotta find teams that still have something to play for.
Rym: Oh, no, no, no.
Rym: So they clinched it.
Rym: So I actually acquired more Seahawks because everyone else was ditching them.
Rym: And I assumed that because of the way that fandom is, the Seahawks fandom, and because of the way Russell Wilson is, because he was close to some NFL records and some other stuff, I assumed they were gonna play full-on post-clinch.
Rym: And they did.
Rym: So I got a lot of fantasy points.
Rym: Fantasy football's kind of boring.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, despite being on break for a long time, I played a bunch of games, but Rym didn't really play any of the games that I played.
Scott: I played a ton of games, but I played-- And also we played a lot of games that we had already played and already talked about on GeekNights before.
Rym: Yup, and I don't have a lot new--.
Rym: Well, it's interesting, though, because like TowerFall, I have watched-- I've been seeing tons of people who are gamers or not that much into gaming be introduced to TowerFall.
Rym: I've seen different people teach it to them in different ways, introduce it to them in different ways.
Rym: I've seen pretty much the full scope, and while I have a lot to say about that, I'm pretty much gonna pull all that into our learning games panel that we're gonna do probably at PAX East.
Scott: We already did an episode on that game.
Rym: Yeah, but that game was very instructive for me, because it's one of the few times I've seen a relatively simple game like that taught and introduced by many different people to many different other people, seen some players go through the progression through mastery, other players drop it immediately because they hate it.
Rym: Who got into it, who didn't get into it was-- Some surprising trends actually appeared.
Rym: So TowerFall was interesting in that regard.
Rym: Also, I really like it, and I'm really good at it now.
Scott: So one of the games that I played that Rym didn't play is something that was really cheap in the Steam sale, called Risk of Rain.
Scott: I'm not sure why it's called that.
Rym: Rain like the rain of Alexander the Great?
Scott: No, rain like shh.
Scott: Water falling from the sky.
Rym: I think I own it.
Rym: I just haven't played it.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: I didn't know what the game was, but I'd heard of it a bunch.
Scott: It was one of those popular indie games.
Scott: It was super cheap.
Scott: So I'm like, "I got nothing to do.
Scott: I'm home.
Scott: I'm not working.
Scott: Let's relax with a nice
Scott: game.".
Scott: So this game is a platforming, shooting, roguelike game.
Scott: So you get put on this partially procedurally generated map.
Scott: You're a little tiny dude.
Scott: You have guns.
Scott: There's four different moves.
Scott: One of the moves, you use all four trigger buttons to do your moves, right?
Scott: So it's like R2 is your regular attack.
Scott: Then you got two special attacks.
Scott: Usually one of them hits a bunch of guys and shoots through them, and one of them is a slow but single power shot.
Scott: And then everyone has sort of a movement, defensive kind of move.
Scott: So depending on the character you choose, these moves are slightly different.
Scott: And the defensive move will be like the ninja guy sort of puts smoke on himself and can be invisible for a little while.
Scott: The basic guy just runs really fast and can sort of do a roll and a flip to get out of the way.
Scott: You know, stuff like that.
Scott: There's one guy who puts a shield up.
Scott: He's like a riot trooper.
Scott: And you're this little tiny guy.
Scott: You go around this platforming map, left and right, up and down ladders, jumping from platforms, killing bad guys.
Scott: And when you kill bad guys, they spit out XP and gold.
Scott: And one really good thing the game does is that XP and gold just comes right to you.
Scott: You don't got to go over there and get it.
Scott: You don't got to collect it.
Scott: You don't got to do shit.
Scott: You just kill the guy.
Rym: Good job, guys.
Scott: And then, you know, there's stuff around like, you know, treasure chests and items to buy with gold and stuff just lying on the ground.
Scott: It's like a roguelike, you know.
Scott: And it's highly skill based, right?
Scott: Bad guys have certain attack patterns and you can figure out ways to kill them from relative safety.
Scott: You level up, you get more powerful, you get more items.
Scott: Mostly the items are what make you more powerful.
Scott: Leveling up doesn't do much at all.
Scott: And as you level up, bad guys get more dangerous.
Scott: And you're trying to get to the exit of a level.
Scott: To get to the exit, you have to activate this teleporter.
Scott: And when you activate the teleporter, you then have to survive for 90 seconds without dying.
Scott: And during those 90 seconds, it spawns hella enemies everywhere.
Rym: So it's like half of the mini boss battle scenes in Human Revolution.
Scott: Including at least one ridiculous boss enemy.
Rym: Hit the door to activate the elevator and then hide and survive for like 20 minutes while the guys come and try to find you.
Scott: Nope, because even when the 90 seconds ends, you can't go in the teleporter until you then completely clear the map of enemies.
Scott: Then you go in the teleporter to go to the next level.
Scott: And I guess you just keep doing that.
Scott: On easy mode, I was able to get to like 5 or 6 levels through.
Scott: And it didn't end really, so I'm not sure if there is an end.
Scott: On normal difficulty, it was so ridiculously hard because the exp and gold payout was so low, you couldn't really get all the items.
Scott: And if you tried to farm, you would level up.
Scott: And then the bad guys would get too hard at too rapid a pace.
Scott: So even when you went to the next level, I couldn't really figure out how to properly scale my play.
Scott: Should I just rush into level 2?
Scott: But when I tried to rush into level 2, and I activated the teleporter as quickly as possible, I wasn't strong enough to survive for 90 seconds.
Scott: And I just died, I couldn't make it to level 2.
Rym: You know what other game has that real hard decision?
Rym: It's NecroDancer, because you can go faster to avoid fights, but then you get less stuff, which makes the later parts even harder.
Rym: But if you stick around getting all the stuff, you might end up having no health.
Scott: I think the biggest problem in this game is simply the fact that they made everything hella small.
Scott: It's like this big ol' screen, and you're this little tiny dude, and everything else is relatively tiny.
Rym: Oh shit, that reminds me, we forgot to play Scorched Earth at the party.
Scott: I know.
Scott: Everything's hella tiny, and a lot of times I died, it's just because I would be stuck in a mess of bad guys.
Scott: And it's like, well I can't really see what the fuck's going on in there, can I?
Scott: And I feel like if you made a game with the same exact concept, platforming, roguelike, really similar, but instead of having this little tiny fucking thing, it was big, like Super Metroid big, that would be a fucking amazing game.
Rym: Ooh, Scott, we never did an episode on Scorched Earth.
Scott: Well, maybe we should.
Rym: Let's livestream us playing it first, and then...
Scott: That's all you, get it to work.
Rym: I will, I'll figure it out.
Rym: My problem, my worry is that with Scorched Earth, we're gonna play it on a modern resolution.
Rym: That game's made for like a 320x200.
Scott: We'll play it at 640x480.
Rym: No, let's play it at...
Scott: Or 800x600, at most.
Rym: Let's play it on your iPad and Retina, pixel versus pixel across a sea, desert.
Rym: So, Emily picked up a game, Motainai, which is another Shuddock game.
Scott: It's Glory to Rome 3.0.
Rym: Yeah, Shuddock keeps trying to make the same game over and over again.
Scott: That was Glory to Rome, then there was Glory to Rome, same game, better art, then there was Euchronia.
Rym: Which is bad, but...
Scott: And then there was Motainai.
Rym: Now there's also innovation.
Scott: That's not Glory to Rome 1, 2, or 3.0, it's a separate game.
Rym: So, I didn't play Motainai yet, but I read the rules.
Rym: Emily played it, Scott played it.
Scott: I played it one or two times.
Rym: And a bunch of our board gamer friends played it like a hundred times and got obsessed with it over the weekend.
Scott: Not a hundred times, but they played it a lot.
Rym: Yeah, they played it a lot.
Rym: They played it all night.
Rym: And the thing is, this isn't a full review now, but what's interesting about it is that it's designed for two or three players.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Rym: He says that in the rules, and that seems to be true.
Rym: It includes two identical decks.
Rym: So you play it with two or three.
Rym: If you want to play with four or five...
Scott: You put in a second deck.
Rym: You shuffle the second identical deck in and the game takes like seven times longer.
Scott: It didn't take seven times longer when he played with two decks.
Rym: Well, you're also supposed to, according to the rules, increase the count.
Rym: that ends the game by one.
Scott: By one?
Scott: That didn't make it last longer at all.
Rym: Well, you only played one game.
Rym: Everyone has played a lot more games.
Scott: I played it twice.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, so, I mean, I'm not that into Glory to Rome.
Scott: I'm even less into Motainai.
Scott: It's a game where like the game ended so rapidly.
Scott: Both times I played, the game ended like right before my turn.
Scott: And it was just like I had maybe two, three turns and the game was over.
Scott: There really wasn't anything to do.
Scott: Which is interesting.
Rym: I see it like a distilled version of Glory to Rome.
Rym: If you play that kind of game, but instead of a lot of diffuse decisions that culminate into a machine, it's what can I do in a few turns based on what everyone else is doing?
Rym: It's deeply reactive, which is a lot like innovation.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like, I mean, a game where you have, you know, all this stuff to like, you know, usually when you play a board game, it's like, it doesn't have to be long, but it's like you want to, you know, you start with nothing.
Scott: You want to build a little machine and then you want to crank that machine one or two times and you sort of see who built the best machine.
Scott: And this, it's like turn one, play some stuff.
Scott: Turn two, get a little bit more stuff.
Scott: If you're lucky, turn three, maybe score some points and it's over.
Rym: You know what it's almost more like?
Rym: It's almost more like Dominion.
Rym: Everyone looks at it and says,
Rym: "Go!"
Rym: And then whoever says, "I got it," wins.
Rym: It's like whoever figures it out.
Scott: I made so few decisions in each game.
Rym: And each one was devastating.
Scott: And it's like there really weren't, you know, a lot of choices.
Scott: It wasn't very interesting choices that I made either.
Scott: It was sort of like, well, I got my hand.
Scott: I'll do the best I can do with the hand I've got.
Scott: And okay, the end.
Scott: And it's just like that was really deeply unsatisfying.
Rym: But at the same time...
Scott: If the game went on longer, it might have been just as good as Glory to Rome where it's like, "Okay, I can build a little thing, get some stuff going on, do some
Scott: cranking.".
Rym: See, that's it.
Rym: Glory to Rome has a long crank cycle and this has more of the like.
Rym: immediate decision, short crank factor matters.
Scott: But you don't even crank.
Scott: It's like almost nothing happened.
Scott: The game ended.
Rym: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: I really don't understand why people like it.
Rym: So interviewing our friends who are gamers who played the shit out of it at the party, their sentiments were that one, none of them had that problem except you.
Rym: And two, that it was satisfying because it was so quick.
Rym: Once you had some fluency in the game, you could just bang the game out in 15 minutes, be done and have had a short, satisfying experience and move on.
Scott: It was very definitely short.
Scott: It wasn't satisfying.
Rym: But the reason why I think you hate it because I hate innovation and I love Glory to Rome.
Rym: You're okay with Glory to Rome and you also hate innovation right alongside me.
Scott: Yeah, innovation's bad game.
Rym: This game is Glory to Rome x innovation in a lot of ways.
Scott: I didn't really see the innovation aspect in it.
Rym: No, in the sense that Glory to Rome, because there's so many more actions and your influence is a little more diffuse, you don't need to know all the cards in the game and what they do to play pretty competently in Glory to Rome.
Rym: You need to know what a few of the big ones do and otherwise you can kind of just wing it.
Rym: You don't even need to pay that much attention to the buildings other people are building.
Scott: One thing I did like about Motainai that I don't like about Glory to Rome is that in Motainai, you're actually taking freaking turns.
Scott: In Glory to Rome, everyone plays simultaneously.
Scott: You can't really pay too much attention to what everyone else is... But in Motainai, you can perfectly follow everything that everyone's doing because they're all taking turns one at a time.
Scott: So it's like, "Aha!
Scott: I can see what the hell's going on
Scott: here.".
Rym: I guess in terms of the puzzle feel, like watching people play, the brain feel of the game reminds me of One Night Ultimate Werewolf, where there's a huge setup and everyone looks at their stuff, stares at each other for a while, and then makes a few moves.
Scott: The other problem is that modern game design, things like Ticket to Ride, is all about.
Scott: on your turn, you do something small and the turns go around really quickly.
Scott: Motainai sort of undoes that and goes back to really old-school design where one person does a whole ton of shit on their turn and then you sit during everyone else's turn doing fuck-all, waiting and being pissed off.
Rym: But that gets around the problem you just said you had with Glory to Rome, where everyone acts simultaneously, so it's hard to keep track of what they're all doing.
Rym: Because this game, because there's so few decisions...
Scott: I think the ideal would be, you still take turns, but you do a little bit on your turn and take a lot more turns.
Scott: That's a modern design that's more enjoyable.
Scott: Less waiting.
Rym: But the game's only 15 minutes, how much waiting could it have been?
Rym: You spent more time waiting in that Hansa game.
Scott: I'm saying most of the game was waiting.
Scott: My turn took like a few seconds and the rest of the 15 minutes was waiting.
Scott: I only got like three turns.
Rym: And you spend most of that turn, when other people are taking their turns, watching everything they're doing and reconstructing the model of how the game's gonna play out in your head.
Scott: I'd rather have more shorter turns than few long turns.
Rym: Anyway, we assumed you wouldn't like the game based on its lineage.
Rym: I'm gonna play it a whole bunch, two or three player, and we'll have a review once.
Rym: I fully grok it, because I do not grok it enough to speak to whether it's actually good or bad.
Rym: But the overwhelming sentiment of our friends was that it was good, except Scott.
Rym: We played, actually, a bunch of LAN party Rocket League, because our friends had two PS4s.
Scott: Rocket League is a great game.
Scott: The only reason I stopped playing it every freaking day is because of the matchmaking problem.
Scott: So I couldn't get a game where either A) there was someone who just dominated me and I was useless, or B) I was the best, and it was pointless to play because no one was competing with me.
Rym: It is interesting how heavily that skilled golf factor...
Scott: And even at this party where you had a LAN air hockey problem big time.
Scott: If I was on a team, it won.
Scott: I just put the ball in whenever I wanted to.
Rym: Yep, but then you weren't playing and the rest of us played, and the games were closer.
Rym: But there was a pretty good, like, me and Adam and Alex...
Scott: Well, Adam has played it, because he has it.
Scott: You and Adam played it about as much as each other.
Scott: Alex had played it a little bit as well.
Scott: I've seen him play it on Steam.
Scott: I've seen his name come up.
Scott: Well, they play it a lot, right?
Scott: They were like one or two tiers above you.
Rym: Yeah, they were.
Rym: That's why I started... Strategy aside, but it is interesting that even when there's skilled golfs when you're playing with friends in the same building and next to each other it's pretty fun even when one player is kind of dominant.
Rym: There's this moment where Scott made this beautiful pass and we saw that the ball was going to go in, and we saw a defender jump to be ready to go after it, and then we hear,
Rym: "Ah!"
Rym: in the other room as we see them barely miss the ball.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's still fun.
Scott: It's just disappointing when there's the air hockey problem.
Scott: I would play some Street Fighter.
Scott: Me and Rym, it's like, "I'm better at Street Fighter and I'll win," and it'll still be kind of fun.
Scott: Why?
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: Playing Street Fighter between the two of us is not fun at all.
Rym: I barely get a hit in.
Rym: There's no contest.
Scott: Well, maybe it's not fun for you.
Rym: It's fun for you to just decide when to end me.
Scott: But at least in Rocket League it's even more fun than that because you have this team aspect where even though I'm dominating because I've played it only because I've played it more hours than everyone else.
Rym: We've got to put Scott on a team with two bad people against a more moderately competent team.
Scott: Not for any other reason.
Scott: I still have to depend on the other people on my team.
Scott: It's like I can't score and defend the goal at the same time.
Scott: When I was forced to go down and try to score, it's like people were scoring goals on us because I couldn't also defend.
Scott: I could just try to get down there as fast as I could and sometimes I couldn't, but sometimes I couldn't.
Rym: What was really cool, though, was that everyone who sat down...
Scott: I'm not like a god of Rocket League.
Scott: I just played it more than everyone else.
Scott: I was slightly better enough that I could reliably...
Rym: A lot of our friends had never played it before.
Rym: When we set it up and had it going just three on three, people just kept playing.
Rym: People were having a lot of fun even when they were on the team that you were crushing.
Rym: Everyone was just super into it the whole time, which is very telling to the fun of Rocket League.
Rym: It's really fun.
Scott: I was trying to give people advice and help them out with the little bit of knowledge that I have.
Scott: Don't waste your boost just going on the ground.
Scott: You just flip and keep your car in between the ball and the net, but some people just didn't want to hear it.
Scott: I'm like, "Why?
Scott: If you were a god of Rocket League, I want to hear every fucking thing you have to
Scott: say.".
Rym: Yeah, but they say, "Oh, just do an
Rym: aerial.".
Rym: You're like,
Rym: "How?".
Scott: Well, if they were actually there, I could ask them, "Hey, should I hold the stick back now?
Scott: or when do I push the boost?
Scott: How much do I...".
Scott: I could get those questions answered.
Rym: We were doing all this on PS4.
Rym: I had my laptops.
Rym: I was just playing Rocket League on my laptop.
Rym: I just joined the game.
Rym: I had a private screen.
Scott: How high can you put the settings on your laptop?
Rym: It looked fine.
Rym: I turned off the dynamic shadows and it pretty much looked great.
Rym: I got an X230.
Rym: It's got a Core i7 in it.
Rym: That integrated video is no slouch.
Scott: Integrated video is the biggest slouch.
Rym: It's Intel's good integrated video.
Scott: There's no such thing, first of all.
Rym: Scott, that laptop can play Counter-Strike just fine.
Scott: I have the settings all the way up at home.
Rym: It didn't need to be all the way up because the resolution on that monitor is 13 whatever.
Rym: It's not the most high-resolution laptop.
Scott: I'm just saying.
Rym: But we were using PS4s.
Scott: I don't like the PS4 controller.
Scott: It's not awful, but I still don't like the stupid D-pad.
Rym: I guess I didn't have to deal with that because I was using my Xbox controller.
Scott: In Rocket League, I didn't have to use the D-pad, so it wasn't really a problem, but in games where the D-pad came into play, it was a problem.
Rym: But the PS4 is pretty inferior to an HEPC.
Rym: It's super inferior.
Rym: Do you know how many times someone would be playing TowerFall in one room and then someone else joins Rocket League in the other room?
Rym: But then they log in on the controller, and it happened to have been logged into the other room before, so it stops the other game and ruins it.
Rym: And that happened back and forth the entire party.
Rym: For some reason, the PS4, if you join a game of TowerFall, it's like, "Whoa, whoa, whoa,
Rym: whoa!".
Rym: You can't just play.
Rym: You've got to make an account and do all this nonsense.
Rym: On an HEPC, you just plug four controllers in and hit start, and it just works.
Rym: The PS4 has way too much overhead in it.
Scott: Not to mention, there were three or four people who had PlayStation accounts, because they had to own the game to play it.
Scott: Some of them owned it, and some of them didn't.
Scott: I don't know, but you go to one PS4 and you'd log in as Phil.
Scott: And you go to the other PS4, and if someone logged in as Phil on that one to play a game Phil owned, then you'd get logged out completely of the other PS4.
Scott: And it's like, "What the hell?
Scott: I can log into my Steam account on a whole bunch of computers, as long as I legit log
Scott: in.".
Scott: And as long as they're not playing the exact same game at the same time, Steam is like, "Alright, you logged in.
Scott: It's you.
Scott: You typed in your Steam Guard one-time code and everything.
Scott: You're
Scott: cool.".
Scott: As long as you don't want to play TowerFall on two computers at once, we're not gonna stop you.
Scott: In my house, I could load up Counter-Strike on my computer, and I could load up, you know, what else is on Steam?
Scott: Civ 5 on my HDPC, and it'll be like, "Okay.
Scott: No
Scott: problem.".
Rym: So, this was the first time also this party that all of us, or many of us, who are in this human versus human, giant Civ 5 game with GMR, we're in the same room together.
Scott: There are three or so people not there.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, a lot of backdoor dealings and discussion happened.
Scott: I didn't make any dealings.
Rym: I made a lot of dealings.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Deal away.
Rym: We'll probably do a show on this later, because we gotta finish this game first or fully grok it, but if you've ever wanted, like, if you play Civ 5, it's a fun game, or any Civ game.
Rym: Civ 5, where all the other players are human, is such a different game.
Scott: Well, simply just because the real-world time it takes.
Scott: You're not just pressing enter, enter, enter, enter, enter.
Scott: You get to think about every turn.
Rym: That's one aspect of it, but the second aspect is, it's a human.
Rym: When I see one lone archer and a horseman in the distance come into my field of view nearby, and I see that it's from, say, England, I gotta think real hard about what the person playing England is thinking.
Rym: Are they actually gonna declare war on me and steal that worker that's out working the colonies?
Rym: Can I risk that?
Scott: Yes, that's what's going to happen.
Rym: So, it's this really steely-eyed, stare-down game.
Scott: It's a political game, as opposed to a "how well can you manipulate this AI
Scott: game?".
Rym: No!
Rym: It is not actually that political.
Scott: It is if someone gets enough power to make it political.
Rym: But even then, the difference is the politicality of a Civ 5 game, because I've been playing other of these games with other sets of people for a while now, is that, sure, politics could be a factor, except there's a long period in the beginning where there is very little you can actually do to your opponents.
Rym: You're almost like all playing versus Solitaire.
Scott: Well, it depends on how close you are to each other.
Rym: Yeah, like if I'm Zulus and I spawn next to you, well, yeah, say goodbye to your workers.
Rym: But even if you want to be political, there's the second element of power.
Rym: differentials might be rapidly divergent based on critical decisions that get made along the way.
Scott: Right, well that's just, you know, I obviously haven't played Civ nearly as much as everyone else because I only played it, you know.
Rym: So there's a few players who have played way less than you, so.
Scott: Oh, okay, but it's like, so obviously I fully expect in short order, it's like I'm keeping up as much as I can and I'm doing better than I usually do because I have a whole plenty of time to think about each turn and micromanage some things.
Scott: I would normally just press enter a whole bunch of times.
Scott: You know, like I'm trying, like I, you know, there was a science and I switched things up to get that science one turn earlier, you know, which made a big difference actually, whereas normally I would just press enter it one more time to get it, you know.
Scott: So things like that, but still I fully expect like someone to stroll on up with like a tank while I still have like a musket.
Rym: I'm worried about that because China's on an island by itself just quietly accumulating science and building an empire.
Scott: Yeah, you're going to sail a trireme past and it's like, well, there's going to be a frigate.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Alright, destroyers, missiles coming over the ocean.
Scott: I fully expect that to happen and in which case we can just stop the game and declare that person the winner.
Scott: There's no reason to spend the rest of our lives.
Rym: It's one of those games where it's so long that it's more like a simulation.
Rym: Like even if you lose, you're kind of interested in like seeing how it all played out.
Scott: Yeah, it's not like you're going to be, it's unlikely you'll be completely eliminated.
Scott: It's more likely someone else will just build a space shuttle while you're sitting there.
Rym: But the other thing that's interesting is that when you play against AIs, the only way to make it even a reasonably interesting game is to put the AIs up, basically to put the difficulty level of Civ way, way, way up.
Scott: Yeah, see, that's how much I suck because I can't beat them when the difficulty is way up.
Rym: Yeah, well, I can't even to a degree when you get too high because...
Scott: I can't even beat it on anything above like Prince.
Scott: Like Prince is hard.
Rym: Oh, really?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: King?
Rym: When I play a Civ 5 game on King, I assume I'm going to win no matter what and it's just a matter of how.
Scott: King is a little bit tough.
Rym: So the difficulty does not make the AI smarter.
Rym: All it does is make them stronger.
Rym: Yeah, crazy bonuses like, oh, they get like twice as much happiness.
Scott: Yeah, see, I don't know like how to optimize and, you know, build you know, really efficiently.
Scott: I don't know like the build paths, just like in Starcraft.
Scott: Same thing happens in Starcraft, even though it's real time, right?
Scott: Is where like, I'll be building as fast as I can.
Scott: Like, I didn't study the best way to...
Rym: Scott, you don't know the build paths in Advance Wars.
Scott: Right, so it's like, I'll just be, you know, I'll just be doing my thing.
Scott: and then suddenly it's like, I got a little zerg-y and oh, here comes a whole bunch of tanks.
Scott: It's like, what the fuck?
Scott: I have ten tanks.
Scott: I'm still building like my first hydra list.
Rym: But here's a nice difference.
Rym: The AI for you might actually be harder than humans in that regard because when we're playing against a human, I've had the same number of turns as Scott and I'm playing by the same rules.
Rym: So, he can only have built so much shit.
Rym: It's not like...
Scott: But like, people already built wonders and like, I'm trying to build an archer to fight barbarians.
Scott: I feel like I'm already behind.
Rym: So, our friend who built the Great Library, James, he, England, any of you who didn't know that, it's England who did that.
Scott: They're not listening.
Rym: Yeah, you know what Scott Johnson said.
Rym: He said it best.
Rym: We all know what happened to the Great Library.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I mean, OK, so...
Rym: He built that by doing nothing else.
Scott: So let's compare me and you, right?
Scott: I currently have two archers and a warrior.
Scott: How big is your military?
Rym: I actually choose not to speak on my military right now because... It's so far away.
Rym: Yeah, but...
Scott: Is it bigger or smaller than mine?
Rym: It is definitely bigger than yours.
Scott: OK, so, do you have... What's the fanciest building you have?
Scott: I have a library.
Rym: I have the pyramids.
Scott: Yeah, OK, so I'm losing.
Rym: I built... You know how much...
Scott: Do you have... How many cities do you have?
Scott: I have two cities.
Rym: I only have two.
Scott: OK, so we have the same.
Rym: I'm not even building a settler right now.
Rym: I only have two cities.
Scott: I also have two cities.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So you're ahead of me because you have a pyramid and I have one worker.
Rym: I don't have any libraries.
Scott: OK.
Rym: Because I built a pyramid instead.
Scott: Yeah, a pyramid's a lot bigger than a library.
Rym: Yeah, what does the pyramid do?
Rym: How much do you think that's going to help me?
Scott: Pyramid spits out workers when it's done being built.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it does something else, I forget.
Rym: My workers work 25% faster.
Rym: Right.
Scott: My workers are actually working mad slow.
Scott: I kind of wish I had...
Rym: Well, maybe if you'd gone liberty.
Rym: I don't know why you went tradition.
Rym: Tradition sucks.
Scott: I didn't go tradition because I needed, you know, I was falling behind.
Rym: You should have gone honor with all those barbarians.
Scott: Well, I didn't know there were so many barbarians by the time I picked it.
Rym: You could still do it.
Rym: You'll still get that honor bonus.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'll see how many barbarians are left by the time my culture reaches.
Rym: Plus, honor does other things like free grade generals, better XP for troops.
Scott: Yeah, maybe.
Rym: That'll matter because Lisa's going to roll over that Russian AI and then come straight at you.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: You know that's going to happen.
Scott: That's all right.
Scott: I got two archers.
Rym: But there's just something about playing Civ 5 with humans and it is interesting that the only way to do this is to use this fan-made, giant multiplayer robot.
Scott: There is built-in multiplayer and it doesn't... It's not completely broken.
Scott: It is completely broken.
Scott: I tried to use it a couple times and it was a fail.
Rym: I set up a pit-boss server.
Rym: It just crashed and ruined a game.
Rym: I ran a game just as multiplayer, which meant it would only play when my PC was running and eventually the game got corrupted.
Rym: I did a hot seat, which also just fucked up at one point.
Rym: There's no way to play this game multiplayer.
Rym: And I asked my friends who got me into giant multiplayer robot, those other people, like, "Hey, why don't we do pit-boss or
Rym: something?".
Rym: And every one of them had the thousand yard stare of "I lost a 300 turn or whatever game to that.
Rym: Doesn't work.
Rym: Every game will get corrupted in the
Rym: end.".
Rym: There's no way to play Civ 5 multiplayer except with this GMR thing.
Rym: So yeah, played a bunch of games.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: [patrons].
Rym: I know there have been a few scant updates to the Patreon.
Rym: I trickled a little bits in along the way, but more Rym's Rants are coming.
Rym: We're finally back from the holidays.
Rym: We had a lot of weddings and sickness and travel and everything.
Rym: We're actually not doing a show on Thursday because more stuff came up.
Rym: But there's a lot of updates.
Rym: So for one, we're going to give you guys, the Patrons at least, a bunch of sort of pre-warning about the panels we're doing at PAX East, MagFest, Zenkai Con, and a few other conventions upcoming because we have that information.
Rym: It's just not public yet.
Rym: So you guys will know.
Rym: Two, the Utena stuff, all the rest of the new equipment I bought has arrived.
Rym: So I'm actually this week doing a little bit of test video and if everything goes smoothly on Sunday, Scott's coming over and we're going to finally fully resume.
Rym: GeekNights Presents Utena.
Rym: All that new pre-production has been largely completed.
Rym: So we might be able to crank these things out pretty quick once we get the ball rolling.
Rym: So otherwise, stay tuned.
Rym: There'll be some Rym's Rants and things coming.
Rym: And I leave you with one of the most wonderful things I have ever found.
Rym: And I don't think this requires any explanation.
Media: Go, go, go.
Media: Go, go.
Media: Gotta go fast.
Media: Gotta go faster, faster, faster, faster, faster.
Media: Movin' at speed of sound make tracks.
Media: Quickest hedgehog around.
Media: Got ourselves a situation stuck in a new location.
Media: Without any explanation.
Media: No time for relaxation.
Media: Don't, don't, don't, don't, don't blink, don't think.
Media: Just go, go, go, go.
Media: G-g-g-go.
Media: Go.
Rym: Nuh-nuh.
Media: Nuh-nuh-nuh-nuh-nuh.
Media: Nuh-nuh.
Media: Sonic, he's on the run.
Media: Sonic, he's number one.
Media: Sonic, he's coming next.
Media: So watch out for Sonic X. Gotta go fast.
Media: Sonic, gotta go fast.
Media: Sonic, gotta go faster, faster, faster, faster, faster.
Media: Go, go, go, go.
Media: Gotta go fast.
Media: Gotta go faster, faster, faster, faster, faster.
Media: Movin' at speed of sound.
Rym: Let's try quick and sketch hard to round.
Scott: Got ourselves a situation.
Rym: Stuck in a new location.
Rym: Without any explanation.
Rym: No time for relaxation.
Rym: Don't, don't, don't, don't, don't blink, don't think.
Rym: Just go, go, go, go.
Rym: Sonic, nuh-nuh-nuh-nuh-nuh.
Rym: Sonic, he's on the run.
Rym: Sonic, he's number one.
Rym: Sonic, he's coming next.
Rym: So watch out for Sonic X. Gotta go fast.
Rym: Sonic.