Rym: It's September 29th 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym, I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight road trips.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: Yeah, this morning co-workers sent an email to the team.
Rym: We're just like yeah gonna be late trouble with the path trains And I didn't think anything of it until then.
Scott: I saw a path was trending on Twitter And I'm like well, but if the path train wasn't the thing that had a problem It just happened to also be in the station that had the problem.
Rym: Yep, well because the it'd be like if the subway was down.
Rym: subway might be trending even though the problem is Grand Central Station's broken Or something.
Scott: what Grand Central Station is where subways are.
Scott: yeah, it's not well.
Rym: Yeah I was about to jump back and make that distinction and if they depending on how they do that train track They're building underground it might not be a terminal anymore.
Rym: Maybe might end up being a station again.
Rym: Maybe anyway.
Rym: Oh, they got a little infographic, and it shows the train, but yeah And a train in New Jersey just didn't stop and crashed through the terminal.
Scott: This is a Jersey Transit train so it goes.
Scott: It's in New Jersey.
Scott: It goes underneath the river blah blah blah blah blah blah blah blah, and then it comes into Penn Station underneath the garden Yeah, and then it stops because that's the end of the road into the second worst way to come into New York City basically.
Scott: But this one wasn't coming into Penn Station yet It was going to Hoboken.
Scott: Right it goes to Hoboken where
Rym: the hobos live and
Scott: then people in Hoboken in New Jersey get off And they either work in Hoboken which is weird But there's stuff over there or they get on a PATH train which then comes over to New York City You know in somewhere close to Penn Station or the World Trade Center.
Rym: I want to reiterate that there.
Rym: well not reiterate but we could have had subways that just go into New Jersey and From New York because so many people commute that way and it would have been great.
Rym: We could have had a tunnel we could have had.
Scott: well we have tunnels.
Scott: we need more tunnel.
Scott: We could have had a new tunnel.
Scott: I don't need more tunnels.
Scott: the Jersey people want more, but fuck them.
Scott: I don't.
Rym: yeah If we had the tunnels though it probably drive rent down a little bit here because then suddenly like people who?
Rym: Hate New York or are dumb could move to New Jersey more.
Scott: plenty of people live it.
Scott: so many people live in Jersey and commute To New York from way down.
Scott: there are people who live like way down in Jersey even in Pennsylvania who take the bus to the City every day.
Scott: yeah, and they don't.
Scott: that's like.
Scott: that's just how they do.
Rym: I could not do that this ferries.
Scott: It's like there's so many.
Scott: you can live Top half of New Jersey you can live and commute to New York City.
Rym: I was looking at a job That was would be like an awesome job that I would want to do and like.
Rym: I was qualified And they were interested even like I talked to some people about it.
Rym: But their main office is in New Jersey like even though it's right near New York, and I was like that's a deal-breaker.
Rym: I work from home 100% or you move an office into New York or this isn't happening pretty much.
Rym: Yeah, technically this job is in New Jersey Nope, but yeah, so here's the crazy thing.
Rym: apparently I don't know if it's on the same track or not because the news was surprisingly sparse.
Rym: But like five years ago this exact same thing happened and injured like 40 people.
Rym: it Just was going slower and didn't destroy the building.
Scott: yeah, didn't destroy the building it didn't kill anyone.
Scott: So it wasn't a big news then and it was quickly forgotten.
Scott: this one was much more serious But basically the same thing which tells me something is fucking wrong.
Rym: in that stage How can the train like say that?
Rym: say the person driving the train like had a heart attack and fell over and died?
Rym: Don't?
Rym: they have like some sort of positive control where if you let's go with the stick the train just stops.
Scott: there were many discussions of this and from what I seen from certain train nerds is that the interval on the positive Thing may have you know been so long that like they push it then they fall asleep.
Rym: Then and like 30 seconds before it would like stop the train and that was just like the critical moment.
Scott: Also, there's there was some regulation that said every train in the Northeast had to have this thing set up But they're not sure if the budget was ever set for it.
Rym: Oh, I think I talked about that when there was an Amtrak.
Scott: They don't know which they don't know if this station or which stations it's been set up in or not.
Rym: Basically, there's all these separate stories about a ton of safety improvements for rail in New York New Jersey in the United States as a whole and in all three of those places.
Rym: Basically, the government sucks and can't actually fund these things.
Scott: I don't think we actually said with what happened is that the train was coming into the station in Hoboken and it went into the Station.
Scott: it didn't stop and it kept going into the station and but it was the end of the track.
Scott: So it went and it smashed the building and smashed the people.
Rym: it bumped it Crashed through the thing that we both forgot the name of and I forget the name of it again.
Rym: So I'm gonna Google right now buffer.
Scott: Stop buffer.
Rym: Stop.
Rym: Yes thing that stops Train at the end of the track, so it had to be going pretty fast.
Scott: But actually I have a second hand account.
Scott: So one of a person who plays netrunner has a co-worker who was on this train not on some next to it train.
Scott: Yeah Coming into that station on that very train and the story was That the train didn't actually seem to be going that fast.
Scott: It just didn't stop.
Rym: Well, that's the thing It's like.
Rym: well, there's so much momentum there.
Scott: a train that's going train is now a train is big first of all But also those MV also, you know If you're a person who's used to cars and trains and not biking and walking.
Scott: You don't realize like 20 miles an hour feels slow.
Scott: 30 miles an hour feels slow, right?
Scott: So the train could have been going like I. even 40 feels slow to people when you drive cars a lot.
Scott: In fact, the only reason you might actually train was going like 70 and then slowed down to 40.
Scott: You know, it feels slow even though it's coming into the station Like the only reason you might notice cuz one is commute.
Rym: So everyone's asleep or you know doing their thing.
Rym: So Maybe you might look out the window and be like Are we getting close to the station and it's still going like it hasn't like slowed down yet, right?
Scott: So So yeah, so that we don't know how fast the train was going But you know, it's probably faster than it should have been.
Scott: obviously The train obviously didn't stop.
Scott: We don't know why yet at least hasn't been reported yet.
Scott: Maybe someone knows why.
Scott: I'm sure the engineer knows why.
Rym: no well, so he was apparently injured and unconscious and they pulled him out of the train.
Rym: I'm sure people on Park at least were saying that he was bolt at the front of the train in the back of the train and then People are talking about how there's a shift change.
Rym: We're like they moved to the front of the train.
Scott: You don't move to the front of the train while the trains coming to the station or like someone else takes over like no one The procedures of this train.
Scott: the trainer does.
Scott: where's that guy with the hat?
Rym: that guy probably posted on a fork later.
Scott: Anyway, so Like this just nobody down the ceiling right?
Scott: Nobody pulled the emergency brake on the train.
Scott: This is the one time you're supposed to pull it.
Rym: Yeah Usually people pull it because like someone's having a heart attack and they're dumb and don't know what.
Scott: I think if you're on a train There's an emergency brake.
Scott: that's always like big red and obvious And depending on the train and where you are in the world it works differently.
Scott: but don't worry about that.
Scott: all you need to worry about is when should you pull that thing?
Rym: and the answer is If you don't know never.
Scott: yeah The answer is almost never right.
Scott: if someone is like on the train with a gun shooting people Do not pull that.
Scott: that is not going to help you.
Rym: In fact that will leave you alone with the gunman.
Scott: now now the train is stopped and the train cannot move again for a Significant period of time until like a pneumatic thing is reset.
Scott: so fun as a crazy person with a gun there.
Scott: Almost any emergency.
Scott: you do not want to pull that.
Scott: you want the train to keep moving so it can get to a station so that you Can run to safety and emergency people can get on the train.
Rym: Did you watch that whole elevator lecture?
Rym: I used this thing a day a long time ago.
Rym: No, because there's a whole section where elevators shitty and old elevators have an emergency stop button, right?
Rym: Modern elevators don't because that button is only used for ill.
Rym: it is primarily used to Beat someone up in an elevator.
Rym: Yes You know why that button was there.
Rym: Because when elevators were stirred first being introduced mass market in the u.s.
Scott: Like modern elevators and modern buildings or they mostly manually controlled them.
Rym: Oh, no, no, like this is when like modern elevators, okay People were dumb and legit afraid of elevators that button was there.
Rym: So they would see the emergency stop button and feel like they could do something if the elevator fucked up Mm-hmm.
Rym: and no one real no one thought except elevator engineers About the use case where you basically don't like.
Rym: there's no reason to have a button like that.
Rym: that button can only harm and never Help.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Anyway, the elevators falling that buttons not gonna stop here here the there are probably more instances But these are the only reasons that I know of that.
Scott: you should absolutely pull that emergency brake on the train.
Scott: number one Someone's like caught in the door or being dragged by the train or between the cars or the trait you see with your eyes.
Scott: The train is about to kill someone if it continues to move.
Rym: It's a trolley problem.
Scott: And therefore if you pull the lever you will say like if someone's arm is caught in the subway door and it starts fucking moving.
Scott: Yeah over like for real and the conductor doesn't notice.
Scott: Yeah, then you run and pull it as fast as you can.
Scott: Otherwise the person will die.
Rym: number two, you're in the front car and you are barreling toward an obstacle.
Scott: Yeah you can tell the train is not stopping when it should be stopping like such as the thing that happened today.
Scott: or three if Somehow like it's an old-fashioned old western movie and the train is detached and it's sort of rolling away on its own That's when you.
Scott: that's what that's for.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So other than that, you should push the emergency intercom button and not the emergency brake.
Scott: Leo I blame also trained designers for making the emergency brake very very prominent and making the emergency intercom Not as prom pretty sure that's a regulatory holdover from far ancient times much like the elevator thing is anyway.
Scott: So the second thing right is you know, yeah, this is this is not good.
Scott: They got to fix them train.
Rym: one person was killed No one on the train.
Rym: the person who was killed was a woman who was standing just in the station.
Scott: I think this is the most dangerous place to be.
Scott: you got hit by a train.
Scott: Yeah Basically as bad as standing on the tracks.
Scott: only you weren't standing on the tracks.
Rym: Yeah, you know your bagel What am I?
Rym: co-workers was like man?
Rym: This is tragic view.
Rym: The worst part about it is Died on the commute.
Rym: No one should ever die on their come.
Scott: Yeah, this is clearly tragic.
Scott: yet I just want to point out the thing that I point out often which is they're so upset over this.
Scott: But meanwhile more people than one person died in cars today and more attention was given to this than to all those people who died.
Rym: statistically About point seven people die per day in New York City as a result of cars.
Rym: So it's possible.
Rym: No one died today in New York City.
Scott: only right that's per day.
Scott: So if we wait like a week more, yeah, we wait two days.
Scott: no two days, it'll be worse than this.
Rym: Well, it's like the terror thing.
Rym: if this happened every day for the next year It's still.
Rym: actually if it happened every day for the next year It would be on par with.
Rym: it'd be similar to the damage caused by cars.
Rym: Yeah I guess the different people are not.
Scott: people are now because of you know Reporting not being realistic people.
Rym: I've not seen anyone who was like we need to do something crazy About this.
Scott: no New Yorkers aren't gonna be but people elsewhere.
Scott: Right who get these?
Scott: people who don't live in New York are the ones who are afraid of things, right?
Scott: So now all these non New Yorkers gonna be afraid of trains?
Scott: I know they still get in their cars without fear every day.
Rym: I encountered two separate individuals Just because I was outside a lot.
Rym: cuz weird.
Rym: So we were doing headshots again in the office today.
Rym: So I was like outside doing a photo shoot.
Rym: I was outside like walking around a lot.
Rym: I encountered two separate people both of whom happened to be older white gentlemen And both of whom heard that this might have been intentional and that they arrested the conductor.
Rym: So that's the level of discourse that's out there.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, it's not a good level.
Rym: Yeah, I don't.
Scott: but the point is is they should be reporting on the news.
Scott: Holy shit cars are killing people all over the place.
Scott: Yeah, right Trains killed three one person this year.
Rym: the narrative of a car killing someone is yeah bad driver Yeah, and also there is an infrastructure thing.
Rym: So let's take a cold analytical point ignoring the human toll because obviously cars have a much higher human toll.
Rym: Look at damage to infrastructure and the GDP and all that sort of stuff.
Scott: every car accident delays everyone commuting on that road for like an hour or two which adds up when you add up all those the time for All those people.
Rym: this might have taken Hoboken terminal out of admission for like a month.
Scott: Yeah, that's bad.
Rym: Like it took the roof down like they This thing might not come up.
Scott: gotta raise the roof literally.
Rym: so the moral is Don't live in New Jersey live in New York.
Rym: If you're gonna commute to New York Jesus.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: That's the real moral like the commute on path.
Rym: So, you know transit is just kind of sad.
Scott: Uh, I mean I've never done this.
Scott: I've always when I wait for a train I wait next to it.
Scott: But well in New York, so already like I mean, I've never I've never waited for a train in front of it But I'm now consciously not going to.
Rym: well the thing is here even if you're not directly.
Rym: Here's the nice diagram if a trains a train Scott go into the waiting room and you know where else this is true Boston When I take the Amtrak, that's true.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, like think those trains like the Acela train comes straight in like say the Acela didn't stop at South Station.
Rym: Yeah, it'll barrel right into like that mac and cheese place that we always eat ahead.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: So it's not any better.
Rym: but yeah, the other moral is Moral.
Rym: just don't live in New Jersey, but like in New York, it's the biggest news today.
Scott: So whatever Yeah,
Rym: and it impacted me a little bit because one of my co-workers sent an email that was like yeah gonna be late
Scott: Yep
Rym: so the other news that's moderately important that you should really pay attention to is that uh, I know like you I Doubt you listen to GeekNights and think vaccines are fake.
Rym: I feel like we've weeded those people out a long time ago But I suspect there's at least some of you is actually a great story today.
Scott: some Some lady who didn't give her kids any vaccines and then her kids all got rotavirus and the whole family was like shitting up The storm for like three weeks.
Scott: and then she changed her mind.
Scott: was the headline?
Rym: local woman encounters Facts.
Scott: Yeah And then her best friend was still anti-vaxx.
Scott: So she lost her best friend, but she's okay with that.
Rym: That would be okay with that too, right?
Rym: But a lot of people don't get the flu shot and usually everyone cites that Lewis black comedy routine about how it gives you the Flu which is not true, which is funny.
Rym: Yeah, but guys get your flu shots.
Rym: And one because I don't want you.
Scott: the thing is comparing the flu to packs.
Scott: Yeah, the other thing is that flu the flu shot in particular is actually every year.
Scott: They basically guess which flu.
Scott: It's a very educated guess.
Scott: It's not a random guess right?
Scott: which flus?
Scott: because there's bunches of different flus.
Scott: All of it was only one flu.
Scott: like we'd be set already it would be gone like measles Yeah, but there's so many flus.
Scott: So they've picked.
Scott: they say ah these flus look hot this year.
Scott: Let's put these X number of flus in the flu shot, but you could still get another flu.
Scott: They've also some years been wrong and some flu got really hot.
Scott: that wasn't in the vaccine and they had to change it up But it's probably too late.
Scott: Yeah, so, you know based on the year Alright, you know the flu shot has different stuff in it, which is why you need to get it every year So you don't get the flu.
Rym: also it does.
Rym: I saw another thing people get it way early like people are like real into the flu shot and then it wears off by the Season really starts and then they get the flu.
Scott: See that's the thing.
Scott: I don't understand right like I had MMR a long time ago.
Scott: I was way small But I never had to get a. I did get it like once again ever when I was also very little and then never again.
Scott: It's like tetanus shot lasts a really long time.
Scott: How does a flu shot only last like a season?
Scott: Well, there's.
Rym: so I have rudimentary knowledge of the answer to that question.
Rym: however If I actually open my mouth I can think of at least two people who listen to the show who are gonna Basically, right.
Scott: Also, it's like, you know, you get that, you know, you get chicken pox once and then you never get it again.
Rym: Well ever you might get shingles or something later.
Scott: Yes, but you never get chicken pox again ever.
Scott: It just lasts for your entire fucking life.
Rym: But there's so part of that work so well.
Rym: part of it is that you know different diseases are different obviously But also that the immunity how are they?
Rym: how many receptors can you have like?
Rym: Imagine if you wanted to have be vaccinated against every virus in the known world.
Rym: Okay, I don't think your immune system has enough receptor.
Rym: like you couldn't keep enough receptors in your blood.
Scott: You don't have enough.
Scott: you have enough disk space to hold all the members like theoretically There's not enough DNA's to make all the different.
Rym: like theoretically there's a limit.
Rym: Well, not theoretically There's definitely a limit.
Rym: and how much you can know like there's a physical brains of physical size There's only so much information.
Rym: It can actually hold in itself.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean, you know, how many viruses are there?
Scott: right?
Scott: lot?
Rym: Yeah, how many a lot and I'm gonna guess billions.
Scott: All right, how many cells are in my body?
Rym: what you did?
Rym: Yes, so you've got one cell.
Scott: Each cell can remember one virus and I think when the time Cell can multiply fight the virus and then reduce itself back to one cell it.
Rym: I don't think it multiplies I'm not.
Scott: no that's not how it works.
Scott: I'm saying that's how it could work if someone was making the system by hand not how it does work.
Scott: Yes, we could decide how it does work as every cell has the same shit.
Rym: It's all We could design cracker humans who are engineered to not get sick with a special immune system.
Scott: Yes, that's what I'm saying.
Scott: But anyway, get your fucking flu shots.
Rym: You don't bring the flu to packs because I got a flu from a packs Not that long ago and to the CDC is actually up their ante and is more strongly recommending.
Scott: Yeah, they used to say like old people and little kids should get it.
Scott: Otherwise you'll die.
Scott: now They're like yo everybody everyone you are a breathing human being get this flu shot.
Rym: The reason is less people are getting the flu vaccine.
Rym: So one fuck them.
Rym: At least if you get the vaccine You're more likely to be okay mandatory.
Scott: We just exile anyone who doesn't.
Rym: yeah Unless you have a metal.
Scott: so it should be free and the government pays for it.
Rym: Yeah, well, I think we need single-payer universal health.
Scott: You can't make it mandatory if right if it's not if they're not paying for it.
Scott: car insurance.
Rym: But yeah, seriously guys get your flu shot.
Rym: I'm gonna get mine probably this week or next week or real soon free ones in my work everybody.
Rym: Yeah You don't work there and my old company.
Rym: They brought a nurse in and gave everyone flu shots.
Scott: Yeah, that's what we're doing.
Rym: If you were on to my work does if you're on the ops team, you could not opt out Unless you had a doctor's note saying why you couldn't get it or proving that you already got it.
Rym: But that only applied to mission critical staff.
Rym: Mmm now side note mission critical staff and that company.
Rym: We also had bug out bags that had One hour respirators.
Rym: we had ropes and we're telling stuff to get out of the building through the window.
Rym: We had like all this like whistles and emergency bullshit, but only mission critical employees got that.
Rym: everyone else didn't okay, so like the ops team and Like certain traders and the like the board like those people all got him but like all the salespeople in middle the office didn't get shit.
Rym: but anyway things of the day.
Rym: so as you all know I'm a big fan of Neil Cicierega's mouth silence and mouth sounds and his area like basically all his like mash stuff up Really heavily style of thing.
Scott: Yeah, see normal people like King Midas because he touches things turns into gold but Rym likes.
Scott: You know King Neil who touches everything and turns it into something.
Scott: Rym likes.
Rym: Yep He's one of my favorite creators.
Scott: internet garbage.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Just like skeletons dancing around.
Rym: Yeah, I could go to each e but I found this other person Grant Willard and his channel is great.
Rym: But I'm gonna link to two videos that he did because these are very Neil Cicierega and style mass up mash ups.
Rym: but what he does?
Rym: so this first one is Literally, he took jingles to a bunch of commercials.
Rym: Mm-hmm Like all you know commercial jingles like Kit Kats and McDonald's or whatever.
Rym: He played the jingles on a piano using the products they sell To hit the keys.
Rym: Okay, and then he made this whole song that mashes them all up together musically to be a complete song.
Rym: No, and it's just really good and really well done kind of like mouth sounds.
Rym: Okay, this other one is more like mouth silence.
Rym: It's just called it classical music mashup.
Rym: He mashed up.
Rym: He made a song that is just the tunes from 57 famous classical songs from among 33 composers and he has this great.
Rym: I can't even name 33 composers like Dvorak Gershwin.
Scott: yeah, I can.
Scott: I can name a lot but I can't name 33. since then I don't know who that is Really?
Scott: No, but says ends song of fame a bunch of concertos and things like.
Rym: can you march of the animals?
Scott: I don't know March of the Animals.
Scott: Okay, sing it for me Metal a sin.
Scott: so you don't know Song again, you don't want me to sing.
Rym: it's playing right now.
Rym: Bunch of this stuff is playing right now.
Rym: Here are Bach all the different box.
Scott: Yeah, I know who they are.
Rym: Do you know which ones which?
Rym: no I don't even know the difference between all the different box.
Rym: I always forget this was your pond and here's some W See it, but the crazy thing is this works as music and is really good and It's like mouth silence in that regard.
Rym: So this guy's channel is amazing and these mashups are amazing.
Rym: It's what he got.
Scott: So I've heard of people having all sorts of crazy pets in this world, right?
Scott: You know just about any animal has been made a pet by someone.
Scott: there's someone out there with like, you know pet wolf pet tiger pet octopus pet shark.
Scott: There's very few animals that have not been turned into the pet of a human right probably like whale Sometimes ill-advisedly and usually only like.
Scott: even somewhere like is you know is Shamu a pet?
Scott: it's SeaWorld and maybe right I don't know slave maybe but I guess no one's ever had like a blue whale as a pet.
Scott: because like What are you gonna do?
Scott: Right?
Scott: Anyway, but here is a pet.
Scott: that's a pretty common animal that you see a lot at least You know, I see them all the time But I've never heard of anyone having one as a pet.
Scott: and it's a crab.
Scott: This guy's a pet crab.
Rym: Oh, I know what videos you're talking about.
Scott: He's got pet crab.
Scott: It's just like oh, it's a crab.
Scott: That's nice.
Scott: That's not a bad pet to have it's probably you know It can't be that hard to take care of.
Rym: is this the guy who is like?
Rym: look how politely he's eating this banana Exactly.
Scott: So he you know, it's like.
Scott: what do you feed your pet crab?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I guess you feed it the same fishy stuff it eats when it's in the ocean.
Scott: But I guess it eats banana.
Scott: cuz I mean really what animal that has a mouth doesn't eat banana?
Scott: Yeah, I mean tell you you don't give everything from an ant to the monkey will eat a banana.
Rym: rabbits Don't commonly encounter bananas in the wild.
Rym: Let me tell you they like bananas, right?
Scott: Like an ant will eat a banana a bunny will eat a banana.
Scott: Dogs leave banana dog lead a banana But depending on your dog, it might not be good at getting in how you present the banana to the cat.
Scott: It might freak out like they do with cucumbers Yeah, but it's like there's a ton of animals that will all like.
Scott: banana is like the closest thing you're gonna get to food that animals can eat right Almost regardless.
Scott: like if you got a brand new animal you've never seen before and you're like I wonder what it eats.
Scott: You can be pretty safe trying banana first.
Rym: That's maybe instead of sending the golden record out into space for aliens.
Scott: It should be a banana, but then it would turn brown.
Rym: It'll be in space.
Rym: It'll be preserved.
Scott: Whoa To protect him from From the disease and from oxidizing?
Rym: send one satellite up and then banana.
Scott: then they'll be a ride.
Scott: Then they'll be a real Russian space travel cuz it's like well if you want to eat bananas, you gotta go to space.
Scott: That's all the bananas.
Rym: We put the good the Cavendish in space.
Rym: It gets wiped out on earth and then all of humanity unites itself to go back into space and get those bananas back We'll have to grow them on Europa.
Rym: So did you see those those geysers like?
Scott: there's why they know listen don't go there, dude Structures are pretty simple.
Rym: Yeah, you know what if I'm pretty clear, it wasn't vague like maybe you shouldn't go there Scott I'm gonna translate those instructions do not go Settle all these worlds except Europa.
Rym: There's something really fucking interesting here.
Rym: Come here first Don't.
Scott: you can go in any of the doors in this dungeon except the secret door.
Rym: go though in that one secret door off-limits Because there's great stuff in there guys.
Scott: Yeah You know if I make a game the secret door just has instant death and there's no way around it.
Scott: I'll teach you not to listen.
Scott: Anyway, it crashes the game.
Scott: Sure So anyway, this guy's a pet crab.
Scott: he feeds it a banana.
Scott: and let me tell you something.
Scott: I like having my dextrous fingers my digits, but Makes you really want to have a scissor built into your hand.
Scott: It's really useful to have a scissor hand.
Scott: if you're a crab there's a.
Rym: there's a movie about the scissor hands.
Scott: Yeah, no, but this crab you want like scissor finger the crab a crab claw is way more useful than whatever Edward scissor hands had Right that monstrosity.
Rym: So whatever we know exactly what he had.
Scott: he had scissors Yeah, her hands, but they weren't like nice clean scissors.
Scott: It was like a big mess of scissors and shit.
Scott: Yeah, I'd rather have The crab claw.
Rym: I wonder if that movie holds up.
Rym: I have not seen it since I was a little kid.
Scott: You know, I've also not seen it since I was a little kid and you know what?
Scott: I don't even know what the plot is.
Scott: isn't the plot just as a scary guy with scissor hands?
Scott: Actually nice who knows where he came from?
Scott: he lives in a weird house and Cuts the shrubs nice.
Rym: Well, you know where he came from.
Rym: you get his whole back story.
Scott: I forget I forget it.
Rym: crater falls over dead when he was about to give him his new hands.
Scott: Okay, I forget that part.
Rym: It's really about suburbia.
Scott: Yeah, I know that.
Scott: Yeah, and then this girl comes and meets him.
Rym: It's Frankenstein with scissor hands.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah anyway, yeah We should watch it again.
Rym: Me I remember really liking it.
Rym: I mean Social media.
Rym: I did not look into this but apparently Tim Burton said something really racist and everyone's done with him.
Scott: now really That's that's news to me.
Rym: I saw something about that.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: What did he say Tim Burton?
Scott: Was it something that was actually racist or was it something that just you know?
Scott: People think is racist was not?
Rym: Tim Burton says something monumentally stupid about miss Peregrine's lack of diversity.
Scott: He's basically like saying nowadays, this is Tim Burton.
Rym: nowadays people are talking about it more regarding diversity, but Things either call for things or they don't.
Rym: I remember back when I was a child watching the Brady Bunch and they started to get All politically cracked like okay.
Rym: Let's have an Asian child and a black.
Rym: I used to get more offended by that, but I just grew up watching blaxploitation, right and I said, it's great I didn't go like there should be more white people in these movies.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: That's what he said.
Scott: Oh, he's clueless.
Rym: Yeah I think the key word is the wet the fact that he refers to and a black.
Scott: Yeah, yeah How old is he?
Rym: Oldest I guess That's like 54.
Scott: He's too old 55 old people.
Scott: That's how they do.
Scott: Yeah, when you say you got to get rid of all the old people that includes the old people that you know made good Stuff, right?
Rym: What was the last good thing Tim Burton made?
Scott: Another thing Tim Burton made good thing.
Scott: Yeah, I haven't seen his recent stuff like his Willy Wonka and whatever.
Rym: Yeah, I've been avoid.
Rym: I actually been avoiding a lot of his new stuff because they don't think I would enjoy them.
Scott: I mean, they're like Nightmare Before Christmas.
Rym: Yeah, that was a long time.
Rym: I remember.
Scott: But also Mars Attacks is like the worst thing ever.
Rym: when we were at RIT I was at a mall with some people just randomly and someone pointed out that the Nightmare Before Christmas was 10 years old.
Scott: then Yeah, I think it's like 20 years old It's really old.
Rym: So I guess in the moment the book club book is Rebecca I'm gonna read it real soon because well, I guess I'll wait until Scott posted on the website then I'll start reading it.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: Yeah, it looks like it's pretty short.
Rym: It's way shorter than that Nazi book.
Scott: I don't know how long it is cuz I have it on a kid.
Rym: So I'd look the number of dots it showed next to it in my Kindle compared to the man doesn't have dots.
Scott: It has a bar.
Rym: Wow You just have like an old Kindle OS sir.
Scott: I'm just using a really old Kindle cuz why replace it?
Rym: I only replaced my old one because the paper white mine doesn't even have a blacklight backlight.
Rym: Ah The backlight is key.
Scott: Yeah black lights nice, but I'm not gonna buy a new Kindle.
Scott: Just get a backlight.
Scott: I can use my iPad if I want that.
Rym: Yeah Well, the new new Kindle is also way better.
Scott: I guess what I mean, it's not better than an iPad.
Rym: Yeah Well, I would say it is.
Rym: I prefer reading text on a Kindle with the paper white to any tablet.
Rym: Sure, but only if it's like book text.
Scott: But if I need a light, I'm not gonna buy a separate thing when I have.
Scott: you know It's just.
Rym: it makes the reading more pleasant.
Rym: Even if you're in good light.
Scott: Let me tell you retina screen fonts look pretty good.
Rym: No but otherwise, I guess the patreon is going.
Rym: the only thing I'll say about the patreon is that I am reading the entirety of FX 9's Castlevania 2 Simon's Quest.
Scott: you should pay to make him not do that.
Rym: I've read two chapters so far.
Rym: the insights they are from chapter 1. are that Tim?
Rym: I think wants to have sex with his mom and that he is also sexually aroused by chocolate?
Rym: chapter 2 I don't even know what to say about these books.
Rym: like reading him as an adult.
Rym: I just don't know what to say.
Scott: I can give you plenty of more books from my childhood Some good and some Castlevania, but that is one of the things I'm gonna start doing in the world.
Rym: I am doing in the patreon is I'm just gonna read old possibly bad books to you.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I will read good books for free.
Rym: then to counter you I guess page I mean a copyright is dubious there.
Rym: I guess I'm giving my take on it.
Rym: Also.
Scott: I'm good books from project Gutenberg.
Rym: Yeah, that's the way to go.
Rym: Why don't we do it?
Rym: Do it?
Rym: Why don't we both pick?
Rym: open and open Creative Commons or Public domain book and just read them?
Rym: start doing audiobooks.
Scott: cuz I don't got time for that.
Scott: I'm doing too much other shit your short stuff.
Scott: What's short Rebecca?
Scott: It's not public domain.
Rym: No, but it's short.
Rym: I can't imagine we'd be sued if we read to Rebecca out loud.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: Yeah So road trips something I don't do anymore.
Rym: Yeah, like they used to be a bigger part of my life and I already realized thinking about the show I'm pretty.
Scott: have we done this before?
Scott: I feel like we've discussed it.
Rym: So I did some cursory searching and couldn't find anything.
Scott: I feel like we've discussed and I feel like discussed.
Scott: every anecdote we're gonna use has been reused.
Rym: So what is the definition of a road trip?
Rym: Cuz I already realized that I can come up with like four tiers of what might be considered a road trip And I feel like the definition at this point has to be something Either the trip itself has to be a looked forward to component of the greater trip like You like you're doing it as a road trip on purpose and you're looking forward to the travel and the destination not just the destination or It has to be more than one day on the road Like you got to stop at a motel somewhere or it doesn't count.
Rym: Mmm Do you have an alternate definition for me or do you think that can?
Scott: well I think there's some people that would argue Right, like for example, we drove to Florida That's my biggest road trip maybe once or twice, right?
Scott: So, you know, it's like it's a trip.
Scott: It's on the road and it takes a while with the stop at least one night if not two.
Scott: so it's a. you know, it counts as a road trip, but You know, I think some people would argue like that's not a real road trip.
Scott: Right, like a real road trip is like you're not driving to somewhere You're just driving like, you know Kerouac on the road and whatnot.
Rym: Yeah, but even then when people say road trip, it's usually in the context of we have a destination.
Rym: That's just an excuse and really we're looking forward to being on the road.
Scott: People driving, you know on a trip for the sake of the traveling driving part versus the destination part.
Scott: We just happen to be using a car and it happens to take a while.
Scott: Yep, but I also kind of lump into this, you know, they're actually never done the road trip just for the sake of driving.
Scott: It's always been to go somewhere.
Rym: So the times I did that I The destination was.
Rym: I ended up back home Like me and a couple of friends were just like one day.
Rym: we were like, let's just drive north until we get bored Not on the highway.
Rym: We just got on like Shainer and drove because in Michigan, you know, there's mile roads Like every mile away from Detroit.
Rym: It's like 19 mile 20 mile 21 mile.
Rym: So we just decided cuz you know, this is way before smartphones.
Rym: We didn't really plan.
Rym: We just drove north until we got bored, but it's not like across the country.
Rym: No, we spent like seven or eight hours in the road, but we just drove north We were bored and we turned around and drove back south.
Rym: Hmm One time I drove down to Florida for the fuck of it.
Rym: Did that a lot of times going to beaches?
Rym: But most of the road trips I had were either the family drove all the way to Florida But we stopped along the way at minor attractions that themselves would not be worth a trip But are worth the trip if you're on the way somewhere else.
Scott: Well, I mean there's plenty of like things that have been set up intentionally along high traffic routes such as I-95 from you know northeast down to Florida right or you know anywhere towards.
Scott: you know If you go to like a major Attraction like say a Mount Rushmore or Grand Canyon.
Scott: all the major roads leading in and out of it are like high Traffic for like even didn't eat.
Rym: there's a bunch of garbage on the highway Hundred miles.
Scott: like if you know that there's this attraction that people are going to and it's like they can't people.
Scott: even if people are Visiting it by flying they can't land right next to it.
Scott: They got to go it's like the nearest city and then drive to it because it's a middle-of-nowhere Attraction because the United States is large.
Scott: therefore they have to use a car to get to it and they're gonna likely come down this Road so you put some business on that road that will specifically cater to someone on vacation such as souvenir garbage or something that's a minor attraction like a go-kart track or a water slide or a haunted house or for you know Something mysterious like a Mystery Shack, right?
Scott: Yeah this sort of thing.
Rym: Maybe that's it.
Rym: It's it's you.
Rym: it has to be Multi-destination trip like there are stops on purpose, right?
Scott: Like if you're in a hurry just to get there and like that's all you want to do You're stopping.
Scott: places isn't gonna happen and you're just gonna.
Scott: you know, it's not a road trip.
Scott: You're just going through the place, right?
Scott: It's not a road trip to go to the grocery store Even if you have to stop at the dry cleaners in the way there.
Rym: now what is real interesting?
Rym: those I was thinking about This when I think of the old days when we would drive to conventions from like RIT or Beacon I felt like like.
Rym: those felt like road trips Like I feel like I would have called them road trips, but they weren't that long.
Rym: They're like six seven hours tops depending on where we were going.
Rym: Yeah, sometimes five Yeah but in the modern era like now if I take a road trip in a car somewhere I would never call it a road trip.
Rym: and the only difference between those trips and these trips are that we put a bunch of people in the car usually and We didn't have smartphones and we had to plan the trip very carefully.
Rym: Like we'd bring snacks We'd put shit in the car.
Rym: We'd print maps.
Rym: There was all this like weird extra preparation and Nowadays, literally I just get in the car and go and if we get hungry along the way I literally just look at the smartphone and figure out where to stop.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, the smartphone really destroyed a lot of the things that the road trip was about.
Scott: right It's like you're not.
Scott: you don't have to get off and explore.
Scott: You don't have to like, you know If you have a paper map, it's like you think oh you shouldn't get lost.
Scott: if you're good at reading the paper map Well, let's say you're perfect at it.
Scott: Like I am like you shouldn't ever fuck up.
Scott: But the thing is roads change Yeah, and maps don't.
Scott: like.
Rym: half of us fucking up on all these road trips Like you and me both is literally guys.
Rym: We're fucking running out of gas.
Rym: It's like midnight.
Rym: Where's the gas station?
Scott: Right and the maps don't help you with that.
Scott: like paper maps are flawed in many ways no matter how good or highly skilled You are right.
Scott: So like they in the era before the smartphone and the GPS and whatnot It's like things just get driving for that long a distance inherently had things that would and could go wrong that you would have to deal with.
Rym: which sort of meant road trips if forget the Other definition just naturally adventurous.
Rym: Yeah, no matter what they encompass preparation and Adventure.
Scott: but now now everyone has magic swords.
Scott: So no monsters really gonna stand in your way.
Scott: It's like there's no Adventurousness whatsoever.
Scott: It's like you're getting.
Scott: it's a guaranteed perfect trip Even if my phone stops working.
Rym: everyone else in the car also has a smartphone and you can recharge the phone, you know.
Scott: It's like there's just so many ways you cannot get fucked over.
Rym: and also I don't ever drive on non freeways anymore.
Rym: Nor do I ever try to take short.
Scott: well And this isn't even counting.
Scott: like all the improvements in cars and highways themselves We'll be getting all the money that should have been spent on trains.
Rym: I mean I had road trips like fancy rest stops everywhere now like one time I was gonna visit my mom when she'd moved way out of the desert and Like I didn't do any prep because I've been so used to the smartphone era So there was.
Rym: I was gonna fly to Phoenix Rent a car and drive hours out into the desert to find her house by which I had a vague address That didn't really like work and a vague set of directions and I was driving like a hundred miles.
Rym: But I flew there and land I get in the rental car.
Rym: I opened my smartphone.
Rym: No service like no data service at all.
Rym: I have no maps and I just winged it.
Rym: I just drove out into the desert and I only.
Rym: I probably added about 40 miles to the trip.
Rym: just you know Dead reckoning with a couple of printed maps I found in the car, but our bought at a gas station.
Rym: But I totally made it and it was a like it was an adventure.
Rym: So that turned into a road trip because adventure was injected into it.
Rym: that would have not otherwise occurred.
Scott: Yeah, the other thing is like a lot of thing.
Scott: if you watch or read, you know romanticized road trip kind of stories or movies or whatever.
Scott: There are things that happen in them that No longer happen in the real car breaks down and you have no way to get help.
Scott: that doesn't happen anymore Right, or you know hitchhikers that aren't peep that are people you should actually let in your car.
Scott: Yeah, or you hitchhike Right.
Scott: No, that does not happen.
Rym: I have hitchhiked.
Scott: Pick you up.
Rym: I was picked up By a scary person in Michigan or a normal person normal ish person.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah There's nothing happened in the story.
Scott: I literally just they just took you where you wanted to go.
Rym: I was my bike like I was by.
Rym: I biked just way fucking away from my house And then my bike broke in a way that I could not easily fix.
Rym: and I was a little.
Rym: I was a little kid.
Rym: I was in high school like 17.
Rym: I have I don't have a cell phone on me.
Rym: No, I have no did.
Scott: How big would it be?
Rym: Yeah, I've got like four bucks on me in cash.
Rym: I'm 40 or 50 miles away from home.
Rym: What am I gonna do?
Rym: It's Michigan at night.
Rym: Like there's no mass transit.
Rym: So I'm just walking down the road Kind of like waving in any car that goes by and eventually a car slowed down and it was some high school kids.
Rym: I didn't know them but they were high school kids and they were like, what's up?
Rym: And I told him the story and they were like we're heading that way We'll drop you off and they drove me like 30 of the miles I needed to get.
Rym: hmm And that was it though.
Scott: I hitchhiked totally fine, you know, I don't want to retread the same material But I was just thinking more about like, you know things that were like we did every time we drove a long distance.
Scott: Yeah And I realized the smartphone has done a lot more to ruin the road trip than just provide really good maps.
Scott: that yeah in real time.
Scott: So for example, right we used to have to stop to use a payphone and call someone or like a long trip in school and like on a coach bus that stopped somewhere everyone to Get off and use the payphones to call their family or whatever
Rym: or like, you know If you have multiple cars on the road trip Like you'd have to coordinate all the stops and then like share information about the next leg of the trip,
Scott: right?
Scott: So, you know, so another thing we used to always stop and there's certain things that we would get to entertain ourselves in the car.
Rym: Yeah, I used to make mix CDs on purpose like we'd make like here's the music we were bringing on this trip.
Scott: But we need entertainment, but we would also.
Scott: for example Tiger LCD games and portable video games are hot.
Rym: Yeah, but when we got a game my brother had a game boy.
Rym: I had a game gear.
Scott: there were these.
Scott: I haven't seen one of these in a while But they're.
Scott: they might still make them.
Scott: these books called yes and no and you have a magic pen that has like invisible review.
Scott: I remember those revealing ink and you could play different games in this book by drawing with the magic.
Rym: We had a box full of hundreds of those little plastic not even video games.
Rym: that had steel ball bearings in them and various feats Of skill.
Scott: Yeah, those are good.
Rym: Yeah, we had like this giant box of them that we'd bring on road trips.
Scott: You know, you could play games like looking outside the car window like how many blue cars you see or whatever I mean.
Rym: nowadays we're like someone's in the back of the car.
Rym: Just like watching a movie on their phone.
Rym: I'm just like listening to music right there be we have.
Scott: we had little board games that were portable He had like magnets.
Scott: We had battleship that was like in two little plastic things and you would just unfold your little battleship in front of you and hide It.
Scott: it was like a little plastic thing.
Scott: It just unfolded into an L shape and the other person had one too.
Scott: You play battleship for reals just as good as the full board game.
Rym: We also like snacks - like we would very specifically like fill the car with snacks and beverages and stuff.
Rym: And now because like we couldn't know where we might be able to stop along the way now one There's rest stops because I don't go places where there aren't rest stops really and - I can just look at my phone and be Like, okay, there's a town up ahead.
Rym: We don't like.
Scott: the only thing that's the same as it ever was that you got to stop To pee and poo.
Rym: Oh, so when I used to drive long distances by myself One of my main goals was to minimize my time on the road by never stopping if at all possible.
Rym: Mmm, so I would always make that drive from Rochester to Detroit Never stopping if I could get away with it.
Rym: and at one point I thought you know What the only thing that makes me stop on this trip is.
Rym: I got a pee at some point So I tried to pee in a jug while driving.
Scott: you get pee all over.
Scott: now You know what?
Rym: I learned my don't piss your pants because you're dreaming.
Rym: instinct is so powerful You couldn't pee.
Rym: I cannot pee if I'm not in front of a toilet Hmm, or if I'm not like in front of a tree or something like in a car.
Rym: My brain was like you might be dreaming you just nope I haven't said.
Scott: I have something similar right if I walk into a bathroom Even if I just peed recently like you gotta pay and I was just going to wash my hands Pavlok's pee.
Scott: Yep Pavlok's pee.
Scott: it make my Wants to come out even if there's like a drop, but if I didn't go in that bathroom, that wouldn't happen.
Rym: But also, you know The point of injection was say you're traveling and something weird happens like we need to find a bathroom and there's no rest stops.
Rym: You've got to go off of the path from the triple-a triptychs that you brought with you a trip.
Rym: take Yeah, you've got to go off the path into dragon land Accomplish your mission and then return to the fabled highway.
Rym: That was always the source of adventure.
Rym: now that literally never happens ever Nope, and if it does smartphone just tells you exactly how to get back to the freeway.
Rym: Do you have any times I got stuck on a service road and?
Rym: Literally could not figure out how to get back on a highway like in the old days.
Scott: I also think that like because less people are road tripping and more people are smartphoning Right is like even if you tried to road trip because less people are doing it.
Scott: the places that appeal to the road trip person right those attractions and things have decreased in quantity.
Scott: Right as less people drive more people fly more people smartphone get where they're going.
Scott: You know people are taking a certain route because the smartphone says it's better and your attraction is on a different route that people used to take.
Scott: and now you're out of business.
Rym: a proper like full-on road trip with the rule of like staying in a Motel when you're too tired to keep driving like that kind of nonsense.
Rym: Those were always with family over the course of like a week or two.
Scott: Well, the real strategy is one person sleeps or one person drives.
Scott: Do you swaps you never to stop driving?
Rym: We did that drive into a Jeep Jamboree in Virginia.
Rym: We went non-stop all the way there.
Rym: two drivers going in shifts.
Rym: Yeah, it was real good time.
Scott: three drivers even better cuz.
Rym: yeah, you know, I remember going to anime central in Chicago.
Rym: That was a fucking disaster.
Rym: That was such a long drive and the car broke down along the way and those back when I was poor.
Rym: So I could not afford to pay the mechanic to fix it.
Rym: So I wrote him a check and then I withdrew enough money from my bank account to make sure the rent check would bounce.
Rym: So the check to the mechanic wouldn't bounce.
Rym: That was that was an adventure that couldn't happen nowadays.
Scott: But I didn't.
Rym: you bounce the mechanic and not the rent Because I felt bad for the mechanic as he was doing real work and the rent was to RIT.
Rym: You could bounce rent like four times to RIT before they really started yelling at you because they're like, whatever We'll just add it to your student loan debt.
Rym: Sure So that yeah, but like all those mini adventures The only other thing that can still inject adventure today is not having money Because the only other reason you do a big road trip unless you're going with your family like for us to save monies.
Scott: Yeah Cuz if you already own a car because you live in the suburbs and you have to own it Yeah, the cost of the car is basically zero.
Scott: It's only the cost of the gas and any place you sleep Alright.
Rym: and guys who tell like motels on a highway so cheap not expense, right?
Scott: So, you know the cost of driving to Florida say or even to California is so much less than the cost of flying there Even though flights are if your time means nothing and you already own a car, right?
Scott: If you have more time you the car effectively cost nothing because you have it already.
Scott: Then road trip save you a ton of money.
Rym: But also now gas got cheap which means driving is cheap, but it also means flying is cheap.
Scott: It might be slightly less cheap in the future.
Rym: It's 1,500 bucks for me to fly a round trip to Sydney.
Scott: I mean, I mean, I mean I mean gas might be slightly less cheap in the near future.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but it's even still.
Rym: it's pretty historically low right now.
Scott: Yes, but I'm saying it's around soon.
Rym: The only like.
Rym: basically my rule is I would never drive somewhere that is not within like six hour.
Rym: drive tops beyond that flying.
Rym: Why would you ever drive that far?
Scott: Yeah driving to Florida from New York takes like a day plus you can fly.
Scott: Flying there takes like 90 minutes and even if you count the time with dealing with the TSA or whatever, it's like that doesn't even matter.
Scott: Oh, no, now it takes three hours big deal.
Scott: Yeah, it's so fast Like I'll 500 miles an hour versus 60.
Scott: It's like it's not even close like when I lived in Rochester.
Rym: The only reason I did all those road trips driving to Michigan was because I didn't have any money.
Rym: I had any money I would have flown every time.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I flew back to New York from Rochester Like a 45-minute flight and it cost like $75.
Rym: that flight is like they are cheese like they say alright, you can take off your seatbelts.
Rym: two minutes later They're like, alright, we're making our descent.
Rym: It's like the aerobics playing.
Scott: pretty much It's great.
Rym: Yeah, so I think just Money and modernity killed the road trip.
Scott: I think the road trip will have a slight comeback with the self-driving car.
Scott: Yeah, dude, because now everyone's got the self-driving car can enjoy themselves.
Scott: You don't need to have someone driving.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: No, here's the.
Rym: here's the magic Scott the self-driving RV.
Rym: That shit is lit.
Scott: I just lit a live in that shit.
Scott: That's you mean my house.
Rym: That is my mom's plan Actually to like fully retire.
Rym: She's gonna sell the house and everything and just go where the pool goes.
Rym: But think about this self-driving.
Rym: self-driving RV means adventure awaits and You hang out.
Scott: you live your life you cut, you know, and then it's like oh I feel like doing something.
Scott: you're like RV.
Scott: Where are we?
Scott: Oh, we're in a cool place.
Rym: Yeah Dude self-driving car.
Rym: right the RV drives you to PAX Drops you off at PAX every day picks you up at night when PAX is done and parked somewhere You don't even need a hotel.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah Self-driving RVs.
Scott: Oh my god, like it's time to leave PAX and it's like you tell it what restaurant you're at And then when you're done eating it's there.
Rym: Yeah If you want like if you're bored, you know You have a little.
Scott: you have a tiny mini car that's attached to your RV.
Scott: that comes out like spy hunter.
Scott: Yeah It comes to get you and bring you to where the RV is parks.
Scott: those exist So it doesn't need to drive around like the clouded city.
Rym: those exist.
Rym: I have seen them.
Rym: You can bring in your little.
Scott: it's like having a Star Destroyer and a tie fighter.
Scott: Yeah, that's how you do.
Rym: That's a good life.
Rym: Yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Juchette James David white Christian coots construction noises.
Rym: my stage calm.
Rym: Sean Hayworth William Isen rose Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Rochelle, Montana Superboy one ping only.
Rym: Aaron serious Brian Fisher sailor vista There's no Ellen shy fried pork, but that's okay.
Rym: Iggy kid Matthew Smith Don Schleich shartavish and Joshua Joestar.
Rym: Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton run for New Zealand Ryan parent Open-landed rural develop.
Rym: Ryan said Roni Finn Eric silver on the rural juror Chris Minkie Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: See, I tried something a little new.
Rym: I showed my web browser instead of just audition.
Rym: It was surprisingly hard to make that work with OBS for annoying reasons that I'm not gonna get into now But yeah, we're for a while experimenting with streaming most of the GeekNights episodes We do along with the pre-production and all that nonsense just on YouTube.
Rym: So you're not following me on YouTube.
Rym: Maybe you should be.
Rym: You'll see GeekNights early and you'll see all the stuff in between the edit points.
Rym: But anyway now I leave you with something pretty great.
Rym: That is related to my thing of the day.