Rym: So one of the annoyances of New York is that you got to pay rent and most land.
Scott: that's not annoyance of New York.
Scott: There's an annoyance of everywhere.
Scott: Well, it's you have to pay for shelters because at least when I live shelters are not free No matter where you go.
Rym: when I live in like I don't know some dumpy small town or like when I rent it Remember the place that you slept on the floor that one time like when you rent a place like that You have the landlord that you like hand cash or a check to like every month or whatever.
Rym: But at least it feels like that's the level of service you'd expect.
Rym: but in New York even in like super fancy buildings You can't just pay your rent online.
Rym: usually Usually you still have to like mail a check every month and it's just just really like old-school archaic nonsense.
Scott: I pay it online.
Rym: Yeah, so my building announced a few months ago.
Rym: Yeah, we got an online system.
Rym: now Just make an account log in here.
Rym: You get your rent stuff.
Rym: You can set up auto pay.
Rym: You can just pay it.
Rym: You can even put a fucking credit card in if you want.
Scott: We don't care go nuts Mmm, I can't use a credit card.
Scott: I have to use a debit card online.
Rym: Yeah, so, uh, I finally like it was set up and I went to pay the rent You know the first of the month in the website and I was gonna set up auto pay.
Rym: and I set it up and then I noticed that the number is not what I expected.
Rym: and I click in and I see that there is a convenience fee to pay with my credit card.
Scott: I don't have that.
Rym: so I think alright fine.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: I'll use my debit card.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: There's still a convenience fee.
Rym: fine I'll set up my checking account.
Rym: still a convenience fee.
Rym: What do you think that convenience fee was?
Rym: Let's play.
Rym: Let's play obviously a lot.
Scott: It's probably some percentage of your rent.
Scott: So it's probably hundreds of dollars.
Rym: No, it was actually only $45 per rent check.
Scott: That's still fuck you money.
Rym: Yeah So and now because I signed up for the account, they won't give me physical rent things anymore.
Rym: No, so I either have to pay $45 a month extra.
Scott: I'd go to small clean I call him and if they did if they fought with me I'd go to small claims court or on the website.
Rym: I can just print the thing and then mail it to them.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: So I did that but They got a choice email for me.
Rym: That was like WTF.
Rym: I do not accept the terms and conditions of bullshit.
Rym: Send me physical printed things again, because I don't know a printer who owns a printer in 2016 on purpose Unless you have an old one that just happens to still work.
Rym: if that if your black and white printer broke today It's a printer right there.
Scott: I see it does not work.
Scott: How does that not work?
Rym: To stop working.
Scott: I think it'll work.
Rym: Nah, so if you so if you Kind of jiggle it the whole time It'll pull the paper in about seventy five percent of the time and it'll print really light gray Whatever you wanted to print sometimes.
Scott: I think you just put a new toner cartridge in.
Rym: I could but I'm not gonna bother.
Rym: I'm probably just gonna throw the whole printer away.
Scott: Cuz but I got a printer works great.
Rym: If your printer died today, would you buy another one as soon as I need to print something?
Rym: All right, when do you?
Rym: when was the last time you needed to print something?
Scott: carries printed out some Netrunner card pictures and then I made them the same size as netrunner cards and I cut them out.
Scott: Put him in the sleeve in front of a garbage netrunner card because you don't have enough copies.
Scott: proxies You don't have enough copy only have three copies of a car.
Rym: I played a physical card game.
Rym: I would have a printer for the.
Scott: put this one card in every deck you got.
Scott: but you only got three of them and you Need like 12 of them.
Scott: and then there's a whole bunch of other cards that you're never gonna use cuz they're garbage way below the Burrito frontier.
Scott: Yeah, and you just use those as to stiffen up the sleeve there and you put the piece of paper.
Rym: I did that with my color desk jet back in the day with magic cards, right?
Scott: That's what you do.
Rym: And then one of my rich friends wouldn't?
Rym: he refused to play with us if we use proxies because he was like, it's not fair.
Rym: I had to get this card with my parents money.
Rym: He didn't say my parents money But that's how he had the card.
Rym: so you don't get to use the card for free and we all just stopped playing magic with him.
Scott: That sounds right.
Rym: Yeah, fuck him.
Rym: He stopped being friends with us and I didn't really regret it.
Scott: I was in middle school.
Scott: I was too stupid to just make magic cards and play.
Scott: I didn't realize that was such a great idea.
Scott: We could have made all the because they're all these decks I would read about and strategy guys.
Rym: Everyone read about those decks like there was.
Scott: Yeah, I'm like in middle school and I'm just like man.
Scott: I'll never be able to play that deck.
Scott: There's no way I can get all those cards.
Scott: Oh damn.
Scott: Oh, well, yeah And then it's just like if I would have realized that I would have been like, oh shit I can just play we it's not it's only us middle school kids plan.
Scott: No,
Rym: my other friends not only would that they would make their own magic cards like design them but the rule was if you ever wanted to play a game with your don't design magic cards, no aunties were allowed and Everyone at the event had to take the magic card that you designed that you wanted to put in your deck and They had to look at you in the eye and say whether or not it was good or not.
Rym: We pretty much never let anyone's fucking magic card in cuz they're always just opie bullshit.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, we didn't make.
Scott: I mean We probably thought of her on magic cards, but no we made him.
Rym: we made him like real high.
Scott: I definitely weren't gonna let anyone use him in a real game.
Scott: And also the ones we would design would be like You know stupid ones like oh, yeah Golden dragon stupid.
Scott: it was like stopwatch.
Rym: It was like for green mana and like to colorless.
Rym: other player skips their next turn.
Scott: There's already a card that does that in magic.
Scott: It's called time time twister time warp something like that.
Rym: I Barely remember it's.
Scott: you'd basically take two turns in a row Vintage magic the other time twister.
Scott: What does it say?
Rym: No, each player shuffles his or her hand Time warp time warp.
Scott: Yeah, it's definitely.
Scott: it's definitely a blue spell where you skip a turn magic card skip turn.
Scott: What's it called?
Rym: Nothing's coming up.
Scott: There's definitely a card that does this.
Rym: there's a deck that theoretically wins without anyone taking a turn.
Rym: If I search for a magic card skip turn nothing comes up.
Scott: It's a really old card that they don't let you use.
Rym: I feel like someone who'd written a blog that was like, all right There's a. here's a card that is no longer around.
Rym: That's funny.
Rym: I Can't find anything.
Rym: I don't know if this exists.
Scott: There was definitely.
Scott: I'll keep looking.
Rym: I mean I'm not saying you're wrong But I am dubious because I feel like that would have come up in a Google search and I definitely did not remember a card Like that and time twister does something very different from that.
Rym: but anyway Things of the day because it's the GeekNights book club.
Rym: We don't waste your time with you know, anything other than the actual book.
Rym: But I feel like things of the day are important.
Rym: So what do you got for me?
Scott: Oh So I think the internet is slowly but surely More than before Realizing who.
Scott: Casey Green is something we've known for like a long-ass time.
Rym: He's he green is one of those unsung heroes of.
Rym: he made things and you don't realize he made them.
Scott: He made like, you know, he's not Neil Cicierega level, but he's the level under that Yeah, and I think he's actually tight with Neil Cicierega.
Scott: He's He probably is I imagine all the internet people who make all the good and live in one house together.
Scott: Yeah, they're all like in the same party whatever, you know, and that's how they figure shit out.
Rym: Anyway, uh Hanging out with hell orb, right?
Scott: So, you know Casey Green made the dog.
Scott: that's in the room It's on fire and he says this is fun.
Scott: So he made a wet.
Scott: He made a new comic where the dog is like, this is not fine It's on the nib and you can go read that.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's actually real good.
Rym: I was poking it around in some political circles.
Rym: Okay, anyway, well cuz you know part of all that was the Republican Party used it and In there and he was like, I guess you're free to use it But fuck you.
Rym: and then he made a separate one like someone paid to make another version.
Rym: That was literally the Republican Party's elephant sitting in the room being like this is fine.
Scott: Anyway, so the He also has a Kickstarter going on where he's selling plush of that dog Plush, you know, he's got it.
Scott: He has a problem where like there's so many people who take his materials and use them without crediting him Which is one thing but it's like it's.
Scott: it's to another level where people like like dick But especially which he invented like people sell t-shirts with a dick But there's so much dick button merch that is not official dick But merch all his official merch is all into pedoco.
Scott: It's not anywhere.
Rym: can I not talking like some kid at an artist alley made like a silkscreen dick But and sold it at like a convention.
Rym: This is like legit looking website selling dick butts like they own it commercially mass-produced.
Rym: Yep, Casey Green's a good dude, or at least a good creator.
Rym: I don't actually know him in person.
Rym: I assume he's a good dude.
Scott: I met him once at a comic-con.
Rym: I met him a few times.
Scott: I don't see him in funny internet videos.
Rym: I follow him on Twitter.
Rym: Sure But yeah, I should get that plush.
Rym: It's a good deal.
Rym: I think it might be a good Kickstarter's gonna cash in which is great.
Rym: Yeah, I'm always happy.
Scott: Yeah, give someone also if you want a patreon That's someone to patreon.
Rym: Yeah, Neil Cicierega and and Casey Green both deserve your patreon money more than us.
Rym: However, I do put money into uh, Neil Cicierega's.
Rym: I feel like I should up that.
Rym: actually cuz I've been listening to more of his stuff lately.
Rym: So I got a cover.
Rym: I always like it when a band or a person with a particular genre or style Covers a song with a completely different style or from a completely different realm.
Rym: Like I've always enjoyed that like Richard cheese I've always been a fan of dread Zeppelin that kind of stuff.
Scott: So, uh-huh magic the gathering.
Scott: one colorless one blue time Walk.
Scott: take an extra turn after this one.
Scott: Ah There you go, I wasn't walk.
Scott: I was not hallucinating.
Rym: pretty sure it was that.
Rym: I think that was an unlimited.
Scott: It was an old at the point.
Scott: is it's an old ass card that I'm pretty sure was banned.
Rym: I don't think it was in revised.
Rym: It was either banned or it was definitely an unlimited at least because when I do a search right now I see copies of it with a white border.
Rym: The only magic sets from that era that had a white border were Unlimited and revised.
Scott: point is it's an old ass car.
Scott: It looks like an unlimited card that is that was banned or restricted or whatever.
Scott: cuz it was way It was.
Rym: I think it was in alpha and beta man.
Scott: If you had four of these in your deck, right?
Scott: That's just like haha.
Rym: Fuck you black borders.
Rym: Definitely in beta.
Scott: Yeah, it's old ass car to get you know, so there you go.
Rym: I don't think I've ever seen this card in person.
Rym: I remember these creepy freaky skeletons.
Rym: I've seen it in.
Scott: I've seen it in stores for sale.
Scott: Yeah, that's about it.
Scott: A lot of money.
Rym: the last listener who still knows a lot by heart of Imagine the Gathering Is it furious that we're slightly wrong about this card in some way?
Rym: so anyway, that kind of thing that I like this is possibly the best example of that ever and Scott was trying to guess before the show what it was, but no, it's not an all-star cover or anything like that.
Rym: I can tell you.
Rym: I give you a hint.
Rym: It's not a metal song though.
Rym: It is covered by a metal band.
Scott: I'm to say if it's a metal cover.
Scott: The original song is not probably metal or hard rock.
Rym: Well, it's covered specifically by a death metal band.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: It's.
Rym: it's about four and a half minutes long in the song.
Rym: It's a pretty long song.
Scott: That's not that long.
Rym: It's four minutes and 33 seconds specifically.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Okay, because it's John Cage's 433.
Rym: All right, you know John Cage's 433.
Scott: Yeah, that's not that excited.
Rym: I think it's pretty exciting.
Rym: So the way they cover it is they cover it in the proper style of they actually do like the whole setup and the county Like, you know one two three, and then they just sit there Mm-hmm.
Rym: I feel like this is very much in the spirit of what John Cage intended people to do with his very avant-garde music.
Rym: So if you're not familiar with John Cage's 433, I suggest you don't listen to it But you listen to this far superior cover of it.
Rym: So the GeekNights book club delayed because our Scott backers book came out and because I read literally the entire wheel of time.
Scott: Just yeah, mostly that that one most of that part reading the great ordeal was not a great ordeal.
Rym: I already started reading the greater wheel of time Great ordeals.
Rym: primary ordeal was that I finished it and I was like, oh shit now there's like four years before this gets concluded.
Scott: That's the real ordeal.
Rym: Patience I gotta learn from myself.
Rym: don't read book series no matter how good they are until the author's dead or the series is done The D&D dead or done.
Scott: Well, there's Oryx and Craig.
Scott: I just learned after finished reading this that it's actually volume one of three and the series is done.
Scott: So.
Scott: so
Rym: having finished it because you said that before and you said that it colored your perception of the book Yeah And I had that in mind when I read the last line of the book and then I turned the page and that was the end I can see why that colored your perception.
Scott: Yes at the ending of the book.
Scott: I did not think of as a cliffhanger I thought of it just like ah the end right.
Scott: but then because there's a book two and three I didn't.
Scott: and soon as I knew that I realized oh that ending is a cliffhanger ending.
Rym: now I do know because other people have.
Rym: basically many of our friends the people who are recommending Oryx and Craig to us so much Have said very specifically that Oryx and Craig is good But it is not the best of the trilogy by far and the three books are not.
Rym: It's not like the second one picks up right where the first one left off No different saying you can guess where the second one's gonna be about right?
Scott: It's like you don't need anyone to like.
Scott: tell you.
Rym: Well, you could guess either go forward or go back.
Scott: now, it's obviously about the people he meets at the end.
Rym: No, not at all.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it is.
Rym: No, at least the summary I was given is that it follows these other characters in a different part of the world.
Scott: I'm pretty sure the end of the second book is gonna be the end of the first book also.
Scott: I Don't think so.
Scott: I think it is.
Scott: Anyway, who knows we'll find out when I read it.
Rym: Yeah, I'll read the other two because everyone's telling me that they just as short.
Rym: They only take six hours that you have to read the whole trilogy and the other ones are better not to say that Oryx and Craig Is bad, but anyway, is it about?
Scott: does it follow other mad Adam people, right?
Scott: Is that what it's going?
Rym: seems like the second one seems to follow two people who are locked in sex dungeons in a different part Of the world during the apocalypse.
Scott: Okay, let's move already.
Rym: So, uh, yeah Oryx and Craig if you did not read it We're gonna be talking about it assuming you read it.
Rym: But if you need to be convinced to read it before we do that, it was it what it's real short.
Rym: It's like it's a 12-hour read.
Rym: if you're a real slow reader like a real slug me like six hours.
Rym: It's a short book.
Rym: It's very pointed.
Rym: It's Good.
Rym: I really enjoyed it.
Scott: What's really amazing about this book?
Scott: I think is that how much it's able to cover in such a small amount of book?
Rym: Yeah without being convoluted or complicated or messy covers to Basically completely separate storylines only linked by the fact that they happen to the same person in Very different time period.
Scott: it covers way more than two story.
Rym: I mean it covers like so much and I mean it is.
Rym: so what is those two storylines?
Scott: But there's also just so much subject matter.
Scott: Yes, right that's covered.
Rym: I think part of that is that the subject matter is Hinted at or given to you like.
Rym: there'll be one short paragraph that describes one tiny thing.
Rym: But what that tiny thing implies is a gigantic story all on its own, right?
Scott: So you got.
Scott: you got the post-apocalypse thing, which I guess, you know nerds love.
Scott: Yeah, we did our.
Scott: what's the?
Scott: what's the book?
Scott: We read.
Scott: well, no.
Scott: Well, there's wool and then the old one with the Can't can't.
Scott: Yeah, yeah Another one of those books in that post-apocalypse Genre, right.
Scott: and then you bring in the UN play God sci-fi in the biology department up.
Rym: you bring in Neoliberal crass consumerist dystopia of like a snow crash kind of world.
Rym: But I'm way worse.
Rym: you get.
Scott: well you get the cyberpunk of all this internet action going on right written from 2003 which explains some of the references, right?
Scott: Yeah, that's you know, how much internet did they know in two thousand three?
Scott: It was a long goddamn time ahead of his time for two thousand three.
Scott: Yeah You got like love stories like Gennaro Love story.
Rym: that's very pointedly told only from one character's perspective and that's very important.
Scott: But you all but it's actually you're getting to love stories.
Scott: You're getting teenage love story and adult love story.
Scott: Yeah together, right?
Scott: You're getting addressing all sorts of societal Subject matters primarily neoliberalism, I think right?
Scott: Well, you know, you got the the rich Suburb Walden corporate places and then you know the partying or caves and the pleblins.
Scott: Yeah pretty much.
Rym: Also, you've got the.
Rym: the super secret cable channel from player of games is the basic broadcast TV in this world Mm-hmm.
Scott: There's the and of course in the post-apocalypse world.
Rym: You've got a whole other thing going on You know and you've got the plot of the second half of the Dominion tank police OAV Which you can only actually figure out if you read the manga because the anime shows it to you but doesn't explain it.
Scott: Well, it's got like a little bit of Lord of the Flies going on little bit.
Rym: if the Lord of the Flies ended way better.
Scott: Sure, right, you know, it's like you got.
Scott: you know It's.
Scott: it's so much happening in this one little bit of culture going on and it's only one of three books.
Rym: yeah, so We're gonna spoil the fuck out of this book and it's really short and you should just read it because it's a really really well Written book like.
Rym: I can't recommend it enough if you listen to GeekNights.
Rym: You would like this book.
Rym: unless you guys can't read then get an audiobook.
Scott: So I'm sure it's an audio book.
Rym: I mean Margaret Atwood is a respected and well-known author for a reason and this book Is worth reading.
Rym: and from this point forward if you're not convinced by everything we just said We're just gonna assume that you read it and we're gonna talk about it.
Rym: And here we go.
Rym: so Where to begin?
Scott: so the title of the book is Oryx and Craig.
Scott: Yeah, which is like the most Not even trying to hide it.
Scott: Adam and Eve kind of symbolism that has ever been done.
Scott: Yeah, it's like there's.
Scott: no I think that's.
Scott: the only flaw I could find in the book is that all of its Messages were not subtle like nothing was like clever or like hidden.
Scott: It was just like here I am.
Rym: So it wasn't a sense though because it was the story of Someone who didn't pick up on all those clues.
Scott: Yeah, but the reader is way smarter than Jimmy.
Rym: Yeah, but that's it.
Rym: you you the the person who has the wider perspective Living for in your ivory tower reading this book with its attached Elegance will read it and you see all the things that Jimmy doesn't see.
Scott: Yeah, you see where this is guys like there's a chapter where they basically I think Were.
Scott: they reveal that like Craig made the Craig people literally, but it's like I knew that like three chapters in.
Scott: well Yeah, they even call some crackers right, but it's like it's like they don't explore.
Rym: I was suspecting in the beginning I wasn't sure before you met Oryx.
Rym: It was possible that Oryx or Craig might have been the creator Because we didn't really know like from.
Scott: for all we knew well And maybe Oryx was gonna be a different scientist once they revealed that you know Craig was like a smart You know going to study at the place.
Scott: I was like, oh, yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Now I understand did the crackers, right?
Scott: Yeah, but Oryx where I figured out Oryx like this mystery for so long Right.
Scott: It's like, you know and even in the end.
Scott: It's like you don't really know, you know like her whole deal Yeah, which is sort of on like.
Scott: was she really that girl from the video?
Scott: Probably not.
Rym: Maybe it doesn't because remember the descriptions of her everything relating to her and in Craig and everything is from Jimmy's perspective pretty much Everything.
Rym: every single thing is Jimmy's perspective not any sort of other.
Rym: There's no other perspective left and Jimmy is yep, and Jimmy is uh Sort of I think he described himself best remember doesn't?
Rym: he say that if he'd been born in the pleb lands go to a public He would have been a shining star but instead he's like the barely acceptable bare minimum of the elite society.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, he's.
Scott: I think that's why you know, he may eat the.
Scott: he's a great, you know Main character.
Scott: right because you're none of them.
Scott: No one who's a reader, right?
Scott: We're all pleb lands people.
Rym: Yeah, neither out as much as I'd like to say it.
Rym: Neither one of us is Craig.
Scott: Everyone reading is a pleb lands person, right?
Scott: all the real-world people like us.
Rym: if you think you're crazy Read crime and punish you can't out of Roscoe.
Rym: Well, I guess you could be a Roskalnikov.
Scott: You can't go into this book with the perspective of.
Scott: you know No one likes to write books from a perspective of like the God narrator.
Scott: not a character anymore.
Scott: That's so out of style right, you know, or the it gives the unreliable narrators in style, but even then that's usually a character.
Scott: Yeah, I like the earnest but possibly uninformed or naive narrator Sure, but the only character that we can relate to in this whole story is Jimmy.
Scott: right because the Crakers are not really people They're from yet in a way.
Scott: they are and they are but they don't.
Scott: they're not.
Scott: we can't relate to them on any like.
Scott: they Don't have a society Basically aliens, right but the book sets up this whole thing of.
Rym: Craig manufactured the apocalypse to.
Rym: why have a clean slate?
Rym: wipe everything out.
Rym: He had the perfect plan and the reason for that was arguably because all the people who had had all these plans up to this point were me and play God's situation and There were increasingly adverse consequences of the science and that we had to get away from all these problems.
Rym: But yet he fell into the same trap because he was a product of the society that had those problems.
Rym: So he had the.
Rym: his perfect plan was just as perfect as all the other perfect plans of that crass and horrible society.
Scott: That's his words.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No, it didn't.
Scott: The pig ooh, we didn't get them all.
Rym: the pigoons are gonna literally be the 1984 pigs pretty much.
Rym: and the Crakers already figured Religion and we're already learning and we're already kind of shaking their head at snowman.
Rym: Like alright guy.
Rym: Yeah, we're smart.
Rym: We figured stuff out.
Rym: We're not that dumb and there's humans still alive.
Rym: But think about that Craig what decided that this highly advanced society was playing God and to per you know He had all these reasons.
Scott: Well, yeah, it wasn't the great society at all.
Scott: It could.
Scott: he definitely used to shake it up, but he thought he was smarter than them.
Scott: And he felt but because I was smart of them, but he wasn't, you know, well, yeah nobody's perfect But he made this.
Rym: well, that's the problem.
Rym: Yeah, he did the thing that only works if you're perfect.
Rym: But because he was a product of that society He was just as flawed as the pigoons and the snacks and everything else along or the snacks Along the way.
Rym: So his plan was just as bad as theirs.
Rym: It just had a lot more collateral damage Mm-hmm.
Scott: Well, you know, I guess you know if he's Adam, right?
Scott: It's like he's so smart cuz he ate from the tree of knowledge, right?
Scott: He was all smart, but it's like I kicked out a pair of dice with the sea, but it's like dude.
Scott: Adam Did not do so.
Scott: Well, I didn't just to one of his kids kill the other one.
Scott: It's like Yeah, even with all that knowledge from Apple eating he had.
Rym: but it's interesting because You have this world that you're not only just seeing it purely from Jimmy's perspective But you're seeing it only from the perspective of the people in the compounds Like you're seeing it from the perspective Yeah You don't.
Scott: you don't learn too and really much at all about Pueblans except for like the few scenes where he goes to the Pueblans and check stuff out
Rym: like you're told
Scott: That
Rym: the rest of the world it feels like when the book starts the entire world outside of these compounds is almost already post-apocalyptic.
Rym: But then you start to realize that That's just the perspective of those people like.
Scott: it ain't great out there, but it's not that bad, right?
Scott: Well, I mean these are.
Scott: it's weird that like everything almost everything in this book is.
Scott: I'm not sure how much of it was, you know time wise before or after other things.
Scott: But for example, right in the 90s, I read spider-man 2099, which is basically cyberpunk spider-man.
Scott: It's actually really good.
Scott: You should read it.
Scott: It's a comic book obviously.
Scott: Yeah and in spider-man 2099 Spider-man is it's basically it's in Nueva York.
Scott: is the setting?
Scott: Yeah Right and there's basically all the cars in Nueva York are hover cars that fly like above these maglev tracks That are above old New York.
Scott: Nueva York is above old New York.
Scott: physically It's this uptown and downtown.
Rym: It's like New Detroit.
Scott: And yes Right.
Scott: So underneath the maglev tracks where the buildings that we currently live in are Located is the same thing as the pleb lands right and up above is where the evil corporate land, right?
Scott: It's like these cut, you know, so they've been it horizontally arranged in Oryx and Craig But it's the same deal right the pigoons and whatever.
Scott: It's like dude and ghost in the shell.
Scott: to man-machine interface Which I think came out about around the same time as this book.
Rym: Actually this book was 2003. it was published.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not sure when man-machine interface was written by You know Masamune Shiro.
Scott: But the whole plot line if you can actually understand any of it revolves around Pigs that they're growing humans organs in and harvesting.
Scott: but then well cuz that was a real-world thing.
Rym: We were working on this ride Exactly, right.
Scott: They're doing cyber shit with the pigs brains and whatever, right?
Scott: You know, so it's like a lot of all of these things in Oryx and Craig are exists.
Scott: It's like there's not.
Rym: man-machine interface ran 91 to 97.
Rym: It was actually pretty slow.
Scott: I came out in I think the US around that time.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I was buying it original run September 91 to August 97.
Rym: Anyway, I don't read that Unless you're brave Unless you're brave or you are that desperate for more ghosts in the show?
Scott: You got to be super desperate like that.
Scott: You know, that's the last ghost in the show You should go.
Rym: that's like Barney drinking the beer out of the cigarette tray.
Scott: but it's weird.
Scott: like I'm reading this book and every single thing in this book is Something that I had seen before in some other cyberpunk or some other sci-fi or some other something.
Scott: well, like they say it's also an inversion though because yet By combining every single one of those things into one book is completely new.
Rym: So here's the inversion that I noticed in like snow crash and those kinds of you know We're like burb claves and all that stuff the crass Consumerism so chipper typified by things called like chicky nubs and soy.
Scott: Oh boy fries or whatever a little fallout action going on.
Rym: Yeah like all that shit in those worlds is aimed at the crass middle-class plebeian like sort of Non-interactive non-important people and the elites have this so much different world Began in this book.
Rym: The oh that is are the ones creating and consuming those things and the pleb lands while they are like You don't really get to see but like there's the moment where he's going to the university That's kind of closer to pleb land.
Rym: Like it's it's like a real university.
Rym: still I never has humanities.
Rym: and remember he brings the chicky knobs home because he's an elite and he gets chicky knobs and they're like What the fuck dude?
Scott: Yeah, then actually, you know, that is interesting I didn't ever thought of it that you know because it's like, you know These sort of fake silly products or trope that are in everything and they're always aimed at like, you know I'll buy for a dollar.
Rym: that's a shit people.
Scott: Well some I think that's you know, the one in the ones you're thinking of.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: They are aimed at the shit people.
Scott: Right the shit people The lower class, you know They're usually in those works shit.
Rym: relative to the narrative of the story the
Scott: upper-class people the people running the society are manufacturing this garbage right, you know obey whatever and Foisting it on the lower classes and they're living it up with the good shit, right the real stuff You know, but the original real deal and brave new world That's not how it is.
Scott: and brave new world the upper-class people who live in the brave new society are the ones with the the Feelies and the soma and all the good shit.
Scott: Yeah, and the people who live in the sticks It's that's a lot more similar to the Oryx and Craig's.
Rym: but I like how this one combines the like Ultra crass Chicken surprise level product names with the inversion of those are the products that are also marketed at the high-end elites.
Rym: And there's the point where he becomes the ad man.
Rym: for you know, the obviously fake shit Yeah, and yet he starts using it anyway, and he even notes like I guess I fell for my own Shit,
Scott: but I mean the other thing is that some of it's it's almost did we fall for those ads because actually I think chicken
Rym: Kind of good.
Rym: Yeah, I actually it's interesting.
Scott: I haven't eaten any but it's like they don't seem bad to me.
Rym: Well because look at the new Craig is the Hannibal Lecter Transhumanist like sociopath right and Jimmy is the normal person.
Rym: normal people are revolted by chicken knobs because that Terrifies some very base sensibility of humanity and our culture.
Rym: But yet from a more from a distance you say I'm a sociopath because I like chicken.
Rym: I'm saying from a more dispassionate or literate or objective frame of reference.
Rym: I say more because there is no objective frame of reference.
Rym: even the judging eye is not an objective reference because it's still dams whores.
Scott: but I digress But I think it dams everyone is it there's?
Scott: anyone had seen that hasn't been named?
Rym: Uh, it did not damn the tears of God and I don't think she was damaged looked at herself I don't know anyway But Craig is the one who you know That level.
Rym: the transhumanist side looks at cheeky knobs and says this is an objective improvement that objectively reduces the amount of suffering of Thinking beings in the world.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Good game.
Rym: Yeah, so the pagoons are way worse because they're putting human brains in them.
Rym: Yeah, but the cheeky knobs, I hope cheeky knobs exist someday.
Scott: Yeah It's like it's the the whore the thing that appears already at the point where if I get the imitation General so's chicken from the vegan place.
Scott: It tastes very good.
Scott: It tastes better than the general.
Scott: so chicken from the not the from the average Chinese place Obviously go to the fancy Chinese, you know, yeah, right.
Scott: I mean, you're probably not getting general so's chicken at the fancy Chinese place Are you yeah?
Rym: I can't get a burger made from fake meat yet.
Scott: Yeah, but it won't.
Rym: it won't be there it's not.
Scott: it doesn't taste like what you want.
Rym: a cheeky knobs sound pretty good actually.
Scott: yeah Especially if it's fried because mostly you eat fried chicken for the fried not for the chicken but on one hand Great something to fry cuz remember we don't get Kirk's Craig's perspective We just see him through the lens of Jimmy.
Rym: Craig goes on and on about how you know This Malthusian nonsense that we're at, you know overpopulation is going to destroy the earth and blah blah blah blah.
Rym: But at the same time you see that all the technology they're using pretty much everywhere that they can especially in the compounds It's all solar-powered.
Rym: like they have moved toward green energy for everywhere that they can.
Rym: and How much?
Rym: because you know in the modern world?
Rym: Malthusian economics and Malthusian stuff is pretty deeply discredited.
Rym: and the idea that the only way to constrain a rapidly growing human population as mass starvation or disasters was discredited by the As his rationale for fucking murdering everybody well, I think you know, he doesn't.
Scott: Jimmy never knows.
Scott: that's gonna happen until it happens.
Scott: So it's not like you needed to see a rationale for it's a late.
Rym: I Gotcha, I wasn't sure just from the beginning if Oryx or Craig was going to be the one to do it until The second relative of Craig's died.
Rym: and then I was like well Craig is the kid from that story about the poisoning kid Mm-hmm, like straight up.
Rym: He's murdering people practicing testing it.
Scott: Well, cuz it's his you know, his own dad got pushed off the thing, right?
Rym: Yeah, I left the bridge or whatever but Craig Was pretty much like there.
Rym: every indication to me is that Craig was wrong?
Rym: Objectively bad failed and like this story is about just this psychotic person Getting the power to do his psychotic thing and kill everybody and that all the justification is Probably pretty flimsy.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think there's any justification.
Rym: Yeah now at the same time we are in a world I mean, he was so close to flood it was so smart and so powerful, right?
Scott: He easily could have you know Shaken things up in a less ridiculous way.
Scott: actually if he'd gone with his that the plan that he was faking Like he could have just become like in charge of the whole company and then stopped being evil because he's in charge of all right now.
Rym: He made Soma like he could have just turned into that and then instead nope Soma kills people.
Rym: Mm-hmm, like his plan.
Rym: his first plan was way better than his second plan And even the designer babies.
Rym: that would have been the kind of thing where the designer babies just replace real humans And eventually it's just crackers walking around, right?
Scott: Well, that's part of the overpopulation thing right?
Scott: is?
Scott: people, you know, at least the people who had access I weren't dying so much Unless they were murdered by corruption, but you know see we're not dying so much.
Rym: But at the same time we know that this was definitely a neoliberal dystopia because climate change has fucked the world pretty badly and The it's always warm all the time.
Scott: Everything's tropical.
Rym: Yep, and the corpse are Making horrific diseases and using them to wage corporate warfare shadowrun style.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So All those medicines are always flawed on purpose and like none of that stuff is a hundred percent effective.
Rym: so those people aren't actually immortal and like that stuff is actually not working out so great.
Rym: and You also get this impression that it's not the.
Rym: the advanced technology is not the problem.
Rym: The I am play God is not the problem.
Rym: the problem is that the I am like God is deeply fettered to this capitalist neoliberal society.
Rym: and It might have been it would have been great if that had been run by some sort of government I guess.
Scott: Or you know anyone who is not evil.
Rym: Yeah Pretty much Craig just got way too much power though.
Rym: So here's a question Scott did Craig create when he was young the extinct a thon thing and Use that to recruit people or did he find it and take it over?
Scott: No, someone else made it because it was older than he was right?
Rym: It's like, you know, but we only know this from Jimmy and I'm pretty sure Craig introduced it to Jimmy as a game I. But I'm just curious what are your thoughts are cuz?
Rym: I can justify both pretty easily.
Scott: I mean, yes something that's not specified and doesn't matter doesn't you know, it's like you can.
Scott: obviously it could be either way Which is a big part of Oryx's character.
Rym: cuz look every time Jimmy fries into her past her answer is always that's stupid.
Rym: Why do you care?
Rym: How does this matter?
Rym: Mm-hmm, which is extra interesting because now he is doing the same thing to the crackers like he's trying to.
Rym: just he doesn't even want to tell them about what came before because he's like.
Scott: It literally doesn't matter and it also will mess you up.
Scott: It'll mess you up and you'll just ask me a bunch of stupid questions, then I won't be able to shut you up.
Scott: Yeah, it's like stop asking me all this dumb shit.
Rym: Does he act that way because she acted that way to Make him that way so he would do his job.
Scott: You ever wonder about you know, they're actually, you know, usually you think right like You know.
Scott: Like in the real world, you know All these religious explanations for things and there's generally this sort of pop mostly false idea that like oh, yeah you know in the olden days the religious leaders were just the only smart people and They would tell people stuff like yeah, don't eat pig.
Rym: Why are you thinking the religious people just wanted people around to shut up and stop bothering them, right?
Scott: Cuz God will because God will punish you because they don't want to explain that like, you know, yeah It's it's gonna be gonna get sick.
Scott: Why the taste delicious, you know, yeah Is that why we have Religion?
Scott: because someone tried to explain things to dumb people and didn't want to have to sit there and give a real explanation.
Rym: But it is relevant to the the whole, you know, the past doesn't matter or what came before Doesn't affect you.
Scott: In fact knowing it might mess you up It's like if I was the girl in the video.
Scott: or why wasn't?
Scott: it doesn't matter, right?
Rym: It'll change your opinion for no reason Yep.
Rym: But remember way back when we did our final thoughts.
Rym: I just thought of this big.
Rym: Oh Remember that show.
Rym: yeah, so a big theme in Big O is whether or not the past before everyone lost their memories matters at all.
Rym: like Does it matter the orange because?
Scott: Never doesn't it right?
Scott: That's a lot of apocalypses.
Scott: Don't I mean, I guess the The Leibovitz one does and so does Eric's and Craig That the previous one causes the next one forever right but a lot of post apocalypses say like fisted the North Star.
Scott: Yeah It's like no people Haven't forgotten what happened before because the people living and the people in the store It's like not enough people died in those apocalypses.
Scott: So they're all walking around and all the adults remember the world before the apocalypse because they lived through it.
Rym: Well, they're also all set in worlds where there's no possibility of reclaiming a better world So they only have the opportunity to make the same mistakes, right?
Scott: But here this is one where people have.
Scott: you know, everything that came before was forgotten except by Jimmy at least in this book.
Scott: Yeah, you know apparently I guess we're gonna see other people in other books who might remember.
Scott: But the only person this book who remembers is the snowman Which is weird because like, you know, I'd even as like snowman like there's no snow anywhere the abominable snowman.
Scott: Well, it's in the myth, right?
Scott: He's alluding to you know, the right the myth because of the global warming, right?
Scott: There are there's no snow or snowmen anymore.
Scott: There isn't even a concept of snow, right but also his abominableness Right compared to you know, the people that he's you know, the crackers right.
Scott: as far as compared to them He is definitely abominable.
Rym: course notice how his mental state changes Rapidly bit depending on where he is When the book starts.
Scott: well also based on the situation.
Rym: He's in right but like he's without Society around him He's barely human and can't even form coherent thoughts.
Rym: like he doesn't like he doesn't wear clothes or bathe He's kind of just this mess.
Scott: He's just trying to basically survive, you know, he doesn't have you know The knowledge or instincts to survive in the wild or whatever.
Rym: But as he slowly but he's also living a worse lifestyle than he could if he applied himself a little bit.
Rym: But then as he returns and you get the impression that he makes this pilgrimage back to those places Semi-regularly and that the cycle just kept repeating until now.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, that's how he had alcohol.
Rym: Yeah, but he Regresses when he's away.
Rym: Eventually something drives him to go back and as he goes back He gets me gets more and more human and more and more cognizant.
Scott: He has to take care of the people.
Rym: He makes plans he remembers and then he starts forgetting it all again.
Rym: Cuz when he goes back the first thing he does is he has a brain fart and he realizes he forgot to get a mirror.
Rym: And it all just collapses.
Rym: and you know that if those people hadn't been there He would have turned back into that basically scab just sitting on that rusty bed frame in the tree waiting You know just getting drunk doing nothing.
Scott: I should have told him to bring me a fish every day three a day Not once a week.
Scott: What are you seeing?
Rym: steamed crabs, but the good kind.
Scott: Yeah, but I won't let eat them eat me.
Scott: So you have to eat grass or whatever, you know, because that's how they're engineered and whatnot.
Rym: Yep so Oryx was definitely not in on it.
Scott: Well, I mean she says as much cuz.
Scott: she calls Jimmy on the phone.
Scott: she's like, oh my god I didn't realize all those things that you know, and it didn't seem like she was lying.
Rym: So if it was her in the video It makes sense that Craig either used her or got someone who looked like her.
Rym: Like this was all Kella style engineered to put Jimmy in the right state of mind to do the things he wanted to do.
Rym: It's very much like a Prince of Nothing Kella situation.
Scott: I think it could have been you know, but it didn't you know.
Scott: how much was You know, I mean he definitely, you know did what he had to do to get Jimmy, you know to do it He needed yeah right up to but suicide by Jimmy.
Scott: But it's like it, you know, did he like?
Scott: was Oryx a person that he genetically?
Scott: Manufactured and then put these memories in?
Scott: it's like, you know It could have been any.
Scott: it could have been.
Scott: it also could it could?
Scott: she could have been the person in the video.
Scott: She could have just been a person who looked like the person in the van again.
Rym: The question doesn't matter.
Rym: It's like, you know, but that's where we get the point.
Scott: doesn't want all these details of like how isn't really important?
Rym: Well one criticism I've seen of the book and almost every one of our friends who recommended the book has brought this up Is that Oryx is definitely treated as this?
Rym: Exotified feminine mystery.
Rym: Yeah, but yet it is clearly from Jimmy's perspective and he is obsessed with her and That seems to be by Craig's design Like it's not a neutral view of her or anything.
Rym: it's Craig's Projection of her through Jimmy's eyes, right?
Scott: You don't see what she's doing when Jimmy's not around, right?
Scott: You don't know what her real deal is, you know completely.
Scott: you only know her deal as far as Jimmy is concerned and you know what the other character I think is the best character in the whole book is The same way which is Jimmy's mom.
Scott: Yeah The only other major female character really and like Jimmy's mom is like the best but you only see her The way Jimmy sees her.
Scott: when he's young he sees her as this, you know woman who's his mom is just a pain in the ass Ruining everything for him.
Scott: Yeah, right and that like a bad mom and then later like this mysterious person that he sort of want.
Scott: You know, it's like Simultaneously causing him problems because security keeps bothering him But also like he kind of wants to see her again or save her help her out because he understands it like oh my mom's actually Doing good now Right, imagine if Craig was like, you know hanging doing it Jimmy's mom's style right that it would be great.
Rym: Yeah, maybe though because those people were still mostly Terrorists.
Rym: at least that's the impression we get.
Rym: Yeah, but they were doing it on a lower scale.
Scott: Listen, if you're a terrorist and you're powerful enough that it works, right?
Scott: That's how.
Rym: But is there an argument to be made that that level of violence?
Rym: Dangerous Murderous activism like it's just a sliding scale.
Scott: It's less murderous than killing everybody.
Rym: The ultimate form of that is literally kill everybody Mm-hmm.
Scott: It's better than bioterrorism, right?
Rym: so another question is did Craig Specifically plan this to get Jimmy to kill him?
Rym: or was that an accident of him being drunk?
Scott: The killing at the end Kill Oryx.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: Jimmy remembers that and it's not likely that's a fabric.
Scott: No, they were right there on the ground Yeah, where he left him, right?
Scott: Yeah, that was you know.
Scott: See that I think partially was a literary device to avoid Like.
Scott: yeah, I'm calling you out amazing author on your cop-out To avoid having to they might still be alive.
Scott: Well, no to avoid having to write any sort of dialogue or further explanations after the head Like you, you know cuz like they.
Scott: well they could have had a conversation there, you know Like, you know Craig spilling some beans or Oryx spilling some beans, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: well if they die, we don't have to spill any beans.
Scott: I read a different way cuz remember when but obviously, you know, it's like Why did he kill her right there?
Rym: So I have a read on that.
Rym: because when Craig when he finally when Jimmy finally got a hold of Craig while the war Well, the apocalypse was beginning.
Scott: Did he know that?
Scott: maybe he was.
Scott: you know that he was.
Scott: Jimmy was taking the serum right to be Immune.
Scott: Yeah, maybe he wasn't in Oryx wasn't and he knew that like he did that on purpose He just he shot.
Scott: he shot her Cuz - cuz he knew then they would have he would avoid having to suffer from the disease and I think I ran away.
Rym: I think it's much more specific.
Scott: So and there was no one left to shoot him.
Rym: It's possible Jimmy Just remember he called he talks to Jimmy and he's drunk Which is odd.
Scott: He's not a person who gets drunk and he's acting differently.
Rym: So a common thing among People who attempt suicide in the real world and survive is that they're very motivated to do the thing.
Rym: But once they begin the action they very often have second thoughts and that's why guns are such a problem and Caused such a high rate of suicide because once you start the action, you're already over the threshold and it's too late.
Rym: So I feel like Craig even at that juncture Regretted what he'd done or feared that he was starting to regret it was worried that he would back out and basically Killed her to commit suicide by Jimmy's gun to make sure that he could not back away from what he started.
Scott: Oh, maybe maybe it was just.
Scott: he did it right and at you know, it's like, you know, he was so sure of it.
Scott: Yep, and then it wasn't After he after he killed the whole world.
Scott: He actually felt guilty.
Rym: It was like oh shit I don't think it's even guilt cuz at that.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: I fucked up.
Scott: I Can't really live with myself.
Rym: at that point He probably could have gotten the vaccine out and started to like save people.
Rym: It's because I was still pretty early when he got back to the facility.
Rym: So I'm free.
Rym: I suspect that was him making sure that he could not stop it because he He's alive.
Scott: then somebody could like force him to save the world again undo it or he might have.
Rym: you know He seems like the kind of person who logically was sure of what he did But he was worried that his fragile human brain might feel guilt and undo it on him himself.
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Rym: I feel like.
Scott: that's what was plenty of reasonable explanations there.
Rym: That's the best I could come up with.
Rym: everything else was hinky or crazy or didn't really fit.
Scott: Yeah Also so that their corpses could conveniently be there when you know, Jimmy goes back right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Otherwise, I mean, I really like this book and I like the ending because it's sort of did.
Rym: it very elegantly says You know Craig's was you know, Craig was wrong and everything's.
Rym: the world just keeps progressing.
Rym: things was different, right?
Scott: Cuz up until you know, it's like yeah, you know up until like the very end part It seems like everything Craig wanted to happen is happening like his design is perfect.
Scott: design You know is into.
Scott: his intelligent design has come to fruition exactly as planned and then at the end of the book They're like, actually it didn't.
Rym: so there was a scene when he's leaving the crackers to go do the thing where?
Rym: The the kids keep asking him shit and he's kind of getting flummoxed and you know starting to fumble over his lies a little bit and the adult crackers sort of Shake their heads and just get the kids to shut up.
Rym: and it's implied that the old old crackers even then are Way more aware of what's going on then they necessarily let on to snowman.
Rym: Yeah, like snowman is Treating them like babies and they're actually they figured more out than he realizes.
Scott: Well, you know, they're also partially like, all right Let's not upset the crazy old man in the woods.
Scott: Yeah, you know, he's actually somewhat useful.
Rym: Also, we feel bad for him.
Rym: Yeah, you know cuz they're like, oh, yeah some other people like you came.
Rym: So we're like, whatever they're right over there.
Rym: You wanna go talk to him?
Rym: Yeah But the fact at the end too that now he is this monster on the like outside of the vision Yeah, an abominable monster with a gun and he's thinking to himself.
Rym: Should I just kill him all?
Rym: what do I do?
Rym: And the fact that who are the?
Scott: I don't know anything about this be yeah humanity is the same after the apocalypse.
Scott: Well, I think the other it's like he is so close to knowing about the apocalypse more than anyone ever Like, you know, like anyone he meets knows nothing.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: You know if he hangs out with anyone it's like.
Scott: will they find out?
Scott: What will they learn?
Scott: just like being near him is like how much can he hide?
Scott: it's like they're gonna.
Scott: you know Already those people already met the crackers and we're like what the hell is up with these people.
Scott: Where did they go?
Rym: Yeah, you know Chris remember to all the smart people inside of the facility.
Rym: He locked them out when if he'd kept them in they could have been an asset or valuable possibly.
Scott: maybe maybe they didn't all die Necessarily, I mean most of them did probably but it's possible that more than one of them is still alive.
Rym: Yep or I mean - and people speaking in Russian.
Rym: so it's clear that there are Probably Significant numbers of humans out somewhere.
Scott: Doing it was not a complete world extinction.
Rym: Well, because you know the moral of a lot of like all these experiments were having side effects because you know Jurassic Park style nature finds Away and yet humans are part of nature.
Rym: So nature found a way.
Rym: There's definitely humans alive.
Rym: Craig was not full-on Hannibal Lecter.
Rym: He made mistakes.
Rym: He wasn't as transhuman as he thought he was.
Scott: Mmm, yes, we gotta read the second one.
Scott: What's the name of the second one?
Rym: Oh, it's the mad Adam trilogy You know, what's the name of the second book the year of the flood and mad Adam?
Scott: Oh, so you're okay.
Scott: So you're the flood rights?
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So the first year the flood was written in 2009.
Rym: Okay, so mad Adam was written a few years ago All right.
Scott: So listen, the first book is orcs and Craig which you already discussed.
Scott: is Adam and Eve, right?
Scott: Oh and the second book is year the flood that Noah's Ark book, right?
Scott: But what biblical thing is mad Adam from here in the flood?
Rym: focus on a book on the group called God's gardeners.
Rym: You know those guys, okay survivors of the same biological source the Survivors somewhere else who are members of the terrorist organization.
Rym: Oh, that's about Jimmy's mom or at least the people she was with.
Rym: she didn't survive probably.
Rym: and the third one is mad Adam concludes the dystopian trilogy Continuation of both books written them from the perspective of two characters introduced in year of the flood.
Rym: learn All right.
Rym: I'm not gonna read any snaps is because you want to know.
Rym: I'm just gonna read the book.
Rym: Yeah, yeah good stuff.
Scott: I wonder when the the flood was.
Rym: It's interesting because the technology they're using like in the libraries is CD roms and DVDs Yeah, which actually was done in 2003 or 2001 to like that era of the real world.
Scott: Let me imagine if you had to write some cyberpunk book, right and you wanted to make it timeless.
Scott: I just go for vague brain stuff and just right It's like cyber link is like the best thing that anyone can imagine.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like in the future when they have whatever is way better than cyber link.
Scott: They're gonna read your book Like 21st century book talking about it cyber links.
Rym: They thought we'd still have human brain and it's eat.
Scott: It's 10 gigabit Ethernet.
Scott: What's a wire?
Scott: It's wireless internet?
Rym: Watch out guys This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: The patrons for this episode of GeekNights in descending order of the amount of money They give us on a continuing basis.
Rym: As long as that amount of money is more than five dollars a month is Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunne Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette James David White Christian coons construction noises.
Rym: my stated I'm Sean Hayworth William Isen rose Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas hot Aaron Cerise Michelle Garcia Brian Fisher sailor Vista Bill Murray's precious little life Iggy kid Matthew Smith Don Schleich chart obvious and Joshua Joe star Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walden to run from New Zealand Ryan parent or open-lander rare Laval Brian Sidroni Rochelle Montanota Finn Eric solver on bonsai buddy Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Han.
Rym: god damn it.
Rym: It is actually really hard to do that.
Rym: it is hard to say all of your names in a row and I'm having increasing trouble.
Rym: I worry what'll happen if many more people join this list.
Rym: It already takes me three full breaths.
Rym: So yeah, we just did Oregon Craig.
Rym: as you listen Scott is still coughing Pretty heavily, which is why I haven't forced him to do a Q&A yet.
Rym: So the two things gonna do and I know I said I was gonna do this before So I'm actually gonna put him up tomorrow and Saturday is one I'm gonna do the AMA on running conventions.
Rym: So we're gonna post about that.
Rym: you patrons.
Rym: yee and two I'm playing a lot of giant multiplayer robot games as if five so I'm gonna open it up to You patrons or at least a subset of you and then I'll expand it if I don't get a full set To start an a player game of sieve basically just me and a to you and we'll play Civilization 5 by mail.
Rym: and I got some other things that are in the hopper and hopefully I'll get those all up on the side Soon, but anyway now I leave you since Someone immediately recognized that the previous thing was from the prisoner something both weird and obscure Oh.