Rym: It's Thursday, November 10th, 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: Somehow we never did a show on this.
Rym: Talking about wallets.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So over the weekend, Scott, uh, uh, Gold me into doing this thing and I did it.
Scott: I didn't goad you into doing it.
Scott: You agreed.
Scott: Well, you told me it was- I told you it existed.
Rym: You told me it existed.
Rym: You expressed- I actually- You expressed mild, uh, suspicion that I would wake up early enough to do it.
Rym: Right.
Scott: I anti-goaded you by telling you you'd have to wake up at not the crack-ass of dawn, but the crack-ass of dawn.
Scott: Crack-a-crackity-crack.
Rym: Like, I got up at- when did I leave the house?
Scott: I woke up at like 4.30, 4.45.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I don't think I actually left.
Scott: I left at like 5.15, 5.30.
Rym: 'Cause it took- it didn't take me that long to bike down there to the starting point.
Scott: Well, I'm farther away than you.
Rym: You are.
Rym: Also, I bike a lot faster.
Scott: You're trying to bike faster.
Rym: Though, yo, I noticed that, 'cause usually when I bike with you, like, no, you're not slow, but you're not fast.
Rym: I could go faster.
Rym: But then you bike.
Rym: Yeah, what I'm saying, when we started biking, I went at the usual speed.
Rym: I think I'll go when I'm with you.
Rym: And then you were like, whoosh, 'cause you have that good bike now.
Rym: You are going faster.
Scott: I'm not tr- I just- whenever I bike, I just go- I'm not in a race.
Rym: You're not huffing and puffing like I am.
Scott: Yeah, you're huffing and puffing and I'm just sorta like, doo-doo-doo-doo.
Rym: No, I was- I was legit impressed with your speed.
Scott: That is- that bike- I mean, oh, yes, I'm so impressed with your speed in that F1 car.
Rym: It almost makes me want to get another bike, 'cause I got a hybrid, which doesn't have- it's not like that.
Scott: Especially 'cause also I was recently mountain biking, so- I didn't buy the- like, when I bought the bike, the guy at the bike store was like, you know, fancy bike doesn't make you go faster.
Scott: I'm like, I know, I'm not buying it to go faster.
Scott: I'm buying it because, you know, it's more comfortable.
Rym: Well, who's the kid in the forum who was like, I'm too slow going up hills, what bike should I buy?
Rym: And we were like, ahhh.
Scott: No matter what bike you buy, the engine is the same.
Scott: Your leg.
Scott: But, yeah, it's just more comfortable, right?
Scott: It's like, if I had to do that ride on my other bike, my ass would hurt.
Scott: So, but on this bike, I could just sit on it all goddamn day.
Rym: Ah, thing is, I wear the, uh, fancy pants.
Scott: I also got the fancy pants, but even using the fancy pants- Not fancy enough.
Scott: Really not fancy enough.
Rym: My pants are pretty- actually, some of my pants are fancy, but most of my bike shorts are bullshit Chinese bootlegs.
Scott: I bought the- this is one brand on Amazon, and it fit, so I got that brand.
Rym: I have two for-real ones that I wear under other shorts, and then I have, like, because Emily and I are the same size-ish, so, I bought, like, six pairs of these bootleg fucking bike shorts.
Scott: Basically, what it is, the New York City Marathon happens, right, and it starts in Staten Island, it goes up Brooklyn, Queens, over the bridge, up to the Bronx, down, and then into Central Park, and then in the bottom of Central Park.
Scott: in the end, right?
Scott: So, we start in Astoria, and we go all the way down to the bottom ass of Brooklyn, we can't go to Staten Island, and then we start, like, way before the race starts, 'cause you can't- otherwise, it's like one of those video games where the spike wall is going from the left side of the screen.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right, all the runners, and also the police would kick you off the road at a certain point.
Rym: Yeah, they'd probably taze you off the road at that point.
Scott: Yeah, you have to get to the end, you have to start way before the runners start, and get to the end before the cops close the road, and there's still technically cars on the road, is that closed?
Rym: Yep, but there's way less cars?
Scott: There's almost no cars, because there's all these people setting up all the water tables, and the clocks, and all the marathon shit.
Rym: So, you gotta kind of avoid all that shit, too, like in the Pulaski, they had that giant timer, and you couldn't get on the regular road yet, and there's all that-.
Scott: Oh, yeah, but I mean, you know, it was like, you get the idea, right?
Scott: It's like, it's a mostly closed road, right?
Scott: You can pedal for a long ass time without having to stop, it's pretty nice, you don't have to pay to enter into some race or anything, or win a lottery, or get a bib, or any of that nonsense, you know?
Scott: And then, so you go up, and I cross over the Queensborough Bridge, and you can cross over the not pedestrian bike park.
Rym: Yep, which I've only done once.
Rym: I did it two times, and that was nice, and then you go- That was the point where I bailed, because I didn't suspect I'd easily be able to get back home without taking my bike on the subway.
Rym: So, yeah, so then- I was in front of my apartment, it was real tempting, you'd be like, "I'll just go
Rym: inside.".
Scott: So then I go to the Bronx, and then I go down, right, the east side of the park, and then over to 59th street, and you can't go to the finish line, it's closed off.
Rym: So you just- Yep, the reddit was like, "Don't fucking go, like, all the
Rym: way!".
Scott: Right, so you're at Columbus Circle, and then they're like, "You can't do- that's the end of
Scott: you.".
Scott: So then I try to go home, and I get back to the bridge, and even the pedestrian part of the bridge is, like, closed.
Scott: And I ask the cops, I'm like, "Oh, can I just go over this fence and go
Scott: home?".
Scott: And they're like,
Scott: "No.".
Scott: And I'm like,
Scott: "Really?".
Scott: They're running over that part, I'm on this part.
Rym: They close it there every year for security reasons.
Scott: And I'm like, "The runners aren't gonna be here for, like, 45 minutes to an hour, right?
Scott: I won't even see the first place person.
Scott: I'll be over this bridge in, like, two
Scott: minutes.".
Rym: You're trying to negotiate with a New York cop.
Scott: I tried to negotiate with two different cops to let me over.
Scott: One was on First Avenue, and one was on that bridge.
Rym: You should have tried to legit bribe them.
Rym: That would probably have worked.
Scott: And one was on the bridge side.
Rym: You should have been like, "My friend Alexander
Rym: Hamilton.".
Scott: Anyway, so they didn't let me go over the fence, right?
Rym: I got a whole roll of George Washington.
Scott: So I had to get over this river.
Rym: The only way at that point was you could either take the F train, which sucks, or you could take the...
Scott: I could take a train under the river.
Scott: Right, so my choices were try to go up the east side path to see if I could get to Randall's Island using that bridge.
Rym: Which you could have, I think.
Scott: I think it would have worked.
Rym: So that's a loop I run on a regular basis.
Rym: I run over the Queensborough, up Manhattan, over the Randall's Island bridge, over the RFK, back home through Astoria.
Scott: I think that would have worked, maybe.
Rym: Because the marathon doesn't go over any of that.
Scott: But I ended up just taking the Skycar to Roosevelt Island.
Rym: And then that's an easy bike home.
Scott: Using the Roosevelt Island bridge, which totally worked.
Scott: And it's free because you just use your metro card to go on the Skycar.
Scott: But when I was on the Skycar, I think I saw people running on that east side path.
Rym: Oh, good call then.
Scott: I think it would have worked.
Scott: No, the marathon wasn't running.
Rym: Oh, okay, I thought you were like, "Oh, the marathon wouldn't have
Rym: worked.".
Scott: No, no, no, just regular people.
Scott: So it was open, is what I'm saying.
Scott: The path, I could have used the... Or the other option was pay for a ferry.
Scott: Oh, yeah, yeah.
Scott: Or go down to use the Williamsburg bridge.
Scott: But if I go over the Williamsburg bridge, what's going to happen on the other side?
Rym: You're going to get the Pulaski area.
Scott: I'm going to go over there and there's going to be a closed road.
Scott: And I can't go north.
Rym: You would have had to go way out, up, and back over in those weird areas that you occasionally bike into by accident.
Scott: So what is even the next bridge?
Scott: If I go north more, what is the next way to cross?
Scott: Like, go to Connecticut and use the Port Jefferson ferry?
Rym: I'll call an Uber and get it to drive you over the... I don't know.
Scott: I guess I could have put my bike in a car.
Scott: But no.
Rym: I was next to my apartment.
Rym: And also, I had gotten ahead of, because you got trapped behind that yelling woman.
Rym: And I finally got past her, and I didn't want to get caught by her again.
Scott: Yeah, they were a group of yelling people.
Rym: They were real excited about this.
Scott: They started yelling less later on.
Rym: Maybe they ran their voices out.
Scott: They got tired on the Queensborough bridge, I think, and took the yell out of them.
Rym: So I think it's obvious we were kind of stalling, because there's only one news today.
Rym: Possibly the darkest day in modern American history.
Scott: I don't know if it's the darkest day.
Rym: It's the most dangerous day.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: Well, listen.
Rym: What do you mean by modern history?
Rym: The Vietnam War is distant past for most people.
Scott: Here's what I'm saying, right?
Scott: We're at a point where people are somewhat legitimately worried about nuclear disaster soon.
Scott: The Cuban Missile Crisis was a thing.
Rym: It was.
Scott: So we're less than that.
Rym: But at the same time, when that happened, it was two extremely competent national leaders talking on the phone and dealing with it.
Rym: I'm just saying, the danger is probably similar, but different.
Rym: But similar actual magnitude in the end.
Scott: I watched Dr.
Scott: Strangelove yesterday because, and in Dr.
Scott: Strangelove, which is a comedy, the two national leaders, even though one of them is intoxicated, are more competent than many national leaders in the real world.
Rym: I mean, we're not going to dwell on it tonight, because I'm pretty sure, as much as all of us have been dealing with this, I don't think you really want to hear yet another podcast.
Rym: spend their entire show talking about it.
Scott: It's too soon, and it's not time yet.
Rym: But I'll say this.
Rym: The mood in New York City was real, real somber.
Scott: Imagine you see someone and they come to work the first day after their dog died.
Scott: Or someone in their family died.
Rym: I knew shit was up, because I went to work early.
Scott: Imagine if every single person in the city, except for that one guy driving his minivan in Astoria, raving his red hat at the window, and he's lucky that we're in a city and there aren't rocks on the ground.
Scott: Pretty much everybody was acting like someone in their family had just died.
Rym: And no one went to work.
Rym: I got a little early.
Rym: It was very, very uncrowded.
Rym: I got on the subway, and I sat down on the four train during the commute.
Scott: That is insane.
Scott: I could have sat down, but I don't sit down.
Rym: And I think what really struck me was.
Rym: I was sitting there, and there was a dude, just another white dude, obviously going to some sort of Wall Street looking job.
Rym: He kind of looked like I do, except he was wearing a suit.
Rym: And he's reading CNN on his tablet, and then he just starts crying.
Rym: He just puts his head down.
Rym: And I saw that playing out all over the place.
Rym: But then I get to work, and no one's there yet, except my boss.
Rym: And he's just sitting there staring at his computer.
Rym: And basically, it looked like he'd been there a while already, and no one talked.
Rym: Everyone just sat staring at the computers all day doing nothing.
Rym: No one really got any work done.
Scott: It was already well known in advance that there was going to be a catered lunch on that day.
Scott: And it was Thanksgiving food.
Scott: We had a turkey leg and yams and stuffing.
Scott: And we pretty much sat in the boardroom eating it quietly.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: The worst part, well not the worst part, but I remember on the night when it was actually all going down, we were doing our Overwatch thing.
Rym: We didn't really want to sit and just watch the whole stupid election.
Rym: So we were playing Overwatch in a big voice chat on Discord.
Rym: And bit by bit, as the news started getting more and more dire, at one point, Scojo was like, "I just can't pay attention to the game.
Rym: I gotta
Rym: go.".
Rym: And he just left, and then everyone just left.
Scott: I'm surprised he didn't even play the game.
Rym: Well, we were playing the game, and then it started looking dicey.
Rym: And I pretty much spent half the night looking at the internet.
Rym: And then I said, "Fuck it.
Rym: I can't deal with
Rym: this.".
Rym: And I just went to bed.
Scott: I went to bed also.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So yeah, we're not going to really dwell on it yet on the show, obviously.
Rym: But Scott's got some ideas.
Rym: I got some ideas.
Rym: And we're not going to take this sitting down.
Scott: Like I said, Rin, before the show, right?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: People are going to yell at me because I was quiet.
Scott: And I was like, "Shut
Scott: up.".
Scott: But the fact is, all you assholes, I was wrong about things that everyone else was wrong about, like what the result was going to be.
Scott: But I was right that you were just tweeting in the wind uselessly.
Scott: And your tweets didn't do shit.
Scott: And now, what are people doing?
Scott: They're still tweeting in the wind.
Scott: So you're eagle time.
Scott: Eagle time is over.
Scott: It is now the sanctuary time.
Scott: And we're going to do shit and not just fucking tweet in the wind.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: This is a video from Numberphile, which we link to occasionally, but I'm not going to...
Scott: Numberphile making all the things of the day.
Rym: I haven't linked to them in a while.
Scott: You know, I figured out, I stupidly didn't realize this before, but Numberphile and the periodic thing is like this one guy, Brady.
Scott: There's other channels, too.
Scott: I'm not sure if he does the Computerphile channel, which I don't watch.
Rym: It's a lot like the SciShow and Vlogbrothers.
Rym: They're all in an orbit of each other.
Scott: There's this one dude, Brady, and he's making these videos.
Scott: And the thing that really gets me about these videos is that he sounds like he's a person from the UK.
Scott: And I know that the periodic place that's college is in the UK, right?
Scott: But it seems like he's traveling around the world making these videos.
Rym: Scott, just saying, if the Patreon got to a high enough level, we'd both quit our jobs and our lives would be making shit like that all the time.
Scott: But I don't want to do that.
Scott: It seems like it's pretty crazy, this thing this guy's got going on.
Rym: But this video is pretty actually specifically interesting, and it talks about weird but fair dice.
Scott: Oh, I saw this one.
Rym: And you might think that a die has to be a regular, you know, like one of the regular three-dimensional shapes to be fair.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: And that is not true.
Rym: To be fair, a die merely needs to be symmetrical, and this video does an excellent job of making that abundantly clear, and I kind of want some dice like that just to start arguments at tables, at conventions.
Scott: It's good for an RPG, that kind of dice, right, where it's not gambling.
Rym: Well, for gambling, it should be fine, actually.
Scott: Yeah, well, you know.
Rym: Also, the funniest thing is he's rolling, what, like the D120, and he rolls a one twice in a row.
Scott: So anyway, you know, back in the day, I remember, especially in the college days, right, there was this period in my life, like when I was in middle school, high school, where like Japan seemed like this mystical place full of nerd magic, and very rarely did you actually learn anything about the nerd magic they had there.
Scott: Maybe like you'd get a video game magazine to be a picture of an arcade game they had there that you were just like, "Holy
Scott: shit.".
Rym: Yep, and it'd have a caption that just says like, "Gundam game in
Rym: Japan."
Rym: It doesn't tell you shit about it.
Scott: Or like you'd get an anime that was dubbed.
Scott: You'd be like, "Oh, glorious," right?
Scott: And then in college, it was like the Japan Fiesta.
Rym: It was like-- RIT that had this giant anime club.
Scott: But anyway, you know, we eventually, like even early in the GeekNights days, we were still like half my things of the day were funny things from Japanese TV, because we finally had internet and YouTube and things like that.
Scott: But eventually, the cool Japan magic never completely wears off, because Japan is still way cool in Nerd Paradise.
Scott: But eventually, you're like, "Okay, another cool thing from Japan.
Scott: All
Scott: right.".
Scott: But here's one that I saw recently.
Scott: that was pretty awesome.
Scott: And you know, it's too early for Christmas shit, but this is too awesome.
Scott: It breaks the rule.
Scott: It's a Coke bottle, poison I don't drink, from Japan.
Scott: And it's a Christmas-style one.
Scott: And I don't know why they only have this in Japan.
Scott: It's like they only, you know, they just hate us.
Rym: All right, I'm just watching this video to see what happens here.
Scott: Oh, you never saw the video?
Scott: Nope.
Rym: I never-- I did not see this.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: All right, so you see he's pulling-- What?
Rym: Oh, I see what's going on here.
Rym: That's good.
Scott: It's real good.
Rym: God damn it.
Rym: Why--.
Rym: This is why we can't have nice things.
Scott: Only, you know, the U.S.
Scott: just doesn't have nice things, and now we're going to have less nice things.
Rym: I mean, yeah.
Rym: Way to bring it back around.
Rym: Well, you know, speaking of nice things, when Emily and I were in Sydney, the one thing that's-- They didn't have that.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: And isn't their money worth nothing?
Rym: But they're doing okay now.
Rym: But the subway in Sydney, because you've been on the trams, like they were like okay in Melbourne.
Scott: It's much newer than ours.
Rym: The subway in Sydney not only has padded cloth seats-- The New York City subway used to.
Rym: Yeah, does not now.
Rym: No.
Rym: Because they would literally be full of poop.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Like they would be cut open, filled with poop, and smeared with poop.
Scott: Metro and art trains have them.
Rym: Not really.
Scott: Yeah, they're padded.
Rym: They're padded.
Rym: They're leather seats.
Rym: They're waterproof leather, and they're, you know, they're padded by the barest technical definition of padded.
Scott: I'm just saying.
Rym: These are thick, plush seats.
Rym: Like if you spilled something into them, it's gone.
Scott: Like first class airplane?
Rym: Yeah, like I could pee into one of those things for days before it started coming out.
Rym: Like you could pee.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So yeah, we could not have that here.
Scott: No.
Rym: In a moment, the Book Club book is Rebecca.
Rym: Rebecca.
Rym: I'm going to read it because I finished all those other books I was working on.
Rym: They're pretty good and all that stuff.
Scott: I'm going to read it because my queue is really open right now.
Rym: You know what I'm going to read right after I finish Rebecca because I've read excerpts from it, but I feel remiss that I've never actually read Fear and Loathing on the Campaign Trail.
Scott: Oh, that one?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And I feel like I missed that man, so I'm going to read that.
Rym: Otherwise, one great thing, GamerX East is this weekend.
Scott: G-A-Y-M-E-R-X.
Rym: It is unfortunately, as of today, if you're not already going, too late to get badges.
Scott: It's sold out.
Scott: Is it sold out or is it just too late?
Rym: It's too late.
Rym: I think it might also be sold out.
Rym: I'm not sure.
Scott: So you can't get them at the door.
Rym: Oh, you might be able to get them until midnight tonight.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: It's because it's in a secure building, so there's a list you have to be on.
Scott: Oh, it's one of those.
Scott: Actually, where is it?
Scott: It's in the Microsoft space.
Scott: Oh, right near the Muji store?
Rym: I think so.
Rym: I think it's that one.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: It's like right there.
Scott: I thought it was in a real space, so it's not going to be as big as I thought.
Rym: No, it's small, but it's sort of like an outreach thing.
Rym: I feel like it's good timing that we're going to this.
Scott: I feel like a lot of people -- No, I mean, I can play games all day.
Scott: Are you going to go there as soon as it starts Saturday?
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: Maybe we should probably just go there as soon as it starts, and we can always leave early and get food.
Scott: Yeah, just going to bring games with me, right?
Rym: Yeah, I'm going to bring a small but choice collection of tabletop games.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And someday we're going to be giving a talk -- I'll bring some RPG.
Rym: We're going to be doing our writing game rules panel, but if you already knew who we are, if you're already listening to this, tell other people to go to our panel, but don't you fucking go to it, because it's a small room, and I'd rather people who don't know who we are -- How small
Scott: am I?
Scott: - why am I doing this thing if the room is so small?
Rym: Because I got to get the word out.
Rym: I mean, even at PAX, where like I think 80% of the people who go to our panels go to them only because they know it's not doing them, there's always at least one person who's like, "Who the fuck are these guys?
Rym: Why are all these people weirdly excited about them, and can I get my money back for my
Rym: badge?".
Rym: And the only other silver line -- oh, yeah, so my thing of the day was the dice thing, where I did the meta -- I'm distracted, obviously.
Scott: You're in the meta moment right now.
Rym: Any other meta other than follow our YouTube channels, follow the other stuff we might be doing, and stay strong.
Rym: I can't believe we didn't do a show on this.
Scott: I also don't believe that.
Rym: Scott legit did not believe me and spent a while trying to prove me wrong when I said we've never done a show on wallets, and I do not fault him for that because I would not have believed me.
Rym: But I was literally -- when Thursday shows come around, you'll know what our process is for figuring out the show.
Rym: Scott's at work, and I'm at work, and I'm sitting at my desk, and I literally look around the room and start typing nouns that I see into the chat, and then Scott one by one says, "Those are all terrible ideas for
Rym: shows.".
Rym: And my wallet happened to be on my desk, and I was like, "Wallets?
Rym: I don't think we've done a show on
Rym: wallets.".
Rym: In fact, I couldn't even find a show on The Jimmy.
Rym: And I remember we talked about The Jimmy so much that the company that made The Jimmy actually found us and gave us free Jimmys.
Rym: Remember that?
Rym: That was a long time ago.
Rym: So the Jimmy wallet, of course, is gone.
Rym: That company, as far as I can tell, is gone.
Rym: And I guess we're talking about wallets.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So big wallet or small wallet?
Scott: I mean, when I was originally getting wallets, right, this was back in the day before there was even real internet or internet shopping or anything.
Scott: So my idea of a wallet was the only kind of wallet I'd ever seen in my life, which was a wallet that folds in the middle, has a place to put money, and then a bunch of card slots and even a photo thingy.
Scott: I felt like I had to get photos and put them in, right, because it comes with the stupid photo thing.
Scott: That's the only image I ever had of a wallet in my mind.
Scott: So when I needed one, I went to the department store, like Macy's or whatever.
Scott: And there's that rack of -- They had a whole bunch of them.
Rym: Black and brown leather men's bi-fold or tri-fold wallets.
Scott: Yeah, and I would buy a bi-fold one that -- I always did the tri-fold.
Scott: The most, you know, normal-looking-ish -- Oh, the ones that has the extra up-flip.
Rym: Yep, it goes buh-bup.
Rym: So you open it halfway, and you can get, like, your cards out.
Scott: Yeah, I think I got that kind of one.
Rym: And then you open it all the way, and the ID is sitting there, because when you're, like, that's the age where you actually have to show an ID a lot for stuff.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Just in general, like, bus passes or whatever, because you're a kid.
Rym: And you use your driver's license, and you're excited about having a driver's license.
Scott: And so I just -- I had that kind of wallet.
Scott: always until, like, even in college, I had that kind of wallet, and I would lose it.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: I only ever lost my wallet once in my entire life.
Scott: I've lost it two times.
Rym: And, actually, I lost it.
Rym: I canceled all my cards and, like, did all the stuff.
Rym: This was in high school, ninth grade.
Rym: And then, literally, like, four days later, a friend of mine in high school was like, "Oh, by the way, I found your wallet in the woods
Rym: here.".
Rym: Literally found it in the woods.
Scott: I think -- I lost two.
Scott: One, I was in Israel, and I had -- I think I put it in a bathing suit pocket.
Rym: That's dangerous.
Scott: No, I wasn't -- this was, like, after --.
Rym: Oh, I know, I know.
Rym: I'm just saying, the danger of the bathing suit pocket is, one, those pockets suck, and it's really easy to fall out, and, two, you might forget it's there and go back in the water.
Scott: No.
Scott: This was not at a water -- I had it, and we were already back at the temporary hoe hostel.
Rym: Okay, okay.
Scott: And I took a shower, and the bathing suit was, like, on the floor or hanging with the wallet in it while I was showering.
Scott: It was a one-person bathroom.
Scott: It wasn't, like, some -- Oh, did someone take the wallet?
Scott: I don't know, but, like, that's where I remembered it being, and the next time I went for it, it knew there.
Rym: Oh.
Scott: And this next time that I lost a wallet was at RIT, and I'm pretty sure I left it on the DDR machine at the Putt-Putt.
Rym: I remember that.
Scott: And then it was not there.
Rym: Because we drove back over there.
Scott: Which is why my anime club membership cards only go so far back.
Scott: They don't go any farther back than that, and since then, I have not lost a wallet.
Scott: I've only replaced highly damaged wallets and such.
Rym: So I had this weird point of pride where I had this trifold wallet, and I always got the simplest, smooth, black leather one.
Rym: Like, never any other color, never any adornment of any kind.
Scott: I would get the simplest, smoothest, brown leather one.
Rym: Before I had credit cards, I had all this shit that I kept in my wallet, and then thinking back -- I also kept a bunch of shit in there.
Rym: Like, I can't picture individually what all those things were, but I remember there being all these different cards in there.
Scott: Basically, there's a whole -- I know what the cards are, because I now keep those cards in the drawer of my desk.
Rym: Oh, you know where I keep mine?
Rym: I have my old Jimmy wallet that's broken.
Scott: Oh, you put it in there?
Rym: All my extra, like, second-tier shit is in that backup wallet.
Scott: So things that I would keep in old wallets that I no longer keep are things like photos, right?
Scott: No one does that anymore.
Rym: I used to carry my Social Security card around for some reason, because I was just stupid, so now that's in a vault.
Scott: I've never kept that in -- I keep that in my house.
Rym: Well, my wallet -- I don't lose my wallet, so...
Scott: Yeah, but even so, right?
Scott: There's no reason to carry it around.
Rym: Not anymore.
Scott: I would keep -- for example, like, I'd get a rewards card somewhere, and then I'd actually -- like, I had a media -- My Funko Land card.
Scott: For example, like, a media play card, which we used to have, right?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: And I would just always have it with me.
Scott: It's like, but now I have --.
Scott: the only rewards card I really have now is, like, the Rite Aid card.
Rym: I just got my phone number in.
Scott: Well, I actually got a -- I give them, like, a fake deal, right?
Scott: So it's not --.
Rym: Well, when I say my phone number, I mean 867-5309, which totally works.
Scott: Oh, I didn't give them -- I gave them -- I don't remember the fake number I gave them.
Rym: I just put in -- I literally put in 212-867-5309 every time, and it totally works.
Scott: Oh, no, that song is 364-5789.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So, yeah, I don't remember the number I gave them.
Scott: So, like -- but that card, I don't carry around with me everywhere.
Scott: I just leave it in my drawer, and if I'm going to Rite Aid, I bring it with me.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: I wish I could just use my phone to do it.
Rym: I don't need the stupid -- So, a card I had -- the thing is, in the old days, like, if you didn't have your card, like, you were fine.
Scott: Like, you needed the card to get the thing, but now -- Well, at least when I was in Connecticut, there was some kind of law where they couldn't make you have the card.
Scott: Ooh.
Scott: You could just -- I don't know if that's still true or -- I don't know.
Rym: Because, like, I have the REI card.
Scott: Someone out there, tell me.
Rym: Because the REI thing is actually, like, if you're a sports person, is a really good deal.
Scott: But isn't REI, in general, a rip-off?
Scott: You could just buy from Amazon and probably save just as much money.
Rym: Nah.
Rym: Depends on what you're buying.
Rym: Like, if I'm getting ski boots that I need to try on in person, and then I'm getting form-fitted to my foot, if I'm getting clothes that I need to try on because they're highly specialized, and, actually, their prices are really good.
Rym: You're thinking of, like, generic sportsy stuff.
Rym: I'm talking, like, specific specialized gear, like bindings for skis and shit.
Scott: Yeah, I don't buy that.
Rym: But, anyway, the way it works is you pay some trivial amount of money, and you remember if they're, like, co-op -- We don't need any REI advertising.
Scott: Talk about wallets.
Rym: I know, but anyway, the card's really good, and it's saved me a crazy shit ton of money.
Scott: But you don't carry it with you all the time.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: I don't -- You know where that is?
Rym: It's sitting in my Jimmy wallet, because if I go to the store, they're just like, "What's your
Rym: name?".
Rym: And then they look me up, and it's all good.
Scott: So, now, since the Jimmy times, I don't use a Jimmy anymore.
Scott: I usually go on Kickstarter and find some tiny wallet, like the tiniest, slimmest wallet I can find.
Rym: That is what I have done.
Rym: I have bought so many Kickstarter wallets, and they've all been great.
Rym: Then they wore out, and then there's no way to get another one.
Scott: I go on Kickstarter and find another tiny wallet.
Scott: So the one I have right now is August brand.
Rym: I don't know what mine is called.
Scott: It's like the month.
Scott: And basically, what it is, is on both sides, there's, like, a little sort of, like, pouch almost.
Scott: And on one side is my MetroCard, and then the other side is some cash that's folded up.
Scott: And then in the middle, there's a little thing you can pull, and you pull it, and all the cards come out.
Rym: I have the slim wallet.
Rym: It's just called the slim wallet.
Scott: Yours looks very similar in mechanism to mine with the boop.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Boop.
Scott: But yours only has a pouch on one side.
Scott: Mine -- Yours has a clip on one side.
Rym: It has a pouch on one side and a money clip on the other side.
Scott: Mine has a pouch and a pouch.
Rym: And the money clip is carbon fiber.
Rym: I can fit, like, 400 bucks in here if I need to.
Scott: Yeah, that actually might be slightly better than mine.
Scott: No, you know why it's better?
Scott: You know why it's better?
Scott: I have to fold the money.
Scott: You don't.
Scott: I don't have to fold it.
Scott: And I think yours can hold more money.
Rym: Like I said, you can fit 400 bucks in this thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And that's right behind the money, is where I put the key to get into a hotel room.
Rym: so I can boop, boop, because all the rest of this thing is RFID blocking.
Scott: So here's the cards I have in the wallet.
Rym: Oh, yeah, let's go through it.
Rym: I got a credit card.
Rym: I have the main credit card.
Scott: The ATM card.
Rym: Backup credit card.
Scott: The backup credit card is in my dress drawer.
Rym: I have ATM card.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Metro card.
Scott: Metro card is in the pouch-y part.
Rym: It's in the pouch-y part.
Rym: Healthcare card.
Scott: Yep, I got that.
Rym: Which covers dental and medical.
Scott: For dental, I need the separate flimsy piece of paper, but I have both of those cards, basically.
Rym: Old by multiple generations.
Rym: New York State driver's license.
Scott: Yeah, I also have driver's license.
Scott: And the picture on it, I have hair.
Rym: Wow, yours is newer.
Rym: Look how fucking beat up an old mine is.
Scott: When does yours expire?
Scott: yet?
Rym: Mine expires next year, actually.
Scott: Mine expires in 2018.
Scott: So two years.
Rym: And then I have business credit card, because I use it actually a lot.
Scott: I have the laundry card.
Scott: Oh, I just used quarters.
Scott: I used to keep the laundry card.
Rym: Oh, and I have second Metro card.
Rym: This is the cash card.
Rym: I only use one of mine.
Scott: My second Metro card's in my messenger bag.
Rym: My second Metro card, I just keep it with me.
Scott: I only use it for AirTrain.
Rym: AirTrain, occasionally Path.
Scott: I don't take the Path.
Rym: I occasionally do, because I have business in Jersey.
Scott: I'm not going there.
Scott: I got the laundry card, and I was keeping the laundry card out of the wallet, but then I lost the laundry card, so in the wallet it doesn't get lost.
Scott: Yeah, that makes sense.
Scott: And then I have two RFID door opening cards.
Scott: One opens the entrance to the office building, and one opens our office.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: So I can get into the office building at night after it closes and the doormat is not there anymore.
Rym: Oh, and I have $45 in cash.
Scott: Oh, how much can I -- Just right now.
Rym: That's just what happens to be in here.
Scott: I have 20, 40, 60, 80.
Rym: Because you don't keep the ones in that wallet.
Scott: I have $80, and then all the ones are in my messenger bag.
Rym: See, I can actually -- I put the ones in here.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: Does that prevent the one problem from building up?
Rym: Because I actually use them, like, regularly.
Rym: I don't have a why.
Scott: But the thing is, having the fistful of ones can actually be useful at certain times.
Rym: I use it at, like, if I -- If we go out to have dinner with friends.
Scott: If I go to a cash-only place.
Rym: Yeah, I increasingly try to boycott cash-only places.
Scott: One time, I was buying some -- just, like, two slices of pizza, right?
Scott: And it was, like, $3.50 or something.
Rym: So I bring out -- Well, downtown, the place I get pizza at, it's $7.45 to get two slices of pizza.
Scott: This is in Astoria.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: At the Chubby's Garbage Place under my -- Oh, okay, okay, okay.
Scott: And I pull out my fistful of ones, and the guy's, like -- the guy sees my ones, and I couldn't understand what he was saying at first, but he wanted my ones.
Scott: So I counted him 20 ones, and he gave me a 20.
Scott: And I was like, "All
Scott: right.".
Scott: Because he's like, "He needed the ones.
Scott: He was a
Scott: store.".
Scott: So the other thing you can do with the pile of ones is go to an ATM and shove them in.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So you can be like -- Maybe you got 70 ones.
Scott: You shove them in there, and then you withdraw 50 bucks, and it's like, "Hey, I just increased my checking account.
Scott: Great.".
Rym: Oh, so the other benefit of this one is that the money clip has this little ridge sticking out of it.
Scott: I see that.
Rym: And what that's for is to -- That actually looks not good.
Rym: No, so I thought that when I first came, I was like, "Oh, this is going to be a
Rym: problem.".
Rym: If you put it with the ridge face in your butt, you literally don't feel it.
Scott: Oh, so you put the wallet in the back pocket.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I put it in the front pocket.
Rym: I've never -- front pocket wallet is garbage tier.
Scott: Front -- What I do -- Rear wallet, first of all, you're sitting on something.
Rym: It's poking you in the butt.
Scott: You're also unbalancing your ass.
Scott: Is one ass cheek smaller than the other?
Scott: You put it on the small cheek?
Rym: Look where it sits.
Rym: It's so small and so slim that it sits to the left of the butt bone.
Scott: You sit on the edge of your chair like that?
Scott: No, even here.
Rym: My butt's not on it.
Rym: Look.
Rym: See the outline of the wallet?
Scott: I see where you put it, and I guess that's true.
Rym: All my jeans are like that.
Rym: By design, I don't wear pants where the back pocket wallet doesn't work.
Scott: But I put it in the front right pocket.
Scott: What do you put in your front right pocket?
Rym: Front right pocket is phone.
Rym: Front left pocket is keys.
Rym: Right now, back --.
Scott: Oh, see, front right pocket is wallet.
Scott: Front left pocket is phone.
Rym: Where do you put your keys?
Scott: Keys somewhere else.
Rym: Ah, no, because I don't carry my bag.
Rym: I carry my bag all the time.
Scott: Well, if I have to take my keys out of my bag, I put them in with the wallet or in a coat pocket, if I'm wearing a coat, or -- I don't like having anything -- Oh, and the key pocket is where any extraneous change goes.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Because I don't want that banging around against my phone.
Scott: Yeah, never put anything metal in the phone pocket.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: That is an egregious offense.
Scott: My boss, he's like, "My phone's all scratched
Scott: up.".
Scott: And I'm like, "Do you put your keys in with your
Scott: phone?".
Scott: And he's like,
Scott: "Yeah.".
Scott: And I'm like, "Duh.
Scott: Don't put anything in with your phone pocket except your
Scott: phone.".
Rym: It's like my face hurts.
Rym: Do you keep scraping it with sandpaper?
Scott: Oh, that must be it.
Rym: But anyway, the ridge does not cause any bother at all, no matter what direction it's facing, but it means you can stick your finger in and very easily pull the wallet out of even, tight pants.
Scott: Ah, easy for the pickpocket to pull it out of your pants.
Rym: Ah, because I wear such tight pants.
Rym: I've actually thought about that a lot.
Rym: So when I'm on the subway, if I'm wearing pants where someone could conceivably get my wallet out pickpocket style, I move it to the front left pocket with the keys until I'm off the subway.
Scott: I've thought about getting an ostentatious fake rear pocket wallet.
Rym: Ooh, it's just full of like explosions.
Scott: Yeah, full of like, you know.
Rym: Skunk juice.
Scott: Contact poison.
Rym: Ampules of skunk juice.
Scott: Just whatever, right?
Scott: Because I mean, it's not really a concern in New York.
Scott: Despite New York being a huge city, it's probably in terms of like, it's not saying there's no pickpocketing in New York City, but pickpocketing per person in New York City is probably the lowest of any major city.
Scott: Like the stories I hear, never having been there, is that like Paris is like pickpocket central, right?
Scott: And I've never heard anyone, like when I've said that, maybe, you know, when I've, uh, when I've propagated that rumor, people have not said, that's just a stereotype.
Scott: It's not true.
Scott: They've said, oh, they said, yes, very true.
Scott: Watch out when you're right.
Scott: So, um, so like I imagined I would use it if I was traveling in such a place.
Rym: So I like this wallet a lot, but I liked the wallet I had before better.
Rym: It was even more minimalist.
Rym: It was just this like metal wire with some leather around it.
Rym: And I held all my cards in the middle so I could flip them up with my thumb.
Rym: And the rest of the wire on the back was a money clip.
Rym: And it was seriously like four millimeters thinner than even this thing.
Rym: And this thing is real fucking thin.
Rym: But it eventually wore out and it was a Kickstarter project.
Rym: So I can't get it again.
Scott: The one I have now is slightly wearing out.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So before this, I used the Jimmy X.
Scott: Me too.
Rym: Which back then, like there wasn't a Kickstarter.
Rym: The Jimmy was literally the only like modern wallet on earth as far as I could tell.
Rym: And right when Kickstarter started, there were like 40 different wallet projects.
Rym: They were all kind of garbage.
Rym: Uh, so I used that trifold for the longest time, but when I switched out of it was when we got the Jimmy, because the trifold is actually inferior to the bifold, but my dumb kid brain didn't realize at the time, because it makes it substantially thicker in your pocket unless you don't carry any cash ever.
Rym: And a thick wallet is not a thing I can deal with.
Rym: I don't understand the people of the wallet where you open it.
Rym: And then inside there's like more divisions in the top so you can like separate different kinds of bills.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Or the people who have the full on bill fold that has like all the cards arrayed in this like deck.
Scott: I mean, back in the day, right?
Scott: It was the best because like, well, you had a million cards.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, no, even more.
Scott: back in the day, like my grandfather, he would like, he owned the mechanic and he was a mechanic and no fucking credit cards, right?
Scott: It's like he just had a cash clip and that was it.
Scott: Money, money, money, just cash, tons of it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that's what we carry around.
Scott: That was it.
Scott: Nothing else.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, but I'm pretty much all I want now is super minimal.
Rym: And maybe seven years ago, I wouldn't have considered this a concern, but you probably should get a wallet that blocks RFID in the modern era.
Scott: There are multiple, I mean, there's no negative to having it.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And there are multiple demonstrated proofs of concept of doing such shit as taking a contact, like basically a point of sale system and just walking up behind someone and charging their credit card through their pocket.
Rym: Like you can totally do that.
Rym: So, yeah, I feel like that is worth it.
Rym: I don't know what else we can say.
Scott: I mean, I'm looking at the currently available wallets on Kickstarter and it's like there's so many of them and some of them are serviceable and some of them are right out.
Rym: You can just buy, because you know who makes the Slim Wallet?
Rym: The same people who make that Trackline belt that we have.
Rym: The thing is, like even some of these buyfolds.
Rym: Look, all they make is that belt, that wallet.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Even some of these buyfold ones I'm seeing on Kickstarter are like actually probably usable because they're so slim, even though they're fold.
Rym: True.
Scott: Right?
Scott: It's like as long as you don't put a fucking shit ton of money in there.
Scott: I could probably deal with one of those, right?
Scott: So, you know, this one is slowly wearing out, like a string came off of it the other day.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: So, you know, when it wears out, we'll see what I go for.
Scott: I might try one of these ones that's made of metal or really, I mean, you can get by with like a rubber band.
Scott: I also have coworkers that use like that Invincible Wallet.
Scott: that's basically just like a folded up piece of Tyvek.
Rym: Oh, I've seen that.
Rym: That thing's actually moderately cool.
Scott: Yeah, it's like it's just a normal buyfold wallet, but it's like basically invincible.
Rym: You know what that's good for?
Rym: I know some people who use that, like if they're going on like extreme sports stuff and they bring a wallet with them, they use that instead of their regular wallet to not get the regular wallet all stanky.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's...
Rym: Leather wallets eventually smell like ass.
Rym: Like that eventually happens unless you don't sweat.
Rym: It's leather.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But I hope you don't sweat so much that it goes through your pants and into your wallet.
Scott: That'd be weird.
Rym: Sometimes it's just hot out and I'm wearing shorts and I'm sitting next to my wallet like, eh.
Scott: That doesn't happen.
Rym: But so do you do the thing?
Rym: When I travel to certain kinds of events or like certain kinds of things I'll do, I will basically go to the Minimal Wallet where I will, because I have another crapo wallet and I'll bring like less stuff with me.
Rym: Like I bring a different wallet configuration.
Scott: The only time I do that is in a water situation.
Scott: If I go to the water park...
Rym: I bring the jimmy, the old jimmy.
Scott: I can use the jimmy, but what I used to do before the jimmy days at the water park is I had this plastic tube on a string.
Rym: I remember that tube.
Scott: And I would open the plastic tube on a string.
Rym: I remember specifically you having that tube when we were at RIT.
Scott: And I would shove money in the plastic tube on a string and then you screw it tight and you wear it around your neck.
Scott: And now you can ride a water slide with money on you and you can get off the water slide and buy a hot dog, eat the hot dog, not have to put their wallet in the not very secure locker at the water park.
Scott: And also you put the key to the not very secure locker at the water park in the plastic tube and all your stuff is in the locker.
Scott: You know, it's also good at the beach if you don't want to leave your wallet on the sand.
Scott: You can just leave your towel on the sand and bring your monies with you so that you can buy ice cream or a fudgy wudgy without having to leave your money in an unsafe position unattended.
Rym: Now what I don't understand are the people who use the wallet.
Rym: that is also a cell phone case.
Scott: I can go for that.
Rym: I mean it's too big to put in any reasonable pocket.
Rym: It seems like most people who do that carry a purse or a bag of some kind.
Scott: If I found, you know, if it accommodated the thing is I don't want a case on my phone.
Scott: In general.
Scott: You know, I could save a whole pocket doing that.
Scott: I see the appeal.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time, the problem is if I lose my wallet between Android Pay and all the capabilities of a modern smartphone I could get home.
Rym: I could deal with shit.
Rym: And if I lose my phone, my wallet guarantees that I can at least make it back to my house.
Rym: If I lose both, what the fuck am I going to do?
Scott: But here's one, that's true, but here's the thing.
Scott: You could use Find My iPhone to find your wallet.
Rym: Yeah, I guess you could.
Scott: However, the major problem is if I'm sitting there using my phone I've got all these credit cards just hanging out.
Scott: That's not a good situation.
Rym: Like on the way home today, right?
Scott: I'm just showing all my cash is sticking out.
Rym: Today I was reading Squirrel Girl, but yesterday I was reading this Wikipedia article on the way home.
Rym: So, I'll just hold all my money flimsily in my hand just right there in the middle of the subway.
Scott: Keep that shit away.
Rym: So yeah, wallets.
Scott: I can't believe we didn't do a wallet share.
Rym: I know.
Rym: I feel like that was actually Such a low hanging fruit.
Rym: I got us by another Thursday.
Rym: So yeah, stay tuned.
Rym: GeekNights is continuing as normal.
Rym: Come see us at GamerX.
Rym: And you only seed so much ground to fascists before you start to do the things that need to be done to prevent fascists from doing what they want to do.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon Patrons in order of them I'm going to give us on a continuing basis are... Christian Kuntz, Han Thomas, and Rymer Chris.
Rym: Shervin Von Horl, Iggy Kid, Rare Lavelle, James David White, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, Irish Wristwatch, Erin Cerise, Brian Fisher, Sailor Vista, Jai Fried Pork, Matthew Smith, Don Schleich, Jar Toppeshen, Jojo Joestar, Tyler Eller, Sean Yeager, Sam Cordray, Clinton Walton, Wren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Brian Sidroni, Finn Eric Silverrod, Kirsch Rimmer, and Turnish Hearn.
Rym: Chris Minkev, Chris Knox, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Rymer, and Thomas Han.
Rym: Keep your heads up, take a small step forward every day, and we'll get through this.
Rym: And now I leave you with something.
Media: We don't want to hate and despise one another.
Media: In this world there's room for everyone and the good earth is rich and can provide for everyone.
Media: The way of life can be free and beautiful, but we have lost the way.
Media: Greed has poisoned men's souls, has barricaded the world with hate, has goose-stepped us into misery and bloodshed.
Media: We have developed speed, but we have shut ourselves in.
Media: Machinery that gives abundance has left us in want.
Media: Our knowledge has made us cynical, our cleverness hard and unkind.
Media: We think too much and feel too little.
Media: More than machinery, we need humanity.
Media: More than cleverness, we need kindness and gentleness.
Media: Without these qualities, life will be violent and all will be lost.
Media: The airplane and the radio have brought us closer together.
Media: The very nature of these inventions cries out for the goodness in men, cries out for universal brotherhood, for the unity of us all.
Media: Even now, my voice is reaching millions throughout the world, millions of despairing men, women and little children, victims of a system that makes men torture and imprison innocent people.
Media: To those who can hear me, I say, do not despair.
Media: The misery that is now upon us is but the passing of greed, the bitterness of men who fear the way of human progress.
Media: The hate of men will pass and dictators die, and the power they took from the people will return to the people.
Media: And so long as men die, liberty will never perish.
Media: Soldiers, don't give yourselves to brutes, men who despise you, enslave you, who regiment your lives, tell you what to do, what to think and what to feel, who drill you, diet you, treat you like cattle, use you as cannon fodder.
Media: Don't give yourselves to these unnatural men, machine men with machine minds and machine hearts.
Media: You are not machines.
Media: You are not cattle.
Media: You are men.
Media: You have the love of humanity in your hearts.
Media: You don't hate.
Media: Only the unloved hate, the unloved and the unnatural.
Media: Soldiers, don't fight for slavery.
Media: Fight for liberty.
Media: In the seventeenth chapter of Saint Luke, it is written, "The kingdom of God is within man, not one man, nor a group of men, but in all men, in you.
Media: You, the people, have the power, the power to create machines, the power to create happiness.
Media: You, the people, have the power to make this life free and beautiful, to make this life a wonderful adventure.
Media: Then, in the name of democracy, let us use that power.
Media: Let us all unite.
Media: Let us fight for a new world, a decent world that will give men a chance to work, that will give youth a future and old age a security.
Media: By the promise of these things, brutes have risen to power, but they lie.
Media: They do not fulfill that promise.
Media: They never will dictate us free themselves, but they enslave the people.
Rym: Now, let us fight to fulfill that promise.
Media: Let us fight to free the world, to do away with national barriers, to do away with greed, with hate and intolerance.
Media: Let us fight for a world of reason, a world where science and progress will lead to all men's happiness.
Media: Soldiers, in the name of democracy, let us all unite!