Rym: It's Tuesday August 31st 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We're talking about death matches usually associated with boomer shooters.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So yeah this past weekend Went on another long bike ride.
Rym: So for the second time I have biked all the way to Poughkeepsie from New York and took a Metro North home.
Rym: that's a real fun ride, but Doing it a second time.
Rym: just having biked a lot and exercised a lot over this over the summer so far and all of last Summer we did it way faster than last time And we literally only stopped once on the entire hundred mile ride.
Rym: to eat lunch didn't stop at any point.
Scott: otherwise I mean if you're eating a whole lunch, that's that this.
Scott: that's a pretty you know.
Rym: yeah, and You know got the camera when you do.
Scott: you know you do 100 miles.
Scott: You know if you have the rest stops on an organized ride You're stopping at the rest stops for like a few minutes and eating some just bars or waffles.
Rym: It's like when I would land in the Harlan Valley railroad.
Rym: I'd land in one of those rest stops.
Rym: I basically walk over just shove cheese balls and crackers.
Scott: Yeah one long stop.
Scott: that's like sitting down and eating food that is equal to several You know and as long as you refill your water.
Scott: It's all good.
Rym: Yeah but especially because and this is a thing that I've thought about more lately because More in terms of running, but biking it also applies, but I realize a lot of people don't realize this More.
Rym: for most people when you do some sort of physical activity, and you're tired if you take a rest You'll be re-energized or perform better after that rest.
Rym: but if you're Skilled capable fit enough like you've trained hard and done a sport long enough Especially sports that rely on aerobics and you get to the point to where you're operating below your your anaerobic threshold Then the primary limiting factors on things like time distance like doing more with the sport are more around caloric intake injury Joints pain like things that are not resolved by the amount of rest you could do during the activity.
Rym: So like on our head when I run a half marathon if I stop for 10 minutes I won't be faster after those 10 minutes.
Rym: It just means it'll take me 10 minutes longer to do the exact same run.
Rym: Like resting does not know.
Scott: it all depends.
Scott: it depends, you know, there's always gonna be just like with your computer There's some sort of bottleneck.
Rym: Yeah, what's the bottleneck?
Scott: You know some people they go biking really far and it's like their legs give up for some people the lung.
Rym: some people It's your but like you have the butt sore.
Scott: Yeah, but hurts your butt hurts too much.
Scott: They got a stat, right?
Scott: There's always something that is the thing that makes you have to stop right?
Scott: It could.
Scott: it doesn't have to be some body thing either.
Scott: It could be like, you know a fly got in your eyeball or time out of water time.
Rym: Like even if I feel like I could keep going these bike trails close at dusk and it's now Exactly.
Rym: I've already biked 100 miles.
Rym: There's nowhere else I can bike.
Rym: but so we get to.
Rym: we bike up to the Kipsy hundred-ish miles and We're gonna bike over that special pedestrian bridge like the bike path bridge.
Scott: the path goes right onto it.
Rym: Yeah to get to the middle of it and like that's where we'd stop the ride.
Rym: It was closed to the public on Sunday.
Rym: Okay for a private event that you had to buy tickets for.
Scott: well, it's I don't think it's a public Thing.
Rym: it normally is.
Rym: so basically there is a bike.
Scott: I mean, it's open to the public but I don't know if it's owned by the state?
Scott: of this I don't know.
Rym: I think it's owned by the state because it was built as part of that Empire project.
Scott: Well, I mean, I guess you're allowed to like you could.
Rym: I guess the what bothers me is faces.
Rym: I didn't realize this could be closed.
Rym: and what bothers me?
Rym: so we get there and there's other Bikers who needed to get over it to finish a ride and it was just closed to them.
Scott: I didn't need to get.
Scott: home is on.
Scott: their home was on the other side.
Rym: Yeah, they were planning long rides.
Rym: We actually met a guy who runs one of the like one of the bike activist Organizations that was instrumental in getting that thing built in the first place.
Rym: He was there.
Rym: He actually took a photo of us and talked to us.
Rym: He was talking to all the bikers who got fucked over by the fact that this thing was closed.
Rym: and the big part was if You live far enough away There's no way you'd know some random part of this bike route is just closed to you Especially a bridge where there aren't other good ways over that bridge like this aren't good ways over the Hudson for a bike up there.
Scott: So I could bike over the normal Poughkeepsie bridge.
Scott: right the can you bike over that thing?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: You can bike over the new bird.
Rym: I know you can bike over the new brick beacon bridge.
Rym: I've done it, but I don't know if you can bike over that Poughkeepsie one.
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: I never tried.
Rym: Yeah But so it was surprising that it was just closed and there was this private event you had to buy tickets for and there are cops Everywhere and it was a whole thing.
Rym: But otherwise, it was a pretty good bike ride.
Rym: I feel like if we do it again, we could do it.
Scott: I'd be like look I don't want to go to your private event.
Scott: I just want to go to the other side.
Scott: I'm not gonna help.
Rym: they specifically had signs.
Rym: no bikes even allowed on the bridge couldn't even walk him over.
Scott: I just I'd be like hey if you bought a ticket I go and fight with them.
Rym: Yeah, so there's no one sneak across.
Scott: I'd be like deal with it.
Rym: Yeah, so I'm actually gonna complain to the state.
Rym: my argument.
Scott: You're keeping me from going home.
Scott: I can't get home.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: My argument would be this this bridge is a part of the infrastructure.
Rym: now like a freeway.
Rym: You can't just close a freeway You have to have a valid like approved detour because people rely on it like the Queensborough Bridge here the bike path.
Rym: They can't just close that bike path.
Rym: It's open 24/7.
Rym: They literally run bus.
Scott: Well, they closed it sometimes but the problem is well when they close it they provide they always alternatives.
Scott: You can take the subway.
Rym: No, no, no It's not they net.
Rym: when they close the Queensborough bridge bike path the city is buses categorically provides a bus that will pick people up on either end with their bikes because bike that bridge is a Critical piece of the bike infrastructure.
Rym: They're not allowed to close it.
Scott: I've never seen them have a bus where they let people your bike Scott the fuck you talking about.
Rym: We talked about this on GeekNights multiple times.
Rym: Remember when they were doing all that construction.
Rym: They wrote that bus has shown up many times over the years.
Scott: There's a there's frequently alternative shuttle buses for things.
Scott: I've never seen any bus that there's only like a couple pictures of it.
Rym: We talked about it on GeekNights because you asked me what was going on when you see if this happens again.
Scott: But I've never seen it happen.
Rym: They literally had a stop with a line and a queue and in front of like around the corner by our apartment.
Rym: Everyone who was trying to get over that bridge on a bike or a pedestrian Would queue up and the bus would come back and the trailer car would come back.
Rym: They load all the bikes into a trailer They put all the people on the bus and they drove it over the bridge dropped you off and let you pick up your bikes.
Rym: And they ran that overnight from like midnight to 6 a.m.
Rym: Every day that that pedestrian path was closed because they can't close it.
Rym: They're not allowed to.
Rym: Anyway, how do you not remember this?
Rym: We talked about this at length on GeekNights multiple times.
Scott: I don't remember seeing any bike trailer.
Scott: They've seen plenty of shuttle buses anyway.
Rym: in some gaming news This was surprising.
Rym: like I was surprised by this I heard like oh there's some update to quake one And I just didn't think anything of it.
Rym: and then Scott was like where I'm paying attention.
Scott: No, I wasn't making I was paying attention.
Rym: and then so the article I'm linking to was like hey The update happened to quick one like the og quake one, but what the update was Is not only does quake one just work on Steam, which it's always just worked on Steam.
Rym: It was literally the first thing I paid money for on Steam.
Rym: I Bought the ID pack that had every ID game up to that point which included quake one.
Rym: It just worked.
Rym: They updated it and what they made it do is You can just start a deathmatch game or a co-op game.
Rym: You can just click on people's names on Steam and invite them.
Rym: It'll just work.
Rym: full cross play room codes matchmaking everything.
Rym: quake one now just works for Multiplayer.
Scott: Well, that's that's only one thing that was done.
Scott: Yeah that you care about Really happened is that they came out right with a quake one HD remaster which is a thing that many games have been doing ever since.
Scott: by on a commando rearmed started that trend way back in the Mid 2000s, right?
Scott: So the difference here is that quake one has shown everyone the correct way to do the HD remaster Which is not to do it.
Scott: resident evil does where it released a completely new game or to do a Nintendo does release a completely new Game.
Scott: that is the same exact thing as the old game where you change some things and you try to correct your mistakes of the Past and you sell it for full price.
Scott: All they did was make it work and make it look good the quake one HD remaster is Literally just a patch to quake one.
Scott: the original quake one just has been patched.
Scott: this many years later 20 plus years later after its release they just patched it to a new version.
Scott: This higher resolution textures support for 4k resolutions, you know But it's just the same.
Scott: goddamn game up like go to that updated to work on modern thing.
Scott: Go into that count, but obviously if you get it on the Nintendo switch or something instead of your computer There is no original quake one on there to patch.
Scott: So you just have to buy quake one and you're gonna get the newest version of it when you do.
Scott: So obviously, yeah they've also.
Scott: I Don't know if this was done earlier or just done now, but you know quake 64 is a thing.
Scott: And the deal with quake 64 is that it does have like different levels, you know, the single-player levels.
Scott: So those are now.
Scott: I don't know they might have added up as a new development or an old development But those are included.
Scott: like you can play the quake 64 levels on your PC.
Rym: Now when I have a quake one, the only thing I have not tested is can I get a mod to just work with this?
Scott: Absolutely, yes, you can you just get any get your wad file or whatever it is.
Scott: It'll just work.
Rym: So my car are you a hundred percent sure?
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's what we were doing yesterday.
Rym: Those weren't nothing we did yesterday was a mod.
Scott: Yeah was we played on those maps that came in a separate pack.
Rym: Nope map map mods are very different from these other mods.
Rym: I'm really what I'm curious to see.
Rym: I'm just gonna try to make it work.
Scott: I I to mods a mod.
Scott: A map is just a mod pay.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: It's a little more complicated than that.
Rym: Did you ever mess with quake one mods?
Scott: It's gonna work.
Scott: it's just quake one.
Scott: It's gonna would you bet?
Scott: it's not any different.
Rym: would you bet money that I can make mega team fortress work in this quake one?
Scott: Sure, why not?
Scott: It will totally work.
Scott: Servers are gonna be.
Scott: I don't know if the servers will take because I you know Hedging hedging.
Scott: there's hedging detected Scott's not sure now, but if you just load if you load it up just locally It will absolutely work.
Scott: that I don't know how they're making the servers Invite.
Scott: if this if the server is running on my computer when it does the steam invite then yes, it will work.
Scott: But if the server is running on some third-party server, you know that they have.
Scott: I don't know how they were frustrated.
Rym: That means it doesn't work.
Scott: if that's true It does mean it works because you don't have to use that.
Scott: you don't have to use the.
Scott: You know.
Scott: if for some reason the way they set up the networking is not gonna work You could use you could still use the old networking and make it work that way.
Rym: Did you ever install like multiplayer mods for quick water quake to like?
Scott: do you put if you put files in a folder the end?
Rym: More to it than that, but okay.
Scott: Anyway files in a folder, but that's all you got to do.
Scott: It's good.
Scott: You'd even quake three.
Scott: You just put files in a folder.
Rym: Anyway, I'm uh, I expect it'll probably just work.
Rym: I do also expect that there's no way to make the multiplayer work.
Rym: I expect it's gonna fall over in some way on that, but I'm curious.
Scott: the only you know, the issue could be that if It doesn't seem like they've made any change, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, I think mods in general will work, right?
Rym: But You were sure because I have not seen anyone report on the mods working or because no one's trying.
Scott: but yeah I'm gonna do general absolutely work.
Scott: The question is there may be a situation where like a specific mod might have some incompatibility With some specific changes in the latest patch and there might be bugginess, right but Mods in general are gonna work cuz it's still just quake one.
Rym: Yes, we'll see though because all the mods that are interesting were extremely complex and made drastic changes.
Rym: I'm really curious to see if mega team fortress will work.
Rym: I'm gonna try this week coming weekend because I have a long weekend.
Rym: I'm going to earnestly try to make mega team fortress work and if I can make multiplayer work I'm not gonna promise I'll play it with any of you cuz I don't think we could get enough people.
Rym: but that'll be interesting to See, that's all I have to say about that.
Rym: If not, I am gonna try to make it work in DOS box anyway Because of a panel.
Scott: I feel as though some people get the impression of the kex engine port of quake is difficult or impossible to mod.
Scott: However, from my experience quake mods work just as well with the remaster as they would with other source ports.
Scott: It's very easy to install them as well here.
Scott: I'll be so.
Rym: here's the prize Mod.
Rym: so here's one problem I've run into.
Rym: I did see that people who had tried to make mega TF work on just the quake source Previously had a lot of difficulties.
Rym: No, so we'll see.
Rym: Oh see if it works here.
Scott: It works.
Scott: Just fine.
Rym: Well, what it?
Rym: which mods?
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: But this person's playing some you know, so I don't know a mod they were playing.
Rym: Yeah, cuz a lot of mods didn't do much or like you said we're just a map.
Rym: That's not the kind of mod I'm even remotely interested in.
Scott: All right Play anyway.
Scott: Yes, check to see if arcane dimensions worked and it did.
Scott: what about smaller mods?
Scott: Yeah, it works.
Scott: Just drag the mod folder to the rerelease folder and type game mock.
Scott: You know square bracket mod in the in-game console.
Scott: It works pretty much the same as it would with quake spasm.
Rym: Yep, so we'll see.
Rym: I'm really curious to see if I can make a multiplayer work with one of those advanced mods like mega TF.
Scott: But every mod every mod ever people bring you up all kinds of mod names and all of them are saying yes It works.
Scott: just you open the console and type game space and the name of the mod folder and all you got to do is Drag the folder into the location.
Rym: No, I've ever got what I will say very specifically if multiplayer doesn't work then the mod doesn't work.
Scott: That's just.
Scott: you're making up some arbitrary.
Rym: The whole point of even I wouldn't even I like quake one mods honestly not worth revisiting in the single-player world.
Rym: I'm only interested in multiplayer mods.
Scott: Yeah, that's just that's just you only interested in.
Scott: but it's just me.
Scott: it works it loads it doesn't crash then it works.
Rym: That's a. I mean, I guess by a facile and pointless definition of the word works.
Scott: That's true All right.
Scott: Well the next time that you say, oh technically it works.
Scott: I'll remember I'll be like, oh, but what about those quake mods?
Scott: Cuz you've made the.
Scott: you've taken the opposite stance that I am taking right now many times Where you'll just say oh technically it works.
Rym: Yeah, by one debt by one very narrow definition of works.
Scott: Hey, yeah, and that's what you do.
Scott: allies, you know, but there are definition It works.
Scott: what I'm really excited about are on the narrow definition side.
Scott: Watch out.
Rym: All right I just don't I'm.
Rym: I'll be surprised if the multiplayer works fully.
Scott: But anyway, I just don't know how they implemented it.
Scott: But the multiplayer work is great.
Rym: Yeah with regular old deathmatch, which we'll get to in the main bit.
Rym: but what I'm also excited about if they do this to quick to Quake 2 is an objectively better deathmatch experience.
Rym: like quake 2 just was like Early pinnacle like a peak for its time of game design of that kind of multiplayer and the mod scene for quake 2 Was where things really kicked off like quake 1 was good and important and we really enjoy playing quake 1.
Rym: But quake 2 is what I'm really interested in seeing get the same treatment.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure that I'm telling you this is what that's the main news here right?
Scott: Yeah, like this is how you do an HD remaster, right?
Scott: Anyone who already owns the fucking game should just get the up get up just patch it, right?
Scott: It's like if I've got you know, friggin What's a they did Wind Waker remaster, right?
Scott: So I guess it's kind of hard to patch that It's a console game, but let's pretend it wasn't a kind of power of PC games.
Rym: but I think the reason why a lot of people don't do what you describe is Almost and so almost every time I've seen inside info about a remake which hasn't been for many years They want to make money on.
Scott: you don't make money doing what they just did.
Rym: Oh, no, not just that.
Rym: a lot of companies don't even have the source code to their games anymore.
Scott: Everyone has the well quake.
Scott: one is open source that helps?
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: but I'd say there are games that had to be re-implemented from scratch based on play and Reverse engineering of the binaries they release.
Rym: that has happened many times Mmm, like there's some public stories about it to have some official Bethesda fact our existing mods supported on PC.
Scott: The PC enhanced version will load any mod the original version supported when existing mods have been placed in the install directory.
Scott: It will not support some mods that require a different source port from the original game.
Rym: Yeah, that's that's the part I'm a little worried about with mega TF specifically, but we'll see.
Rym: like I said, I'm gonna try it.
Rym: I'm gonna try to make it work.
Scott: as long as it's a normal mod doesn't require like Where you just put files in a folder as opposed to like modifying the EXE type mod.
Scott: It will function.
Rym: So yep, so we shall see if I can make that work.
Rym: It'll be exciting.
Rym: in some other news this was making the rounds and The story was actually for once.
Rym: usually when you see a story like this if you actually read the details, it's way less Specific.
Rym: but in this case, it was actually quite specific.
Rym: The Chinese government has mandated and there will be it looks like there there will be policies and punishments to enforce this that any Online game a game with online multiplayer of any kind or online single-player where someone plays the game online from a client locally Anyone all games must have real identity age verification and anyone who is on an account that is under the age of 18 will only be allowed to play for a total of Three hours per week between 8 p.m.
Rym: And 9 p.m.
Rym: Local time.
Rym: Friday Saturday and Sunday with right It's a little.
Scott: I think a lot of articles have written like you only play for three hours a week and that's technically correct.
Scott: Yeah It's where way of saying is saying there are only three Specific hours during the week in which play will be available.
Scott: three windows, right?
Scott: Yeah, eight to nine o'clock Friday eight to nine o'clock Saturday eight to nine o'clock Sunday.
Scott: It's not like oh you could play your three hours on Monday.
Scott: No, you can't do that.
Scott: It's like yeah, there are three specific hour time slots and that is when you can play, you know the end.
Rym: So imagine when you were in high school playing quake one.
Rym: You could only play the deathmatch between 8 and 9 p.m Friday Saturday and Sunday.
Scott: also Holidays, they're gonna put also if there's a holiday I guess like a Chinese national holiday then then between 8 and 9 holiday then between 8 and 9 p.m.
Rym: On those holidays.
Scott: Yes, exactly now.
Scott: So first of all, you know, I think people in the gaming space see this news But you know, I'm also in the the kpop space right and China is doing similar Crackdowns on things of this nature, right?
Rym: So online is osmonds online Socializing there like it's a there's a lot all sorts of there.
Scott: Yeah, there's all sorts of like these specific, you know I guess cultural restrictions.
Scott: They're like, okay, you can't have any of these, you know Competition shows and so, you know, there's like they're identifying things that they think are like, you know Bad for the youths sort of like how when we were in school, they banned Trapper Keepers and all that stuff, right?
Scott: So don't bring your Tamagotchi to school only, you know Those rules that we had in school were like really specifically targeting like, you know one thing and they also affected these rules are You know, they're more broad trying to like address the whole issue.
Rym: Well, there's another nuance there.
Rym: Those rules only affected us when we were on school property.
Rym: We could do whatever the fuck we wanted.
Scott: That's all right.
Scott: But that's not the point.
Scott: I'm trying to make the way I'm trying to make.
Scott: is you know The?
Scott: the difference is a specific rule, right?
Scott: They're not saying like China wasn't like.
Scott: ah that video game is a problem that fortnight.
Scott: They weren't like banned fortnight.
Scott: They were like, okay, we're gonna ban aiming anything like that because there's anything like that.
Rym: we didn't cover it on GeekNights partly because I like it.
Rym: if you don't necessarily want to take the Language and rhetoric in government press releases from foreign nations that face value There's a lot of reasons like think about what American government press releases look like to the outside world.
Rym: so a while ago the Chinese government issued a bunch of statements basically saying that Gaming social media and a bunch of other things were effectively quote spiritual opium and there was a lot of rhetoric coming around coming out around how those things are colonial artifacts that should be excised from Chinese society and I've treated that like I would any government rhetoric.
Rym: But it seems like with this no new news that the government is now acting on the that rhetoric directly and specifically.
Scott: Yeah, I mean this is you know the exact opposite of you know, the What you get.
Scott: in countries like this one this country we can't do anything.
Rym: The government is just like stuck like there should be a little ground like government.
Scott: it like China.
Scott: The government's the opposite of stuck.
Scott: They want to do something.
Scott: Boom.
Scott: They just fucking do it, right?
Scott: They're like just getting shit done.
Scott: The problem is half the shit they're getting done is evil and genocide and the other half of this shit They're getting done is actually yeah, maybe not the worst.
Scott: America Kind of cancels out.
Rym: America's genocide comes from the free market as opposed to from an authoritarian power.
Rym: So it's exactly I make a quote marks.
Rym: You can't see that if you're not watching the live stream.
Rym: But exactly this is obviously a problem partly for a lot of reasons.
Rym: but I wonder how this is actually going to affect the Chinese gaming ecosystem because Part of what's going on here that you there's other articles you can read if you want to read about what what like the index
Scott: There are some positives to it China,
Rym: I would argue there are no positives to this specific rule.
Rym: This is an egregious over.
Scott: You're not gonna have kids, you know, they get less kids gambling away on some gotcha games But there's lots of non gotcha games that exist that are enriching.
Scott: You won't grow up paying.
Scott: you won't grow up paying to win.
Scott: I guess it less likely you'll grow up paying.
Rym: if I had not been able to play the non gotcha video games that I played Growing up.
Rym: I would be a radically different person today and probably a worse person.
Scott: Yeah, no, I didn't I said but it's at least you if you grew up today.
Rym: We like we recognize that gotcha games and these gambling mechanics are harmful and I would welcome Nuanced carefully mandated restrictions.
Scott: They've thrown the baby out with the bathwater, but they did throw out the bathwater.
Rym: We're sitting in bathwater Yeah, but what all what's also going on is the Chinese government has increasingly been cracking down on Chinese large technology companies that they see as a threat to their own power.
Scott: Yeah, and you know, that's it.
Scott: and the one again, it's like yeah.
Scott: in the United States We let companies be as powerful as they want more powerful than the government and that's anti-democratic.
Scott: China isn't democratic to begin with so they just shut down anything that Approaches their level of power to make sure the government is always the most powerful thing.
Scott: in the United States The government isn't powerful enough.
Rym: But I feel I feel like what's gonna happen here is the rest of the world's gaming is going to increasingly just like with the internet Basically cut itself off from the Chinese market.
Scott: because well, yeah, you're not why would you?
Scott: well You're not gonna unless you're making a game just for adults only, you know, you're not expecting children to play your game.
Scott: Then you're just not gonna even bother trying to sell in China.
Scott: You're not gonna translate into Chinese.
Scott: I would even less likely to considering the rhetoric out of the government.
Scott: I would be leery Chinese people outside of China that you might want to.
Rym: Oh, yeah I'm saying going after the Chinese Market itself as in the market of people living in mainland China who may play your game.
Rym: exactly that market is gonna come with so much Baggage like this.
Rym: like if you run a game there you have to do real ID age checks to enforce this rule or you get Fucked.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well, I mean companies already have their own separate Chinese servers example, like, you know battle net or you know Any of those right?
Rym: So like you can't just get on Tiananmen Square on those servers like for real.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: Yeah, so, you know, they're.
Scott: they're probably just gonna.
Scott: the difference is like now I guess only Unless you're between those three hours, right?
Scott: The battle net server will cut off all the kids from playing Diablo or over what.
Rym: here's some other things that are interesting.
Rym: whatever this crackdown which seems not just to be aimed at controlling society But also at reining in the powerful companies many of which are making a lot of money from online gaming like 10-cent many of which Companies are not Chinese companies, right?
Scott: Basically taking money from Chinese kids and bringing it over to this side.
Rym: Yep, but there's been another side of this where Chinese companies were heavily investing in the gaming industry and sector Which was starting to drive?
Rym: the sensibilities of Online especially lower tier gacha style game design in countries outside of China because those companies Taking that investment also wanted to reach the Chinese market and would implement Without saying too much out loud Themselves a lot of Chinese censorship rules to not run afoul of problems in that market.
Rym: I feel like if that economic ecosystem the investment ecosystem is under attack You're gonna see non Chinese government controlled gaming companies Increasingly start to back away from what they've been doing where they've been Following Chinese rules if they weren't required to to have access to that market if the markets gonna be destroyed.
Rym: Anyway, why even bother following those rules that you didn't have to follow in the first place.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: I think this is gonna be a positive.
Scott: I think it's also sort of a. you know how in Russia we see this sort of thing with the ransomware, right?
Scott: Well, we know it's mostly these Russian dudes are doing the ransomware But the rule the unspoken rule is that they don't ransomware other Russians right because they're trying to bring money into Russia Even if it's into the hands of a few evil dudes and not have money, you know, you're not ripping off your own country, right?
Scott: Damaging yourself.
Scott: So in this much in the same way here Chinese companies making all sorts of gacha games Taking money from kids around the world.
Scott: just hey, we're not gonna take money from Chinese kids.
Scott: Yeah But don't hurt.
Scott: don't hurt your own people.
Scott: Yeah, take money from around the world and bring it to China.
Scott: don't hurt our own people though.
Rym: That's why my hope here is that what about what the side effect of this will be?
Rym: Non Chinese game companies start to back away from Chinese censorship rules because they can't?
Rym: well I think it's.
Scott: those two things make me think there might be a sort of you know, cultural slash economic Warfare thing going on where basically, you know Countries allow companies to engage and exploit.
Rym: Shadow run is real except without elves and sex bots, right?
Scott: It's like okay in every country is like allows itself to host Country companies and those companies are allowed to engage in you know Evil business practices that are exploitative as long as it only engages in the exploitative business practices against God Foreign consumers, but not local any local because everyone will.
Scott: anyone who doesn't want to get exploited make sure to only consume local Because they're not allowed to rip off the locals.
Rym: This is just privateering in the digital era Pretty much.
Rym: It's just literal privateering.
Scott: Anyway China's doing if you look if you look around China's been doing this more and more and more to mostly things kids are interested in.
Scott: you know Music.
Rym: yeah now where I think this might backfire is because in many cases Often the Chinese government like the people in acting these policies do seem to earnestly believe in these ideological lines.
Scott: Well, I mean, I think to some extent they are gonna get some of what they ask.
Scott: Oh, yeah, right is like, you know It's.
Scott: obviously it's not it's not perfect like you would imagine it but it's like yeah without the video games The kids are probably gonna you know, do my work.
Rym: That is where I was.
Rym: so say that this is someone is my guess is that the mistake They have made in these policies.
Rym: Is that the children who have more access to gaming as a whole?
Rym: Knowing that there is a harmful aspect of gaming with gacha games Will probably have better outcomes and the Jane McGonigal attack of gaming makes people better.
Scott: as long as the games are good I feel like well But you're only cut off from multiplayer games and your parents could still let you play in their account and you can play all The local non online games.
Scott: you reading what and if you're a really cool Chinese kid You'll set up a LAN party at your house to play multiplayer games that way.
Scott: So there could be a market for games with LAN support in China for multi.
Rym: I do though suspect that this is a presses to further crackdowns on gaming in mainland China.
Rym: I Think this is just the beginning.
Rym: This is far from over and it's going to get.
Scott: I think that based on the rhetoric that let Basically anything that becomes too popular with the kids that they see as harmful.
Scott: They've already, you know established this pattern.
Scott: They are going to restrict or crack down on it in some way Right either completely banning it or in this case in other cases just limiting the parts of it that they see that are like not Cool.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: So it's like with the kpop thing.
Scott: I don't know the details because I read the article a while ago and didn't read too closely.
Scott: But it's like they didn't ban like singing and dancing and music shows on TV, right?
Scott: They banned like this sort of competitive aspect that a lot of the shows have because they saw a lot of like fan culture.
Scott: Well, you know full of people, you know, like, you know attacking each other, right?
Scott: And that's the part that they thought was bad, right?
Scott: So it's like in Korea, you'll just see like these straight-up competition shows.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, this group's better than that group and whatnot.
Scott: They're like they banned in China.
Scott: They banned like ranking type stuff, right?
Scott: You're not.
Scott: no more rankings, you know, there was a lot of things where you know They would like have fans send in money or click on votes to like.
Scott: You know get their group their favorite group ranked higher than the other one.
Scott: Yeah, they crack down on that sort of thing.
Scott: All right, they're not like.
Scott: hey no more singing and dancing pop music.
Scott: They're they're keeping that.
Rym: so The part that they see is negative.
Scott: in this case kids playing online games for too long instead of doing something else or That's they crack down on only that part.
Scott: right they didn't crack down on just no game no video games for any kid ever yet.
Rym: Yeah, and you know, so well a telling point that we'll move on is I have some numbers here Nettie's which net ease Gaming company in Chinese gaming company.
Rym: Their stock was down 8% immediately after this news.
Rym: Oh, yeah, ten cent dropped but less.
Rym: but ten cent owns a lot of non gaming stuff.
Scott: Also, even though ten cents a Chinese company a lot of the customers are not Chinese children, yep Net ease has more invested in that specific.
Rym: And in one more news.
Rym: This is just a cloud link to a couple of Twitter threads that can sort of go more into this.
Rym: But if you like tabletop games and you're not paying attention to the tabletop industry Which frankly most tabletop gamers don't and that's fine Like most people most people like movies But don't pay attention to the movie industry.
Rym: Tabletop games are about to get like four to ten times more expensive and this is not gonna get better anytime.
Rym: soon Tabletop is entering.
Scott: There's a lot of reasons for it.
Scott: I actually I welcome it.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the tabletop has gotten to the point where there's definitely a bubble of too many games too many small publishers.
Rym: It's starting to contract again.
Scott: You can have too many.
Scott: I don't want to say there's too many games too many small Publishers.
Scott: right because I don't think you can have too many.
Rym: I would say I don't think I don't think you can and I think there should be a huge number of small independent publishers.
Rym: I don't think the market can bear that many and most of these games right getting bought right in cat.
Scott: I think that there's too many.
Scott: there's not too many games.
Scott: There's too many people attempting to live off of those games.
Rym: Also live streaming.
Rym: like I don't there are way more hours of live stream content made than every human on earth could watch and that There's only so much money in tabletop to go around.
Scott: So, you know, it's like it's great that I love.
Scott: I want more people to make more games all the time, you know as many as we can get.
Scott: all the new ideas Just you know a flourishing ecosystem of new games all over the place.
Scott: But the people some people have to realize that like yeah, you know, even if you've got some you know players for your game That might not be enough to live on.
Scott: don't go, you know.
Scott: Don't go down that road and risk your livelihood on that.
Rym: So in a nutshell, but there's many more factors at play, but the biggest ones are one.
Rym: remember that Suez Canal problem.
Rym: There's.
Rym: the echoes of that are still affecting the global economy.
Scott: Well, it's not that specifically that one problem, but it's basically global shipping, right?
Scott: You have a situations where there are.
Scott: there are like docks where they're just boats sitting out there because it's not enough dock.
Rym: The first one is that that one incident had.
Rym: we have still not recovered from that one incident in it.
Scott: That's that's small compared to some of the other shipping problems.
Scott: There's a lot of shipping problems that are all on top of each other.
Rym: It's bigger than you'd think but the recovery from that was made harder because what you just brought up There aren't enough workers and any of the ports of call current in some places in the world is not enough containers.
Scott: Yeah, basically shipping is a problem, right?
Scott: So board games you usually most of them are printed in China and shipped on boats literal boats to the unit to do the rest Of the speaking of China between tariffs political issues and everything else going on.
Rym: It's getting harder to interact with Chinese manufacturers.
Rym: unless you are big so small Printing.
Scott: just.
Scott: there aren't a lot of other places to print.
Scott: They're more expensive.
Scott: Most people who are making tabletop games.
Scott: the trend these days is to make a big fancy game with lots of shit in it And not a nice little time.
Scott: you make a nice little tiny game like a deck of cards.
Scott: You can probably just have it printed in the u.s You know, no problem.
Scott: Well soon as you want components beyond a deck of cards some basic six-sided dice We get your big old box full of miniatures and boards and plastic shit.
Rym: It's like nope, even just cardboard like more complex shapes in cardboard hard to get in the u.s I'm actually gonna read it.
Rym: I'm gonna quote Restoration games because they were talking about this at length a while ago.
Rym: quote and before anyone asks about printing domestically It is literally not feasible for 90% of games.
Rym: There are no domestic manufacturers Capable to the door able to do what most modern games require and definitely not enough to handle the current demand Like yeah most components that your game.
Scott: if you want to print your game in the u.s.
Scott: It literally has to be like deck of cards.
Scott: That's it That kind of game.
Rym: or as soon as you get any have to build the capacity yourself and guess what.
Rym: that is not feasible.
Scott: or you can if you made your game out of just standard components You know, like just green meeple wooden cube, you know d6, right?
Rym: You could go you could then you can maybe make your game Maybe but even then those things are also in high demand because wood got very expensive.
Rym: the non Shipping supply chain is under extreme pressure not just from kovat but a lot of things are higher priority to ship than board games.
Rym: Yep Like the US housing market is struggling with the limited supply of lumber versus the demand which has.
Scott: if you're losing a bit I've heard it lumber is easing.
Rym: But if you look at the list of people to ship lumber to When there is limited supply board game manufacturing is near the bottom of that list, right?
Scott: Well, you got it.
Scott: you know the shipping.
Scott: the thing with the shipping is you see there'll be a boat right and the boat can hold so much stuff and You want to pay to get your stuff on that boat.
Scott: Well, the a lot of people want to get their stuff on that boat Not just people with board games other people and there's only so much space.
Scott: So the price for that space goes up.
Scott: and if the price of that space goes up too much Which it has then depending on your product it may or may not be worth it to even go on the boat at all.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like okay I could put my board game on that boat But the cost to do so would be so high That I would lose all my money and I would be like in the negative even if I sold every copy of the game I put on that boat at MSRP.
Scott: I would be like in the hole a zillion dollars now there.
Scott: So what am I gonna do?
Scott: Just let my board game sit on the other side of the world and wait and wait and wait and wait and wait.
Rym: now there Might be one.
Scott: I'm not making any money because I'm not selling any games.
Scott: I don't have anything to sell my stores empty.
Rym: There might be one minor positive side effect in that because I had a news I was gonna talk about.
Rym: we just didn't do a show about Counterfeit board games because they've been rampant and like Amazon's trying to crack down partly because they're not gonna come over either.
Rym: Yeah, cuz guess what?
Rym: It's just as hard to make a counterfeit as the real thing in this current environment.
Scott: Well, I mean even if you made the counterfeit, you know, you can cut off your price with regards to the IP you can but He's yeah, the shipping cost the same for everybody.
Scott: So
Rym: yep, so my Advice Like the basically if you're a tabletop designer and you don't have plans around this honestly, the best thing you can probably do is pause stuff try to shrink operations or now is the time to work on designs of games that will come out three or four years from now like the big ones or invest now in pivoting to digital because I think the future of Complex tabletop board gaming honestly, and I think this might be a catalyst to drive this more is you build digital first you release digital Play.
Rym: testing at scale via digital is how you get your final version and the physical game.
Scott: It might even make the physical one.
Rym: then because a lot of people still like the physical one I still want to play a few people.
Scott: that'll be like a niche like bonus thing I would.
Rym: I still prefer to play physical route over a digital route.
Rym: I only play digital route because I can't easily play physical route right now.
Scott: digital route is just way better.
Scott: It's so much faster.
Scott: You don't have to get it takes so much less time.
Scott: You don't have to look up rules.
Rym: I'm saying just you design that what.
Rym: the one of the primary things that makes tabletop good We talked about this a lot on GeekNights Is that you designed around?
Rym: physical constraints and it forced your game to be more elegant.
Rym: even if you weren't trying to be elegant design your sure.
Scott: design your Game as if it were physical and digital.
Rym: I think the future is you design for physical you deliver digital Then you get all the play testing feedback.
Rym: So you don't have to issue like version 1.1 of root with stickers to fix problems And then once the game is mature you release a special physical edition for the hardcore nutbags like us who want to own it.
Scott: And I'm not I don't need to hard.
Scott: I'm perfectly happy not to own Physical one.
Rym: I do prefer playing tabletop games in person with people.
Rym: My only exception to that honestly is train games.
Rym: I will never play one of those in person again in my life.
Scott: I Got the one either.
Scott: There's the one train the New England when I ordered.
Scott: I think I'll play that one in person.
Rym: Good luck.
Rym: I will play it with you on 18xx games.
Rym: It goes on there But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so check this out.
Rym: this is an academic paper Cornell University Under the economic theoretical economics category and it is titled fairer chess.
Rym: a reversal of two opening moves in chess creates balance between white and black.
Rym: The tldr is if you have the start of chess be a snake like how settlers starts.
Rym: It seems it might actually Eliminate the difference between black and white meaning the first turn first mover advantage.
Rym: That is huge if true and it looks plausible based on this paper And this is something fascinating that I'm surprised.
Rym: No one has positive this before or if they have why no one noticed.
Scott: Well, I think you know it's that we have settlers is a good example right and settlers they recognize this sort of this first mover advantage when you're setting up and putting out Your initial settlements and then as soon as the game starts you go around in a circle.
Scott: Yep, right It's like.
Scott: well, why don't you just keep sneaking the whole damn game?
Scott: if you recognize that that's fairer Why not?
Scott: Just keep it up.
Scott: Why do you have to and then you think other games?
Scott: I think what happens is that games tend to either be simultaneous play just go in a circle or they have some other turn mechanism like there's an action to become the first player or you bid to be the first player or in Power grid you arrange the turn order based on how many cities.
Scott: you have all these sorts of other mechanisms, right?
Scott: Once you need a better turn order there you invent a new turn order mechanism.
Scott: That's better than a snake that goes back and forth.
Scott: Yeah, I guess there are a lot of games out there even two-player games that are still just take turns in a circle and There's often, you know backgammon chess checkers.
Scott: It's like even if you just start the game with a snake like player one goes first then player two goes twice.
Scott: Yeah, right and then you know.
Rym: Well, this is back to something we've talked about a lot in convention panels Like we talked about the lot and play to win a bunch of game mechanics.
Rym: We've brought this point up so many times and the point is very much that Turn order is something that a lot of game designers just ignore.
Rym: They just oh, we'll go clockwise don't worry about it and they focus on the rest of their game.
Rym: yet Turn order is often the primary and sometimes sole determiner of victory in perfect play.
Scott: If it's a turn based game turn order matters a lot.
Rym: Yeah, and Many tabletop board games of the German persuasion like the ones we like the the hobbyists your quote serious weird different.
Rym: Whatever, however, you want to categorize those board games.
Rym: They often have mechanics around manipulating turn order for a very good reason.
Rym: And yeah, that's just a blind spot in most game design For whatever you know, that's it.
Scott: I mean, I think it's relatively, you know recent like a few decades recent You know people making games with different kinds of turn order actually experimenting with that.
Scott: And so any old game that's so old and entrenched like chess where no one's.
Scott: you know There's alternate versions plenty of them But no one's changing the rules of the original right.
Scott: if any games that are older than a few decades that are still around The turn order is sort of stuck in a bad way.
Scott: Yeah, no reason you can't play Monopoly with the snake.
Scott: It's probably just better.
Rym: They almost definitely.
Scott: no reason you can't play Scrabble with a snake.
Scott: It's probably just better.
Rym: I suspect the prob.
Scott: a reason for this is I bet some game designers literally don't even think about it But in fact Scrabble would probably be the best if like whoever has the lowest score goes next or something like that.
Rym: But I suspect part of it.
Scott: Whoever's seen whoever's seen the fewest tiles from the back Whoever's drawn the fewest tiles from the back?
Scott: you track of how many tiles each person is drawn.
Scott: So whoever's seen the fewest new tiles gets to keep guess.
Rym: so my counterpoint for game designers who do recognize this I have noticed in my entire gaming life that a lot of people struggle Profoundly.
Rym: if any game doesn't just go clockwise Well, it's hard to keep.
Scott: you need a mechanism to keep track.
Scott: that doesn't compete even with those mechanisms.
Rym: I see people just repeatedly mess it up forever and It's something that if you have a non-standard turn already have to deal with but a snake you don't have to deal with it Because the snake is still a very simple pattern and literally the new chess move.
Rym: Like if you follow these rules, it's just white then black then black goes again Then white then white goes again, and then you alternate for the rest of the game.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: That's the only change.
Scott: Well, I didn't know why would white goes.
Scott: I thought it would just be white black black white black white black.
Scott: In the game.
Rym: the game normally would be alternating white black white black white black.
Rym: All you do is group all moves into pairs first.
Rym: So white black white black white black then just flip the second one.
Rym: That's the only change.
Rym: so it goes white black black white white black white black white black.
Rym: That is the change specifically.
Rym: It's easy if you see it written out.
Rym: It makes a lot more sense.
Scott: Yeah, that does make a lot more sense.
Rym: But I was just thinking you know I had to say when I read the paper like I had their same struggle.
Rym: But then when I saw the little diagram of like what the turn order looked like it just clicked instantly.
Scott: Yeah, I think it would.
Scott: would it still be fair to just go, you know, white black?
Rym: Because the paper Specifically makes the argument that this exact change makes the game fair.
Scott: Yeah, it's still I think.
Scott: I. you know, it seems good.
Scott: No, I'd also better than just going white black white black.
Rym: So the most salient point though, I'm just gonna read this little sentence.
Rym: Do you think of the day?
Rym: Is that?
Rym: Because humans playing chess, it doesn't fucking matter.
Rym: It only matters for machines because the way chess is.
Rym: but quote this conclusion is supported by computer analysis of chefs chess openings.
Scott: Oh, that's true.
Scott: Chess is a really easy game to test this with because yeah You can just have computers play it against each other to see.
Scott: yeah, the results are Yeah, so what do you guys?
Scott: we could do the same thing with checkers.
Scott: we can get some checkers playing computers.
Rym: The problem is I think with checkers.
Rym: It doesn't matter because checkers is is.
Scott: The solution would say the same.
Rym: the solution is a draw no matter what.
Scott: so I don't think Snaking would it not be a draw if you change the turn order.
Rym: if you change the turn order and checkers either it would Guarantee that white wins or it would still guarantee a draw.
Rym: I don't know that there's any way to figure that out.
Rym: But brute force because checkers was solved by brute force and I don't think we would just basically change the turn order and run The brute force again and see what the first was done like 20 years ago.
Rym: So I wonder if we could do it faster.
Rym: I'm I'm uh, I'm not invested enough to think about this beyond what we just said, but someone else go figure that out
Scott: okay, so My thing of the day this YouTube channel is apparently quite old I guess but YouTube told me about it recently probably because I was watching like some factories and things of that nature and this is Somewhat-related.
Rym: Tangentially, it's all related to gears video.
Rym: We watched once a long time ago.
Scott: Yeah, so this is dude in Texas somewhere.
Scott: He runs a transmission business called precision transmissions and you know it's like okay, it's a dude fixing transmissions, but First of all an automatic transmission.
Scott: It's like yeah Yeah, I know the principle of how one works because I'm a nerdy guy who reads the internet and such, right?
Scott: I know the principle but you open up an actual automatic transmission and look inside and it's like what the fuck?
Scott: Yeah It's like so that's hydraulic and that's electronic and that's a valve and that's a clutch and there's the planetary gears.
Scott: it's like you can understand some of the parts on their own and then you put them all together and just like.
Scott: but This guy has a YouTube channel and basically he takes apart transmissions.
Scott: He this guy knows more about Transmissions than I know about computers.
Scott: He doesn't know so much and he's breaking on all the parts and he can really specific things.
Scott: He's like, oh, yeah this washer He's like it's too thick too thin.
Scott: Oh, yeah, you can see that one's worn out.
Scott: You got to replace this one.
Scott: It's like, you know, you could do this or you could do that but this one cost a lot is it?
Scott: it's like even if you don't give a shit about cars or hate cars or You know whether you don't even care about how a car works.
Scott: It's just really.
Scott: it's always fascinating and enjoyable to see someone who knows a shit ton about something Breaking down that something and this channel as like they're doing so many videos on here.
Scott: It's like wow, this is real good There's.
Rym: I subscribed immediately after you sent me the ladies.
Scott: Yeah, it's like did you just?
Scott: he just brings out a transmission?
Scott: He's like, okay, here I am again.
Scott: Let's open up this and some of the videos.
Scott: the most the most entertaining videos are the ones of the transmissions real busted That the best one.
Scott: he opened one up and like black sludge came out and it was smelling real bad.
Scott: And he was like, yeah, you should be glad you're not here.
Scott: this thing stay.
Rym: I can say that I know what a busted transition transmission smells like because I had one go on my Sun fire Did did what looked like mud come out of it it?
Rym: They were taking they were messing with it to decide if it was even salvageable and it smelled like something died.
Scott: Yeah Be sort of like red magenta Translucent color.
Scott: so if mud is in the transmission, that's y'all kind of bad.
Rym: But like the best way to describe it is.
Rym: it smelled Like the smell of when an animal has died in the woods and you're like bike past that animal.
Scott: He also was telling stories about finding like, you know, like bees living in transmission.
Scott: I don't see any of that.
Scott: there might be videos that I haven't seen because there's a lot of.
Rym: yeah I know what I'm looking for on YouTube after we do the show.
Scott: These are in my transmission watch.
Rym: There's a whole like.
Scott: if you've never seen the inside of an auto dramatic transmission or seen how one works Then I even more highly recommend this channel because you're gonna.
Scott: Every single almost every single person who has a car has bought one of these ridiculous machines that someone invented at some point Right.
Scott: It's like holy shit.
Scott: You have one of these that you probably have one or more than one of these things and you don't even realize it.
Scott: It's like the most complicated most advanced piece of machinery you own.
Rym: Well, in fact based on the demographic that I assume still listens to GeekNights based on interactions out there the one listener.
Rym: Yeah If you respect heavily like the weird engineering that went into your computer and you don't think much about your car Your car is so much more complex than your fucking computer.
Scott: Well, your car now has computers in it true these days.
Rym: but computers because they're general purpose Like the substrate almost doesn't matter that much like it's so disentangled from what you use it for.
Rym: but with a car All that stuff the computer does still has to translate to a whole bunch of high precision physical objects Interacting with each other in the real world and that is a messy difficult dangerous space.
Rym: That is so much more interesting and fascinating and important than the purely theoretical computation of a computer.
Scott: Yeah, I mean a CPU might be more complex in its arrangement than an automatic transmission But the automatic transmission gets it done with fluid under pressure as opposed to electrons, which is much harder to do.
Scott: Yep, at least for you know for someone like me who thinks in electrons the fluid seems hard In the meta moment.
Rym: the geek knows book club book is still the tale of Genji.
Rym: I am still continuing to read it.
Rym: I think September October.
Rym: We're definitely doing this show.
Scott: Maybe October you had it a month.
Rym: Well that so have you read any since the last time we talked?
Rym: no, okay, I had in a month October.
Scott: I'm not gonna lie.
Rym: Yeah, I Still reading So I'm not good.
Rym: So previously I kept saying Wow Genji really sleepwalks through life.
Rym: I moved on to Genji there.
Rym: There are more ghosts and ghost murders than I expected.
Rym: But now I just have one question Does Genji actually have a fucking job?
Scott: Does anyone in this entire at the part in the book where I am Genji like is it as a government, dude?
Rym: Yeah, he is a government.
Scott: He governs.
Rym: So here's my question does any character at any point in this entire book?
Rym: Except for two characters who we hear have a conversation outside, uh Have a job that they actually do anything in?
Scott: because yes, they do.
Scott: However, what's happening in this book is much like when you watch a movie?
Scott: Yeah, and you say hey doesn't anyone go to the fucking bathroom, you know It's like they'll show you someone going to the bathroom if it's meaningful like Jurassic Park.
Rym: Does she even keep going to school after like the sake you watch a rom-com?
Scott: There's no like just scenes of people going to the bathroom every day.
Scott: and Genji is not about the work that people are doing But you know what these people who run the government are doing.
Scott: Yeah, it's about the the the drama the soap opera shit that's happening, you know On their spare time, but so here's that's all that you see.
Scott: You don't see them taking a shit and you don't see them, you know governing and meeting with Ambassador whatever the fuck you did with an imperial.
Rym: what I do know about Han era Japan and like the kind of role Genji has is that at that level of government in that era a lot of roles were purely ceremonial and basically we're just a way to enrich that were that class of people.
Rym: Yeah, that's true because I just I think back to.
Rym: there was one conversation where you that remember when he was way early But I keep thinking back to it where he's having sex with some woman in But in like.
Rym: she's staying in a poor part of town incognito.
Rym: So he's with her in the poor part of town and there's some workmen like outside the house and they're talking and he's really mad.
Rym: Like I can hear these poor people talking.
Rym: It's so weird and the woman's like, yeah, you gotta put up with the poor people talking.
Rym: That's where I am.
Rym: But the three lines of dialogue maybe four that those poor people have are the only naturalistic dialogue I've encountered in this entire book so far.
Rym: They have a normal conversation about normal things.
Scott: one of them Because when you're trying to woo someone you're using poetry that you wrote gave to your Servant who then gave it to the snuck it over to the other person because you know I can't go over there directly.
Scott: You gotta talk to someone through a screen.
Rym: I'm also enjoying how Genji basically is better at poetry than everyone else.
Rym: He knows.
Scott: Well, that's basically the point.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So yeah, tell again She's pretty good.
Rym: But again my advice to you if you were gonna read it with us start now.
Rym: You'll probably finish it by the time we finish it, but do not fuss over the fiddly details.
Rym: Just let the story wash over you and just try to enjoy.
Rym: read it for enjoyment Don't really take you.
Scott: if you do if you try to read all the detail It'll take you longer to read than it's taken us.
Rym: Yep, and that said Otherwise our stuff's on the internet.
Rym: go find it.
Rym: Let's talk about deathmatch.
Scott: Well some people I just want to say quickly some people have applied to our forum lately which still exists.
Scott: You can come and talk to us in our forum or a discord for that matter.
Scott: But people who've come to the forum when you apply to Register for the forum you have to type in a reason that you are coming and I've seen some people lately Type it in some reasons that are like hey, I want to make friends and talk about stuff.
Rym: Oh, don't tell that That's that's a bot.
Rym: you're a bot right?
Scott: That reason is too generic for me to believe that.
Scott: that is a listener of the show.
Scott: You if you want to I will like just accept you easily.
Scott: You just have to write a reason that indicates that you are a GeekNights listener.
Scott: You could write something like I've been a GeekNights listener for two days and I heard this episode Clearly something that's clearly not a bot.
Scott: It doesn't take much.
Scott: It could be just.
Scott: you know Literally just like you know, I want to make fun of Scott clearly.
Scott: That's not a bot if you wrote that right?
Scott: So it's like just something that I will read and say that's not a bot.
Scott: That's a real listener.
Scott: Approved right, but if you say just I want to discuss things I want to learn something That's got I can't trust it.
Scott: That's human.
Rym: I feel like you're gonna what I feel like you're gonna want to discuss Bitcoin and you want to learn about how you can get Us to like Bitcoin.
Scott: So if you get rejected Don't dismay.
Scott: It's nothing personal.
Scott: Just try again and write a better reason in your reason box.
Rym: Think of it as you have to pass a Turing test to get into the forum and we've set the bar a little higher than the average Turing test.
Rym: Yeah, convince us in a couple sentences that you're probably human.
Rym: That's all you got to do.
Scott: They not need to dig less in a sentence.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, I mean I could imagine Very very short sentences that would convince me that you're cool to join.
Scott: If you wrote I am the listener that would get you in.
Rym: that would literally get you in no question at like.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I will say if anyone applies to the forum and like Within a week of this episode and you just put in the letter a in lowercase.
Rym: I would approve you.
Rym: What are the odds?
Rym: that's what a bots gonna try.
Scott: bots never gonna try the letter a.
Rym: It's the best password.
Rym: What can I say so?
Rym: death matching was a like.
Rym: the concept of a deathmatch game is Actually pretty new in terms of like gaming as a genre or something people would describe.
Scott: It's about 20 something years old.
Scott: Yeah, I'd.
Rym: so the games that did very similar things did exist for a long time in a lot of forms.
Rym: I Argue that doom and quake were what made deathmatch with a capital D becomes something that people started to try to put Even one older than that.
Rym: I don't think there is one unless you start to use broader death definitions like some of those old networks.
Rym: PC games What are were arguably deathmatches but not not a here's person shooter deathmatch like we're talking.
Scott: Here's how what it has to be to be a deathmatch, right?
Scott: It doesn't even have to be a first-person shooter.
Scott: It's a game in which there are several Characters each.
Scott: each character is a player.
Scott: All right, and you are thrown into the same arena as each other.
Scott: It can't be one-on-one cuz that's just a fighting game.
Scott: So I'm We're not done yet.
Scott: With what I've said so far, I guess a MOBA is still in the category But I'm gonna add more things to it to exclude MOBAs.
Scott: And once you're in this arena Everyone is on Generally equal footing to some degree in terms of you know what they do in the game, right?
Scott: But what the main your main goal is?
Scott: to kill the other players to destroy them in some way.
Scott: Everyone is on their own.
Scott: You're not on a team or anything.
Scott: team deathmatch is a different thing and You kill people and when you kill them You get a point.
Scott: you kill someone doesn't matter who it is.
Scott: You get a point And you compete until either time runs out and you see who got the most kills or and you said a number of kills and whoever gets that number of kills first is the winner.
Scott: and There is respawning because obviously if you just died and didn't come back like counter-strike You would it would just be you know, last man standing.
Rym: Yeah, that's a battle royale, which is a newer Genre that appeared.
Rym: that is distinct exactly.
Scott: So there has to be some sort of respawning either quake where it's immediate you die and you're instantly brought back to life on the next frame or Timer like most other games these days where you die you wait a little bit and then you play again.
Rym: So the term itself deathmatch was literally coined by John Romero.
Rym: And the other thing that I remembered like I've ever vaguely knowing the history of FPS is but I was Thinking about this more in light of the show we were gonna do.
Rym: According to people who worked at ID the idea for the deathmatch primarily came out of the team liked to play Japanese fighting games and trash-talk each other and then they started to wonder could we apply this to other games?
Rym: Could we get that same feeling in other games?
Scott: It's also just you know Would you already have a game like doom or quake stood up as a single-player game and you've got the networking code in there to?
Scott: allow Multiple people on the same map.
Scott: the deathmatch is like
Rym: you
Scott: have to write almost no code because remember have that if
Rym: doom One was the first FPS for all intents and purposes like Wolfenstein is on the line because it's almost like it's on the edge where it's literally on the line between a maze game and a FPS because the the
Scott: the
Rym: shooting is the least interesting and important part of Wolfenstein.
Rym: Wolfenstein 1 obviously, I'm not talking about recent 3d.
Scott: Well Wolfenstein 3d.
Rym: Yes, but doom Was a single-player game.
Rym: Vanishingly few people on earth had the ability to play that game multiplayer.
Scott: So I had included right in the official thing.
Scott: But yeah you can
Rym: plug some not plug a null modem in with your serial ports or be a wizard or have an IPX network or Something and you can play doom deathmatch and doom deathmatch What I find the most fascinating is that doom and quake one the first two real deathmatches.
Rym: We're just tacked on things that most of the player base will do to you also.
Rym: Oh, yeah doom - Then quake - like that the whole span.
Rym: the final do.
Scott: final doom.
Rym: it was a tacked on mode that eventually small number of people could play a genre effectively invented from nothing.
Rym: and yet the first ones are One hundred percent playable today and fun today And in many cases are better than deathmatch games that have come out recently.
Rym: like well There's not much.
Scott: there's not much you have to do To make it.
Scott: it's not much you can do to make it better.
Rym: It's like a lot of the things that made it better Arguably also made them more fiddly.
Rym: like we were playing quake one a bunch lately and last night We're playing with some friends and we all agreed that it was almost refreshing To play a deathmatch first-person shooter where there's no reloading.
Rym: There's no waiting to respawn There's no rules about being spiked.
Rym: the game just fucking goes.
Scott: pop up up go go go.
Rym: Well, like it was a lot of those said it was almost less mental effort to play despite being just as difficult.
Scott: Well that has less to do with deathmatch itself than just with the fact that newer FPS's have made a lot of those changes and add a lot of those things from quake for various reasons of their own Right, you know because they're.
Scott: you know, single-player games are trying to be easier.
Scott: their main modes are something else, right?
Scott: But as a result the it's just a side effect that the deathmatch mode Suffers from those things, right?
Scott: It's like you're trying to make half-life.
Scott: half-life was optimized for the single-player adventure play, you know mode, right?
Scott: That's it's a. there is half-life deathmatch.
Scott: It's kind of meh, right because the changes they made to half-life Yeah, I'll make it good at being a single-player story game make it not a great death.
Scott: It's not a bad deathmatch game, but it's not great.
Rym: You know a case in point a friend of ours quake 3 is nothing but deathmatch.
Scott: quake 3 doesn't even have Friggin single-player.
Scott: It was just multiplayer.
Rym: So a friend of ours Let's just call him George, but he's just a friend of ours.
Rym: We were playing.
Rym: he'd never played quake 1 before.
Rym: so we got together last night.
Rym: We played quake 1 deathmatch and not only did he do fine after the first couple rounds, but he had fun.
Rym: They yeah, how many games?
Rym: unchanged from their original release.
Rym: Decades in the past hold up Among contemporary games out of the box for someone who has zero nostalgia for them.
Scott: That is a short list.
Scott: It's like it's just like a backgammon or a chess.
Scott: I don't need to do it and doom one.
Rym: deathmatch are all our timeless games.
Rym: They happen to also be genre defining like firsts.
Scott: And if you try to gussy it up, right if you try to take backgammon and gussy it up It's like you're.
Scott: you can't make it better.
Rym: backgammon legacy.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you.
Scott: there's nothing you can do to it.
Rym: I dropped already.
Rym: I dropped a nuke on the fourth chevron on black side.
Rym: wait till the next game.
Scott: We'll see how that affects everything you look at like a modern FPS where there's all these different classes and things like that.
Rym: Oh, yeah, watch has a deathmatch mode.
Rym: It's not that fun.
Scott: Yeah, all the classes and things are great for the modes that they're meant for right where you you know You're doing some sort of competing over, you know points on the map or something on teams
Rym: Team deathmatches, which I would argue are literally a completely separate genre from deathmatches.
Rym: That is a controversial and statement that we could debate like I. Obviously no team.
Scott: I agree team deathmatch is a completely different game.
Scott: It's like I'm like almost you know, I'm saying I can only changing one rule but in that one rule change you've changed everything because.
Rym: but team deathmatch in overwatch because the classes is More fun than team deathmatch in like a quake one because the class is like.
Rym: there's a whole different dimension to team dynamics.
Rym: It's more like professional sports like football, but I digress with deathmatch.
Rym: I think a very important element is that they are stateless and that every player has the exact same Capabilities much like a fighting game.
Rym: You can all choose any fighter.
Rym: if I if you choose Ryu I can also choose Ryu.
Rym: The game is a pure unadulterated test of your skill at this specific game.
Scott: Well, there there is one not thing in deathmatch That is not a test of your skill.
Scott: Which is that?
Scott: because it's every man for them every person for themselves.
Scott: There is an element of politics in the death.
Rym: mother is.
Scott: however, there is some sort of coordination amongst the players.
Scott: You can gang up on someone and on to intentionally I would argue.
Rym: and well that is true.
Rym: in Practice these games tend to be so fast and so skill based.
Rym: well that huh?
Rym: Well, we'll get to that Someone who is skilled enough to be able to engage with politics is skilled enough to win anyway and even in the lack of communication.
Rym: The pattern of almost all deathmatch games is that the skill is not killing people while not being killed You actually you want to die.
Rym: actually dying is fine, too.
Scott: You.
Rym: sometimes you're going for a high rate of kills because the only thing that's ranking you is how many kills you've gotten.
Rym: If you kill ten people and then die That is way better than killing five people with never dying or one person and never dying or two people very slowly and never dying.
Rym: You want to so you want to kill as fast as possible and you want to optimize toward killing.
Rym: if you're losing a fight You're better off just getting killed especially if the person you're fighting with is not beating you to give that frag to someone who can't beat you and then Responding somewhere else and trying again.
Rym: It's almost like a reset but - yep in that situation The primary skill to be good at deathmatches when there's a disparate set of players is Note who is bad at the game like Oh blue is bad and target that follow them around.
Rym: Just milk them for kills over and over and over again.
Rym: That is how you win deathmatches.
Rym: if you see two people fighting Hang back and just spam them from a distance.
Rym: Maybe you'll get them both.
Rym: Let someone else do the hard work.
Rym: kill stealing is a primary component and skill of deathmatches Mm-hmm.
Scott: So the thing is all those things we just talked about Right those things align better with the old FPS is than the new one.
Rym: Oh my god, quick one.
Scott: We talked we take it.
Scott: quake one is so fast right that even if you try the politics, it's too fast Strike speed.
Rym: I tried to play counter-strike after playing quake one again a couple.
Rym: we like oh, it's like molasses like Like.
Rym: I felt like my game was broken.
Rym: I was moving so slow.
Scott: right if you play counter-strike deathmatch somehow It's like it's so slow.
Scott: politics have time to enter into the game.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, there's not.
Scott: the skilled cap is still pretty high in counter-strike.
Scott: is it gonna click on heads there?
Scott: Yeah, but it's still.
Scott: it's still lower than quake.
Scott: So You know, you're gonna have.
Scott: you're not gonna Have that situation right.
Scott: suddenly, you know ganging up on someone can counter someone with a lot of counter-strike skill Whereas in quake if someone's really good and ganging up on them isn't gonna help you.
Scott: They're too good Yeah, they're just gonna kill you.
Scott: Anyway,
Rym: yeah, if for bad four of weak FPS players getting up on one strong quake player the strong one will just get four kills Exactly, but what is interesting is I've seen this trend with quake and doom over the years that like I and it also Was true the few times we've played the new quake recently among our friends Is that up to a certain limit even if there's a big disparity in skill?
Rym: Everyone can still have fun because you're all fighting and killing and when you die your respawn instantly.
Rym: But then the better players just get more kills during that time, but you're still playing.
Scott: Yeah, so the reason so that's the thing is you Encounter strike.
Scott: when you die you're out right or if there's a respawn time where you're out So suck those games, you know a lot of games these days punish you for being bad at it by making it less fun.
Scott: It's like you literally lose fun If you suck.
Scott: if you play quake deathmatch, you might get no kills And that's obviously less fun than killing all kinds of people.
Rym: But you're still running around shooting rockets jumping.
Scott: you are non-stop running around shooting rockets for every literally you do.
Scott: there is Zero respawn time where you are dead and on the next frame you are alive.
Scott: So just you are non-stop playing the entire time.
Scott: you're moving fast.
Scott: You're exploring the map.
Scott: Hopefully the maps are interesting and are fun to interact with.
Scott: and even if you don't kill anyone ever you're still shooting people.
Scott: There's just guns lying around everywhere.
Scott: It's not like I'm not good enough.
Scott: I couldn't get the good gun.
Scott: It's like no, it's just sitting there.
Scott: You picked it up Shoot rockets and lightning and never you're gonna get to.
Scott: and great fun stuff.
Rym: I die a lot, but I still get to shoot.
Rym: that lightning got a whole bunch before I die.
Scott: Yeah, and sometimes dying is fun.
Scott: You thought you're in the water.
Scott: You shoot the lightning gun.
Scott: You kill everyone else in the water and yourself.
Scott: Oops.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I electrified the water my V I remember way back.
Rym: I said up to a point because when I was in high school I played a lot of out cuz what I had cable modems very early like 1997.
Rym: So I was playing online.
Rym: FES is all lots.
Rym: But I had friends who were serious enough about it to be semi-professional And a couple of them were like they played in leagues.
Rym: they played for real like they played real tournaments like they were serious players and I play with them casually like I wasn't as good or into it as they were but Occasionally and this is mostly they play mods like mega TF or weapons factory or whatever.
Rym: But occasionally I would try to play just deathmatch with them Couldn't move I would die instantly no matter what.
Rym: there I couldn't have any fun I could not even shoot before I was instantly dead all the time.
Scott: No, I guess you must be playing on a tiny map But the map is big enough.
Rym: or a big map full set of players.
Scott: You should be able to spawn occasionally when no one else is in the in that room.
Scott: You spawned in just like randomness and survive at least until someone shows up.
Rym: So here's a question for you Would you consider a quake map that was designed to be a one-on-one in a small room Deathmatch or not?
Rym: if it was all the same rules same same thing, but it's only one-on-one.
Rym: I Mean because that's basically just a fighting.
Scott: Are you respawning instantly respawn instantly?
Scott: It's just a big big room and it's who gets the most and who gets the most kills.
Rym: exact same quake one.
Rym: We played except the player limit is two and the room is small, right?
Scott: I think with the small room are there weapons and health and stuff in the weapons now just lying around?
Scott: Yeah, see I think so.
Scott: I mean I guess it still is a deathmatch.
Scott: the problem is it might end up being a tilted one because whoever gets that first kill Right can now pick up all the right even though the other person is gonna respawn instantly.
Scott: They had does that no matter how good you are?
Scott: There's that fraction of a second where you have to reorient your brain, right?
Scott: Yep I have a person how and the other person is still in the room and they know where the spawn points are.
Scott: you know presumably so.
Scott: there will be a rocket coming at you as you're spawning if they're any good and You will spawn and probably immediately get hit by the rocket.
Scott: Even if you're holding W as you spawn.
Rym: So the solution to that, but I would argue this is not a deathmatch.
Rym: This is something different.
Rym: But there was a mo a mod in quake one that I've really liked.
Rym: that set up an arena where two players Would be in a room with every weapon or whatever the setup was.
Rym: you both agreed on there.
Rym: it's a perfectly symmetrical small map and The doors would open.
Rym: you both run out.
Rym: you fight till one person dies Then you both are back in those rooms the doors come up you run out you fight till one person dies.
Scott: Yeah, that's not a death man.
Scott: Oh, but that's a fun game.
Rym: That was a real fun game and Overwatch is deathmatch modes are not nearly as fun as they have a mode where you're both set as the same character whether you like It or not and just whoever kills the other one first.
Rym: That's it hmm.
Rym: But I just I think that that first mode in quake one was interesting especially considering that id Developed the deathmatch rules based on the feelings they got playing games like Street Fighter 2 trash-talking each other while they played.
Scott: Yeah, you they they.
Scott: I think it's really just the the mode that comes automatically.
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: You know we're here.
Scott: We are playing this FPS.
Scott: It's an FPS.
Scott: We made a map all right.
Scott: now There's two people in the map.
Scott: yeah, all right.
Scott: well obviously it's a game about killing things.
Scott: so and now we're gonna kill each other Instead of killing AI and that gets so much more interesting cuz you can't People the most wins.
Scott: it's like the first did nothing.
Scott: You know you know game design whatsoever.
Scott: Just do it.
Scott: Yeah I do also think that one way you can mess up a deathmatch.
Scott: I think is You.
Scott: you have to have maps that are Designed to make the deathmatch good.
Scott: if you have a bad map it can sort of ruin the whole thing even with the exact Same rules and the exact same game.
Rym: exactly I would say that sometimes deathmatch is powerful enough to survive a bad map.
Scott: But so yeah, it can survive a bad map, but definitely some maps are much better than others.
Rym: Oh, what was that crazy one?
Rym: We played last night the weird multi-layer angle thing that was an A+ map.
Scott: Oh, you're the one that was like ricochet.
Scott: Yeah, yeah the outer space one with the teleporters Plus chef kiss do whoever designed that map you you should get a map design prize of some kind.
Scott: But yeah, you know there's some maps that are just really good because they'll be I think the ideal map right.
Scott: you got to have Enough space for the number of players.
Scott: if there's too many players in a small space it too much if there's not enough players in The big space is too boring.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: You got to have the right balance of different interesting Situational weapons like.
Rym: you can't have weapons that mostly do the same thing Unless you're making a deathmatch where everyone has just like a pistol and it's really simplistic and minimalist.
Scott: You want to have some areas that are really claustrophobic and contained hallways nooks and crannies So you can get stuck in there with someone.
Scott: but you also want to have your big wide open areas.
Scott: You can rocket jump and you know snipe people and also
Rym: so you can have dynamics Like if you encounter someone who appears to be strong in an area where you're not good at that kind of fighting You can try to bait them into following you into a place where you have the high ground like that.
Scott: Or if you spawn your particular weapon like, you know, maybe a grenade launcher is good in hallways Right, then you stick to the hallways.
Scott: You don't go to the big open area with the grenade launcher.
Scott: Oh now I've got the rocket launcher.
Scott: Now.
Scott: I'll go to the big open area.
Scott: See if I can get somebody.
Rym: I like maps that have a game as a.
Scott: if the game is a railgun go to the big open area.
Rym: At least one gimmick like the lava pit that you can hit the button and it just opens like I like it there being a Of some kind because it's always
Scott: really good because they force players to move, you know and usually what you're gonna be doing in a deathmatch is You know, there'll be some sort of route.
Scott: you have to go around the map.
Scott: They're always moving.
Scott: if you sit still you're gonna die.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So you got to be moving to either find or run away from players.
Rym: So you have a row is moving.
Rym: I used to call it the loop and yours do.
Scott: your loop is gonna be including health armor weapons Ammo right to keep yourself stocked up.
Scott: you encounter people you kill them and you keep going on your your route.
Scott: You might change your route based on certain situations, but you know, you're moving around all the time.
Scott: You need features in the map that cause players to change up their movement.
Scott: Yes, right like like ah, there's a quick debt.
Scott: The quad damage appears at these intervals in this particular spot.
Scott: Push a button and go up an elevator to get there, but it's so worth getting it.
Scott: So once in a while your people are gonna group up at this spot to try to get this
Rym: Or you're gonna group up away from the spot with a rocket launcher wait for all the all the noobs to group up and get a whole bunch of kills
Scott: Except the noob with the quad damage is gonna come.
Rym: Yeah, you can't let him actually get that quad damage.
Rym: That's the problem.
Scott: Yeah You know, so that's that's how it's got to do.
Rym: Yeah, but I think deathmatch is.
Rym: I think there's still a lot more space to explore in deathmatch and I wonder if Quake 1 and then if they follow on and do quake 2 and more deathmatch is not dead like it is popular.
Rym: It's just not talked about as much in a lot of gaming circles.
Rym: But deathmatch is more popular than a lot of games that you and I play.
Scott: and I think the the deathmatch.
Scott: You know, the deathmatch doesn't have to be a first-person shooter No, but I don't think it has been applied enough to non first-person shooter games.
Scott: so You know, it's like why?
Scott: why you know Smash Brothers is you know has the stock mode and the time?
Rym: Yeah, you do respond.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's sort of like a deathmatch But you have to really take a lot of health from someone to kill them in Smash Brothers.
Scott: Alright, you know, otherwise it sort of is a deathmatch.
Scott: But the fact that people have so much health like even just from spawning, you know You end up having this gameplay of grinding people down.
Scott: Imagine if you played smash we're just like.
Scott: I guess you can just do this in smash with the rules.
Scott: You know settings they let you have.
Scott: just make everything a one-hit-kill all the time and give everyone stop.
Rym: I mean, that's how quick three deathmatch just was effectively because it was literally just.
Rym: everyone has a rail gun Everyone is one shot killing because everyone gets headshots.
Scott: Yep, if you I guess if you took Smash Brothers and put it on like almost no health 30 stock One hit kill or even table time.
Rym: Remember we played that board game so many years ago at a PAX.
Rym: it was basically just like a quick three deathmatch and It actually shockingly really Recreated the feeling of playing it.
Rym: Yeah, but it was a little slow and you Yeah, obviously there were problems with it, but you could have tabletop deathmatches.
Rym: You could have top-down tap deathmatches turn-based deathmatches.
Scott: But yeah, it's like, you know, we people worry about player elimination, you know in games it's like, you know, it's like oh, yeah it's like.
Scott: well another solution for player elimination besides making it welcome is Just have people immediately respond.
Scott: all the time The train train deathmatch.
Scott: it's like run a train company as soon as it's bankrupt you get a brand new train company Who eliminated who eliminated the most train company.
Scott: your score?
Rym: Your score at the end is how many bankruptcies did you cause - how many did you did happen to you?
Scott: Yeah, exactly, right.
Scott: That's a crab bucket and you just you everyone you spawn you take a bunch of loans, right?
Rym: This Has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Scott: Okay For the logos be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi McNichol Ellen dress Linky G dread lily turn away Chris or I'm her Clinton Walton text Finn just like a dude guy.
Rym: shy 85 Rebecca done review metal 34 cowards Ryan parents and Erickson German van Horl Taylor Braun under program law at Oh Pierce at threat open seed.
Rym: right you hold the key to my heart and a whole bunch of People who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: Like I said, I did pause the patreon for one month because we skipped a bunch of shows between travel and some Early kovat waning things that we did but we're mostly on a regular schedule now.
Rym: Anyway for tonight, I leave you before I go play some quick one with That boy's got problems Same way.
Rym: when you were his age when I first met you it was all I could do just to drag you away from Wolfenstein.
Scott: Now that was a real game.
Rym: all you needed was a 486 and a 9600 bald modem.
Rym: those were the days.
Rym: Nowadays, she's all his virtual reality garbage and their fancy schmancy full sensory awareness gear.
Rym: I'm more concerned that he hasn't seen sunlight since he got that new game.
Rym: At least his little brother likes to play outside.
Rym: Where is the little grunt anyway?
Scott: Oh Dead body Whoo, it stinks.
Rym: How long's it been here man?
Scott: About three days.
Rym: Hey check this out Dumbass Where'd you get that?
Scott: Dad's closet.
Scott: He keeps all kinds of shit in there.
Rym: cool, man Must be cool to have a dad who's such a badass Was a badass.
Scott: he's whack now man.