Rym: It's Wednesday, May 26th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are reviewing Spider-Man 2099.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, I have not been called up for jury duty in like a decade.
Scott: We just talked about it.
Scott: You can figure out our whole jury duty history by listening to enough GeekNights, 'cause every time we have a jury duty, we do an episode on it.
Scott: It's the opening bit guaranteed, no matter what.
Rym: We'll probably remind you that if you're on a jury, you have a natural de facto right to nullify, in that even if someone is clearly guilty, and you're instructed just to decide if they are guilty, you can still vote not guilty if you believe the law itself is unjust, or you think the punishment is unjust.
Scott: Or you just fucking feel like it.
Scott: It's like...
Rym: It's not illegal.
Rym: They can't stop you.
Rym: They can't know your hearts.
Scott: They can give you all the instructions they want, but at the end of the day, it's like the reason you're there is 'cause you have the power to choose guilty or not guilty.
Rym: Jury of your peers.
Scott: No one can make you choose in the United States, either one.
Scott: It's up to you what you choose entirely.
Scott: And if you just have some other reason, you know, you can Google jury nullification on your own.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I suggest you do if you get called up for jury duty.
Rym: But I gotta go back in tomorrow, and I am 100% sure they will never, ever in my life.
Rym: let me sit on a jury.
Scott: Even though I really would like to be on a jury.
Scott: What two lawyers opposing each other would both look at... It could be that one of them is looking at Rym and saying, "Oh yeah, he's gonna say what I want him to
Scott: say.".
Rym: And the other one's gonna be like, "He just said he hates the
Rym: cops.".
Scott: The other one would be like, "Fuck
Scott: no.".
Scott: There is no way that two opposing lawyers would both take Rym in, question him, hear his answers, and both say, "Fuck yeah, going on my jury.
Scott: I like this
Scott: guy.".
Rym: The last time I went through Vardear, like, it was almost a scene from a comedy movie.
Rym: They asked me a question, I gave a short, honest answer, and I thought they were gonna, like, follow up or grill me because the answer was an atypical one.
Rym: Like, it was the one they wouldn't expect.
Rym: But instead, literally, both lawyers kind of look at each other and they raise their hands, and I was just dismissed with no more words, and that was it.
Rym: The question was, "Would you trust the testimony of a law enforcement officer over the testimony of a private
Rym: citizen?".
Rym: And I said, "Absolutely
Rym: not.".
Rym: Kind of waiting for them to, like, ask me why, and they were just like, "Nope.
Rym: Get out of here.
Rym: You're done.
Rym: Go
Rym: home.".
Scott: And it's like, "I will trust the testimony of any human equal to any other
Scott: human.".
Rym: I would actually trust the testimony of a cop less than a private citizen.
Scott: Could be, depends, you know, but equal at most, right?
Rym: But also, I don't trust eyewitness testimony at all because I know that it's mostly bullshit.
Scott: Of course not.
Rym: I'm going to judge based on evidence.
Scott: I'm judging going to be based on the physical evidence more than is going to outweigh what anyone says by, like, a thousand.
Rym: So, yeah, in the news, we're not going to, like, do a full review here.
Rym: We'll talk about spoilers and go in-depth on this.
Rym: At some, like, when the last Adventure Time special comes out, we'll probably do a show.
Scott: Yeah, we did episodes on the first two.
Scott: They're only making four.
Scott: I really didn't feel like making four GeekNights episodes for four Adventure Time episodes.
Rym: Because we only do 26 animation episodes a year on average now.
Scott: Yeah, so...
Rym: So four twenty-sixths of GeekNights becomes Adventure Time?
Rym: We already turned, what, five twenty-sixths of GeekNights into train game reviews?
Scott: If they do, if after the next one, the Peppermint Butler one, they're not doing any more, we'll do an episode.
Scott: But if they announce, like, "Hey, we're going to do some more even," then we'll hold off, I guess, even longer.
Rym: Yeah, but I think it's worth Geek Biting because we did watch Finn and Jake together again, the third installment.
Rym: Uh, Geek Biting, what I would say is it's good.
Rym: It's solid.
Scott: It is good.
Rym: I think it's the, it's either the weakest of the three new Distant Lands episodes.
Scott: That's not to say, it's not weak.
Rym: It's just like saying, "Oh, I had this great, like, custom donut, and then I had this fancy eclair, and then I had a really good
Rym: milkshake.".
Rym: Like, yeah, the milkshake might have been the weakest of those three, but it was still amazing.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: Uh, the one thing I would say, though, is that it was poignant.
Rym: It hit moderately hard.
Rym: I got a little bit choked up.
Rym: But it also didn't actually, like, push any particular boundaries.
Rym: It didn't really do anything particularly new or different.
Rym: And I would even argue that the major beats and moments and the story it told were already told by the show itself, and this didn't add anything.
Rym: But I still enjoyed watching it.
Scott: I agree with that.
Rym: Like, I don't think it's a different opinion of the characters, and even the Jake thing is 100% derivable from having just seen the show.
Scott: The other ones, I think, had some sort of higher concept in some sense or another.
Scott: Yeah, the Beemo one the most.
Rym: Because it played with the timeline.
Rym: It also played with your expectations about what Beemo's up to.
Rym: That character who is so 100% obviously looks exactly like Finn's dad, and you're like, "I wonder what the deal is with
Rym: that?".
Rym: Like, there's good stuff there.
Scott: This one was just really straightforward.
Scott: Yeah, it was just taking what it was on its face and just sort of tying it up in a way, right?
Scott: And then it's like, "Okay, but you didn't try to go anywhere
Scott: new.".
Scott: It wasn't as necessary.
Scott: Not even just story-wise, but art-wise or anything like that.
Rym: The Beemo one did interesting stuff and also explored an unexplored aspect of what is Beemo like when these other people aren't around for real on a real mission.
Rym: Like a real adventure.
Rym: Marceline and Bubble Gun, that one just resolved their relationship and a big chunk of the world around them in a really good way.
Rym: And this one just kind of told you something that if you were even remotely perceptive to the show, you already knew.
Rym: I guess the part I actually like the most is the whole thing with death.
Scott: Yeah, because that's a whole part of the universe that did not get enough screen time in the show.
Rym: In fact, I think most of the screen time that those characters get in the show are in those specials, and you don't actually get much plot, if anything, around them.
Scott: Right, it's like that part of the universe where death is is sort of established in some episodes.
Scott: There's one episode that really goes in on it, but other than that, there are other parts of the universe to get more attention.
Scott: So, going back there was cool, but going back there in this way was sort of like, "Well, I didn't really learn anything more.
Scott: I learned some more about it, but not that
Scott: interesting.".
Rym: Well, the most compelling arc was between life, death, and the third unnamed character, those three, because that did the stuff I like about Adventure Time.
Rym: It didn't explain everything.
Rym: It gave you just enough.
Rym: You know the gist of these characters, and you just have to infer a lot of what happened.
Rym: You don't know the whole story, and it was sad.
Rym: Life being angry was a very good moment.
Rym: That was well animated and fun.
Scott: Yeah, it's good.
Rym: So yeah, it's worth watching.
Rym: It's Adventure Time.
Rym: It is better than the weakest episode of Adventure Time.
Rym: Not that I could even name what that episode might be.
Rym: All right, you got any other news?
Rym: I guess I got a couple little things we can talk about.
Scott: Yeah, there's not any big news.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: There's that camera news.
Scott: Do people care?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know if Wednesday people care.
Scott: Right, considering we just talked about digital cameras, and then suddenly a news comes that changes some of what we said.
Scott: But yeah, the camera that I have that I use for pretty much all our video stuff and also some photo stuff is the Panasonic GH5.
Scott: The GH4 was pretty much like the first camera.
Rym: The X1, and then I have a fancy Panasonic camcorder.
Scott: Yeah, which was one of the first ones to do 4K video at any kind of reasonable consumer accessible price.
Scott: And the GH5 expanded upon that.
Scott: But now, nowadays, everyone else has gotten into that market.
Scott: So it's like, what's Panasonic going to do?
Scott: They started this thing, kind of, and everyone else has come and been eating their lunch away.
Scott: You know, Nikon, Canon, Sony, everybody.
Scott: So they announced the GH5 II and the GH6 is coming later this year.
Scott: They announced it exists, and they gave some specs, but not all the specs, right?
Scott: And basically what the deal is, the GH6 is going to record at not 6K or 8K, but 5 point something K. Right, so more than 4K at like 60, right?
Scott: It's like ridiculous, and it's going to cost $2,500.
Scott: That's a lot.
Scott: And it's like, okay, if you are someone who's a filmmaker or something like that, still $2,500 for better than 4K video.
Scott: It's like, you're waiting for that, right?
Rym: Now, it's interesting, on the Panasonic website, they have a big caveat noted about it, saying that because they have an estimate.
Scott: Nothing is final.
Rym: Yeah, the recording time, but they make a prominent note that the camera's video recording time is limited by its own temperature.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That is something we didn't talk about on the show, that the large fancy camcorders, one thing they do have often is active cooling.
Rym: So they can record, I could use my camcorder for 12 hours constantly, in hot weather.
Rym: it'll be fine.
Scott: Panasonic, they have the BGH, which is one of those box style ones, where it's literally just a box that you put a lens on and everything else is external to that, that you have to attach yourself.
Scott: And that one, I believe, has fans in it, right?
Scott: But if you have the carry around, you know, sort of SLR shaped cameras, they usually don't have fans on them.
Scott: So the cooling is a factor.
Scott: But the GH5 II, they were announcing all the upgrades of the GH5 II versus the GH5.
Scott: And I already have a GH5, so those upgrades got to be something significant to make me want to switch over, right?
Scott: And switching over actually wouldn't be, you know, prohibitive because I could sell my GH5 after I get the GH5 II and I'm just paying the difference.
Scott: So it's sort of like an upgrade fee, if you think about it that way.
Rym: I would even consider buying it from you just because all I have is an old GX1.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: The problem with the X is, it's actually a fine camera for like what I do.
Rym: The problem is, what I would want to use it for is a secondary video camera.
Rym: The X, the GX cannot output HDMI.
Scott: No, it can't do that.
Rym: It can record video, but I had to hack the firmware to record more than like 20 minutes of video because of that stupid EU tax law thing.
Scott: So they're announcing all these features for the GH5 II versus the GH5.
Scott: And they're nice features, right?
Scott: Better image stabilization, which is already amazing on the GH5, and they're making it better.
Scott: You know, more FPS on the 4K.
Scott: You know, you get the vlog included instead of having to buy it.
Rym: Ah, they did warn you the GH5 II also does not do raw video output.
Scott: No, almost no one does that.
Scott: Only like the ultra pro cameras do that.
Scott: You know, all these really nice features, right?
Scott: They're announcing, but I'm like, you know what?
Scott: Those are all really nice.
Scott: You know, if I was buying a brand new camera today, obviously I would get the GH5 II.
Scott: But those are not worth going through the hassle of paying $1,700 for the new one and then selling the old one, right?
Scott: It's like, it's like, cause none of those things really matter for what I do.
Scott: And then they come out and the last thing they say is like, by the way, also the camera can just stream on its own directly to YouTube.
Rym: Like we said, all the good new cameras are doing this.
Scott: It's like camera, you can just have camera and that, and that, and just if you've got wifi somewhere, or you can even use your phone as a hotspot and use that wifi.
Scott: And the camera will go from the camera to YouTube or Twitch or Facebook live.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: That's all you need.
Scott: Camera, internet service, no other equipment necessary.
Scott: And I'm like, God, that's the one feature to add that to the GH5.
Scott: I would have to carry around like a thousand dollar extra piece of equipment.
Scott: And they're just gonna include that shit in the camera.
Rym: Or a hundred dollar piece of equipment that won't work and might catch fire.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: And I'm like, well, maybe I will buy the new one and then upgrade.
Scott: But I have a lot of other questions.
Scott: I'm gonna, I'm gonna get the answers to these other questions.
Scott: They actually, so Panasonic did say- My strategy is I put in a pre-order just in case, but I can cancel it.
Scott: I can cancel it.
Scott: So when I, if I don't like the answers to my questions that are technical and not necessary to discuss on the show.
Scott: I'll cancel my pre-order.
Scott: But if the questions have good answers, then I'll be, I'll be good.
Rym: So they made a point actually Panasonic about why they don't include raw output in these.
Rym: It's not because they can't.
Scott: It's because- It's sort of pointless.
Rym: It's pointless because one, their image processing in the camera is better than what anyone who would use this camera professionally would probably do on their own with the raw footage.
Rym: Like it's a lot of work to take raw footage and make it look good.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Like we do, like I do with raw photos in Lightroom.
Scott: It's not really, it's not really saving you anything unless you're ultra, ultra, you know, Hollywood in case you're not using this camera.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But also that they encode at a bit rate, basically the way the camera encodes the video it saves and outputs is pretty good, like better than their previous iterations of cameras.
Rym: So they basically were pretty open about why they made that decision.
Rym: If you want to read more.
Scott: So we'll, we'll see how that goes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So that's a, that's a news.
Scott: Any other news?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So in some little news, it's kind of been for since Fujiko Mine came out, we've hit an era where Lupin generally is pretty good when it comes out and that track seems to be continuing.
Rym: Like the 3D CG movie was good.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There was a period of time where like Lupin, you know, Lupin never truly faded from the world of anime, right?
Scott: But, you know, there, the quantity of Lupin product being pushed at any given time has waxed and waned and it waned quite a bit.
Scott: In fact, at the time when our interest was the highest in our, in the college days, right?
Scott: There was only, we were mostly watching older ones and newer ones weren't coming out too much.
Scott: So like the later two thousands, they started to come right more.
Scott: And now at the anniversary times, they're coming at a steadier clip, right?
Scott: So yeah, there's more Lupins coming out lately and they're all seem to be at this relatively very good quality level.
Scott: I don't want to say they're S tier or even A tier, but it's like, I don't see any bad ones.
Scott: I don't see any bad ones.
Rym: So if you want to get back on the Lupin train, one, you could just watch that 3D CG movie.
Rym: Like it's fine.
Rym: But two, Fujiko Mine is the one that kind of started this new era of Lupin.
Rym: And it is a fantastic show that you should watch.
Rym: So, uh, the news is what we're getting specifically is there's going to be a sixth full on Lupin TV anime specifically.
Scott: How many episodes?
Scott: 26?
Rym: It doesn't actually say yet.
Rym: I'm digging through this.
Scott: Some of those Lupin TV series were longer, right?
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So part five was the one that was out.
Rym: It doesn't tell me yet how many episodes are going to be in part six, but it's for the 50th anniversary.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And the other little news we got, so Funimation has added a few more shows and, uh, they're a little bit notable.
Rym: Uh, God messenger, not that I've watched much messenger.
Rym: God messenger comes later, right?
Scott: Yes, it's messenger Z, great messenger, and then I think God messenger is after that.
Scott: It's like, uh, you know, so it seems like it seems like the Lupin part five series just came out in 2018.
Scott: So it's three years old and that one has like 24 episodes, I think.
Scott: So I imagine that the sixth one will also have a similar 24 episode run just by guessing.
Scott: I have no confirmation on that.
Rym: That little Nemo anime they picked up, which I've never actually seen except some clips, but honestly, it looks pretty good.
Scott: I've just never, just read the original little Nemo comics.
Scott: That's where the action is.
Scott: I could watch a couple episodes.
Rym: The NES game was pretty good too, though it was really hard.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, little Nemo is this thing where it's like, uh, for Windsor McKay, right?
Scott: Uh, is ridiculously good, but it's in public domain and that's why you keep seeing it coming back and being published in all sorts of places, right?
Scott: Because anyone can do it.
Scott: It's public domain.
Scott: So that'll be so awesome when that happens to something more popular than little Nemo.
Rym: The NES game was just really fun because it's got all these little animals that you can kind of like crawl into their skin or ride them around and it had a lot going on for an NES game.
Scott: Yeah, it's not a bad NES game at all.
Rym: And, uh, Space Adventure Cobra, the original one, is also going to be on Funimation now.
Scott: I think it's on Crunchyroll already.
Scott: I kind of want to watch it.
Rym: I have planned to watch it for a long time.
Rym: Way back, way, way back, Gerald at Anime World Order was of all people.
Scott: Gerald is like, Gerald is like Cobra fan number one, right?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But he sold me on it and I just haven't, I've seen some episodes.
Rym: I just never watched like a lot of it.
Rym: I never watched the whole thing.
Scott: I think I watched one episode.
Scott: I think there was like a newer, newer one, like a remake or a, you know, some, a newer version at some point.
Rym: I watched, I think we might have even reviewed that on Geek Notes.
Scott: And I think I watched one or a few episodes of that.
Rym: Did we talk about that or not?
Scott: Check our, search our website.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: If we did, it was so long ago, right?
Rym: That would have been ancient times.
Rym: I don't think we have ever reviewed it on GeekNights.
Rym: Well, alright, put that in the hopper.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: This is not a new artist, but I bumped into this song recently and it's great.
Rym: if you've never heard of Brushy One String.
Scott: I have not heard of Brushy One String.
Rym: He's a cool Jamaican singer and his shtick is that he sings while drumming on and playing a guitar that has one string on it.
Rym: He's just Brushy One String.
Rym: And he does the song Chicken in the Corn.
Rym: Apparently it was made famous in a documentary, pseudo-documentary that I've, I guess there's a real documentary.
Rym: I haven't actually seen it, but I've been, it's seen it pop up numerous times in conversation.
Rym: And I've made a point that I want to watch it at some point.
Rym: Rise Up, which is about the underground music scene in Jamaica.
Rym: And it looks like a really good documentary.
Rym: But apparently this guy was featured in it and his music is popular.
Rym: He only has three albums out.
Rym: But check this guy out, because this song is really good and really catchy.
Rym: It's a really good video.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So, manga genius Naoka Urasawa, right, who made Monster, Pluto, 20th Century Boys, etc.
Scott: Apparently had a YouTube channel.
Scott: I didn't know that until recently, so I subscribed to it.
Scott: But most of the videos I saw when I went to it weren't subtitled.
Scott: And I was, and you know, were not really useful to watch without subtitles.
Scott: So, I didn't really watch any.
Scott: I saw one show up in my feed, like, today.
Scott: And it said it had a big thing on the thumbnail, "ing
Scott: sub."
Scott: And I'm like, well, click.
Scott: I'm clicking on that.
Scott: But most of the video is actually not Urasawa talking.
Scott: He talks in the beginning and at the end to sort of introduce what the video is.
Scott: But what he is doing in the video is just illustrating one scene, right?
Scott: Just a character from his current manga Asadora, right?
Scott: Just standing, like, on a road, right, facing out of the paper, right?
Scott: But he draws it using, I guess, like, fountain pen.
Rym: Yeah, that looks like a fountain pen.
Scott: And he doesn't, he intentionally, this isn't his normal process, right?
Scott: But he intentionally does not pencil beforehand.
Scott: He's just fountain pen only.
Scott: And he explains in the video how he's trying to show you, right, how, like, you know, he draws some lines and then how the, you know, the emotion of the scene, like, appears at, like, a certain moment, right, in his process there.
Scott: And most of the video is almost entirely uncut footage of just him drawing the whole thing.
Scott: Like, every line he draws is on video here, right?
Scott: I don't know if it cuts away from him to go to the bathroom at any point, but it didn't look like it.
Scott: There's not a lot of cuts, right?
Scott: It's just him, his entire drawing from blank paper to completed.
Scott: And it's just, like, this fucking genius guy.
Scott: And then at the end, he's, like, you know, he's, like, you do a drawing and there's just so many things you want to improve.
Scott: And I'm, like, what the fuck are you going to improve?
Scott: He's, like, really makes you want to, makes you want to draw better the next day.
Scott: And I'm, like, fuck you.
Rym: Or is that me going around just recently?
Scott: I can't even draw, I can't even draw a goddamn stick figure.
Scott: And he's sitting there being that, like, that, you know, artist, the typical artist.
Scott: He's, like, oh, my beautiful drawing that I made with the fountain pen and no pencil beforehand.
Scott: Oh, yeah, you know, it's got so many problems.
Scott: I'm, like, oh, my God.
Scott: He starts by drawing, the drawing begins, right?
Scott: He's drawing the hand attached to a hat before he draws the head underneath the hat, right?
Scott: So he starts by drawing a hand attached to the brim of a hat.
Rym: Because that's the emotional center of the scene.
Scott: And then he draws the head and the neck.
Scott: And then somehow the arm, the arm comes around to meet the hand.
Scott: And everything is correct in proportion and angle wise and everything.
Scott: Even though the hand was there long before the shoulder.
Rym: Yeah, if either of us tried to do that, you know, the image where two railroad tracks meet in the middle and they don't line up?
Scott: It's, like, goddamn this guy.
Scott: But yeah, if you want to watch, you know, genius Urasawa draw a still picture, here's like YouTube dot com.
Scott: And then, you know, while watching the video, I realized, like, you know, I thought, you know, because I think he had a manga.
Scott: Wasn't there like a shonen bat manga he did?
Scott: I don't think that ever came out in English, as far as I'm aware, legally.
Rym: If it did, we just didn't notice.
Scott: I have to search again.
Scott: But I knew he was working on this Asadora manga, but it's so recent.
Scott: Like, it's it's not that old.
Scott: I didn't think it was in English, but I went and I searched and actually volume one came out like January of this year when I wasn't paying attention because, you know, pandemic going on.
Scott: So, yeah, there's two volumes out already and volume three is on the order form.
Scott: This month should be out in July.
Scott: So I went and I grabbed volume three onto my order form and I put one and two in my cart.
Scott: So maybe we'll talk about that.
Rym: All right.
Rym: In the moment, we're slowly, cautiously emerging into the world bit by bit with outdoors stuff.
Rym: I was a jury duty today, obviously, but then you went to your office one time.
Rym: I went to my office one time.
Rym: I'll go every now and then, but not going to make a habit out of it.
Rym: But yeah, no conventions yet.
Rym: Stay tuned on what we're going to do at PAX East online.
Rym: It seems like it's branded PAX East online to replace PAX East.
Scott: Well, yeah, I mean, the online PAX is the way they differentiated them geographically because obviously they're worldwide no matter what was time zones.
Scott: Right.
Scott: All of they weren't having events around the clock.
Scott: So the live streams of things were at times in the local time zone of the pack.
Scott: So the existing the car, the two packs on lines that already happened, the West one and the OS one broadcast their events at West local times and also local time.
Scott: So the PAX East online is going to put out its events at East local time.
Scott: So if you're in Australia, it'll be really inconvenient for you because all the if you want to watch live or chat live because it will be happening at the, you know, 24 hours opposite whatever or 12 hours opposite whatever time you get the idea.
Rym: But otherwise, obviously no conventions in person anytime soon.
Rym: So we're kind of just waiting.
Rym: Everything's still just hanging out in the hopper, starting to prepare the technology and pipelines for the stuff we want to start doing.
Rym: Once the pandemic, once we're more in a post COVID world, there's a lot of stuff we've wanted to do.
Rym: This kind of just on hold.
Rym: So I guess stay tuned for a lot of that biz.
Scott: A camera that live streams itself, if we get that thing and it works.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like suddenly we don't have to do the effort of setting up OBS on the computer.
Scott: We don't got to do the effort of editing video.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We can literally just go somewhere, plug microphones into it somehow, turn it on and just live stream.
Scott: So whether at a convention, just hanging out, playing a board game.
Scott: We can just turn this camera on and push a button and it streams.
Scott: You might want to follow us on YouTube, Twitch, wherever.
Scott: Because this camera might, you know, if that thing works out, we might just start random unscheduled stream whenever appropriate.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that's ultra low effort for us if it works.
Scott: Ultra low effort.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It also makes some of the larger things that are high effort easier because this reduces the amount of effort necessary.
Rym: But there is a lot of other high effort pieces we got to deal with.
Rym: Being vague because I'm not going to shit talk anything, but stay tuned.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: Book Club book, which I'm reading at a slow, I paused reading it to read a bunch of Spider-Man, but I'm going to resume reading.
Scott: I'm in a reading mood, but I'm pretty much in the mood to read anything.
Scott: So yeah, I used some of my read mood to read what we're about to talk about.
Scott: But prior to that, and probably starting after tonight, I'll do some more Genji reading.
Scott: It helps when it's warm out because then I can go on the balcony and read.
Scott: That's nicer than bed reading.
Rym: Balcony, go to the park right there because Queensbridge Park is just right next door.
Rym: Can't use our little garden yet.
Rym: There's like 20 workers and a whole bunch of platforms as they're replacing the entire facade of our stupid building.
Scott: Well.
Scott: So yeah.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Spider-Man 2099.
Rym: I will admit, I had never read any until now.
Rym: This was something that Scott would bring this comic up a lot when we were just like early days at RIT.
Rym: Like anytime superheroes came up, Scott would like make a point of saying, "Oh yeah, Spider-Man 2099.
Rym: That was the good one.
Rym: That's the one I
Rym: read.".
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So yeah, so the backstory is that when I was a kid in the early 90s, I didn't really, you know, I read comics in the newspaper and I enjoyed a Spider-Man or whatever, but I wasn't reading comic books, comic books.
Scott: And then a friend down the kid who lived down the street was reading comic books.
Scott: And then the comic book store opened in the mall.
Scott: So once the comic book store opened in the mall, well, it's like, well now, right, I can buy comic books.
Scott: So I went there and while there were many comics characters, I enjoyed like regular old Spider-Man or X-Men and, you know, all the space, cosmic stuff, obviously, you know, mostly Marvel stuff.
Scott: All the comics, you know, I just had this thing where I needed to know the whole story.
Scott: I couldn't, even then I was like against the cross.
Scott: I understood these crossovers and I was against them.
Scott: Even then, A, because I didn't have enough money to buy that many comics.
Scott: I was like, no, you're not, I'm not falling for that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But B, I was like, well, I haven't read, you're on Uncanny X-Men 200 and what?
Scott: It's like, I'm not buying 200 comics.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There weren't trade paperbacks or anything in those early nineties days, you know, and I wanted to start with number one and get the whole story.
Scott: So there were comics that I would buy.
Scott: I bought this miniseries like NX at one point, which is only like a four issue miniseries, just because it was a cool cyborg dude, but also I could get the whole, I saw number one on the shelf in the comic book store and I'm like, I can read the whole damn thing.
Scott: Hooray.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it just coincidence that at that time, 1992, I believe when I was a kid going to comic book store.
Scott: There was a new thing from Marvel, which is 2099.
Scott: They made a whole bunch of comics that were based on the idea that, well, it's the Marvel Universe, but in the year 2099, like almost over 100 years from now.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because it was 1992.
Scott: So 2099 was sort of like, you know, out there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's sort of a cyberpunk universe because it's so far out there.
Scott: And what they did is they had different series.
Scott: They had Spider-Man, obviously.
Scott: They had X-Men 2099, which I bought the first issue of, but didn't read any more of.
Scott: There was Ravage 2099, Punisher 2099, Doom 2099, and maybe some others came later.
Scott: I think there might've been a Fantastic Four 2099 later.
Scott: I could be wrong on that, but at the start they just had this set of them.
Scott: So I obviously couldn't afford to buy that in my comic books.
Scott: And as we discussed earlier, I was stupidly spending a lot of money on superhero cards.
Rym: That was something we were talking about a lot in our own life.
Rym: I did a similar thing where I would buy these fucking cards and then I'd have them and I'd piece together the stories, or at least try to piece together the stories of superheroes I'd never read because they weren't in the comics I was reading, but it would have been cheaper to just buy the comics they were in.
Scott: The first issue of Spider-Man 2099 was $1.75 in 1992 US dollars.
Scott: And nowadays a comic book would be like $3 or $4, a floppy one like that.
Scott: It had a fancy foil sort of cardboard cover and it came with a poster, I think.
Scott: But issue two was $1.25 maybe, and I think the price went up over time a little bit, but really cheap.
Scott: A pack of cards then was about the same price, maybe even more.
Rym: A pack of cards, because there are a lot of different Marvel cards.
Scott: It depended which cards you bought.
Rym: Yeah, the regular ones were about the same price for a pack as the comics, but there was this one series that was fancy, because I remember as a kid, this was probably '92, '93.
Scott: The Masterpieces one, which was an advertisement on the back of issue one of Spider-Man 2099, was an ad for Marvel Masterpieces, which were thicker cards with fancier oil painting art.
Scott: They were really unbelievable.
Scott: I have this very good art on these cards.
Rym: Very clear memory of being at the Gibraltar Trade Center in Michigan, and those cards were $4 a pack.
Scott: Yeah, they were expensive.
Scott: I only have a very small number, like a handful of those cards, because they were so much money.
Scott: But they're really nice.
Scott: Maybe I could get a full set of them on eBay cheap or something nowadays, right?
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: Anyway, so when I was a kid, Spider-Man 2099 came at an exact right time, and I bought every issue until the comic book store went out of business.
Scott: So I didn't finish the series, because the comic book store eventually went out of business when that was no longer a thing.
Scott: But that was after years, right?
Scott: It's like only 12 issues a year.
Scott: Once a month I'd go to the comic book store and get an issue.
Scott: And these issues are tiny, so you're going to get a very small amount of story every month over this very slow pace, right?
Scott: I got to like 20 or 30 issues.
Scott: That was like three or four years' worth.
Scott: And then the series ended after that, but I wasn't able to get those issues until later in life by using eBay and such.
Scott: Much later in life.
Scott: I would think I was living in Beacon maybe when I scooped those up.
Scott: The remainders?
Scott: I don't even remember.
Scott: Maybe even later than that.
Scott: So I never read the whole thing as a kid, but I read it every issue every month for a very long period of time.
Scott: And also, going back in my mind, as I became an adult and realized, I hadn't read, for example, like William Gibson novels, like pre-college I want to say even, right?
Scott: But when I would read them or watch Ghost in the Shell or something, like all these cyberpunk tropes, like I already understood them, right?
Scott: And I didn't know from where.
Scott: And then I realized, oh, it was from Spider-Man 2099.
Scott: That's where I learned all cyberpunk related things was from this comic.
Scott: And now reading it again, just yesterday, it's like there's even more stuff.
Scott: I can see that this comic borrowed from and introduced me to.
Rym: You know, it's fun because I double checked.
Rym: You know what got me into cyberpunk primarily as a kid?
Rym: Because it also came out in 1992, was Shadowrun 2nd Edition.
Rym: Because the first edition was in '89 and the second edition is the book I had.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I also just want to briefly, we got to talk about the adverts.
Scott: You know, a comic book, floppy comic books.
Scott: You read this pirated version online, right?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So I read the actual comics.
Rym: It's on Comixology, too.
Rym: I checked.
Rym: You can actually read it legit.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: But yeah, I read the actual comic books from the 90s that I have, which means the advertisements were still in there.
Scott: Oh, that's a treasure.
Scott: So, you know, we say block all ads everywhere always, which is true.
Scott: But once the thing an ad is for is no longer a thing, suddenly that ad transforms into art, right?
Scott: Because it's like you can't buy the thing anymore.
Scott: So notable things advertisement-wise, lots of ads for cards of all shapes and sizes.
Rym: Cards for so big back then.
Rym: Not that they're not big now, but...
Scott: Ads for foods like Charleston Chew or, you know, Justice Fruit Pie equivalent, right?
Scott: Lots of SNES and Game Boy game ads, right?
Scott: I mean, '92 is some peak SNES time.
Scott: Hook for SNES, you know, things of that nature.
Scott: Wing Commander SNES, Chuck Rock SNES.
Rym: Rad Final Fantasy Mystic Quest ad.
Rym: Because when Scott mentioned that he saw an ad for it, I imagined in my head what that fucking ad looked like because it was weird and I remembered it.
Scott: It was a big ad campaign in all of the video games.
Rym: It was a weird ad campaign because some of these SNES ads from the early 90s were like, "Hey, this is a game you could
Rym: play.".
Rym: But a lot of them did this weird, like, the ad almost had nothing to do with the game at all.
Rym: Like, it's a picture of a brain.
Rym: Get out of body.
Rym: Brain transplant, $40.
Rym: A tiny print at the bottom.
Rym: Final Fantasy Mystic Quest on the SNES.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Also ads for movies, which were basically, when there's an ad for a movie in a comic book, it's basically just the movie poster taking up a full page.
Scott: I saw Aladdin coming soon.
Scott: Ooh!
Scott: Disney's Aladdin coming soon.
Scott: Candyman coming soon.
Scott: Ooh!
Rym: Right?
Rym: Those hit me right in the old.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: What was the other one?
Scott: Army of Darkness coming soon.
Rym: Wow.
Scott: It's like, holy shit.
Rym: I saw all of those in the theater.
Scott: Right, it's like, I don't even know if I saw all of those.
Scott: Anyway, but yeah, the ads were really something.
Scott: And lots of ads for, like, you know, buying comic books, right?
Scott: I forgot you could subscribe to comic books, like, directly from Marvel.
Scott: Like, that was a thing.
Scott: So yeah, really interesting.
Scott: The ads are really a historic thing going on here.
Scott: Okay, so now let's talk about the comic, right?
Scott: So, Spider-Man 2099 is basically, it's far future.
Scott: It's still, it is the Marvel Universe, though.
Scott: So there was, like, this, the Marvel Universe is in the past, but clearly something has happened that has, you know, the heroic era ended, right?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's very mysterious, but all the superheroes are dead and/or gone.
Rym: Yeah, with a few caveats.
Rym: Like, Doctor Doom is doing something.
Scott: But is that the, I forget if that's the, I haven't read, I have some Doom 2099, but I haven't read enough to know if that's the original guy.
Rym: All I know is whoever is in that Doctor Doom costume is like, "Oh, just as I reemerged, so too does the Spider-Man.
Rym: There is no way.
Rym: This is a
Rym: coincidence.".
Scott: Sure.
Scott: It could be the original Doctor Doom Resurrected.
Scott: It's definitely running Latveria, which still exists somewhere on the map, right?
Scott: But clearly there's, you know, if there's a government, it's not really doing much.
Scott: It's now a very William Gibson-esque cyberpunk dystopia.
Scott: There are mega-corporations that sort of really actually run the world.
Scott: The police are just, you know, they work for the corporation, right?
Scott: They're corporate cops.
Scott: They're not public cops that someone voted for, right?
Scott: The company that runs everything is Alchemists.
Scott: If you watched these, you know, what's the Spider-Man movie?
Scott: The good one?
Rym: The animated one?
Scott: If you watched Into the Spider-Verse, the name of the company is Alchemax.
Scott: that came from this comic.
Rym: I assumed it was just Alchemax, like alchemy and chemistry.
Scott: It could be, it could be, oh sure, Alchemax, whatever.
Scott: How you pronounce it, I don't know how you pronounce it.
Scott: But that's where the company came from, right?
Scott: That was from this.
Scott: So, yeah, it's corporations run everything.
Scott: There's a cyberspace world.
Scott: You didn't get that far to actually read about the cyberspace brother.
Rym: No, I got up to reading this.
Rym: I got up to when he fights the vulture and deals with him and goes back uptown.
Scott: So there's this jerky dude who is a genius geneticist person who was brought up by the company.
Scott: Like he went to company school, right?
Scott: Because he was gifted, they brought him into the company school.
Scott: They taught him everything he knows, right?
Scott: But he's a huge asshole, right?
Scott: He's just an asshole to everyone.
Rym: Yeah, like it starts, he's being an asshole to people who deserve it.
Rym: But then he's also an asshole to like his friends, his fiance.
Scott: His fiance is like the best, awesomest person and he treats her so poorly.
Scott: It's like, why are you, how did you even get with this guy to begin with?
Scott: He treats his brother who's a really nice, you know, if somewhat milk toasty kind of guy.
Scott: You know, but talented and has his own positive traits.
Rym: Dude reminds me of a good looking cereal figgis if any of you have watched Archer.
Scott: Yeah, his name is Miguel O'Hara, right?
Scott: So his mom is Hispanic, his dad is Irish, he didn't get to that part yet.
Rym: Yeah, he did.
Rym: That came up right away.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: He breaks that up like four times.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: Because you actually see the mom and dad eventually.
Scott: Because in later issues, there's sort of a backup feature that is like young Miguel O'Hara.
Scott: And it shows him in the company school and stuff.
Scott: And you actually see his parents and everything.
Scott: We didn't get that far.
Scott: So, but yeah, he's this guy and he's just an asshole.
Scott: In his mind, when you see what he's thinking, he's not really thinking bad thoughts or doing bad things.
Scott: In fact, one of the first things you see him doing is advocating for not human testing.
Scott: He's got like a genetic device.
Scott: He doesn't want to test it on humans.
Scott: Like he has a high moral standing in terms of what he wants to do.
Scott: It's like you're presented as a good person.
Scott: He just is really rude and nasty to everybody.
Rym: Whether they deserve it or not.
Rym: He's rude and nasty to people who deserve it.
Rym: And like, it's not spoilers for this old comic book, but like in the first couple issues, like basically what happens is he's like working for this evil company.
Rym: They make him do something too evil and it causes someone to die.
Rym: It's a very RoboCop style scene.
Rym: And then he's like, fuck it.
Rym: I quit.
Rym: Fuck you all.
Rym: And he just quits and leaves.
Scott: The high moral standing.
Scott: actions wise, right?
Scott: But not behavior wise.
Rym: It doesn't work out of course, but he tries to quit.
Scott: So yeah, obviously he becomes the Spider-Man, right?
Scott: The genetics of the original Spider-Man are like in their database and he combines them with his own DNA in order to kick the company guy, the evil company boss guy, sort of gets him addicted to a drug that he will die if he doesn't get it and sort of trap him in the company.
Scott: He tries to kick the drug by modifying his own DNA.
Scott: He figures, well, I'm going to die from the drug anyway.
Scott: He's like, if this fails and I die, I'm breaking even.
Scott: So he tries it, goes wrong because this other jerk comes into the play and combines his DNA with the original Peter Parker Spider-Man's DNA.
Scott: And now he's biologically Spider-Man, right?
Scott: His webs come out of his actual, like these glands in his arms or some shit as opposed to Peter Parker who made a web shooter, right?
Scott: He climbs with claws that he has to retract, not with stickiness.
Scott: The only thing he has that's not his actual power is he has a costume that, because he's Hispanic, from the Day of the Dead festival, he had a costume made out of, what's it, UMD or something?
Rym: Yeah, like ultra unstable matter or something.
Scott: Unstable molecules fabric, UMF, I think.
Scott: I don't know, but it's basically fancy material that is bulletproof and everything.
Scott: It's really fancy and he has that because he wanted, he owns it because obviously a lot of money.
Scott: So he bought it to wear to the festival in case, you know, because the festival is going to get rowdy, right?
Scott: And then he turns that into his Spider-Man costume and now it's armored.
Scott: But other than that, all his powers are biological in nature.
Scott: And so yeah, he ends up just by, you know, he's not like even trying to be Spider-Man the way that Peter Parker decided to go out and be Spider-Man after a certain amount of time.
Scott: He's like, "All right, I'm going to go find criminals and stop
Scott: them.".
Scott: He's just caught in these scenarios, right?
Scott: Of people going after him, going after the people he knows and loves and, you know, just bumping into circumstance.
Scott: Like he has to do Spider-Man shit.
Scott: And even though his skills are not high, his powers make up for it.
Scott: And he usually wins even against like these trained killers sent to hunt him down, right?
Scott: He's just too strong for them, even though they have much more combat training and such.
Scott: And yeah, other than that, it's his cyberpunk troubles.
Rym: The first many issues are he's just trying to figure out what to do.
Scott: The first three issues are the origin.
Rym: Yeah, but it's like every time he just almost has a moment to rest, some random superpower jerk-off shows up and tries to fight him.
Scott: Yep, pretty much.
Scott: There are some issues that are too much fighting, right?
Scott: Like he fights the Vulture for most of an issue and it's sort of like, "All right,
Scott: dude.".
Scott: But all the circumstances, they get a lot done.
Scott: When they're not fighting, there's a lot happening in just a few pages, right?
Scott: There'll be like two pages where the boss, Spider-Man's girlfriend, the good one, the fianc, goes to meet the evil corporate boss, right?
Scott: Stone, Tyler Stone, yeah?
Scott: To sort of ask him, because he's like, "Hey, where's my fianc?
Scott: I haven't seen him in forever.
Scott: You're his boss.
Scott: Do you know where he
Scott: is?".
Scott: And he shows her all this shit like, "Hey, look, we're terraforming Mars.
Scott: We're terraforming under the
Scott: sea.".
Scott: He shows her all this stuff and it reveals this whole part of the universe within two pages.
Scott: And it's like, "Whoa, that's a lot of information that really fleshes out this world a
Scott: lot.".
Rym: The world is actually moderately complex in an interesting way.
Rym: I enjoyed reading what I read and I'm going to keep reading it.
Scott: It's a really good cyberpunk world because it's not really inventive as far as cyberpunk worlds go.
Scott: It came out in the early 90s after other cyberpunk things already existed, right?
Scott: Like when did Neuromancer come out, right?
Scott: Neuromancer.
Scott: No way, it came out after this.
Scott: '84, right?
Scott: So it's ten years of cyberpunk or more, right?
Scott: At least ten years of cyberpunk stuff.
Scott: it's borrowing from.
Scott: But the cops fly around on these bikes, they're 100% Akira.
Scott: Peter David is the writer on this.
Rym: You go downtown to where the corporations don't give a shit and they basically just hire random thugs to be the cops down there.
Scott: Well, so New York, it takes place in New York/Nueva York, right?
Scott: Which is very fascinating.
Scott: What they've done is the original New York is on the ground, right?
Scott: The floor of Earth.
Rym: Yeah, that's downtown in this comic.
Rym: That's literally down.
Scott: Yeah, downtown isn't south, it's down, right?
Scott: They ran out of space and they built New York at some point vertically up.
Rym: Jetson style.
Scott: It's sort of Jetson style in that it's up, but it's not Jetson style where everything's spread out.
Scott: It's compacted and up, right?
Scott: So if you're up in New New York, up above, you're in a flying maglev car, right?
Scott: You're not using the wheels on the car.
Scott: You're in a skyscraper because everything is a skyscraper, right?
Scott: There's no dirt.
Scott: If you've got dirt, you've got the dirt from somewhere, right?
Scott: You go to the park, it's not dirt.
Scott: It's like a floating platform of some kind, right?
Scott: And then you can pop the wheels out of your maglev car, bop onto a road, drive down a tunnel that goes down and come out into the old New York on the ground where everything sucks and everyone's either unemployed or part of a gang, and it's the warriors down there, right?
Scott: And everything up above is cyberpunk dystopia, so it's either the warriors cyberpunk or evil, wealthy cyberpunk people on top, right?
Scott: It's kind of a fascinating world.
Rym: Especially because it's all layered over this, like, the precursor, like, the people who are reading other Marvel comics have fresh in their minds what was going on in the Marvel comics in the contemporary era, and you see echoes of what was going on in this future era.
Rym: Like, there's the people who've worshipped Thor, like, the Thorites wandering around dressing up like Thor.
Scott: Even though the heroic era has ended, clearly it was so impactful, right?
Scott: I mean, if anything from the real Marvel universe was real, that would impact history forever, right?
Scott: And so it does.
Scott: So yeah, there's the people who believe in Thor, like, that's their religion, and some of them are fanatical and some of them are sort of normal.
Scott: They just believe in Thor the way, like, a normal Christian person would believe in God, you know?
Scott: It's like, you know, whatever.
Scott: And then you have, for example, you know, you might not, if you're not, you know, I didn't realize this as a kid, but like, they taught, like, one of the evil cyber companies is Stark Fujikawa.
Scott: It's like, oh, at some point Iron Man's company merged with a Japanese company.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: One sour note that does not hold up well is that the first villain he fights is this, like, super fakie Japanese samurai stereotype.
Scott: No, the first villain he fights is Venture.
Rym: True.
Scott: The second villain he fights is- Venture's cool.
Scott: The Specialist is the second one.
Rym: The Specialist is a stereotypical- He is a samurai, screaming, fanatic Japanese with both a samurai sword and nunchucks for some reason.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's the typical, you know, racist stereotype depiction of, you know, of Asian-ness, especially Japanese, you know, imagery and aesthetic merged with the cyberpunk stuff.
Scott: So it's very in with the times and the style there, but it's, you know, a very, you know, the depiction is like, oh, we have to uphold our honor, right?
Scott: And it's like, oh, God, really?
Scott: But it's from 1992, so, you know, it doesn't excuse it, but I gotta point it out that it's there, right?
Scott: It doesn't hold up well at all.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, the character is dispatched and it moves on from that pretty quick, but that corporation is still one of the major players, so it's not gonna go away entirely.
Scott: No, that plot definitely comes back into play after a certain point.
Scott: But yeah, if you want to read a Spider-Man story, right, but you don't have to know shit about anything else- Yeah, you don't need to know anything.
Rym: If you ever heard of Thor, all right, you're good.
Scott: Right, it's like, if you know some stuff about the Marvel Universe, like, it plays in, but not really.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: There is a, you didn't get to the crossover, there's a Hammer-Thor-related crossover at some point.
Rym: Oh, Thor shows up?
Rym: How could I have possibly?
Scott: Well, no, there's one issue, the crossover that comes, I forget what it's actually called, it's Hammer-something, it's related to the Thorites, but it's one issue in each of the 2099 comics, right?
Scott: So I forget what the order is of that, but it's basically like you would have to stop reading Spider-Man 2099 for a minute and read, like, a Doom issue, a Ravage issue, a Punisher issue, right, to get the whole story together.
Scott: It's a very tiny little crossover.
Rym: I can deal with that.
Scott: And after that, it's sort of, I don't think it crossovers again after that.
Scott: I think it just keeps going straight.
Scott: I don't know if they wrap, you know, I don't think I ever finished all the issues that came out at the time, so I don't know if it ever, like, wraps things up.
Scott: But what does happen is over the years, you know, obviously there was a big gap of many years, but they started using Spider-Man 2099 again in other comics, like, he still exists.
Scott: There have been other Marvel comics where he came as a character, like, from another dimension or they went to the 2099 dimension or, you know, I think he was trapped in the regular Marvel universe for some time and then got sent back.
Scott: It's like, you know, Miguel O'Hara, the character, he keeps going and he's still a part of Marvel in some ways, right?
Scott: But this core story of Spider-Man 2099 is, you know, I don't know if it ends, but it goes and then they don't print any more comics, so it's ending whether you like it or not.
Rym: Yeah, the dialogue is actually better than the other comics I read from that era.
Rym: Like, it's a little verbose like these kinds of comics tend to be, but the dialogue actually conveys a lot of information.
Scott: You don't get the "I hit you, you little guy," right?
Scott: It's like when they're fighting and all the frames and the panels are full of combat, they're actually just talking to each other, like, about, you know, whatever it is that is at issue here, right?
Scott: Usually they're like bargaining, right?
Scott: It's like, "Listen, just stop fighting me and, you know, I know what you want.
Scott: This is what I want," right?
Scott: It's like, "Don't kill me.
Scott: What if I kill
Scott: you?".
Scott: You know, that's the kind of conversation they're having.
Scott: It's just sort of a big contrast with regular Spider-Man who will have sort of witty, good-natured banter, right?
Scott: And not generally kill people.
Scott: Spider-Man 2099 will be an asshole to people and kill them by accident.
Scott: Like, he kills people and he's like, "Oh, fuck," right?
Scott: He's like, "Oops," because he's like usually with his claws by accident because he forgets he has them, right?
Scott: It's like he slits a dude's throat with the claws and he's like, "Oh, fuck.
Scott: I wasn't trying to do that.
Scott: Oh,
Scott: no.".
Rym: He's still learning his powers.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Just, you know, just killing people by accident, that's all.
Scott: You know, no big deal.
Scott: Just murder.
Rym: But it's also got just like a pretty fun and varied cast of characters and I'm honestly pretty into it.
Rym: Like, there's not really much to spoil.
Scott: I grew up on this thing, right?
Scott: Like, I was reading this every month.
Scott: This is like my number one thing from like the early 90s for three or four plus years, right?
Scott: And that really, you know, looking like I didn't think about it much at the time, like after I, you know, but now that I think about it, it's like, "Oh, that really doesn't form a lot of what I like
Scott: now.".
Scott: I like things like this and this was probably the first thing like this that I was into, right?
Scott: That probably set my taste, I think, more so than a lot of things.
Scott: Oh, one last somewhat unrelated thing.
Scott: So, I guess you wouldn't see this either not having read the actual issues.
Scott: But in the day, they would always dedicate a page of each comic to the bullpen bulletin, which is sort of like this behind the scenes sort of like you'd get one, there would be a one panel comic, like a far side, but it would be, the main character of it would be the editor-in-chief of Marvel Comics, right?
Scott: The top half would be a letter from Stan Lee and the bottom half would be a letter from the editor-in-chief guy, who at the time I think was, was it Tom DeFalco, I guess, maybe?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I had to look at it again.
Scott: And it was like telling you about what was going on at Marvel Comics, right?
Scott: And it sort of was interesting in that even if you were just reading one Marvel comic, by reading this thing, you sort of got this behind the scenes.
Scott: They brought you, sort of gave you more of a community feeling, right?
Scott: Like, "Hey, Marvel readers, you're in with us, right?
Scott: Let us...".
Scott: Because if you didn't have that, you would just be reading the comic.
Scott: As a kid, you're not looking at who the writer is.
Scott: I didn't pay attention to who the writer was until late 2000s, right?
Scott: I didn't know Peter David's name before then.
Scott: Now I know exactly who he is, right?
Scott: But I didn't know it.
Scott: then, even though we wrote all of these issues, pretty much.
Scott: And that sort of community building, by having that one page, I think is something that nowadays we have it, but we have it so much that you don't notice it.
Scott: Like, someone has a Patreon, it's like you are involved with the creators on everything, right?
Scott: It's like no matter what art you're into, like you know who the creators are, you're following them on Twitter, that's sort of like automatic, right?
Scott: That you're in that behind the scenes, knowing what the creators are up to community thing.
Scott: You don't have this sort of "you're only getting the artwork and the creators are inaccessible and unknown unless they purposefully bring you in" kind of thing.
Scott: So that really stood out to me, that bullpen bulletin page.
Scott: And also, just to wrap this up with another feel old, the bullpen bulletin page in the very first issue, Stan Lee's note is basically an advertisement because he's so excited that X-Men cartoon is about to be on Fox.
Rym: Oh no, I remember when that premiered.
Scott: Stan Lee's like "X-Men's gonna be on Fox real soon" and I'm so excited that it's not... Yeah, and he's excited because it's actually true to what X-Men is about and isn't, you know, one of those messed up adaptations.
Scott: And then in the further issues, like four or five issues in, you start seeing ads for X-Men cartoon VHS tapes.
Scott: Because each of these issues is a month apart, so yeah, by the time you're on issue five, you've seen a bunch of episodes, they're weekly, right?
Scott: The VHS tapes are coming.
Scott: That dates this comic.
Rym: Yup, and I guess the last thing is the dialogue, it is clear.
Rym: these characters say the word "fuck" specifically a lot and they just translate it to "shock", but the way they use the word "shock" is 100% just "fuck".
Scott: Yes, obviously, but I think it gives it sort of like a, they're trying to increase the cyberpunk feel, right, of like.
Scott: people have a different language, but they didn't go far enough with it, right?
Scott: People still have, like, you know, their 20th century accents from whatever, you know, nationality it was.
Scott: I feel like by 2099, there's gonna be a lot more, you know, a lot less of that, right?
Rym: Yeah, I mean, what do we sound like compared to people from the, like, 70s?
Rym: Mostly, we just use a lot of new jargon.
Scott: Same swears, for the most part.
Scott: Accents that, like, my parents' generation had, a lot of those are fading already, right?
Rym: Yeah, though I did see a thing about how.
Rym: there's a strong argument that the total number of English accents is not changing, it's just that different ones are gaining prominence, and localized, like, they're localized based on interest and internet stuff as opposed to physical location with a few exceptions.
Scott: That's good.
Scott: Oh, I guess we didn't talk about the artwork at all.
Scott: The artwork in this comic is serviceable 90s comic artwork.
Rym: Because some parts of it, like, not Mobius quality, but, like, it has this Mobius aesthetic to it, like some of the sci-fi-y stuff.
Rym: But some parts of it are just very comic book punching.
Scott: Yeah, I think what it is, is you can definitely see the effort that, who's the penciler?
Scott: Was it Leonardo?
Rym: Oh, they're really trying to make it look good, and look cool, and look different, and they're definitely leaning into the "it is the future, things are weird, for
Rym: real.".
Scott: Yeah, but there are some parts where the effort level clearly goes up on the drawing, right?
Scott: So it's like, there'll be these really impactful panels suddenly, where, like, you can tell that all the artists, the inker, the color, everyone, just like, that was a big two-page spread, they went hard, right?
Scott: And then there'll be a bunch of panels you're flipping through quickly, and you can see that they didn't put as much effort onto those, right?
Scott: They're not as detailed, they're not as attention-grabbing.
Scott: And then you'll turn the page, and you'll see one that's amazing, and it looks like Spider-Man 2099 is coming out of the page at you, and staring you right in the face, right?
Scott: With something really intense.
Scott: And then the next page is just a lot more sketchy, just, alright, breeze through this, right?
Scott: And it's sort of like, okay, you wanna be disappointed, they didn't put as much effort into all the art, but also, that effort controls the pacing and impact of the story as it goes, 'cause you, okay, flip through, flip through, suddenly don't flip through, right?
Scott: Really, you know, this page you're gonna spend some time on, so they'll put better art to sort of keep you on this page longer, right?
Rym: But it also serves a good purpose of, it's often a little disorienting about where the characters are in space, but usually, especially during a fight, at least in the issues I read so far, but that almost serves to highlight how disoriented the characters are in terms of what's going on.
Rym: Like, he didn't even know a lot about downtown.
Scott: Dude, Spider-Man 2099 is this dude who's been living in the fancy cyberspace.
Rym: Imagine someone who was born, went to Google school, worked at Google his whole life, quit Google when they made him kill somebody, and now he's pissed at Google, and has literally, like, never ridden the subway before.
Scott: And his biology has gotten completely fucked up with a bunch of powers, right?
Scott: And it's like, all these, like, first year of this comic, the dude doesn't even get to go back to his apartment for more than five minutes.
Scott: And he's getting bounced around all over town by villains, and it's just like, he's on this hell rollercoaster.
Scott: He's a jerk, but he's getting bounced around like this hell rollercoaster of life between different situations.
Scott: Like, he can't just, like, you know, take a nap or fucking, you know, stop and eat a sandwich.
Scott: Like, he is just, like, everything that's bad is happening to him constantly.
Scott: And, you know, everyone in his life is trying to find him, like, "Where are you?
Scott: I've been trying to call you for
Scott: days.".
Scott: He's like, you know.
Rym: Yeah, I'd say it's pretty worth reading.
Scott: Yeah, no good very bad month.
Rym: So, if you want to scratch a Spider-Man itch, and you also want to scratch a cyberpunk itch, you could do a lot worse than Spider-Man 2099.
Scott: You could also, you know, Peter David, who wrote this, is a really good comic writer, so if you like this, you can look up other comics that Peter David has written.
Scott: He is quite good.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi McNichol, Alan Joyce, Link E, G-Dread, Lily Tenebrae, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, JustLikeADudeGuy, Kashiyaia85, Program ThreadOpen, SeedUndertakeLawAdoption, Pierce Absorb, Rebecca Dunn, ReviewMadBull, 34 Cowards, Ryan Perrin, Sam Erickson, Shervin Harrell, Taylor Braun, Ewold, TheGeedOfMyHeart, and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: It's weird being outside, but bit by bit, I'm going out and doing things.
Rym: I got a little more jury duty tomorrow, so you won't see a lot of new content from me until maybe the weekend, but I'm working on something.
Rym: But anyway, now I leave you with...
Scott: Oh, did you get any cool birthday presents?
Scott: Presents?
Scott: Like Christmas presents?
Scott: No, just presents, like stuff you want or stuff you need.
Rym: No.
Scott: Why would I get presents on my birthday?
Scott: It's like a Christmas thing.
Scott: So what do you do on your birthday?
Scott: Just usual stuff.
Scott: Have cake.
Scott: We had a big steak dinner.
Scott: That was awesome.
Rym: Have a couple people over.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And you get your birthday tickles, of course.
Scott: I'm sorry.
Scott: Your... Your birthday tickles.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Tickles on your birthday.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So you're getting tickled?
Scott: No, why would I get tickled?
Scott: Because you just said birthday tickles.
Scott: Yeah, you get to tickle your parents on your birthday.
Scott: So you tickle your... Yeah, like I get to tickle my mom, and then I get to tickle my dad.
Scott: So on their birthdays, you don't buy them a gift?
Scott: No, they get birthday tickles, and my dad gets to tickle me and my mom, and my mom gets to tickle me and my dad.
Scott: How long are you tickling each other for?
Scott: Just like a standard amount, like 30 to 45 minutes probably.