Rym: It's Wednesday, September 22nd, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we're talking about those anime magazines you all forgot about.
Scott: Comic magazines, too.
Rym: Also comic magazines.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So today, I did something that I haven't done in almost two years.
Rym: Almost two years.
Rym: Alright, so something involving the pre-COVID world.
Scott: Yeah, I went to my office where my employer rents office space.
Rym: I was actually at my office today, but I go in like once every other week-ish, maybe.
Scott: I hadn't been there and I'm not going back there.
Scott: It's unlikely I'll go back there ever, question mark?
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: So I went there because apparently there were some people coming in.
Scott: I don't know how many, but when I was there, I saw on these two floors and on the bottom floor where I worked, there were two human beings that I saw.
Scott: One was eating and one was working on this giant office floor with many, many desks.
Scott: But I guess they had some people coming in and they wanted to clear out desks that hadn't been used.
Scott: Because my stuff had just been sitting there like a little Scott Museum.
Rym: Oh, we're doing something similar.
Rym: People who haven't used their desk in a long time are getting moved to less great locations, it looks like.
Scott: Right, so they put my stuff into boxes into a closet, I guess, and I said, "Alright, I guess I'll come get
Scott: it.".
Scott: So I went there and I didn't see the person who boxed them up, the office managing person.
Scott: She was just like, "Yeah, I left your boxes in the kitchen area on that floor.
Scott: Go get
Scott: them.".
Scott: And smartly, I brought some FreshDirect bags with me because carrying boxes on the subway sucks.
Rym: I love how everyone in New York City has like 50 FreshDirect bags that we're using for all these kinds of tasks.
Scott: The IKEA bag would also have worked.
Rym: Yeah, but the FreshDirect bag, how often do you go to IKEA?
Rym: I've got so many FreshDirect bags, even considering how many we donated.
Scott: So yeah, I was able to add handles to the boxes and bring them home.
Scott: But the thing is, now that they're home, it's like, "Aw shit, I remember all the things now that I see the things.
Scott: I remember all these things, but I did not remember having all these fucking things.
Scott: I have no use for these things at
Scott: home.".
Rym: Yup, it's like, "Let's see, what do I got at my
Rym: desk?".
Scott: "I've got so much garbage
Scott: here.".
Rym: "I got a Goomba, I got a couple of plaques, I got a bunch of
Rym: packs.".
Rym: You know what the saddest thing is?
Rym: You know what's actually in my desk, like in my drawer right now?
Rym: The Marantz, the microphones, and basically a lot of the shit that I brought to PAX East right before COVID.
Scott: I mean, you know, tchotchkes are one thing, but I had a pair of shoes that were like the office-only shoes.
Rym: My office-only shoes are in my desk next to the Marantz.
Rym: Well, one of the Marantz's.
Scott: I got a salad bowl for the salad lunch place.
Scott: There was a whole very light hoodie thing that I forgot I had.
Rym: So when I went in today, I wore a jacket, like a sport jacket.
Rym: When I got to work, an identical sport jacket that I'd left there was sitting, like hanging over the back of my chair.
Rym: Because I'd left it there at some point in the past, so now I have two jackets hanging over that chair that are actually the same jacket.
Scott: Uh, yeah.
Scott: So, there was so much junk there, and I don't need all this junk, so we're gonna bring back the segment, second dibs.
Scott: Here we go, you ready?
Scott: So, I have for you today, if you're watching our stream on YouTube, you can see it.
Scott: A keyboard!
Scott: Because obviously I wasn't gonna use whatever shitty keyboard work gave me, right?
Scott: That looks like a nice keyboard.
Scott: Some Dell garbage, right?
Scott: So, this keyboard I bought in the year 2015.
Scott: It is a six-year-old keyboard.
Scott: It is identical to the keyboard on my desk.
Scott: I bought a second one of these, that's how much I liked it.
Scott: It's a code WASD, it's a code keyboard by WASD keyboards, model V2B.
Scott: It is a USB keyboard.
Scott: It has the completely normal key layout with a numpad, nothing strange about it.
Scott: The keys, the switches in this one are a Cherry MX Clear switches.
Scott: The ones in the one on my desk are brown switches.
Scott: I tested them, and I prefer the brown, so the clear one's gonna go.
Rym: I use brown at work.
Rym: I like brown.
Rym: I mean, I prefer blue, ideally.
Scott: I had the clear ones at work, and then I bought the brown ones for home, and I think I do prefer the brown.
Rym: What's the deal with the clear ones?
Rym: I actually forget which one that is.
Scott: It's basically the same as brown, only I think that the strength is different.
Rym: Okay, okay.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: They feel a little mushier and less clicky than the brown one.
Rym: Oh yeah, the clickier the better.
Rym: That's why I like blue and black the most.
Scott: Well, I mean, I like blue the most, except for the noise, otherwise I would get blue.
Rym: I just live with the noise, but to my credit, I did not get blue at work, because I feel like someone would have killed me.
Scott: Yeah, so the other thing, this keyboard has a bunch of dip switches on the back for various settings.
Scott: So my favorite setting is the one that lets you turn the cap slot key in hardware into control or command or whatever, so that way you don't need to mess around.
Scott: On Windows, you still need to do some registry editing to remap the key, but you just remap it in hardware, it'll just work.
Scott: You can also do other things like flip your alt and windows keys, things of that nature, you know.
Scott: It's a micro USB keyboard, you get a cable, it comes with a cable, and I have it here for you.
Scott: And micro USB goes into the keyboard, and the other end is whatever you want, probably regular USB.
Scott: It's a keyboard, it types, it's working perfectly.
Scott: However, the only thing is, it is from 2015.
Scott: So the keys are the original, the key caps are the original ABS key caps, and they've been A, sitting in an office, and B, were touched by my grubby hands for years and years.
Scott: So they're all shiny and kind of gross.
Rym: You can clean them.
Rym: Yeah, that shininess, you just got to live with it.
Scott: You can clean them if you want to, but what I recommend you do is get this keyboard from me, and then go online and do what I did to my other keyboard, the one I have at home right here.
Scott: And buy some PBT key caps, right, made of the different plastic, not the ABS plastic, and they'll never get shiny, and they have that nice texture to them.
Scott: And I'll give you the keyboard, the key cap swapping tool also, because I have a whole pile of them.
Scott: So you can swap all the keys on it really easily, just go online and find any, you know, Cherry MX compatible key cap set for a 104 key keyboard with the colors that match your preference that are made of PBT.
Scott: Oh, and the keyboard has a backlight, so you want to get some double shot ones, that way the light will shine through the lettering on the keys, right.
Scott: If you don't get a double shot one, the lights will sort of be like, because there's a little LED in every single key.
Scott: So if you don't get double shot keys, the light will be really meh, you're sort of wasting it, right.
Scott: So yeah, this keyboard available, I don't know, I guess, you know, if really no one wants it, it could be free.
Scott: But actually, you know, it costs a lot of money to buy it, you know, also for some amount of money, like what, you know, how much did this thing fucking cost me?
Scott: I don't even know.
Rym: I don't think, especially with COVID getting in my way, like, I kind of forget what things cost because I own everything I need.
Scott: Okay, so in the year 2015, it cost $170.
Rym: That's a lot more than I paid for my fancy keyboard.
Scott: Well, that was with, that was with tax.
Scott: Let's see what they charge for them brand new at the WASD website.
Scott: Let's see, WASD keyboards, mechanical keyboards.
Rym: Alright, look at what my keyboard costs now.
Scott: Yeah, they charge like a hundred, they still charge $185 for the equivalent, the current model of this keyboard, so.
Rym: Alright, the new DOS keyboards are around the same amount of money, it looks like.
Scott: Yeah, okay, okay, and actually they're charging, oh, that's without, without keycaps, they're charging $130.
Rym: Though mine, the keyboard I own was only $120, so, Mr.
Rym: La-Dee-Da with his fancy keyboard.
Scott: Well, I don't need, I don't need the money that badly, and this is also really old and used, so, I mean, what, $50, right?
Scott: Maybe $70 at the most, something like that.
Scott: If you need a mechanical keyboard, you know, come contact me.
Rym: Alright, so a little bit of news.
Scott: And I got, I got a lot more junk here to get rid of too, we'll see about that in the future.
Scott: Oh, and the listener who took the monitor from last time seemed to be very happy with it, so, this is a good program.
Rym: The problem is the things I want to give away are too low quality.
Scott: Yeah, I got, I got low quality things to give away, but most of them I gave away on Facebook Marketplace.
Scott: Someone came yesterday and got my, the ethernet cable that used to connect from in my bedroom at Beacon, all the way down the hallway, all the way across the hallway, all the way over to the cable.
Rym: I remember that ethernet cable.
Scott: The mega long, beat up ethernet cable, like, it still worked, I tested it.
Scott: I don't know how long it was, ridiculously long.
Scott: Someone came and took it for free, I'm like, here you go, they were very happy.
Rym: Alright, so, before we get to some news, I got a little geek bite, because I continue to watch a lot of cartoons that Scott doesn't watch, and other than, you know, Rick and Morty we'll all talk about in another show, like, now that I had a big finale and changed everything up, and pissed off all the fanboys, but Star Trek Lower Decks, I finally watched some of this show, and what I got to say about it is, if you're not a fan of Star Trek, I have
Scott: no idea.
Scott: Oh, it's not a pirate, I thought, when you said Lower Decks, I was like, oh, I thought it was a pirate show.
Rym: No, it is, so it's literally, you know, you've seen some Star Trek, and I don't really like Star Trek, but it's always focused on, like, the important ship, and the officers running the important ship, like, it's always the big bucky mucks.
Scott: And this is basically on an important ship, but it's focused on people who die.
Rym: This is on, like, the second tier ship, like, the ship that comes in after first contact to literally deal with the follow-up to first contact, like, that kind of thing, like, boldly going where the Enterprise just went.
Scott: Oh, so it's not even the same ship, it's, like, another ship.
Rym: Yeah, well, also, you realize all the Star Treks are, like, completely different ships, one of them is not even on a ship, it's not a space station, like...
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Rym: Okay, so anyway, this show is about, like, the low-ranking, like, grunts just, like, sleeping in hallways and, like, doing the normal job, but it fits all of that pretty well within the canon of Star Trek, which is actually pretty interesting.
Rym: So, the way that you...
Scott: 'Cause I'm about to ask, like, I know enough about Star Trek to know that it's basically space, communism, paradise, utopia.
Scott: It is.
Scott: Why would you take that job if you were a human being and not, like, a robot?
Rym: Because those jobs still require extreme skill.
Rym: Think like, uh...
Scott: But why would you want it?
Scott: That answer is why they need it, it's not.
Scott: why would you do it.
Rym: Well, the same reason.
Rym: why would someone...
Scott: You could just live in space communist utopia on Earth.
Rym: Yeah, so, uh, if you've watched Star Trek, the answer to that question is just the same as the answer in They Were Eleven.
Rym: Most people just live in space communism, no give a shit.
Rym: The people who are bored with that are the people who joined Starfleet.
Scott: Right, if I was bored with it, it would make sense why I would be Captain Picard or whatever.
Rym: Yeah, how do you think Captain Picard got there?
Scott: Why I would be in the engine room on the Enterprise, why would I want to do that?
Rym: 'Cause everyone at the top goes through all of that to learn how the fuck everything works along the way.
Rym: The lowest-ranking Starfleet officer is still the best of the best of the best of the best.
Scott: But if you're just gonna die before you can be Captain Picard...
Rym: They don't die, the red shirt thing was mostly the original show.
Rym: There is not a high body count in like...
Scott: Space is very dangerous.
Rym: Yeah, and also they have a lot of technology.
Rym: Anyway, the way the show progresses is it both...
Scott: Earth safe.
Rym: It makes fun of Star Trek canon pretty directly.
Rym: It's full of references that anyone who's watched the existing canon of Star Trek will get, understand, and appreciate.
Rym: It is earnestly funny.
Rym: But it also fits pretty well into the canon of Star Trek.
Rym: It looks like they're taking great pains to not break any of the canon.
Rym: So where this show plausibly is in the same universe as Next Generation or Voyager or whatever.
Scott: But if you're not a Star Trek fan, it's gonna be a miss.
Scott: You won't get it.
Rym: I feel like if you're not a Star Trek fan, but you're a fan of science fiction comedy... I think you would still find the show engaging and funny.
Rym: I think the jokes... Kind of like we talked about Spider-Man on another show.
Rym: Most people in America at least have a passing understanding of Star Trek.
Rym: So that if they watch this, they'll get enough of it to where it'll still be funny and make sense.
Scott: You just won't get the inside inside jokes?
Rym: Yeah, you won't get the inside jokes.
Rym: You won't really get.
Rym: the fact that someone says they're serving on the Voyager is really funny.
Rym: But you'll get like, "Yeah, that's probably the name of a
Rym: ship.".
Rym: "Wasn't that the ship in that other show I didn't watch or I heard
Rym: of?".
Rym: But the voice acting is funny.
Rym: It's really rapid fire.
Rym: There's a lot of characters.
Rym: And it seems like it's got a good thing going on.
Rym: I would recommend it if you even passingly enjoy Star Trek.
Rym: The humor is also quite dark.
Rym: And I appreciate that.
Rym: So in some other big anime news that we just haven't had a chance to talk about yet... There's a live-action Cowboy Bebop that is actually happening.
Scott: Yeah, I don't even know if this qualifies as anime news because it's not anime.
Scott: It's not animated.
Scott: It's a live-action TV show that Netflix is making.
Scott: It just happens to be an adaptation of Cowboy Bebop.
Scott: Now usually, I'd say 99.99% of the time, the thing I say is like, "Why?
Scott: Why does this need to be
Scott: done?".
Scott: You can just show Cowboy Bebop, "Why do you need to remake
Scott: it?".
Scott: If you think there's money to be made from this property, then just take what already exists and just fucking show it to people.
Scott: People who haven't seen it won't know that it's old.
Scott: Just pretend it's new.
Rym: Especially, it's a trend you saw in America a lot where a lot of just basic people just sort of have this idea that animation is for kids.
Rym: And that the animated version of something is inferior, so if something's mature enough or good enough, then there'll be a live-action version of it and that's the one they'll watch.
Rym: That idea has been very pernicious in America in particular, and it's not uncommon in the rest of the world either.
Scott: And also, on top of that, it's like, "Why does this need to be
Scott: done?"
Scott: is the first question, which I still don't see.
Scott: why it needs to be done ever.
Scott: But B, most of the time when people do it, it's garbage.
Scott: There's very, very few, if any, live-action adaptations of things that were originally animated properties that are any fucking good.
Scott: So you got your live-action Disney remakes of Disney animated films.
Rym: Except those are animated.
Rym: They're just 3D CG, photorealistic.
Rym: They're not live-action.
Scott: I'm just saying.
Rym: It's just funny that so many people, like this gets back into that other problem, a lot of Americans refer to those Disney movies as the live-action versions because they fall into that same trope of, "Well, they took this old good Disney thing, but now they made it
Rym: real.".
Rym: But it's still literally just 3D CG.
Rym: It's still an animated cartoon.
Scott: There's a live-action Ghost in the Shell.
Scott: It exists.
Scott: I've never seen it.
Rym: Yeah, I have no intention of seeing it.
Scott: I have no intention of seeing it at all.
Rym: The best I've heard is, I think, that Battle Angel Alita.
Rym: People I trust said it was better than they expected, and that's as far as I got.
Scott: Battle Angel Alita was not... I don't think there's an... Is there an anime for that?
Scott: I thought it was just a manga.
Rym: I've never actually seen any of it.
Rym: That's not the kind of anime.
Scott: I've read a couple volumes of the manga.
Scott: I don't know if there's an anime of it or not.
Scott: There might be.
Scott: Regardless.
Scott: There's not a lot of success going that route.
Scott: So, why do this?
Scott: But, the only thing I gotta say about this particular instance is that, judging based on the materials and the facts and information that they have released so far...
Rym: Especially information that was released today that I'm about to touch on.
Rym: I don't know if you saw this.
Scott: For example, they told us Yokokana was involved in the music.
Scott: We've seen the cast.
Scott: We've seen shots from production shots of what it looks like.
Scott: And the indication is that this is probably likely... Can't guarantee it could still be garbage.
Scott: This is likely as good as anyone's ever done on this kind of endeavor.
Rym: But the most important thing...
Scott: Good?
Scott: I guess?
Rym: And I'll link to the article that was on Animator News Network today.
Rym: The showrunners have confirmed that it is not going to be a remake of any of the animated show.
Rym: It's just going to be more of that show.
Rym: All original stories in that universe canonically expanding it without necessarily remaking any of it.
Scott: Canonically?
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: The article says that.
Rym: That it will "expand the
Rym: canon.".
Rym: They said it is expansion to the canon of the anime, adding original stories.
Rym: It will not be a full-on remake saying that "just redoing the anime will leave the audience hungry for something they already
Rym: saw.".
Rym: That's a very promising sign right there.
Scott: Well, the fact that there's self-awareness by the people who wrote that.
Rym: Because there is a possibility, much like Evangelion had the movie remakes, and we're going to talk about those two weeks from now.
Rym: But here, we might be in a situation when this all comes out.
Rym: Well, I was making quote motions.
Rym: You couldn't see.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: But there's a possibility, there's a future where we will see that Cowboy Bebop consists of this animated show, this one animated movie, and this one live-action show.
Rym: And they all complement each other.
Rym: That is possible.
Scott: My hope is that somehow, obviously this is going to appeal to people who already enjoy Cowboy Bebop and just want more.
Rym: Oh yeah, but imagine the kind of basic person who's like, who won't watch cartoons, sees this, loves it because everything about it looks great if you've never heard of the anime.
Rym: And then Netflix is like, "Hey, did you know this was based on this Japanese
Rym: cartoon?".
Scott: Right.
Scott: If this gets even some people to watch the original, then I guess it's worth it, right?
Scott: People who wouldn't have watched the original ever otherwise without this existing, then I guess it's a positive.
Scott: Even if it sucks.
Scott: In itself, right?
Rym: And the other thing, I'm going to list some things they talked about that make it clear, this definitely takes place during the show and not after the final episode.
Scott: You don't say.
Rym: I mean, there are actors for several characters who definitely could not be in the show were this show to take place after the end of Cowboy Bebop.
Rym: Much like the comic book movie.
Scott: Oh yeah, let me just have my, you know, let's run a space runaway.
Scott: Ide on, it takes place after the last episode.
Scott: Let's run Evangelion, it takes place after the last, season three, we'll say.
Rym: Evangelion 2, it takes place right after End of Evangelion, Death and Rebirth.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: Granted, if they announced that and Anno was behind it, I would watch it.
Scott: You can't have a movie called Attack the Tokyo Gas Station.
Scott: that's a sequel to Godzilla.
Scott: It's like, the gas station ain't there anymore.
Rym: So I know you didn't watch it.
Rym: One could argue that if there were a sequel to End of Evangelion, Death and Rebirth, it could canonically be the good place.
Scott: You should finish watching these rebuilds before you say anything.
Rym: You should watch the good place before you say anything.
Rym: That is a top-tier, like, S-rank show.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: I do not say that lightly about a live-action show in America.
Scott: And some actual anime news.
Scott: Something we've asked for, right, we've got a situation where we made a-- A monkey's paw has curled a finger here.
Scott: A monkey's paw situation, right, we went to the genie and we asked for something and the genie said, "Okay, here you
Scott: go.".
Rym: Monkey's paw, give me an anime about hockey.
Scott: Right, so there's plenty of sports anime out there, plenty of sports manga.
Scott: And there have been many sports manga about ice hockey, quite a few.
Scott: But they've never been translated to English, I've seen them though in their original forms.
Scott: But obviously couldn't read them.
Scott: I don't know if there are fan translations either.
Scott: So, I've been waiting for an ice hockey anime.
Scott: We got a bicycling anime.
Scott: that wasn't too bad, it was fun.
Scott: It wasn't, like, legendary.
Scott: good, but, you know, Yo-Yo Pedal is fun, I like it.
Scott: They didn't finish the anime though, they'd sort of stopped, which led me disappointed.
Scott: But anyway, ice hockey anime is coming.
Scott: Hurray!
Scott: Bad news.
Scott: It's a really, it's gonna be a garbage anime.
Scott: So, at first, I looked at this-- Not good like Yo-Yo Pedal.
Rym: I looked at this and it's definitely like a Moe show, like, it'll be hockey and it'll probably have scenes like, "Senpai, how do pucks work?
Rym: Let's talk about the curve of a
Rym: stick.".
Rym: Like, it's gonna be really, really Moe anime.
Rym: crap, I suspect.
Scott: But, there's a little-- It's also tied into some, like, microtransactions video game stuff.
Rym: So, lately, there's been a trend where the red flag that anime is gonna be bad is if it is actually part of a mixed media project.
Rym: Because usually that means it's actually a mobile game and the anime is just promoting the mobile game.
Scott: Exactly, that's exactly what this is.
Rym: It is animating this thing and if you look at things C2C has animated, it is things like that.
Rym: I don't think any of these are good.
Scott: This is not going to be, you know, a good story with good characters that have any sort of fun to them or anything interesting, right?
Scott: It's just gonna be, "But, it's ice
Scott: hockey.".
Scott: It's like, "Please, can't you make a Haikyuu or a, you know, Yuri on Ice or a Yo-Yo Pedal level of quality but make it ice
Scott: hockey?".
Scott: Why can't you do that, right?
Scott: You know, a free, even make a free ice hockey, right?
Rym: Oh, I've said that for years.
Rym: I want to see an anime with the production quality of free, but it's either hot boys playing hockey or hot boys skiing.
Rym: Like professional ski competition.
Scott: Ooh, skiing anime.
Rym: It's like wearing nothing at all.
Scott: Nothing at all.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: anyway, there's many different kinds of sports anime and the only kind that's not any good is the kind that they decided to finally make ice hockey.
Scott: It's like, "Come
Scott: on!".
Scott: So, very disappointing.
Scott: Just avoid this show.
Scott: Do we even say the name of the show?
Scott: What's it called?
Rym: Oh God, it is called, uh, what did I put it?
Rym: Pura Ore, Pride of Orange.
Scott: Yeah, we don't need this.
Scott: Also, the orange part bothers me because that's the Philadelphia Flyers colors.
Scott: They can go fuck themselves.
Rym: Yeah, I think the team they play for is called the Dream Monkeys.
Scott: At least that's a funny name.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I, uh, I am...
Scott: If we go bowling and we need a team name, we'll put Dream Monkeys.
Rym: I will watch one episode of this, but I am confident it is bad.
Rym: If somehow I watch that one episode and I have a desire to watch more than one episode, I will eat my fucking hat.
Scott: Yeah, well, I mean, we haven't done and probably won't do Judge Anime by its cover, but we would be like, there's no way that the judge is wrong on this one.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And if you're wondering why we're not doing more Judge Anime by its cover, so remember when I complained about how even just like a review of an anime where we had a single screenshot got taken down with a copyright strike from these companies.
Rym: Judge Anime by its cover, I've gotten copyright takedowns from screenshots that are tiny and blurry and in the background.
Scott: I have never gotten any copyright message whatsoever for any Judge Anime by its cover episode that we put on to my YouTube channel.
Rym: That didn't even have the slides in it from an anime.
Rym: Boston got copyright takedowns.
Scott: None of my Judge Anime by its covers that are on my channel have any notices takedowns.
Scott: If I still was monetizing, I would be able to monetize.
Scott: That is fascinating.
Rym: That's honestly fascinating.
Scott: My channel is a safe space for anime judging.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: But also, Judge Anime by its cover honestly was only popular at conventions.
Rym: It wasn't that popular on the internet for a lot of reasons.
Scott: I don't care how popular it is.
Scott: I just care if I like making it.
Scott: It was a little bit of a hassle to make.
Scott: It was a lot of effort to make.
Rym: And yeah, anyway.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: So I bumped into this.
Rym: It's just a short 52-second YouTube video.
Rym: And the best way I can describe this is it's a skit that's very funny and it asks a fundamental question.
Rym: And the question is, why do we do this to ourselves as humans?
Rym: And the thing that we do to ourselves is as soon as we wake up, reach over, find our phone, and turn it on.
Rym: And look at the words and images that are presented to us on this phone as the first thing we do.
Scott: I do that, yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So if you watch this video, you'll see what I mean.
Rym: The video is very apt and very funny.
Scott: I like doing that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I also do this, but you'll see when you watch this video.
Scott: I do it with an iPad.
Scott: And also, thanks to iOS 15 that just came out, they have a new focus feature.
Scott: I don't really care about the focus.
Scott: It's meant to be like where you enable or disable different notifications for different apps and different scenarios.
Scott: So it's like, oh, I'm doing this now, so I only want these notifications.
Scott: That's what it's meant for.
Scott: But one of the side features that they just added is the ability to set -- you can set many different home pages on your phone or your tablet.
Scott: And then you can assign a subset of those pages to a particular focus mode.
Scott: So I could have an indoor biking focus mode.
Scott: And if I choose that, suddenly the home page on my phone will literally just be the apps I need for indoor biking and Spotify and nothing else.
Scott: So what I did is I created a morning focus mode.
Scott: So when I wake up, it actually automatically and intelligently on its own enters the morning focus mode.
Scott: And in a row are all the apps that I check every morning and then widgets I need with information I want to see every morning like weather, calendar, tasks, that sort of thing.
Scott: And it's pretty good so far.
Scott: I've used it for two days maybe.
Rym: I will try that out.
Rym: The package that arrived today is either my new iPhone or the MagSafe battery for my new iPhone.
Scott: They didn't come together.
Rym: Yeah, they shipped separately.
Rym: And one of the two arrived.
Rym: I did not look to check which one it is yet.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So yeah, thing of the day.
Scott: Did I do thing of the day?
Rym: Yeah, you did.
Rym: Dua Lipa.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So but I didn't actually do it.
Scott: Now I have to do it.
Rym: Now you got to do it.
Scott: If you don't know, Dua Lipa is a singer songwriter person who makes dancey cool music.
Scott: You either don't know them.
Scott: If you do know them, you like them.
Scott: Maybe you don't like them.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: I like Dua Lipa.
Scott: Dua Lipa is cool.
Scott: Dua Lipa I think is like, my perspective is Dua Lipa, she is the master of collaboration.
Rym: Wait, wait.
Rym: What's YouTube saying here?
Rym: There's a thing on the bottom.
Rym: It says she's on tour.
Rym: Oh, this is March 1st.
Rym: It's just old.
Rym: Never mind.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Dua Lipa is the master of collaborations.
Scott: Like in terms of like featuring on other people's tracks, getting people to feature on her tracks, but also doing like fashion collaborations.
Scott: It'll be like, oh, such and such brand X Dua Lipa.
Scott: Like she like joins with everybody and makes all these deals.
Scott: And I think I feel like.
Scott: that's how, like I've never actually seen like Dua Lipa stuff that was just Dua Lipa.
Scott: Like here I am.
Scott: It was always something X Dua Lipa, right?
Scott: Every single time.
Scott: And that's the only reason I knew she existed to begin with because of so many, she kept repeat reappearing paired with other things that I did already know.
Scott: So a really good agent and business dealing going on over there in Dua Lipa's territory, I got to say.
Scott: But my thing of the day is Dua Lipa is fundamentally a singer songwriter and has a new music video for a song called Levitating.
Scott: And the music video is an animated music video.
Scott: It is 100% 2D animation and it is a strong, perhaps copyright infringing Sailor Moon.
Rym: Oh, the aesthetic of this hits me right in the soul.
Rym: Like so hard.
Rym: This is like a weapon against me.
Scott: I'm surprised that if this wasn't Sailor Moon X Dua Lipa with an official partnership, I'm surprised they don't come at her with some kind of lawsuit because wow, it's literally just a Sailor Moon music video.
Rym: It is so good.
Rym: This aesthetic is everything.
Scott: And the song's not bad either.
Scott: Pretty good song.
Scott: So check this out.
Rym: In the meta moment, the GeekNights Book Club book is still the tale of Genji, but we are...
Scott: I read some yesterday.
Rym: Yeah, I've read some as well.
Scott: Stuff was happening.
Rym: I think we'll be able to talk about it pretty soon.
Rym: I still worry that my opinion, like most books I read, my opinion changes and then as they get to the end, I have like a final thought.
Rym: But I hit this point where there's nothing different, I'll say, except for reacting to specific things Genji did and trouble he got into along the way.
Rym: But I do know that something's going to happen not too far from where I am that radically changes everything.
Rym: But I also haven't decided if I'm even going to read past that point because it's not even clear if that is canonically part of the original novel.
Scott: I mean, there's this stuff going on with that, right?
Scott: But I figured everything on these pages was written by the same author and was, you know...
Rym: There's a point near the end beyond which there seems to be dispute about that.
Scott: I mean, possibly.
Scott: Who the fuck knows?
Rym: There's a character who dies.
Scott: Yeah, I'm going to read everything in the whole book that is there.
Rym: Yeah, I'm just saying it is possible that everything after a certain character dies might not have been written by the same person.
Rym: And I was reading a bunch of stuff about this, but I've got to read more to sort out my thoughts on that so I haven't decided.
Scott: Regardless, I think part of the problem is that the plot keeps progressing, things keep happening, but there isn't too much in the way of character development.
Scott: Characters are who they are.
Rym: Genji has never at any point learned anything.
Scott: Right, it's like none of the characters change.
Scott: They might change their mind and do a different thing.
Rym: Or some of them get killed by ghosts.
Rym: Sometimes that happens.
Scott: Things happen to people, people do things, but people are who they are and that's it.
Scott: And I haven't seen anyone develop or grow.
Rym: One character who is developing, but it is too creepy to even get into right now who that is and how they're developing.
Scott: Yeah, so that is what sort of makes it, you know, it's like you're reading more, well your opinion won't change because it's sort of like soap opera, things are happening.
Scott: It's like the events.
Rym: Which is interesting because in a way, that's how a good chunk of another very long book that I read long ago, The Count of Monte Cristo is.
Rym: In that it's just a very, very straightforward.
Rym: this happened, then this happened, then this happened, then this happened, then this happened.
Rym: And The Count himself is not changing or evolving in any way.
Rym: He's just great and he is doing his plan and at no point is he changing his plan.
Rym: He's just adapting the plan.
Rym: But then at the very end of the book, I guess spoilers for The Count of Monte Cristo, he changes his plan and evolves as a character.
Rym: But that doesn't happen until like the last hundred pages of the book and the book has many times one hundred pages.
Scott: Yup, anyway.
Rym: Anyway, otherwise we're not planning to go to any conventions, obviously.
Rym: You can see our most recent PAX panel on the YouTubey.
Rym: We just linked to it, Atari Game Design.
Rym: I am working on a panel that will either debut or maybe I'll debut because it's a topic.
Rym: Scott doesn't care about that much.
Rym: But I gathered, I think, all the, I need to play one more game and get enough footage to do the analysis and then I'm ready to rock on this thing.
Scott: I'm working on things.
Scott: I'm not, but I can't shit talk anything, right?
Scott: So I'm not going to say what I'm working on, if I'll finish it.
Rym: Notice, I did not say what this thing, what this panel is about specifically to cover my own ass.
Scott: I didn't say what things.
Scott: Is it panels?
Scott: Who knows what it is.
Scott: But yeah, I have spent hours of my time producing works of some nature.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: In recent days, I have done that.
Scott: Will you see those works?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I'm a little sidelined by the fact that we're about to get a new couch and also it's warm, so I'm spending most of my time outside, but very soon.
Scott: It's still warm in the late September.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Now when it gets cold, I'm also outside at the time because I'll be skiing, but we're about to enter that magic era, not too long from now, where it's too cold to do the things I like to do outside, but not cold enough to do the other things I like to do outside.
Rym: And that is the most productive Rym is ever in his life.
Scott: Here is also another fact that is not a lie.
Scott: Ooh.
Scott: I have 18 paid time off days I have to use before the end of the year, unless my company again extends rollover beyond the normal 10 days.
Rym: Oh, if my company lets me roll over more than five days, I'm rolling over like all the days I got left.
Scott: We are also, my company always by default does not work between Christmas and New Year's.
Scott: It is very likely that I will simply not work in December, in which case it is more likely that I may make something in December.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: With no promise whatsoever.
Scott: I may lay on the couch for December.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I'll admit that I've had, I've enjoyed doing, being less productive and creative and doing less creative output for a few months and enjoying myself more, but I'm feeling that itch like pretty hard again.
Scott: So, all right, so let's talk about some magazines in the categories relating to cartoons, comics, anime, et cetera.
Scott: In the United States, historically, there have not been too many of them, and at least not too many that were like big.
Scott: If you look in your comic book, you know, if you run a comic book store and you look at the order form for Diamond, Diamond is in trouble now because they lost all their deals.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's like a James Bond magazine that keeps coming out.
Scott: It's like, what content do you have for that?
Scott: I guess there's a new James Bond movie now.
Rym: Well, it's kind of like how there are still Firefly podcasts to this day.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And there are some comic books magazines out there, like this Back Issue magazine or something, and it's like for the extreme comic nerds out there, right?
Scott: And I think some of these are quarterlies.
Scott: They're really narrow, and I don't know much about them.
Scott: But in terms of major ones, we can list them, and we're going to go through these sort of historically as like when I encountered them in life, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So the first one I really encountered in life was Wizard Magazine.
Scott: You ever read Wizard Magazine?
Rym: I read Wizard Magazine because back then, there was no internet.
Rym: I couldn't learn about any of this stuff.
Scott: So I didn't actually read.
Scott: I never bought Wizard Magazine.
Scott: At the time, it's weird because I was in middle school.
Scott: If I saw Wizard Magazine, I was interested in the contents of that magazine.
Scott: Other people had them, other nerds I knew, and I might skim them and read them when I was at a kid's house or something, but I never felt the need to buy or subscribe to Wizard Magazine.
Rym: I similarly would read them at friends' houses, or occasionally I'd read them in bookstores, though I don't remember if Wizard did this specifically, but a lot of the magazines like this I used to read in bookstores started coming in plastic sleeves that prevented me from reading them in the bookstores.
Rym: Wow, Wizard actually ended in 2011, and also it didn't start until 1991.
Rym: It started later than I thought.
Scott: Also, Wizard ran those conventions.
Scott: Remember Wizard World Philly?
Scott: That was the same wizard, right?
Scott: So I always thought it was strange.
Scott: First of all, the name and that we had Dungeon Magazine.
Scott: We had Dragon Magazine.
Rym: Now, Dungeon Magazine was Adventures for D&D.
Rym: Dragon Magazine was commentary and articles about D&D.
Rym: Wizard Magazine had nothing to do with wizards or dungeons or dragons.
Scott: Wizard Magazine had to do with comic bookstores.
Scott: It's like, what?
Scott: But it's called Wizard.
Rym: I have memories of knowing about Wizard, flipping through it and everything, but I am hard-pressed to say anything that I learned ever from looking inside a Wizard Magazine in my entire life.
Rym: Wizard Magazine was literally- I feel like it was a kid-brain thing where I would just flip through it and not internalize anything.
Scott: Yeah, it was the most consumerist, collectorist, not mainstream because comic books weren't mainstream, but mainstream in terms of the comic world, right?
Scott: It was like, yeah, superheroes, yeah, collect stuff and put it in bags and buy ultra rare cocoa beans and a magazine is 90% ads and everything is great, buy stuff, right?
Scott: That's what it was.
Rym: See, also, in the gaming space, Wizard was one step less bad than what Scryed, which was literally just, here's how much people are selling every fucking magic card for.
Scott: Yeah, well, Scryed isn't anime.
Rym: Oh yeah, but similar, it's aimed at this consumerist demographic.
Scott: Wizard Magazine wasn't talking about any indie comics, right?
Scott: It was either Marvel, it was DC, or it was Spawn, and otherwise it wasn't in there.
Scott: It's like they weren't trying to teach you anything, they were just trying to make you buy something you already like.
Scott: So you liked these comics, you bought Wizard to get news about the things you already liked in the pre-internet era, and then you would buy more shit, and that's what Wizard was.
Rym: But at least that news was also available in other places, and America, for me, was way more important.
Scott: You're skipping over a lot of magazines.
Rym: Alright, I'll follow your list then.
Scott: Okay, so there was another thing called the Comics Journal, which is from the 90s.
Scott: I don't know if it still exists, and what this was is you go to the comic book store, and you check out, and they give you a bag with the comic book store's logo on it, right?
Scott: Yeah, that's how they do.
Scott: And then in with your comic books, they would put this thing that was like, you know, a few pages of newsprint for free, that was the comic news.
Rym: I've never seen or heard of the comic news.
Rym: I'll admit, I've never seen or heard of the comics journal until now.
Scott: Well, the comics journal's different.
Scott: This is comic shop news.
Scott: So, comic shop news was this free piece of shit newspaper thing that was only a few pages.
Scott: they put in there, and I don't remember what the contents of it were, even though they gave it to me every single time I went to the comic shop, and I looked through it.
Scott: I think it was mostly ads, obviously, because it was free, but I don't know what the hell was in that thing.
Scott: I read it many times.
Rym: I don't think my comic shop gave any of that stuff out.
Rym: I just don't remember comic shop news.
Scott: It was a very 90s thing, the comic shop news.
Scott: So, yeah, the comics journal was something else.
Scott: I didn't encounter the comics journal until much later, but it is quite old.
Scott: I don't know if it exists anymore.
Scott: It had times where it went digital only, I think.
Scott: But this was made by Fanta Graphics, and this was like, you know, it was thick, right?
Rym: And this was like indie- Well, because it was a bi-annual magazine.
Scott: Yeah, and they'd be like deep, deep interviews with like indie comics people, like pages and pages long.
Scott: That was like, you know, the real deal biz, the comics journal.
Scott: And it went on for bi-annual, but it had like hundreds of issues, I think.
Scott: It went on for a long- It's still going.
Scott: It's still going?
Scott: Okay, because I know it had troubles going in and out of print and digitally- Because this was a real deal thing.
Scott: It wasn't some rah-rah, spend money, you know, rigid garbage.
Rym: Rich Buckler sued them because they called him a plagiarist showing his art side by side with Jack Kirby art, and he sued them over it.
Rym: I don't think he won that lawsuit.
Scott: Yeah, so if you, you know, if you want to, you know, do some research on what was really going on, especially in the indie comic scene back in the day, comics journal, that was the real stuff.
Rym: Yeah, and the thing I have to say about that kind, like in general, like these types of magazines is that they are really important for research, like modern research into the history of comics, the scenes at the time, because they're like- It's not quite an academic journal.
Rym: But they're just, they're an artifact.
Scott: But it's not a magazine either.
Rym: They're an artifact with so much contemporary information about like a particular year in comics that like a researcher could have a field day cross-referencing this with other information.
Scott: And it's like the amount of work that goes into making this thing versus what they charge for it is like just so dramatically, you know, imbalanced, right?
Scott: I was surprised like, you know, how long it went on, like, wow, it's like it's someone's whole job to like work really hard to make this thing and they're probably getting almost no money for it, right?
Scott: So the comics journal is definitely worth looking into, even back issues of it, right?
Scott: Whatever you can get.
Scott: I think there is archives of it you can pay for or get somewhere.
Scott: Yeah, I guess it's not unavailable.
Rym: I guess part of it is that I really didn't read a lot of superhero comics until actually like high school and later.
Rym: I was so deep into anime that anime magazines are where I have the most like nostalgia and memories.
Scott: So I guess actually, you know what, something I mentioned I didn't put on the list here that's worth at least mentioning a little bit is TV Guide, which obviously has no place in modern society.
Scott: And is it dead?
Scott: It should be dead.
Scott: If it's not dead, it's close to it, right?
Rym: I mean we stopped getting TV, like we even stopped, like we grew up in the late 1900s and TV Guide just stopped appearing in our house right when we moved.
Scott: We never had to, we never bought it.
Scott: We just used the newspaper's TV section.
Rym: Oh, we subscribed to it and we used it.
Scott: We did not, but it did have, parts of it were not just the guide part, parts of it were talking about shows and stuff and would occasionally talk about animated shows.
Scott: So it is not an anime magazine, animation magazine, but parts of it were occasionally.
Rym: TV Guide is how I would find out if an animated show I like would continue the next year or not.
Rym: Like that was, or if it moved, like a show would move, like you kids don't understand what it was like in the 90s when you'd watch a TV show, like a cartoon, like Mask or something, even the 80s that you like.
Rym: Cartoon, it's on TV, you watch it, every week you know it's on like Saturdays at 7 a.m.
Rym: or whatever, and then one day you turn on the TV at that time and your show's not on.
Rym: There was almost no way to figure out what happened if there's a different way to watch it except by reading something like TV Guide.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, oh, is Sci-Fi Channel going to show in the late 90s, are they going to show some 80s cartoons at, you know, six in the morning on Sci-Fi Channel?
Scott: There's no way for you to know that unless you have TV Guide.
Rym: I remember, you know why we stopped?
Scott: Unless you happen to flip to the channel at the right time.
Rym: I remember exactly when we stopped getting TV Guide.
Rym: Where we lived in Michigan, similar to how we got cable modems really early nationally, we got cable really early.
Rym: And there was one of those early cable channels that would just scroll through.
Scott: The cable channel tells you what's on you.
Rym: Yep, and once we had access to that channel, a TV Guide just stopped appearing in our houses.
Scott: Yeah, so we never had, we never bought it, but I always see it at the grocery store.
Scott: Anyway, so there was a Nickelodeon magazine, which is somewhat animation related.
Scott: It was mostly just a kid's entertainment magazine from what I remember.
Scott: I think my brother might have gotten it for a year or so.
Scott: My brother got it too.
Rym: I remember like half reading it.
Scott: But I mean, it was animation related and it did, you know, I don't know how much it counts.
Scott: But more importantly, there was Disney Adventures.
Scott: So I never bought Disney Adventures, but I did see it on the checkout aisle at the grocery store.
Scott: And it was sort of a digest size deal, like an Archie comics thing.
Scott: And it was really interesting in that even though it was called Disney Adventures, I never actually bought it, but I would look at it occasionally.
Scott: It had comics in the back, right?
Scott: And those comics were often like tailspin comic, right?
Scott: It's like there was good shit in there comics wise.
Scott: And I'm wondering now that I haven't thought about this magazine in decades, if those comics, some of which were good, are like compiled anywhere that you can get because some of them are probably worth reading today.
Scott: But in the front part, there was entertainment news targeted at kids and it wasn't exclusive to Disney.
Scott: Even though it was Disney Adventures magazine, they would be telling you shit about like all kids media.
Scott: Like other cartoons and things that were going on.
Scott: So if you were a kid and you were into, you know, cartoons in the United States, and this magazine was still in print, which it is not, it was really like, you know, if I was born five years later, I probably would have had this magazine and learned all kinds of stuff about what was going on.
Scott: Like new shows coming, going, movies coming out.
Rym: Oh yeah, there's a whole list of all the original, like not based on an existing Disney property comics in there.
Rym: Little Gloomy, Society of Horrors, The Last Laugh, Luna Park, Kid Blast Off, Gorilla Gorilla.
Scott: This was basically, if you want to think about Disney Adventures magazine, it was like the print version of Disney Afternoon.
Scott: It was like, it was pretty good actually.
Scott: Even though I didn't buy it ever, I knew enough of it that I knew that it was the real deal.
Scott: So you can probably easily get, you know, I don't know if people are scanning it.
Rym: So it looks like they released, they released back in the day, seven volumes that collected all the comics that were in them, it looks like.
Scott: Oh nice, okay.
Rym: This might have been a long time ago, but I'll bet there's a way to get these comics.
Scott: Which is probably hard to get also, but the library probably has them or something.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I'm going to bookmark this to remember to look into, to inquire about that a little bit.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's largely forgotten.
Scott: I haven't seen anyone mention it.
Scott: I bet if I tweet like, hey, I remember Disney Adventures magazine, it might blow up.
Scott: Anyway, so let's talk about the actual anime shit now, right?
Scott: So I did not think about anime magazines at all.
Rym: This is where Scott and I sort of switched places, because I turned into a weeb when I was in fourth grade, which was a long fucking time ago.
Scott: I was, like I knew anime was a thing, you know, earlier.
Scott: But when?
Scott: I guess whenever, when Akira came out in the US.
Rym: Yeah, I was a little bit, I was a bit before that.
Scott: Was that 80 something, right?
Scott: Late 80s, early 90s, who knows?
Scott: I knew anime existed, you know, but I wasn't, didn't actually have access to anime.
Scott: I would go to the comic shop and you see those Ranma VHSs there, but I didn't buy or watch those, even though I knew they were there, right?
Scott: Dragon Ball was on, whatever, but I wasn't, you know, you know, Sailor Moon was on.
Scott: I wasn't, I didn't actually watch that either.
Scott: I watched Voltron and Macross, Robotech, whatever, but I, you know, I wasn't, I didn't actually watch Dragon Ball and Sailor Moon, even though they were on TV.
Rym: But I went, like, by the time I was in middle school, I was already mailing strangers on the internet to get VHS tapes back.
Rym: But it was a weird world, because again, late 1900s, I knew anime existed and I was obsessed with it and I would get as much as I could.
Scott: I couldn't buy it.
Scott: I would try to watch, anytime sci-fi channels showed anime, whatever, I would try to watch it.
Rym: Literally watched every single anime that was in the local video stores, which was not that many, like maybe 20 tapes total.
Rym: And I'd watch them all multiple times, like I was obsessed.
Rym: But this was pre-internet, and even as the internet started to appear more and more, there was very little reliable or factually correct information about anime in America.
Scott: Most of it would just be like a little GeoCities fan site.
Rym: It was either, it was fan sites?
Scott: You're lucky it'll be some JPEGs.
Rym: But even worse, the fan sites would have content like, here's screenshots, or like, later on, here's an RM video of 10 seconds of the opening animation to like Ranma.
Scott: But I'm a fan of the thing, here's the thing, I'm writing my thoughts about it.
Rym: But also, nobody in America except people who were like, were professionals, knew shit about it, and kids would make stuff up about anime.
Rym: So you couldn't even trust the information you could find.
Scott: And there were zines, there were zines made by some smaller organizations.
Rym: I was too young to find zines.
Scott: And I had no access to those, though.
Rym: I was going to gaming cons in the early 90s, but I didn't go to anime cons until 2002.
Scott: I didn't even know an anime con was, you know, I didn't really understand.
Rym: Yeah, Scott and I at RIT learned that anime cons existed when the people who ran the RIT Anime Club were like, hey, let's go to the anime convention.
Rym: And we were like, what?
Rym: There are anime conventions?
Rym: Oh shit, oh fuck.
Scott: Before I went to college, like, the idea of a con, it's like I sort of understood from, because there were cartoons that made fun of them, like that.
Scott: there were Star Trek cons.
Scott: And I understood that there was Magic tournaments, because I went to one.
Scott: And I was going to a lot of- I understood that there were baseball card, you know, pro wrestling figure trade show type things, because I went to some.
Scott: But I didn't fully understand that there were cons.
Scott: And like when I was in the year 2000 in college, they're like something something Otakon, OhioCon, whatever.
Scott: I didn't fully understand what the hell they were talking about.
Scott: And I don't, I don't really, I don't remember how I ended up going to the one.
Rym: Yeah, I would do a lot of gaming cons, which honestly not that different from what I do at PAX is today, except they're the old Grognard gaming cons where you'd have to schedule in advance and tickets.
Rym: And they're very Gen Con-esque, just like shittier and smaller.
Rym: Like I went to Michigan a bunch of times.
Scott: But for somehow I like I understood they existed, but I had never conceived of like going to it.
Rym: But because of this dearth of actual reliable information, it was very hard for me to engage with anime other than getting as much as I could and watching it.
Rym: But I didn't have sources to know like who was involved, who directed something.
Rym: Like it was just hard to find out those kinds of things.
Scott: What other anime are available that I don't know about.
Rym: Animerica was the first time I encountered any reliable source of information about anime in my entire life.
Rym: And this started in like the early 90s.
Scott: Yeah, so I didn't know Animerica existed until we were in college.
Scott: I would skimmed it a few times here and there when it was lying about, but I never bought it.
Scott: And why?
Scott: I should have bought it.
Scott: Why didn't I buy it?
Scott: I couldn't afford it.
Rym: I would read other people's copies, especially in high school.
Rym: I knew people who subscribed to it and I would get their lead.
Scott: Again, it made no sense.
Scott: Like I should have subscribed to, you know, Wizard.
Scott: I don't like, but I should have subscribed to that when I was a kid in middle school.
Scott: And why didn't I subscribe to Animerica when I found out?
Scott: Two reasons.
Rym: One, kid brain.
Rym: And two, like when I was young, our parents were very clear.
Rym: Like we could each subscribe to a magazine.
Rym: Like they're not going to let us subscribe to everything we want because we're kids.
Scott: I subscribed to several magazines.
Scott: I had GoPro, GamePro.
Rym: Nintendo Power was the big one for us.
Rym: That was like the magazine we cared the most about.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: PC Gamer, etc.
Rym: But Animerica was just the first glimpse I and a lot of anime fans in America ever had into like actual information about anime in Japan and the anime industry.
Scott: So it was made by, so Viz made Animerica.
Scott: But Viz was most of the anime industry at the time in the U.S.
Scott: at least.
Scott: So that they were covering most of the stuff.
Scott: So it was a little bit Viz promote-y.
Scott: And it did have manga in the back because they're promoting the mangas that they sell.
Scott: But yeah, Animerica was kind of good actually.
Rym: Especially because not only did nothing exist even like it that we had access to, but it was very informative, very well written.
Rym: And it was also, while it was a little like it would focus on anime that Viz was involved with, it was also not as consumerist as the comic book stuff in America at the time.
Scott: Yeah, they would show, they would put fan stuff in, you know, usual stuff, letters, columns, right?
Rym: In retrospect, there were photos from conventions, but I guess I just assumed they were all like Star Trek conventions.
Rym: Like I didn't know.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't know.
Scott: I blame a lot of that on Kid Brain.
Scott: There's also Animerica Extra.
Scott: Animerica Extra was just manga.
Scott: And it was like a few chapters of a few different manga like compiled, but not as thick as like a real Shonen Jump was.
Scott: So that was a thing.
Scott: And what I find really interesting is I remember specifically like, was it 2004 or 5?
Scott: It was like the anime boom.
Scott: And anime was huge.
Scott: You would think Animerica would keep going, but actually at the anime boom, like at the peak, they stopped it.
Scott: And I think what happened, if I remember correctly, is everyone who had a subscription, they ran out your subscription with issues of Shoujo Beat instead.
Rym: Oh, that's really common in the magazine industry.
Rym: So remember the Disney thing we were talking about?
Rym: They just ended it one day and everyone who was subscribed didn't get a refund.
Rym: They just got Sports Illustrated for Kids until the subscription ran out.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they stopped doing Animerica and Animerica Extra and they just did Shonen Jump and Shoujo Beat as manga compilation things only.
Scott: And I think, yeah, you just got those instead.
Scott: I remember at the convention, we were like at Otakon and they were like, "Subscribe to Shoujo Beat stuff going on," right?
Scott: And that was the end of Animerica.
Scott: So the other big anime magazine was New Type.
Scott: So New Type I didn't know about until I got to college.
Scott: And there were issues of New Type there.
Scott: And there was a Japanese-only thing that someone imported.
Scott: But it didn't matter that you couldn't read it too much because it was mostly pictures.
Rym: Now, we talked about New Type USA and New Type on the show a few times because it was a moderately...
Scott: New Type USA came out while it was a new thing when GeekNights existed.
Rym: Yeah, in fact...
Scott: There may be a New Type USA episode of GeekNights.
Rym: So there is an episode from 2008 when we reviewed Bone and the news for that episode is that New Type USA is dead.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So basically, the story is we saw New Type at RIT in the RIT Anime Club library and flipping through it, one, just images of anime we'd never seen or heard of that were like upcoming, that were not available in the US yet and a lot of text that we really wanted to read.
Rym: When New Type USA was announced...
Scott: Mostly pictures, though.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: When New Type USA was announced, everyone, like the Anime Club, us, everyone in America, anime fans were so excited about this.
Rym: Finally, the Forbidden Magazine will get access to it.
Scott: I mean, if you looked at a New Type in the early 2000s, if you just had one...
Rym: It was like this big format, like glossy printing.
Scott: For a Japanese person, it would be no big deal.
Scott: But for someone outside of Japan who was a fan of anime and manga, seeing one of those things, it was like the print quality, the size of it, the colors on it, it was like an art book, basically.
Scott: It was almost like getting a few pages of art book from every different anime art book and you could somehow get that monthly.
Scott: It was just like this unbelievable thing.
Scott: You wouldn't treat it like some piece of shit magazine like in An America and recycle it, right?
Scott: It would be like,
Scott: "Whoa.".
Scott: So, fast forward.
Scott: I got a New Type.
Rym: New Type USA comes out.
Rym: Like, we, however we knew, like pre-ordered subscriptions to it.
Rym: And it wasn't cheap.
Rym: It was real expensive.
Rym: And we got the first issue.
Rym: And what I remember is as I was flipping through it and looking at the pictures, I felt really good.
Rym: But then I read the words and the words were nothing.
Rym: There was nothing in that magazine.
Rym: It was just pictures.
Rym: It didn't say anything at all.
Rym: It did not share any useful information.
Scott: It was like, "Hey, this new anime is coming out here.
Scott: Here's all the characters drawn from every different angle by the character
Scott: designers.".
Rym: The text under a caption for an image of a character would be like, "This is character so-and-so.
Rym: She is very important in the
Rym: show.".
Rym: And that's it.
Rym: The interviews were the most insipid.
Scott: I mean, the magazine is really useful for artists, cosplayers especially, to get reference for things like that.
Scott: And just to look at and see what... It serves the same purpose as like anime chart serves now, right?
Scott: You could judge anime using a new type instead of animechart.net or whatever.
Scott: But as a magazine, it left a lot to be desired text content-wise.
Rym: Yeah, and it cratered pretty hard as everyone in America simultaneously realized that even if you don't read or speak any Japanese, you get the same information out of the Japanese version as you do out of the very expensive American version.
Scott: Yeah, and it was very expensive either way, right?
Scott: Cos it was so big and fancy and colorful.
Scott: Now, the Japanese one did actually include manga in it and manga that were not available anywhere else, right?
Scott: Or at least not anywhere else easily.
Scott: So most famously, Five Star Stories, right?
Scott: Which is a huge deal as it is a fascinating topic in its own right.
Scott: But Five Star Stories is from New Type magazine originally.
Scott: Full Metal Panic also originally from New Type magazine.
Scott: And I think what's really funny is that New Type is named after New Types from Gundam.
Scott: And I don't think there was any Gundam... I mean, there have been plenty of issues in there with Gundam stuff, right?
Scott: But manga-wise, I don't think there was any Gundam manga published in New Type magazine.
Scott: So that's interesting.
Scott: But yeah, they didn't do that with New Type USA.
Scott: There wasn't a manga in it that you couldn't get on its own.
Scott: To sort of carry it, right?
Scott: If New Type USA had included Five Star Stories in the same original order that the original New Type did, that's a really strong manga that if people read might have kept buying just to read that, right?
Scott: So, anyway.
Scott: As New Type was a big deal.
Rym: I guess part of New Type's failure was that that insipid level of information was coupled with the fact that that was around the time when digital fan subs appeared for real and really grew.
Rym: And also, legit ways to watch anime made it everywhere.
Rym: And there were websites that actually had real information about anime that you could just look at.
Scott: The New Type USA magazine specifically came too late.
Scott: If somebody, maybe five to ten years earlier, had just simul-translated and published New Type Japan in English directly...
Rym: Oh my god, if I could have gotten New Type in English...
Scott: I think that would have been much more successful.
Scott: Although it still would have been expensive.
Rym: But I could have gotten New Type in English in elementary school when I was obsessed with anime, and that would have been the only thing I wanted for Christmas.
Scott: If I would have seen New Type on the shelf at the bookstore in the 90s, yeah, I wasn't going to mess up and not buy that.
Scott: Unless it was 40 bucks or something.
Rym: And at that point, that insipid, useless information would have been more than I had access to at the time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, there was an anime magazine that also appeared very briefly around when I was in college.
Scott: that I did buy, because it was issue number one came out when I was in college.
Scott: And I was like, "Oh, a new anime magazine was called Anime Insider, I
Scott: think.".
Scott: And I bought the first issue, and I bought the second issue, and never bought it again, because it was basically Wizard Magazine, but for anime, but worse.
Scott: It was so, like, nothing as far as content-wise.
Scott: It was just ads and stuff.
Scott: It should have been something to give you for free.
Scott: But it existed, and I remember it, because I bought it off the newsstand two or three times when it was new, and then stopped buying it.
Scott: But I just remember it clearly, because I was like, "Whoa!
Scott: A new anime
Scott: magazine!".
Scott: And I guess I feel, personally, I like to start with a number one of something.
Scott: So, something bad that just happens to be number one.
Scott: Like, I'll choose that over an America number 100.
Scott: For some reason, right?
Scott: But what I think does... So, the last one, does it still exist today, Otaku USA?
Rym: I don't know, actually.
Scott: Does Otaku USA still exist?
Scott: It looks like there's a website.
Scott: Yeah, the sole surviving anime and manga magazine in the United States.
Scott: And their website is things posted today.
Rym: There you go.
Rym: Nike releases some Gundam unicorn sneakers.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, yeah, I think this might still... If the website still exists, yeah, you can subscribe to it on their website.
Scott: They'll sell it to you.
Rym: The great and honorable Patrick Macias is still listed as the editor.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Very cool.
Scott: I mean, this... Yeah, this is still a thing.
Scott: If you want, like, actual anime articles, content, editorial, right?
Scott: It comes six times a year.
Scott: You know, I don't know if it's just anime.
Scott: I think it's all things Otaku.
Scott: Even their website, you know, has headers for games, manga, cosplay.
Rym: I think just between Otaku USA and Anime News Network, your cup overflowed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, but, you know, Otaku USA is still a thing.
Scott: You know, you can get deep dives, real magazine-level, you know, articles about Otaku shit in English.
Scott: I'd actually... Even though I know people who've written for it, worked on it, I've met Patrick Macias briefly one time.
Scott: Right?
Scott: I know it's existed for many, many years.
Scott: I've never read a single issue of Otaku USA magazine.
Scott: I'm not gonna lie.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I've never read it even once.
Scott: I just know what it is.
Scott: Was it for Otaku USA?
Rym: So way, way, way back, I wrote a, like, it was just published.
Rym: I wrote for one of these magazines a review of an early Otakon, like, as a podcaster.
Rym: And I don't remember which of these magazines it was in, but it was, like, a four-paragraph review that I wrote.
Rym: And they did, in fact, publish it with my byline.
Rym: And then I didn't have time or energy or care to write any more articles after that.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, yeah, if you like that sort of thing, this exists.
Scott: And the subscription cost for one year is 16... Oh, it saves $16 a year.
Scott: So it's 20 bucks a year for the print edition.
Scott: Print and digital combo, 25 bucks a year.
Scott: That's not expensive at all.
Scott: If you go for two years, they'll give you a free T-shirt, too.
Scott: So... And that gets you six issues.
Scott: 20 divided by six, that's, like, two or three dollars an issue.
Scott: Right?
Scott: That doesn't seem bad at all.
Scott: If you like it, go get it.
Scott: But, yeah, magazines as a whole are mostly dead.
Scott: We'll talk about that next Thursday.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: 'Cause next Tuesday we're doing gaming magazines.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And I guess next Thursday we're doing magazine magazines.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Talk about some Reader's Digest and some...
Scott: Time in life.
Scott: Some people.
Scott: And also some meta.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Magazines as a thing.
Scott: So, yeah, magazine, you know, September is a magazine half-month.
Rym: Highlights?
Rym: Sports Illustrated for Kids?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: With regular Sports Illustrated.
Rym: Yeah, I read the... Sports Illustrated for Kids, when we get to that show, was fucking better than Sports Illustrated.
Scott: I mean, Teen Vogue is better than Vogue.
Rym: Teen Vogue is, like, consistently better.
Rym: Teen Vogue is shockingly a great magazine.
Scott: Teen Vogue might be the best magazine that exists now.
Rym: Like, if you think we're joking, like, we are so not joking about Teen Vogue.
Rym: Like, go read an article from Teen Vogue and we'll see what we mean.
Scott: Even if you're not a teen, you know, the only thing that will bother you if you read Teen Vogue if you're not a teen is all the ads are targeting teens.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And it's mostly ads.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are... Because we're going to have a lively discussion about these old magazines.
Rym: And really stay tuned to that Tuesday episode because gaming magazines are probably where we have the most memory and most experience.
Rym: But for now, I leave you simply with... Come on and join the Adelaide Parade.
Rym: Adelaide to Adelaide.
Scott: We're going to Adelaide's house today.