Rym: It's Thursday, November 11th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Night.
Rym: We are talking about the Alien franchise.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, I've been biking to work still because it's been like unseasonably warm and beautiful in New York for the last week, like 60s and sunny every day, like I'm eating lunch in the park.
Rym: So, uh, I noticed something.
Rym: For once, nothing weird happened.
Rym: I didn't get to see, uh, a divine comedy, like Two Stooges.
Rym: I didn't get to see a crazy guy.
Rym: I didn't have anyone threaten me over a city bike.
Rym: Nothing happened, but I noticed something previously in the morning.
Rym: It's really hard to get a city bike because everyone's biking.
Rym: And then in the evening, it's also really hard to get a city bike because everyone's biking.
Rym: It got cold and that did not change at all.
Scott: But now we've talked about this and the studies about it.
Scott: This is an old, boring topic.
Rym: Yeah, so there's one more factor.
Rym: Today and yesterday, there were no city bikes in the morning and an infinite array of city bikes in the evening, despite the fact that it was warmer and nicer in the evening than it was in the morning.
Scott: The only difference- Did the city bike valets come and fill it up?
Rym: Nope.
Rym: There is one difference that I've seen.
Rym: I also saw a lot fewer people biking on the way home than I saw biking to work.
Scott: Was there something going on after work people were doing?
Rym: So before we shifted away from Daylight Saving Time, it was light out when I biked to work and it was light out still when I started biking home from work.
Rym: Now it's light out-.
Scott: Do you think the dark is the scaring people?
Rym: I think the dark is the primary factor because when I biked to work today and yesterday, tons of people biking.
Rym: City bikes are hard to get.
Rym: On the way home, hardly anyone's biking.
Rym: The only difference is it is dark when I walk out of the office.
Scott: I guess it's possible that people are scared of the dark.
Scott: All the city bike data is public, so you could look and see the rate of rides based on- You could line up the calendar- Every day that I've biked- Here's my anecdote.
Rym: Every day that I've biked home before Daylight- Before we went away from Daylight Saving Time, it was high to walk many blocks.
Rym: Many of the stations were empty and there were no e-bikes within a mile radius of me.
Rym: Now, when I walked out, not only was every dock completely full, but there were like 10 e-bikes just sitting there that no one was even using.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm saying if you looked at the data, it's like their city bike, they might be filling up those docks or something while you're in the office, and it might have just been a coincidence that they started doing it when it got dark, you know?
Rym: It's possible, but the correlation was so strong that we'll just see if it continues.
Rym: I don't know, that's all I got.
Rym: That was literally the most exciting thing that happened to me in two days.
Scott: So, you know, I'm only biking inside these days, mostly.
Rym: It's too cold.
Rym: It was like almost 70 the other day, it was beautiful.
Scott: That's cold.
Rym: I biked home in a t-shirt today.
Scott: I was biking inside this morning, and I'm trying to do, in Zwift, which is like the VR bike MMO, there's basically all these different places you can go, and there's different routes, and I'm trying to complete all the routes that are in the game.
Scott: And I've done the vast majority of them, but there are a few that are like ultra long, ultra big hills, and I've only done a few of those, like maybe three, like the French mountain and the other one.
Scott: Anyway, so, you know, when I'm biking in the morning, it's like a wake-up bike shower, so there's not too many that are short enough that I can finish them before I have to do stuff, right?
Scott: So this is one that I basically always do when there isn't one available that it's completable that I haven't completed before, and it's just like hilly route, and it's like you bike this one big hill, and then you sort of go do do do do, and if you're fast enough, I'll do the hill again.
Scott: I
Rym: mean, before COVID, when I would use the exercise bike in the building, usually what I do is I just tell, I pick this one setting that would randomly generate hills of varying sizes, and I just told it how long I had to bike, and it would just give me a random route every time.
Scott: Well, this is like a virtual place, right?
Scott: It's the same road every time.
Scott: It's not random, but by doing that same one occasionally, frequently, I can measure against myself, right, in the same spot, right?
Scott: So, you know, that hill that's at the beginning of the loop on the hilly route, it has a separate timing just for that hill, so you'll pass this little gate, and it'll start the clock, and then when you get to the top of the hill, it ends the clock.
Scott: So usually, just chilling, not trying hard, it'll take me four to five minutes to get up the hill.
Rym: Ooh, did you try hard?
Scott: And I was like, you know, I didn't huff and puff, right?
Scott: I huffed only.
Scott: I'm like, you know what, let's just see.
Scott: You know, I got nothing else to do today, right?
Scott: So, it was only on that portion, right?
Scott: So what, for three, four minutes?
Scott: And so, it turned out.
Scott: I got by basically, you know, to go up the hill, it's not a long hill, it's just steep and short, and it has like two phases.
Scott: Like, you go up and it's kind of steep.
Rym: I will say, when I'm biking in the real world, I prefer steep and short over the same climb, but longer.
Rym: Like, give me the steepest hill and get it out of the way.
Scott: Eh, whatever.
Scott: But it's a tiny plateau, like a second long, and then there's an even steeper part, and that's right.
Scott: So, I'm like, you know what, here's what I'll do, is I basically just won't normally, I'd go to the low gear and go doo-doo-doo-doo, right?
Scott: Just, you know, week-a-week-a all the way up.
Scott: I was like, you know what, we're just gonna not use the low gear, right?
Scott: We're just gonna keep going like it's flat until we get to the top.
Rym: That is what I do.
Rym: I try to keep my cadence the same and do the highest gear I can and just, my goal is to not slow down on uphills ever.
Scott: Uh, okay.
Scott: Anyway, so, I got up the hill.
Scott: It took instead of four to five minutes, it took about three minutes and change.
Scott: So, I saved like a whole minute.
Rym: Not bad.
Scott: But that's like a 25% improvement, which is significant, right?
Scott: Because you really get diminishing returns, you know, biking, right?
Scott: Over something so small, right?
Scott: It's like if you think about a long race, right?
Scott: Like a day-long Tour de France stage, a pro is going to finish hours and hours and hours before I will, right?
Scott: But if it's like, if it's one hill, it's like the pro is going to finish, you know, maybe a minute or two before me, right?
Scott: But that's still very significant.
Scott: So, uh, what happened though is I was huffing, right?
Scott: My body decided to evict like all the phlegm and mucus in my lung.
Rym: That's good.
Rym: I guess.
Rym: That happens.
Rym: So, it's not uncommon.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I think it's also, it's also getting kind of dry.
Scott: I got to get, oh, it's dry.
Rym: And also like everyone, like my allergies got like my allergies act up around this time of year, every year.
Rym: They're doing it more this year than they've ever done in like recent history.
Rym: And all my coworkers are sneezing like the same way.
Scott: No, I'm not sneezing.
Scott: It's just because I huffed when I took the shower right after, I just kept coughing up phlegm like constantly all over the place.
Scott: And I coughed up so much.
Scott: I don't even know where the hell, where did it come from?
Rym: If that my body is full of that much because you don't really do winter sports because you'll basically, your lungs will generate a lot more mucus.
Rym: It'll come out in like cold weather for a lot of reasons, but, uh, your lungs can hold a terrifying amount of mucus and they're constantly making it.
Scott: I wish there was some way to like, you know, I don't like to boggle and I don't, not like you, uh, there was some point of order.
Rym: I do not enjoy boggling.
Rym: It is simply that that is my body's like first response mechanism to any trouble.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, uh, I wish that I do wish there was some way, because right now it's like the only way to get the mucus out of the lung is like coughing and coughing sucks.
Scott: If there was some way to like mucus boggle, just like squeeze it out all at once.
Scott: Just like blorp.
Rym: The problem is it keeps making it.
Scott: It can't make it that fast.
Rym: It can make it way faster than you realize.
Scott: That's too fast.
Rym: You know what that mucus is doing?
Rym: It slowly moves up with your little cilia in your lungs, collecting garbage quickly.
Scott: It didn't move up slowly.
Scott: It moved up quickly.
Rym: If it didn't move, it's not that it moved up quickly.
Rym: It's that you generated more than normal and then you had to expel it most likely.
Scott: Anyway, uh, so the point is I was in the shower and I was coughing so much in the shower that I slightly damaged my throat.
Scott: It hurts.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Uh, the other, the other thing that can cause that is because you rarely huff and or puff to a significant degree.
Rym: So if you don't push hard with cardiovascular exercise a lot, then when you do push, you'll generally make more mucus and have more troubles like that because your body kind of reacts to it.
Rym: If you huff and puff all the time, your body will get to the point to where you won't have any problem like that under any amount of exertion.
Scott: Eh, we're not doing that.
Scott: Yeah, but that's the option.
Rym: Just like if you don't want to shave, you could do, uh, like laser, like remove the hairs, like do some sort of, uh, medical procedure.
Rym: You can do the same thing with your lungs by just huffing and puffing all the time and then you'll never have to cuffle them up again.
Scott: The point is I just wish, you know, like I could just expel all the mucus and feel nice and clear.
Rym: See, this is how all the fake medicine gets a lot of people because they don't know.
Rym: Like imagine if you didn't know and someone said, Hey, your body makes a lot of mucus toxins.
Rym: Imagine if you can, I can give you a thing that like spell all that crap.
Rym: I mean, you know, if there was such a thing, yeah, but the problem is there isn't, but it's really easy to feel like there should be.
Scott: So a little bit, I mean, I guess there is, is like you go to a doctor who put like a vacuum tube down your lung and somehow suck it out without collapsing your lung.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: There are, that's, uh, there aren't really things like that.
Scott: That seems like a bad idea.
Rym: So, uh, there's a bunch of random news we can talk about, but one thing I want to talk about briefly, not on tech news day, but today is that YouTube is, uh, removing the dislike counts on videos, but they're not removing the dislike button because they still want that feedback.
Rym: And I have actually very mixed feelings about this in terms of how it'll impact people.
Rym: Because on one hand, I don't, uh, so I said there's one use case.
Rym: I've seen that's been very helpful.
Rym: One use case with a bad problem with dislikes is that if a Nazi uploads a video, like, yeah, a lot of good people will dislike it.
Rym: It'll have a huge ratio of dislikes to likes, but also when good people upload things, bad people will brigade them with dislikes just to try to drag their video down.
Rym: But the other place I see dislikes commonly are pseudoscience, woo videos, fake information, bad and wrong tutorials, where they have a lot of dislikes and then the comments show people are saying this tutorial is wrong.
Rym: This information is absolutely objectively incorrect.
Rym: This video is bad.
Rym: And without that feedback, that's actually how I very quickly determine if a tutorial is worth watching or not is if it has a lot of dislikes, I'm very skeptical of it.
Scott: I hadn't thought of that because I don't, I basically don't look at the dislikes ever.
Scott: The only time I look at the dislikes is occasionally I'll see a comment that's like, you know, whoever the one person who disliked this is like, oh, you see a video that's like on a very good video.
Rym: That's like cute buddies jumping in the, in the forest.
Rym: And you see like 10 million likes for dislikes.
Rym: And you're like, who are those four people?
Rym: The fuck is wrong with you?
Scott: I almost never click the dislike button.
Scott: Like very rarely.
Scott: I forget it.
Scott: Basically.
Scott: I basically forget it even exists.
Scott: Um, the only time I use the dislike button is if I watch like a video and I'm like trying to learn some information and the information is wrong or the person it's either wrong or usually it's just the format of the video is just so long.
Rym: That's what I use it for.
Rym: If I find a tutorial or something, mostly nonfiction stuff, and it ends up being YouTube shouty manner wrong.
Rym: I use the dislike button immediately.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: The other thing is the like button.
Scott: I don't even use the like button for liking things.
Rym: I use it to remember things to remember what I use it.
Scott: because right.
Scott: Because on YouTube, there's a page you can go to that says, here are the videos that you've liked.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: You ought to know where all my things of the day are.
Rym: You want to know like.
Rym: that is my fee.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: That's my number one thing in the day place is like video.
Scott: I liked it.
Scott: So I'm using it to save the video for later, but I don't want to add it to a playlist.
Scott: Like the read late, the watch later.
Scott: That's stuff I watch later, right?
Scott: It's not stuff that I, you know, this is stuff I have.
Rym: That's a good point.
Rym: I use the like YouTube thing the same way I use Twitter likes.
Rym: I want to remember the tweet existed in my own feed because there's no fucking ways to have bookmark instead of like.
Scott: they changed it to like, I just kept using it like it was bookmark.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I use like, like it's bookmark.
Scott: And I even, I even have things that are set up to where if I like a video on YouTube or favorite a tweet or anything like that, it automatically gets saved to my pinboard.in.
Scott: So that's where I actually collect.
Scott: everything is in one place.
Rym: So I saw some chatter about the like dislike thing.
Rym: that was fascinating.
Rym: So, because this is why I have a mixed opinion of this because, you know, the tutorial use case, I literally this morning I disliked a video I was watching at work.
Rym: I found some like Kubernetes video talking about a way to use Kubernetes and it was just like bad wrong crap.
Rym: So I was like, nope, dislike.
Rym: But I saw a conversation of a bunch of creators like YouTube people, like small time YouTubers, and they were reacting to this saying, yeah, we don't really get brigaded with dislikes.
Rym: Like that's actually rarely a problem.
Rym: It seemed like the thing that the problem we have is that people attack us in the comments and send messages to us and harass us.
Rym: Someone disliking our video actually does not impact us in a material way.
Scott: The only way even looking at the dislike, you know, exactly like.
Rym: the only reason dislikes matter to them is because that can drag them down in the algorithms.
Rym: And YouTube is going to still use the dislike information.
Rym: So all the negative outcomes of the dislikes will still affect small creators.
Rym: But now they lose that data point and they lose that feedback when they watch other videos.
Rym: But one smart person in that long thread with like 10 people talking in it, they pointed out that the people who are complaining the most about the dislike counts are brands.
Rym: Big companies and brands are the people who are the maddest about dislikes showing up.
Rym: Notice how like Square Enix and Nintendo disable like and dislike counts all the time because they don't want people to see how many people dislike their ad videos.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Scott: That's a good point.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But it's anecdotes like that's just some smart person.
Rym: And while that feel I feel like that's true, I don't have any evidence to back that up, but I just looked at a whole bunch of YouTube accounts and yeah, almost every brand has hidden the like and dislike counts on all the videos.
Scott: I mean, you know, I'm more and more, you know, I'm basically just, you know, personally, right?
Scott: It's like I can't do too much to affect how all these different networks run their algorithms and their likes and dislikes and all that stuff.
Scott: But what you can do is I could just control what I go, what I use and how I use it.
Scott: So it's like, I don't really have any feeds that are algorithm controlled, right?
Rym: The only one I have, the only one is I will occasionally, if I'm just sitting on the couch, like before we watch a movie, I open YouTube and it shows me it's algorithmically curated selection, mostly things I subscribe to,
Scott: but also things I go to my subscribe page, I don't go to the homepage.
Rym: I do both with YouTube, but that's the only place I do it with.
Scott: Well, you know, it's like, even on Twitter, it's like I'm getting, I'm basically decided I'm not looking at retweets, at least naked retweets.
Rym: I really, really like naked retweets.
Scott: I just filter them all out now.
Rym: But I only follow people who tweet and retweet only good stuff.
Scott: There were some people who retweeted good stuff, but you know, when I put the feeds side by side, you know, the no retweet and the retweet one, the no retweet one is like, oh, it's only content actually created by the people that I'm following directly and nothing else based on.
Scott: basically nothing else is occasional quote.
Rym: I will say that retweets are how I wanted.
Rym: This is, retweets are the primary way I find interesting people and art that I was not following that I want to now follow.
Scott: If there was some, but that's the thing is finding more stuff that I didn't know about.
Scott: that was a problem in the olden days.
Rym: Well, now there is a ton of stuff, but I can say I found a lot of there is.
Scott: no, I don't need more stuff.
Scott: I have too much stuff.
Scott: If I, if I had a shortage of stuff, I agree.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I turned that shit right back on.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like, I have so much stuff now.
Scott: It's like, even if there's more stuff, I, I, I'm already, my hands are full, right?
Scott: It's like, I don't need more discovery.
Scott: I need anti.
Scott: I need to clean less anti discovery.
Rym: I heavily curate who I follow though, which does significantly cut down on that being a problem.
Scott: I cut down like followers by like a very large percentage on pretty much everything.
Scott: And also, uh, I wanted people to know this, you know, you might not use Instagram at all because it's owned by Facebook and that's very valid.
Scott: Um, and Instagram itself has become a bad, real bad, just even if you, even if it wasn't owned by Facebook, right?
Scott: What is now is not great.
Scott: But if you go to Instagram in your desktop web browser and Microsoft windows, it is a completely different experience.
Scott: It's like, it's like Instagram from, you know, 10 years ago, there's no ads.
Scott: There's none of that bullshit.
Scott: There's no algorithm.
Scott: It's showing you Instagram posts from people you follow in reverse chronological order is like, it's, it's like you think, Oh, is it?
Scott: Cause they haven't updated it in forever.
Scott: And most of the users are mobile anyway.
Scott: It's like, yes, but they actually just added.
Scott: finally after how many years, the ability to post to Instagram from the desktop website, something that hasn't existed until as recently as like this month.
Scott: So, uh, I could actually Instagram, if you stick to desktop web version is one of the better social networks that exists.
Rym: The listener pointed out something else.
Rym: The most disliked video in the history of YouTube is YouTube's own 2018 YouTube rewind.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: I remember.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They can't, they canceled YouTube rewind.
Scott: cause it, it sucks.
Rym: Well, cause people disliked it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But the last thing I'll say is this does remove, uh, I'll just link to this tweet quote, YouTube is removing dislikes and now's your last chance to see the greatest example of camaraderie on the platform.
Rym: It's the video from Futurama of the, uh, the neutrals responding.
Rym: And it to this day still has the same number of likes and dislikes 548,000 something.
Rym: And that number has been extremely stable for the entirety of this video's history since 2009.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: If I made, if I were to make a social network or any kind of, you know, content user content publishing site of any kind, right.
Scott: Uh, I would absolutely, if I had features such, you know, I might have features like save for later, like, et cetera, those features would solely be for the purposes of individual users, you know, uh, collating their own collections and lists.
Scott: Uh, and there would not be any display of any numbers or any metrics to anyone.
Scott: unless a creator wanted to see their numbers that I might let them see them like in their creator dashboard.
Rym: I would definitely want to see my numbers or I wouldn't bother using a platform because I have no idea if anyone was watching anything.
Scott: Who cares?
Scott: You're creating it for the sake of creating it.
Scott: You'll get it.
Rym: If I was doing that, I wouldn't even publish it though.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's because you're an egotistical kind of jerk like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I'm happy to create and I don't care.
Scott: if any, I don't, if no one sees it, what's the point about if, if I'm only creating it because for other people, right.
Rym: I'm only creating it for me.
Rym: I wouldn't even bother uploading it anywhere.
Scott: Van Gogh wasn't like, Oh, I'm not going to paint these sunflowers.
Scott: I don't know how many people are looking at him.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It wasn't like counting.
Scott: He wasn't counting people entering, you know, the gallery for you.
Scott: Did he sell those paintings?
Scott: He also killed, he also killed them.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But I'm just, I'm just asking you a question.
Rym: Did he sell those paintings?
Rym: Some of them.
Rym: Did he sell paintings for money in order to like, as a job, like?
Rym: that's a question I'm just asking you.
Scott: You get the idea though.
Rym: But actually, so an idea I've always had along those lines is I think there is a very narrow use case for semi algorithmically curated content.
Rym: The real problem is it's across all the users of the platform.
Rym: What if, imagine, I'll just make up an example.
Rym: What if there was a YouTube where you could use likes and dislikes, there's algorithmically curated feed as an option, not the default, but like it defaulted to your feed and you could click like, I want to see the algo feed, but that feed was only informed by your interaction with the platform and the interaction of people.
Rym: you've specifically said, I like the same things that person likes.
Rym: So like you and your friends have a locally semi-curated feed of your collective likes and interests?
Scott: I think a better idea than that is to simply, you know, a lot of the problem of the algorithms is their opaqueness, right?
Scott: It's like, even if you add features like that.
Rym: If I could click on a YouTube video and it was like, here's the data that led us to think you'd like this video.
Scott: No, no, no, no, no, no.
Rym: That would be fascinating.
Scott: No, what I think you need to do is don't have some sort of machine learning algorithm that you might not even know fully as the creator of the algorithm, how it chose things.
Scott: You might have a general idea, but not a specific idea.
Scott: give instead, right?
Scott: Make the default as everything you follow in reverse chronological order, and then just give the user direct if they really care, right?
Scott: That's a power user tool only pretty much because normal people aren't going to use it.
Scott: Be like, you really want a fancy feed?
Scott: Okay, here you can type in rules, right?
Scott: Program your own personal algorithm.
Scott: Go right ahead, right?
Scott: You know, some point system, go nuts, whatever you want to do, right?
Scott: You can make your own algorithm.
Scott: You'll know how it works and you'll be able to, you know, choose how automatic recommendations come to you on your own.
Scott: And everyone can customize their own algorithm or even share algorithms with each other, right?
Scott: We're not going to tell you how to find new stuff.
Scott: You tell you how to find new stuff.
Rym: One problem is that most people, the way they want to consume media is they want something to tell them what to watch.
Rym: Like it or not, that's how people are.
Scott: So don't do that.
Rym: So don't give the people what they want and they're trying to have the money to do.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Make it, you know, old school only.
Rym: But I think more the idea that platforms like online communities were better when they were still public and open and big, but they were also more local and had their local cultures.
Rym: Like, you know, Lotax died recently.
Rym: Shitty dude.
Rym: A lot of complication.
Rym: I'm not, I don't want to get into him, but something awful is a place, good or bad.
Rym: It was its own culture and community distinct from like Fark, distinct from like Slashdot, distinct from all these different places on the Internet.
Rym: There are very few places on the Internet anymore.
Rym: Everything is everything.
Rym: And that is where you see a lot of the social friction that we see today.
Rym: Right.
Scott: You are seeing that trend is, you know, things like discords and slacks and whatnot.
Rym: You know, I mean, we've we've I've retreated back away from public Internet other than like Twitter and like content we're making right now and publishing out to mostly conversing in a series of semi-private discords.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: People are, you know, retreating into, you know, closed, you know, group even, you know, subreddits are the same thing.
Rym: So got any news?
Scott: Yeah, we got.
Scott: so I got a combo news here.
Scott: Sorry.
Scott: News one.
Scott: So the Valve Steam Deck, which I'm still don't give a shit about, but people seem to be giving a shit about it.
Scott: And it does seem like it has some potential.
Rym: I did see a bunch of chatter on Twitter of, well, if I can't get it by Christmas, I don't want it at all.
Scott: OK, sure, whatever.
Scott: But they're delaying it till 2022 because the economy has supply chains.
Rym: I did.
Rym: I can't imagine the person who did not expect that to happen.
Scott: I mean, I don't even know.
Scott: I don't even know they had a release date to begin with.
Scott: So the fact that it was like they had a date for it, I assumed 2022.
Rym: Then I saw the news delayed and I was like, what?
Rym: Delayed till when?
Rym: And said 2022.
Rym: And I was like, what?
Scott: I don't know what the I didn't even know it was had an original date.
Scott: So something I did know about the playdate, the little yellow handheld console.
Scott: So what happened to them was not necessarily a supply chain issue or kind of maybe, but they got a shipment, a whole big box full of play dates right from across the ocean.
Scott: It came in.
Scott: They were tested them to see if they were going to send them out to customers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they found that the batteries in them were really shitty, like really shitty, even though they had tested and chosen this specific battery.
Scott: And it worked so well, you know, in testing originally.
Scott: So they went, they gave it the go ahead.
Scott: And then, of course, when it actually arrives, ship battery.
Scott: So they ended up having to do is send them all back across the ocean.
Scott: So thankfully they didn't send them to customers yet.
Scott: Otherwise this would have been way worse.
Rym: And it wasn't just, they perform worse than they expected.
Rym: A huge percentage of them literally did not work.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So they sent all of them back across the ocean.
Scott: They bought new batteries from somewhere else.
Scott: And now the people on the factory and the other side of the world are going to swap all the batteries.
Rym: It looks like the factories in Malaysia for this particular product.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, and then it's going to come back across again.
Scott: So, you know, here similar issue, right?
Scott: It's being delayed.
Scott: Uh, you know, another handheld computer device is gaming devices delayed.
Scott: So similarity there.
Scott: Uh, but here I want to point out, you know, just the risk of doing any business venture, right?
Scott: Just even if you do everything right, shit can go wrong.
Scott: And if you're not enormous, like say Apple absorbing risk, it becomes very difficult, right?
Rym: I took a lot of at my last job, I ended up taking a lot of classes and getting certifications around corporate risk management to be able to decide how much risk can we assume, but not like.
Rym: they're lucky to have survived.
Scott: They're lucky to have survived this, right?
Rym: This would have just like, it could have just ended play date, but like, let's assume that they have a good contract and they can fuck over the people who gave them the bad batteries and get all their money back.
Rym: They're not going to get that money back.
Rym: Now they need to have money to solve the problem now because that litigation might take a long time and might fail.
Rym: They might lose like the place they got the first batteries from might just say, well, we're bankrupt.
Rym: Sorry.
Rym: And disappear.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: And so, uh, the final news, right?
Scott: We already know inflation's a big deal lately, right?
Scott: Uh, and it turns out the report just came out.
Scott: The consumer price index rose 6.2% in October, which is the largest increase since 1990 when I was eight.
Rym: So inflation's kind of skyrocketing for a bunch of reasons, but I think the real, the fundamental reason in my, this is not the opinion of my employer, nor is this financial or investment advice, but it is my personal opinion as a professional in capital markets.
Rym: This is a symptom of a dire state in late capitalism.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I mean, you basically have all these factors all at once, right?
Scott: It's not.
Scott: usually people think of inflation as like a monetary policy thing.
Scott: Like you printed too many dollars.
Scott: So now they're worth less because there's those greater supply of dollars.
Scott: That is partially true.
Scott: Uh, that can happen, but here we're seeing a lot of supply side inflation, right?
Scott: It's like people want stuff and there's just less stuff.
Scott: There's not enough video cards.
Scott: There's not enough, you know, uh, chips for cars.
Scott: So the cars cost the cars that do exist, cost more, right?
Scott: So used cars cost more, you know, it's like supply of things goes down for anything that causes prices to go up, right?
Scott: Is inflation.
Scott: And there's other kinds of inflation that you don't even think about.
Scott: For example, let's say, you know, you go to a restaurant, right?
Scott: And the restaurant has a hard time getting staff because, or labor, uh, prices have gone up, so they can't hire as much staff, but they kept the prices on the menu, the same, right?
Scott: So you go to the restaurant, you buy the same food for the same amount of money.
Scott: It's like, well, that's not inflation, but actually it was because the level of service has gone down.
Rym: So the people in capital markets are starting to use the term skimpflation to cover that specifically.
Scott: because it's like you're getting, you're, you're still paying the same prices.
Scott: You're making the same money, but you're getting less level of quality for your money.
Rym: If you went to a hotel, like a four star hotel, not a five star hotel, not a three star hotel, but like a four star hotel, a regular old Marriott in a big city somewhere, like the nice one.
Rym: In the eighties, seventies, eighties, nineties, you'd pay an amount of money for a room.
Rym: And it's about the same amount of money today, accounting for inflation for that room.
Rym: But you got way more amenities for that money.
Rym: In the old days, the concierge knew a lot more about the town than the concierge today.
Rym: I'd say the last 10 times I've talked to a concierge at a hotel, they have known less than my smartphone did about anything.
Scott: Or the concierge would be at the hotel 24/7 at that little desk.
Scott: How often is that little desk is usually empty.
Rym: I remember at an Otakon in 2000 and like five or six, me and Adam wanted to keep partying at the, after like everything closed at 2 AM.
Rym: And we were like, Oh, where can we get some food?
Rym: We wanted some Chinese food.
Rym: The concierge knew like the one place that had food late at night.
Scott: Good.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I haven't even seen a concierge at a desk at a hotel other than a five-star hotel in the last decade.
Scott: I did when I was on vacation, when I was on a tropical island, the concierge at the vacation hotel was very good.
Rym: But another example of this is Disney is a really big example.
Rym: Disney has cut tons of basic things that used to just be free or accessible to people who attend Disney, but haven't reduced ticket prices.
Rym: So you get less.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because things that the company has to buy are the prices on those things are going up.
Scott: So rather than keep continuing to provide the same service they did and raising prices for their customers, they're just not cutting service levels and keeping their price the same.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like if a bowling alley, rather than you know, raise prices on shoes, right.
Scott: For the shoe rental, they could just keep the same shoes and not buy as many new shoes and hand out ratty your shoes.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Or even an example in Midtown Manhattan before COVID, if you want lunch in Midtown Manhattan, like it's moderately expensive just because it's Midtown Manhattan, but there were so many lunch places that you could find tons of places that you could just walk in.
Rym: There's like two people in front of you in line, get your food, you walk out, you're good to go.
Rym: Now, as we're not post-COVID, but in the current state that we're in, I have to go to the office three days a week.
Rym: When I go to get lunch, everywhere that still exists that sells lunch, the prices are the same.
Rym: The line is out the door.
Rym: Absolutely out the door.
Scott: Anywhere you want to go.
Scott: Low supply plus lower service, right?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Lower supply.
Rym: There's fewer, like half these places are gone.
Rym: There's so many empty storefronts, fewer employees, so less service, but also they're not paying the despite the fact that they're doing more work.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And the prices of the food have not changed.
Scott: So yeah, basically all these things are combining, right?
Scott: And you're seeing, you know, in the two stories about the handheld gaming devices, how, you know, the economy can affect just this really narrow category, right?
Scott: For different reasons, you know, in the same way at the same time, but that's happening basically in everything.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And I'm surprised it hasn't been disaster.
Scott: Like I'm surprised we're at this, we've somehow managed as a society to like not have, you know, we think about historically.
Scott: when you go to history class, they always teach you about like these big immediate disasters, right?
Scott: Like so-and-so invaded such a place.
Scott: And that was like the moment, right?
Scott: The boom moment, right?
Scott: Or the great, you know, stock market crash in 1927.
Rym: But the great stock market crash wasn't like click and the entire economy is destroyed.
Rym: That's just what basic social studies implies.
Rym: Tiny parts had a catastrophe, but it was a very long and slow spread that affected people, sectors, industries, unevenly.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So we have this expectation that like a disaster is like immediate.
Scott: It's like, we're basically in a disaster.
Rym: We have been, we are in, as Americans at least, we are in four simultaneous disasters, like four real disasters.
Rym: And I don't know how, what the outcome is going to be.
Rym: One, this, the economy is actually grinding to a halt.
Rym: Like it's happening.
Rym: Two, COVID, like COVID is not done.
Rym: So we're in the middle of a a hundred year global pandemic.
Rym: We have climate change on the verge of destroying everything.
Rym: And we've got the rise of fascism.
Rym: So a fun times ahead in the United States of America, but also the world is seeing like other countries are grappling with the same thing.
Scott: They got their own disasters.
Rym: It increasingly feels like America is by and large a collapsing empire.
Rym: Like people say, oh, Rome collapsed.
Rym: Like, yeah, that's true.
Rym: It collapsed over like 80 years, like very slowly and steadily was just collapsing.
Rym: And we could just be in the middle of a long collapse of a country that became great and powerful due to mostly luck by happening to be in the right place at the right time during a big war, once, about 60 years ago.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So there are a lot of adapters out there.
Rym: Like if you want to get from HDMI to that yellow RCA cable that goes into something, there is a string of adapters you could use that would make that happen.
Rym: Like that's possible.
Rym: Some adapters are bad, like the both sides of these Christmas lights are male adapter, which exists for two purposes, killing people and accidentally killing people.
Rym: Usually Americans are on Christmas time.
Rym: But my thing of the day, the doctor has posted an adapter that the doctor made themselves.
Rym: This is a real adapter.
Rym: There's video of them using it.
Rym: And on one end of this adapter is HDMI.
Rym: And on the other end of this adapter is water hose.
Scott: H2O.
Scott: H2O to HDMI.
Scott: You only have to change the two O's to the DMI.
Rym: Really funny when he plugs this into a laptop and turns it on.
Rym: Like really funny.
Rym: That's all I got.
Scott: So there's a webcomic that I never heard of before today called Namesake.
Scott: I've never read it.
Scott: I don't know if it's any good.
Rym: Oh, I thought you knew about it and you were just linking to it because of Cursed Sword.
Rym: This is good biz.
Scott: I had no idea.
Scott: So people that create the webcomic are named Isa and Meg.
Scott: And I discovered them because on Twitter, I saw a comic that they drew with a funny little crow.
Scott: Everyone likes a funny little crow.
Scott: So that funny little crow comic is a new comic that they are doing.
Scott: that is on Naver Webtoon, where all the comics are these days.
Scott: So on Naver Webtoon, that's my thing of the day.
Scott: You can go and link to this comic.
Scott: There's only seven strips so far.
Scott: You can get in on the ground floor.
Rym: Real important to get in on the ground floor of a comic like this.
Rym: Otherwise it's like order the stick where Scott will probably never read at this point.
Scott: It's not a serial though, so you're okay.
Scott: But the comic is called Crow Time.
Scott: Every all seven strips so far are excellent.
Scott: And you can go to their Patreon as well, which there is a link to their Patreon on Webtoon.
Scott: And if you give them a dollar a month, you can see the Crow Time pages a week early before they're on Webtoon.
Scott: So I actually like that because I don't really use Webtoon that often, but I check Patreon like every other day, every day, something like that.
Scott: So I'm basically paying a dollar to see the comic on Patreon instead of on Webtoon.
Scott: But yeah, if you pay even more money, you can see their namesake stuff or you can go to guess their namesake website and read that other comic.
Scott: I don't know if it's any good.
Rym: Crow Time is good news.
Scott: The Crow comic is thing of the day worthy.
Scott: So read the Crow comic for free on Webtoon at the very least.
Rym: And then at the moment, the GeekNights Book Club book is The Tale of Genji.
Rym: We will definitely finish it by the end of the year at the rate I'm going.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: It's my opinion of Genji has not changed.
Rym: That's what I'll say about that.
Rym: But there's a little more action is happening.
Rym: More different things have been lately.
Scott: Whoa.
Scott: Exciting.
Rym: Not that different, but it's not just, oops, he slept with the wrong woman.
Rym: Oops.
Rym: The woman he slept with.
Rym: Turns out she's super ugly in the daylight.
Rym: Like we're past that into slightly more complex situations.
Scott: I think the funniest one is they got better at writing.
Rym: The funniest one is still, oh, shit, she's really ugly.
Rym: Otherwise, our last panel, Atari Game Design on YouTube.
Rym: I will be at PAX Unplugged 2021 doing a panel rare game mechanics on Friday.
Rym: Do not expect to play games with me because I'm literally after that, just going to get a bunch of people, even if you're there at the whole pack.
Rym: So you're talking about games with people you don't think you've ever played.
Scott: I don't think you've ever.
Scott: It was the last time you played a game with the listener, which listener I play.
Rym: I mean, who, what counts as any listener?
Rym: I played a game with Pat at the last packs we went to.
Scott: That doesn't count because that's a friend.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So what I got, I got to find someone who is not an active friend.
Rym: I played games with, I was hanging out at the last magfest.
Rym: we went to in tabletop late at night playing games with randos.
Scott: Randos?
Scott: But were they Geeknight's listeners?
Rym: No, they weren't the listener.
Rym: They were just randos.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: When's the last time you played a game with the listener?
Rym: I should start a train game with a listener.
Rym: It'd be nice to play with it when it's not a crab bucket knife fight like it is with us at this point, but, uh, yeah.
Rym: Otherwise just stay tuned for our biz.
Rym: Our website redesign is underway.
Rym: We got stuff in the hopper.
Rym: Uh, I won't be streaming advanced words anytime soon.
Rym: Cause that got delayed too.
Scott: And let's just get right into it.
Rym: Alien.
Scott: We did our last Thursday show on actual extraterrestrials and we'll do this one on Alien, the sci-fi franchise, all of it, as much as we have experienced.
Rym: Which I will say for myself consists entirely solely of Alien, Aliens, Alien 3, Alien Resurrection, Prometheus, Alien vs Predator that I saw part of on cable and Alien Fireteam, the video game.
Rym: And I think I'm running out.
Rym: Oh, and uh, I guess that, uh, USCMC mod we played of torchbearer.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So of your list, I have not played, I have not seen Alien vs Predator, but I've seen all the Alien, the main, I guess, what is it now?
Scott: Five, six movies.
Scott: I've seen all six of those movies for better or worse.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: I did not see covenant.
Scott: You don't need to talk about it if you want.
Scott: Um, I've played the old side scrolling alien predator video game.
Scott: I played the original Alien vs Predator FPS a little bit.
Rym: I did play that a little bit.
Rym: It was, it was actually ahead of its time.
Scott: I think it was, uh, it was something I played, uh, alien isolation a little bit.
Scott: I didn't beat it.
Scott: I got like, you know, I don't know how many hours steam says I've played.
Scott: Well, I'll look it up while I'm talking.
Rym: I really want to play that.
Rym: I just haven't played it yet, but, I know there's a VR mod, so I'm just going to play it in VR.
Scott: I played it for 90 minutes.
Scott: Um, and then I stopped according to steam.
Scott: Um, and is that it?
Scott: Have I experienced, oh, there's, I know there are alien comics, but I've never read any of them.
Rym: Yeah, me either.
Rym: So alien, alien, like it's interesting thinking.
Rym: as a kid, I always thought of like the movies that I cared about the most were all these trilogies.
Rym: So I remember thinking about, uh, back to the future, Indiana Jones, star Wars, and alien.
Rym: Wasn't a trilogy until 1990, what, two and alien three.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So when I was a kid alien, before I saw it was basically like my mom who loves scary shit, right?
Scott: I know your mom loves scary.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: Our moms would get along to a big degree.
Scott: Even my grandma loves, you know, loved alien.
Rym: So I saw alien as a little kid, right.
Scott: But my mom would, you know, like threatened me with like alien, like, ah, like it's, you know, to me before I saw it, it was like, I just imagined the scariest possible movie.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like there could not be a movie scarier than alien, even though I didn't see it.
Scott: So I didn't actually know how scary it was.
Scott: Um, and I don't know.
Scott: I think that like, you know, is it the best horror movie, right?
Scott: It's like, I know it's obviously not that scary to an adult human being, uh, unless you're easily frightened, but well, it's scary.
Rym: It's scary more for, from my perspective, more from a future science space dystopia angle.
Rym: But right.
Scott: I think as like, you know, cause alien one really is a horror movie, but I think just in the horror category alone, I think the thing might be the only one on top of it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: John Carpenter's the thing.
Rym: I could watch that again.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: Watch it anytime.
Scott: Watch it every day.
Scott: You won't get old.
Rym: I haven't seen it in like a decade.
Scott: That blood scene.
Scott: It's all about the blood scene.
Scott: Um, so, but alien, right.
Scott: Brings in not just the horror angle, right.
Scott: It also brings in on equal measure, right?
Rym: The sci-fi cyberpunk dystopia angle, both the cyberpunk late capitalist dystopia, and also the, the replicants will replace us dystopia, which is often the same, but not always right.
Scott: And at the same time, you know, the feminist angle, right?
Scott: So alien is like this trifecta and also to separate it from those other trilogy things, right?
Scott: When, you know, I don't really know, you know, what Ridley Scott or any of those people were thinking when they made alien.
Scott: I haven't watched all those, you know, behind the scenes.
Scott: I'm sure alien experts know all this, but from the perspective of just a consumer, it seems like star Wars, Indiana Jones, et cetera, were originally intended to be like these franchises.
Scott: Whereas it seems like in alien was just intended to be that one movie.
Rym: Well, an alien came out at the like 1980, 1979, and then aliens was like six years later.
Rym: And then alien three was six years after that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It seems like they hadn't, you know, when alien came out, it was just like a that's, we just made one movie like Jurassic park.
Scott: We just made one movie.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then Jurassic park was a success.
Scott: And that's why he made more books and made more movies for Jurassic park.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Michael Crichton didn't go into Jurassic park.
Scott: Like I'm making a Jurassic park too.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, he just made the one book and then it
Rym: became, I don't, I actually don't know the full story of him, you
Scott: can't ask him now, but alien same kind of deal where there was one alien and then it became a franchise just because it was so big and so good that the capitalism couldn't help itself to make more.
Scott: Um, and I think what really helped alien was that the first one was good, but the second one also being good, right?
Scott: That just the fact that when you have two hits, then the entertainment industry is ready to like buy in forever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They don't, even if you keep making more crap after that, it's like there have been two, they believe that they can make more good ones.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Right.
Rym: But one thing that was, that stands out also terminator, right.
Scott: They made the same director on the two also.
Scott: Right.
Rym: All these late seventies through early nineties, like things that became franchises like this that were violent, scary aimed at adults.
Rym: I remember in childhood in the eighties, every kid knew alien, almost every kid had seen alien and the kids who hadn't lied about seeing it.
Rym: And even the kids who hadn't seen it knew everything about it.
Scott: For some reason, also it came out at, you know, compared to when we were born, right.
Scott: The timing was such right.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: It was, you know, it wasn't, I remember cause it was on VHS.
Scott: It was, you know, it's like, oh, you know, it was on TV, even edited, obviously when aliens came out.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: My parents were like, well, you got to see alien before we this new one.
Rym: So yup.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: But I guess what really stuck with me as a kid, at least, I mean, I didn't see aliens when I was four, but I saw that was still at the phase of alien.
Scott: One is the scariest movie in the world.
Rym: How old was I when I saw alien and alien and aliens in the nineties at some point, I definitely saw them in the later eighties still.
Rym: Cause that was still living in the one house.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So I was at most nine years old when I saw alien and alien.
Rym: that's so, but the thing that stands out the most to me today is that especially alien and aliens, which I liked the most.
Rym: alien three was okay.
Rym: Like I didn't, it was okay.
Scott: It's the best way I'd describe it.
Scott: I wouldn't even give it an okay.
Rym: I mean, okay.
Rym: When I say, okay, that's a three out of five stars out of, I give it a three out of 10 stars, but, uh, alien and aliens are the money there because they both are in the same universe telling similar stories, but the tone of them is so different.
Rym: And I liked them both equally for different reasons.
Rym: Like I don't want to, I almost don't want to say they're equal movies.
Rym: I think alien as a better made movie.
Rym: Like if I just had to try to rank the two of them, but aliens speaks to a lot of things.
Rym: I like space Marines as an aesthetic is something I'm just jacked for all the time, no matter what.
Scott: Well, the way I see it is the alien.
Scott: It's like, okay, we have this universe, this characters, right?
Scott: And alien is like, okay, we're going to do a horror movie set in that universe, right?
Scott: Aliens comes along and says, all right, we're going to do an action movie set in that universe.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they both did a good job.
Scott: They're like top tier, like second best horror movie.
Scott: And you know, very highly ranked action movie, like way up there.
Scott: What I would have liked to see is like, okay, for the third movie, we'll do, you know, comedy set in that universe.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or just pick another genre, a romance set in that universe, but obviously serious.
Scott: Not, you know, a joke.
Scott: Um, but like, and just do like, you know, because just make a really good movie in a genre.
Scott: And then, you know, you could sort of make alien, this skin that could go on any.
Scott: And I do think that like, it might be hard to do comedy and romance.
Scott: Those are tough examples.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But there are other genres, you know, you could do like a historical, like a documentary, right?
Scott: A fake documentary.
Scott: Um, you know, there are lots of film genres you could apply an alien skin to and simultaneously, you know, just try to make the best possible movie of that type and just happen to have an alien skin on it.
Scott: And that would have been, I think what I would prefer for alien to have continued, but instead alien continued after the second to try to do all this like world building and other weird stuff.
Rym: Here's where it really fails for me.
Rym: The whole franchise after alien and aliens, especially Prometheus.
Rym: And I assume covenant.
Rym: I am not interested in the world building of the aliens.
Rym: I'm interested in the world building of the humans who don't fucking treat those aliens with the amount of respect and care that they should because of the cat.
Scott: Some of that world building, you get some of that, that's way more.
Rym: what I'm interested in.
Rym: The, the, the incapacity of a capitalist society like this to deal with an existential threat like the aliens is the story I am most interested in.
Scott: Well, I mean, that's, that story isn't for me.
Scott: Probably.
Rym: Yeah, that story is in Prometheus, but also covenant.
Rym: But I guess it was almost like it was almost comedic in Prometheus.
Rym: How incompetent those characters were, as opposed to say in aliens where the space brains show up and are super competent.
Rym: Of course, there's big asterisk on that because we've all seen the movie, but they show up ready to kick ass.
Rym: They arguably do a lot of things right.
Rym: And it doesn't matter because the situation they were in was fucked before they even got there.
Rym: The fact that they exist in the way that they do is all means that they were already doomed to fail because they are not there to protect humans from the aliens.
Rym: They're there to uphold this like dystopian cyber thing that the rest of humanity is living on back in Earth that we don't really even interact with.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They were going there to save the mines, which produce a lot of.
Rym: they're not there to save the colonists.
Rym: They're not there to save anyone.
Rym: They're just there to save the profit extraction for the homeworld.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And also, you know, extract profits from alien biology also.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But yeah, Alien as a movie was one of it's one of the.
Rym: there are a lot of horror movies that do this.
Rym: I'm not I can't even say it's the best of them ever.
Rym: I would have to sit and think long and hard to make like a reasonable list, but it did a really good job of having huge tension that just builds and builds and builds and not giving you a release
Scott: way
Rym: like the release comes way later than you are waiting or hoping or wanting.
Rym: But it makes it so tense the whole time.
Rym: And like like the chestburster scene to this day, like I think back to like watching that the first time, not expecting that to happen.
Rym: And that scene was so tense for so long of like, is he going to survive the surgery?
Rym: What's happening?
Scott: Well, I mean, the meaning of that scene, right, is like it ties in because throughout Alien, it's, you know, that scene is, I think, the most.
Scott: it's probably the most iconic scene, but it's also the overall theme of Alien.
Scott: one is the things that would be scariest in life for a cis man.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like giving birth.
Scott: Some something is living in your stomach and it's going to come out.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, there is something you can't kill with like a gun.
Scott: It's like there is a computer that won't listen to you.
Scott: The woman is the smartest and most badass person around.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And she doesn't take your shit.
Scott: And she won't fuck you either.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like she cares more about the cat than she cares about you.
Scott: It's like, yeah, it's pretty much like, you know, like.
Scott: not only is it, you know, feminist and showing you right, Ripley, this amazing character is a woman who gets all the shit done.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But also it's like basically horror world for straight dude.
Scott: Like every single thing about Alien.
Scott: It's like, you know, worst possible nightmare.
Rym: But that that feminist narrative like that, that goes way deeper than even that.
Rym: Like along the way, like think about what happens in this movie.
Scott: What's where do the aliens come from?
Rym: Hey, every single time, every single person or situation that should have been Ripley's ally, which would mean they're also humanities ally, had ulterior motives and was not actually an ally when push came to shove.
Rym: Right.
Scott: The heads, the aliens heads are phallic and they have the mouth comes out like that.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Like Ash, you're here to help me.
Rym: No, I'm a, I'm an Android.
Rym: I am literally here to bring the alien back to earth and I will literally murder you once you figure this out.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, that's, that's.
Scott: the other thing is, you know, a lot of movies will have some kind of, you know, like, you know, obvious or not obvious, you know, message.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you get like a, like a Fern Gully with an environmental message.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It just hits you over the head with it.
Rym: Like, Hey, this movie is about this.
Rym: But then you get a movie like RoboCop where you just get one scene, the locker room and men and women are just in there and they're like, there's only one locker room and it's not a problem.
Rym: And that little, like there's a message there, but that I think 99% of viewers didn't even.
Scott: Well, but that's only like a one scene message right here, an alien.
Scott: It's like, they've managed to have several, you know, main themes and it doesn't get cluttered.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, you got the, the computer theme, the capitalism theme, the feminist theme, the right, the, the not listening to the experts, you know, all this stuff.
Scott: And it's like, normally that would like become a big mess.
Scott: Like how do we address all these different lines?
Scott: Right.
Scott: How do we keep all, you know, we can't fit all this into the short movie and have each thing get enough screen time, you know, be coherent, be significant all at once, but they manage it.
Scott: And I think part of the reason they manage it is because it's horror, they kill people off.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's one of those, just like dread, where there's less and less people as the movie goes on.
Scott: So that creates more space for things to exist as the movie progresses.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, they don't really focus on, you know, that Android plot too much until most of the other people are dead, you know, except the Android.
Scott: Um, they see, like, they give you a little hint of him and the early at the start of the movie, they're like, this is Android at the start.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, he's there and they give you a little hint, like, yeah, he's probably, you know, a bad computer, like how 9,000, you know, probably.
Scott: And then he doesn't really, that doesn't really come out till, you know, much later.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're not, they don't spend all this time harping on it.
Scott: They go, they spend the time on the other stuff, but also a lot of those things.
Rym: just, they compliment each other because all these dangers that Ripley faces along the way are not like.
Rym: the alien is not, arguably not even the biggest threat to her.
Rym: And she and the team would have been a lot more successful, but for all these other obstacles that humanity had created for themselves and put in the way.
Scott: So in aliens, right.
Scott: And the second one, what they, the main, the, the second theme, right.
Scott: That they go into is like this like motherhood theme, right.
Scott: Cause you know, you're fighting, right.
Scott: It's like, you know, she finds the girl, right.
Scott: And you know, at the beginning of the, if you watch the, so I guys, people might not know this cause.
Scott: I didn't know this until somewhat recently.
Scott: So I had only ever seen the special edition of aliens, right.
Scott: The original, same for me, but I'm not sure the, I recently discovered the original cause.
Scott: I watched it by accident.
Scott: Cause it was, if you go on Amazon prime video, if you watch aliens for free for $0, they will show you the original theatrical release.
Scott: The original theatrical release is garbage.
Scott: Don't watch that shit.
Scott: All right.
Scott: It doesn't have the mini gun auto cannon scene, the target scene.
Rym: One of the best scenes in the history of cinema.
Rym: I love that scene so much.
Scott: And it doesn't have, I thought of mentioning this because it doesn't have the scene with Ripley, you know, space texting her daughter at the start of the movie, which is the ridiculously important scene.
Scott: So it's basically missing a lot of important scenes.
Scott: So you want it, just always see the special edition of aliens no matter what.
Scott: Uh, but like I was saying that theme of motherhood, right.
Scott: She texts her daughter who basically, you know, hates her because she hasn't been in her life, even though it's not her fault.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Um, I mean, she finds basis, right.
Scott: She finds newt in the place and is like a surrogate mother for newt.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then of course the big bad is the mama alien.
Scott: It's like, you couldn't be more hit over the head with the mom theme and aliens.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then you just combine that with awesome space Marine battle.
Rym: But keeping the same like late capitalist libertarian cyber dystopia in that the space Marines are not a military, like doing normal military things.
Rym: They're company men.
Scott: And then also aliens and alien, even though one's a horror movie, one's an action movie.
Scott: They both, I guess, spoilers.
Scott: Uh, they have that same ending structure where you get away.
Scott: You've, there's an escape at the end.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then there's a, as a square boss of like, Nope, alien still here.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Now you've escaped.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They do the same exact thing.
Scott: And you can see that if you, you know, a lot of, uh, media out there that has been inspired by alien, like, I don't know, Metroid, stuff like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Always does the same thing.
Scott: It's like, Oh, the mother brain is dead.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: It's like same exact thing goes on.
Scott: Um, and that may have been the, the invention of the square boss.
Scott: Possibly.
Scott: I don't want to, you know, it's one of the oldest ones I can think of.
Scott: I don't want to say for sure it's the oldest, but I'd have to think, cause that would be 1986.
Scott: Well, no, first alien had the square boss too.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So 1979.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Before basically almost all video games.
Scott: So well, before I find another man, you would need to find another movie or a book where you thought it was over.
Scott: It wasn't over and you had to kill the end guy again.
Scott: It was a secret end guy.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: But probably was some book or something.
Rym: I've seen aliens again more recently, just randomly, like I watched it again, not that long ago.
Rym: And uh, so I don't want to say I enjoy it more than alien cause it's been longer since I've seen alien.
Rym: So I want to watch that again first before I say anything about these two, but I'll just say they're equally good from my perspective.
Scott: They're like top tier, you know, all time.
Scott: Great movies.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: So let's talk about some of these other movies.
Rym: So for me, this was just bad.
Scott: So alien three is just this weird thing.
Scott: I don't know why anyone likes it.
Scott: Like it has.
Scott: no, you know, it's like, yeah, it takes place in the same universe as alien, but it's like in this weird prison place and it like really, it's just strange.
Scott: It's like some kind of weirdo art movie kinda like.
Scott: I just don't, there's nothing enjoyable about watching it.
Scott: Like you can understand what it's trying to say and what the ideas are, but it's like, there's no point.
Scott: It's not fun.
Scott: It's not, there's no entertainment whatsoever.
Rym: I only ever saw it once.
Rym: Like I actually never watched it again.
Rym: I just saw it the one time in the theater in 1992.
Scott: It's like, why?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, and then alien resurrection is, uh, you know, that's a Joss Whedon mess.
Scott: So I dislike it for a lot of the same reasons.
Scott: I like other Joss Whedon things, but it, you know, it really felt like a direct to TV kind of movie.
Scott: Just like lots of ridiculous stuff happening.
Rym: Apparently alien resurrection had a sequel planned, set back on earth and Sigourney Weaver said, nope.
Rym: And that seems to be a big part of why it didn't get made.
Scott: Well, good.
Scott: Um, so yeah, I'm not a, I'm not a fan of alien resurrection at all.
Scott: It's just like, you know, some nerd just trying to have fun with alien and making a mess instead.
Scott: Uh, it's like whatever.
Rym: Alien resurrection lost that sense of isolation that the other movies had.
Scott: Even the, I mean the prison one wasn't that isolated, but yeah, the, I mean, they, everything lost that sense of isolation except alien and aliens for a covenant had a little bit.
Rym: I never saw a covenant had some isolation aspects.
Scott: Um, right.
Scott: So Prometheus is supposed to be a prequel.
Scott: Uh, and on the one hand it's tantalizing revealing like these secrets like, yes, there was this other alien race, right?
Scott: How did these eggs get here?
Rym: One thing I remember I was like, it was surprised me how unsurprised the humans were in alien and aliens that the alien existed.
Rym: Like they were more worried about what it would do, which implied that humans had already encountered aliens elsewhere, but it didn't really get into that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Cause the start of alien, they find this ship full of eggs and it's a big like U-shaped ship.
Scott: So in covenant of Prometheus, they're like, Oh look, it's a U-shaped ship.
Scott: This is the first time humanity found one of these.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Uh, you know, so I
Rym: came into that movie thinking, all right, we're going to find out like why humans were not surprised by the mere existence of aliens at all in alien, but
Scott: how did the right, the company in alien one was like, you know, knew about the alien and was trying to capture it and use it.
Scott: So how did the Wayland corporation know about it?
Scott: Prometheus answers that question.
Rym: But even in that movie, the humans involved are very unsurprised by the existence of aliens and nor do they seem to care that much about it.
Scott: No.
Scott: Uh, well, some of them do, but yeah, Prometheus is like, on the one hand, it's sort of revealing all that, you know, world secrets.
Scott: Some of them at least, right.
Scott: Which is, you know, if you care about the franchise, it's kind of fun.
Scott: And you know, it's always exciting to have terrible secrets of space, like revealed and answered.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's satisfying.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But like even Evangelion has a better precursor race story than Prometheus.
Scott: But yeah, but the actual story in Prometheus is like meh.
Scott: Um, and it's like, what kind of movie is it?
Scott: It's not a horror movie.
Scott: It's not an action movie.
Rym: It's like, what's like, you know, it's like, could have been a long plotting sci-fi movie, but what it, it doesn't actually reveal enough to be that compelling.
Rym: And it ends on a, not a cliffhanger, but a, Oh, guess what?
Rym: There's going to be a really, really long sequel.
Rym: Uh, that like, that's where it ends.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I think what it, it was satisfying is the word I would use.
Scott: If it wanted to be a sci-fi movie, it should have gone to be, you know, some more like, you know, 2001.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Gets, get really abstract at some point.
Scott: Instead of being so concrete the whole way through.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Um, but I guess the other thing that bothered me about Prometheus was that it, it set up this whole precursor thing and like started to tell this real story, but it did leave it reasonably ambiguous as to what the aliens were up to.
Scott: And like, what was the disaster that happened on that ship or give you, yes, they give you some answers, but then they leave just more questions unanswered and like, excuse themselves from fully building the world.
Scott: It's like, we'll do a little bit, right.
Scott: We'll tell you like one answer.
Scott: Like, yes, it's like, look at that.
Scott: There were giant people, right?
Rym: But more importantly, anything else, there were a lot of ways you could read what that civilization was up to.
Rym: And like, maybe they just made a mistake, but everything I've read about the canonical explanations, like what they were intending is the least interesting possible option.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So let's talk about alien covenant, which the aliens were up to the least interesting possible option.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Oh, still coming out.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I know.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: I to Prometheus, like direct.
Scott: Um, and it's has a lot more in common, like not quality wise, obviously, um, with a movie like silence of the lambs, right.
Scott: Where obviously sounds the lambs of the legendary eight plus film, like alien one tier.
Rym: I just watched that again recently.
Scott: Uh, God damn that movie and alien covenant is a really man movie.
Scott: Uh, I guess alien covenants better than alien three, maybe a little bit, barely.
Rym: I mean, I saw it three in the theater and I was young, so I can't, uh, uh, but alien covenant was really focusing on like, you know, it spends a lot of time philosophizing, right.
Scott: And it was like this one bad guy character, right?
Scott: Like a Hannibal, but he's not obviously not nowhere near as good, uh, an interesting, a character is just a really mad character, but it's like, it's a bad guy.
Scott: He's philosophizing all the time, right?
Scott: It's an examination of him and through him an examination of the situation and what the aliens were up to both the xenomorph ones and the giant ones who flew the spaceships, right.
Scott: What their deal was and you know what happened here.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, he reveals quite a lot about what went on, but what was revealed is like, like you said, the least interesting possible explanation for things and simultaneously continues to reveal so much while also not revealing enough to fully satisfy.
Scott: Like giving you one candy from a, from a whole sleeve of smarties.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It's like, does it continue following that?
Rym: like religious angle.
Rym: that was while it was in Prometheus, but reading like intentions from the creators, they intended it to be even stronger than it might've read.
Rym: Does it still have the religious aspects?
Scott: I mean, you can always read a religious aspect into anything, I guess.
Rym: Um, I mean, I read a thing that they intended.
Rym: the, the inciting incident in the alien side is there with something to do with humans, like killing Jesus.
Rym: Like it was some weird, like trying to tie it into human religion in a really, really pedestrian way.
Scott: I mean, you can read something like that into it.
Scott: The fact that it's called alien covenant.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Um, but just give me, give me a covenant with Lilith and I'm much more interested suddenly.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But it's not, it's not like that.
Scott: It's really, uh, it's just me.
Rym: Um, yeah, this was, uh, I can like to, there's a, yeah, the thing where they were Ridley Scott and everyone, they're talking about like, what was the intention of Prometheus?
Rym: And there's this idea that the aliens and Prometheus were mad because we killed Jesus.
Rym: And they kind of intended that to be a literal reading.
Rym: Uh, okay.
Scott: Maybe I don't know.
Rym: I guess I could, you know, movies.com or ask Ridley Scott when you throw religion and spirituality into the equation for Prometheus, it almost acts like a hand grenade.
Rym: We heard it was scripted that the engineers were targeting our planet for destruction because we had crucified one of their representatives and that Jesus Christ might've been alien.
Rym: Was that considered Ridley Scott?
Rym: We definitely did, but then we thought it was a little too on the nose.
Rym: So that was the direction they went at first.
Scott: I mean, that is the general angle, right?
Scott: Is that the, the, the, the, you know, the big aliens, right?
Scott: The one that you see a skeleton of, right.
Scott: Where they created and used the xenomorph aliens to punish humans.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's absolutely the factor.
Scott: It's like, it's like, that's really boring.
Scott: That is super boring.
Scott: That is not an exciting answer to anything.
Rym: Um, I'm, I'm, I'm even more disappointed now that it just follows that theme and covenant.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, there's a, I guess some kind of twist to it in terms of what actually happens on the planet that they're on in covenant, but you know, if you got to, you know, that time you can spend that time watching.
Rym: He gave a longer answer.
Rym: He did say that they intended for it to literally have been Jesus who was crucified was one of the aliens that then caused them to decide to destroy humanity.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, whatever.
Rym: That's boring.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So yeah.
Scott: Uh, but you know, the alien franchise has spawned, you know, outside of those main movies, lots and lots of stuff.
Rym: Well, it also, it looks large like Spider-Man, like that alien is so universally recognized.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And for such like HR Geiger without alien would have been like an obscure artist, right?
Scott: Like people, despite having created so many great works with such a unique style, that is uniquely horrifying to pretty much all humans, regardless of where they're from or what their history is.
Scott: Uh, you know, but like without alien, it's like, you know, you might know HR Geiger if you were like an art nerd and bought an art book or something, which I know a lot of people who have, but because of alien, everyone recognizes if you see, they might not know HR Geiger's name, but if they see that artwork, you'd be like, Oh, it's, it must be something alien related, right?
Scott: You can't, you can't miss it.
Scott: Um, so that's huge, right?
Scott: To just have, you know, as a, as a visual artist, right?
Scott: To get in some sort of platform for your style.
Scott: I think of it in the same way.
Scott: I think of like Amano and final fantasy.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I should talk to Amano.
Scott: was that final fantasy?
Scott: Probably not.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I remember this moment as a kid, when I got, I was looking at the final fantasy too, in quotes for rule, like book had this amazing art, like the characters look so good.
Rym: And that was what I really put the pieces together and realized that Amano had been responsible for multiple sets of art.
Rym: I had liked not just final fantasy art.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Uh, so you got that aspect, but yeah, there's not only things officially in the franchise, but you've got so many things that are just, you know, Metroid like things right.
Scott: Inspired by alien are actively alien, right?
Scott: It's like that one movie.
Scott: They just made a one-off movie.
Scott: They weren't thinking about any of this, you know, that it was going to be some huge franchise or any, you know, and ended up being this cultural phenomenon that still exists.
Rym: And then somehow they decided to make a sequel that was nearly equally good or possibly actually equally good, but different.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That is notable.
Rym: That is the like almost bigger accomplishment of yes, somehow made more.
Rym: That wasn't just the same, but also still felt like it was the same and it wasn't bad.
Rym: And it man, it was at least as good as what you did before.
Rym: Like that is so rare.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: That's like the bomb that set it off.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was like, you made something so good that you demanded a sequel and the sequel is good.
Scott: It's like, all right, well, I guess this is a thing forever now.
Scott: It's like, yup.
Scott: It's a thing forever now.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Like Terminator became a thing forever, even though really it had just one and a half good movies.
Scott: Well, Terminator's I think fading somewhat.
Scott: Maybe it'll be back.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I think we can end there.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion, news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi Bay, Nicole Allen, Joyce Link, Eiji Dread, Lily Tenebrae, and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names, Chris Rymer, Clinton Walton, Dex Finn, JustLikeADudeGuy, Chi-I85, Rebecca Dunn, ReviewMedbull34, Cowards, Ryan Perrin, Sam Erickson, Sherwin Von Horro, Taylor Braun, The Iron Front, you old, the key to my heart, and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names.
Rym: So, uh, yeah.
Rym: We, uh, really only like two of these alien movies and I feel like I'd watch both of them again.
Rym: It's been a while.
Rym: But, uh, for now, I don't have anything new to say, so I'm just going to leave you with... Uncle, Uncle!
Rym: The Droid Caravan's almost here!
Scott: What are you so fucking delighted about the Droid Caravan?
Scott: I mean, you know, what a low fucking level of entertainment it is.
Rym: But Uncle, you grew up on Sand Planet!
Rym: You love Sand Planet!
Scott: No, I don't love Sand Planet!
Scott: I grew up here, yeah, I don't fucking... Who would want to, who would love this place?
Scott: This is an awful, awful fucking world.
Scott: And you're all excited about it, and look, I get it, you know, I'm sitting out here too, just like you, you know, here I am, like, acting like I'm above it.
Scott: I want to see the fucking weird droids.
Scott: I want to see what fucking dumb idiot bullshit droids that they've, that they're trying to fucking peddle and, you know, sell to people.
Scott: I want to see it.
Rym: Droids!
Rym: We got fucking droids!
Rym: We do it every week!
Rym: Come on, guys, speed it up now!
Scott: Every Sunday.