Rym: It's Wednesday, February 3rd, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are talking about Lupin the third, the first.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So, uh, two days ago-ish, right?
Scott: Sunday night through early yesterday, there was a blizzard in New York.
Scott: It dumped a whole ton of snow, like top 10 snows of New York.
Scott: It was big time snow.
Rym: It was the kind of snow where if it wasn't COVID times, I literally would have taken days off work and, like, gotten myself upstate to stay at a ski place.
Scott: If it wasn't COVID times, I would have stayed in like it was COVID times.
Scott: Yeah, I also would have gotten a snow day.
Scott: Oh, my office would absolutely would have closed.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: And it wouldn't have been, like, actually work from home, like, all day.
Rym: It would have been the work from home as in, yeah, do what you can, but yes, no.
Scott: Work would have been closed, closed.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Scott: So, uh, when it snows like that in New York, right, you don't really want to order food delivery, even if you can, because that is such a jerk move, right?
Rym: Right.
Scott: Food delivery people shouldn't be risking their life to bring you a dinner when in the middle of a blizzard, right?
Rym: My policy has always been that if the weather's bad to a certain point, I'll just give a giant tip, like 20 or 30 bucks, and if it's been, like, on that point, I won't order it.
Scott: If it's raining or something, like, and I really need the food, maybe I'll do it and pay a lot, you know, but, so anyway.
Rym: But there's a line.
Scott: There is a line, and you can tell that most people agree with this policy because every time I looked out the window, you did not see any delivery people.
Scott: I think I saw one on, like, the morning after, right?
Scott: I saw one, and that was it, right?
Scott: So people, people are, you know, not, but then again, it's like, I wonder from the perspective of delivery person, like, you must be in a tough spot.
Scott: You're like, damn, I want money, right?
Scott: I'm not making, I'm not making anything today, but also, damn, I don't want to go outside, you know, getting an accident, who knows what, right?
Scott: So it's a tough, tough spot, I don't know, but I, you just feel guilty doing it, right?
Scott: So anyway, it comes this morning, and you look outside and the road is clear.
Scott: It's perfectly plowed and melted, and it's not precipitating, and the sun's out, and you're like, okay, it's still cold as hell.
Scott: But now I'm in a situation where without guilt, I can order delivery with a big ol' tiff on there.
Rym: Yeah, but it already got warm enough.
Rym: Snow's already, like, melted significantly.
Scott: Right, and since we've been inside for a few days and fresh air, I canceled our delivery for good reason, right?
Scott: We needed some food.
Rym: The day the blizzard happened, I put in a delivery slot for Thursday.
Scott: Yeah, ours is also Thursday, but we had, like, a Monday, and it just got canceled.
Rym: I luckily happened to have gotten a Saturday, so I was good.
Scott: Anyway, point is, needing food, road's clear, guilt gone, tip big, I'm okay ordering bagels for breakfast, right?
Scott: That'll carry us for, you know, whenever.
Scott: So I order the bagels, you know, and I'm going, getting ready to bike inside, like I've been doing in the morning.
Scott: And the bagel, I realize, is specifically late, right?
Scott: It should've been here already, right?
Scott: So I go and I check, you know, I'm looking at the thing, what time it said it was gonna be here.
Scott: It said it would be here, like, you know, 8.37.
Scott: It's already, like, you know, closer to 9 or whatever.
Scott: And I'm, like, looking closely, and I go, oh shit, I forgot to click delivery.
Scott: The default is pick up.
Scott: The bagels must be sitting at the bagel place.
Scott: And the thing is, if I go to get bagels outside, there's close places that are not even at the subway.
Scott: But if I get delivery, there's a better bagel place.
Scott: that's further away.
Rym: Yeah, like, if I go out to get a breakfast sandwich, there's a place I'll go.
Rym: But if I'm ordering a delivered breakfast sandwich, there's a very specific different place I will go.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So I had to suddenly not bike inside this morning, not do any normal morning stuff, and instead put clothing on, which is why I'm wearing clothing.
Rym: I was about to say, you're wearing, like, a real shirt.
Rym: Like, I got...
Scott: I had to go outside.
Rym: I got all these Hawaiian shirts that I usually would wear, like, just when I'm lounging around.
Rym: So I'm doing like that, because they kind of look like a dress-ish shirt, because there's technically a collar.
Rym: And I just got pajamas on otherwise.
Scott: Yeah, I know, right?
Scott: So I had to go outside this morning and walk all the way down the road to get the bagels.
Scott: They were just sitting there waiting for me.
Rym: You know, it's almost a nice excuse to just be outside, though.
Rym: Like, I look forward to the excuses.
Scott: Well, I gave a huge tip, which I guess should have gone to me.
Scott: But instead, I guess the vehicle preparers have that money now, which is fine, but, you know.
Rym: Hopefully, I mean, hopefully it goes to them and not to, like, the owner of the place, if there was no delivery.
Scott: I'm sure they see it.
Rym: Well, because Amazon just got hit with, like, stealing the tips from all their drivers.
Rym: Like, that was a big thing.
Scott: But the way the systems work usually at these places is, you know, you go into any restaurant in New York City, especially a takeout delivery type restaurant, they have a tablet and maybe even a printer if they're more old school, right?
Scott: But usually just a tablet sitting there, like maybe one tablet per service or one tablet with all the services, some kind of setup, and they can see exactly the invoices of everyone putting in orders, right?
Scott: And then they transfer that over to their internal system, right?
Scott: Usually printing out a ticket for, like, you know, a receipt for what to make and stuff, right?
Scott: So it'll say on there, you know, I've seen it because it's right there.
Scott: You can see it.
Scott: It says, ah, such and such and a tip, right?
Scott: So if the owner was, you know, keeping all those monies, because I guess all that money, you know, digitally goes to the owner's account, the people who are working, they still see how much all those tips are.
Scott: So if at the end of the month, you know, the owner comes back and is like, here, one dollar for everybody.
Scott: They'd be like, I saw what people were tipping.
Scott: You know, you know, I didn't add it up on my own, but I know what people are doing on average.
Scott: Just don't seem right.
Scott: So anyway.
Rym: So you got some, there's some big, there's a bunch of news, actually.
Rym: I was surprised.
Rym: Usually Wednesdays we struggle unless we've watched something to Geek Bite.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So I think the most important one to me personally is about who you're gonna call.
Scott: So when we were kids, right, there was Ghostbusters, the movie Ghostbusters to the movie.
Scott: Right.
Rym: There was Ghostbusters cartoon.
Rym: that was not the one that we wanted to watch.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: I didn't even know about that one until Internet time.
Scott: I used to watch it.
Scott: It didn't, it didn't air where I lived.
Rym: It aired where I lived.
Rym: And it was like, there were kids who watched it and knew about that.
Rym: And even the original live action show, like.
Scott: But yeah, there was some other show called Ghostbusters.
Scott: that was cartoon.
Scott: that was, had nothing to do with the Ghostbusters movie.
Rym: It's the one with the Jeep and the giant gorilla.
Rym: Like that's how you know it's not the real Ghostbusters.
Scott: It was much, it was basically a Scooby Doo knockoff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: As far as I remember.
Rym: I had a bunch of toys for that Ghostbusters.
Scott: Anyway, so, but then the real reason that kids were fans of Ghostbusters in, you know, late 80s, early 90s times, right, whenever those times were, I guess, I guess that was the time, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Was not because of that original movie, you know, although we did watch it and enjoy it.
Rym: I love that movie as a little kid.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But Ghostbusters carried forward with greater fandom instead of just, you know, there were a lot of like single movies that kids were a fan of.
Scott: That didn't carry, you know, for example, like Robocop, right?
Rym: No, Robocop had the cartoon that I watched.
Scott: It did, but Robocop cartoon was not a long lasting deal.
Rym: Well, when the Robocop cartoon faded away, so too did Robocop fandom among kids.
Rym: There was that, kids knew the predator, but there wasn't a predator cartoon for them to watch.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So thing, you know, you needed to keep, you know, in those days there was no internet.
Scott: You needed to keep some production up, right.
Scott: To have kids carry on with your property like Ninja Turtles did.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You were all bombarded with new Ninja Turtles stuff all the time.
Scott: It's still going.
Scott: Pokemon still going.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So Ghostbusters had a Ghostbusters to keep going.
Scott: There was a cartoon that, you know, called the real Ghostbusters.
Scott: And there was also a toy line to go with the show.
Rym: I had all those god damn toys.
Rym: The cartoon.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: The best toy, the one I had was that like maid old lady witch where you pulled her hat up and there was an eyeball under there and she pulled her whole head up.
Scott: Like her whole body opened up like a mouth.
Rym: So the thing about that, like those toys were basically based on the cartoon, not the movie.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: And the cartoon, unlike all the other cartoons we were watching in that era, even though I was actually starting to watch anime in that era because my family got me into it.
Rym: The Ghostbusters cartoon was good, dark, and fucked up.
Rym: Like way more fucked up than I think a lot of parents realized.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: And that's kind of why it was so popular with kids.
Rym: Because kids were watching me like wow, that was fucked up.
Rym: And then we watch He-Man like wow, what's this plebeian, boring cartoon compared to the Ghostbusters?
Scott: And actually the real Ghostbusters cartoon didn't stray too far from the movie.
Scott: Usually a lot of times, even as a kid, you can get angry at poor adaptations.
Scott: The sort of thing like hey you took Tom Bombadil out.
Scott: That sort of thing.
Scott: Even as a kid you'd get angry at that sort of stuff.
Scott: I remember you read Jurassic Park and then you watch the movie and you'd be like hey!
Scott: You changed all this bullshit.
Scott: But the real Ghostbusters cartoon, it wasn't exactly the same.
Scott: Let's not get carried away here.
Rym: But it followed the canon of that movie's universe.
Scott: Slimer was not a friend of the Ghostbusters in the movie.
Scott: He was a one time enemy that they destroyed.
Rym: But if you think about the Ghostbusters movie, what it implies that no one in the movie addresses is like this Cthulhu-esque existential terror world that humans inhabit briefly.
Rym: And the cartoon just leaned into that.
Scott: The real Ghostbusters was a great cartoon.
Scott: I remember it being a great cartoon and not being crappy like a lot of other ones that don't live up.
Scott: But now the news, why is this news?
Scott: We can now prove to ourselves whether our memory is correct.
Scott: They are putting the real Ghostbusters cartoon on YouTube.
Scott: Supposedly the whole thing eventually for free?
Scott: Maybe?
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: But regardless there's at least some episodes, at least one up there now on the Ghostbusters YouTube channel I think.
Rym: The last time I tried to verify if this was kid memory or if it was legit was in RIT, we pirated like one episode and we all watched it together.
Rym: The one where at one point it was raining croutons.
Rym: That's the scene I remember.
Scott: Oh okay.
Scott: But yeah.
Scott: So now if you were not of our age, or if you've never seen it, even if you are of our age or older, I recommend you actually do go and attempt to watch some of this at least to see what was up.
Scott: It's notable, noteworthy, quality, you know.
Rym: It was a solid show.
Rym: Well we'll find out if it was truly a solid show because you're all gonna watch it and you might come back in the comments and be like, "Ribbon Scott, you're just
Rym: old.".
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: That could easily happen.
Rym: So in some other news, a little bit of a geek bite.
Rym: So I'm not super into the MCU, like I don't really enjoy a lot of those movies.
Rym: But WandaVision, which I'm sure you've heard of, I'm not gonna like try to explain it, but WandaVision is a show that you can just watch that is set in- On Disney Plus though, right?
Rym: Yeah, it's on Disney Plus.
Scott: You can't just watch it if you don't have Disney Plus.
Rym: It's a show that appeared one episode by episode, like three episodes came out, and then a fourth one happened, so I've seen enough to see where it's going.
Rym: And it's higher concept than I expected.
Rym: I expected it to be good because of the concept, which I'll get into in a second, when I watched episode one.
Scott: Because Scott, you had this idea- I didn't watch it at all.
Rym: You should probably watch it.
Rym: The problem is episode one is good at being a very clever and deep homage to an era of television.
Scott: That's what I assumed it was.
Scott: Based on the still image I saw with the logo, that is exactly what I assumed the whole show would be.
Rym: The second episode does that from the next decade of television, and at that point- Next episode, Bewitched.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: That's even more clever than I had given it credit for.
Rym: I like it.
Scott: I'm warming.
Scott: I'm sweetening.
Rym: The cleverness is deep, as in every tiny little detail.
Rym: If you're a kid who watched Nick at Nite, or you're just old, you'll notice a lot of very subtle bits and very subtle components.
Scott: I definitely could see how that would be amiss on people who weren't familiar with the tropes of 50, 60, 70s television.
Rym: In episode one, there's a moment where something happens, they're laying in their separate beds, and there's a noise out the window.
Rym: But they do some magic and pull the beds together.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: The second episode worried me because it was still just homage, and as much as I like homage to those eras of television, the second episode wasn't as funny as an actual episode of Bewitched or I Love Lucy, which were both really funny shows.
Scott: Right, what I'm guessing here already, just as somebody who simply has knowledge of the characters, even though I don't watch Marvel movies or anything.
Rym: Is something going on?
Scott: Is that clearly, right, the best, the only good?
Scott: Scarlet Witch, I don't know any comics personally that involve the Vision that are any good.
Rym: I know less about comics than you, but I can know enough to say that House of M is the only interesting storyline I've ever even heard of.
Rym: that involves the Scarlet Witch.
Rym: And Vision, I didn't know anything about.
Scott: That's exactly right.
Scott: Vision is an Avenger who's a robot and should be awesome because in concept he's awesome.
Rym: I didn't even know he was an Avenger, I just knew he was a robot.
Rym: I assumed he was from space.
Scott: He's like an android or whatever.
Rym: I knew he was a robot from space and I didn't know anything else.
Scott: He's something like that, but the point is...
Rym: Didn't Ultron make him or something?
Scott: I don't know, something like that, but in concept he should be really awesome.
Scott: But in reality, I've never read a comic with the Vision where he was interesting or cool at all.
Scott: He was lame.
Scott: And I keep saying lame, I'm trying not to.
Rym: I know you're working on it.
Scott: Working on it.
Scott: And the Scarlet Witch, I've never read a comic book other than House of M where the Scarlet Witch was cool.
Scott: I never cared about the Scarlet Witch other than in her relation to Magneto, it's Magneto's daughter.
Scott: And that's what made her cool.
Scott: Not any of her powers or anything.
Scott: Except for House of M, which is an X-Men storyline in which she creates some alternate universe that all the mutants are trapped in.
Scott: And it's ridiculous, but still good.
Scott: So as soon as you tell me that the second episode is a decade later, it's like, "Oh, this whole WandaVision thing, she's created an alternate universe they stole from the comic books again without giving credit to the people...".
Rym: It's obvious that this is a... You watch it right away if you know anything about the Scarlet Witch.
Rym: That's the first thing I thought is, "Okay, clearly the Scarlet Witch has created this universe.
Rym: Now, how close will it be to House of M?
Rym: What's it gonna
Rym: do?".
Rym: That's the only thing I didn't know.
Scott: The thing that seems to keep happening, and I guess I've noticed it more because I've been following this Twitter account.
Scott: There's a Twitter account called, I guess, the Claremont Run, right?
Scott: Because this is guy John Claremont who wrote basically all the X-Men comics that are famous.
Scott: You know, the Dark Phoenix ones, all those were all written by this Claremont.
Scott: Oh, Claremont and Burn, but Burn left.
Scott: Claremont's the guy, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: He's still alive, too.
Scott: But they mentioned, basically it posts one thread a morning, and the threads are always great.
Scott: But they talk about, like, "Hey, they made all these X-Men stuff in
Scott: Hollywood."
Scott: And all of it is based on, basically, mostly John Claremont's work.
Scott: It's not based on the other X-Men storylines, right?
Scott: It's mostly based on these original stories that John Claremont wrote.
Scott: And they didn't hire him to write the X-Men movies.
Scott: They don't credit him that much.
Scott: Maybe he, like, you know, does a cameo in one or something.
Scott: I don't know if he's getting money or what, but it's like, everything they make is based on his original work.
Scott: Those are original stories, right?
Scott: He wrote those from, you know, back in the day on his own, right?
Scott: And now people are just rewriting Dark Phoenix five times over.
Scott: It's like, he should be getting paid five times over and credited five times over, and he's not.
Scott: So if they're doing House of M here, right, as WandaVision, shouldn't they-- I don't know who wrote House of M. It's probably a name I know, but I don't know the-- I can't pull the name out of my, you know, ass without Googling it.
Scott: But is that person getting the credit?
Scott: Are they writing this show, right?
Scott: If you have-- the person who wrote the original thing you're adapting, right?
Scott: You're making Lord of the Rings the movie, you know, token is not alive.
Scott: So it's understandable, right?
Scott: But if he was alive, why would you just not get him to write the movie also?
Scott: It makes no sense.
Rym: The only-- so, like, here's an example of how the show goes.
Rym: They're doing this homage, but then, like, one color object appears in the first episode, and Wanda sees it and kind of, like, gets unnerved by it.
Rym: And, like, a character kind of glitches out a little bit in a weird way, and, like, no one can deal.
Rym: Like, he's trying to figure out.
Rym: The second episode gets weirder.
Rym: Like, there's a few more moments like that.
Rym: And my worry was, the show's just gonna be, it's the homage plus a couple weird things, and just go through all the decades.
Rym: But it did not.
Rym: The third episode, everything becomes color.
Rym: Now it's the Partridge Family/The Brady Bunch.
Rym: And also, the plot escalates rapidly.
Rym: And I'm not gonna, like, spoil much, because the show's worth watching.
Rym: It's not that long so far.
Rym: The fourth episode goes to, basically, the outside of people trying to figure out what the fuck's going on.
Rym: And, like, it turns into a proper superhero story.
Rym: And I'm actually really enjoying it.
Rym: The second episode, I got a little worried.
Rym: Third episode, I was unworried.
Rym: And now the fourth episode, it's fun.
Rym: Like, I see what they're doing.
Scott: Wikipedia says that, yeah, they pitched it to, you know, them.
Scott: They pitched it that it would be based on House of M and some other stories, right?
Scott: So, that was already in their thoughts.
Scott: And House of M was written by Brian Michael Bendis and Olivier Coypel.
Scott: I knew those names, I just didn't know they were the ones who wrote it.
Scott: And, yeah, they don't seem to be involved.
Scott: Other people are writing it.
Scott: I wish I could do that.
Scott: Like, you know, it's like, you know, when you own intellectual property like that, I guess you can, you know, sort of plagiarize people without it being plagiarism, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, I'm gonna keep watching it.
Rym: I'm not bored with it.
Rym: I'm enjoying it more than I've enjoyed most MCU things.
Scott: I'm gonna continue to not watch MCU things.
Rym: Yeah, you could probably stand to at least watch just the first episode, because you at least will appreciate the ridiculous level of detail they put into this.
Scott: But I could just watch, like, I Dream of Jeannie.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I'm sure it's on the internet somewhere.
Rym: I think Big Witch was funnier.
Rym: And honestly, I Love Lucy is funnier than both of those.
Scott: I like I Dream of Jeannie better because the guy was an astronaut, right?
Scott: So, there was that whole thing going on.
Rym: Yeah, I can see that.
Rym: But honestly, I Love Lucy is the one that I love the most.
Scott: Eh, sometimes.
Rym: Of course, I was weirdly into Andy Griffith as well.
Rym: Like, I earnestly enjoy that show.
Rym: And as a kid, I was really into Dragnet because I didn't know.
Rym: So, in some other brief news, the One Piece manga, like, you all, like, everyone's heard of One Piece.
Rym: Even people who don't read comics, like, they hear of, like, "Oh, that's that pirate thing," right?
Rym: I don't think people fully appreciate how widely read One Piece is.
Scott: Alright, so I want to just put this into perspective for you, right?
Scott: So, here's some numbers from Wikipedia, right?
Scott: So, the numbers from Wikipedia say that if you consider all Batman comics ever, right, the floppy ones, right?
Scott: Because the number of trade paperbacks of Batman that have been sold are not significant, right?
Scott: So, the number of Batman floppy comics sold.
Scott: There have been about 17,000-ish issues of Batman comics of one type or another since 1939.
Scott: So, how many, so 40, so 70 years, we're gonna say, right?
Scott: From 1940 to 2021, 1939, 21, 70 years, right, of Batman comics.
Scott: All of those floppy issues added up, they sold 484 million floppy comics-ish.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: Based on rough numbers, right?
Scott: So, you gotta think, 484 million divided by 40 years divided by 12 months, because those are monthly floppies, right?
Scott: It's basically the number of people-ish that read Batman, right?
Scott: It's like a turnstile-related counter.
Rym: Yeah, uniques and turnstiles, I was about to say.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Okay, One Piece sells by the volume, right, and has 98 volumes.
Scott: There are 98 volumes of One Piece, and those volumes have sold 480 million.
Scott: So, about the same number as floppies of Batman.
Scott: But you're only dividing, not by 17,000 issues, but by 98 volumes.
Scott: So, that's you're dividing by 100.
Scott: So, what's 480 million divided by
Scott: 100? 4.8
Scott: million, right?
Scott: What's 480 million divided by 17,000 issues, right?
Scott: And then, you also gotta consider the years, right?
Scott: Batman hit, it took 400, to get 404 million sales of floppies, they had to go for 70 years.
Scott: One Piece came out in 1997.
Scott: It's only 20, not even 25 years old, One Piece, right?
Rym: Oh, that just makes me feel old, because I remember, like, when One Piece started, and I was like, ah, that show looks like it's gonna be, like, that comics too.
Scott: I didn't know One Piece existed until about four or five years after, three to five years after it started.
Scott: I didn't know about One Piece in 1997.
Rym: I think I didn't know about it until, like, 1998 or '99, when I think back.
Scott: I didn't know about One Piece until 2000.
Rym: 'Cause I was super into anime and manga in high school, but I knew one guy, only one person, who was way more into it than I was.
Scott: But anyway.
Scott: One Piece, this doesn't even include, you know, One Piece anime, but I guess we're not counting BTAS either, right?
Scott: But yeah, and that only, that's the volumes, right?
Scott: If you count the actual shonen jumps that One Piece is in, right?
Scott: We're talking billions, right?
Scott: So, people just are not, like, realizing, I think, you know, scope-wise, in America, there's this perception of, like, the big two.
Scott: We talked about this before, right?
Rym: Yeah, there's the marketing machine of, oh yeah, Marvel and DC sell all these comics.
Scott: In other industries, there are big X, right?
Scott: There's, like, big, how many big book publishers does less and less every day be merging, right?
Scott: But it's like, or record companies, there's the big this many, right?
Scott: You know, in every industry, there's, like, a big X. You know, some very small number, like, less than five handful of companies that are the big ones, and everyone else is medium or small.
Scott: In U.S.
Scott: comics, there's this perception of the big two, DC and Marvel, and it's true that their intellectual properties of superheroes are big in the culture-wise, right?
Scott: But in terms of comics, they are not actually big, right, in terms of all comics sold, not even in the
Scott: U.S.,
Scott: but indefinitely in the world, they are not big.
Scott: It's like, Batman comics are, you know, more popular than other superhero comics, but it's like, in terms of all comics in the world, they are not that popular.
Scott: One Piece is the king of comics throughout all history, and you've got to, and even starting at One Piece, you've got to go far down the list before you find Batman.
Scott: It's like, Garfield crushes, you know, Batman easily.
Rym: Like, Archie comics are widely read.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I mean, you know, if it's the North Star crushes it, right, you know, it's like Asterix and Obelisk, they crush it.
Scott: I assume that, like, probably Donald Duck comics crush it, depending on how many you include in your tally, right?
Scott: Tintin probably crushes all superhero comics ever.
Scott: So, you know, you need this perspective correction, I think, if you're, you know, thinking about comics and how popular they are, relatively speaking, and it's such a big reality distortion, that's why I feel the need to bring it up repeatedly.
Rym: Maybe the Scarlet Witch is involved.
Scott: It takes that much repetition to sort of break the spell, right, of false perception.
Rym: Well, like, you know, what we always just talk about with conventions and the turnstile counts and all these conventions saying, "Oh, yeah, 200,000 people showed up at our
Rym: convention."
Rym: Like, nah, that's not the number everyone thinks it is.
Rym: Or not?
Rym: 200,000 people in that building.
Scott: The perception that San Diego Comic-Con was, you know, so, like, ten times bigger than Otakon, when it was really just kind of bigger than it, you know, not that much bigger.
Rym: Of course, it'll be infinitely bigger than Otakon if things don't pan out for Otakon this year, which we talked about in the last show.
Rym: But things of the day!
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: So, we both saw the same thing in a tweet today, even though the thing itself is a year old.
Scott: But I snatched his thing of the day first, so deal with it.
Rym: I had it queued up for the show, and then Scott was like, "Oh, yeah, here's my thing of the
Rym: day.".
Rym: And he sent it to me, and our rule is, if you send the other person your thing of the day, it's theirs.
Rym: That's dibs.
Scott: That's right, you get dibs.
Scott: So, there's an animation studio in London that I didn't know about.
Scott: But apparently, this animation studio, I did some quick research on them.
Scott: They really remind me of the early days of Studio Gonzo, making small commercial animations of high quality.
Scott: Gonzo used to do video game intros and those sorts of things.
Scott: So, for example, the animated Wargroove promo animation, they made that.
Scott: So, the thing that they made a year ago is this 90-second.
Scott: It's a minute and a half long.
Scott: It's a song, and it looks like a trailer or an opener to an animation that doesn't exist.
Rym: All I want is to see the show that this was pretending to be.
Scott: Well, you might.
Scott: So, this was made a year ago.
Scott: They uploaded it, but there's been a lot of hints.
Scott: it might be coming for real.
Scott: It's called The Mighty Grand Piton.
Scott: What it is, basically, you watch this in 90 seconds, you get the whole concept.
Scott: There is a black girl from London, and her family goes on vacation to the Caribbean to Saint Lucia.
Scott: I think one of those islands.
Scott: I don't know the names.
Scott: There's too many islands.
Scott: Sorry, I don't know all the Caribbean islands.
Scott: That's my fad.
Scott: And on that island, it's pretty much an Iron Giant situation.
Scott: She finds a giant robot, anime style, and fights what seems to be giant monsters of some kind.
Scott: There's a giant ant in the animation that you can see it fighting.
Scott: And adventures and such and such.
Scott: So, this is awesome because A, there's tons of anime like this.
Scott: Little kid, giant robot, but it almost always involves a young Japanese boy like 99% of the time.
Scott: And a young white boy like 1% of the time Iron Giant.
Scott: It almost never involves a young girl who's got a robot to themselves.
Scott: And definitely not a black girl.
Scott: And definitely not on a Caribbean island.
Scott: So, that's just like A+, not even A+.
Scott: It's S+.
Scott: This just looks great.
Scott: And the animation is great, and the song is great.
Scott: that goes to this.
Rym: I was about to say, it gave me that same feel of that 2Mix video, White Reflection, everyone saw.
Rym: Where everyone said, "Oh, I want to see the anime of
Rym: that.".
Rym: Like, it gave me that same feeling.
Scott: It's just a music video.
Scott: It's like, "What do you mean,
Scott: anime?".
Scott: But here, no, I really hope that, you know, we've seen some good animation coming from Ireland.
Scott: Why not from the big island?
Rym: Albion.
Scott: Yeah, people from the Albion island make animation about, you know, the Caribbean island.
Scott: That would be terrific.
Scott: You know, the best thing about this?
Scott: The supposed hints about this becoming an actual show/movie are true.
Scott: But yeah, well, this is more than worth 90 seconds of your time.
Scott: Watch it two times.
Rym: The top comment on the YouTube video from a year ago is, "The whole world needs to see
Rym: this.".
Scott: Sure, yes.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: You, like, played the clarinet and know some music, so you know about time signatures, right?
Rym: Yeah,
Rym: 3/4. 3/4, 4/4,
Rym: like, you know what that means.
Rym: Like, 4/4 means there are, we're speaking in quarter notes, and there are four quarter notes in a measure.
Rym: Like, one, two, three, four.
Rym: One, two, three.
Rym: Like, that's pretty straightforward.
Scott: One thing that wasn't straightforward is, like, you got 4/4, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Which means you got, what, four per measure, right?
Rym: Four quarter notes per measure.
Rym: That's the same as 1/1.
Rym: One whole note per measure.
Rym: It is the same.
Scott: Right, so if you made 8/8, it wouldn't be any different.
Rym: It wouldn't actually be any different.
Rym: Usually it just means, like, you'll draw all the eighth notes out.
Rym: Like, it's sort of like how you'll draw the music.
Rym: Like, 2/4 and 4/4 can be written, there's a lot of...
Scott: Sure.
Scott: So, uh... But they're equivalent, and that's why people don't bother doing, there's only certain ones people actually use unless they're ridiculous.
Rym: And then there's the ones like 6/8, where it's, we're talking about eighth notes, but there'll be groups of them, like, duh-duh-duh-duh-duh-duh-duh-duh-duh-duh-duh, like groups of triplets, but that still makes sense.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: So, uh, what about the weird ones?
Rym: Like, every kid knows that there's that weird song in the time signature of 5/4, Mars, Bringer of War.
Rym: The classic song, it's in 5/4, there's five quarter notes per measure, and it makes it unwieldy, and, like, difficult to listen to, and it's a whole thing.
Rym: Uh, what if I told you that 15/16 is a commonly used and amazing time signature that you've probably never thought ever heard of?
Scott: I've probably heard songs in it and just not thought about that they were 15/16.
Rym: Probably haven't actually heard that many, because usually the way you get the feeling of 15/16 is like a funk groove, which isn't often written in 15/16.
Rym: So, this video is Adam Neely.
Rym: This is a backup thing of the day, 'cause I had to scramble, 'cause Scott got the good thing.
Rym: Uh, I had this cued up as, like, a backup since Christmas.
Rym: This is Christmas songs, like, a bunch of Christmas songs you've heard rewritten into the time signature of 15/16.
Scott: Oh, I think I saw this.
Scott: You posted it.
Rym: And they're all, I think I posted it, like, in our group or maybe even in the forum, but they're all amazing.
Rym: Like, they're really fun to listen to.
Rym: I particularly like God Rest Ye Merry Gentlemen in 15/16.
Rym: In the meantime, I'm edging toward reading books, 'cause I can't go anywhere.
Rym: I'm just stuck inside.
Rym: And at some point, I gotta just not play Hades and do a non-Hades thing if I'm just sitting around.
Scott: Yeah, I'm reading a game that is very book-like.
Scott: I'm already, like, on my second play, and then I'm reading comics.
Scott: But, yeah, I haven't read the book club book quite yet.
Rym: I'm getting there, though, 'cause the problem is Overwatch has been good again.
Rym: There's been a lot more cash of the flag action in the arcade, which is a problem, 'cause I'll just sit in there forever.
Rym: But, yeah, stay tuned.
Rym: We'll probably be reading the book at some point in the nearing future.
Rym: Otherwise, stay tuned for whatever online cons we do.
Rym: The online convention scene has dried up a little bit.
Scott: I think people have realized, yeah, they don't really make money.
Rym: Yep, and especially for cons that are struggling to survive COVID until a post-COVID world, online cons just cost them a lot of money and resources, but don't actually get them anything.
Rym: And especially, online cons don't really give that same feeling that people expect, so a lot of cons are struggling to make a useful and good online con experience.
Scott: You've said this over and over.
Scott: A con is not the content provider.
Scott: A con is a logistics provider, and if you don't have any need of those logistics, if you're not going to a place, so they have nothing to offer unless their brand is stronger than the brands that they can put on their platform.
Rym: And it's hard, because it's not like the old days where cons had content that literally did not exist anywhere else.
Rym: Like, anime cons in the early days were, "Yo, kid, you wanna see some anime?
Rym: This is the only goddamn place you can see it at
Rym: all.".
Scott: Also, for most cons, even the biggest cons, right?
Scott: San Diego Comic Con, the biggest con, right?
Scott: The online platform of San Diego Comic Con is weaker than the online platform of a single artist alley person.
Rym: Yup, they're like a glass cannon whose sole purpose is to make people be able to buy badges, see the schedule, show up.
Scott: Right, so you just pick a random weave in the anime artist alley table selling, I don't know, crocheted cutie stuff, right?
Scott: A typical artist alley table you would see, you go find them at San Diego Comic Con.
Scott: They probably don't have as many Twitter followers as San Diego Comic Con does, but I guarantee you, their online community engagement that they have with their customers is probably better than how people have with San Diego Comic Con itself.
Scott: People aren't looking at Comic Con Twitter for stuff, right?
Scott: So there's not that much that Comic Con can even offer them other than that's not the actual con.
Rym: And most of what I've enjoyed from online cons have just been panels, and that's what we do at online cons, but we could just do those on our own, like we don't actually even need an excuse.
Scott: Most YouTube channels with Pete that have a talking head style are just someone doing panels on their own constantly.
Scott: That's all they are.
Scott: We just do a lot less panels if we only do them live.
Rym: Yeah, because it's more fun to do them live, and I think we said this before, you know why we haven't made a whole bunch of videos during COVID?
Rym: Because it's not fun to make videos when Scott's in Astoria and I'm in LIC.
Rym: It's way more fun when we do them together in front of one camera.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So let's just get right into it.
Rym: Lupin III.
Rym: I is not only the latest iteration of Lupin movies, and I'm saying quotes because if you look at the history of Lupin, you've basically got the manga, you've got the TV serieses, and then you've got the specials, some of which were theatrical movies and some of which were basically OAVs.
Scott: Some of which were OAVs.
Scott: I think there were some TV, direct-to-TV movies possibly.
Scott: Basically, any format of video that exists, any distribution mechanism for video, Lupin has been there.
Scott: They just keep making more Lupin stuff at a steady stream for as long as Lupin has existed.
Scott: Make a little short series here, make a movie there.
Scott: It just keeps coming and coming and coming.
Scott: It doesn't stop.
Scott: It'll keep going forever.
Rym: Well, say that there's a median Lupin, and these specials, let's not talk about the TV series, just these specials, these movie-like things, these one-offs, they vary to a surprising degree, both in tone and quality, because much like James Bond, it's like a different director.
Rym: Takes like, "I'm gonna do a Lupin," and they'll take this palette of characters and this palette of tropes, and they'll construct their own Lupin.
Rym: So, in the same universe that has Lupin, the Castle of Cagliostro, you've got Legend of Babylon Gold.
Scott: Yeah, and what was the one?
Scott: that was mostly about Zenigata and he was all sad?
Rym: Oh, the Fuma Conspiracy.
Rym: No, no, no, no.
Rym: That's the one about Goemon.
Scott: Fuma Conspiracy's just the normal, really good one.
Scott: What's the one where Zenigata's fired and he's sad in Japan?
Scott: I want to watch that one again.
Scott: I just forget which one it was.
Rym: The thing is, I like them all, even the stupid ones.
Scott: I just like Lupin.
Rym: Babylon Gold we make fun of because it's got a lot of flaws, but I would watch it again.
Scott: There's worse things to watch.
Rym: The one with Hera Maphrodite is probably the worst one.
Scott: That's a real bad one.
Scott: Isn't that like Desert something?
Rym: Yeah, I think we even showed it in the anime club.
Scott: For me, the median Lupin is the Assassin Island one.
Scott: That is the default.
Scott: It's good.
Scott: It's not amazing.
Scott: It's not bad.
Scott: It's just like, this is Lupin.
Scott: He has to go to this island of assassins and deal with them and such and such.
Rym: And this is what I want to get into before we do this review.
Rym: It's a two-dimensional chart because there's median Lupin in terms of quality, and there's median Lupin in terms of how close to the standard tropes is it.
Scott: I think the thing is, a lot of Lupin fans always talk about the jacket color, which isn't always a complete perfect guide.
Rym: This is closer to a green jacket Lupin, even though he's wearing red.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: You can't fully rely on the jacket color, but there is, up to a certain point, a correlation between Lupin's jacket color, whether it's green or red.
Rym: Green Lupin, regardless of what he's actually wearing, is like the Cagliostro good guy at heart, always does the right thing, mischievous but not outright evil.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you watch Lupin TV series, like the one we watched most of, He murders so many people in the first fucking episode.
Scott: Or if you read the Lupin manga, the old actual monkey punch one, it's like he is lewd, crude, murderous, actually stealing things, actually a criminal, actually a bad kind of person.
Rym: Like Green Jacket Lupin will knock someone out and get away.
Rym: That manga Lupin will machine gun down an entire room of unrelated and innocent dinner party guests.
Scott: Yup, to steal stuff, right?
Scott: He's actually a thief, right?
Scott: But the movies, especially the theatrical ones, they tend to really tone it down and make Lupin more of a sympathetic character.
Scott: Like yes, he's a thief, but this time he's stealing things, he's using his thief-like skills, but he cares about people.
Scott: so he's not going to compromise.
Scott: goodness to do thieving.
Scott: And allow the greed to overcome his other desires.
Rym: But there's also this, I don't want to say high concept, low concept, but some of these Lupins are just a by-the-book, here is every Lupin trope, in the correct order, beginning to end.
Rym: Like, go him on and Jigen will show up at this point.
Rym: Fujiko Mine will show up at the first part, fuck Lupin over, get away, reappear later to help him, but then fuck him over again.
Scott: Zenigata will appear and chase Lupin and not catch him, and then maybe catch him, but then he gets away.
Scott: He'll use his disguise trick.
Rym: But then you break away from those tropes and you get the ones where Lupin and Zenigata openly team up for real, or the ones where Zenigata tries to kill Lupin.
Scott: Some of them go into more supernatural territories, like the Mama one.
Scott: They get into real weird stuff, like what the heck is going on here?
Rym: Legend of Babylon gold, spoilers, aliens are coming back for their fucking gold.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: Some of them go into the supernatural territory, and some of them stick to this more realistic territory.
Rym: Realistic in that Tagliostro is very realistic, except for the acrobatics of Lupin and that car chase.
Scott: Right, but there isn't actual magic, or actual wizards, or any supernatural ghosts, right?
Scott: They'll either be a hint of them, but then a Scooby-Doo revealed that they were actually some science or mechanism, or they won't be there at all.
Rym: So the last context, before we dive straight into this movie, is that there was a long period of time where the Lupin specials and shows and everything were just kind of super bad to the point that a lot of them weren't worth watching.
Rym: And then starting around the time of the Fujiko Mine anime TV series, the quality suddenly returned.
Scott: What was that?
Scott: It was a Jigen's grave?
Scott: What was that like?
Rym: So Fujiko Mine was the one that really did something interesting and different.
Rym: I think we reviewed it a while ago.
Rym: That show was amazing.
Rym: Then after that, in a similar style, is the grave of Jigen Daisuke.
Scott: Oh, that came after that?
Scott: Okay, I can't remember what the order was.
Scott: I'll trust you.
Rym: I would say that that cluster of Lupin set off a Lupin renaissance, and Lupin III.
Rym: I is a top-tier Lupin.
Scott: It's pretty up there.
Rym: It's down to number one, but it's like top five, top ten at worst.
Scott: This is what they've done.
Scott: It's the first 3D CG Lupin.
Scott: Every Lupin before now may have used computers to help animate, obviously, but they were all 2D.
Scott: There may be 3D behind the scenes, but they didn't look 3D.
Scott: This is like Toy Story 3D.
Scott: Obviously looking much better than the original Toy Story because it's 2021.
Rym: Yeah, we'll get into that, but it looks great.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like you might get hesitant whenever anything makes a switch to 3D like that, but this is definitely a Mario 64 situation where it works out.
Scott: They somehow managed, even in 3D, to maintain all of the characteristics of the character's signature movements, and looks, and facial expressions, and everything somehow has completely made the transition.
Scott: Jigen's face is a little weird, I think.
Rym: I like it, though, because it made him extra hot.
Rym: It's not bad, but I do think Lupin's face is-- It made him more human and hotter.
Scott: But Lupin's face is just Lupin's face.
Scott: There is no--.
Rym: The thing that stands out the most about the character designs in the transition to 3D that no still image is going to catch for you, they are emotive to a surprising degree, to the point that I think this was the most acting a Lupin character has ever done on the screen.
Scott: Yeah, that could be.
Scott: But yeah, they basically-- I don't really see a downside to the switch to the CG thing at all, really, for this movie.
Rym: I mean, it's not like, as you might see, the Ghibli 3D airwig does not look great in comparison.
Scott: The only real disappointment is just that, hey, I'm a fan of 2D animation, I'd like to see it carry on and not fade away.
Scott: But in this particular instance, I don't think any harm was done, other than the general harm to, "Oh no, there's less 2D animation in the world,".
Scott: but this isn't a bad 3D animation.
Rym: But no matter how hesitant someone is, are there complicated feelings about 3D?
Rym: Thirty seconds into this, you don't even remember that it's 3D, you're just gay being in the spectacle.
Scott: It did not remember.
Rym: The movie is great and just dives right in.
Scott: There are none of those weird moments where the CG is awkward or breaks your fourth wall into remembering, and there's none of those uncanny valley moments where it's too real.
Scott: It's still cartoony, but still, right?
Scott: It's great.
Rym: In terms of-- The voice acting is top notch.
Rym: I only watch the sub, I can't speak to the sub.
Scott: I know, sadly, that some--for the longest time, Lupin, all the characters had the same voice actors, and it was only relatively recently, like within the past some number of years, that some of those original voice actors sadly passed away.
Scott: Whoever they got, it sounds like Lupin, it sounds like everybody, right?
Scott: There was no problem, basically.
Scott: Whoever they got the new voice actors are sound like the old voice actors.
Scott: Sort of like how when there's Muppets, right?
Scott: It's like, yeah, Jim Henson doesn't do Kermit anymore, but if you watch a new Muppet thing, it sounds like Kermit the Frog, right?
Scott: It's like whoever they got doing it is doing it fine.
Scott: It's the same situation here.
Scott: Clearly there are voice actors who can do the voices of these characters just fine.
Scott: They're just perfect.
Rym: If you did a blind test and played them talking from this and them talking from older Lupins, I would really struggle to tell the difference.
Scott: It's possible that even, you know, it is 2021, I don't know that they did this, I have no evidence-- I don't think they did this.
Scott: It's possible that they used computers to help out, or to make it sound even more like the original, but whether they did or didn't, you can't tell, so what does it matter?
Scott: So, along
Rym: those lines, the music, 'cause this is set in like the mid to late '60s, like specifically, like it's a Showa era, like the movie is set in that time setting, and the music is the Lupin music from all out of the old Lupins, and it, they got to Yuji Ono, the soundtrack has like, the score has 61 songs in it, and a bunch of the compositions are like that Showa post-war jazz stuff from old Lupins, to the point that they even evoke the themes, like from the songs in Cagliostro specifically, to make sure it feels like a Lupin movie.
Rym: Right to the point at the very end, you know that song that creeps in when the movie's starting to end, before the scene that ends every Lupin movie begins, where everyone's escaping?
Rym: For a second, I thought it was actually the song from one of those other Lupins.
Rym: I had to go check.
Scott: Yeah, they did the same thing that every good soundtrack does, when it's a soundtrack for like something that's a series, right?
Scott: Star Wars, Indiana Jones, James Bond, right?
Scott: Is they, they have those core musical motifs, right?
Scott: You know, and then they just remix and rearrange into something new, and you could do a bad job of it, but you can also do a great job of it, and I don't think even bad Lupin movies don't really mess up those, you know, musical motifs ever.
Scott: It's not like you're gonna take the soundtrack and just play it for fun.
Rym: Yeah, but like play the ending theme to any Lupin that's ever been made, except the really bad ones that fucked this up, and anyone who's watched a bunch of Lupin just be like, "That's the end to a
Rym: Lupin!".
Rym: They're all running away now, and Zenigata is trying to chase them, and the credits are about to roll.
Scott: It's new, good music, but if you are a Lupin person, you identify it immediately as Lupin music.
Scott: There is no question.
Rym: So in terms of the movie plot itself, like it's a by-the-book Lupin, except for a couple of minor pieces.
Rym: Piece number one, this isn't a break from the trope, because Lupin's enemies being Nazis is not uncommon, but in this case, it is like, "Nope, Lupin versus the
Rym: Nazis.".
Scott: Yes, it's so Indiana Jones, right?
Scott: It's like there are a lot of the Lupin movies where he's not outright evil, end up being very Indiana Jonesy or more national treasure-y kind of thing, where it's almost that sort of archaeological historical conspiracy mystery.
Rym: This one is like a full-on Raiders of the Lost Ark.
Scott: The only difference between this and Indiana Jones is that Indiana Jones just sort of goes somewhere and doesn't really do anything.
Scott: He's just sort of there getting beat up until the bad guys lose.
Rym: Like, who beat the Nazis in Raiders of the Lost Ark?
Rym: It wasn't Indiana Jones.
Scott: It was the Nazis.
Scott: God.
Scott: Lupin actually uses him and his allies, use their skills and abilities and such to directly conquer and overcome many conflicts and challenges.
Rym: So the only break from the tropes of Lupin, because this movie is literally like, Fujiko shows up.
Rym: at the moment you're thinking, "I bet Fujiko's about to show up to do her
Rym: thing.".
Rym: It's just by the book, except it brings the lore of Lupin himself, like Lupin III, the ancestor of Arsne Lupin.
Scott: Lupin I is the ancestor of Lupin III.
Scott: This is Grandpa, I guess, right?
Rym: So it brings that in directly in a way that I have never really seen in a Lupin before.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In every other Lupin thing I've ever seen, they basically make no mention of Lupin II or Lupin I or Lupin's mom or anything, right?
Scott: It's like, here's Lupin III, yeah, you know he's the grandson of Arsne Lupin because that's where his name comes from.
Scott: But we're not going to mention that at all.
Scott: We got nothing to do with it.
Scott: Nothing.
Rym: This one is like you get this flashback to a bunch of Nazi shit and like families and people separated and like a treasure that Arsne never got and how Lupin like was almost destined to meet the person he meets and do the thing in this movie.
Rym: That's a trope or a beat, not a trope, it's a beat that I don't think we've ever seen in a Lupin work.
Scott: Yeah, a Lupin movie has never been, that I know of, has never been about Lupin's history in any way, shape or form.
Scott: And not to spoil anything, but the moment where you see- It's not spoiler, it's in the title, the title of the movie is Lupin III I.
Rym: The moment when you see that hat sitting at the end of that tunnel.
Scott: That was a plus moment right there.
Rym: Well, the two's the first when they come into that whole area and the Nazi guy walks forward.
Rym: All I could think was about a pious man kneeling down.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: It's very, very in and of jones.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: It's like, you know, anyway.
Scott: So the only downside I can see, right, plot wise, was that while all the characters were on point, right, I think that the three typical allies, right, I think Zenigata got the right amount of screen time that Zenigata usually gets.
Rym: Yup, because he got the extra beat of, all right, there's like- Because he was there in the beginning scenes too, to add to.
Scott: But Jigen, Goemon, and Fujiko.
Scott: Fujiko could have had maybe like one or two more things going on.
Scott: But Jigen and Goemon especially, I think, barely appear in this movie.
Rym: But that's kind of by the book, a lot of the Lupins.
Scott: They do, it's true.
Rym: Those two show up in that fucking car and like save Lupin once or twice and otherwise don't matter.
Scott: It's true that they don't appear much, but I think they're appearing in this.
Scott: I don't know, I have to time it to figure out exactly, but it feels like they even have less than the usual amount of screen time.
Scott: I think you're right, but I think that's partly because- I think you need to give them like one or two more scenes to bring them up to their average level.
Rym: I would say that the movie backed off on them a little bit, because it actually took Lupin and the new character.
Rym: There's always the new character in a Lupin.
Scott: There's always the new plot character who's in this movie only, and you never hear from them again every single time.
Rym: It gives both of them more development than they would either get in any other Lupin.
Rym: Like that's the trade-off.
Scott: Yep, I think that is true.
Rym: I did particularly enjoy the villains, because there's two villains, like even on the movie poster.
Rym: you can look at it and be like, "Okay, those are the two
Rym: villains.".
Scott: The one villain was more of like just a Nazi, but the other one, the more main villain that gets more focused, is actually somewhat interesting and complicated even though he's-
Rym: Also a Nazi, but like one's the Nazi fanatic, like Hitler's still alive in Brazil type of Nazi, and the second one is like complicated relationship with granddaughter and the world.
Scott: Right, he actually cares about a person.
Rym: Yeah, and as a villain duo, they work better than the villains tend to in a lot of Lupin's.
Scott: Yeah, especially since it's not always clear, in a lot of Lupin's it's clear that there's a boss and there's a square boss.
Scott: That's the real boss.
Rym: Oh my god, the one where the boss keeps murdering with the flyswatter, with the poison one by one like that.
Scott: Right, but in this Lupin it's not always clear which of them is like the bigger boss.
Scott: There's almost like this sort of up and down between them.
Rym: There's a power struggle between the two of them that was never resolved until the end of the movie.
Scott: Yes, in some points in the movie like one of them is like sort of like threatening the other, like, "Oh, I'm in charge
Scott: here.".
Scott: And then at other points it's like, "No, I'm in charge
Scott: And it's not the usual Megatron/Starscream thing where like one of them is just a jerk, and Megatron is actually in charge.
Scott: It's more of a, you know, I guess I can't use Transformers again, it doesn't really fit.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's like, yeah, it'd be like if there were two Megatrons and they were there at the same time.
Rym: There's an active power struggle between two people who are equally powerful and equally weak, just in different ways.
Scott: And it's kind of interesting.
Rym: Like that's more nuanced than I think any Lupin villain has ever been.
Rym: Ever.
Scott: That's true, that's true I think.
Scott: And considering that the rest of the plot of the movie is so, I guess, cookie cutter, you sort of need that to like spice things up and keep some interest.
Rym: Now I will say, I'm good with how cookie cutter the rest of it was, mostly because it was such- It was an excellent cookie.
Rym: It was a visual treat, like the acting was perfect, everything was so good, that it was like the best possible completely plain sugar cookie.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, hey, let's make a chocolate chip cookie.
Scott: It's just a chocolate chip cookie.
Scott: We didn't spice it up with like, you know, some Sriracha chocolate chip cookie, or peanut butter chocolate chip cookie, or fancy expensive chocolate, right?
Scott: It's just a fucking damn good chocolate chip cookie.
Scott: Look at that, it's a perfect circle, exactly the right consistency and texture, perfectly baked.
Scott: It's like, dang, don't come here expecting, you know, your Sriracha peanut butter cookie, right?
Scott: But guess what, the absolute perfect chocolate chip cookie, you would tell me you wouldn't eat that?
Scott: You'd be like, no, I'm not going to eat that.
Rym: But along those lines, the other thing I would say is, I would add this to my list of, if someone had never seen or heard of Lupin at all, this would not be a bad one for them to see first.
Scott: If they, yeah, I mean, you might see this first, I think it would be great.
Scott: Yeah, seeing this first is perfect.
Scott: Because every Lupin, whenever anyone sees Lupin first.
Scott: If they become such a big Lupin fan that they're going deep and watching the ones with Lupin is evil, this starting one might cause a surprise later.
Rym: I don't think that's a problem, because most people get started on Cagliostro.
Scott: If you're going that deep, you know, yeah.
Rym: People already start on Cagliostro, and then they watch like, I don't know, Mama, and they're like, what the fuck is wrong with Lupin?
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Yeah, this is a perfectly fine first Lupin movie.
Rym: Yeah, you know, partly just because every Lupin movie, anyone, the first Lupin movie you see, you got, like, you're going to learn the deal with these characters just by jumping right in.
Rym: Like, there's no, like, the origin story movie to watch.
Rym: Even the first cartoon, the first episode of the first show just assumes you know who the fuck these people are and dives right in, because it kind of doesn't matter.
Rym: You'll figure it out along the way.
Scott: And also, maybe, you know, the fact that some of the side characters barely appear might intrigue someone who maybe, you know, thinks, you know, if you think Goemon is cool or something, or you think Jigen is cool, and you're like, oh, I want to see more Jigen, well, guess what?
Scott: There's a whole, there's plenty of other things you can watch that have a lot more Jigen action in them.
Rym: Well, like, case in point, the show, the Fujikomiine anime series, that one almost does, like, an origin story of all the characters, but, like, a twisted one.
Scott: But that one is the one I would not show to someone first, because-- Oh, no, no, if you don't know anything about Lupin, that's no good for you.
Rym: That nonsense is completely uninteresting to you, unless you already care about and are interested in these characters, and then you see, like, those versions of those characters and that evolution of, like, the characters together, and you're intrigued by it, and, like, you want to go deep.
Rym: Someone could watch this, and, like, oh, I wonder what the deal is with Jigen, and then watch Fujikomiine and Grave of Jigen Daisuke and be like, ooh.
Scott: Yep, so try to think of anything negative to say, because it wasn't, like, a perfect movie in all ways, right?
Rym: I kind of would have liked it to be a little longer and have, like, one more-- You said longer.
Scott: I was going to say shorter.
Rym: I think they already cut a lot out.
Rym: I think the movie was actually edited pretty much perfectly, because, much like Indiana Jones and the arc of the covenant, like, that whole story, it skips over a bunch of stuff, like, when he just rides the submarine to the destination.
Rym: This movie, like, Lupin and the girl are about to go break into a thing.
Rym: It just cuts to them having already broken into the thing.
Rym: It cuts to the good part.
Scott: It does do that, but at the same time, when it starts getting towards the end, and you think, like, ah, this is the climactic thing, it felt like I was starting to feel a little bit like, ah, this is the final eh, and it's like, that wasn't the final eh?
Scott: There's another eh?
Scott: And then another eh?
Scott: And then it was over.
Rym: I don't know, the Hitler no Fukkatsu eh was a beat that I both didn't expect and appreciated greatly.
Scott: I mean, it wasn't bad, but it felt like, you know, I looked at my watch at least one time, right?
Scott: Not ten times, but, like, one time.
Rym: I think part of the reason I didn't was that if I had to describe the animation, like, the end result of watching everything, like, kind of like we talked about in the very beginning about the animation style, it's so rich and, like, thick and detailed and textured and stylized, like, all the little details on the screen were just such a pleasure to the eye that I kind of just wanted to keep seeing more of it longer.
Rym: But, to your point, the movie was edited well enough to, like, not make it drag on, and if they added more scenes, I might have started to feel that drag.
Scott: The other thing is that some of the action scenes, right, were excellent, especially, like, the laser, you know, a typical laser tunnel, right?
Rym: Oh, the laser tunnel was so good.
Scott: Laser tunnel, laser tunnel's such a clich, right?
Scott: It's like, oh, you gotta, even a coupon is a clich.
Rym: But the twist with the cane and the hat?
Scott: Right, but not just the cane and the hat, but, like, the way it was animated and, right?
Rym: When it slows down for the one moment.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: It's like, that may be the best laser tunnel I ever seen.
Scott: Fuck you, Mission Impossible laser tunnel, right?
Scott: It's like, you suck compared to this one.
Scott: But on other parts, right, the action scenes were kind of, okay, good, you know, nothing to write home about, right?
Scott: But if you think of, like, other coupons, like Castle of Cagliostro, you've got, like, the iconic clock scene, right?
Rym: Or the swimming through the canal scene.
Scott: Right, it's like, this didn't have, maybe laser tunnel scene is the one, but other than that, it didn't really have the X scene, right?
Scott: Or more than one of them, at least.
Rym: Like, the two action scenes, well, the three action scenes that actually stood out the most, that were just, actually, no, none of them were iconic, but they were all, like, above average, because I was trying to list them.
Rym: Like, there's the fist fight he has, which was just, like, cowboy bebop levels.
Rym: There was the plane fight.
Rym: when Fujiko comes in.
Rym: Like, that was actually really fun.
Rym: The bit where he grabs onto the front of the wing, and then the girl grabs on, and kind of knocks him off, and they, like, go back and forth a little bit.
Scott: Well, that started with the scene where they're falling out of the sky.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: But then you've got the car chase in the very beginning, which was-- You've got to have a car chase at the start of a Lupin movie, otherwise it's a Lupin movie.
Scott: Come on.
Rym: But yeah, you're right.
Rym: There were many great action scenes, but there was no, like, THE action scene.
Scott: Yeah, there's nothing, like, you know, some iconic thing to--.
Rym: Well, like, Babylon Gold.
Rym: All right, they're on motorcycles on that clown face.
Scott: Motorcycle on the clown face.
Scott: That's iconic.
Scott: It's a very memorable scene.
Rym: But yeah, I would, like, without reservation recommend watching this movie to anyone who would listen to GeekNights.
Scott: If you're an anime person, if you like animation, do you like animated movies at all?
Scott: At all.
Scott: If you like Indiana Jones, if you like a Lupin, if you, you know, any-- Most people would be well-served watching this movie, I'd say.
Rym: Like, I would recommend this to, like, my dad, or my mom.
Scott: How long is it?
Scott: Two hours?
Rym: Not even.
Rym: It's, uh, 93 minutes.
Scott: All right, you want 93 minutes of fun, that's got a better.
Scott: 93 minutes of fun?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Want to watch a movie?
Scott: Just pick this one.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon Patrons for this episode of GeekNights!
Rym: Ahh!
Rym: Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, E.G, Graham Finch, you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: Now go through the last year or so of podcasts.
Rym: Ed Makram, St.
Rym: Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin.
Rym: Review Mad Bull, 34 Cowards, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, Just Like a Dude Guy, Chris Reimer, Finn, Shervin Von Horl, and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: Yeah, this Lupin was real good.
Rym: And we still, I haven't actually seen The Grave of Jigen Daisuke yet, and I think we're gonna, Emily and I are gonna watch that soon because I'm feeling Lupin pretty big right now after that movie.
Rym: So stay safe out there, and for now, I leave you with... Does your father know you're doing this?
Scott: My dad's dead.
Rym: Oh, I'm sorry, I didn't know my condolences.
Rym: Does your mother know you're doing this?
Scott: My mom's in prison for killing my dad.
Rym: Okay, I get it.
Rym: You're joking.
Scott: Well, I've got a sense of humor.
Rym: I laugh at Tony Danza.
Rym: Of course, if you aren't joking, I feel bad and I apologize.
Rym: All right, that's it.
Scott: I'm gonna count to three.
Scott: One, two, three!
Rym: I'm not horsing around here.
Rym: Lucky for you, I don't have time for this right now.
Rym: Come on, Bobby, let's go to the Fun Center!
Rym: Fun Center!