Rym: It's Monday, March 1st, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are talking about cryptocurrencies and why they are terrible.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So you might recall on a previous GeekNights at some point.
Rym: Time just doesn't exist anymore for me But I talked about how I had to replace the fans in my computer because the computers like yeah from 2016 And a new fans.
Scott: new fans came in the mail.
Scott: the new fans came and you put him in and they're great.
Rym: I put him in and they're great.
Rym: God damn it.
Rym: That's the whole opening bit.
Rym: But what I can say is that one of the fans Was smaller than the fan that could have gone there.
Rym: They came.
Rym: actually Kate case actually came with 120 millimeter fan in the by 120.
Rym: No, so the fact the case can fit a 140 back there But the case stop the one that came.
Rym: stock in this NZXT case was a 120 but the stock intake either.
Rym: so I put 140s everywhere because why not?
Rym: and The fact that the top fan had not been pulling its fair share of air previously was significantly impacting the performance of the GPU.
Scott: Why did they not?
Scott: You know if NZXT knows this why didn't they?
Rym: well This is a case from 2016.
Rym: They don't even make this case anymore.
Rym: Their cases are way better now in terms of air flow.
Rym: Well, except for that one Recall the one that's a literal danger to your house the one that I was thinking about buying from a HD PC.
Scott: Well, not anymore.
Scott: But you could buy the recouped.
Scott: you buy the recalled one, it'll be just fine.
Rym: Yeah, but basically yeah.
Scott: So I get if people don't know NZXT who is a great maker of computer cases.
Scott: They're really.
Scott: they're really pretty good.
Scott: I would buy them if I was gonna but even despite the recall, I would still buy one.
Scott: Yeah That's the recall only affected.
Rym: I guess we could have done this as news, but we didn't.
Rym: the recall only affected.
Rym: If you want one of those stupid risers to mount your video card vertically into the side Which I don't.
Scott: I do that in my.
Scott: I do that in my HD PC.
Scott: that lies flat, but otherwise Yeah, don't do that.
Rym: You know, like if you're doing a mid tower, that's pretty much just gonna be a worse cooling solution for you.
Rym: It also introduces Risk of problems independent of start a fire.
Scott: Yeah, only one NZXT case has a fire hazard and got a recall but everything else is fine.
Rym: Yep But it was interesting that you know the K the faith the can at the fake case fan in the back had been busted for some time like once.
Rym: once I realized it wasn't really spending much and What was happening is when I played games?
Rym: The inside of the case would get hotter and hotter because the airflow wasn't great.
Rym: the puller fans on the front were effectively also Pushing out that hole in the top.
Rym: I only had one puller fan.
Rym: We're up equalizing now that everything's fully equalized with all these fans and everything like reconfigured The inside of the case stays pretty cool.
Rym: The GPU stays around 50 when I'm playing overwatch and max settings.
Rym: before when with the old fan it was held to hover it around 56 hmm Whatever.
Scott: That's that.
Rym: Yeah the most I could milk out of that.
Scott: The only thing I can say is that we did an episode on computer maintenance way back.
Scott: Yeah, at least a while at least a while back and I've been doing more Using my Google tasks.
Scott: I guess you whatever task managing thing you might to-do list kind of thing you use in your life.
Scott: I use Google keep sure As you Google tasks, and I've been putting more recurring tasks And one of the ones that I have is clean out filters on CPU fans to remove all the dust.
Scott: So I've been doing that like every few months and you know a month or two and that's good I guess.
Scott: Yeah, all my fans are working cuz I don't hear any noises down there.
Rym: So yep fans have gotten better too because the old fans I had plugged into the 3-pin like they were standard.
Rym: the new fans I got are all 4-pin.
Rym: So my software can control them better.
Scott: I Mean, yeah, I don't think all mine are that way.
Rym: Yeah, but that's just this computer that feels like it's brand new.
Rym: I built it in like 2016 and that was a long time ago.
Scott: It's not that long.
Rym: All right Yeah, so in the news, there's ton of tech news, but it's not quite time for the tech news.
Scott: It's almost time.
Scott: Rym's getting excited.
Rym: I'm getting excited.
Rym: It's my favorite.
Scott: You don't want to use all your news.
Scott: You won't have any.
Scott: when your time comes.
Scott: you'll blow for a whole year, right?
Scott: You'll do like.
Scott: you'll have just a really crappy news for a tech news roundup.
Scott: It'll be a shitty one and then you won't be able to do another one for a whole year.
Rym: Maybe Some days you should lay it the future of GeekNights.
Rym: The Monday show is gonna turn into just tech news roundup.
Scott: That's that's all you want it to be.
Scott: But I think you should just hold off on this tech news roundup for 2021 until you build up enough good news But it's always there.
Rym: I got so much tech news.
Rym: every time we do a tech show that I'm like holding back.
Rym: always Make sure you're just saying round up like Christmas for me.
Scott: Don't don't waste one.
Rym: Well, especially because usually traditionally the tech news roundup happens just as convention season is ending and We're going into our like lull before convention season starts up again.
Rym: Of course that didn't happen this year.
Rym: So in the news, if you're not familiar, there are many social media platforms out there and one of them Quite literally the worst of them is called close to the worst of them I mean if there's meant there are several is still the parlor one, right?
Rym: Parlor is not as bad as gab sadly really Like.
Rym: They're all bad.
Rym: But the Nazi I didn't.
Scott: I wouldn't.
Scott: I didn't think that either.
Scott: any of them were better than any of the others.
Scott: They thought they were just all equally Nazi.
Rym: so if I had to describe the differences parler is people who got kicked off Twitter and Gab is people who are openly pedophiles and open like like right parlor, isn't that?
Rym: Like if Hitler were still alive his account would be on gab because even parlor would have kicked him off.
Rym: You sure really grab is so much worse than parlor.
Rym: You have no idea?
Scott: Yeah, I haven't looked.
Scott: I haven't looked at either one.
Rym: So I'm trusting the reporting of people who follow like fascist groups.
Scott: Yeah, all I know is that the name that those are the names of fascist social websites I'll make.
Scott: gab is reddit style and parlor is Twitter style.
Scott: That's all I know.
Scott: I don't know anything else.
Rym: the thing that far-right extremist social networks have in common Is that they rarely?
Rym: Have good IT or technology.
Rym: because most people who are good enough at technology to do a platform like that Right aren't actually fascists.
Rym: They might work for a company that does things that enable the sort of neoliberal dystopian hellscape that we live in But they're not like down with the Reich.
Scott: So those those places even you know, even if someone had no morals and high skills of IT Those places that are on the far right don't have a lot of money.
Rym: That is also true.
Scott: You're gonna.
Scott: if you have no morals, you're just a mercenary or in capitalist society You're gonna work for the goog right this the Facebook's or whatever.
Scott: You're not gonna work for the gabs.
Rym: They can't pay you Yep, so gab Parlor, I think I hacked a while ago.
Rym: gab like just recently got mega hacked and it appears That someone downloaded their entire database every post every private message Completely in the clear ready for anyone to read.
Rym: they got for all their groups.
Rym: They got raw unencrypted passwords.
Rym: They got the hash passwords for the actual accounts themselves.
Rym: The only thing we don't know there is Rumblings that those hash passwords don't even appear to be salted, but no one's sure.
Rym: yet Like I'm still waiting for confirmation.
Scott: hit him with the rainbow table.
Scott: See what comes out exactly Our rainbow tables.
Rym: So yeah, if you are a piece of shit and you have an account on gab Everyone can read every awful thing you posted pretty sure is mostly child porn and planning the riot and the attack on the Capitol.
Scott: Okay, now this child porn hugging.
Scott: the FBI hasn't done anything about that.
Scott: They loved going after child porn.
Rym: I imagine they will be doing something about this leak.
Rym: Okay, I think a lot of people are in a lot of trouble around child porn because of this.
Scott: good.
Rym: Yeah, I mean no good person has an account on gab this whoever did this hack which apparently was done via a Hold on.
Scott: Hold on.
Scott: Hold on the person who committed this hack.
Scott: It doesn't hear him had to make a gab account in order to figure stuff out.
Rym: So yes, someone may have a research gab account.
Rym: if you have an earnest gab account, you're definitely a bad person.
Rym: that's a good clarification, but the vulnerability that was used by the person who hacked it who is known as Jax Perot and my little anonymous revival project got all the data via a Simplistic SQL injection attack.
Scott: that makes sense.
Scott: But if you database dump, you're probably gonna get it via injection.
Rym: Yep, and shitty social networks like this tend to have just one giant database that runs everything.
Scott: I mean, yeah, you're not that big.
Scott: You need to have some you know, like multi-stage multi-region kind of partition database setup, you know.
Rym: So keep the hacktivism up like go after these right-wing platforms because they are usually really soft targets.
Rym: Oh, yeah in some other news Fries which I'll be I've never been to a fries never seen.
Scott: if I may I. if I've been to one I don't remember it but I assume that they're just the same thing as a Best Buy or what a circus city used to be Or pretty much like I.
Rym: I'll be honest I never understood it front people being obsessed with fries Really reeked of people just like caring a lot about their local non Wegmans grocery store Right.
Scott: It's like there are certain stores that really are you know us in the same category as other stores But do something special and different to like level them up, right?
Scott: So for example, you have furniture store, but then IKEA is like it's got something going on That's significantly different.
Scott: right.
Scott: where you have that You know, it's the layout of the place and the way you shop there and the thing at the end, right?
Scott: And then you got your supermarkets, but then you got your Wegmans.
Scott: Wegmans is still just a supermarket.
Scott: It's just so big and has so much good stuff, right?
Scott: You know, but then you got your TJ which is also different.
Scott: It's smaller, but they've got special stuff.
Scott: It's all a stuff right.
Scott: and then you get your Stu Leonard's which is in that IKEA zone of like.
Scott: is this even a Park right?
Scott: What the hell is this?
Scott: There's an actual cow here.
Scott: Where did this milk come from?
Rym: You're you've talked for as long as you knew shit like I'll Stu Leonard's not the Stu Leonard's.
Scott: then we finally went I was like all right, this place is Weirder than I expected like it's something It's only people who live in the Northeast US could possibly know about Stu Leonard's and let me tell you it's really something good.
Scott: But yeah, I never.
Scott: I never.
Scott: if I'd have been to Fry's it's only been once I don't remember it But I I have.
Scott: I can't imagine you can do something with that sort of store to really make it that special Wegmans or IKEA level different experience than what you get out of a Best Buy.
Scott: So I never believed anyone who was like so high on fries.
Scott: They remind me of the people who are really high on What are those burgers from out west?
Rym: Oh in and out or yeah?
Scott: It's like I can't imagine.
Scott: in and out is like significant actually any big freaking deal compared to like crappy old five guys.
Scott: It's like, you know, what could possibly be special about that?
Rym: So it was telling that when this hat when this news broke my first thought was fries was still in business.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't think.
Rym: I basically thought that every store except Best Buy had gone down And I'm still kind of amazed that Best Buy still exists, but I think I can come up with some reasons Why I think they exist because they're the last one.
Rym: coupled with they have an online presence.
Rym: That's pretty good.
Rym: Like they just sell stuff online.
Scott: the same way to get that.
Scott: GameStop is the last one.
Scott: I have the last one though GameStop is dying still.
Scott: but but Best Buy also, I think a lot of their stuff Comes from the things that they sell that you can't just buy online.
Scott: and also They some they get stuff right?
Scott: Yeah supply runs out at other places.
Rym: I guess electronics are such an interesting like they're.
Rym: they're not completely unique But they're in a unique class of digital good or not digital goods goods Non-digital goods physical meatspace goods that people need to buy because most people will only ever buy televisions or maybe whole computers.
Rym: and There's a very relatively small subset of the population who buys components of computers or more advanced electronics.
Rym: Mmm, I guess I'll leave appliances out.
Rym: That's a whole different thing.
Rym: Like that's my cells.
Scott: Yeah, where would you buy appliances if not Best Buy?
Rym: I mean, I would just buy appliances online and have them drop-shift me too.
Scott: But I think I don't think people.
Scott: I think while I think well overall our society has gotten used to buying things online I still don't I'm not sure I don't have you know But my gut tells me that like only people like us are gonna buy a TV or a washing machine online.
Scott: I think a lot of people TV is increasingly online would guess that a lot of people would not do that.
Scott: They would want to go to a Best Buy to buy your TV or your washing machine.
Rym: I think there's data that TVs at least are going the other route.
Rym: but appliances might be like cars.
Rym: I remember those old studies I wonder if this is still true showing that most people when they want to buy a car They basically buy whatever the dealerships kind of push on them.
Rym: They never go out shopping for a specific car like people.
Rym: there's a whole weird ecosystem around that.
Rym: But anyway, we thought with computer components in particular We're in this interesting space right now in that like I won't buy computer parts from Amazon because I've gotten too many counterfeits and scams Like in the last several years.
Scott: I have but that was years ago and the scam rate has gone way up since then.
Scott: Yeah, and I would be I would buy some from there but only After you know, very careful Checking.
Rym: Yeah, but the trend in this sector in especially stuff like computer components where there's a big OEM market is That I think people who know and want to buy these types of components are either gonna go to a specialty retailer online like Newegg which like focuses on that sector and is very trustworthy because their brand is on the line and They're also buying name brands of the electronics themselves.
Rym: Like they know what they want They've done the research in advance and they're buying specific things, which means also a generic Electronics retailer a physical one or an online one Doesn't have really a well an avenue to compete with that.
Rym: Why would someone physically go to a fries when they could go to Newegg and get the same experience for a video card?
Scott: Sure, but I think that's also if you think just in the physical shopping world, right?
Scott: Let's say somebody wants to go to a store and buy a thing.
Scott: Well, if you live in New York City, right I can.
Scott: if I want to buy a thing There's a store for that thing.
Rym: that is true here, right?
Scott: If you live out in the the mega who knows where right?
Scott: It's like Walmart is the store.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: You got no other store.
Scott: but if you live in between You might have a Walmart and a Best Buy and then but you're not gonna have like a camera store there.
Scott: It's not like there could be but not likely to have a camera store or you know, like some kind of specialty Place like that.
Scott: So if you need something that is in any sort of electronic category, you might not even have a GameStop.
Scott: It's like yeah that only place to buy video games in town is Best Buy or I guess Walmart does sell video games, too Right, but yeah, you get the idea.
Scott: All right, but I guess it's your store.
Rym: But I guess part of what's what's happening there, too Is that you know what I just said about the brands a lot of the kinds of electronics that might previously have been bought even by professionals in places like this.
Rym: those are the kinds of people who are more likely to buy online and The brands that actually sell those trustworthy goods are increasingly going direct to consumer Like NZXT, you can buy NZXT computer components directly from NZXT and I as a personal rule for like five plus years now if a brand I am buying something from because I shop mostly based On brands and the trustworthiness of those brands.
Rym: I will always buy direct if I can.
Rym: I only go to a generic retailer if I cannot buy directly from the source.
Rym: And if I have to go to a retailer, I always try to go to a specialty retailer first.
Rym: Amazon is like the last resort or It's the place I go for Undifferentiated commodified goods like I need ten white plates.
Scott: I need Sometimes price.
Scott: sometimes price matters a little bit, right?
Scott: So, you know, there are situations more to buy directly from the brand than from Amazon Depends how much more right, you know, it's easy.
Scott: It's easy to say when it's only a little bit more, right?
Scott: But sometimes Amazon just has a huge sale and if it you can if you're pretty sure you're gonna get legit good.
Scott: Then you can't you know, it's like.
Scott: well I got no choice.
Scott: I'm saving $300, right?
Scott: You can't say no But I think the world is moving toward this.
Scott: No one can blame you for shopping on Amazon when you're saving 300 bucks.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but I have increasingly found that buying direct is never more expensive than Amazon except for very old things.
Scott: Yeah, it's you.
Scott: I mean I bought this new 4k monitor.
Scott: I bought it from LG comm now the LG comm web store e-commerce software.
Scott: wise their website was not the greatest But The monitor is here and I paid the right amount of money for it, you know And the last time I bought a video card the 1050 that's in my HD PC, which I was in 2018.
Scott: I bought that from EVGA comm yeah.
Scott: Yeah that directly it totally showed up.
Scott: Yeah, I paid a normal price for it.
Scott: It's still worth just as it's still selling for what I paid for it in 2018.
Rym: But I think the few the future of non commodified goods Specifically and fry like this fries thing is just a symptom of this.
Rym: I think we're gonna see showroom big-box stores where Brands will pay to showcase their goods But most of the actual purchasing will be done online or if it's in those stores that yeah There's tons of this in the city.
Scott: There's like tons of like clothing store.
Scott: That's where we bought our bed.
Rym: We went to a bed matures that had yeah the mattress there was like 10 mattress brands.
Rym: All just put like samples of other mattresses in this dumpy little storefront and we laid out them all.
Scott: Only businesses right that are like, you know, the kind that will like buy Instagram ads to sell their product, right?
Scott: They in the city.
Scott: They open up little showrooms.
Scott: It's literally just alright.
Scott: You really don't want to buy our stuff until you see it.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Well, here's we rented out the cheapest place.
Scott: You can come see the stuff and then buy it online.
Rym: Yeah, I guess the part that they get back to you know, the gig nights thing like you and I the way we shop.
Rym: We also have to remember that we and people like us and like a lot of people listen to the show Engage with buying things very differently because I think the average GeekNights listener I mean averaging one person doesn't really do much but will have an idea of what they want first and then go look for that thing.
Rym: but mass market purchasing by non experts of any good is primarily driven by.
Rym: I want thing and then it seems to be almost random.
Rym: which Iteration of that thing they actually end up buying?
Scott: like marketing drives them what happens to be in a store They physically visit drives them and it's like alright, we're gonna buy, you know They just think I want to buy a big new TV and they go to.
Scott: you know But they don't whereas we're like.
Scott: I want to get this exact.
Scott: I want to actually know what OLED means.
Rym: Like if I ever bought a car again, I'll go to a fucking dealership.
Rym: I'm gonna know in advance.
Rym: I want this specific make model color feature set and I'm going to buy it.
Rym: and that's it.
Rym: Like.
Rym: there's like.
Rym: I'm not gonna talk to a human being.
Rym: I'm gonna try to buy it online if I can.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: All right some other news, you know, we always said Twitter can't make money because you're the products.
Rym: Well, mm-hmm Twitter's getting desperate.
Rym: They're really trying to make money.
Rym: They're going to now allow people to have a subscription where I could say some of my tweets.
Rym: You have to be paying me a monthly price to be able to see those tweets.
Scott: So the twitch model the twitch model aka the patreon model aka subscribe to my you subscribe to my tweets And then Twitter takes a cut.
Rym: Yep, exactly On one.
Scott: I mean that's that's slightly good in that you're not the product as much anymore.
Rym: Yeah If you block all ads I think most of the problems Twitter has as a platform both in terms of damage to society And in terms of like the shitty experiences we have with it.
Rym: I think most of them would have been resolved if Twitter had charged money for its service in some way rather than monetizing Advertising from the beginning.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: I what I think is is somewhat true and somewhat good Thinking at least correct thinking on the side of the Twitter people is like hey look, you know We're seeing a lot more popularity on Twitter of like people making long threads yeah, which is like well and it's like.
Scott: Twitter was founded on the Only post 140 characters and now it's about posting a whole post.
Scott: and it's like let's just go back to blogs.
Rym: people Twitter would just link to someone's blog instead of that thread and they wrote their thread as a blog post.
Rym: Now you got rollers.
Rym: It's right, but I'm an old man yelling at a cloud.
Scott: So whatever like just let's just delete Twitter and go back to blogging.
Scott: Come on Anyway.
Scott: But anyway, but Twitter is correct and wise to recognize that.
Scott: that's a thing and that's a lot of people are you know?
Scott: on Twitter To read those qualities are usually quality.
Scott: when I see a retweeted thread.
Scott: That's usually the good stuff.
Scott: That's what I'm on Twitter for as long as you're following good people.
Scott: and if there were to say You know someone retweets a thread and then it's like oh you want to follow that you follow that person who posted a good thread and it's Like oh, you know that person's posting even more good stuff.
Scott: Just pay like one dollar and it's like That's why like I'm saying this is a or if you click on a thread It's like one out of X and the thread starts off.
Scott: good and it's like to read whole thread.
Scott: Subscribe to this person's Twitter.
Scott: one dollar.
Scott: It's like mmm.
Rym: Yeah, maybe especially if it was like absurdist words.
Rym: They're like, what are these anti-fascist accounts?
Rym: I follow or a good skeleton, you know, I'm not.
Scott: I'm not saying I'm a big fan of that, but I'm not entirely opposed and it's it's not.
Scott: it's not ads.
Rym: This is a good thing.
Rym: We as a society Irrespective of the broader problems of capitalism We have to get some of our technology back to a point where the users pay for a service as opposed to the service Milking the users data for other purposes, right?
Scott: But now there's the question of you know, we're getting to we're gonna start.
Scott: if they do this We'll have to start asking all the same questions.
Scott: We ask about twitch.
Scott: It's like, okay I'm that people are subscribing to and YouTube also.
Scott: people are subscribing to my tweets.
Scott: I'm now a Twitter employee.
Scott: Twitter is bullshit and they're gonna have all those battles again, right?
Rym: It's like but it also shows a couple other things.
Rym: one Twitter is Probably in trouble and trying to monetize because fleets didn't work and ads definitely aren't fucking working for them.
Scott: Just charge money to have an account.
Scott: It's that simple.
Scott: Yep and you know charge money.
Rym: sauce would be let me it's free to have an account that lets you read and Maybe you can even like follow and reply in some limited capacity, but to have regular full-on Twitter You got to pay like two dollars a year.
Scott: I mean consider this right?
Scott: So tweet bot which is a third-party IO App or Twitter right that lets you block all ads and is just better in most ways than the official Twitter app Right.
Scott: They I had tweet bot 5 Which I only cost a flat one-time fee to buy the app and then you have it forever.
Scott: but they recently came out with tweet bot 6 which is slightly improved and I was like Yeah, fuck it.
Scott: I use this app like more than most other apps, you know They want like a few dollars a year instead of a flat fee.
Scott: Okay, so I got tweet bot 6 for a few dollars a year.
Scott: That's money Twitter could could have just had if they would have sold me No ads no nothing and I would have just not used tweet bot.
Scott: use the official Twitter app and paid them that money.
Scott: Take that money.
Rym: the incremental cost of 20 was zero if It caught.
Rym: if it costs money to have full access to Twitter's features 99% of bots disappear instantly.
Scott: Yep true.
Rym: So I think this actually is a good move for Twitter and I think it foretells a possible few.
Rym: if Twitter runs into enough problems of failing to monetize all the bullshitty ways Eventually either Twitter will fall enough to where investors who just want it to make a profit without having to pay back all the VCs could run it and then it could be a real product again or It'll somehow make enough money to be healthy in a way That isn't just trying to cram ads into people's faces.
Rym: that relies on bot networks and outrage culture.
Rym: So we'll see how this all goes.
Rym: But yeah, I think it's a pretty good thing.
Rym: I'm not gonna make you pay to read my tweets though, cuz my tweets are not that great.
Scott: No, there's no.
Scott: nothing I tweet is worth money.
Rym: All right, I think I'll skip one of these news as we go a little while.
Rym: one last thing This is a science news partly a health news but also This is one of those things where we talk a lot like Scott will often say things like a new study comes out that proves Something and Scott says but we always knew that Yes We have conventional wisdom But having data and evidence to back something up is really important because sometimes long-standing wisdom can be wrong.
Rym: This is a study talking about running and cycling and the impact.
Scott: Oh, I sent you this, right?
Rym: You sent me.
Rym: this is a great this is old.
Scott: this is from 28 this old news.
Rym: But we didn't talk about it and almost no one talked about it except in very narrow Circumstances, but people talked about you'd probably just didn't hear.
Rym: Yeah, I don't follow.
Scott: I didn't hear either though.
Rym: So it seems like biking.
Rym: people were talking about it a lot And as far as I can tell the running community didn't say didn't even notice because they don't care
Scott: anyway,
Rym: but basically the study and the data shows that Here if we're not talking about like your physical bodies like vo2 max max heart rate like oxygen processing and muscles Like if you get past the point like you're above the line where you're good at those parts Like you've optimized your own physical body in that regard.
Rym: There's a question about whether or not training in a sport Like getting better at the technique of the sport can make you more efficient at that sport or
Scott: better Think think of the vo2 max, you know that your cardiovascular system right as sort of the engine it provides power.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: so you can level up your power.
Scott: You can get more horsepower, right?
Scott: You know, you can make your body just freaking stronger and you have more power.
Scott: Yep, but it's how much you know, okay Well, you have this power now.
Scott: Let's say your your your body has a hundred horsepower, whatever.
Scott: that is in terms, right?
Scott: It's like okay, well, I have a hundred horsepower But how fast do I actually run?
Scott: do I run five miles an hour ten miles an hour 20 miles an hour, right?
Scott: It's like how much you know to convert that energy into actually going right?
Scott: So that's the efficiency we're talking about here.
Scott: It's like yeah You can level up your power by working out or whatever increase your vo2 max to whatever your body's limit is based on your DNA and other environmental Restrictions, but you got to convert that into the actual going.
Scott: Yeah, right How efficient are your muscles at doing what they do?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So and that's what we're talking about here and that efficiency also covers technique.
Rym: Do you have techniques that could possibly improve that in some way in a measurable way beyond just making the engine better?
Scott: So imagine your max could be X and without increasing it at all.
Scott: You can just change the way you move your body with a coach and some training and yeah throw something harder further faster Better because so like to do it the proper way.
Rym: if I magically had the exact same body as some professional baseball home run hitter Could I hit the same number of home runs?
Rym: or are there skills I can input above and beyond that power?
Rym: This study shows something very interesting.
Rym: with running technique matters and You can improve your physical efficiency by training.
Rym: Your body will change in ways beyond just the engine to make you more efficient and there appears to be no Serious upper bound to that.
Rym: like you can keep training and keep getting more efficient.
Rym: I mean, obviously there's an eventual bound.
Scott: It's also.
Scott: there's also a bound on.
Scott: you know, the real bound is just on the engine.
Rym: Yep, the engine's gonna limit you before like you can't get better at the efficiency part But with the gains in efficiency won't matter too much as your engine is top.
Scott: So if you get for the already flooring at the end, yep.
Rym: So if you just keep training and running and practicing running you will get better even if your cardiovascular System does not get better.
Rym: but cycling.
Rym: once you get to a basic like a this baseline level of Efficiency and skill of doing the motions of cycling.
Rym: It appears that you cannot get more efficient.
Rym: Yeah, there's nothing else.
Scott: Most of the efficiency most of the efficiency of bicycling comes from the bicycle.
Scott: Yep, right It's you know You're just putting that horsepower pretty much directly into the bicycle and it's so efficient that like there's nothing different You can do body wise.
Rym: besides put more power into the pedals real It's like you put the power of the pedals there you go, right, you know, yep so the argument that was made then was that if you are a Cyclist and you are training that engine you're training like the cardiovascular system.
Rym: You can actually be more efficient in your training By doing cross training with running instead of training cycling because you can get more.
Rym: you can work out the engine more in less time.
Rym: Doing more time in the saddle won't actually help you that much once you get to a certain point.
Rym: But anyway What did I have?
Scott: oh, yeah, I've been wanting to talk about this for a while.
Scott: it's almost news territory.
Scott: But then our friend at YouTube a big Clive and Clive my boy Big Clive with his excellent electronics related videos on YouTube.
Scott: He has a certain style that is Somewhat off-putting but not shouty YouTube guy and not wrong and that's why I like big club.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, but yeah, I've been wanting to talk about these Dubai lamps.
Scott: So if you haven't heard right the I guess King I don't.
Scott: I don't know what the is.
Scott: the king of Dubai is Emperor of Dubai Sultan of Dubai.
Scott: I don't know what the person is.
Scott: I'm sorry person who runs Dubai, but also I'm not sorry because you're sometimes doing bad things.
Scott: But a somewhat bad Good thing you've done is you ordered The creation by Commission and partnership with Phillips the company that makes light bulbs.
Scott: that are a million other things These light bulbs and you have a license on them.
Scott: So now they're your light bulbs and they're not sold anywhere else in the world And it's hard to get them anywhere else in the world.
Scott: You have to like get them sent from Dubai.
Scott: And basically he was like, yeah, I want more efficient air efficiency.
Scott: again to the topic of the day.
Scott: He wanted more efficient light bulbs in Dubai.
Scott: All right The LED ones were not that efficient in terms of watts per I guess lumen or however, you're gonna measure it Right, you want to you know, and he wanted light bulbs that lasted longer.
Scott: So if you look at LED light bulbs that you get in, you know Local store in not Dubai anyone who lives outside Dubai, which is imagine 99.99 percent of our listenership if not a hundred You're gonna see that there's actually very few LEDs in there.
Scott: They're running those LEDs kind of hot to put out more light and as a result They sort of burn out faster.
Scott: not that they burn out as fast as like old filament light bulbs, which burn out super fast But they won't last as long as you're running them hot and you're getting you know Less light per watt per electricity that you're putting into the bulb.
Scott: So, how did they solve this in Dubai?
Scott: They basically just made light bulbs and big Clive does nice teardown explaining everything about these light bulbs.
Scott: They just put more LEDs in there and ran them lower.
Scott: They put less power into each LED, but there's more of them.
Scott: So you're getting more light.
Scott: You're not getting necessarily.
Scott: each.
Scott: each individual right diode is putting out less light But there's more of them and each one is getting less power to it, but there's more of them, right?
Scott: But yeah, it's a more efficient bulb with more right that lasts longer Because you're running them cooler, right?
Scott: They're not heating up so much taking more damage over time.
Scott: These bulbs probably last forever.
Scott: But then again if you're anyone in Dubai You now basically by decree only have three light bulbs or to choose from there for light bulbs to choose from.
Scott: that's it.
Scott: They had to use this light bulb everywhere in Dubai.
Scott: You can't use any other kind of light bulb anymore, right?
Scott: the end Which rules out a lot of different styles of light bulb, but it's really fascinating and it's also questionable Right as to whether this is actually better or not because on the one hand Let's say the whole world had the same decree.
Scott: right.
Scott: use these Dubai lamps everywhere on earth, right?
Scott: That would be very power efficient.
Scott: It would save us a lot of electricity coming from the power plants, right?
Scott: Whatever are powering our power plants we would be able to cut down on that and that's a good thing in terms of the environment, but We'd have to make a lot more LEDs right?
Scott: each one of these bulbs has way more LEDs in it and there's a materials and Manufacturing cost that goes into making these.
Scott: they're more expensive to buy.
Scott: Even if that you could get them there are a few dollars more than the other normal style now I have ever read about like the transition to CFLs and LEDs so far.
Rym: is that because incandescent bulbs used so much electricity that Nearly unlimited mining and supply chain to make these things as long as they last long enough in general is worth it.
Scott: But I'm not comparing these to the old light bulbs and comparing these Dubai LED lamps to the ones we have which are also LEDs.
Scott: just less efficient.
Scott: right because what if I get less efficient LEDs, but there's less LEDs in there?
Scott: So the manufacturing there's like way less materials used.
Scott: we can get like four or five bulbs instead of one.
Rym: Yeah, but the fact that they were out faster is the real problem.
Scott: where our faster is true But you could power them right with like a solar Cell and it doesn't matter if it's more or less efficient really because if as long as you have sufficient power to power it You know, it's green energy, right?
Scott: Manufacturing any of them is not you know, even if the power even if the factory was run on solar cells The materials are still mined.
Scott: Yeah at some point so It's questionable.
Scott: I don't know so I do the math on that But it's still fascinating and big Clive here will break down the circuitry for you, which is also fascinating.
Rym: It's interesting because in my own life.
Rym: I've transitioned almost all my lights increasingly to Intrinsic lighting fixtures that have like their own inbuilt like a raise of LEDs that are not replaceable.
Rym: hmm So, uh, I think of the day.
Rym: it's something that is not like it's not good and you probably shouldn't use it But it's neat.
Rym: So you might have noticed that whole hubbub about game stonk Game stock stocks and all the stock market nonsense going on and the diamond holds and all this Rocket ships.
Rym: so a lot of nerds are really into trying to trade in the stock market and trying to make money with Cryptocurrencies which we'll get into in the main bit and some enterprising nerd has made what they're calling the game stonk terminal.
Rym: I want to read this about because it's really really short.
Rym: Game stock terminal is an awesome stock and crypto market terminal that is developed for fun.
Rym: When I saw my GME shares tanking the implementation and Python allows to easily add more commands expand on the configuration.
Rym: Feel free to make requests.
Rym: I'm happy to work on them in my spare time.
Rym: It's basically the way people are talking about it is.
Rym: it's a quote Bloomberg terminal But it's open and it's for the masses and anyone can just use it.
Scott: Well has an interface similar to a Bloomberg job.
Rym: It's a command line interface where you can type stuff and See stock stuff.
Scott: So if you were used to using a Bloomberg terminal You might come to get a similar user
Rym: really worthless if you're used to losing a Bloomberg terminal because here's
Scott: But I'm saying the user experience in terms of like, you know, the interface
Rym: Because I'm
Scott: trying to mimic it right the same way like, you know, this
Rym: is
Scott: why Windows
Rym: the way people are talking about this thing like oh, yeah, it's like a Bloomberg terminal Using it and looking at it and like seeing the way people are talking about it and what it is.
Rym: I Equivalent of Stock market interactions like this is like this is the kind of tool someone would make if they had seen what stock market stuff looks like but didn't actually Understand how and why people trade stocks and tried to make something that had the visual aesthetic of a tool they happen to have seen Because basically all it lets you do is use a kind of mediocre Command-line interface to make it draw charts of stock prices and run really simplistic Regression models against those prices and look up publicly available data from like sources out there Things like the Bloomberg terminal.
Rym: that interface is not what people pay for.
Rym: Nobody's paying to have something.
Scott: get that for free from Yahoo Finance.
Rym: Yeah Yahoo Finance does more than this little terminal.
Rym: does people pay for those types of services because they give you data?
Rym: The data is the only thing anyone wants with any one of these platforms out there and this is the interface That is superficially similar to one of those platforms, but without any of that data.
Rym: That's actually worth anything.
Scott: I Think that you know, that's someone who hasn't used one of those things, right?
Scott: It's just some day trading game stop buying.
Scott: person doesn't really know what's you know going on and it's extra fascinating to see what?
Rym: commands were implemented first based on what people care about because they have this section called due diligence where you can like Type the word news to see the latest news for some company or
Scott: type the word
Rym: To see your recent posts on reddit about this company or type the word short to see the short interest in this company.
Rym: like that stuff's just in Yahoo or Google or Google Finance or whatever and No one who would use a tool like this has any idea how to actually use any of the information they would get out of It to make a stock trade.
Rym: a human being is not looking at stuff like this to make stock trades.
Rym: This is like you're just a hobbyist playing a game and you're gonna fuck yourself over.
Rym: Don't trade stocks.
Rym: If you don't know what you're doing Don't trade stocks period yeah.
Rym: Well, let some like 401k trade them for you in the meta moment.
Scott: Yeah Oh, I do have a metamom whoa, whoa.
Scott: Yeah, right, so I found out.
Scott: You know since I was spending a lot more time playing video games I was poking around steam and I was cleaning out my steam friends list because I had way too many steam friends And it was hard to find actual friends in that list.
Scott: So I sorted it out a whole bunch and I'm sorry if I unfriended you because there were a lot of people who's done names.
Scott: I'm like, I think that's a listener, but I don't know them and it's not like I'm playing games with them or messaging them Or anything, right?
Scott: So why are my friends with them on Steam?
Scott: So I unfriended a lot of people.
Scott: if you want to be my steam friend You can just message me on any platform and I will be a steam friend.
Scott: again if you want to play games with me.
Scott: It's not a you know, don't don't be sad You know.
Rym: speaking of which?
Rym: along those lines I I mentioned this in the stinger a couple episodes ago and I posted a few places.
Rym: I'm gonna start up a play-by-mail game of sip six for any of the listeners who want to be in.
Rym: I'm looking for like 8 to 10 players and I will make a post.
Rym: Well, we're gonna do online speed instead of quick speed for obvious reasons but I'm gonna make a Google forum post.
Rym: people can like put their stuff in so I can make sure I am friends with you on Steam so I can invite you into this game when I started up in a week or two.
Scott: Anyway, so while I was doing that I took note of some steam features, right?
Scott: and I noticed I've known for a while that there's like the steam curator feature because Occasionally, I'll see people like linking to steam curator pages on Twitter and it's like here's the list of games.
Scott: We've got together We're promoting as a group or stuff like that, right?
Scott: And I realized like wait a minute that curator thing is like a is like a steam Group feature and there's been a GeekNights group on steam for like ever.
Scott: It has actually lots of people in it.
Scott: I don't know how people aren't using the group, but they're in the group.
Scott: It's got I think a couple hundred people at least in there And You can make a curator page to go with your steam group.
Scott: So I went ahead and did that.
Scott: Yeah, so there is now a GeekNights' steam curator page, which I basically included the games We recently talked about on this podcast.
Scott: But you know, maybe we'll do a little bit more over there.
Rym: Yeah, but there's about what I want to curate in there.
Scott: Yeah, but there's a. there's actually a whole bunch of features that I haven't really thought about but they're in there.
Scott: So there is basically this perpetual chat room.
Scott: That's just always there.
Scott: That's like the GeekNights steam chat room.
Scott: You we have a GeekNights discord.
Scott: You can come there.
Scott: I don't think you need to use the GeekNights steam chat room, but it exists.
Scott: It's it's a thing.
Scott: I guess there was a little forum on there with one posted.
Scott: I just deleted that form.
Scott: There's still a link to go to that forum.
Scott: There's like a discussions tab on the steam group, but if you click on it, you'll get an error now because I deleted And they don't remove the tab when you don't have any forums And we can make announcements there as well.
Scott: So I am using steam a lot more these days being at home all day.
Scott: So if you want to do GeekNights steam biz, you know You don't really need to be friends of me directly on steam.
Scott: if you're just in the GeekNights steam group All right, it's a public group.
Scott: You could just join it Totally public.
Scott: just come on in.
Scott: you can just search for it.
Scott: There it is.
Scott: You know, I don't think you think you're smart enough to type GeekNights into steam to find.
Scott: You can follow the little curator page and then even if you'd ever want to listen to our stupid podcast which I guess you are doing it now, but You'll see when we wreck it.
Scott: if we ever talk about
Rym: people in the stream right now
Scott: Yeah, if we talk about a game that happens to be on steam I'm gonna try to remember to go add it to our little curator page
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: and we can also add like some extra lists to it, too.
Scott: We can be like, you know list games Scott likes a Rym dozen or something like that, you know You'll
Rym: see more stuff up here in there because that you
Scott: can use it If you ever think if you ever sit in there and you're like man, you know, there's a steam sale.
Scott: What should I buy?
Scott: or man?
Scott: I really like to play a game right now But I don't know which game and I've played all the games on my steam library.
Scott: Let me go actually buy a new game.
Scott: You can go to the GeekNights steam curator page and see if any of those games strike your fancy.
Rym: So, you know along those lines actually I'll shit talk it now because I did.
Rym: I've been working on this for a while.
Rym: You know how if you're not aware I put every board game review we've ever done on YouTube.
Rym: It's basically the part of the gig nights episode.
Rym: That's the review without like things the day or news any that other crap.
Rym: It's just the review of that game and they're pretty much all on YouTube except a handful of like games were reviewed in episodes from like 2005 where fair like that garbage review we did of T&E as part of a larger episode in Literally 2005 does not need to be on YouTube.
Scott: But oh that does remind me.
Rym: so now there's some metal.
Rym: look at this.
Rym: So that was successful and if you're not aware of that go check it out.
Rym: I'll link to it.
Rym: I am working on doing the same thing for all the video games we've ever reviewed meaning you'll be able to find link to and listen to a The review of any video game we've ever talked about without any of the news and other nonsense as well And I'll start publishing those on a semi-weekly basis.
Rym: Once I get my pipeline completely Rockin and a little bit ahead.
Scott: So the two that reminds me is that in that steam curator page We have the ability to link from our curating page directly to our review of the.
Rym: look at that.
Rym: It's almost like the thing I just said and the thing you just said is gonna make it real easy.
Scott: So when you go to the curator page and you see a game and you're like should I get this game?
Scott: Well right there in steam is an embedded YouTube video of us reviewing the of the GeekNights episode of us talking about that game.
Scott: That's helpful.
Scott: And the other thing I forgot about is that the steam curator thing has a feature Where people can actually send games to us saying like it's sort of like an inbox on steam on on the curator page From like for game creators people who are making games and putting them on steam to send those games to us and saying hey Please check out my game.
Scott: So I guess you can try to use that.
Scott: I don't I can't promise I'm gonna play your game, but you can try to use it.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: see what happens Now.
Rym: we got people in the stream talking about they're gonna engage with this.
Rym: I think we should do a lot with this team group.
Scott: Well, maybe maybe not.
Scott: we'll see it's low-hanging fruit.
Scott: The effort is yeah Right like I'm saying is we on every single platform steam discord Twitter Not so much Facebook anymore Instagram if I remember to use it.
Scott: You know ever we are on every platform wherever you YouTube we are there, right?
Scott: So you can come and find us in the place that you like to be including even steam All right, so we don't know.
Rym: this won't be a super long main bit But or else we've never done a show on this and I think it is where you deleted a show on this.
Scott: Yeah, pretty sure we've talked about this.
Rym: We've trashed coins in the past Yeah, but what we've never done is done an episode to actually as a main vent like talk about what this stuff is.
Rym: So we're gonna talk about Cryptocurrency like as a concept because it's new right.
Rym: this did not exist in any meaningful way.
Rym: It's quite.
Scott: it's actually more years old than you realize at this point.
Rym: But so the in the early to mid 2000s there was.
Scott: I thought it would have been dead by now But I was wrong.
Rym: there was chatter about this kind of thing.
Rym: But Bitcoin like the famous one that people know that kind of kicked off a lot of interest in it 2009 like that's when that appeared.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Rym: So what a cryptocurrency is is actually a complicated question to answer because it's not as easy question answer.
Rym: well, it's complicated if you actually think about what this technology does because fundamentally what cryptocurrencies do is make a Ledger a generic ledger imagined like an Excel spreadsheet literally a spreadsheet.
Rym: Yep, but I say ledger because spreadsheet implies some other features that these don't have.
Rym: but it means that there could be a spreadsheet out there that I can put updates into and Scott can put updates into and Scott and I can agree to put an update in together and the spreadsheet itself will prove Who put those updates in there and when?
Rym: it'll prove that Oh Brim and Scott agreed to put this update in there and it'll prove that those updates have not been tampered with and I don't have to trust Scott and Scott doesn't have to trust me and neither of us has to trust the ledger itself.
Rym: We can write this distributed trust.
Rym: that quote just works.
Scott: Yeah, so fundamentally the principle of the cryptocurrency Right is actually the only positive thing about it, right?
Scott: And I can see why that principle is so alluring.
Scott: that has dragged people into it Despite literally everything else about it being absolute dogshit.
Scott: So the principle is like hey if you wanted to set up like, you know a bank or a new currency Digitally the easy way to do it It's just make a server that has a spreadsheet and just keeps track of everything right.
Scott: and anyone wants to do anything.
Scott: They would contact the server and the server would say, okay, so and so is given ten dollars to someone.
Scott: so and write it down So and it keeps it just.
Scott: they'll just have a database that keeps track of how much money everyone has.
Scott: It's super simple super easy.
Scott: It just works.
Scott: It's just great.
Scott: But the problems with that is who's controlling that server Now?
Scott: can you trust them?
Rym: now the right is the server get compromised.
Rym: We can trust the people running those things for the most sure but can I want to give money to sell someone else?
Scott: But I don't want anyone else to know.
Scott: I wanted to be secret, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, it's all these.
Scott: what if the government takes down the server?
Scott: They don't like what you're doing?
Rym: Well, I guess that's why I wanted to say there was a complicated answer because they call it a crypto currency But all it really is is a distributed shared ledger.
Rym: The currency aspect of it is the use case people imagine for this technology first, which was basically Have something digital that acts like physical cash Yep, an intrinsic asset.
Rym: I'd like if I give Scott $20 Physically the only way to get that back from him is to fight him and take it or like break into his house and steal $20 like I can't.
Rym: I can't undo the transaction.
Rym: I can't like call Andrew Jackson on the phone and be like, yeah, I need that $20 back from Scott, right?
Scott: But but if we're using say an essentialized currency like say World of Warcraft gold, right, you know World of Warcraft could just be like, you know what?
Scott: We're deleting half the gold in the world.
Scott: We're just gonna delete your account.
Scott: We're gonna you know, you mind go you you had you had a. you were gold farming and selling the gold.
Scott: We're gonna delete all your account and get rid of all that gold.
Scott: It's like they just run it and it's like well You don't want that you want to.
Rym: well It's something I don't want that.
Rym: some people do want that because I'm gonna make a very specific argument right now.
Rym: I don't want to get into currencies and like Economics in this episode too much, but I am of the opinion that you generally do want Governments and professionals heavily manipulating currency to achieve desirable social outcomes.
Scott: Yeah, maybe.
Rym: maybe in some cases I would like the game developer to have the ability to fuck with the in-game currency to make the game better.
Rym: Imagine if World of Warcraft like the use some blockchain Bitcoin technology and literally had no way To interfere with the valuation of the in-game currency, right?
Scott: Anyway, so that principle though is alluring no doubt, especially for you know Anti-authoritarian people which I think people on the far right and the far left are combined in our anti-authoritarianism.
Scott: You know, we don't want Kings right.
Scott: I guess maybe people on the far I do want a king but they don't want the king we have.
Scott: Yeah, so there's still.
Scott: they're anti this authority Even if they're not and they're anti existing authority, even if they're not anti all authority?
Scott: Yeah, right and anarchists are anti all authority, right?
Scott: so there's sort of this combined desire for the core principle, but the Implementation of Bitcoin specifically and many of the followers of Bitcoin
Rym: pretty much all currencies
Scott: pretty much all cryptocurrencies have fallen on this one question, which is the problem whenever you're starting any new currency is Okay, we've started a new currency.
Scott: Well you print money.
Scott: Okay, you printed a billion dollars.
Scott: You've got them in a pile.
Scott: It's like it's not doing anything until you give it out to people.
Scott: How much do we give out to who right?
Scott: who gets what to start with?
Scott: and we're just gonna give everyone in the world One and then that's it.
Scott: Are we gonna you know?
Scott: What are you gonna?
Scott: you need some way to determine how much you're gonna give to who like to start with.
Scott: the second problem?
Scott: That all cryptocurrencies have that regular currencies might not necessarily have.
Scott: is that because you have this distributed ledger?
Scott: You need people to use their computers to sort of run the ledger and to you know, make it work.
Scott: It's not because there isn't a central computer doing all the work and keep your track of everything.
Scott: You need people to turn on their computers and run software that will make the thing go?
Scott: if not And if let's say only let's say.
Scott: I started a cryptocurrency today and the only computer Running the cryptocurrency was one that I bought and set up in like the cloud just a little cloud server.
Scott: If this currency got popular and people started using it I'll say I gave everyone in the world one one Scott dollar and they started using it Basically trade.
Scott: it would take so long for that computer To do even like one transaction because it's one little weak computer.
Scott: It would be a useless currency because you have to wait for my little computer to do work every time you're exchanging The one dollars that I gave everybody right
Rym: now, but even worse now It's basically just a centralized currency again because Scott server is the only server sure like
Scott: exactly.
Rym: So you don't get any of these supposed benefits of the technology itself.
Scott: Yeah, so the way Bitcoin decided to solve to basically both of these problems at once How do we give out the money and how do we get people to turn on their computers and make them help us?
Scott: Run this network of you know computation.
Scott: They combined both of those problems into one solution, which is the worst idea ever And basically they said hey look You're gonna run your computer and help run the Bitcoin network.
Scott: Right help, you know enter transactions and process them and do all that stuff for this shared ledger and We're basically gonna run a lottery sort of effectively.
Scott: right where?
Scott: You know every 10 minutes or so every amount of work Which is adjusted to sort of.
Scott: you know bring it down to.
Scott: you know one per 10 minutes.
Scott: They keep adjusting it to sort of keep it in that window.
Scott: We're just gonna give a Bitcoin to someone who was doing that work.
Scott: You know every 10 minutes or so They just give out another coin until there's a set number of how many coins they're gonna give out and then it's done.
Scott: But that number is off in the future, so that's not a problem yet, but it will be.
Rym: And at some point, but the important thing about that technology is that it's usually there's two fundamental.
Rym: There's more than two but these are the only two that anyone really seriously talks about of how to make these networks run either proof of stake or Proof of work because you need to have a
Scott: way
Rym: to get a bunch of people to do what Scott described and You have to make sure that enough people are doing that that there isn't just one sole authority running the whole thing Because then they could start fucking with it.
Rym: So exactly proof of stake is all is the idea.
Rym: and again I'm super paraphrasing here because I don't think this technology is useful or me like for most purposes on earth.
Rym: So I don't think you need to learn a lot about it nor do I want to learn that much more about it.
Rym: to be honest, but proof of stake would basically mean imagine if all right, I Want the Bitcoin network to keep working.
Rym: So I keep computers running to make a part of it keep working But they don't use a ton of resources like they do today.
Rym: in order to participate in the network.
Rym: I have to freeze some percentage of the bitcoins.
Rym: I own like some real money worth of that asset in a provable way Basically saying if my if the work I'm doing on the network is found to be fraudulent.
Rym: I lose my stake.
Rym: I Cared that the network continues to function.
Rym: thus I have no incentive to fuck with the network because I would lose so much Personally that it wouldn't be worth it to me.
Rym: and there's more to it than that.
Rym: proof of work is what most of these things use.
Rym: proof of work is Basically solve Sudoku's by idling your car's engine.
Rym: Just do a bunch of worthless computing Mm-hmm and like solve problems that are specifically very very difficult to solve But very easy to prove that someone has solved Mm-hmm.
Rym: Yeah, I mean if you know we've talked about cryptography in an old episode think of this is like non-reversible math or difficult to reverse math or Asymmetric math.
Rym: easy to go one way hard to go the other way.
Scott: That's nice.
Scott: Like I'm trying to.
Scott: I'm trying to figure out rims password.
Scott: It's really hard to figure out.
Scott: It's a guessing guessing guessing guessing guess, but if I get it right, it's very easy to know I have the right one.
Scott: It's like is this the correct password?
Scott: Yes, that's a very easy question to answer.
Scott: It takes to say like I'm in millisecond so fast.
Rym: So if we're getting into that like the real cost and problem with these algorithms and how bitcoins is Bitcoin in particular.
Rym: But they just applies to all of these currencies.
Rym: The problem is that we use the term currency.
Rym: people talk about these as a Solely as speculative investments.
Rym: Yep, people are only participating Because they assume that the value of these things will go up over time and they won't make money.
Scott: You turn you see that a Bitcoin is worth a zillion dollars, right and you say well If I turn on my computer and have it waste energy like in the next ten minutes There's a good chance on entering this lottery every ten minutes basically and the more computers I turn on the more lottery tickets I get.
Scott: so if I can do that Then I can win this lottery and that if the coin is worth so much if I win the lottery and I'm mathematically I'll win about these many.
Scott: so that means I'll be able to pay for this many computers as long as some rube is willing to Give me real money because I can't obviously pay for Or or the person who's selling me the computers and electricity is a rube who will take the coins?
Scott: Right, but in that case, what are you doing?
Scott: So it's paying you in coins to run a computer and then you're just paying for the computers with coins.
Scott: You're doing nothing like you're getting.
Scott: what are you getting out of it?
Scott: Maybe there's some profit their margin of real dollars in there somewhere Of like a spare coin that you don't need.
Scott: you get an extra.
Scott: you minted five coins.
Scott: It only cost you three to pay for the computers and you sold two to someone else for cash real cash, right?
Scott: No one wants actual coins.
Scott: people want real cash.
Scott: The allure of the Bitcoin is that you can turn it into real dollars, right?
Scott: You know one wants a freaking coins.
Scott: They want real dollars.
Scott: if the if a Bitcoin is worth zeroed out the real dollars and you couldn't pay a rent with it No one would give a shit.
Rym: now This is the interesting problem.
Rym: every most of the talk around Bitcoin and cryptocurrencies, especially in the early days was around Using it as a decentralized currency to be a transaction network that didn't rely on the banks.
Rym: So like I could buy I don't know a video card from fries online and Literally just pay with bitcoins and have an intrinsic cash like transaction online.
Rym: But and that would be in principle would be good especially for doing illegal things, you know, ah, yeah That's that second part I was about to say because the problem with cash based transactions is that they're non reversibility and Difficult of traceability difficulty of traceability.
Rym: it causes a lot more problems than it solves Because you're basically just saying hey, all right, right.
Scott: you think about a normal person, you know doing anonymous transactions Maybe buy some weed or something.
Scott: It's like, okay cool, whatever.
Scott: All right, but Usually it's gonna be money laundering, right?
Scott: It's gonna be real crime that you don't want happening.
Scott: It's not right.
Scott: and then any normal person it's like average person can just use regular cash.
Rym: it's That's like the.
Rym: all the arguments as to why we would want to use a cryptographic intrinsic currency are Pretty specious at best because most of the arguments are around.
Rym: Oh, well, you don't want the payment processors to control things While you avoided some payment processing fees.
Scott: great Yeah, but you know.
Rym: but those fees arguably pay for that system existing and working in the first place and The incremental cost to individual users is relatively low.
Scott: Yeah, also it's like, you know, you could you know, even if the the coin network Right wasn't eating up all the power on earth and causing heart horrific climate You know change if it was just.
Scott: you know, a few computers, you know, a few people did it.
Scott: It was.
Scott: it was all good right?
Scott: the the fact that the value of the coins is constantly changing Makes them not a good currency.
Scott: Yeah volatile.
Rym: I might try to buy pizza from like the local pizza shop and by the time the transaction finishes Bitcoin went up a thousand dollars and now I've literally paid a hundred bucks for my pizza or Right.
Scott: So currencies that you actually use for buying and selling goods on a frequent basis need to be relatively stable.
Scott: They don't need to be absolutely stable, right?
Scott: You know as they need to be predictable even if they are not necessarily stable, right?
Scott: Right if the value of a dollar is like dropping precipitously people rush out to spend dollars really quick Right before they're not worth anything.
Scott: It's like quick.
Scott: Give me that pizza.
Scott: That means this value isn't changing But the dollar is becoming worthless quick.
Scott: Take my dollars, right?
Scott: I don't want them.
Scott: But if the value is rising people just hoard it.
Scott: They just put that shit in the mattress and they wait and they don't buy anything.
Rym: Oh, this is even worse than that.
Rym: cash and crypto currencies have this fundamental problem.
Rym: They're intrinsic, right?
Rym: So even it even if they're super volatile or not vols save.
Rym: they were perfectly like a one.
Rym: Bitcoin was worth one dollar and that Was magically like real didn't have to worry lost it in.
Rym: they locked it in.
Rym: somehow It's still cash.
Rym: Cash can be stolen.
Rym: You can rob someone of cash.
Rym: cash can be lost in a fire.
Rym: How many bitcoins are buried in a kiss an encrypted hard drive where someone forgot the password?
Scott: Yep, there's a lot of bitcoins that are just gone cuz someone forgot lost the encryption key and that's it.
Scott: There's no way to get them out the whole unless you I guess you could try to brew.
Scott: I wonder If we could like find see but thing is I think that would cost more than just mining coins is if you could find some Abandoned coins and try to mine the key to try to unlock.
Rym: there are people doing just that.
Scott: Okay, but it's like.
Scott: I think it might be more efficient just mine coins.
Scott: Yeah, isn't efficient at all.
Rym: But effectively all the arguments for crypto current currencies being used as actual currencies for the most part have been ridiculous Because in practice no one gives a shit about these as currencies.
Rym: They don't solve any problem that most people have.
Rym: The way people buy and sell things actually works really well today for the most part.
Rym: So as speculative instruments, like yeah, they're just a bubble like all bubbles.
Rym: They're not worth anything and someday this whole particular system is gonna come crashing down.
Rym: But good the third problem is that because we're using these proof-of-work algorithms Not only did they not solve a problem people actually have but they are literally destroying the earth.
Scott: Yep Using the Bitcoin that people are spending more electricity Mining coins than like entire country's worth of people, right?
Scott: I Think it's like you.
Scott: basically I think is you just?
Scott: I really don't have a problem with going around and just like if you're mining Coins, we just confiscate all your computers.
Rym: I honestly think the governments of the world should make it illegal to use and interact with the Bitcoin network or any proof of work Currency that is traded as an asset like it.
Scott: and it's not because it's not because of the principle right.
Scott: that core principle It's very anti-government and I actually agree with that core principle of like yeah, fuck the man.
Scott: Let's get our own money.
Scott: That's out of government control.
Scott: It's like yeah, you know, that's actually kind of a good thing.
Scott: The problem with that can't destroy the earth.
Scott: to do that, right?
Scott: I would argue that you have to find another way.
Rym: I would argue that even that the idea of a currency not controlled by governments and experts is Probably more dangerous than valuable to society.
Scott: Yeah, you mean yes and no, but it's also cyberpunk cool.
Rym: Yeah, it's cyber cool.
Rym: But all the cyberpunk cool things are trying to fight against the systems that are entrenched in neoliberal late capitalism anyway Like shadow like oh, yeah cool We got cred sticks with intrinsic digital cash.
Rym: half the plots of that game are.
Rym: let's murder that dude and steal his cred stick.
Scott: So now there's one more.
Scott: there's one more cryptocurrency related thing I want to talk about.
Scott: So this is news literally like a couple days ago.
Scott: So I never knew how to pronounce this this This musician's name.
Scott: It's three LAU.
Scott: I don't know if it's eelow or three lau or I never knew how to say this person's name.
Scott: I'm sorry You know, but anyway Basically what what this person did recently is They.
Scott: there's a. there's a thing called an NFT a non-fungible Token.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I'm extra mad about those.
Scott: Well, okay.
Scott: So this is good and bad parts to this again, right?
Scott: So a non.
Scott: so a dollar is Fungible by what?
Scott: by fungible in this sense?
Scott: We mean that if I got a dollar and rims got a dollar right we can swap dollars and we're.
Scott: it's the same.
Scott: a dollar is A dollar right.
Scott: a Bitcoin is a Bitcoin.
Scott: bitcoins are fungible, right?
Scott: It doesn't matter if I have Bitcoin a or Bitcoin B. They're both one Bitcoin, right?
Scott: Imagine if every single Bitcoin right was you a unique snowflake.
Scott: So imagine a good example for nerds be Pokemon cards, right?
Scott: So at the Pokemon card factory Instead of printing, you know a thousand Charizard cards Every single Pokemon card that comes out of the printer is a brand new Pokemon.
Scott: There's a million Pokemon and they're all unique Pokemon.
Scott: to catch them all you would need a million Pokemon.
Scott: Literally every Pokemon in the universe is perfectly unique, right?
Scott: So what you they do is they they make a cryptocurrency right not Bitcoin a different one and They make it to where each and every coin in the currency is a unique snowflake, right?
Scott: it's like I have number five and In this way you can do some cool things.
Scott: Right, it still has all the same awful problems of all the other cryptocurrencies, right that we've talked about it already.
Scott: But the sort of unique and only positive feature and this is what three Lau is.
Scott: or however, you say the person's name I should really look it up talked about them is They're selling their art this way and it's basically like hey, we're basically selling like limited edition artworks, right?
Scott: It's like you couldn't sell a limited edition artwork in the digital realm Normally, right, you know if you make a JPEG, it's like you.
Scott: just there's an affinity.
Scott: JPEGs.
Scott: now deal with it, right?
Scott: But in the real world, you could print a thousand albums and that's it.
Scott: There's a thousand albums the end.
Scott: so the NFT allows you to be like hey here I've made a thousand albums or even a thousand unique songs and each one is right.
Scott: and then You attach your artwork to the Currency coins unique coins and FTS.
Scott: and now look you three.
Scott: This person sold them for a cut all of them in total for three point six six six six six million dollars.
Rym: And didn't this use like more electricity than that studio spent in two years to accomplish?
Rym: Yeah, something like these non fungible tokens are also using a ton of electricity.
Scott: They sold a collection of limited edition NFTs for three point six six.
Scott: Also, I want to point out that pundit also broke the record in non fungible token sales by selling 33 unique items for a total of 11 million dollars.
Rym: So the problem with those non fungible tokens though Is that they don't prove ownership or restrict ownership of anything.
Rym: people can still copy the underlying asset.
Rym: All they do is there's one shared ledger somewhere that says Scott owns this one Doesn't mean you actually have it own it can do anything in particular with it Except transfer that ownership.
Rym: It's not really different than a server that just says who owns what scan at what time?
Scott: Mm-hmm, but as long as human, you know It's the same thing with the Bitcoin if people are willing to put value on that right the same way.
Scott: Someone's you know, this World of Warcraft There's just a database somewhere that says your character has a sword.
Scott: the people at Blizzard could push a button and up do an update statement in their SQL database and give Everyone every a full inventory of every rare.
Scott: They're all the items right?
Scott: It's like tada.
Scott: It's done.
Scott: It's completely false scarcity Right, but it's a way to create a false scarcity in the digital realm Which can be cool can also be kind of not cool, right?
Rym: But remember this isn't like.
Rym: generally not a fan of is on this like only whoever has the key can listen to the Wu-Tang album.
Scott: Well, it would be.
Scott: it would be like that is if you did a digital one and you just made one non fungible token.
Rym: No I wouldn't because people can just copy the music out and share it without the token.
Rym: all.
Rym: the only thing the token gives you is You can point at that database and say at that ledger and say I own.
Rym: that Doesn't actually prevent anyone else from having the actual thing.
Scott: Maybe maybe not.
Scott: anyway It depends on what the thing is.
Scott: if the thing is like, you know They use this technology with like those crypto cats, right and it's like, you know You go to the website and is like that's Scott's crypto cat the same way.
Scott: It's your sword in World of Warcraft, right?
Scott: It's like it but I did that.
Scott: this is the.
Scott: you log into the.
Scott: you log into the game.
Scott: The game checks the ledger and now the game sees that I own the sword.
Scott: So I have the sword.
Scott: You you get your character in.
Scott: the game doesn't have the sword because the ledger doesn't say so.
Scott: there are I think the ledger as is data.
Rym: There's a bunch of game companies that want to do this kind of thing for skins To have skins be like themselves tradeable outside of the games.
Scott: But do you think you just you can just do it the old-fashioned way that they do it now?
Rym: Database all the ways people like to use crypto currencies for Currency like actual currency are just kind of failures.
Rym: all the ways people try to use this technology for these other interesting things It is the use cases where just putting a database in place is Somehow we're like not the option and somehow this technology makes this thing work are vanishingly small.
Rym: There's almost no reason ever use this kind of technology for any of these use cases compared to traditional methods Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, you know like I guess TLDR, right?
Scott: I think that all the people who support coins, right are.
Scott: You know some I can partially understand.
Scott: it's like they're so allured by the principle of the coin, right?
Scott: You know Jack from Twitter the CEO of Twitter is one of these people right and that The the promise and the principle of the non-government Give it to the man cyberpunk, you know money money of the people, right?
Scott: You know that principle.
Scott: you can believe in it so strongly.
Scott: but when you look at the reality of How these things work the actual effect they've had the actual results literally everything about them They've lived up to that principle?
Scott: basically not at all.
Scott: Yep They're pretty much used almost exclusively as money laundering instruments for crime or as speculative instruments Yes, and pretty much everyone who's like it's it's telling that everyone who is pro coin is Like.
Scott: when I first heard of the coins, you know people were they always talk about them in the future.
Scott: tense They're like they.
Scott: they see the promise of coins.
Scott: like they're admitting coins aren't there yet Right, like they're basically saying coins suck now but they still believe in them in the future.
Scott: and That's what someone says.
Scott: when they own.
Scott: they still own the asset in a Ponzi scheme or when at the top of a pyramid scheme.
Rym: Well, like look at in those early days how many?
Rym: scams and like cyber thefts happened of these digital assets because They're intrinsic assets.
Rym: like you can steal them.
Scott: Yep, but there is no in my opinion.
Scott: There is no future.
Scott: There is no positive future for coins and they're hurting people outside of the coin world, right?
Scott: It would be one thing if you when you did coin shit, you only hurt people who are doing coin shit, right?
Scott: But you're hurting everyone when you do coin shit.
Scott: So Fuck everyone who's in the coin world go to hell and fuck them coins and find another way to achieve Your cyber utopian principles that actually fucking work.
Rym: Because frankly even if there were valid uses for this technology that made sense and actually solved a problem in the world these proof-of-work Algorithms and the electricity they're wasting makes that a non starter.
Scott: Yeah, and if you want to if you want to set up a currency or whatever Postgres is free and it uses one computer and with one computer you could run you could have like so many users is unbelievable.
Scott: Right, just do that.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott special Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the patreon patreons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce I mean nickel link eg Grand Finch you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: now.
Rym: go through the last year or so.
Rym: podcast maker.
Rym: I've seen Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan parent review mad bull 34 cowards Right, Lily Tenebrae just like a juke guy Chris Reimer shirt from on oil and a whole bunch of people who do not want me To say their names.
Rym: I'll have a forum a form of some kind posted about that sieve game coming up soon.
Rym: Stay tuned, but for now, I just simply leave you with magic man.
Scott: Stop this nonsense immediately.
Rym: Magic man have some of these bangers.
Rym: Why don't you bang?
Rym: Just a few more laps and I'll break the creep world record.