Rym: It's Thursday, July 15th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we're talking about counterfeits, bootlegs, and illegitimate goods.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Warm, Diddy.
Rym: Warm, indeed.
Scott: I, uh- Finally a warm day, but of course it's a day where I gotta fuckin' work and I can't go to the beach or whatever.
Rym: Yup, but at least, so, in pre-COVID times, like, I would bike to work unless I had to, like, be dressed up extra fancy for, like, a special meeting or something.
Rym: I'd bike to work every day, use my own bike.
Rym: But, uh, in COVID times, once I start, like, nowadays, it's kind of a pain in the ass with all the protocols they've got at work to, like, bring my bike and use the bike loading dock.
Rym: So I've been using the city bikes instead of, you know, taking my real bike.
Rym: Also because my building, like, years ago, people freaked out about, I guess, theoretically, supposedly, someone's bike got stolen from the bike room, which, frankly, I don't even care.
Rym: But because of that, the building, like, I have to talk to the doorman and they have to, like, buzz me in and it's also a pain in the ass, so the city bike's just better.
Rym: But because it's so hot, I've been using those e-bikes pretty much every day to and from work.
Rym: And I gotta say- Using the e-bike?
Scott: I just use the- I've never used the e-bike.
Scott: I just keep using the regular one.
Scott: Why would I pay money for the e-one?
Rym: So, the reason I use the e-one is only for commuting.
Rym: Is that, uh, and usually, I actually only use it on the way to work.
Rym: On the way home, I use a regular bike.
Scott: I got nothing against the e-one, it's just.
Scott: I don't need to use the e-one, I can use the regular one, so why should- I could, but I'm usually wearing, like, pants and a real shirt because I'm going to an office- Why are you wearing pants and a shirt when it's warm?
Rym: Because of the kind of job I have.
Scott: So, I can't, like- I would just show up in shorts and t-shirts.
Rym: So, riding a regular city bike, I'll be a little sweaty coming into work and I don't always want to be, but the thing about the e-bike, I realized, that taking it to work, it costs about half what a MetroCard swipe would and it is five-
Scott: Well, that's on top of the price.
Scott: If you didn't have the annual pass, it wouldn't cost.
Rym: Ah, but I have the annual pass because I use regular city bikes all the time in my regular life.
Rym: So, it's basically free because I'm paying for it anyway, but the e-bike is just objectively better than the subway unless it's raining.
Rym: Or, like, super cold.
Scott: As long as you're going somewhere the subway goes.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So, basically- Or somewhere the city bike goes.
Scott: The subway goes more places than the city bike does.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So, I'm using these e-bikes to go to work so I don't have to huff and puff with a giant fucking city bike over the Queensborough bridge.
Scott: You know, the other way to avoid huffing and puffing is just bike slower.
Scott: Nah, I'm not willing to do that.
Scott: You seem to be incapable of doing that.
Rym: No, fuck that.
Rym: If I'm not going, like, 15 miles an hour, I'm not happy.
Scott: I just go,
Scott: "Doop-doop-doop-doop-doop-doop-doop-doop-doop.".
Rym: You've seen my Strava's when I went, like, Emily and I were out joyriding.
Scott: I just go,
Scott: "Doop-doop-doop-doop-doop.".
Rym: So, in the last three times I've gone over the Queensborough bridge on my way to or from work, so yesterday coming home, today going to, and today coming home, I want to see what your guess would be.
Rym: How many times was I passed on the Queensborough bridge by a motorcycle that was gasoline-powered in the bike lane?
Scott: Probably at least five or six times.
Rym: Exactly six times.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: Yeah, they use them all the time.
Rym: They gotta do something about that, especially considering that traffic in New York City is literally the worst it's ever been in history right now.
Scott: I mean, listen, it's like, yes, I agree.
Scott: Technically, you know, you're not supposed to be using, you know, that vehicle should be in the driving area and not in the, but, you know, you're right.
Rym: I'm totally cool with it, but gas-powered two-stroke engines should not be in that space.
Scott: Yeah, of course, you're right, but that problem is so insignificant compared to the real problem, which is, right, that person is there not because you're punishing that person, it doesn't help you, right?
Scott: You need to, the only, because you need to, that person is there because a car has pushed them there.
Scott: They feel safer in there than they do over with the car.
Rym: So, the problem though, so...
Scott: Punishing them does nothing, right?
Rym: So, here's my, these are not...
Scott: Even if cops were good and were, you know, it's like, there's no point.
Rym: So, here's the thing though, these are not, like, these instances, I'm not talking about, like, little putt-putt, like, the kids... Yeah, I know, yeah, I know.
Rym: But what happened to me three times just recently, one of them was on my home just now, it was a full-size motorcycle honking and, like, driving fast on that bike lane.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but that, if the cars, if the cars were lessened, that person wouldn't be there.
Rym: I don't know, actually.
Scott: I don't blame that person.
Scott: That's such a small, insignificant problem compared to the... How many lanes of cars are over there?
Rym: Well, you gotta get rid of all those lanes of cars.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: That's the real problem.
Scott: I'm not gonna go be blaming, like, this, you know, sort of side effect.
Scott: That's, like, one motorcycle guy when there's thousands and thousands of cars right fucking there, right?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But it is a very narrow path.
Rym: Granted, that'll be a little less bad when they actually make it bikes only and get rid of the pedestrian access, which is supposedly coming this year.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But, yeah, no, I mean, there was actually two, two, some things going around recently.
Scott: One of them was, like, look, you know, evidence shows in this, you know, one study each, but, you know, whatever.
Scott: One study was, like, yeah, increasing cop enforcement doesn't actually reduce the number of crashes.
Rym: Oh, yeah, because I saw a bunch of other articles talking about that.
Scott: And the second one, the second one was, like, actually camera enforcement.
Scott: that's on all the time and just tickets.
Scott: every single person does.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, even from a naive analysis, think of it this way.
Rym: What percentage of people who are flagrantly violating very objectively easy to observe traffic rules like running stop signs and red lights don't get ticketed because there is an absolute enforcement.
Rym: So the odds are you'll get ticketed so infrequently that there's no deterrent effect.
Scott: So this is why I say you should defund the police, which don't increase safety.
Rym: Like I said, every stop sign and red light in New York City should have 100 percent enforcement with no exceptions via technology, and the police should not be able to chase anyone or interact with someone in person for those violations.
Rym: They're just mailed tickets.
Scott: And the penalties should not be just these fines because a fine is a price.
Scott: It means a rich person can still do it.
Scott: The penalty should be you're not allowed to drive ever again and we confiscate all your cars and you're not allowed to buy a car.
Scott: And if we catch you driving, then we kill you.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Something really horrible that would make you... I don't know.
Scott: I don't know what to do about someone who has lost their license and drives anymore.
Rym: This is something, I don't know if it's still true, but I remember growing up in Michigan, most people who were getting pulled over for drunk driving had suspended licenses for drunk driving.
Rym: And they just keep driving and no amount of consequences will stop them from driving short of putting them in jail.
Scott: Well, I mean, that's the fault.
Scott: They're living in Michigan.
Rym: Take away their car, they get another car.
Scott: Yeah, that person, it's not their fault.
Scott: I mean, they shouldn't be drunk driving, but it's not their fault.
Scott: The fault is they're stuck in a place where if they don't have a car and drive, they can't go anywhere.
Scott: But they also choose to drive drunk so frequently that they get pulled over repeatedly.
Scott: So any consequence that you administer by pulling them over or ticketing them is not worse than the consequence of you can't go anywhere.
Scott: So in order to make them, it's like you either have to make it a place where they can go places without the car, then they'll be like, oh, OK, why would I, you know, there's no way to go anywhere.
Rym: We'll just get on that with a deadlocked impossible to change Senate and the 40 years of infrastructure investments necessary to do that, even just in the orbit of major cities.
Scott: If you had some fucking guts, like some people from Texas have some guts, right, then maybe something would happen.
Rym: Yeah, actually, that's the news we could talk about.
Rym: So if you're not aware, American politics is, of course, super fucked up.
Rym: We basically have fascists on one side and a coalition.
Scott: It's been super, I mean, it's been super fucked up.
Scott: It's just, you know, there's more realization and, you know, consequences of the fucked upness happening.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But one thing that's happened specifically.
Scott: At what point was it not fucked up?
Rym: And recently, and this is this is kind of an amazing, this is the kind of thing that, you know, when people say a lot of Americans who are on the left and the reasonable positions also don't understand our government that well.
Rym: So they'll get mad.
Scott: People in general don't understand our government that well.
Rym: Why doesn't Pelosi, the Speaker of the House, do X or why doesn't the president, Joe Biden, do Y?
Rym: And usually the answer is that's not actually within their powers.
Rym: That's not something they can do.
Scott: It's within their power if they act in a Trumpian way and just ignore what's within their power and do things anyway.
Rym: No, no, no, because there's a fundamental problem there.
Rym: The Trumpian way was usually preventing something from happening or making something happen badly.
Rym: Making something actively happen is usually not possible.
Rym: And that's sort of the word, which is so happens that the bad side in America almost exclusively wants to prevent things from changing or break things.
Scott: So we can let's at least find the things that we want to stop from happening and stop them from happening.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: And that's actually I think Biden signed more executive orders than like any modern president.
Rym: But when people say like, oh, why don't the Democrats do the crazy option?
Rym: They kind of already are in in many cases where like the crazy option, they're doing as much as they legally can.
Rym: And they're not at the point where they're going to start throwing bricks.
Rym: So in the state of Texas, which is a fucked up state that was formed due to a land grab where we basically stole a bunch of land from Mexico in order to protect slavery and the Alamo is a farce.
Rym: But I digress is going to pass extreme voting restrictions, like the kind of voting restrictions that arguably end democracy in Texas and threaten the ability of like a Democrat to ever win a statewide election and all sorts of nonsense.
Rym: The Democrats in the state legislature of Texas are doing the crazy thing.
Rym: What they did is they fled the state.
Rym: They went to D.C.
Rym: and they're in hiding.
Rym: So now the state legislature cannot have a quorum to vote on this bill.
Rym: that will destroy democracy.
Scott: And they also can't change.
Scott: They also can't change.
Scott: They don't have enough people to change the rules about quorums.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: So the consequence of this, though, is that those Democrats will be arrested if and when they ever return to Texas.
Rym: The governor has actually ordered their arrest because their governor is a super piece of shit fascist who really wants these voting restrictions to be in place.
Rym: So that is the level of politics we've got going on in America right now.
Rym: I'm not going to give you the play by play on that whole story, but I highly recommend you read about that in particular, because that's what you do.
Scott: You could do a similar thing in the U.S.
Scott: Senate if you, you know, some Republican senators just couldn't find their way to the Senate somehow.
Scott: There just happened to be, what is it, 10 we need missing?
Scott: 10, I think, to get 60?
Rym: So it's a little bit.
Rym: Quorum in the Senate is a little more complicated, but you need, you may effectively need 60 affirmative votes to bring something forward.
Scott: Right.
Scott: OK, so you got, you got what, at least 48.
Scott: So let's get let's get 12 just to be safe.
Scott: 13.
Scott: How hard is it for 13 old white dudes to have a hard time?
Scott: How hard can that be to arrange when you say command the largest military on earth and a secret service and, you know, let's actually, people always spread these conspiracies.
Scott: Why not do a real one?
Scott: If you can have a CIA start a bunch of revolutions, everyone know you've done it, but there's no consequences.
Scott: Oh, well, have a CIA, you know, delay 13 old white dudes.
Scott: Everyone knows you did it, but no consequences.
Scott: Same thing, right?
Rym: Wait till they wait till they go poop because they probably all poop at the exact same time every day.
Scott: That's way less bad than overthrowing countries that aren't even your country.
Rym: Just telling you, wait till they poop at their scheduled time and lock them in the bathroom.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: But yeah, if you live in America and you're not in Texas, your local politicians, they're the ones you can pressure to do this kind of shit, because usually there are a lot more interesting loopholes to exploit at the state and municipal level than there are at the federal level.
Scott: And of course, in the exact spot where I live, every single small representative that I have is already about as left as can be.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I'm represented in the state by outright socialists.
Rym: I mean, even at the federal level, Maloney, my rap, not the most progressive, but also going hard against the Republicans.
Rym: Like, she's not bad.
Scott: Well, she's one of those, well, you know, she's one of those ones where, you know, she sort of goes with, she went with the flow, right?
Scott: She saw things moving to the left and she moved to the left.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I don't care why someone gets there.
Rym: They just got to get there at this point.
Scott: We're still voting against her in the primary.
Rym: Oh, of course.
Scott: I mean, I will always vote for- We have an actual, there's an actual socialist who's trying to primary.
Rym: I will always vote for the most radical progressive in any primary, because why not?
Rym: Worst case, they don't get the nomination.
Rym: And also, as the number of people who vote that way in the primaries grow, that pulls the rest of them a little bit further.
Scott: But there's no point in me calling any of my at least smaller rep- I mean, I guess I can call the state senators.
Rym: They need- But that's the problem.
Rym: We live in, like, if you live in a state that's doing okay, you have no influence on the federal government because a senator in America from a state you don't live in not only gives zero fucks what you think, but if you call them, they will use the evidence that people from out of state are calling them as an excuse to ignore popular will and actually do the thing that's unpopular.
Scott: Well, it's like, even if- and it's like, what?
Scott: If I call Schumer, what?
Scott: He's like, "Okay,
Scott: yes.".
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: No, I think I wrote a letter to Schumer a while ago.
Rym: I was mad about, like, something.
Rym: I wanted a January 6th commission, and his response was basically, "So do
Rym: I!".
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I co-sponsored all these things that you want.
Rym: Here you go.
Scott: Keep voting for me.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And before anyone says, "Well, why don't you move to West
Rym: Virginia?".
Rym: No one should have to move to a shitty place to make the place they live better.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Anyway, you got some news about bowling balls, it looks like here.
Scott: I do.
Scott: So apparently, in New York, you know, people- I don't know if you haven't heard about the world of recycling, right?
Scott: But there's plenty of exposés out there.
Scott: you can read about the realities of recycling in various places and how a lot of stuff you recycle just ends up in the trash, et cetera, et cetera, right?
Scott: You know, industry is really responsible for climate change more than we are, et cetera, as consumers, yada, yada.
Scott: But this particular story, right, was quite interesting from a different angle, is that at the recycling center in New York City, a few bowling balls show up about every day.
Scott: Just a few bowling balls a day, so like 1,000 something, 1,200ish balls a year, they get there, right?
Scott: People think they can recycle a bowling ball.
Scott: You got this bowling ball, right?
Scott: Maybe it's broken, maybe you just don't use it anymore, you can't sell it, you can't give it away.
Scott: And, you know, you feel bad just throwing it out because it's such a large, heavy, not necessarily inexpensive object.
Scott: And it's like, so you recycle it to feel better about yourself, but they can't fucking recycle the bowling ball.
Scott: So they got too many fucking bowling balls there.
Scott: And then, so it's like, I just think that's really fascinating because it always reminds me of my often repeated anecdote about the bowling ball, where you, my friends that bought the bowling ball, you think you're gonna get involved in some hobby, right?
Scott: And then you don't, and now you've got this hobby equipment that you bought that you don't use, right, lying around.
Scott: And I always say, you know, don't buy a bowling ball.
Scott: If you're gonna buy equipment for your hobby, make sure you're actually gonna do that hobby and you're not just gonna buy a bicycle and not ride it.
Scott: That would be a bowling ball, metaphorically speaking.
Scott: And here's literal bowling balls showing up at the recycling center, three a day, right?
Scott: So people are making this mistake en masse, right, of buying hobby equipment and not using it.
Scott: And yeah, it was fascinating because in the article I learned about bowling balls and how, like, the ultra bowling balls, like, only get so much use, like, the ultra pro ones.
Scott: And there's one, like, there's really good ones, but they crack, so the pros keep going through ball after ball.
Scott: How they make the bowling balls without holes and then, you know, you buy a bowling ball with no holes in it and then they drill the holes for you, right?
Scott: So then it's like, well, now it's got the holes in it.
Scott: You can't, like, give it to someone else.
Scott: It's your ball, now it's for your hand.
Rym: Granted, I just used alley balls.
Rym: They were fine.
Rym: Not that I was a particularly good bowler.
Scott: Yeah, I used those too.
Scott: I've never owned a bowling.
Scott: My parents owned bowling balls.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I never owned one.
Scott: But I was thinking, right, oh, what if I went to that recycling center and I got the bowling balls?
Scott: They're basically gonna give it to me for free, right?
Scott: The problem with recycling is that they can't sell the stuff to anyone, right, at a reasonable price.
Scott: But I could get the bowling balls, three bowling balls a day, and then I bet I could set up an installation at some museum or gallery.
Scott: that's, like, a mountain of bowling balls.
Scott: Right?
Scott: And it would have so many meanings to it artistically, right?
Scott: You know, it's like, you know, the story that I tell of the bowling ball, you know, the trash.
Scott: I'd be like, this is how many bowling balls are attempted to be recycled each year, right?
Scott: Look at how many there are, 1200 bowling balls and a pyramid, right?
Scott: Whoa, right?
Scott: It would also be fucking cool, bowling ball pyramid.
Scott: All the different balls, all the different colors, you know, that were involved in it, right?
Scott: Maybe I could mix some pins in there, you know, who knows?
Rym: I can imagine a lot of uses for it, a lot of bowling balls, many of which are illegal.
Scott: Yeah, it would be sort of like, you know, that Ai Weiwei one with all the bicycles and the big tower, but kind of like that, right?
Scott: So I was like, yeah, I should do that, and then I realized, wait a minute.
Scott: Even if I get a gallery to agree to accept my installation, and even if I can construct the installation, right?
Rym: What, are you gonna bike over there on a city bike and pick up three bowling balls a day?
Rym: So you set one in the front of the city bike.
Scott: Even if I get it, I imagine like, okay, I get a mini storage container, right?
Scott: And I put three bowling balls in it, then I put six in, and eventually what?
Scott: They're so high that when I open the container, they fall on me and I die.
Rym: But Scott, that, that moment when they find your body is the true installation.
Rym: That's the art.
Scott: It'd just be me at the mini store with the open door buried in bowling balls with my body bruised severely.
Rym: And the exhibit is called the individual responsibility.
Rym: That is exactly, that the individual trying to take responsibility for these massive problems as opposed to systemic solutions will in fact just kill the individuals and not solve the problem.
Scott: Yeah, there was, I also saw a tweet today that showed a, like a mudslide in California or someplace, and it was a Prius was being washed away in the mudslide.
Scott: And it's like, it's like, yep.
Scott: And you know, you buying the hybrid or electric car is not going to make up for to solve the climate change.
Scott: You know, everyone having no car that will solve it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Even honestly, even just having slightly better mass transit in like the four biggest cities in America would have a measurable impact.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Anyway, so that was it.
Scott: It was just an article about a small, fascinating article, but it, yeah, it has a, there's a lot to say.
Rym: I didn't know about those reactive balls at all.
Rym: And that's, that's like, that's a whole topic.
Scott: It spoke to me personally, this article.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Not that I ever particularly want to bowl again.
Rym: I feel like most people who end up bowling in America in the year of our Lord 2021 are there because someone else thought a bowling party would be a good idea and everyone showed up because no one wanted to say, no, we don't like bowling.
Scott: Or in the bowling league.
Scott: There's bowling league people.
Rym: Yeah, but I don't feel like that is a growing hobby.
Scott: I'm not sure.
Scott: It seems, hold, hold and steady.
Scott: I would guess.
Rym: Ping pong was rising for a while, but it seems like it hit its plateau.
Rym: Anyway, and some other news, this is kind of relevant to our main bit, but a doctor in Napa got in California was, it looks like the DOJ went after them.
Rym: Because they were faking vaccinations.
Rym: Now this isn't like someone who just like prints out an image of the vaccine card and writes some bullshit on it to try to pretend they got vaccinated.
Rym: This was a doctor selling vaccination cards that they had filled out legitimately to make it officially look like this person had been vaccinated when they were not.
Scott: So obviously this person was caught and now they're not a doctor anymore.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: This has happened a few times already, but.
Scott: It's Dr.
Scott: Nick out here.
Rym: The reason I want to link to this article is because you got, this is, this is why homeopathy and chiropractic and acupuncture and all that bullshit is so harmful to society.
Rym: You can make a straight line from the deregulation of those industries in the nineties to the rise of fascism in America today.
Rym: Not all the rise of fascism, but like bring an elevation of the rise, like an acceleration.
Rym: Because if you look at this story, which is typical of these kinds of story, you always wonder like, so what does this doctor, are they crazy?
Rym: Do they just think the vaccines are fake and they're trying to help people?
Rym: No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Rym: I'm going to read the, uh, the money line, uh, the say the line part from this article.
Rym: Quote, "The doctor was also accused of selling her patients what she called immunization pellets that she said contained small amounts of COVID-19.
Rym: She falsely claimed that those pills would give people immunity from the
Rym: coronavirus.".
Rym: So whenever someone is doing this kind of crap, they're rarely doing it because they actually believe that the vaccines are dangerous.
Rym: Usually they are selling some sort of supplement or natural medicine scam and this is just part of their marketing.
Rym: This is how they sell this bullshit.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, also, you know, the surgeon general, what, like, uh, today, right?
Scott: Did a whole speech about like, yes, misinformation is really, you know, like a severe problem, right?
Scott: He's like, he's like, the internet company should be blocking it.
Scott: And he wasn't, you know, it's like the, if you read articles about this, you know, they mostly are focusing on the vaccine COVID misinformation, which is, uh, obviously a big problem.
Rym: But it's about everything.
Scott: The surgeon general was talking about all, he said, it's an urgent threat, right?
Scott: All, uh, you know, medical misinformation is an urgent threat to, you know, the safety of humanity, I guess.
Rym: And if you'll take any major right-wing conservative media company in America and look at where they make their money, they've almost all of them eventually come to rest on the same industry, the fake supplements industry.
Rym: Uh, in some other news, uh, that is also directly relevant to what we're going to have more news.
Rym: One more, uh, this is, this is pretty, this is also directly straight up relevant to our main bit, but, uh, it's not actually what we're going to talk about today.
Rym: Uh, so a U S consumer agency, and there's a whole bunch of other lawsuits around this, but there's a big one now, uh, the federal government, the consumer product safety commission is suing Amazon.
Rym: Uh, this is breaking news as of today, like a couple hours ago for, to force them to recall a huge number of hazardous products.
Rym: Amazon has so many products that they're not counterfeits.
Rym: They're not bootlegs.
Rym: This is not like a fake hairdryer that from like a full legs.
Rym: These are just products with brands that you might not recognize because they're not real.
Rym: Like it's a shell company.
Rym: It's, there's probably the same product sold under a hundred different brands, but these are things like carbon monoxide detectors that just don't work.
Rym: Uh, hairdryers that will just kill you if they get wet, like they don't have any safety controls in them.
Rym: Children's sleepwear that says, that says non-flammable, but that are in fact extremely inflammable.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, these are things that technically speaking, uh, customs is supposed to be watching this stuff when it comes in, right?
Scott: Cause almost none of this stuff is manufactured in the U S very, very small amount of it.
Scott: So your customs is, is, is failed here, right?
Scott: They should have turned this stuff away at the port.
Rym: Um, but now Amazon should be doing some control and maybe not letting any wacko sell shit on Amazon.
Scott: Well, I think that's.
Scott: the other problem is even if you go to a place and eat, you know, a store like a Walmart or a target or a best buy, they're not good stores.
Scott: They're just, they're evil also, but they won't have just, but every, everything they sell in those stores, there is a person whose job it is.
Scott: They're called a buyer, right?
Scott: They buy, they buy wholesale goods.
Scott: That's a job you can have.
Scott: It's a fun job.
Scott: I've always wanted it, but it's hard.
Scott: It's a powerful job also because you basically can choose who makes money and who doesn't.
Scott: It's a very powerful position.
Scott: But, um, that person, right?
Scott: If you work at say, if they're the buyer for target, right.
Scott: And they're buying children's clothes, they're not buying the inflammable clothes.
Scott: And if they buy something that will be, that would be the end of them.
Rym: And if they buy something that says non-flammable and it turns out it is in fact inflammable, then they're going to see whoever they bought it from.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Target will see.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Amazon is like, Hey, where we have a website.
Scott: Anyone who wants to sell anything, just sign up at our website.
Scott: Amazon may not ever even see the merchandise.
Scott: It may go, you might just go to the Amazon website, buy something that sends a signal to someone else that someone else mails you something directly.
Scott: Amazon has not seen those goods.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But yet they are now, uh, I guess, you know, what's the word for when you like, uh, aid in a crime, aiding and abetting.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well here, actually I can, I can summarize it.
Rym: The CPSC said that Amazon had to quote, accept responsibility for these dangerous goods.
Rym: Uh, this is, this is some dangerous shit.
Rym: If you read the article, Amazon's response was it is unclear why they have filed a complaint seeking to force us to take actions almost entirely duplicative of those we've already taken, which is obvious.
Rym: corporate bullshit speak because, uh, according to CPSC, Amazon's unilateral actions are insufficient to remediate the hazards posed by the products in question.
Rym: I hope the USPC or the CSPC comes down on Amazon like a ton of bricks.
Rym: This isn't just like Amazon should be broken up, but independently Amazon should be prosecuted for even selling these things in the first place.
Scott: In my opinion, there's a lot of things that should be, there's a lot of things, a lot of these companies, almost every, almost every company period that is successful comes through.
Rym: Amazon is complicit.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Almost every successful company ever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Got it.
Scott: Start with crimes and then basically gets it sorted out later.
Scott: Crunchyroll started.
Rym: I was about to bring up crunchyroll.
Scott: It's like, it's like, you know, almost every Uber, they just started out by ignoring every taxi law there was and there's blatant, just ignore all these laws and nobody arrested them for it.
Scott: And then they got enough money and then they became a thing.
Scott: And now you can't like, I feel like you should still like, if I became in a position of power, I would just arrest the CEO of Uber.
Scott: Like you filed, you know, I'd be, if I was a prosecutor, I guess I'd have to be a federal prosecutor.
Scott: and I'd be like, Hey, here's all these taxi regulations you've been ignoring for the entire existence of your company.
Scott: We're going to take you to court over them.
Scott: No, I don't know why nobody's done this yet.
Scott: I love it.
Scott: Regulations still exist.
Scott: You're still ignoring them.
Rym: And we accept this stuff.
Rym: If you go to the Wikipedia page about crunchyroll under history, the first heading is origins and illegal distribution.
Rym: The second heading is move to legal distribution.
Scott: I mean, even small businesses, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, a small business, there's so many laws and regulations and taxes and all sorts of stuff you have to do.
Scott: If you do everything by the book correctly, perfectly, and you're starting like, say a restaurant just out out of the gate, you do everything perfectly.
Scott: Doing everything perfectly costs you so much money.
Scott: You're just done.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you want to start a restaurant, just so I can start slinging food.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And then when the health inspector comes and gives you the F grade and tries to shut you down, then you fix your shit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's how you get a business actually off the ground, which is a problem, obviously.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So and this is why, you know, people get credence when they start making arguments for deregulation.
Scott: They're like, oh, we got to deregulate.
Scott: So people can actually succeed.
Rym: Yeah, but no, if you have deregulation, that same thing will happen.
Rym: But that second heading, the second heading move to legal, that'll never happen.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: The restaurant will just keep operating with rat poop in the food forever.
Scott: It's like you can't.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So following my theme, this video is called This Tent Could Kill You.
Rym: Dangerous Cheap Tent.
Rym: This is one of those things that like should not be allowed to be sold, but yet is sold because it's cheap.
Rym: And because I'm getting into camping again and I had to buy a bunch of new camping stuff, these things are front of mind because I know about camping equipment.
Rym: I understand like the risks, the dangers, what you need.
Scott: You watched a bunch of YouTube videos about it.
Rym: Well, no, I also grew up camping a lot.
Scott: The people who made those YouTube videos know about camping equipment.
Scott: You just watch YouTube videos.
Rym: Well, I also learned this as a kid from like my Cub Scout, like den leaders and everything.
Rym: And yeah.
Scott: OK, how much time?
Scott: OK.
Rym: Not I mean, some of those things haven't changed much.
Rym: You know, it's changed since I was a kid.
Rym: And now, one, people tend to use bear canisters instead of hanging their food from a tree because the ladder doesn't actually really work that well.
Rym: Two, tents are just better.
Rym: Like they're so much better.
Rym: If you have an old tent, literally throw it away.
Scott: That was the thing in old movies.
Scott: You'd always see someone struggling to set up a tent.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And I never understood it because I never set up an old shitty tent.
Scott: I only ever set up a pretty good tent in my life.
Rym: Water purification, so much better.
Rym: When I was a kid, it was put you put iodine and bleach into the water, then drink it.
Rym: It tasted like shit.
Rym: It's so much better now.
Rym: But this video is a 10 minute long video that takes one of these cheap, no brand, like bullshit fake tents that I wouldn't blame an on expert for buying.
Rym: Kind of like a bike.
Rym: How are you supposed to know a Huffy is a piece of shit if no one told you and you don't know a lot about bikes?
Rym: You go you go to go to Amazon.
Rym: You see that huffy and you think, oh, I need a bike.
Rym: The specs are good.
Rym: They read this box.
Rym: All right.
Rym: This is a tent.
Rym: It's waterproof.
Rym: It says I can camp with it.
Rym: I'm going to buy it.
Rym: I'm going to camping.
Rym: And this tent is dangerous for like so many reasons.
Rym: This tent is just like a death trap and it is terrifying that it is allowed to be sold by anyone.
Scott: So what do you got?
Scott: All right.
Scott: So every I think it's every year, if I'm not mistaken, there is a person in New York City who is called the public advocate.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're basically they're.
Scott: it's.
Scott: they're a weird.
Scott: it's a weird position to be in because basically you're not the vice mayor.
Scott: You're not the deputy mayor.
Scott: But if the mayor goes down, you're next.
Scott: And at the same time, you can submit, you know, bills to the city council to vote on.
Scott: But you can't vote on shit.
Scott: You can just be like, hey, you guys want to make a lot of this.
Scott: It's an idea I had.
Scott: You're also.
Scott: generally I've the public advocate is like sort of the opposite of the mayor.
Scott: Like everyone just loves the fuck out of them.
Scott: Usually I've never seen people say bad things too much about any of the public advocates I've had.
Rym: I think part of it is that public advocate is a position like in New York City in particular, where progressive activists who tend to also vote in primaries and vote in elections regularly care a lot.
Rym: And conservatives, but also uninvolved people don't think about it or even know it exists.
Scott: Anyway, so one of the things the public advocate does every once in a while, I think it's annually, is they release a list of the fucking worst landlords of the city, just like a ranking.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's sort of fun, but it's also true.
Scott: So this dude made this, I guess, his YouTube channel says Jeff seal.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I assume that's the person's name.
Scott: They made a three part documentary.
Scott: It's like a full on movie, basically.
Scott: It's very Michael Moore, old school style.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I like that style.
Scott: Not that old, not sort of the, not sort of what Michael Moore became over time, but more of his original kind of deal where he goes to find these landlords.
Scott: So in the movie, in the movie, you know, he's got, he's looking at the, he's going to the tenants.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then he's trying to, you know, confront the landlords.
Scott: And then he sneaks into the landlord convention.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And so the landlord convention.
Scott: So, um, yeah, if you want to get mad about how it's legal for someone to own proper, you know, own land period, uh, and, you know, charge people for shelter, which is necessary for life.
Scott: Read about the term rent, then, and then to also do a bad job of it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, you know, it's like, it's one thing to be a landlord.
Scott: It's another thing to be a bad lid.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Like slum lord on purpose.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: So you can watch this, uh, pretty good documentary here and get, get mad.
Rym: I'm uh, I'm already mad.
Rym: The only reason I even I'm okay with my landlord is that I do prefer a corporate landlord as opposed to an individual person because I have found generally individual people who are doing it as an investment tend to be way more like weirdly aggressively shitty companies are a little more afraid of being sued if they're big enough or a little more.
Scott: like after the show, I'll tell you something quick about my landlord.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, in the meta moment, still reading the, uh, tale of Genji, uh, Genji continues to sleepwalk through life and, uh, yeah, I would have made some different decisions from what.
Scott: it's the first novel ever written by any human being in the history of literature period anywhere on earth.
Scott: The first novel, we still have it.
Scott: We, you know, of what, what there is of it.
Scott: We have all of it.
Scott: You can read it.
Scott: We're reading it.
Scott: It's translated into our language so that we can read it.
Scott: Um, supposedly if you were a Japanese person reading it in Japanese, it would be sort of like reading Shakespeare.
Scott: Like it's a really old style language, you know, so it'd be as hard as an English, you know, someone who speaks current English, like some teenager trying to read Shakespeare.
Scott: They're going like, what the hell are they saying?
Scott: It's that kind of thing.
Scott: Uh, but thankfully it's in English.
Scott: Uh, and the English translation is actually easier to read than a Shakespeare depending on which one.
Scott: Um, so yeah, it's just long.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And we will be live.
Scott: We're still going there.
Rym: This weekend on Saturday at 1 45 PM Eastern time in the PAX 2 Twitch stream with an all new Atari game design panel that we recorded a while ago.
Rym: We gave it to PAX.
Rym: Uh, if you like the overlay and like the aesthetic of the panel, let me know.
Rym: Cause I made that myself.
Rym: PAX didn't make that for me.
Rym: Uh, I spent some time on that.
Rym: I'm kind of proud of it.
Rym: Uh, if you don't like it, speaking, tell Scott so he can make fun of me.
Scott: And, uh, speaking of packs online, you know, it's happening right now as we speak, if you're watching this live, you're not watching this live.
Scott: Well, there's going to be VODs of PAX East online.
Scott: So you're, you're, you didn't miss anything.
Scott: Uh, but there is a few things.
Scott: Number one, the keynote, which I didn't watch yet.
Scott: I'm going to watch.
Scott: the VOD was by the CEO of Jackbox.
Scott: So I'm assuming that's a great keynote.
Scott: I just based on that alone and I'm going to check it out.
Scott: Uh, I might be wrong though.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: Maybe the CEO of Jackbox is a boring person, but I guess that's possible, but it seems unlikely.
Scott: Tonight, Thursday the 15th at 8 PM Eastern time, uh, you may also have to watch a VOD of this too, because that's one hour from the time that I'm speaking.
Scott: Uh, is a panel in the PAX2 channel where they are going to rank the best bathrooms in video games.
Scott: I'm going to watch, I'm going to watch that live in an hour.
Rym: That is so good.
Rym: What a topic.
Rym: A plus topic.
Scott: Our panel is Saturday and then the Omegathon final is Sunday and also Saturday.
Scott: Our panel's at 1 45, but it's 7 30 PM on Saturday.
Scott: This is a super art fight at PAX East online.
Scott: Uh, I don't know if it's prerecorded or not, but, uh, if I got nothing to do on 7 30 Saturday, I'm going to be watching that also.
Scott: I put it on my calendar.
Rym: I would bet it's prerecorded based on other things I know, but not sure.
Rym: There are, I think there's a few things that might be live live at PAX.
Scott: Prerecorded or not.
Scott: A super art fight.
Rym: Yeah, a super art fight is always a good time.
Scott: So, yeah.
Rym: Anything you want to foist?
Rym: I had nothing new today.
Rym: No one took me up on Omegathon.
Scott: Oh, we're still foisting?
Rym: If you have something, will you just move on?
Rym: The second dibs?
Scott: Yeah, let's move on.
Scott: I do.
Scott: I'll have things.
Scott: We'll get a dibs next week.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We're, we're getting rid of a lot of baseline stuff.
Rym: before we move on to things.
Rym: I want to start, uh, I got to decide if we call it second dibs officially or call it the foisting.
Scott: It's called second.
Rym: I like foisting though.
Rym: Too bad.
Rym: I like to foist things on people in general.
Rym: So my go-to moves.
Scott: Did anyone get your ogre?
Scott: Does anyone want it?
Rym: No, there are people who will want it and third dibs, but these are people who will only get it when it is a time where we will see them in person again.
Scott: So like, but no, you have not had any second dibs required.
Rym: I have not had a second dibs request for the ogre big box.
Scott: Well, that's a shame.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I do have a backup plan for it though.
Rym: If you want it, like let me know.
Rym: Otherwise someone else is getting it.
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Rym: So counterfeits and bootlegs.
Rym: It's interesting.
Rym: Now what I want to be clear about is what we're not talking about are scams.
Rym: Like things that are just a straight up scam.
Rym: Like on Amazon where you buy one kind of hard drive, they send you a different hard drive.
Scott: I think if we just say what a counterfeit and a bootleg is and just say anything that's not, that is not what we're talking about.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So a counterfeit or a bootleg is when you're at least in the, in the year 2020, we're not talking about, you know, uh, you know, gun and running whiskey up from who knows where that kind of bootleg, right?
Scott: Uh, a counterfeit slash bootleg in the year 2021 is when you are selling, you know, a one good.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But actually you are not getting the good you think you're getting.
Scott: You're getting the good.
Scott: Perhaps manufactured by someone else.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So for example, you tried to buy, I always remember this.
Scott: I was in Israel in the, in the year 2000 and in the store there was a disc man, or was it some headphones?
Scott: It was.
Scott: maybe it was just man with headphones.
Scott: Doesn't matter.
Scott: And it said on the package, literally pass anonic, it literally said, pass anonic, right?
Scott: So that is a bootleg.
Scott: They, they're, you, you know, you trick someone, they think they're buying Panasonic, but you know, if they're really foolish and they don't look closely, I guess they're getting pass anonic.
Scott: So today, this is a much more insidious problem with e-commerce because you are not there at the time of purchase to verify the goods before you hand over the money.
Scott: So, and people are, have gotten wise and they don't sell a pass anonic.
Scott: You look at it and it says fucking Panasonic on it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, uh, and, but act, you know, it's like you would need a really discerning eye to know that it's not what it says.
Scott: it is, that it was not made by the Panasonic corporation.
Scott: That was made by someone else.
Scott: And that it is usually going to be made at inferior quality, right?
Scott: Usually at a lower price point, but not that low, just lower than the official goods.
Scott: Um, sometimes at the same price as the official goods.
Scott: Now you're fooled even more.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And these are the kinds of things that honestly I'm angry about, about this than I am about all the other orthogonally adjacent things we could talk about because this not only could harm the person buying, but it can also harm the person making the real thing.
Scott: It also harms the person.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The person who makes the real thing is harmed.
Scott: The person who buys the thing is harmed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the people selling the thing are probably exploited and harmed.
Rym: Also, it's really just a bad, I got a straight up counterfeit battery on Amazon.
Rym: Once it said Panasonic on it, I bought a Panasonic battery, looked like a Panasonic said it was a Panasonic.
Rym: It, uh, failed on me almost immediately.
Rym: And I tried to do like a return warrant.
Rym: Like I did a service request warranty thing with Panasonic.
Rym: And they were like, that serial number is just fake.
Rym: That's not our battery.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Tough shit.
Scott: Go complain to where you bought it.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Play to Amazon because it's always Amazon.
Scott: It always is.
Scott: Well, partially it's because Amazon, I don't know what the status of this is now, but there was that inventory mixing where they mix all the inventory mixing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So let's say, you know, if they still do this, I'm not aware, but the way it worked was like Amazon sells, I don't know, fucking Panasonic headphone.
Scott: And let's say you have a Panasonic headphone that's mint in box and you want to sell it.
Scott: So you send it to Amazon.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they, you know, don't separate the one you sent them from the legit ones.
Scott: They just mix them all in.
Scott: And if anyone buys one, they might've bought yours.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They might've bought one of the stock ones.
Scott: You don't know, but it's like if they click on the Amazon website on your store, you get the money, but the inventory they actually get delivered to them could be the one you sent them.
Scott: It could be a different one because Amazon's like, well, they're all the same product.
Scott: What does it matter if it's the one Scott sent us or the one that we ordered?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's all the same thing, which is mix them all together.
Scott: And what happened was people sent bootleg things to Amazon and they got mixed in with the real things.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So it didn't matter if you bought them from bootleg store on Amazon when you were looking at the seller and the list of sellers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which you can choose the seller or if you bought them from Amazon directly because the bootlegs got mixed in with the real shit.
Scott: And so, you know, you'd only get.
Scott: you only know you got a bootleg if you if you're the kind of person who can tell the difference.
Scott: It's a big problem in the board game world now.
Rym: Actually, I was going to use that as a news on our next Tuesday show because there's a big there's big movements in the counterfeit board game market lately.
Rym: There's a bunch of news around that.
Scott: But yeah, board games.
Scott: People just be like, you know, at the factory, it's like, OK, we know we're printing out these board games and we notice we're selling a lot of them.
Scott: We're sending a bunch of these over.
Scott: It's like, well, it's just a bunch of JPEGs.
Scott: Let's just print them in this other printing facility, lower quality, cheaper and sell those.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So we don't care about the intellectual property law or even just, you know, I have a factory that could make board games, download some scans of a game that's popular and just start selling the game.
Scott: Yeah, just like people go online and they don't know that much about the board game world.
Scott: They're not super fans.
Scott: They just type in this game.
Scott: They want to buy.
Scott: They see my listing.
Scott: They click.
Scott: They see the prices lower on this site.
Scott: They click buy and they end up with a copy that had was not made by the person who actually made the game.
Scott: The person who actually made the game made no money on this transaction.
Scott: The money went to this other person and the person who bought it got an inferior copy.
Scott: That's not as good as the legit one.
Rym: I remember when I was in high school, I got a counterfeit 20 dollar bill, like just like I had a counterfeit 20.
Rym: And I wasn't sure I was debating what to do with it.
Rym: And from what I could tell, if I had reported it to the government, they would have taken it and I would have been out 20 bucks.
Scott: The Secret Service handles that.
Rym: What I did, statute of limitations I'm assuming has long expired, is I just used it somewhere knowing it was a counterfeit because I didn't want to deal with it and I didn't trust that I would get my 20 dollars back otherwise.
Scott: I mean it's entirely possible.
Scott: I guess I get most of my 20s from ATMs, but it's possible.
Scott: I could have gotten one which is very unlikely to be counterfeit.
Scott: It's possible.
Scott: I could have gotten one as change somewhere that happened to be counterfeit and then used it because it's not like I'm fucking checking.
Scott: But I've never knowingly had one that wasn't just like monopoly money.
Rym: In high school I had a knowing obvious counterfeit 20 dollar bill that I got somewhere in the course of getting cash from someone or transaction and I had to get rid of it.
Rym: There's really no recourse.
Rym: You're just SOL.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Unless you know you can find the person who gave it to you and be like,
Scott: "Hey!".
Rym: Yeah, they're like, "Oh, it's just in my
Rym: wallet?".
Rym: Great.
Scott: Yeah, well you report them, they're the ones who get busted, right?
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But it's interesting because there were some goods over the course of my life where I would maybe get a counterfeit on purpose.
Rym: Not now, but say I wanted a fancy Rolex style watch.
Scott: Fake Rolex.
Rym: Just as good as a real Rolex if you're only trying to impress people who aren't going to look at it too closely.
Rym: To be perfectly real.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I've gone on YouTube and I see these videos comparing real ones to fake ones and they're really close.
Scott: You can see the differences when they zoom in with their jeweler's loops and stuff and show you and you're like, "Oh yeah, I can see that the real one is superior in these
Scott: ways.".
Scott: But it's like if you're just wearing it, you will never fucking know.
Scott: And anyone else who doesn't bring out their jeweler's loop isn't going to fucking know either.
Scott: And the price of the real one is tens of thousands of dollars and the price of the fake one is hundreds or maybe ones of thousands of dollars.
Scott: And that's why I still won't buy the fake one because there's still too much money for just something that only tells time to pay more than I pay for an Apple Watch which not only tells time but does fucking ten billion other things.
Scott: That's ridiculous.
Scott: But it's like, yeah, obviously if you just want the thing that fucking tells time, it's like, sure, there is some legitimacy to the high price of the real Rolex.
Scott: It's a handcrafted, possibly made of valuable gold, platinum, who knows, precise mechanical device and that is indeed worthy of a high price.
Scott: But I do believe the price is perhaps maybe too high.
Rym: But usually too, the kind of person who buys a counterfeit Rolex probably knows it's a counterfeit and is doing it on purpose because that seems like it would make sense.
Rym: Like, oh yeah, here's a Rolex, 500 bucks.
Rym: Nobody thinks that's a real Rolex when they buy it.
Scott: No, I mean, look how many people go down to Chinatown and they buy counterfeit handbag, right?
Scott: And it's like, why?
Rym: If you follow the guy who's just buttering Rolex, Rolex, Rolex under his breath, you know exactly what you're about to do.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the thing is the counterfeit handbag is like people buy it because it's like you can't go to the real store and get a hand.
Scott: They want a handbag that looks like that, that is in that shape, possibly with that logo on it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the real store only has one at real price.
Scott: So you go to a shady place and the counterfeit handbag holds things just fine.
Scott: There's nothing wrong.
Scott: It's not like a counterfeit battery that explodes on you or doesn't work.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's that the legitimate good is ridiculously overpriced.
Scott: You know, it's like, yes, they deserve some money for the design they've done.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the work they've put into marketing their, their trademark value.
Scott: It's like, there's a reason you want their brand.
Scott: They did work to make their brand what desired.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they deserve some compensation for that.
Scott: But do you deserve $10,000 for a fucking bag?
Scott: No.
Scott: There's no bag on earth.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That is just a bag that doesn't like, I don't know, clean your kitchen for you.
Scott: That should cost $10,000.
Scott: Now, it's just ridiculous.
Rym: I think we're a lot of like.
Rym: the average GeekNights listener runs into.
Rym: counterfeits is especially not as much lately, but before streaming was a thing.
Rym: Anime bootlegs were real common.
Rym: Like there were fan subs.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: Separate bucket.
Rym: Let's just bucket those aside.
Rym: There were legitimate releases which were 20 to $40 per VHS tape, if you were lucky.
Rym: And then there were the like bootlegs that were sold even sometimes in stores.
Rym: that attempt like pretended to be a DVD or VHS box set of an anime, but were just fucking straight up counterfeits.
Rym: And they were usually also very low quality.
Rym: Well, we had that Planetest bootleg that the subtitles just Peter out after the first five or six episodes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Sometimes the bootlegs were, you know, it's like, Hey, you could buy the legit thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which is higher quality.
Scott: And this is just trying to trick you out of your money.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, you could, it's like you could tell one booth at the anime con has a box set for $200.
Scott: When that was still a thing.
Scott: And the other one is a box set for $20.
Scott: And it's like, Hmm.
Rym: I guess what always fascinated me about anime fans in particular in that era was that so many people would buy those bootlegs seemingly earnestly thinking they were legitimate and they just got a good deal.
Rym: Like it was kind of a thing and it always bothered me.
Scott: People don't know.
Scott: That's why bootlegs continue because people don't know.
Rym: But then you look at these things and it's like, wow, that the cover on the DVD box is clearly.
Scott: People don't look closely.
Rym: An 8 by 11 piece of like laser printed paper.
Scott: There, there are some people who know like us, right.
Scott: Who are paying attention to detail.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And like, you know, researching and focusing and examining and whatnot.
Scott: And some people just aren't right.
Scott: They just don't know that you like, you pointed out to them and they're like, whoa, I didn't notice that because they don't look closely.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're not focused.
Scott: They're just sort of, you know, coasting through, uh, you know, this process right without, you know, we're hyper examining every single thing we do.
Scott: I think it's more simple.
Rym: Be if you're, you should be suspicious of something that seems like it's too good of a deal like that.
Scott: Some people aren't suspicious in life in general.
Scott: We're suspicious of everything, even things that are legit.
Rym: Peace and point.
Rym: If I'd like, if I, if an email that I get is even has like the slightest whiff of being a scam, it just gets deleted immediately.
Scott: Today they announced that handheld steam thing.
Scott: And what's our first reaction.
Scott: Is this real?
Scott: That looks like it's fake.
Scott: Right.
Scott: First, first reaction.
Scott: And then it's like, no, it's real.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, it is real.
Scott: Um, but our first instinct is always everything is fake.
Scott: Everything is bullshit.
Scott: That's a lie.
Scott: That's, that can't be real.
Scott: I'm checking this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And not everyone has that that we have and that you can't always get it either if you don't have it already.
Rym: And that's why I definitely separate someone who seeks out counterfeit goods because they're cheaper from someone who unknowingly ends up with a counterfeit good, especially if they paid full retail price for that thing.
Rym: Like that battery.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, yeah, it's like, it's like, and it's buying 70 bucks.
Scott: I was pissed, but it's like the watch in the bag.
Scott: It's like, that's okay.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's like almost legitimate reason there.
Scott: There's another, speaking of the DVDs, another legitimate reason, you know, getting something that's just not available where you are, which isn't an issue anymore with the internet, but it's like we, we would get, you know, bootleg attack the gas station.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But I knew we went in eyes open.
Rym: I am buying a bootleg.
Rym: This is just piracy in a less digital way.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But they were, you know, there wasn't another option though.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like you're providing a certain bootleg service is the only service we can get.
Scott: And in other place, parts of the world, right.
Scott: You know, it's like we're in the New York city, right?
Scott: Legitimate goods of everything are, are basically available here.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Pretty much if we have the money, right, we could go and get pretty much any legitimate good if we're willing to wait in a line at the, at the appropriate store.
Scott: But it's like some people.
Scott: you live in a place, most of the world, you know, even United States, some goods not available, right.
Scott: The thing you want, you can't get it.
Scott: It was a limited thing.
Scott: It was a, you know, even, you know, it's like, yeah, you would need a ridiculous amount of money to get it where you are because no one ships it there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, and if someone's making a bootleg one that functions, right, then it, you know, I guess if it doesn't, it doesn't function at all, that's, that's not good for you, but it's like, yeah, bootleg one's the only one you're going to get.
Scott: It's like, okay, that's why wouldn't you do that?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Rather to have nothing.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Because it gets into sort of this broader, like there's another topic for a future.
Rym: show around things that are not technically bootlegs.
Rym: They're just knockoffs, but they're not violating any laws otherwise.
Rym: They're just a knockoff of something.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So for example, you could, right, I've got here a Shure SM57 microphone, right?
Scott: So let's say I live somewhere where I can't just order one online easily.
Scott: And I want a microphone.
Scott: Well, it's like there could be a microphone that looks a lot like this and says Shure SM57.
Scott: On it, but it wasn't made by the Shure corporation.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And how, you know, there might be another one that looks like this and functions like this, but doesn't say Shure on it.
Scott: It just says like microphone on it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They just maybe copied the design or something.
Scott: And then there could just be like, I don't know, some other microphone.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like, which one do you buy?
Scott: The legit one isn't available.
Scott: And the legit one, if it was available, would be the most expensive.
Scott: If you don't need the legit one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, I guess, you know, the one that says Shure on it has some questionable questionability to it.
Scott: Because they're sort of, you know, right.
Scott: Taking advantage, you know, the Shure corporation could arguably be be harmed.
Scott: They're definitely legally speaking.
Rym: That's the last point I want to touch on with brands.
Scott: Morally, morally gray area.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the other two, it's like, what's the moral gray area in the other two?
Scott: It's like, you know, you know, hopefully that you're just you just need a microphone.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Does this one work?
Scott: It's like, OK.
Rym: Ooh, the listener actually had a really good.
Rym: They framed this pretty well.
Rym: I actually want to read what they typed here.
Rym: Blah, blah, blah.
Rym: If a movie isn't available anywhere, a pirate becomes a curator.
Scott: Yeah, sure.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But I guess the what this comes down to is that especially with all the other types of scams we're not talking about today and knockoffs and everything, there was a time where brands were almost overrated.
Rym: And then we got to this period where brands are kind of very important now because a brand implies that there is accountability.
Rym: There's someone you the government or you can go after if a product harms you in some way or is inadequate in some way.
Rym: Or if there isn't, like if the brand sucks, at least you can know where that thing came from.
Rym: Like knowing this is a real sure microphone versus a knockoff that looks like a sure microphone.
Rym: That's real important in a society where if I type microphone in Amazon, there's a million things that look like they're complete pieces of shit and no one would know otherwise.
Rym: I'm a professional.
Rym: I would choose to buy the brand that I trust because of that accountability and my trust in that brand.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: I mean, but not accounting for the fact that, you know, someone might put a brand on something.
Scott: that's bootleg, right?
Scott: It's not actually the brand it says it is.
Scott: That's why I say, but forgetting that right back in the day, right?
Scott: In the olden days, probably even within our lives, like maybe the 80s or earlier when something had a brand on it, you knew like it was like almost 100% guaranteed that the that company that with that brand label made that thing.
Scott: Nowadays, right?
Scott: There is legitimate rebranding run rampant, right?
Scott: You buy something and it says a legitimate brand name on it.
Scott: It's sold in the store, the legitimate retail store of that brand.
Scott: It is not a bootleg.
Scott: But that company did not make that thing.
Scott: They bought that thing from some other no name place and they slapped their brand on it.
Scott: Now, ideally, it's like a white label product line.
Rym: Now, ideally, if those are low tier goods, then they're degrading the quality of that brand over time.
Scott: Sure, possibly.
Scott: But it doesn't, it still is like, you know, the brand there is like, yeah, it's the real brand on the, on a product that they're really, that brand is really selling, but they didn't make it.
Scott: So you're not really, it's not really that brand's product.
Rym: They're officially, with a paper trail, vouching for it in some way, which is a step above buying the Sorny.
Scott: Possibly, yes.
Scott: But it's still, it's still not a phenomenon that has always been around.
Scott: I feel like, you know, if you go back, there was a time, you know, in last entry where that rebranding wasn't as big of a thing.
Rym: Or look at cereal where there'd be the generic cereal that is literally the same cereal just without the brand name on it.
Rym: Like that was the era where I would seek out non-branded things because they were the same as the branded things, just cheaper.
Rym: Now I'm almost at the point where not only do I seek out brands that I know and to a degree trust that to a degree, because it's capitalism, you can't really trust anyone.
Rym: But also I honestly, unless something is like bottom tier or like local goods or groceries, like really simple stuff, I buy almost everything if I can direct from the manufacturer or direct from the brand via their e-commerce platform.
Rym: And I really try to avoid buying things from marketplaces of any kind, including Amazon.
Rym: Like when I buy Shure stuff, I buy direct from Shure or I buy it from a company like Sweetwater that like specializes in audio here.
Scott: There are certain specialized retailers out there that have like these, you know, online that have very close, like industry retailers for certain kinds of goods and have very close relationships with the actual manufacturers.
Rym: Like Sweetwater's example, not to like plug them, but that is where I buy audio equipment from.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So for example, like in the camera world, right?
Scott: You have B&H where you shouldn't buy anything from, right?
Scott: I don't, I don't support them, but then there's like Adorama is another one.
Scott: What's another one is the camera store in Chicago.
Scott: I think that's where they are.
Scott: I know, but there's a few of these like online camera stores that have very close relationships with Sony, Canon, Nikon, right?
Scott: Panasonic, Fuji, everyone.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And like those places are only selling legitimate goods.
Scott: They're legit retailers of the thing.
Scott: And sometimes those, those like they'll have their own website, of course, with their own e-commerce, but sometimes you go on Amazon and you'll see that you're actually buying from one of those stores.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that's actually a safe purchase.
Rym: Well, well to a degree.
Scott: You're just giving Bezos money for no reason.
Scott: Why don't you just go through to the real store?
Scott: But also depending.
Scott: You are going to be getting legitimate goods if you do.
Rym: Depending on how much co-mingling of inventory still happens, that might not guarantee your safety.
Scott: No, if you see one of those stores as like the seller, you're actually going to get it shipped.
Scott: It'll ship from that store.
Rym: I don't know if that's true in all cases, to be honest.
Scott: Every time I've done it, I've gotten a package that was clearly from the store, like with their tape on it, not even Amazon's tape on it.
Rym: So that battery had the Panasonic tape on it, which was extra funny, like on the little box.
Scott: But yeah, that's the thing.
Scott: So there are retailers that are like industry retailers that can be trusted to always carry industry goods.
Scott: Like Newegg, for example, as long as you always buy first party from Newegg and not from some other sellers listing things on Newegg, you're going to be getting legit goods.
Scott: Newegg doesn't have, you know, exGA video cards.
Scott: They only have EVGA, right?
Scott: But there could be a third party seller on Newegg.
Scott: You got to go watch out for that.
Rym: But honestly, the best way to go, if you can, is to always buy direct and direct to consumer brands are actually growing in not just like entirely direct to consumer brands are growing, but also brands that previously would make a lot of relationships with retailers and would not sell directly because they were afraid of poisoning that.
Rym: well.
Rym: They've started to sell direct partly to avoid all these problems we talked about because we live in a capitalist hellscape.
Rym: And partly, why even have that middleman there?
Rym: It's not that expensive to run an e-commerce platform if you're even like a middling sized company.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like I'm seeing, you know, like I look around the city, like I was just in Manhattan to go to the dentist and I biked around.
Scott: And it's like, yeah, you know, the stores for like sneakers are still huge, right?
Scott: So, you know, Foot Locker, those kind of places still in business.
Scott: But the lines for the shoes are at the Nike store.
Scott: There was no there's no line for shoes at a Foot Locker, right?
Scott: They don't have that limited edition thing there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But now it's like a Nike store.
Scott: That's like just that didn't exist when I was a kid.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was either Foot Locker or Foot Action USA.
Scott: There was a sneaker store.
Scott: There was not this sort of direct like.
Scott: there was no Reebok store or a mall.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That was that.
Scott: now that's a thing everywhere.
Scott: The brand just has its own fucking store, even brick and mortar for getting the Internet.
Scott: They just have their own goddamn store selling their own goods.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, you're getting the real thing there.
Scott: And people are going to those stores more than going to.
Rym: And I think that is caused by these two things we just mentioned.
Rym: One, cut out a middleman who's just rent seeking, you know, talking about landlords earlier.
Rym: And two, trying to get out of the hellscape of bootleg like the bootleg ecosystem that's growing and growing and growing right now.
Scott: Great example, Apple store.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're just like, fuck this cop USA bullshit.
Scott: Just like an Apple store.
Scott: Done.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Microsoft has the Microsoft.
Scott: Whatever I buy, whenever I buy an Apple thing, I just buy it.
Scott: There's an app.
Scott: There's an app you can get for your any Apple device.
Scott: There's an Apple store app that like does fancy stuff.
Scott: If you walk into an Apple store, like let you buy stuff and just walk out.
Scott: But you can just at home open up the Apple store app and buy any Apple product and then it will show up at your house.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: My laptop, my my laptop, the surface.
Rym: I bought it directly from Microsoft.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: So that's how that's how I do.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are... Now, I found this file and I'm going to subject all of you to it.
Rym: I look forward to whoever recognizes what this is first.
Rym: Hi.
Rym: Just to see.