Rym: It's Wednesday, June 9th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are talking about comic and cartoon merch.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, last night, at almost exactly 3.10 AM, someone very near our apartment put on what I have to assume was a full professional fireworks show.
Scott: You were loud enough to be one.
Rym: It was loud enough to where I was woken up.
Rym: Like, first, I had a dream.
Rym: And in the dream, all hell broke loose, and it turned into a war.
Rym: And I was, like, in a war and trying to escape.
Rym: And then I kind of woke up, and it was so loud that I sat up, and it took me a minute.
Rym: I actually had to think, is that a war?
Rym: The fuck is going on outside?
Rym: And it took me about 30 seconds to wake up enough to recognize that this was not the sound of gunfire, which, if you're not familiar, is very distinctive.
Rym: It was the sound of a shit ton of fireworks.
Rym: Like, holy crap.
Rym: This was a lot of fireworks.
Rym: And this went on for, like, a half hour.
Rym: So I laid there for a half hour.
Rym: I didn't call the cops, one, because fuck the cops, but two, because this has been such a problem in Queens lately that probably thousands of people had already called them.
Rym: There was no point in me calling them.
Scott: It's basically the same problem we discussed with the fart cars, right?
Scott: You know, is there a certain people?
Rym: Both of these things started last year during COVID.
Scott: No, they've always been around.
Scott: The fart cars started before we were alive.
Rym: So I guess the difference is, the fart cars started becoming a lot more common during the quarantine.
Scott: Yes, there has been an upscaling, an escalation, right, in these things in recent times, past couple years.
Scott: But they've always been a thing.
Scott: They're not new.
Rym: But the fireworks, there was some thing that happened, because it wasn't just in New York.
Rym: It was all over America.
Rym: All summer last year, people were freaking out about illegal fireworks everywhere.
Rym: Best I can tell, something happened where a lot of really cheap illegal fireworks made their way to the US, and people could just get them.
Rym: And it turns out, if it's easy to get illegal fireworks, people use them, which honestly, when I was a kid, we went through a lot of hassle to get illegal fireworks and enjoyed them mightily.
Rym: If they were as easy to get when I was a kid as they are now, I would have been a problem for my local community.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, people in our neighborhood growing up had them, but they were, you know, they didn't have that many, right?
Scott: They would just, they'd be like, you know, on their way home from whatever state they would stop at the fireworks store.
Scott: They bought, you know, like maybe one or two of those boxes full of random stuff like the little cardboard tank or, you know, a little spiral tower.
Rym: No, we would go down to Tennessee and get mortars and bottle rockets.
Scott: The disc that spins in the street, you know.
Rym: Yeah, we'd go down and get like the dangerous good stuff from the south and bring it up every year.
Scott: Yeah, but they would get like one box of stuff.
Scott: They wouldn't fill the entire back of their, you know, a truck with like an arsenal.
Rym: Yeah, our big like illegal fireworks shows when I was a kid were like two mortars and about a half hour's worth of bottle rockets.
Rym: And then we'd shoot Roman candles at each other and go home.
Rym: Like it wasn't like this.
Scott: For example, like, you know, someone would come and they'd have a bunch of like the tiniest fireworks, you know, the ones on a string, right?
Scott: They'd have like a shit ton of those and then it'd be like, yeah, I went and I was able to get fireworks from out of state.
Scott: Look at all these.
Scott: I bought a million of the cheapest firecrackers and one M80.
Scott: And you would fire all the little guys and then you would make a small hole in the back in the backyard with the M80.
Rym: And that was the highlight.
Rym: See, most M80s were fake.
Rym: I found like a lot of things that were called M80s were not because if it was a real M80, it's it's like an eighth to a quarter stick of dynamite, depending on how you look at it.
Rym: Like old M80s.
Scott: I mean, regardless of how of whether it was, you know, an eighth, you know, how big of an explosion it was, it was big enough, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, what we do is we take an M80 and we put it in a garbage can that was upside down and launched it into the air in the woods.
Rym: Like that was our our toy.
Rym: Anyway, so that happened and I'm a little tired this morning because I woke it up for a half hour at 3.10 a.m They've never been loud enough to actually wake me up or bother me because I don't mind them that much.
Rym: But they must have been like on our street or like right next door.
Rym: So, yeah, that was fun.
Rym: And other Rym only opening bit news.
Rym: I just want to briefly tell the story of Glamdring the Foe Hammer.
Scott: OK, you and your you and your Foe Hammer.
Rym: I fully admit I'm the only person on earth, I think, who makes this who finds this amusing, except for the person who made the original.
Rym: In 2012, I can't believe was that long ago, The Hobbit movie came out.
Rym: It was pretty good because it had the songs.
Rym: I really enjoyed it.
Rym: The second Hobbit movie was terrible and I didn't even bother watching the third Hobbit movie.
Scott: I only saw the first one, which had good and bad points, and then I didn't watch the other two.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I found it funny that you didn't realize there were three of them.
Scott: And also, I thought that I thought there were only two.
Rym: There should have only been one because the first movie may be two at most because the first one ended when they all get picked up by the eagles in the trees with the fire.
Scott: The way I see it is the books, there were three Lord of the Rings books, depending, you know, we could talk about token stuff, right?
Scott: How they were like, you can, it could be, I don't know, it could be seven books or whatever, but the point is there were three Lord of the Rings books.
Scott: There was one Hobbit book, so there should be one Hobbit movie.
Rym: But the first Hobbit movie got like four fifths of the way through the book, and then they made two more movies somehow.
Scott: I mean, you know, it could have been one long movie.
Scott: The Hobbit book isn't any longer than a Lord of the Rings book.
Rym: But the real sin was there wasn't any singing in the second two movies, which was just like, why even make a Hobbit movie if you're not going to put all the songs in there?
Rym: Like, come on.
Scott: You sort of, that was the one, you know, that singing, the beginning of the first movie was like the only part that actually captured the feeling of the Hobbit book.
Scott: And then it's like, okay, they're trying, I can see what they're trying to do, and then they abandoned it.
Rym: When they sang, they cracked the pots, cracked the plates and banged the pots or whatever, that song, I got legit fucking excited.
Rym: And when they sang that Misty Mountain song, I got chills.
Scott: They should have kept that feeling going for the whole fucking movie, and then that's the whole movie.
Rym: Yeah, you didn't give me any tra-la-la-la-lolly here down in the valley, like what, what the hell?
Rym: But almost immediately after the Hobbit came out, someone who is now gone, as far as I can tell, made a YouTube video that they just called Fauxhammer.
Rym: And it was basically the video that I'm going to link to because I found it really funny.
Rym: No one else did.
Rym: I think I even linked to it on the GeekNights.
Rym: In fact, I did.
Rym: I found, I linked to it on the old GeekNights forum long ago.
Rym: It disappeared.
Rym: It got taken down for copyright at some point.
Rym: And the YouTube account that uploaded it also got taken down, and it was just gone.
Rym: It is, as far as I can tell, I would love if someone could find this for me or find the person who made the original.
Rym: It disappeared within a couple years of it being made back in like 2012.
Rym: And every now and then I'd remember it, I'd want to reference it or bother someone with it, and I couldn't find it.
Rym: So yesterday, I was like literally playing a Blades in the Dark game, and I remembered it again because I wanted to reference it.
Rym: I searched for it.
Rym: I couldn't find it.
Rym: And I was like, "Fuck it.
Rym: I'm going to remake this thing from
Rym: memory.".
Rym: And I remade this video as shot for shot as I could from my memory.
Rym: It's 36 seconds long, and I uploaded it to YouTube.
Rym: So I have recreated a piece of the internet that was gone.
Scott: Probably inaccurately because your memory.
Rym: Yeah, but I think I got it as close as I possibly could.
Rym: I hope against hope I can find the original and see how good my 2021 memory of this 2012 video.
Rym: that was also stupid shitposting that was made for me and me alone.
Rym: How accurate that was.
Scott: That is a common fun activity I see people doing.
Scott: I see people doing stuff like, "Draw Pokémon from
Scott: memory.".
Scott: It's like, "How good is your memory?
Scott: Draw
Scott: Pokémon.".
Scott: And then when you're done, you look and you're like,
Scott: "Ahh.".
Rym: But it's also hard because, as we know with the Mandela Effect, it is very easy to have a very clear memory of something that is just not true.
Rym: You can remember things that didn't happen.
Rym: So yeah, you can watch Glamdring the Foehammer, and if you don't find it funny, well, yeah, I made this for me.
Rym: Alright, so you got any news?
Rym: It is anime, manga, and comic day.
Scott: Yeah, so there's this auction company, Heritage Auctions, right?
Scott: They got a janky old kind of website, but they run legitimate auctions.
Scott: You know, they're trying to make money.
Scott: They're an auction place.
Scott: They're, you know, exactly what you think they are, right?
Scott: It's the kind of place that would, you know, you imagine this place being run by like a 90-year-old guy selling coins and stamps.
Scott: It's the kind of, that's the kind of deal it is.
Scott: But they got this auction that just started.
Scott: It's got maybe 17 days left, like a couple weeks left.
Scott: And it's full of all sorts of anime and animation stuff.
Scott: Mostly sells, but not just sells, other stuff as well, including like some action figures and some, all kinds of stuff.
Scott: And it has material from things as old as like, you know, Testagen 28, Astro Boy, I saw even one like, you know, ancient manga from 18-something, right?
Rym: Alright, alright.
Scott: And also it's got like Simpson's cells, peanuts, you know, great pumpkin cells.
Scott: It's like Evangelion cell going for a bunch of money already.
Scott: Like there's all the variety of stuff in there and the quality level is like, you know, usually when you look at the cells on sale, like a convention, it's like, you know, it's the back of someone's head.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's that kind of stuff, right?
Scott: Almost all of these are like, whoa, really?
Scott: Where the hell did you get that from?
Scott: You know, it's like, I don't know where this collection came from, but it's on sale and you can bid on it.
Scott: And my strategy is going to be, I'm not paying like $100 for a piece of plastic with some paint on it, no matter who painted it or what that art is.
Rym: Because I have one irresponsible Captain Tyler cell.
Rym: that's really good, but I recall paying what felt like a lot of money for it at the time.
Scott: But hopefully some of these will, there's so many items in this auction, I'm wondering if it's possible that like some of them will go unnoticed and I can be like $1 and just snatch something that no one cares about, right?
Scott: Some of the items, yeah, at the end of the auction, I think the way it works is that some of the items go for live auction, which happens I think in person and on the phone and on the internet.
Scott: But some of them don't.
Scott: Some of them are just like, you know, no one cares about these.
Scott: So it's sort of like internet only.
Scott: And those are the ones that you might be able to sneak out of there for $1.
Scott: Because every single item started at $0.
Scott: Even the ones that are now at like many hundreds started at $0.
Rym: Some of them are still at $0 and are pretty great.
Scott: A lot of them are still at $0.
Rym: Oh shit, this is a really good Sailor Stars sell.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of stuff in there that's like, whoa, but there's so many items.
Scott: Like I went through every single item and you can pick, you can basically watch the ones you care about.
Rym: Alright, the Ava01 losing its shit is already $400.
Scott: Yeah, that's the one.
Scott: I followed that one yesterday and then today I got the, they send you an email that's like, you know, every day you can have a thing that's like a report on all the things you're watching.
Scott: Yesterday it was $0, today it was $500.
Scott: I'm like, unwatch.
Scott: The end.
Scott: There's a perfect blue cell in there.
Rym: Yeah, it's interesting because cells from anime are such a, like, they really only existed for this brief span of time.
Rym: And that's it.
Rym: Like, there won't be more.
Rym: No one's ever going to do this again.
Scott: I mean, there might be like one thing here or there, but, you know.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: Yeah, I got a few.
Scott: I wish they would auction off like, you know, hey, you know, the actual files on our computers at the animation studio, right?
Scott: You know, but, uh, and then it's like, yeah, if you want to share the, you know, if you want to share them on the internet after you buy them, that's on you.
Scott: But we know they're all, they're not accessible on the internet.
Scott: Clearly they're on our hard drives at our studio.
Scott: We'll sell you the, a copy of our like Photoshop file, right?
Scott: You'll be, we're only selling it once.
Scott: You don't need NFTs and crypto bullshit, right?
Scott: Just be like, hey, we have these files on our hard drive.
Scott: We'll sell you the PSD.
Scott: We're only going to ever sell it.
Scott: one time, we promise.
Scott: We'll sign a contract with you.
Scott: We'll send you the Photoshop file and we'll never sell it again.
Scott: And now it's yours to do with what you wish, right?
Scott: That kind of thing.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Thing is, actually, now that we've rearranged the room, the few cells that we own, I'm getting them nicely framed and we're going to put them up and do a thing with them.
Rym: Because the only reason to own one of these cells is if you're going to display it and show it to people.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I have this, I have this space back here behind me to the right.
Scott: that is strangely a conveniently like movie, regular movie poster size, but I gotta, I gotta choose one.
Scott: I got, I have some, but also I could buy a new one.
Scott: Obviously I wouldn't buy an original one.
Scott: I would buy like a reproduction of one, you know, but there's so many choices.
Scott: It's hard to, it's hard to pick just one to go in there.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So in some other news, I'll do a brief Geek Bite on this.
Rym: While it is a live action show, it is an adaptation of a comic that I actually didn't finish reading, even though I was really excited about it.
Rym: We even talked about it on GeekNights.
Rym: Jeff Lemire made fame, I was about to say famous for Essex County, but I suspect that is the thing he's actually least well known for.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Jeff Lemire is just a creative powerhouse and Sweet Tooth, a comic about a hybrid deer boy in a post-apocalyptic world.
Rym: I read the very beginning of it and it was really good.
Scott: And I read the first couple of volumes.
Scott: I have all the volumes except for apparently a newer volume.
Rym: There's one more volume.
Rym: It'll finish in August.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, yeah, it's called Sweet Tooth Returns or something that I didn't realize was coming out is just coming out now, right?
Scott: How many years after the original comic ended?
Scott: I have all the six original volumes.
Scott: I just haven't read them all.
Scott: So I'm going to do that and then I'm going to watch the show.
Rym: So I watched a couple episodes of the TV series on Netflix.
Rym: So far, it's real good.
Rym: And what I appreciate about it the most is I just learned today, one, they make the kid really cute instead of sort of gangly and weird looking like in the comic.
Rym: Like the hybrid kids are just really cute.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, that makes sense.
Rym: But two, the ears are prosthetics.
Rym: They're not composited.
Rym: It's all practical effects, which is kind of cool.
Scott: Well, I mean, at least for that part of it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And three, it's a kind of heavy adaptation.
Rym: Like from what I remember of the beginning of the comic, this leaves a lot out and focuses on different things.
Rym: And that actually gives me a lot of hope, because usually if a TV show like an anime adaptation of a manga, for example, is just exactly one to one, the manga or the comic, those tend to not be that great.
Rym: And I usually would prefer to just go to the source rather than read the adaptation like the Death Note anime compared to just reading the Death Note manga.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, that's the dilemma when you're adapting something.
Scott: Which is why I'm usually like, stop making adaptations, just make everything original.
Scott: Then you don't have this problem.
Scott: But anyway.
Rym: But if the adaptation is loose.
Scott: When you make an adaptation, if you just adapt something 100% perfectly true to the original or whatever came before, it's like, why even bother?
Scott: I just pick one of the choices.
Scott: Like Urasawa's Monster.
Rym: That manga is like one of the best comics I've ever read.
Rym: And the anime is just that, but not in the original format.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And you could also go the route where you change everything up.
Scott: But the problem is a lot of times people change everything up and it's like, ah, you ruined it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You have to, when you're adapting, somehow change things up and not ruin it at the same time, which is, you know, difficult.
Rym: Now, in my experience, like as a reader of things and also working with creative people, I feel like a general rule is the best adaptations are where the original thing wasn't that great.
Rym: But there was good stuff going on and someone takes that and then adapts it and polishes the parts that were good and leaves out the parts that were meh.
Rym: And it ends up diverging further from the source material than a lot of adaptations, but often can end up being better than the original or at least complimentary to the original.
Scott: I always say the best, I think I probably said this before, I say it often, I must have said it on the show at some point, the best adaptations are usually when you adapt Broadway or theater to movies.
Scott: Because you don't have to change much, right, at all.
Scott: And really what you're doing is you're just replacing the single stage with, you know, the limitations of having sets.
Rym: No, Les Mis, that movie, yeesh.
Scott: I don't think I saw Les Mis, the movie, I just saw it in an actual Broadway theater.
Rym: Phantom of the Opera, the movie, yeesh.
Scott: I didn't see that either, I just watched Phantom of the Opera in the theater.
Rym: Alright, well what's a Broadway thing was turned into a movie that was good that you have seen?
Scott: Cabaret is a legendary movie, West Side Story is a legendary movie, I mean there's just so many, Chicago.
Rym: Yeah, but I guess I can think of an equal number of counter examples.
Scott: I'm not saying it's 100% guaranteed, right, I'm just saying.
Rym: Yeah, but so far we get like a 50/50 hit rate with our anecdotal not comprehensive.
Scott: If I bring up my powers of Google, I could probably vastly increase the hits.
Rym: Yeah, but I suspect I could vastly increase the misses.
Rym: The thing is I couldn't use Spider-Man Turn Off the Dark because that was a Broadway thing made from Spider-Man, so that doesn't count.
Rym: Anyway, what I will say, because I don't want to try to trick you again into turning a whole show into a news roundup, but Sweet Tooth seems like it's adapting enough and leaving behind details enough to focus on interesting things to make a pretty good show.
Rym: And so far, the first season is only 8 episodes long and what I've seen I've liked.
Scott: I saw the trailer, it looked good.
Rym: It just looks great.
Rym: In some other news, if you didn't notice, Netflix is for real making a Cowboy Bebop live action series.
Rym: That is actually happening.
Scott: This isn't one of those where it keeps getting brought up but never actually finished and you don't believe it's going to really happen.
Scott: Like, Ava live action, never going to happen, Akira live action.
Scott: These things that people have been trying to do for a long time and never happen and it's just like, whatever.
Scott: Why are you even bothering with that nonsense?
Scott: Or it's not one of those things where they do it and everyone just wipes it out of their mind?
Scott: because it was so terrible, which is obviously going to be from the beginning, like Ghost in the Shell live action, which I didn't even see.
Scott: I forgot it existed until very recently.
Rym: It sucks because I feel like the best case scenario for a live action remake, because this is a special situation.
Rym: Like, Cowboy Bebop is a phenomenal standalone work.
Rym: This is like, if you're a gamer nerd, Chrono Trigger.
Rym: No one made anything like it before.
Rym: No one successfully made anything like it or better than it after.
Rym: It kind of stands alone.
Rym: Cowboy Bebop very much stands alone for a lot of reasons.
Rym: We probably reviewed it back in like 2006.
Scott: Regardless, I feel like what's the reason to do this?
Rym: I don't feel like there is a reason to do this.
Rym: There is a very, very good reason to do it because someone believes they will make money.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, so this doesn't need to be made, but the news about it is actually a very enticing news.
Rym: Yup, Yoko Kanno, one of the greatest composers of modern music.
Rym: Like, Yoko Kanno is a very important person if you somehow don't know who this is.
Scott: The person who made the music for the original, which is a very important part of the original.
Scott: It probably would have been like a B show at best without that music.
Scott: Has been hired to make the music for the live action remake.
Scott: They could have just reused the music.
Rym: I feel like you could have reused it straight up.
Scott: Yeah, just reuse it directly.
Scott: Why even bother?
Scott: You know, Anno made Shin Godzilla and he just reused the music from Ava.
Scott: He didn't make the music, right?
Scott: You know, the same timpani, whatever track that is.
Scott: But they're at least getting the original composer to just make more music.
Scott: And it's like, all right, all right.
Scott: I guess that's something positive maybe, you know.
Rym: Yeah, it's interesting.
Scott: It makes me want to hear the soundtrack to it.
Rym: Yeah, I'm pretty much down for anything Yoko Kanno does.
Rym: It's just interesting to think, too, that Cowboy Bebop was such a phenomenal score.
Rym: Irrespective of being a phenomenal show.
Rym: It was like this intersection of music and writing and acting and like everything came together.
Rym: But like Escaflowne, that was Yoko Kanno music.
Rym: Ghost in the Shell, like Stand Alone Complex.
Rym: Yeah, all that biz.
Rym: Lot of Yoko Kanno in there.
Rym: So I'm still not confident that this will be good.
Rym: I feel like the best case scenario is that it is not so bad that it taints the legacy of Cowboy Bebop somehow.
Scott: Like that somehow is moderately well received.
Scott: I think that tainting the legacy is like not a concern for pretty much anything, right?
Scott: That's something that you see fanboys saying, right?
Scott: Like, "Oh, you ruined Star
Scott: Wars.".
Scott: It's like the originals are unchanged, right?
Scott: And name one thing whose legacy has been ruined, right?
Scott: There's plenty of things that have had shitty adaptations and have had shitty sequels or prequels tacked on, right?
Scott: And the legacy of exactly zero of the good ones have been tainted.
Rym: The things that get tainted are usually because the creator did something shitty in the real world.
Scott: Yes, that can happen.
Scott: But I'm saying there has never been a single quality artwork in any medium that I'm aware of that was tainted because of a shitty adaptation, remake, prequel, or sequel, right?
Scott: If there's a good thing, the goodness of that good thing carries on, right?
Scott: And I can't think of a single example of something that was actually tainted.
Rym: What'll be interesting is...
Scott: Other than by what Rym said, which is the shitty creator, or something else coming out, right?
Rym: The only thing I'm curious about is will people, because there's two things I've noticed as we've gotten older.
Rym: One, a lot of the younger anime fans performatively hate Cowboy Bebop.
Rym: Like, they think it's old person anime, it's edgelord.
Rym: I see young people, a lot of people have seen it.
Scott: Do you have evidence of this?
Rym: Look at the comments on some of our older YouTube videos.
Rym: But more importantly, I did encounter a lot of people in my life who wouldn't watch Cowboy Bebop.
Rym: Mostly people who we would not be friends with, but I encountered in other circles.
Rym: Because they won't watch animation.
Rym: I'm curious if this will get an audience of people who have never seen the original because they don't watch animation, but will watch this because it's hyped and it's on Netflix.
Scott: I mean, I don't think so.
Scott: I think, you know, if you, historically, other things that have been adapted to live action have not gotten... People who are like, you know, the people who have that ingrained attitude that animation is for kids, or, you know, they only want to watch live action things.
Rym: They tend to not like good things in general.
Scott: They tend not like good things in general, yes.
Scott: But also, you know, there have been plenty of live action adaptations of things, and those live action adaptations have either A, not drawn in an audience of newcomers, and have only drawn in an audience of the people who are a fan of the original thing, right?
Scott: And B, have definitely not brought people, you know, I'm not going to say nobody, but have not caused a massive surge of, you know, popularity for the original thing.
Rym: Well, the one difference here, though, is that here it looks like Netflix is actually trying to market this pretty heavily, and I'm curious to see if they do broad-based marketing, like the generic, like, put posters up at subways.
Scott: I mean, Netflix would have to... Netflix, do they even have animated Cowboy Bebop on Netflix?
Rym: I don't know where you'd watch Cowboy Bebop, currently.
Scott: Yeah, because, I mean, that's the minimum that you would have to do, is you would have to have both of them there, and you would have to have Netflix recommend to anyone who watched one watch the other one.
Scott: That would be like the start to even have a chance, right?
Scott: I mean, how many people, you know, watch Lord of the Rings and, you know, or read a game, watch a Game of Thrones, and it's like, sure, that did increase people reading the original book, right?
Scott: But A, it's percentage-wise pretty small, right?
Scott: Even though it does cause a surge, it's not, you know, most people who watch the movie did not go read the book, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, look at Marvel movies, so many people will think, "Oh, I should go read the comics,".
Rym: and then they find out why they don't like comics, at least those comics.
Scott: Yeah, or, right, and that's the thing, is the... and books don't have that sort of, you know, barrier where some adults have a closed-minded attitude about, you know, they don't have some closed-minded attitude that books are for kids, right?
Scott: It's like, so, you could, you know, you see a limited surge for books, you're gonna see, like, no surge for animation or comics from, you know, people with that mindset, but people who don't already have that mindset, right, they might, you know, they might be good.
Rym: But, like, I wonder how Netflix is gonna market this.
Rym: Is that something we don't know, partly 'cause we don't see ads, like, we avoid ads?
Scott: The same way they market all their other stuff.
Rym: Yeah, but who will they target, what kind, where are they gonna run the ads, 'cause sometimes they'll run very focused campaigns, or...
Scott: In the Netflix app, where they do normally.
Rym: Yeah, they also buy, like, subway posters and things, like, that happens kinda often.
Scott: Yeah, we'll see if it becomes subway poster popular.
Rym: I'm curious to see when and how they market it and how well it does and everything, but not actually really curious to watch it.
Scott: Hmm, I mean, now I'm curious to watch it so I can hear the soundtrack.
Rym: Yeah, maybe I can just buy the soundtrack.
Scott: Maybe it's on Spotify, or will be.
Scott: So, tiny little thing.
Scott: The regular one is.
Rym: I forgot about this.
Rym: This was announced in May, about a little under a month ago.
Rym: But, uh, El Hazzard, The Magnificent World, the OAVs, are getting a Blu-ray remastered, like, re-release.
Rym: That is a forgotten show.
Rym: Like, people do not remember that show by and large.
Rym: And, uh, while the TV series of it is garbage, it is not part of this, thankfully.
Rym: Unfortunately, this includes both the first OAV, which is an underrated anime, and the second OAV, which is, just don't watch it, it's terrible.
Scott: Right, it's one of, look, the, what do you know, the TV series and the second OAV, and, I guess, are there movies maybe?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: They have not tarnished the quality of the original OAV.
Scott: How about that?
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah, it's hard to remember, like, just how bad that TV show was for El Hazzard.
Rym: But, uh, I rarely encounter people younger than us who have ever seen, heard of, ever thought about El Hazzard.
Scott: Why would they?
Scott: It was a less than, it was an unpopular, you know, minor show from a long time ago.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It was moderately popular.
Rym: It was part of a boom.
Scott: And, uh, I found this only, I think the only reason it was popular at all is because someone bothered to license it at, like, the right time.
Rym: But, uh, one thing I have found is over my life, whenever I've recommended someone to watch it or shown it to someone, they've always enjoyed it, because it, I'm not saying it's great.
Scott: It's fun.
Rym: It's just, it's, it is underrated and underwatched.
Scott: We did a show on it probably in 2000-something.
Rym: It is.
Rym: Yeah, I'm sure we reviewed it at some point.
Scott: 1078-something like that.
Rym: Something like that.
Rym: But, anyway, things of the day!
Rym: So, uh, you know that Super Mario Brothers movie?
Rym: Like, the one, the live action one?
Rym: The, the, the, the disaster?
Scott: Yes, we know.
Rym: So, there is an extended cut of this movie available, because if you've ever read much about, I'm gonna link to this article that goes into a lot of depth, but it also links to the entire movie with the extended cut.
Rym: Basically, they didn't know what they were doing with this movie.
Rym: Like, the hit, like, the production was just, like, this nightmare.
Rym: And, uh, they filmed a ton of stuff that ended up not getting included.
Rym: They filmed a ton of stuff kinda angling for this to be an R-rated, adult, serious, cyberpunk movie.
Rym: And, uh, most of that got cut out.
Rym: Like, a lot of really dire, weird stuff got cut out.
Scott: I mean, the aesthetic of the movie is weird.
Rym: The thing is, the aesthetic is actually something I love.
Rym: Like, the movie is bad.
Rym: Even though I like some aspects of what it could have been, and, like, the style of it, and the radical adaptation, you know, to follow a theme.
Rym: The reality is, the movie is also boring, bad, unwa- like, it's not worth watching.
Rym: But, uh, what we've got here is, for free, on archive.org, you can watch the entire two hour and five minute long, completely uncut, full filming, where they have spliced in everything that was edited out of the movie into the narrative of the movie.
Scott: The last thing you want to do to any movie, even a good one, is just, it's like, a director's cut is one thing, right?
Rym: This is the Morton Jankle cut.
Scott: Yeah, just undo all the edits.
Scott: It's like, put all the film back together.
Scott: It's like, no.
Rym: Ah, well, because this is not, this is not a, you want a seven hour Lord of the Rings movie, and there's a reason why they cut all that stuff out.
Rym: Like, this is not that.
Rym: Don't watch this to enjoy this as a movie.
Rym: It's not better than the original movie.
Rym: It's in fact worse, because it's longer, that movie's bad.
Rym: But, because it includes all that stuff that was cut, it's almost like a historical lens into the production hell.
Scott: Someone else can watch it.
Rym: There's a bunch of clips of it, and the stuff they cut out.
Rym: There's a lot of weirdly, like, violent, gross, and sexual stuff that they filmed, that they apparently wanted to have in this movie, and were told no.
Scott: Anyway, so, uh, someone named Mel Olivera, right, MelkyCurdy on Twitter, I don't know if that's a famous person I should know or something.
Scott: But they tweeted two tweets, and these two tweets contain a subtitled video that's a few minutes long, showing, basically, it's like a mini-documentary behind the scenes.
Scott: They go to Tatsunoko Productions, where they are, you know, back in the 80s, where they are still, you know, drawing the movie, Matt Cross Do You Remember Love, and they're talking to the animators.
Scott: Like, the first thing they do is they go to Itano, and he's, like, drawing some robot, and they're like, "Hey, what's going on over here,
Scott: Itano?".
Scott: He's like, "Oh, you know, drawing robots,
Scott: right?".
Scott: They go show people painting cells, they show them photographing everything, right?
Scott: It's like, "Whoa, what's going
Scott: on?".
Scott: You know, it's like, this is some kind of thing to see here in color, right?
Scott: So, yeah, you don't see stuff like this too often.
Scott: I wonder how much more material like this is out there.
Scott: that has just been, you know, lost to time and space.
Scott: But this hasn't been, so while these two tweets are still available, I don't know if it's on YouTube or anything, or saved anywhere else, maybe you can, maybe you know how to save Twitter videos, you should get on that.
Rym: I mean, the janky way to save a Twitter video is just to watch it while recording in OBS.
Rym: Like, that totally works.
Scott: I thought about doing that, yeah.
Rym: I have done that two things before.
Rym: Mostly when I need clips from an anime.
Scott: But not to the Fauxhammer?
Rym: Not to, well, for the Fauxhammer, I just pirated The Hobbit movie, and then I pulled out the clips I needed.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway, in the meta moment, we will be live with a, well, it's an old topic we've done before, it is basically a brand new panel with totally different content.
Rym: We'll be live at PAX Online, PAX East Online, I should clarify, 2021, on Saturday, July 17th at 1.45pm on the PAX2 channel, not PAX3.
Scott: We already know the channel, how about that?
Rym: Yeah, we're upgraded to PAX2 with Atari Game Design.
Rym: We're gonna play a bunch of Atari games and talk like real talk game design about those games.
Rym: Some of them are good, some of them are bad, some of them are interesting.
Rym: And a big difference, if you've seen our old panel on this, is we're gonna talk about a lot more single player games.
Rym: In that original panel we did, we focused exclusively on multiplayer games for a reason.
Rym: So we're gonna talk about a lot of different kinds of Atari games in this one.
Rym: Should be fun.
Rym: Otherwise, mostly still stuck at home, but we're going outside a lot.
Scott: Book Club Book is still the first book ever, first novel ever.
Rym: Not the first book, but the first novel.
Scott: Yeah, Tale of Genji, so if you wanna read that, you can get yourself the fully unabridged, you know, properly translated penguin classic Ultimate Edition or whatever.
Scott: And, you know, get reading, 'cause it's long.
Rym: Yep, I feel like my real time to plow through this book is coming soon, because the beach we would go to...
Scott: You said the same thing for how many shows in a row now.
Rym: Yeah, but I've been moving slowly.
Rym: It hasn't accelerated, but it's going.
Rym: But the water temperature at the beach we might go to to just lay and read all day has reached the minimum threshold of "I can touch that water without
Rym: dying.".
Rym: It's 63.1 degrees Fahrenheit as of today.
Scott: How many degrees?
Scott: So are you saying if I get some 62 degree water and splash it on you, you will die?
Rym: If I jump into...
Scott: Like the Wicked Witch of the West.
Rym: So, I think the way I would describe it, if you want me to actually be specific about it, is below that temperature, that is water that I will get up to my ankles in and no further.
Rym: But above that temperature, I will go into that water completely and stay in for at minimum five minutes.
Scott: Okay, so when you're asleep, or when you're not paying attention, I'll get a bucket of water that's more than ankle high, that's 61 degrees, and put both your feet in it.
Scott: Or tie you up and put both your feet in water.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So yeah, otherwise just keep an eye on us, our YouTube channels.
Rym: If you look at my YouTube channel, I just uploaded the Fauxhammer.
Rym: Sometimes we stream games.
Rym: If you hang out in the Discord, Scott does it more than me, and a lot of the listeners will do it sometimes.
Rym: People just hanging out, being chill, streaming a game, couple of people are watching, really just chill.
Rym: fun times.
Rym: Check out the forum, all our other stuff, and yeah, the next time...
Scott: Whichever way you like to internet, we internet that way with you.
Rym: You probably won't see us in person at a con, the earliest con where there is the highest chance that we might be at in person is going to be PAX Unplugged in November.
Rym: Don't expect us, I'm not saying we'll be there, or that it'll happen, but that's the first one that we're even considering right now.
Rym: The way things are.
Rym: But if it happens, and things are safer by then, I'm looking forward to it.
Rym: Otherwise, let's get right into it.
Rym: We're talking about merch today, mostly around cartoons and comics.
Scott: Well, there's obviously the often mentioned phenomenon of cartoons and comics that were created as a vehicle for merch, your Voltrons and whatever.
Scott: So there's just always been this sort of extreme synergy between buying stuff and comic and cartoon art as a tie-in, if not straight, reason for existence tied to those merchandise of various sorts.
Scott: And even today, various anime and comics, even though they are not created the way, say, Transformers was created solely to sell things, but they make most of their money from selling merch.
Scott: They're not making their money from the actual comic or anime itself.
Scott: The money still comes from other things, endorsements.
Scott: And I think it just stems from the fact that if you're doing anything, it doesn't matter your genre or your medium even, but if you design a character that can be drawn as opposed to a real person, that character can now be placed on things.
Scott: They have a logo that can be placed on things.
Scott: They can suit any role for anything.
Scott: They're just always available for any job.
Scott: You don't need to hire them, you just need to license them.
Scott: There's various aesthetics and symbols and a visual language associated with any sort of character.
Scott: Even if you're not going for it, you get it for free.
Scott: And it goes even back, probably even further, but the oldest one you think of is Mickey Mouse.
Scott: You just slap ears on fucking anything.
Rym: I mean, that was the hat, the Mickey Mouse hat.
Rym: It's just two black orbs and a half orb.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: It's the Yamago with two orbs on it that you wear forward.
Scott: And then, we could probably do a whole show, so we shouldn't talk much about it here, but then you have the fan merch thing, which is, I guess it does go way back, but it didn't explode until maybe a few decades ago.
Rym: It's interesting, you can track the kinds of merch that I cared about very clearly by what era of my life I was in, so specifically, and it's so radically different, culminating now in.
Rym: I don't want anything about anything, unless it's a very subtle, small, usually pin or article of clothing at most.
Scott: Yeah, so when I was a kid, I didn't have any fucking money.
Rym: But I wanted this stuff so bad.
Rym: X-Men cards, like X-Men t-shirt, P-Man, everything.
Scott: Right, there were things that I liked, and the amount of merch available was not high, at least not as high as it is today.
Rym: Well, there's a 50/50.
Rym: Some things I liked, the amount of merch I had access to was a cornucopia that overfloweth, because it was a popular intellectual property.
Rym: The only reason I didn't have it all is because my parents, rightly, didn't buy it all for me, and I didn't have any money.
Rym: But then the other half of the things I liked, there was zero merchandise.
Rym: Like, when I was really young, I was really into H.P.
Rym: Lovecraft and Monty Python.
Rym: Wasn't a lot of merch for that stuff, not that that's animation.
Scott: Even if you were a kid who loved Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles, right, it's like you can go to any store, the clothing store, you can get Ninja Turtles clothes.
Scott: You can go to the toy store, you can get everything Ninja Turtles, right?
Scott: Video games, Ninja Turtles, you can get anything, right?
Scott: But, you couldn't get everything because there wasn't an internet shopping, right?
Scott: So like, you could go on TV, and you could see, okay, they got the turtle van, and then you look at the, you would buy.
Scott: like, you know, Leonardo, and you look at the back of the Leonardo action figure, the back of the piece of cardboard, and you would see all the turtle action figures.
Rym: Yep, and you see one that you don't have that you want, but then you go to Toys R Us, it's not there.
Scott: Yeah, you go to Toys R Us, and you'd be like, okay, there's like a hundred, there's like two, you know, five rows of Baxter Stockman's that no one wants, right?
Scott: And you can always get the four turtles, and it's like, you know, there'd be like one shredder left, maybe.
Scott: It's like, you're looking at the back of this package, you're like, I want one of each of these.
Rym: The thing I always wanted was more foot soldiers, because I wanted a bunch of enemies.
Scott: You just wanted to have like 20, you're watching the show, and what are they doing?
Scott: They're fighting like an army of foot soldiers.
Scott: Like, well, listen, if I'm playing, I need like 20 foot soldiers.
Scott: We had one foot soldier.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Well, I was a big fan of the Robocop cartoon, and we had all the goddamn Robocop toys, like those cap shooter things, and there weren't generic bad guys in the Robocop cartoon.
Rym: So we ended up finding, I think when Children's Palace went bankrupt and did a 90% off sale, which, by the way, was a terrifying mob.
Rym: That was, imagine a horde of children literally destroying a building.
Rym: But we found a pile of one random specific villain who had a name from that cartoon.
Rym: There were like 10 of that action figure, so we just bought them all for like 10 cents each, and I used those as my Robocop villains, and that was so exciting.
Scott: Okay, yeah, but, so yes, when we were kids, it's like, pretty much if you slapped, you know, the image of any intellectual property that I enjoyed on a thing, right?
Rym: Nintendo cereal.
Rym: I ate that shit.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't, but, you know.
Rym: The Mario cartoon, I watched it, and I wanted merch from it.
Rym: Irrespective of merch I wanted from Nintendo, I wanted merch from that cartoon because I was a kid, and I was stupid because I was a kid.
Scott: Exactly, I just wanted anything, you know, I went to the store and there were choices of things.
Scott: The thing that had the character on it that I liked was clearly superior.
Scott: I wanted that one, right?
Scott: It's like the thing, and I'm sure that works on kids today.
Rym: Didn't matter what it was.
Rym: I wanted, like, all the cartoons I watch, yeah, He-Man toothbrushes, give it to me.
Rym: Give me two of them.
Scott: Yep, I mean, I see kids today, it's like they're wearing like Minecraft, you know, sneakers.
Scott: It's like, it still works, right?
Rym: As a kid, the thing that bothered me, I wanted clothes, but like, those were the hardest things to find.
Rym: Like, usually Toys R Us and the toy stores wouldn't sell that stuff.
Rym: Like, it was hard to get, like, Kids R Us.
Rym: Yeah, but they didn't have a lot of branded stuff, and usually they'd have a tiny limited selection.
Rym: It was never the thing I was into at the time.
Scott: Anyway, you know, so after that, right, there came a period, you know, mostly towards college times, high school college times, where I had fucking money.
Scott: I was spending most of it on computers and stuff, right?
Scott: And a lot of the places, like the comic book store was out of business by the time I was in high school.
Rym: Yep, by then I knew, like, as much as I wanted X-Men cards, by then I did not want X-Men cards anymore, even though they were plentiful.
Scott: Yeah, I was spending my money on, like, you know, video games, right?
Scott: Things of that nature, computers, you know, and then even when I got to college, I go to comic book stores, I can go to that again, but I was getting comics I was going to read.
Scott: I wasn't, you know, there wasn't a lot of buying stuff that didn't do anything, right?
Scott: It's like, yeah, I would, you know, there were certain intellectual properties, you know, of comics and animation that I liked.
Scott: You know, I remember I bought, there was a Voltron comic that came out in the early 2000s, I have every issue of, right?
Scott: It was okay, but I bought it.
Scott: If it wasn't a Voltron comic, I wouldn't have bought it, right?
Rym: But yeah, I wasn't buying, like, tchotchkes or toys, I was buying, like...
Scott: There was a period, I was in the early anime cons, like, '02, '03, right?
Scott: It's like we had suddenly opened this world of, like, oh my god, this, the merch for these things is actually available here and nowhere else, in this country at least.
Scott: I finally have access to it and money, so I did go on, like, a mini spree of, like, buying just all kinds of, yeah.
Rym: That's actually where, you know, we didn't want to talk about the fan stuff, but that was where, the first time where I encountered a unique phenomenon that I never encountered in my life around my fan, the toys and merch I wanted for cartoons and comics.
Rym: I wanted whatever shows I was into, because I was watching anime a lot at that point in my life, and I wanted, like, high school onward.
Rym: I wanted merch from the anime I was watching specifically, but when I went to anime cons, they tended to only have merch from shows from three to four years prior that no one cared about anymore.
Scott: Or, and then it sort of switched up and it became shows that were the brand new hot shows, right?
Scott: And I didn't, I wasn't watching those, or I didn't like them as much, I didn't like them enough to buy merch from them.
Rym: But I also had this changing relationship of what I wanted out of merch, because as a kid, merch was, like, kid brain, like, I just wanted it for no particular reason.
Scott: Even if something was free, I'd be like, "Okay, I'll take it.
Scott: I don't even care what the hell it
Scott: is.".
Rym: I had so many free posters that I threw away before I went to college.
Scott: Yeah, and it wasn't even just, you know, anime comics merch.
Scott: Like, I would go to, like, a kid's bar mitzvah or some shit, right?
Scott: And they would give away, like, inflatable saxophone and, like, you know, plastic top hat and all sorts of stuff.
Scott: And I was just like, "Yeah, give me all that
Scott: stuff.".
Scott: And I was like, "Woo, free
Scott: stuff!".
Scott: And then when I got home, that stuff lasted, like, a couple days, and then it was in the garbage, right?
Rym: But then I hit this era where I didn't want toys, because I wasn't playing with toys anymore, and I didn't want crap.
Rym: But what I wanted was social currency and ways to display my fandom of these cartoons and comics to other people.
Rym: I wanted things like wall scrolls.
Rym: I kind of wanted some of those busts and things for a while, but thankfully I couldn't afford them.
Rym: Little plastic figures to line up above my computer.
Rym: Like, that kind of crap.
Rym: T-shirts, pins, buttons.
Rym: But that was the era where the thing, for whatever reason, all the cartoons and anime and comics I was reading were never the things where official merch that I wanted was available in the US.
Rym: And it was too expensive to import, so I tended to buy mostly bootleg illegal stuff made by nerd fans in the artist alleys because they tended to be making unlicensed merch for the things where there was no easily accessible official merch.
Rym: There was, like, a weird golden era of that specific phenomenon.
Scott: I think also what happened is, you know, a lot of the things I bought is I have, like, a good couple sacks full of various plastic figures of different kinds, right?
Scott: And some of them are pretty cool, but it's like, you know, I guess in the college days I was putting them all up on the shelf.
Scott: Like, "Oh yeah, that's so cool," right?
Scott: And in the Beacon days, I still had them on the shelf.
Scott: I was like, "Alright, they're cool," right?
Scott: And then it was sort of like, I didn't feel like, you know, that display was a cool display anymore, even though I still thought some of the figures were cool.
Rym: But it was always sort of cluttered, and more importantly, that shit would get dusty, and I was unwilling to dust it.
Scott: You gotta dust it.
Scott: You gotta put them in that glass case that everyone has.
Rym: I was about to bring up the glass case, because that was the moment.
Rym: My specific moment was, I have all these plastic figures, and they look awesome, but they get dusty.
Rym: "Oh, I should put them in a plastic case,".
Rym: but then I imagined having a plastic case full of that stuff in, like, my future fancy apartment.
Rym: And I realized that I don't want things, and I started trying to get rid of all my things, and all the only merch I want now.
Scott: I don't need any more of this shit, right?
Scott: And I already had learned my collecting lesson long ago with Imagine the Gathering, right?
Scott: So I was doing it for collecting, and the purpose of a lot of this stuff was displaying, and I'm like, "Well, not displaying
Scott: anymore.".
Scott: And so now, it's at the point where even if there is some sort of character or something that I really like, even my fucking favorite, right?
Scott: It's like, if it's not on a quality thing that I'm going to use, then I'm not interested, right?
Scott: I could see two t-shirts, and one of them has, I don't know, Spiderman 2099 on it, and another one is just an amazing plain t-shirt.
Scott: It's like, "Give me the amazing plain t-shirt, please.
Scott: It's a better
Scott: t-shirt.".
Scott: If you're gonna give me a t-shirt that says something on it, it's gotta be a good t-shirt first.
Rym: That was it.
Rym: for so long, I'd wear any goddamn t-shirt, like a lot of people who are in their early 20s do, in late teams, and then I learned better.
Rym: The nicer t-shirts fit better and work better, but for the longest time, any t-shirt that had cartoon or comic, especially cartoon intellectual property on it, tended to be the big ugly square prints on the garbage tier, like Hanes cotton black shirt.
Scott: That's the thing.
Scott: Uniqlo, for example, they make tons and tons of t-shirts and other clothing, especially t-shirts.
Scott: Lots of nerdy things printed on them, and when they make those, I go and I check them out on their website or even at the store before times.
Scott: They would make ones for properties that were like, "My favorite fucking property," and I'd look and all the designs would be meh.
Scott: They had a whole Mario series.
Scott: I didn't even buy one thing, I don't think.
Rym: Every now and then I do.
Rym: I got that Bowser Jr.
Rym: shirt.
Scott: Yeah, every now and then they'll have one where the quality and the design is actually tasteful and good, and I'll be like, "I'll buy
Scott: that.".
Scott: But otherwise, it's like, no.
Scott: But if I was a kid, and Uniqlo existed when I was a kid and they had those Mario clothes, I would have won everything.
Rym: Yep, they would have had to drag me kicking and screaming out of that store, possibly.
Scott: I would have been like, "Oh, I'll just replace an eye from my entire wardrobe with every single one of
Scott: these.".
Rym: And I guess the shift is it went from, and this is something that gets into nerds, because it's Wednesday, we'll focus on anime nerds, like the weebs and anime cons.
Rym: There is a big difference between wanting merch, especially clothing like that, as a shibboleth to tell other people, "I like this property," to find other people who also like that property, versus, "I like the specific aesthetic of that design and choose to wear it for that
Rym: aesthetic.".
Rym: And I'm not going to say that is a sign of maturation or anything, like.
Rym: that's not where I'm going with that.
Rym: I'm just saying that I personally radically and suddenly shifted from one mode to the other mode, to the point that I don't use fashion or merch or anything as a shibboleth ever.
Rym: The only shibboleth of the things I'm into I will ever use are talking, and that's it, just talking to people, conversations, human interaction, being in an event together.
Rym: It's not like, "Oh, you're in a Batman shirt.
Rym: I bet you're into Batman.
Rym: We're going to be best friends and talk about
Rym: Batman.".
Scott: You know how many people have Batman shirts and aren't huge Batman fans?
Scott: It doesn't tell you anything.
Rym: The listener's talking about their changeover from, "I would buy the lunchbox or the thing that just has the lazy Batman logo right in the center in a big square with no thought to the aesthetics
Rym: whatsoever.".
Rym: Very much like the Red Dragon t-shirt.
Rym: I had a mask lunchbox that was just the mask logo.
Rym: It was basically just a shitty sticker stuck on the front of a completely generic, super cheap, Folly a Party red lunchbox.
Rym: I used that thing until it fell apart and loved it as a kid.
Scott: I think another thing that contributes to the problem is that the fan merch is usually good, but there's also the bootleg not fan, just bootleg bootleg merch out there.
Scott: Especially for anime stuff, but it just really clogs up the marketplace in general.
Rym: Right now, I'll pick some cartoon on Amazon which has full of bootleg crap.
Rym: My Little Pony t-shirt.
Rym: I'm confident.
Rym: most of what I find is unlicensed crap.
Rym: Oh wow, that's a lot of unlicensed crap.
Scott: The aesthetic of most of it is even the official stuff.
Scott: I remember what was the place, We Love Fine or whatever.
Scott: They had all these licenses to properties that I enjoyed and we were making stuff, even some useful stuff that I might have bought.
Scott: But their designs were just so tacky.
Scott: I was just like,
Scott: "No.".
Scott: Even though you're the only people making a Rainbow Dash, it's like, "No, that's ugly as hell.
Scott: What's wrong with
Scott: you?".
Rym: Even worse, I feel like a lot of these are probably just stealing someone's fan art.
Scott: A lot of them, yeah.
Scott: And then, you do have the good ones out there.
Scott: Like Fangamer, which puts a lot of effort into making a good design.
Rym: Even these official ones are bad.
Rym: You put the zipper right through Twilight Sparkle's face.
Rym: That's an aesthetic.
Scott: You look at something like Fangamer, and it's like, "Yo, I can see that they put a lot of stuff into the...".
Scott: The designs are less tacky.
Scott: They're actually pretty quality.
Scott: Some of them are subtle.
Scott: But even though they are good, a lot of them, when they stand alone, a lot of these properties are ones I don't care about.
Scott: Or even though it's good, it's still not something I'm going to buy or use from myself a lot of the time.
Scott: There's such a narrow window you have to hit to make something that I will actually buy that and use that, and now you'll get my money.
Scott: Whereas if Fangamer existed even 15 years ago, it's like, "Oh no, I would have been in big
Scott: trouble.".
Rym: Here's an example.
Rym: The Great Pretender.
Rym: Pretty good anime we just watched.
Rym: Let's say we were younger and super into it.
Rym: One, I don't think anyone sells a t-shirt for The Great Pretender, but say I was desperate to get a t-shirt for that cartoon because I really liked it.
Rym: I imagine that t-shirt would just be like the character's face is lazily stuck in the center of the t-shirt and that's it.
Rym: There's no way the t-shirt would be an asymmetric background from the show without the logo and without the name of the thing.
Rym: I feel like most merch for cartoons, especially in America, focuses on making sure anyone who sees you wearing it clearly identifies which intellectual property it is to the expense of any aesthetics.
Scott: Another problem I see that happens to me a lot is, "Okay, I like a thing, but my favorite thing, character usually, but not always character, but my favorite aspect of a particular property will not be the main character or the main villain or
Scott: something.".
Scott: And so even though that property as a whole might have a shit ton of merch, it's like your actual merch.
Scott: options for the thing you personally care about are very, very limited.
Rym: Oh my god, there are Great Pretender shirts.
Rym: One, there's a bunch that are just the Freddie Mercury album cover, but just a big square in the middle of a t-shirt.
Rym: It's just terrible.
Scott: Okay, sure.
Rym: But there's a bunch that are literally just what I said.
Rym: It's just like, "There's Lawrence, front and center, with the words 'The Great Pretender' on
Rym: top.".
Scott: Well, a lot of these things you're probably finding on the internet are probably just, you know, someone has a print-on-demand factory and they've got a database of JPEGs.
Scott: and when you search, you land on the JPEGs and then they slap the JPEGs onto various items.
Rym: Yup, which people wouldn't be doing if there wasn't some money to be made there.
Rym: Someone's buying these enough.
Scott: But that didn't exist when we were younger.
Scott: That wasn't a possibility, right?
Scott: Print-on-demand was not something a normal person could access even if they did mail order.
Scott: And you definitely didn't have JPEGs, right?
Scott: It's like even if you tried to do it, where would you get the artwork to do the printing?
Rym: When I was in high school, a big thing I did on the internet was look for JPEGs or just images like GIFs or bitmaps from anime I liked.
Rym: That was not easy to come by.
Scott: How could you get it?
Scott: What was someone going to do?
Rym: Take a photograph of their TV from the VCR.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: So we're sort of in a wondrous time in that you can get merch of anything of any form, right?
Scott: A mug, any sort of apparel, keychains, like literally any item of any property.
Scott: It's like you can probably find a merch of it somewhere, but it's sort of a dark time and that so little of the merch is well designed, high quality, good, useful, right?
Scott: The thing that you're specifically interested in, like finding that perfect storm where you're actually going to spend money on a thing is like even rarer, right?
Scott: It's like, yeah, there wasn't much merch for a thing in the 90s, but if I was a kid and I went to the store, it's like there would still be a section of the store that had something and I could buy all those.
Rym: But I guess I do feel like a lot of people who buy branded merch for cartoons are specifically doing that whole shibboleth, like show off the thing I'm into, make sure that people know I'm a fan of this intellectual property thing.
Scott: I think there's also, you know, the extreme nerds, right, is like they really identify strongly, like personally with maybe a particular thing, right?
Scott: Like, you know, you meet some nerd and that nerd is like, they're all about the Flash.
Scott: The Flash is their thing, right?
Rym: I remember that guy from that con who was into Silver Age Spider-Man.
Rym: I think that was his entire life.
Rym: I'm not saying there's anything wrong with that.
Scott: Yeah, the Flash isn't unpopular, but he's not, you know, Superman level or he's not Spider-Man level.
Scott: He's like on the next tier of famous superhero, right?
Scott: He probably even got pushed down by the fact that other heroes are rising in popularity.
Rym: DC Comics sells a pretty good The Flash shirt.
Rym: Looks like it's official.
Scott: If you buy, you can probably like literally have a Flash, you know, it's not as probably as not to the Hello Kitty extent, but you could probably have a Flash everything in your house, right?
Scott: Flash cups, Flash silverware, Flash clothing.
Rym: Some of these t-shirts are moderately classy too.
Scott: Flash bed sheets.
Rym: Like just a red t-shirt with the Flash logo in the middle, like that's actually a good aesthetic for what The Flash is.
Scott: They've been printing that t-shirt probably for 30 years.
Rym: Yeah, it's the same t-shirt someone had in the 70s.
Scott: It's the same, yeah, it's the same t-shirt.
Scott: They've been printing that forever.
Scott: But you know, that's where we're at now, so I don't know, you gotta decide how you're gonna be, right?
Scott: Are you gonna, like maybe you're a person who doesn't find that aesthetic tacky.
Scott: Maybe you're still young, right?
Rym: Ah, you're making a value judgment there.
Rym: I heard that still you slipped in there.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, I am making a judgment.
Rym: For all that Scott complains about people talking about fashion stuff, Scott is very particular about fashion.
Scott: You know what, I look like some...
Rym: Like some what?
Rym: Why is it wrong to wear sandals with socks?
Scott: What's wrong with that?
Rym: What's wrong with wearing Crocs?
Scott: Because what's wrong with it is that people like me will look down on you.
Rym: But why?
Scott: Because I will.
Rym: Why do you look down on someone wearing the t-shirt that is just like Wolverine in a big square taking up the entire center of their chest with the word Wolverine on the bottom?
Scott: Well, because you're telling me that you're signaling, right, that your aesthetics, or you don't care about the aesthetics, or your aesthetic taste is so far out of line with mine.
Scott: I do not have much in common with you, so I don't want to associate with you.
Rym: But I'm trying to think, other than a few Nintendo shirts that I got from Uniqlo recently, actually I bought them right before quarantine so I haven't worn them in public much.
Rym: I'm trying to think of the last piece of merch I bought from any cartoon of any kind.
Scott: I mean, does a gun block count?
Scott: I bought some buildable Evangelion models.
Rym: I guess that counts.
Rym: You're doing that.
Rym: I don't do that.
Scott: I'm just thinking back.
Scott: It's like, I'll buy those, I won't buy an action figure.
Scott: An action figure doesn't do anything.
Scott: I don't really actually like displaying them or looking at them that much.
Scott: But building them is fun, right?
Scott: I wish I could build them and then someone who would want them would take them.
Scott: But usually people want to build them.
Scott: After I built them, I'm like,
Scott: "Fuck.".
Scott: When I was a kid, I had like- I'm like, "That was fun building this, but now what do I
Scott: do?".
Rym: I was reminded, one of the listeners was talking about the old iron-on bootlegs.
Rym: I had a lot of Bart Simpson shirts when I was a kid.
Rym: Like, a lot.
Rym: And one time, Cedar Point made me turn it one inside out because Bart said the word "hell," I think, on it.
Rym: Or "damn" or something.
Rym: I forget exactly what was on the shirt.
Scott: The only thing I had- I think I had a South Park shirt that was like a Kenny Dyeing shirt of some kind.
Rym: I had a lot of bootleg Simpson shirts, too, that were just iron-ons.
Rym: Yeah, I cannot- the last intellectual property from a show that I got was probably like a pin from an anime con at least like four-plus years ago, maybe?
Scott: Yeah, who knows?
Rym: Who even knows?
Scott: But yeah, it's, you know, for all we've said about it, right, that merch industry sustai- that's what's sustaining everything, right?
Scott: That is the thing that's holding everything up, right?
Scott: It's not your, you know- Well, it's that and advertising cross-promotion type stuff.
Rym: Like, there's the whole ecosystem there as well.
Scott: But it's like, yeah, it's like, you know, people buying comic books aren't holding up comic books, right, you know, directly.
Scott: People watching anime isn't holding up anime.
Rym: People watching cartoon- you know, you're watching Adventure Time on Cartoon Network- Openly, nakedly, that's what they were.
Scott: You know what I'm saying?
Scott: Like, kids watching, you know, I guess it's over, but if you're watching Adventure Time, right, there were ads during it.
Scott: That helped a lot, but, you know, it was people buying all that Adventure Time stuff at the store that was holding the show up for how many years.
Scott: Not the- not anything else, so.
Rym: I do like some of the- a lot of backpacks came around for a while.
Rym: Like, the branded backpack from a show.
Rym: Like, a lot of people had Finn's backpack.
Scott: It's been around forever.
Scott: We had Ninja Turtle backpack and stuff.
Rym: But the ones more recently, like in the last couple decades, were a lot higher quality than what we had as kids, but I guess that's just not the way it goes with everything.
Scott: Qualities.
Scott: In some ways, that's actually weird, the way quality has changed over time, right?
Scott: Is that, you know, obviously we already discussed how there's all the bootleg, print-on-demand, low-quality stuff, right?
Scott: But if you only count the officially licensed stuff, in some ways, quality has skyrocketed.
Scott: There are, you know, today, the highest, like, the cap on quality.
Scott: Like, if you buy official merch for, like, Ghibli stuff, like, that stuff is, like, so well made.
Scott: It's, like, unbelievable that, you know, some- and it costs a lot, too.
Scott: It's not cheap, right?
Scott: And that was just- didn't exist.
Scott: But on the other hand, people are putting out some low-quality biz, and the quality of certain things has decreased over time.
Scott: When I was a kid, if you wanted to buy, like, a lunchbox with a thermos, you got, like, a fucking metal lunchbox.
Rym: Eh, not always.
Rym: I had the plastic one where, literally, every- there's this one specific type of plastic lunchbox that came with a shitty plastic thermos and a couple other things.
Rym: They were all identical, but they all had a different sticker of an intellectual property on the front.
Scott: I know the one you're talking about, yeah.
Scott: I'm saying before- that was, like, the turnaround, right?
Scott: Is, like, before that, I had a metal one, right?
Scott: And then those came out afterwards.
Scott: The quality of the official stuff went down.
Scott: Well, look at backpacks.
Rym: I remember I had a branded, like, mask backpack.
Rym: Every backpack was the exact same backpack where the shoulder straps came in toward the middle and were always too tight on your neck.
Rym: Every kid had identical backpacks, but they all had different cartoon intellectual property on them.
Rym: Now, like, you get a BMO backpack, it's just physically shaped like BMO, and it's really high quality.
Scott: Yeah, but it's, like, you know, it has to do with, you know, what was cheap to produce, what would sell, and who are the companies who own the intellectual property choosing to license to in various territories.
Scott: It's always different.
Scott: And that's gonna affect, you know, if you license- if you give a license out to, like, you know, awesome statue maker, they're gonna make, like, these unbelievable expensive statues.
Scott: If you give a license out to just anybody, who knows what the hell they're gonna make, right?
Rym: You get the Subway franchise of merch.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi McNichol, Alan Joyce, Linki G, Dread Lily, Tenet Break, Chris Rahmer, Clinton Walton, just like a dude guy.
Rym: Program Threat, Open Speed, Undertake Law, Adoption, Pierce Absorb, Rebecca Dunn Review, Med Bowl, 34 Cowards, Ryan Perrin, Sam Erikson, Shervin Mount Horrell, Taylor Braun.
Rym: You sold a key- hold the key to my heart and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their name.
Rym: I'm trying something just to make it clear that all the money we spend on equipment probably matters.
Rym: I recorded this with my like fancy gaming headset that I use when I'm playing like Overwatch instead of the nice audio interface and the fancy Beta 87A.
Rym: Yeah, the nicer microphones are just superior in every way.
Rym: But anyway, for now I leave you with something that you really should have seen coming.
Scott: Fauxhammer.