Rym: It's Tuesday, September 28th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Rym: I forgot to push And this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight we are talking about gaming magazines, you know, like Nintendo power and biz.
Scott: Let's do this so astute The listener who may be watching and not just listening.
Scott: astute watcher may notice I'm not wearing the headphones that I've worn for at least a year and change.
Rym: Oh, yeah I just I didn't even ask I just assumed.
Scott: So I've had this pair of Bose QC 35 to Headphones for a long time.
Scott: They just been in an office unused for all right.
Rym: You went into your office to get all your crap.
Scott: Yeah, so, you know, I went to my office to get all my crap which we talked about in a previous episode.
Scott: And so I these headphones were among my crap and I went to use them and I was like, oh, yeah These are actually like the best.
Scott: Why did I not go get these earlier?
Scott: I could have been using these the whole time.
Rym: It's funny because at home like I'm wearing my Sony like studio monitor headphones the closed ones I have just the exact same headphones.
Rym: I have two pair of them one at home and one at work.
Scott: Well, they I had you know, the AKG ones that I've been using at home, right?
Scott: We're open.
Rym: So I actually have a closed and an open plugged into my computer at all times and I use whichever one Based on like if I'm playing a game or working and I want like I could stalk Emily or hear things.
Rym: So I wear the open ones but recording GeekNights or mastering audio I wear the closed ones or like.
Scott: point is I had those because I'd never had to use them in a situation before Right.
Scott: I didn't have to a wear them all day.
Scott: Be aware them right while they were in noises.
Scott: I was wearing them like alone in an apartment, you know for music or game audio.
Scott: That was it.
Scott: That's those are the only audio that came out of my home computer, but now I'm working at this computer all day.
Scott: I got Spotify going while I'm working.
Scott: I got noises coming from open window because the weather is we open window weather now.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and as an aside that stop work order out our building is over and they're drilling on the wall again.
Scott: Okay, but yeah, you know we used to always make fun of Bose because Bose was I guess in his origin Sort of this audio file brand like overrated like they weren't bad.
Scott: They were just way overrated Overpriced and overrated and still a bit overpriced.
Rym: The worst thing is nerds would always be like audio.
Rym: people would always be like no highs No lows must be Bose.
Scott: What are the audio audio file telling are like above Bose?
Scott: They got to go to somewhere other nonsense.
Rym: Oh, I work with someone who's one of those audiophiles and good lord Did he spend like thousands of dollars on preamp our cable?
Scott: Yeah But Bose is always like, you know get normal people who you know We'll have money to buy a more expensive thing with that, you know, sort of like a luxury brand in a way.
Scott: But but you know, I'm sure some Bose products, I don't know their whole product line ours probably still bullshit like that.
Scott: But the quiet comfort noise cancelling headphones are legit.
Scott: They actually have newer ones now.
Scott: This is 35 2.0.
Scott: They have 45 now Which is like a few dollars like tens of dollars more than these and is slightly different.
Scott: I guess super closed.
Rym: I really like monitors.
Rym: I just Sony above and beyond.
Rym: I prefer the closed without noise cancellation No matter how loud my environment is.
Scott: Well, have you had the noise cancellation?
Rym: Yeah, I find it doesn't matter that much compared to a truly closed like isolating.
Rym: I mean These are.
Rym: these are truly closed if I turn the noise cancellation off and it makes an enormous difference With these I literally can't hear anything like at all like Emily Yeller size literally can't hear a thing when these things are on.
Scott: I mean, I can't hear.
Scott: you know It's.
Scott: I can hear nothing when they're on and I can hear even less when the noise cancellation is on.
Rym: I can hear everything through my Sennheiser's Yeah, but anyway, it's.
Scott: it does make a huge difference, you know throughout the day right in terms of like just you know Distracting noises and whatnot being heard and such.
Scott: You know.
Scott: and usually for example right now Podcasting right?
Scott: I would usually have to turn Rym up because discord is quiet.
Scott: for some reason.
Rym: I don't reason.
Rym: I can explain why.
Rym: if any nerds care I'll do that in the stinger.
Rym: I'll explain why anyway.
Scott: So yeah, if you have a pile of money, I do recommend This one Bose product and no others.
Scott: And speaking of speaking of getting the shit from the office last episode I did offer up my keyboard as a second dibs my office keyboard and listener purchased it.
Scott: I sent it to them.
Scott: They received it today and they are very happy with it.
Scott: So that's two for two on the second dibs.
Scott: We sold a monitor and a keyboard.
Scott: I'll find something else to sell soon because I definitely have some more crap.
Rym: I actually have Second dibs when we get to that part of the show, but it's not time for that.
Rym: It's time for news.
Rym: You can't use that here.
Rym: So, uh, there's a ton of gaming news.
Rym: I think we even skipped a Tuesday show at some point.
Scott: So we're not gonna always a ton of gaming news.
Scott: When is there?
Scott: not?
Rym: but there was like more than usual between the Nintendo Direct a bunch of old stuff We didn't even talk about and the blizzard story just continuing to it.
Scott: I mean the Gen Con happened.
Scott: a pax happened that you know a tax happen.
Rym: We were in debt.
Scott: Game devs of color expo happened.
Rym: Oh, there's so much going on.
Rym: So a few things we'll talk about.
Rym: one There is some big news on the financial side of tabletop gaming.
Rym: if you don't know as Modi As my day as my day The company that basically is the second largest maker of board games in the world Mm-hmm.
Rym: I want to say Hasbro is technically the biggest publisher.
Scott: I don't know maker.
Rym: Well, they sell most of the articles is so much like way back when we were talking about how complicated and like difficult to summarize the relationships between publishers producers Like development studios in the video game industry is.
Rym: tabletop is getting just as complicated.
Rym: So most of the articles refer to them as a maker rather than get into that can of worms.
Rym: But anyway, they're basically the big ones They now are responsible for ultimately and own the IP for like most of the tabletop games You probably know about that are right.
Scott: So what happened was way back.
Scott: was it a year few year ago?
Scott: I don't know how long ago.
Rym: I feel like we even talked about it on GeekNights.
Scott: We did, you know They were already kind of a big board game publisher over in Europe and I forget what the exact order of events.
Scott: But they think they were acquired by some sort of private equity.
Rym: Pa I partners one of the bigger like private equity firms in the world.
Rym: They're a big deal.
Rym: They seem okay.
Rym: Well, I will not give any judgment on the quality of their purchases because I'm not a financial advisor.
Scott: But anyway Anyway, the asthma day started acquiring other board game company.
Scott: Tom is notably fantasy flight, but also others as well.
Scott: He man Catan studios days of wonder Yep, so they brought all of these big-time board game places under one roof.
Scott: So, you know you think you're a private equity firm, you're either gonna a do some Toys R Us type scamming.
Scott: But that's not what's going on here.
Scott: Instead you just you bought this thing.
Scott: Your goal is to make it more valuable than it was when you bought it and then sell it, right?
Scott: So they bought asthma day and if they did there are two main methods they did to increase the value of the company As outsiders.
Scott: Sure, they acquired these other board game companies and merge them.
Scott: now, you know one plus one normally equals two.
Scott: But if you get enough big companies together one plus one can equal three because when there's less competition Right and you have more control over the market a bigger market share Suddenly, you know have more power in the market.
Scott: And even though you only had one plus one the value of the thing, you know of yourself goes up, right?
Scott: And the second thing they did was cut right laid people off Got rid of redundancies got rid of you know, things that weren't selling.
Scott: Well, if you could just look at fantasy flight alone You can see how much stuff they cut away from that company and got rid of and only kept the business lines That were profitable like the Star Wars stuff.
Rym: Yeah, right Like a lot of in games, especially in tabletop for a long time a lot of smaller studios.
Rym: You saw this in the anime industry too.
Rym: in America.
Rym: The people who ran the companies for a lot of reasons would use profitable things to prop up underperforming things for a lot of different reasons and Private equity generally just says just drop the unperform underperforming things entirely, right?
Scott: If it doesn't make you know, okay sure that thing made money, but it didn't make enough money.
Scott: So getting let's get rid of it.
Rym: Yep, or that thing makes a lot of money, but it takes up all the time of our best development team.
Rym: Let's cancel that whole thing and have this development team work on this other intellectual property that we acquired in this other company and work With those artists and make something that'll sell way more.
Scott: Regardless they successfully increase the value of asthma day significantly and now they're attempting to sell it for they bought it for 1.1 point billion euros in 2018. now they're selling it for they're asking two billion So they basically made eight hundred million dollars if they successfully sell.
Rym: Yep, never mind any profits They gain depending on the relationship.
Rym: Like.
Rym: I'm not too deep in exactly how their relationship worked.
Rym: But any profits they would have taken along the way as well like revenue or anything.
Scott: So we'll see if it sells and to whom for how much and that will have a significant impact on the future of Board gaming worldwide.
Rym: Yep, and I think your two takeaways are one a lot of nerds Really really misunderstood this news and think that Goldman Sachs is buying as mode a. that is not what?
Rym: Oh Many Tweets or like full-on news articles on bullshitty blogs said Goldman Sachs buying games gonna ruin them Like they're just managing the transaction.
Rym: I understand that you're mad about capitalism, but that is that is so far from what's happening here.
Scott: If that that would actually be amazing.
Scott: if it happened I could go work for Goldman's right.
Rym: make it work, right?
Rym: But Speaking of making a fortune the other thing this actually is really really like the real news here.
Rym: Is that board gaming is fucking huge Globally and the fact that these kinds of sales are happening mean that capital like the people who have capital Believe that it is still an underserved and untapped market that we've only scratched the surface.
Scott: Part of that value increase was definitely just the growth of the into the.
Scott: you know, the pie, right?
Scott: Yeah board games as an industry got bigger.
Rym: therefore board game companies got bigger and it's very telling that it's private equity Involved in this and not public companies.
Rym: or like Hasbro or something like Hasbro probably couldn't even afford to buy as mode a. It gets real complicated with public companies real copy.
Scott: Hasbro, I think has two billion dollars somewhere.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but basically what I'm getting?
Scott: Apple could afford a hundred as mode days with just the cash they have.
Rym: Private equity is often maligned unfairly though to be fair private equity can suck shit but because capitalism fuck is is terrible, but The difference between a public company and a private company at this scale is not what you think it is.
Rym: in general Private companies can take way bigger risks can do a lot more aggressive stuff without having to be beholden to anyone who's holding them accountable because of.
Rym: if a private equity backed company goes under The people who backed it just lose everything like they're just done And they know that risk and that happens all the time.
Rym: public companies have a very powerful fiduciary duty to their shareholders.
Rym: That's why you see things like in our next news of shareholders suing a company if they believe that company didn't maximize profits.
Scott: Private equity can kind of do whatever it wants, but sorry Yeah, I mean like, you know if you invest in a private company, you know If you're on the board of the you know private equity firm, you might be able to choose the CEO of the company, right?
Scott: Yeah, but it doesn't have to listen to you that much.
Scott: you could change the CEO, I guess Or a private company could donate all its profits to charity.
Rym: if a public company just heard that the shareholders could sue over it.
Rym: So Generally, what what this means is that people who invest in public companies like rich people with capital.
Rym: Those are generally safer investments that are more regulated more scrutinized.
Rym: There's more public information.
Rym: Private equity goes after things that are either very risky or things that people who have money and inside knowledge think are way undervalued by the rest of the stock market.
Rym: Mm-hmm, I'm generalizing a lot here and this is not investment advice But my read on this is that board gaming has only scratched the barest tip of the surface of the real market.
Rym: Like I think we're in the.
Scott: we're also, you know, given the other things going on in board game world, right?
Scott: You know shipping and production and supply chain issues.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: Yep So yeah We will see and I think we'll save that for another show in some other news.
Scott: if that destroys many smaller board game companies suddenly the big ones get even bigger.
Scott: that makes Hasbro and Edmo as modé ever more powerful because the bigger boat is Easier to weather a storm with.
Rym: yeah, also a bigger boat has too many people who cannot afford to let it sink Yep.
Rym: So in some other news the Nintendo Direct happened.
Rym: There's a ton of news.
Rym: if you want a play-by-play of everything They announced go to a site.
Rym: that'll give you that like.
Rym: we're just gonna talk about the ones that we're interested in.
Scott: Often the big one that no one knew was coming.
Scott: that's a big for us.
Scott: is that that Actra is a remake that came out.
Scott: So now I don't know out there if any if the listener ever heard of Actra is there they had to.
Rym: if you listen to GeekNights.
Rym: I feel like we've granted.
Rym: I don't think we've talked about.
Rym: Actra is or except in like 2007.
Scott: Actra is a Super Nintendo game.
Scott: That was that's truly unique.
Scott: not entirely unique But very unique in that a incredible soundtrack a plus soundtrack B. it's two games in one.
Scott: There's a town game and as a side-scrolling normal kind of action guy with a sword game sort of like Strider a little.
Rym: yeah that juxtaposition was So crazy to kids when it came out.
Rym: It was like one of the earliest widely known genre destroying games.
Scott: Yeah, and the town part affected the the actiony part, right?
Rym: You level up your shit you go the actiony part you find an item you go back and use that to help the town part.
Scott: right, so the the problem was Actra 2 came out.
Scott: cuz Actra 1 was a hit and Act raiser 2 was just the actiony part and was said we are town part.
Rym: We even did a panel on this.
Rym: It's one of the few lost GeekNights panels.
Rym: if someone in the audience recorded a panel from like PAX West Called egregiously unrealized potential.
Rym: Holy shit.
Rym: Get me that video I will die will pay you.
Rym: but we only ever did that panel once and Almost everything we talked about except the poke.
Rym: I think the Pokemon MMO is the only thing we talked about.
Rym: that has not come true and we talked a lot about.
Scott: I thought it was forgotten.
Scott: masters was the one that no one now steal from.
Rym: the forgotten masters also Had some of that.
Rym: but we talked about like SOP with and stuff in that panel.
Rym: This one is where we were like bionic commando the remake of the NES game did better than the game.
Rym: They made it to promote Act ready.
Rym: right the point is.
Scott: Released an HD remake of Act raiser.
Scott: if you've never played Act raiser in your whole life find a Super Nintendo ROM or buy this thing.
Scott: Interesting notes.
Scott: the music in Act raiser was made by the guy who made the streets of rage music
Rym: also a plus and game music and
Scott: He said on Twitter he's like hey, you know, I made some extra tracks for this remake and what he did was he made the tracks The old Super Nintendo way right because you can play the remake in old-school mode or recurrent mode quote And he
Rym: features an upgrade to use a kosher soundtrack by kosher himself, but you can stick to the original score if you like.
Scott: Right, but he may be because most of the tracks were already scored for a Super Nintendo in the 90s.
Scott: And then we're sort of HD remade right to be except somebody added new songs.
Scott: So in order to keep everything on the level he composed those new songs in their old-school Super Nintendo Way first and then HD remade those.
Scott: that's amazing Yeah, so even though it's the year 2021 if you've never played this game.
Rym: I honestly recommend playing the remake.
Scott: I just assumed it'll be fine, but I'm disappointed that they just didn't make Act raiser 3.
Rym: Yeah, because maybe maybe that's coming.
Scott: who knows?
Rym: I think it could come because the problem with Act raiser was that The mashup and the music was really all it had going for itself.
Rym: because honestly just from a pure game design perspective The town part is simplistic to the point of being insulting and was fun.
Rym: It was to a kid.
Scott: That is ultimate fun if you really can't lose at the town part, but if you play it today babies first It's like baby's first popular.
Rym: Yeah, but if you play it today like you'll look at it, and he'll be like.
Rym: so I just wait.
Rym: You basically just wait pretty much Yeah, but and the platforming part was only okay, it was not bad But it was like a mediocre to average platformer for its.
Scott: It was just a platforming hit guys with sword thing.
Scott: It wasn't anything special about it.
Rym: Yeah, you had pretty limited movement, and it was difficult like very difficult especially in the later levels for kids.
Scott: But I'd rather play something like demon sword for NES.
Rym: Yeah, absolutely There's a lot of platform 2d platformers from that era that Ninja Gaiden is better than Act raiser.
Rym: Yeah, Act raiser.
Rym: You know what it felt like.
Rym: it felt like a lot of parts of Faxanadu.
Scott: if anyone remembers that I Rather play Faxanadu than just the action part of Act raiser.
Rym: I feel like it's a close race.
Rym: I'd have to play them both again.
Scott: It is pretty close.
Rym: Anyway, yeah cuz the thing I don't I can't speak to out of Faxanadu is how NES annoying is it?
Rym: I have not played it since I had an NES a little bit, but not too much Yeah, so uh in some other Nintendo Direct News, it looks like the cut.
Rym: the original console war is Done to the point that there is now a Sega Genesis classics coming out of the Nintendo switch.
Scott: Well, so the way this is working is that if you have Nintendo online, which isn't free but is inexpensive It's like one annual fee of like 20 bucks.
Scott: It's cheap, right?
Rym: Well, we did the like plan thing So I'm just mooching off of you.
Scott: Yeah, I think the family plan is worth it.
Scott: I don't think the individual plan might.
Scott: absolutely.
Rym: I would not pay for it if I had to pay for it.
Scott: It depends how much.
Scott: if you're playing a Nintendo switch games online a lot, then it's probably worth it.
Scott: But anyway the The way that works is if you have Nintendo switch online plan Then you get free access to NES and SNES games and among other games like Tetris 99 and stuff like that Just on your switch for free as part of it not for free.
Scott: It's part of the thing, right?
Scott: They're adding n64 games and Genesis games Which you know is actually pretty.
Scott: the n64 ones are significant because you know emulating those is a little is Still easy, but a little bit different than emulating, you know an NES game, which is trivial, right?
Scott: You know, there are difficult.
Scott: It's not difficult like emulating a Saturn game.
Rym: Yeah, but like the fidelity is not quite there for most of the emulators The MB the fidelity is there but it's not quite there.
Rym: if you're like speedrunning or something, let's say oh it depends.
Scott: but anyway the point is there.
Scott: now the n64 and Genesis games are coming to the switch, but You need to pay more.
Scott: you need to get a switch online plus Can you know you pay more money to get those like an upsell to the next level just kind of meh.
Rym: Well, the other thing there's gonna be a retro controller.
Scott: But well there they already sell retro NES and SNES controllers that you could use with Bluetooth with your switch.
Scott: I have the NES one.
Scott: It's exactly what you think it is.
Scott: It's a Bluetooth NES controller, right?
Scott: But they're gonna sell Genesis ones and n64 ones that are Bluetooth wireless controllers to work with a switch and You can buy those if you have the account, right?
Scott: It's like if you have the account then you can just buy the controller.
Scott: Otherwise they won't sell you the controller.
Scott: you could buy one from someone else.
Scott: however The Genesis controller they're selling is the original us three button controller.
Scott: People in Japan are going to be able to buy a six button Genesis controller.
Scott: That will not be sold as far as we know so far in the US which is bullshit because there are Several Genesis games where that controller is basically mandatory Though many where it's not.
Rym: yeah Well their argument they made a very clear statement that they're not gonna go back on this and the answer and what they said was For the mass market in America.
Rym: No one ever had a six button one.
Rym: So I had it.
Rym: Yeah, we've only super nerds did most.
Scott: most people absolutely needed it to play several like officially the fighting games like Street Fighter.
Scott: It was like essential.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it's essential if you care.
Scott: It's not actually essential to make the game work Super Street Fighter 2 tournament edition was like one of the top Genesis games.
Rym: Oh, yeah But I'm saying their their argument is very few Americans were acquainted with the six button controller at the time The Genesis was available in stores Anyway, so that's just a sad thing.
Rym: Any other major news is I mean, yep So the blizzard saga is ongoing and I do want to mention a few updates to that.
Rym: So one Cal is a state of California has actually weighed in I think we talked about this a little bit before Accusing blizzard of shredding evidence of abuse in the company.
Rym: So there is a state level like possibly criminal investigation going on as part of this.
Rym: Also In in this backdrop the person in charge of overwatch - kind of one of the biggest deal games They're working on has quit blizzard.
Scott: You're just leaving So and a lot of people are quitting or a lot of people resigning.
Rym: Oh, yeah, people are quitting blizzard left and right.
Rym: It's not clearly everything.
Scott: You know the the doubt the the worrying started when it became Activision Blizzard, right?
Scott: That was the worrying started but nothing bad happened immediately.
Scott: Then there was that big layoff like a few years ago And that's when the.
Scott: that's when it was like, oh that was.
Rym: that was when most of the people I knew who were working at Blizzard at the time we're gone.
Scott: Yeah, there was like a big layoff a few years ago, I think it was a news for sure.
Scott: I Remember I was why I was the time when I was like playing hearthstone a lot and I was watching a hearthstone streamer And he had to just turn on his.
Scott: his partner worked at Blizzard doing something I don't know and he basically had you like.
Scott: he got up there was like, you know to take a phone call.
Scott: He came back and he was like gotta go because his partner was just laid off in the big layoff.
Scott: Yep So turned his stream up.
Scott: Oh That was when things started going downhill and then you started to see big names at Blizzard leaving Right, you know the people who ran hearthstone, right?
Scott: They left to make a different company and then you started to see like, you know, the CEO right the historic Blizzard people Right, they bailed, you know Yeah, and then the shit hit the fan.
Scott: and now it's like, you know, the curve was already downward trending.
Scott: now It's like a straight vertical line.
Rym: So with poop at the bottom shareholders have sued Blizzard.
Rym: I think we already talked about that over the sexual harassment and such.
Rym: the SEC is now investigating Blizzard over that same situation not as part of that shareholder lawsuit per se just in general and There is some breaking news.
Rym: It looks like from today.
Rym: Yeah, this just broke.
Rym: It looks like Activision is now agreeing as part of a settlement Just in the just to not win a settlement for I guess the Federal Employment Agency Lawsuit.
Rym: there's so much stuff going on.
Scott: I can't actually I can't even tell which.
Scott: basically I see headlines that are like bad stuff at Blizzard and I can't tell if it's a rerun an Update or actually a new bad thing.
Scott: So the civil right after bad thing.
Rym: in in the middle of all that there was a civil rights lawsuit By the US Equal Employment Opportunity Commission against Blizzard.
Rym: today It was announced that they are settling and with 18 million dollars The company will now put into a fund to deal with and pay victims of harassment and assault within the company.
Scott: Yeah, somebody tweeted.
Scott: I don't know if this is true because they didn't cite any facts on this and it doesn't sound true to me.
Scott: They tweeted saying that you know Call of Duty something something Activision makes five million dollars a day, which Hard to believe that Numbers handy.
Rym: I could look that up.
Scott: But yeah, but they're like.
Scott: so they're.
Scott: so they were like.
Scott: the 18 million is nothing And I'm like that.
Scott: that 18 million is kind of nothing to accompany that.
Rym: but remember that only deals with one Tiny story in the sea of bad news around Blizzard.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Scott: it doesn't mean you know, it's not like.
Scott: oh they got off the hook right there.
Scott: They're still in the deep.
Rym: This does not resolve any of those other situations that are going on.
Scott: Also, I question five million dollars a day on one game.
Scott: Why would you have any other game?
Rym: But in other Blizzard news I guess Diablo 2 the remake like came out in the middle of all this and I Didn't actually never played Diablo 2 the original Just played the original.
Scott: I mean the remake is probably a little easier user interface wise But also don't give this company any fucking money.
Rym: Yeah I do feel like there is a future where The end result of all this is a company with good game design and good people working in it.
Scott: But I think it was a blizzard was before it was Blizzard activated.
Rym: So some of the one of the several of these things predate the Activision Merger and several of these things were specific to Blizzard executives and early.
Scott: I'm not saying that the company wasn't like horribly sexist and toxic in turn with its internal culture.
Scott: It was blizzard.
Scott: I'm saying is that before it was before the Activision days It was one of those companies that only produces, you know Well designed hit games every single time.
Scott: like you knew if it was a blizzard game It was gonna be a big.
Rym: they still are Accomplishing that.
Rym: the people I know who do still work there talk about how that is still true and like now I think that some you know to some degree.
Scott: Yes, but also they converted into making everything You know micro transaction money.
Rym: well the problem there is that trend is happening everywhere and it's gonna continue to happen because the Meta reality is that there's no way to make money with big games without that.
Rym: Under modern capitalism, you're gonna see that same creep everywhere.
Rym: Uh, I mean, there's a real Failing.
Scott: they also have made some failing games like the that MOBA the crowd.
Rym: So I feel like a good company can rise out of the ashes of this.
Rym: but the word Ashes, there's a load-bearing word in my scent.
Scott: at the end of the day no matter what happens There will be a company that owns the rights to Diablo Starcraft Warcraft Etc.
Scott: And that company has value no matter what because those brands are so valuable, you know.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so it's just a little video.
Rym: The it's titled if this doesn't win the spill to see our next month And that award means nothing.
Rym: and all the video.
Rym: you don't even need to understand anything.
Rym: that's happening in the video.
Rym: read any text.
Rym: But if you watch the video, you will see people playing a game.
Rym: You will be able to endure it into it from the video which is less than a minute long.
Rym: what the rules are to this game?
Rym: This game is amazing.
Rym: I would love to see it played in like a PAX or something like an omega-thon.
Rym: I'm not even joking.
Rym: and this game involves Cash money and mousetraps and blindfolds and that's all I'm gonna say.
Scott: I mean if real but like, you know, they're joking if this doesn't win this field this yard.
Scott: But it's like a game that you can a just looking at it.
Scott: You want to play it B You don't even need to be taught the rules.
Scott: You can figure them out by looking at it.
Scott: Yeah, it's like a game that can do those two things is already like.
Scott: No, you need a genius designer.
Rym: What do we say at all our panels?
Rym: Those two things we talked so much about.
Rym: elegance.
Rym: Nothing is more elegant than a game that Scott just described.
Rym: you look at the board and you go Oh, I know exactly how this game works.
Scott: And you're right.
Rym: Yeah, that's the key.
Scott: You're right Napoli and say I know how this works and be wrong.
Rym: You cannot look at this and you and I both looked at scythe and had an idea about what that game was.
Scott: Yeah, we're wrong.
Scott: Yeah All right.
Scott: So another thing of the day.
Scott: So a lot of computer sciency people.
Scott: They love to have these sort of programming competitions where pro you write programs that compete against each other at a game, right?
Scott: It's like hey everyone write a chess bot We'll have a have the chess bots have have a chess tournament and we'll see which one wins Right, and then you're I guess the best AI programmer, right?
Scott: So a lot of those Projects back in the day used to be you would just program at a bunch of you know hard coded heuristics Which could be very strong And often are still the way to go.
Rym: I mean watch me play Bomberman for real and I follow some very simple flow chart rules that will often win me a game.
Scott: Nowadays, you might do some machine learning when your heuristics, you know, can't get you over the last mile or whatever.
Scott: So here someone made a competition of basic programming Bomberman bots.
Scott: it involves co-op and competitive because sometimes you might have teams And I don't even know what all the rules are because they didn't read them all.
Scott: But it's a competition called Bomberland where you have to program a Bomberman bot a Program that will play Bomberman and compete against other programs playing Bomberman to attempt to win at Bomberman and that is Pretty good.
Scott: That is anyone entering this.
Rym: Yeah, I you know what I want to see.
Rym: I want to see like two years from now and SGDQ where they show off like the ultimate AI that exists in this game.
Scott: somehow I don't know.
Scott: But yeah, you can you can enter this thing.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I think it's an ongoing kind of thing.
Rym: It's not like a one-shot team In the meta moment the game has.
Rym: book club book is the tale of Genji.
Rym: I did not read this weekend, but I was reading for a while ahead of Scott.
Rym: So I think we're still on track to finish in October.
Scott: It's weird because if you look at the Kindle report at the bottom, it says I'm like 30% done, right?
Scott: But if you look at the chapter number this 50 something chapters and I'm on chapter 20 something that feels like I'm halfway.
Rym: Is it a Prince of nothing situation where there's like a hundred pages of glossary?
Scott: I do.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know either a this big chapters coming up that are long or B There's some sort of post credits shit that's taking up a pile of pages Making me think I'm not as far along as I am or C both.
Rym: Yep Find out we are steamrolling along as Genji continues to sleepwalk through life Discarding women left and right in his pursuit of the little girl.
Rym: He's attracted to that.
Rym: He wants to groom into his perfect wife to replace the woman who spurned him.
Rym: kinda Man Genji kind of a shitbag.
Scott: Yeah Any other meta things we will not be at literally any convention even if they might happen.
Scott: Yeah, and if you don't believe us about like we've already not gone to conventions But like we have hockey tickets that we paid for and we're not going to the hockey game.
Scott: Yeah We're just losing money technically.
Scott: So we're not losing money.
Scott: The money's already lost.
Rym: at least those were preseason games.
Scott: that that's what are you gonna do in a few?
Scott: Weeks, and there's a real game you gonna go.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: I haven't thought about that yet.
Rym: I'm just compartmentalizing that I'm gonna think about it this weekend.
Rym: You better think fast, yep But otherwise our discords rocking.
Rym: we're playing games we're doing stuff.
Rym: It's still warm outside enough to.
Rym: we're still biking a lot, but we're working on some projects.
Rym: I'm working on some panels that might just turn into online panels.
Rym: Not at any particular convention.
Scott: We'll say I had an idea for a thing and then I actually went to do the thing and it turned out to be not As great an idea as I thought.
Scott: so didn't do it.
Rym: I still think it's a good idea But you're gonna.
Rym: you gotta wait until you see one of your sources and you're inspired like you see it.
Rym: You're like, that's the one.
Scott: I don't think it's gonna happen.
Rym: The problem is you're not gonna watch enough of that kind of content to find the one.
Rym: Anyway, I mean I'm still working on.
Rym: I need to.
Rym: I failed and it looks like other people failed to get mega team fortress to work with quake online because the online multiplayer doesn't seem to work with it, but Instead I looks like I can get it to work locally so I can at least get the footage Material and analysis.
Rym: I need to do that our other panel I was talking about.
Scott: you could also get it to work with the not Remaster.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I could do it that way.
Scott: I think the only thing is every player would have to install the mod themselves Identical and then you have to run the server and then everyone have to type in the IP address of the server.
Scott: Oh,
Rym: I'd have to run it like completely old-school the way I would have before the quick remaster even existed
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: which we'll see if I do that or if I just play the game locally and run around with a rocket and a stopwatch And analyze the video to figure out what I need to figure out.
Scott: Yeah, I went online and I downloaded just some maps not mods just maps, you know to get some more deathmatch variation And they totally worked in the remaster.
Rym: But you didn't make that JSON file that you need to make them show up in the menu.
Scott: Even if you did that, it doesn't matter.
Scott: The problem is that if I start a server and someone joins the server They'll just be disconnected because they don't have the map.
Scott: it won't automatically download the map to them from the server.
Scott: Yeah You have to independently go and get the map and put it in the folder themselves in order to actually play multiplayer.
Scott: So I could do that and I could just give you a zip file to all my friends and we could all install the same Maps that I found on the internet or I could just give you the link and you could install the same maps.
Scott: But we couldn't get more players in easily because they would have to you know Right and we couldn't communicate with them because they wouldn't get into the server.
Scott: Yes, we switch to a normal map.
Rym: now I just look forward to quake to getting the similar treatment because I am confident they will support the popular mods in quake 2 Because nobody would play quake 2 online much unless they included action quake support and lithium deathmatch support.
Scott: There is no reason that any mod that is simply maps, you know, and you know Sounds you know those sorts of things right and not anything that modifies the exe file should not just work.
Rym: So, yep.
Rym: So, uh, yeah that aside we'll get right into it continuing our two-week long Odyssey into magazines.
Rym: We're talking about gaming magazines, which there's way too many to talk about even all the ones we read But any magazines were the biggest deal.
Scott: right if you were a kid in the 90s, there was no internet.
Scott: There was no other news source.
Rym: Like if you were a mega nerd like at the mega ist of nerd you could dial into a BBS that would have information about games.
Scott: maybe Maybe but yet there was.
Scott: games were a big thing especially video games and there was no information source For video games that was widely available.
Scott: There wasn't a TV show about video games.
Scott: Oh, he's not one that had news regularly, right?
Scott: There was like that one work of the game show where kids would run around collecting NES cartridges or Captain N. Yeah, but those didn't give you video game news.
Scott: You might see some a few TV commercials for video games.
Scott: you might see some ads for video games in like a comic book magazine ads in comic books and piece and dot.
Rym: I almost had PC games and ads on TV were how I found out.
Scott: about 90% of the video games I cared about might find out about games just because someone else has them.
Scott: you might go to Toys R Us And look at the wall of games and just see one that you never saw before.
Rym: Yeah, you might go to that local blockbuster and rent every NES game one by one.
Scott: Oh, yeah Yeah, but yet to get information about video games.
Scott: The only real way was magazines.
Scott: That was it, you know Cuz no one's uncle actually worked at Nintendo unless you lived in Redmond, Washington.
Rym: Right it.
Rym: every fucking kid you knew had an uncle who worked at Nintendo and told you a lot of secrets that were not real.
Scott: They were not true, but they tell.
Scott: then there was the Japanese kid who came who's family moved from.
Scott: you know Japan for real.
Scott: who?
Scott: in fourth grade when everyone said what do you want for Christmas?
Scott: He said he wanted a Super Nintendo and everyone was like that doesn't exist.
Rym: I Have a similar story.
Scott: It was we thought he.
Scott: we thought he was making up his uncle working at Nintendo.
Rym: I think this was first grade.
Rym: I might have been second grade.
Rym: I'm going based on Remembering what the classroom looked like but we had a guest who came in.
Rym: She was the mother of a Japanese exchange student who was in the school.
Rym: so she flew over the u.s.
Rym: And she came to our school and She was just like answering questions of all these first graders about Japan.
Rym: and then at the end She was like, hey tell me a word and I'll teach you how to write it in Japanese and I raised my hand first.
Rym: I was super excited and I was like Famicom and The teacher and all the kids were like what the fuck and she was like, ah Famicom.
Rym: And she was real excited about that.
Rym: and we talked about the NES for a while.
Scott: Yeah, anyway Say there was no way to get information about video games except magazines and video games were a big deal.
Rym: Yeah, like before we were born like both of us.
Rym: our families had Atari's and televisions.
Scott: Yeah video game video games were a big deal in the 80s and 90s and there were several magazines that were had that sold large numbers of copies.
Rym: now to be clear not just video games because tabletop Dungeons & Dragons like that was also big in the 70s.
Scott: Like there was also no way to get news about those other than magazines.
Scott: mainstream.
Scott: You know things that publish news about all sorts of topics like newspapers or you know More general magazines didn't talk about that stuff.
Scott: You had to get a specialized magazine.
Scott: Yeah, no other news source that was widely available.
Rym: So I guess we'll go and cut a lot.
Rym: Not only that when one showed up like that we were subscribed to.
Rym: Usually it was the fight with me and my brother if we got to read it first followed by it being read and reread and re re re read for an entire month until the next one came
Scott: out
Rym: I Would spend a lot of time looking at screenshots of games.
Rym: I'd never played imagining what they might be like.
Rym: So just like last week We'll go in vague chronological order and the one I remember the earliest one I remember was literally just called electronic games and I mostly experienced I know that one existed.
Scott: I don't think I ever actually read it.
Rym: I experienced it by reading back issues that were like on coffee tables and like on shelves at relatives houses Like I think my uncle had them this - this was talking about like Atari Games and in television games
Scott: and that one goes way back to like the Commodore, you know You know Apple PC type era.
Rym: Yeah, like this is.
Rym: this magazine started in 1981 like before I was even born, but yeah, there was no NES.
Rym: But that was an era when I was too young to even seek out information.
Rym: so I would just read like kids often don't have a sense of time in the pre internet era in that I would get a Bloom County comic or a Dunesbury comic or a Mad Magazine from the 60s like Mad Magazine from the 60s was a Big example where as a kid, that's just this is a funny thing I'm reading and I have no like sense of place or time of the where this artifact came from.
Rym: So I'd be reading these electronic games magazines being really excited about like Atari 2600 or Commodore games that were already very old that I just didn't know about But the one you didn't have a lot of information But the one that like changed everything was Nintendo Power.
Rym: for me That was we I remember so clearly.
Rym: we were in a superstore in Michigan I think was a Meyers which was one of those like Walmart adjacent type places and we're doing grocery shopping and we hurrying our parents into walking through the video game aisle and we saw a Magazine there called Nintendo Power.
Rym: It was in fact the first issue of Nintendo Power and we Convinced our parents to buy it.
Rym: It wasn't cheap for compared to magazines at the time and we basically convinced them to subscribe to it.
Rym: We didn't actually get one delivered for like two more months so we had to go back and buy the second issue but starting with the third issue it came and Nintendo Power was my primary interface into the world of gaming
Scott: Pretty
Rym: much up until like early high school like late middle school.
Scott: So I didn't get Nintendo Power.
Scott: not because I didn't enjoy it.
Scott: I bought a few and my brother had a subscription I guess in the n64 days.
Rym: He says wow We unsubscribed in the n64 days.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, the reason I didn't go for Nintendo Power is you know I would read one now and again at a friend's house and ever and I'd be like, whoa, right?
Scott: I'd enjoyed it greatly.
Scott: but even my kid with brain was like Nintendo makes this magazine.
Scott: It's not independent.
Scott: I can't be trusting this.
Rym: Ah, see I thought of it differently.
Scott: I did not subscribe to Nintendo Power.
Scott: I know its contents entertained me greatly.
Rym: I knew most Nintendo games for crap.
Rym: I knew most video games were crap because I grew up with in the target in television before we even had in any s. But the Nintendo games that were good were so high quality.
Rym: and I wasn't reading Nintendo Power to get news about games.
Rym: I was reading it to learn about Nintendo games I didn't have access to to figure out if they were worth buying not based on their games.
Rym: I didn't know I didn't read the words.
Rym: when I think back to being a kid.
Scott: I barely read the words.
Scott: Oh, I read all the words.
Rym: I read the words like after the fact I'd mostly look at the images look at like maps of games Like I remember looking at the maps of levels of Strider To decide if Strider was worth buying at a garage sale.
Scott: because I saw some actually read all the words in the magazines I bought.
Rym: I'd go back and read all the words like later, but mostly I was reading Nintendo Power not to get news.
Rym: I was reading Nintendo Power because every issue had at least one article that gave some insight into like the Japanese side of Nintendo or like like a name of someone like Miyamoto would like be mentioned or like so something about.
Rym: hey Mario 3, you know, it's coming but here's some like screenshots from it.
Rym: and that's what I was reading Nintendo Power for.
Rym: and then secondarily I was reading it to get tips about Nintendo games.
Rym: I was struggling to beat.
Scott: Hmm well, yeah tips are a thing.
Scott: So I bought Game Pro, I think I started.
Rym: Oh games driving to Game Pro.
Scott: the first issue I got Magazine world way late.
Scott: Yeah yeah had Mortal Kombat 2 on the cover and It had inside a guide for doing combos in Super Street Fighter 2 Turbo right or yeah, Super Street Fighter 2 in the arcade, right?
Rym: So I went for reviews compared to Nintendo Power.
Scott: Well, so with Game Pro, right, you know I was reading all the words the letters.
Scott: column was a lot of fun.
Scott: Yeah, you know the the editors had all these personalities.
Scott: The biggest most famous editor was scary Larry who I'm pretty sure works at Nintendo Company and or still works there.
Scott: He's we definitely did work there.
Scott: I think he still does.
Scott: And then you know, there would be a section in the back that you know had a few pages of like arcade stuff and foreign Stuff.
Scott: right, you know, like oh my god, look at this machine.
Scott: One arcade machine.
Scott: You'll never play.
Scott: Yeah, right There were some tips and things in there but often they were not for games that I had so they didn't help me that much.
Scott: Yeah, I was mostly just actually looking at you know news from the world of you know Video games like.
Rym: what's happening was definitely more like news and reviews for me as opposed to Nintendo Power, which was mostly tips and tricks.
Scott: Yeah, so But yeah, I subscribed to Game Pro like even up until the all the way through college.
Scott: I think I stopped subscribing when he lived in Beacon at some point Mmm, and then I gave all the magazine to some teacher who used him for a craft project.
Scott: I think They're all in archive or online.
Rym: you can we ever actually subscribe to Game Pro?
Rym: I just like read copies of it laying around read him in Walden books that kind of thing and I'd Subscribe to it.
Scott: I got every single for like years and years and years.
Scott: I got every single one.
Scott: It definitely went downhill over time as those editors all left and all those writers left.
Scott: It was literally just at some point, you know You're just printing what big game companies wanted them to print right ads advertorials.
Rym: Yeah, that's our.
Rym: but that even for me We're still way later because even before I was reading Nintendo Power like around the same time I was getting Dragon magazine, but not subscription.
Rym: that shit wasn't cheap either.
Rym: I was buying random one-off episodes of our episodes issues of Dragon magazine With like my allowance money at the local gaming store from like this giant cardboard box of just one's going back into the 70s.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't do that because I was like I ever bought.
Scott: I don't did I ever buy a dragon or dungeon magazine.
Rym: I probably bought easily 50 or 60 Individual issues of Dragon magazine before I was able to afford to a subscription to Dragon magazine Long time when in the era where D&D was the only TTRPG for me right in the in those days You know high school college earlier.
Scott: Oh, yeah, you started way later than me, but I was also He middle school out played.
Scott: but I was basically like a core book only person, right?
Scott: I was like member in college that you guys would always buy like, you know When third edition was the thing you guys are always buying like sword and this or cuz.
Scott: that's where I was like, oh, sorry I was like.
Scott: I do not buy any extra stuff I buy.
Scott: my place is look Dragon magazine was the magazine.
Scott: Dragon magazine felt to me like Extra extra stuff except it wasn't what your.
Rym: but the funny thing is that was basically dungeon magazine.
Rym: Dragon magazine was pretty much a lot of commentary Advice news ads Miniature nonsense like there was a lot going even at video game reviews.
Rym: But I just think there was a lot going on in Dragon magazine, but it wasn't just here's supplements for your game.
Rym: It was mostly commentary and articles and stuff just like long I mean, I saw a dragon magazine at the game store, but yeah I never.
Scott: I don't think I ever really read it that I didn't have.
Scott: I think there was a comic that was in it.
Rym: There were multiple comics in it.
Rym: nights at the dinner table is the one a lot of people remember which?
Scott: well That's its own thing now, right?
Rym: Yeah, but a few other print I think.
Rym: oh, what was the name?
Rym: There was one about a henchling.
Rym: I forget what it was even called.
Rym: There's a bunch of comics in it.
Rym: It had a but it had a whole like comic section at the end, but it was so dense with content that I read dragon magazine religiously Pretty much through all of elementary school and into middle school.
Rym: in the era before I had people to play D&D with and then in.
Rym: But I finally had people to play with when we were playing either rules cyclopedia D&D or like a D&D first edition.
Rym: By then I was playing actively and also using dragon magazine And I subscribed to it well into RIT.
Rym: dragon magazine was like a big part of my life until I don't remember a dragon Magazine ever showing up at the apartment.
Rym: Yeah, they arrived.
Rym: I kept getting them.
Rym: I had them.
Rym: There's a giant pile.
Scott: I never remember a single.
Rym: Yeah, I you never read it.
Rym: You never seem to go.
Scott: I didn't But I didn't read it.
Rym: dragon magazine was pretty legit.
Rym: The only complaint I really have about it as like having escaped the orbit of Dungeons & Dragons was that dragon magazine's essays were very typical of the D&D discourse that happens today just on the internet where People were writing big essays about how to fix problems that are only problems if you're an insufferable shithead.
Scott: I Because people don't change right?
Scott: Yeah, it's like they're still playing the same game D&D.
Scott: Yeah, and you're still a shithead.
Scott: So you're gonna right have the same problem and write the same solution over and over again And you're not gonna stop playing D&D or every D&D Conversation.
Rym: the discourse that
Scott: is gonna stop being a bad person that has
Rym: happened about the rules Seems to all be the same as the article I read in dragon magazine as a kid called romancing the stone skin, which was about Literally how to prevent your players in second ed D&D and a D&D from abusing the stone skin smell because that was considered a Significant problem and I cannot describe to you how much discourse there was about that specific problem on.
Rym: It was an alt fan D&D whatever the whatever the alt net board was for Dungeons & Dragons.
Scott: So the other big thing I guess is mostly middle school times, you know late late middle school was you know?
Scott: Magic the Gathering when CCG's became a thing.
Rym: Yeah, there were only two magazines.
Rym: Scry is no inquest.
Scott: Yeah, there were no way to get news about those either other than magazines.
Scott: So there was inquest magazine scry magazine and I think another one that we didn't have.
Scott: the internet says there was one called duelist But I never had that.
Rym: Everyone I knew would talk about scry when I was in middle school like big into magic.
Rym: So one day scry was.
Scott: there was scrying inquest.
Scott: at the time I felt like they were both kind of equal and they were both honestly super shitty.
Scott: Yeah, that they didn't really.
Scott: they were mostly just ads for you know.
Rym: Oh, I was even working out.
Rym: scry was mostly the sheet of the current going rate of every magic card.
Scott: Yep, because there weren't there were so few at the time that you could put them all in a magazine.
Rym: Yeah for a complete price card I would borrow my friend's copy of scry just to keep up to date on what my magic cards were worth so I could go sell The ones that were valuable to make money to buy more magic cards.
Rym: That was like a big part of my middle school life was selling valuable magic cards to get more really magic.
Scott: These magazines did not have any helpful information in terms of strategy, you know, oh scry was absolute Garbage content.
Rym: other than that priceless like it was just.
Scott: it was just ads just buying into the might as well.
Rym: I've just been Laura Mipson text for all.
Rym: I gave a shit about scry.
Scott: Yeah, but CCG's were such a big thing at the time and there was no information source for them.
Scott: So if you were into them those mag and you didn't have you weren't like part of a community because you were just a little kid.
Scott: Yeah, the magazine was like your key to knowing what the hell was going on.
Scott: Like, you know knowing that there was a new set coming to the comic shop, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I didn't know otherwise that would have showed up seen Ice Age and we're like, what the hell is that?
Scott: Yeah, thanks to the magazine.
Scott: I knew what the hell it was.
Rym: The full title of scry was technically scry collectible card game checklist and a price guide.
Rym: Yep, that tells you everything you need to know about it though.
Rym: fun fact dragon magazine was how I learned about magic the gathering because remember interesting.
Rym: so there was a D&D CCG that came out right after magic where they tried to hop on that train like everyone did.
Rym: it was terrible It was so bad.
Rym: But dragon magazine had an article about magic the gathering where an editor like played it and reviewed it and I was fascinated.
Rym: But kid brain I didn't realize they were talking about magic.
Rym: So I bought the D&D collectible card game and it was so bad that I like was offended.
Rym: But - I think it was - two or three dragon magazines later All the articles were about how every D&D group got completely ruined because the players don't want to play D&D They show up and then they want to play magic.
Scott: It's a better game.
Rym: Yeah But that was like the -.
Rym: I learned
Scott: about magic because some kid I was friends with brought it over to my house and we Played it and then I saw the box the little starter box that his revised starter box And I was like, I've seen those at the store on the counter now I know what the hell that is.
Rym: I started playing I started playing in the middle of unlimited run anyway.
Scott: So last some last magazines here.
Scott: There's a magazine that I've read a couple times I haven't bought it called Game Informer.
Scott: And the thing that's notable about Game Informer is that it's owned by Gamestop Yeah, so even worse.
Scott: I don't know if it still is but it might still be if it still exists.
Scott: Yeah, Gamestop is still the publisher Yeah, but even worse than Nintendo Power, right?
Scott: There was official PlayStation magazine things like that which were effectively the same as Nintendo Power But a magazine owned by the retailer felt to me as even worse than that, right?
Rym: So apparently it's a weird scam.
Rym: In 2017 the total circulation of Game Informer was 7.5 million and it was the fifth most popular magazine in America.
Scott: It's huge.
Scott: Absolutely huge.
Rym: But it appears that almost all of that circulation was copies that were put into Gamestops that no one ever read.
Scott: Also true Also, I think like if you were like doing if you were a big kid who is doing a lot of you know If we were younger, we would have been those kids who were constantly buying and selling games.
Scott: Oh, yeah Gamestop.
Rym: That's why I don't begrudge those kids.
Scott: I think if you did that and you got the Gamestop card and stuff you got Game Informer.
Rym: Yeah, by then I was already an internet citizen and I didn't need any of that crap anymore.
Rym: But yeah, I understand why kids are the way they are.
Scott: Yeah, so Game Informer was a thing.
Scott: so there was in the.
Scott: there was also the PC gaming magazines, right?
Scott: So the thing about the PC gaming magazines that set them apart was a. they could come with games.
Rym: You couldn't do that for like, you know that the sole reason I subscribed to PC gamer was to get that fucking disc and later That CD.
Scott: I didn't subscribe.
Scott: I would just buy issues on the shelf if I saw that the CD was advertising games that I didn't already have demos of or shareware of Cuz.
Scott: they'll always share where.
Scott: they never gave you full versions on that.
Rym: Oh, no thing is as a kid Kind of didn't matter.
Rym: I played the doom shareware for a long time.
Rym: It was perfectly happy with it.
Rym: I never had the real version of One Must Fall 2097 or Rapture Call of the Shadows.
Scott: But I wouldn't had any version if it wasn't for a PC gamer CD-ROM.
Rym: Yep PC gamer which also had that racist coconut monkey caricature.
Scott: That's coconut monkey.
Scott: So if you put that CD-ROM in your computer, it wasn't just a CD-ROM full of demos.
Scott: There was sort of like this little application that was sort of like a front end.
Rym: I installed that shit every time I got an issue.
Rym: That was an era when you could take a random disc sent to you by a magazine and it honestly wouldn't fuck your computer up And they would put little Easter eggs in it and it was cute and sometimes funny.
Rym: But yeah nerds would like scrutinize the files on those discs and later those CDs to like try to figure stuff out about games.
Scott: But PC gamers mascot was this racist coconut monkey.
Scott: That would be like hello.
Scott: I am coconut monkey.
Scott: Yeah, it's like whoa, dude.
Scott: Whoa at the time.
Scott: I thought it was just a cute monkey, but now it's like whoa.
Rym: Yep, like Apu was offensive as a caricature and coconut monkey is way worse than a coconut monkey like Left through warp speed beyond Apu into a terrifying realm that as a white kid growing up in the Midwest I did not even like get it.
Scott: Yeah There were some other PC gaming Magazines besides PC gamer even though PC gamer was the biggest one and they also had CDs a game where I think also felt like the most Respected one.
Scott: Yeah, definitely I think.
Scott: the other thing that said PC gaming magazines apart was that they would talk about hardware.
Scott: you GamePro would never talk about hardware.
Scott: It was all about games.
Scott: right and Nintendo was only about Nintendo games PC gamer.
Scott: You would see ads like voodoo card.
Rym: Yeah, PC gamers How I learned about like glide drivers and like when video cards became a thing for real what the deal was with video cards.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's why we mentioned it even a little bit in our tech Episode because it was like partially a tech magazine.
Scott: right because it was PCs and the games that you played on them together.
Rym: Yeah and pretty much for me PC gamer like the content was great right up until I stopped reading it and the sole reason I Stopped subscribing to PC gamer was the internet.
Rym: 100% replaced everything.
Rym: I was getting out of PC gamer.
Scott: I can download demos now.
Scott: Bye.
Rym: Also, hey people are reviewing games online.
Rym: All right, cool.
Rym: I don't even I don't even trust game reviews anymore.
Rym: yeah, I don't read reviews like I died like I don't know if it's obvious but We basically don't use game reviews at all.
Rym: Like I don't use reviews of anything, right?
Scott: It's like a lot of board game people are like out there, you know going to like.
Scott: there's all this board game media.
Rym: You know like so-and-so, you know, I almost never read game reviews of any kind.
Scott: I only don't play games and I do not consume reviews of pretty much media Period movie reviews book reviews nothing.
Scott: I just don't.
Scott: I don't need them.
Scott: I know what I want.
Scott: All I need to know is what it is and when the release date is.
Rym: I will sometimes read a review mostly when I'm doing research for a panel or trying to get better at a game but Not to decide if I like the game or not or should buy it or not.
Rym: for sure Hmm.
Scott: So just brief mentions.
Scott: There was a magazine called EGM.
Scott: It's like trying to gain.
Rym: Oh, yeah Stay tuned Scott.
Rym: Yeah, stay tuned.
Scott: I don't know if it still exists.
Rym: Oh, it still exists.
Scott: I found it Okay But does it still?
Rym: if anyone knows what the fuck I'm referencing you are one of the original listeners of GeekNights.
Rym: I'll just leave it at that.
Scott: I don't know if it's still in print, but it was like to me.
Scott: it was the most generic Gaming magazine like.
Scott: it just covered all video games Reprinted press releases, you know just industry shill.
Scott: You don't have anything valid but it.
Rym: but I
Scott: Also have this memory that probably would be confirmed if I bothered to google it that it had a long history Right that like old like it feels like that was an old magazine That had you know, like a history of being really good and then just fell from grace over time.
Scott: That's like.
Scott: that's what my I don't know if electronic gaming monthly is related to electronic games, which is an old magazine.
Scott: So there could be some confusion.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: and then lastly I want to give a brief mention to games magazine Which is not much of a magazine.
Scott: It's mostly crossword puzzles and things like that.
Rym: Oh, oh, yeah I know what you're talking about.
Scott: Yeah It's basically this magazine that comes out and it has like a variety of you know, little puzzles crossword word search Cryptograms all that sort of stuff, but I think it's notable, you know, because you could just buy a collection of those puzzles.
Scott: Why would you buy games magazine?
Scott: There are two things I remember about games magazine.
Scott: granted I haven't read one since the 90s.
Scott: is that a?
Scott: it would actually talk about like, you know things happening in the sort of the Puzzle game adjacent world.
Scott: It was like a little bit.
Scott: It did have some content in the front And I think it might have even had a letters column.
Scott: but B it was sort of like this hotbed of You know, like here's a new kind of puzzle right and things like that like puzzles you hadn't seen.
Scott: there isn't some collection of like a Thousand of these puzzles in a book because they weren't sure yet if that kind of puzzle was gonna be popular.
Scott: So It's like before.
Scott: there was a book with like a thousand Sudoku's in it because Sudoku wasn't a big thing in.
Scott: the u.s Right games magazine would have a Sudoku in it.
Scott: Yeah And then that's how they found out that Sudoku was a big deal.
Rym: as to think it is I don't know so long as I kind of last and least Dungeon magazine which I didn't really actually talk about the deal with that one.
Rym: Oh, I never subscribed to it because it was way expensive.
Scott: Well, I just knew it existed.
Scott: I never looked at it.
Rym: So it wasn't like the sister to dragon magazine in any real way.
Rym: It was just if dragon magazine was.
Rym: essays articles content.
Rym: dungeon magazine was.
Rym: here are four modules.
Rym: Every issue was just.
Rym: here are specific modules for D&D games.
Rym: You can just run these as a game master.
Rym: The idea was only game masters subscribe to it and read it and players were encouraged not to read it because it had like The stories that your game master might just run for you But the way I would be less expensive than buying actual modules.
Rym: Yep, it was also a way just to find interesting modules Like it was just.
Rym: it was a wide range of content But generally what I would do is buy old back issues from the dollar bin at that same game store.
Scott: I'm an easy like that.
Scott: It's like there's.
Scott: no it doesn't matter.
Rym: It's like the only ones are better one.
Rym: because my players were very much less likely to have read a dungeon magazine from like mmm, I Want to say it's.
Rym: I don't think I actually had any issues of dungeon magazine from before like the late 80s.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I didn't even see a magazine.
Rym: so it's probably early 90s.
Scott: Yeah, so yeah when it comes to gaming especially magazines were the key way to get news about it in the 80s 90s.
Scott: Yeah, the internet became a thing in the mid 2000s.
Scott: And so being nerds of the time.
Scott: We read a lot of them nowadays.
Scott: They're useless.
Scott: They don't never reason to exist.
Rym: Yep, and the content that was really timeless from these things mostly essays has migrated online pretty effectively.
Scott: There is a lot of thankfully scans of most of these magazines are on the internet.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but also just people are writing very insightful essays on game design and games Even just for free and putting them online like that content is just out there.
Rym: or Twitter threads?
Scott: Yeah, there are Twitter thread to subscribe to get to a magazine to get the equivalent of a current Twitter thread I get for free.
Rym: Yeah Now I can just follow Cole early on Twitter and he'll just throw insights at me randomly.
Scott: people on board game geek Just throw down whole like these design diaries.
Rym: It's like, alright, that's This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leaf or web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: Geeknights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi McNichol Ellen Joyce link eg dread Lily Tenerbrae Chris for armor Clinton Walton decks Finn just like a dude guy.
Rym: kashaya Hi 85.
Rym: Rebecca Dunn review mad bull 34 cowards Ryan Perrin Sam Erickson sure I'm on home Taylor Braun underground pro law.
Rym: it appears right.
Rym: seed ab threat open.
Rym: You hold the key to my heart and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: so yeah, if you plug professional audio equipment like say the beta 87 a microphone that I have plugged into a audio device via USB and all this nonsense and you try to use it in something like zoom or discord what you'll often find is That you are quieter than other people.
Rym: The main reason for that is that to ensure that you're not clipping and to take advantage of all the headroom on such a professional device you tend to have Relatively low levels so that even very large spikes are Accommodated by the hardware.
Rym: and then in post-production or in live like say on the stream you run it through a compressor.
Rym: But generally consumer level stuff and gamer headsets will pre compress the audio to make it Apparently louder.
Rym: so you have compressed audio where you've lost fidelity but it has a total higher average amplitude compared to Audio that has a lower average amplitude because it can accommodate and Include all of that extra information that would otherwise be lost.
Rym: with all of this combined Basically fancy microphones sound quieter in things like zoom and discord than crappy gamer microphones.
Rym: So, uh, there's really no easy way around that unless I actually have discord.
Rym: pick up a mix Separate from my main direct input and run that through a processor that will compress the audio and then amplify it.
Rym: So, yeah, there you have it.
Rym: But anyway for right now, I leave you with Christianity again.
Scott: after cowboys you went all the way back around.
Scott: Oh god.
Scott: Why can't I die?