Rym: It's Monday, November 1st, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, on the 16th anniversary of fucking GeekNights, we're talking about documentation.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: It's all- I'm happy that we started GeekNights back in 2005 on Halloween.
Scott: Even though- We didn't start it on Halloween.
Scott: We started it before Halloween.
Scott: And then somehow, coincidentally, I don't even feel like we realized that the first real episode was Halloween.
Scott: We just sort of were like, "That's good enough to go
Scott: live.".
Scott: And then later on, it was just like, "When's our anniversary?
Scott: Oh, Halloween,
Scott: okay.".
Rym: So years ago, I actually told the exact story of how we did this.
Rym: Because remember, for the Patreon people, I remastered with better audio all of the beta episodes, re-uploaded them, and I recorded commentary tracks for all of them.
Rym: So I listened to all that early beta GeekNights.
Rym: The decision point we made was specific- The one good news is, if anyone goes and listens to them on the Patreon now, while the content is unlistenable, the audio is at least listenable.
Rym: I learned a lot since back then, and I also was able to salvage some of that Logitech audio in ways that I even surprised myself.
Rym: Good lord.
Rym: So, way back, we actually published our first episode.
Rym: It was the following episode, like a November 1st or 2nd episode.
Rym: We then decided, "Hey, the episode we did one before this, actually, we think it was pretty good.
Rym: Let's also make that one
Rym: public.".
Rym: And we went back and published the previously unpublished October 31st episode.
Scott: I mean, I do recommend that pattern, right?
Scott: If you're going to make a continuing content of some kind, right?
Scott: I guess maybe that's not right.
Scott: Because let's say you're writing a series, like a book, and you're doing a chapter by chapter.
Scott: You can't write some beta chapters and make chapter three actually chapter one and throw out chapter one and two.
Rym: Maybe you could, but...
Scott: Yeah, but like a podcast, they're all standalone, so yeah, you can throw some out.
Scott: But it's like, I guess the art process is generally going to be like sketches, whether it's literal sketches or just practice drawings, practice whatever it is you do.
Scott: Make short movies, songs, practice meh ones.
Scott: You start out by not sharing them with anyone because they're too awful.
Scott: And then people seem to jump from not sharing with anyone to share with the world, and I guess you can do that.
Scott: But I guess the path we took of share with no one, share with close people only to make sure if they give you the thumbs up, then go to the world.
Scott: It's like you can hide some more of your trash from the world and also have some beta episodes hidden away for fun times in the future.
Rym: But also, this quote gets misused more and more lately, but the idea of making the machine.
Rym: that makes the machine.
Rym: Those episodes, the purpose wasn't to make content for us and every process is different.
Rym: Our goal there was specifically to figure out how to make a podcast at all.
Rym: We were learning a process.
Rym: The episodes that got recorded were just artifacts of that process.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You might be wondering why I'm wearing sunglasses inside of a podcast.
Rym: I mean, you might be wondering why I have a mustache like.
Rym: it's the year 1997 and I'm back in high school.
Scott: Yeah, but it's that time of year where the earth tilts upwards in the wrong direction, so up away from the sun.
Scott: So the sun now, because I have a south facing window right here to my right, the sun late in the day, like currently five, but I guess starting next week, it'll be around like four.
Scott: There's a period right before sunset where the sun just blasts right straight through these giant windows, right into my face, my monitors.
Scott: And it caught me today at like an even worse angle than last Friday and blasted me right in the fucking eyes.
Scott: So my eyes hurt.
Rym: It's even funnier because around that time is when, because the buildings around the garden behind our building are set up, it's pitch black out the window right now.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: It's dark now.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But, uh, but even though the lights on, yeah, it gets dark before then.
Rym: So yeah.
Rym: Anyway, uh, so my mustache is because I did something that I've threatened to do for years, but I never did it.
Rym: You know, there's a history in RIT anime of I was poor.
Rym: I was also lazy and I had very little free time despite being so lazy.
Scott: So I tend to, well, you also, I think you, you didn't care that much.
Scott: I also did not care, but, but you were, but you were up for it.
Rym: You were like, you know, there's, there's this weird dichotomy of, or not dichotomy, the duality of not caring about something enough to do a good job, but caring enough to do the thing at all.
Scott: So like, yes, I want to do that thing as, but not if it requires any work or effort or investment, but if I could just do it, it's like, yeah, it's like, would I love to drive a formula one car if I didn't have to practice driving to not die?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I remember you had to drive one.
Scott: I'll die.
Scott: Therefore I don't.
Scott: Wasn't?
Rym: there's a robotics club at RIT and you asked them, Hey, can I join, but just be the driver of your little robot car?
Rym: And they were like, fuck you.
Rym: No, of course not.
Scott: Well, no, I think that was literally just a race car, the formula, SAE, whatever.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't remember what that, exactly the details there, but yeah, but they weren't looking for a driver only.
Scott: Right.
Rym: They're looking for engineers to work on a car.
Rym: So I, I've threatened for years while a listener even photoshopped me at one point, but, uh, the costume I wore is basically my own body because at least in a photo, my own body looks very close to Sean Connery in the 1974.
Rym: Well, movie Zardoz.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So long ago, someone took the famous Zardoz Sean Connery photo and photoshopped Rym's head onto it.
Scott: I don't know who originally did that.
Scott: Uh, it was too, it was too uncanny.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Whoever did it, uh, it must, it must've been some listener or someone we know.
Scott: I don't know who it is.
Scott: Claim credit, whoever you are.
Scott: Um, I could probably find it if I put in a lot of effort.
Scott: Whoever it was, uh, you know, posted that Photoshop with, uh, you know, Zed from Zardoz, Sean Connery with Rym's head on it.
Scott: And it's like, Oh, you didn't even realize it was not a great job of photoshopping, but it was so, uh, so it's such a match that it didn't need to be a good job.
Scott: It's like, Oh, I didn't even realize that that wasn't, you know, um, so I basically made it real thanks to that person.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And Emily actually printed out a papercraft Zardoz head and, uh, it was a whole thing.
Rym: So, uh, our friends had to see this and now you have to see this too.
Rym: It looks exactly like everyone predicted and expected.
Scott: And, uh, the only thing is I think you got the, you know, get the red suspenders instead of the, the bandolier aspect.
Rym: I constructed this costume basically by getting three things.
Scott: that will four things on Amazon, but that's more effort than I think any costume you've ever worn.
Rym: The boots were $29.
Rym: That costs more than I said.
Rym: I mean, every costume I wore at RIT over the course of five years combined.
Scott: I mean, that's not like cheap, but for a boot, that is the cheap, a cheap boot.
Scott: That is such a cheap boot.
Rym: Uh, I had, I already had a red Speedo and I bought a, I bought Japanese traditional underwear to use as the loincloth and I bought red suspenders and a cheap metal gun.
Rym: So there you go.
Rym: Uh, if I want to approve this, I could, I'd have to make the bandolier or buy it from a place that's not like shadow gray market Amazon because there are no red bandoliers on Amazon.
Rym: I'd have to get a real bandolier.
Rym: that probably costs actual dollars.
Rym: Yeah, I think you could, you could probably for something like that, it's like, yeah, you could be, I'll get two red belts and just put like loops on it and put some like shells and it would be fine.
Scott: You could do something like that.
Scott: That wouldn't be too bad.
Scott: But I think if you wanted it to be like better find another person who's a cosplayer, we might know some.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: Hey, I'll pay you to make a red bandoliers, right?
Scott: Just two of them.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I could probably find a red bandolier if I looked anywhere other than the bottom of the barrel on Amazon.
Scott: There might also be, you know, you might be able to get a white one and just dunk it in some red dye from the craft store, but they're going to be brown.
Scott: They're going to be brown though.
Scott: Usually they're all, they're all black or camouflage.
Rym: The ones that I found.
Scott: Well, a leather one's going to be brown, like an old school one.
Rym: So yeah, we had a little Halloween gathering and that was, that was what came out of that.
Scott: All right, let's move on to some news action.
Rym: We'll see how long I keep this mustache cause I look exactly like how I looked in high school.
Rym: It's, it's actually kind of creepy.
Rym: I look identical to like my senior photos from high school.
Scott: All right, so news.
Scott: So the biggest tech news sort of, uh, you know, this is one of those items where like, is it really a tech news, right?
Scott: It's a business news about a tech company.
Scott: But yeah, everybody knows Facebook is pulling a Google, changing the name.
Scott: So Facebook is the social network now.
Scott: The company is called meta or something like that.
Rym: There's a lot going on here.
Rym: We even talked about this a little bit on Thursday.
Scott: Oculus brand is gone and they've got, you know, they're going to use the meta brand over for all that other stuff.
Scott: And basically, you know, I think this plays into what a lot of people have been saying about Facebook, which is like, yeah, you see them doing all these desperate things, right?
Scott: Trying to get children to use Facebook, you know, fighting, you know, allow, you know, allow it, you know, being so permissive of, uh, uh, bad people, you know, posting bad things on Facebook just to keep the user counts up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, it seems like the evidence suggests, like Facebook itself is not the social network is not doing well.
Scott: They sort of, you know, even though it's so large, it will take a long time for it to like become small and dead, like MySpace.
Scott: But, you know, which wasn't, I guess, if not, if MySpace had been the size of Facebook, it'd probably still be around.
Scott: But it seems to be.
Scott: Facebook is in decline.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And they recognize, I've seen multiple, there's been multiple stories just recently, like the last couple of days of insiders leaking and revealing that even internally, basically everyone in Facebook agrees that the brand, the word Facebook is just pure poison to the outside world.
Rym: Like it is seen like it has shockingly, well, not shockingly, expectedly negative connotations to almost everyone.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So yeah, Facebook is on its own.
Scott: It's, you know, it's still huge, but it's down, it's trending downwards.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So they got this other sideshow and I guess you can see the synergy there, which is like, okay, we made this sort of social network of the beginning of the information age.
Scott: We were the champs in terms of looking at screens and typing text, you know, let's take to survive in the future.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We got, we got to put out multiple game plans.
Scott: If we can't save Facebook, that our game plan will be, you know, even if it's not for quite a while, cause they got a long runway.
Scott: Cause how long will it take for Facebook to die die?
Scott: Right.
Scott: A long time.
Scott: Even if they do nothing.
Scott: So they got this long runway.
Scott: that even though I still say that, you know, the current VR tech is not going to achieve any sort of mass thing.
Scott: for, you know, maybe we'll be seniors by the time.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It's a lot sooner than that.
Rym: You're weirdly pessimistic about this hardware that you've literally never used.
Scott: Anyway, the point is you're not going to see that thing in people's homes being used frequently.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Anytime soon.
Scott: Anyway, the point is that is a future.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, ah, the future social network will be the one we imagine in cyberpunk world in Snow Crash.
Rym: But that already gets away from what a social network has always been.
Rym: Because if a social network is about sharing information, then fire and forget content or fire and forget respond to something like that kind of interaction is the primary way people can share and disseminate information.
Rym: You actually descale if it shrinks back to.
Rym: I'm having a real physical conversation with someone in real time.
Scott: Well, I think the way it lines up is if you think of a social regardless of how you interact in the space, which is obviously drastically different, it's still a space that is not a real world space that people come together in.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I guess the difference is a real Facebook page is a place people come together in.
Scott: a, you know, a chat room is a place people come from all around the world come together.
Scott: So a virtual roar, you know, room like VR chat is a virtual place that where people come together in.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I guess this is where we need to differentiate, because social media is almost too broad of a term now, what these spaces are.
Rym: There are spaces where strangers come together and interact via video or via small chat or via throwing 100 page Tumblr posts at each other or via VR or via inside of a video game.
Rym: All these things have very different affordances, very different user experiences, very different externalities that are intrinsic or possibly not necessarily intrinsic, but are made intrinsic by capitalism.
Rym: It's there's so much going on here that it's very almost naive to talk about all of this as just social media at this point.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So the short term news is that a lot of the oculus stuff is no longer going to need a Facebook account.
Scott: I don't know if that's all of it, but at least some of it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I know the quest they said is which people.
Rym: people resisted what I posited way back when Facebook said they were getting rid of the oculus brand and requiring everyone who uses oculus, including dev kits to have a Facebook account.
Rym: I remember saying the gaming industry won't stand for this.
Rym: And so far it looks like the gaming industry didn't stand for this.
Rym: People truly did not make Facebook accounts.
Rym: They gave up on the platform instead.
Scott: So they gave up on that, which I guess is a positive.
Scott: The negative, I guess, is that it's still the same fucking Zuck dude running this.
Rym: The problem is not that Facebook exists.
Rym: The problem is that Facebook as an institution makes reliably harmful decisions in its space.
Scott: And as we've seen from all the recent, you know, revealings due to court drama and all these documents that got released about, you know, mostly Facebook, but also others is that, yeah, you know, it's not that they Zuck doesn't seem to have a malicious evil motive only other than just the capitalist motive.
Scott: Right.
Scott: All their decisions seem to the thing that they all have in common.
Scott: It's not like they're always deciding in favor of white supremacy or always deciding in favor of, you know, a good point.
Scott: But here's always just.
Scott: they're always deciding in favor of profits for Facebook.
Scott: That is us.
Rym: Every the externalities.
Rym: How do they get profits?
Rym: via engagement?
Rym: What drives engagement, anger and conspiracy theories?
Rym: Therefore, more anger, more conspiracy theories, more profits.
Scott: But there are instances where they decided against anger and conspiracy theories where it either didn't harm or helped the bottom line.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But if it harms that bottom line, they reliably always make right.
Scott: There's a decision between money and safety for the users.
Scott: They choose the money option and don't lose.
Scott: all the stories and anecdotes and all the documents are following that pattern.
Rym: And don't lose and all this shuffle.
Rym: A very important point that all the leaks from within Facebook are showing that there was at no point ignorance involved in this.
Rym: People inside of Facebook at all levels were constantly raising the alarm.
Rym: Like everyone there was smart.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: They knew what they were doing.
Rym: They're like, look, this is causing white supremacy.
Rym: We need to do something about it.
Rym: And they were just categorically ignored.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So I guess just the last thing is simply what everyone else is saying is true is like you what you keep trying to recreate this cyberpunk stuff, you know, VR land from all these books.
Scott: But didn't you miss the point that that was a dystopia, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: In that world, not a good thing.
Rym: People went in.
Scott: Why are you trying to make this?
Scott: It's like reading Dante's Inferno and like using it as your playbook.
Scott: It's like, no, that's the wrong one.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Shadowrun.
Rym: We need big mega corpse and like NFTs and cash cards and like, no, those are all like you read Jurassic Park and you're like, oh, great idea.
Scott: I mean, let me try to make some T-Rexes and velociraptors.
Rym: What book did you read?
Rym: Are the nerds whose reaction to Jurassic Park was, ah, that park would have been great if Nedry hadn't fucked it all up.
Rym: Like how to imagine missing the point of that movie so badly.
Scott: But Zuck is Nedry, the in charge guy.
Rym: So what do you think is going to happen?
Rym: I think like my guess, my pure guess is the one thing that's going to happen.
Rym: Facebook, the platform, like the social media platform is going to see fewer and fewer updates, less engagement and just decline into nothing over time.
Scott: I think a lot.
Scott: I can't predict what's going to happen, but I can say that it depends on what action governments take.
Scott: But I can't predict that.
Scott: So I don't.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because if if there are antitrust actions that actually come into play, which is right now, I'd say 50/50.
Rym: Vote for Democrats if you want more of that, guys.
Scott: Yeah, which I do.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So let's say let's say I get my way.
Scott: So if the best possible thing happens, the government breaks up Facebook and all the other companies, all the big tech companies into their component products.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So Amazon, the store is now separate from Oz, the computers.
Scott: It's a big AT&T breakup.
Scott: And right.
Scott: Because we're saying this is Scott's favorite.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We don't make the mistake of letting them join together again, like we did with AT&T.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: Scott, I know you don't like Star Trek, but so the new Lower Decks show, they address this directly in that in old Star Trek, there was an episode where there's a planet that was destroying itself and everyone was stupid.
Rym: And they worshiped a god.
Scott: Sounds like Earth.
Scott: OK.
Rym: And that God was actually just a leftover computer A.I.
Rym: that was telling them to do bad things for its own purposes.
Rym: So in Lower Decks, there's an episode where the plot is Starfleet, like 100 years later, goes back to this planet because they fucking started worshiping that computer again.
Rym: That is literally the plot of the episode.
Rym: Like, guys, what did we fucking tell you?
Rym: It's it's.
Rym: it's actually really funny how it plays out.
Scott: I'm just imagining them worshiping the computer in the Twilight Zone again.
Rym: That's the same one.
Rym: Like, don't eat the food.
Scott: It's radioactive.
Rym: Fuck you, Dad.
Rym: I do what I want.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: I hate I hate how relevant Twilight Zone episodes are at every stage of my life.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if that all if that all happens, I could actually see it.
Scott: I guess it then depends who runs it.
Rym: Two things have to happen.
Rym: The breakup has to be such that no one of these companies is too powerful to.
Rym: Zuckerberg himself cannot be in charge of any of these companies.
Scott: Well, or more than one, at least.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But it probably go for the VR one, knowing the problem is the VR one is the one that I think has the most long term real potential.
Rym: But it's also I think that I think will work.
Scott: So the two things that they you know, there's a lot of things they acquired.
Scott: But Facebook, Instagram and WhatsApp are both right now really meh.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Instagram got turned into Sky Mall.
Scott: And WhatsApp is who knows.
Rym: WhatsApp is how I communicate with old people.
Rym: I know I don't have it.
Rym: I have because of some people I know.
Scott: While both of those are really meh right now, I actually believe that if though like if you made me in charge of Instagram or WhatsApp right now, they could be saved.
Scott: Those are things that are not beyond saving Facebook.
Scott: The only reason I think Facebook itself, Facebook Marketplace could be its own thing that could be saved.
Scott: It's starting to have some scam problems and falling a bit.
Scott: But Facebook, the social network, you know, events, groups, that sort of thing.
Scott: I think the old any measure that would save it would actually kill it because because capital is just going to you're just going to scare people away and they'll go to some other thing.
Scott: And there's no one who would use even a saved.
Rym: Well, here's a very important point.
Rym: Look what's happening on all social media.
Rym: If you actually ban bad actors like the horse paced people, white supremacists, Republicans, et cetera, when you actually ban those people from platforms, then they migrate and mass to whatever platform will let them do their crap and they keep on going.
Rym: But they are segregated from the better platform at that point.
Rym: But without those people, these platforms can't make money because the money is driven by all these toxic engagements because the only way any of these things make money is selling your data and or selling ads to you via that data.
Scott: There's also the side effect, right, which I think we've talked about in the past of the people who are more likely to be.
Scott: that kind of horrible person who believes in, say, a conspiracy theory is also a more gullible person who is more vulnerable to ads.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You can write, you know, you look at the alignment of scams, you know, fake medicine scams.
Scott: All right.
Scott: And milking those people for money.
Scott: And it's like you make more money off having that kind of horrible person as your customer.
Scott: If you have me as your customer, I block all your ads and I don't buy a damn thing.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: You give me a free to play game.
Rym: I play it for free.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I don't ever pay for single microtransactions.
Rym: So here's why government has to step in.
Rym: The problem is the ad revenue will follow the worst content for all the reasons we described, unless there are laws and regulations that ban those ads and or that content.
Rym: Because if you remove that, you remove the moral hazard from a company to even go after that business in the first place.
Rym: If the white supremacists aren't making you money, even the evil company will kick them off their platform.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And the only platform that will keep them is the the actively pro white supremacist platform as opposed to the pro money at all cost platform.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, so that's, you know.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: He basically told everyone his plan with the typical evil villain presentation.
Rym: So I can say one thing.
Scott: You can't complain that the evil villain didn't tell us what they were up to.
Scott: We just don't have a Superman to go punch him in the face.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So I think to see what we can do.
Rym: But in this space, what we're going to see, too, is I think the platform is not going to succeed with a lot of developers because so far I follow and talk to a lot of VR developers just because that's the thing I'm very interested in.
Rym: Categorically, they have all said things over the last week to the effect of you can't fool me, Facebook, meta is just Facebook.
Rym: I'm waiting this one out.
Scott: So even if they have the best hardware, that's not.
Scott: it's not enough.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Betamax was better.
Scott: It wasn't enough.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The best product is not how you make money in a capitalist society.
Rym: And some other minor news.
Rym: We'll just link to this.
Rym: But this is not as scary as it seems.
Rym: It's only theoretical, but it's worth talking about briefly.
Rym: This article is making the rounds like yesterday and today of vulnerability in compilers, meaning malicious code could be presented in a way that appears nonmalicious until it's compiled and then it becomes malicious.
Rym: And the vulnerability has to do with, of all things, Unicode encoding of text in regard to left to right versus right to left text specifically.
Scott: This is one of those, you know, old tricks, right, where someone sends you a link.
Scott: It looks like Chase Bank dot com.
Rym: But actually, the A is Cyrillic character and the E is like some Estonian Cyrillic adjacent character.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Because they're using Unicode characters, your eyeballs look at your screen and your font renders it.
Scott: And it looks like the word you think it is, but it's a different word.
Scott: So you can mess with source code in such a way using Unicode right to left characters and whatnot, so that when a human being reviews the code and the pull request with their eyes, that what they see looks like correct code.
Scott: that's going to do what you said it does.
Scott: And they run it through their compiler to compile it and then test it.
Scott: And now it's right.
Scott: if you somehow have, you know, affected the compiler in such a way you have, you know, got some sort of security flaw on their computer of the person testing the code, at least.
Scott: And if that code actually gets deployed, well, that you know, because it you know, it'd be really hard to get the code to also pass the unit tests if anyone tried to test the functionality.
Scott: But if you could do that, whoa.
Scott: You get that code deployed everywhere.
Rym: The net result is actually exploiting this particular vulnerability seems to be about as difficult as exploiting when hash collisions are discovered in a lot of algorithms.
Scott: It's pretty difficult to actually pull this off.
Scott: It's just an interesting theoretical possibility that the old Unicode trick of fooling people's eyes could apply to this sort of situation and not just a normal old phishing situation.
Rym: But the good news is the real story in this article is that researchers identified the possibility before there appear to have ever been actual practical exploits using this.
Rym: And because it was theoretically understood, it is now being patched broadly to prevent this particular attack.
Rym: So it's a success of security research as primary academic research, as opposed to the more common method of find vulnerabilities in the wild and then go patch them.
Scott: Yeah, it shouldn't be too hard for a compiler to prevent this from doing anything bad, right?
Scott: Just detect the characters that flip from right to left and then, you know.
Rym: The old bite eyes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: OK, so one more news.
Scott: Yeah, just quickly.
Scott: So we could probably talk a whole lot about Roblox itself, which is a whole thing if you're not aware about the Roblox phenomenon.
Rym: Which I'm curious, let us know, do you know what Roblox is or not?
Rym: Because I've found that people younger than us know what it is.
Rym: People who are older than us who don't have kids have never heard of it or think it's a game and literally don't know the rest.
Scott: It is a game, kind of.
Scott: I mean, yeah, it is.
Scott: It's a strange, it's a really unique thing that is simultaneously amazing and also garbage and child exploitation all at once.
Scott: So, but regardless, they had this enormous outage for something that has so many users and is such a big system.
Scott: It was down for like more than 24 hours, like a very large number of hours.
Scott: It was out and it's like out.
Rym: And the funniest thing is a lot of people would have no idea this happened because none of this news would even except every child on earth who has wealthy enough to have a computer or an iPad or something.
Rym: Oh my god, I found a Twitter thread where someone compiled, like it was a bot finding all these people who looked like parents asking what the fuck Roblox is and why their kids are screaming and crying and flipping out.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And also, the thing is that the children who are using Roblox, right, are not on Twitter.
Rym: Yeah, Twitter's for old people, guys.
Scott: I'm just saying, any social broadcasting thing, it's like, you know, I guess not until you're more teens are you even using that, right?
Scott: You know, because even if you're an eight year old and even if your parents let you use Twitter, you're not tweeting.
Scott: They let you use Facebook or Instagram or whatever.
Scott: Maybe you'd have fun with filters and photos and Instagram, but, you know, I don't think an eight year old is going to be like, you know, posting on Instagram.
Scott: Why is Roblox down and searching on Instagram for Roblox?
Scott: Why is it down?
Rym: I feel like when I was maybe not when I was eight, but I was like talking to their friends on Instagram.
Rym: Ten to twelve is when I would be doing that kind of stuff.
Rym: Had that even existed or been a possibility at the time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, you know, I don't think that, you know, broadcast information, you know, like kids are probably aren't just reading the news.
Scott: So why would you be interested in, you know, news?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, I don't know.
Scott: There is a eight year old going on forums somewhere.
Scott: There's a forum.
Rym: You know what they are doing?
Rym: So they are streaming the Roblox crap on Twitch and YouTube, usually with accounts, probably a lot.
Scott: Yes, but not in any of the places where like this information broadcasting going on.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The only news story that gets broadcast is Roblox is down.
Scott: But you can't see the actual terror and, you know, you know, pain that that outage caused.
Rym: These kids were losing money to the Internet.
Rym: These kids are paying for ads for the games they make.
Rym: They have.
Rym: there's a whole like real money ecosystem around Roblox that a lot of parents don't think even realizes there.
Scott: There's a lot when they check their credit card statement.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Or they will now because little Johnny was flipping the fuck out that Roblox was down for more than 24 hours.
Scott: Also, if you have to get a gift for some kid, you know, you buy you can.
Scott: I think you can buy like a Robux gift card at the drugstore.
Rym: Pretty sure you can just buy Roblox bucks with cash.
Scott: Almost any almost any kid's going to love some Robux as a gift this holiday season.
Rym: Oh, this article is spot on.
Rym: Roblox is valued at almost 30 billion pounds.
Rym: Yet these child workers see only a fraction of that money as their labor drives its valuation up.
Scott: If you make content for Roblox and then someone buys your content that you made, you split it with the Roblox company 3070.
Rym: That's worse.
Rym: They they get the 70.
Scott: It's people are complaining about Apple getting the 30.
Scott: Roblox gets the 70 70 and children made something.
Scott: So it's a child labor producing a digital work.
Scott: It sells the child gets 30 percent of the revenues from the sale and the company gets 70.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: That's all right.
Rym: I don't think we saw yet what the cause of the outage was, but it's interesting because this I don't think Roblox has ever had a major outage before, at least not since it got really big.
Rym: that I'm aware of.
Scott: So I think it's also just unique in like.
Scott: when in history have like, you know, it's not like Tickle Me Elmo has like an outage or a child's favorite toy.
Scott: All our NES is didn't simultaneously have.
Scott: I remember playing Nintendo.
Rym: I remember when broadcast TV like like one of the networks went down in Detroit for like days.
Rym: We just couldn't.
Rym: One of the channels was just gone.
Rym: That was an existential.
Scott: You got other channels, though.
Rym: Yeah, like six of them.
Rym: It was it was the ladies like hurt that many channels back then.
Scott: I'm just saying it's, you know, but there isn't a case for like every kid, you know, so many kids like everyone's same favorite toy all broke at the same time.
Scott: Nobody could play.
Rym: I do.
Rym: All bicycles just stopped working when the BBS that I got my pirated games from when I was very young, dialing into disappeared.
Rym: I guess I don't know if I got raided or whatever, but it got shut down.
Rym: That was how I found all the other nerds in my school, because when I got into school, some people were talking about that.
Rym: But most people had no idea what the fuck that was.
Rym: And I actually made a bunch of friends by figuring out who else was using that anonymous, pirating BBS in my neighborhood.
Rym: Anyway, one last news.
Rym: And I talk about this on a Monday because something that technology people, especially computer types, people who do the kind of jobs that me and Scott do really need to internalize is that the main value of technology is not developing the next new technology.
Rym: The main value of technology is taking existing technology and deploying it in more places, more fairly and more equitably.
Scott: And more wisely.
Rym: Yes, more wisely.
Rym: That impacts people more than any new technology.
Rym: Making Facebook better will not impact nearly as many people as making more trains or making more clean water or taking an old vaccine and getting it in more people's hands.
Rym: So a story that just happened.
Scott: Veins.
Scott: Arteries.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: This is a huge story in New York City.
Rym: The Long Island Railroad now has the ability for its trains to terminate, not just in Penn Station, which is out of the way and sucks shit, but also in Grand Central Terminal, one of the most used and most important train stations in the history of the goddamn world.
Rym: Central to New York City, the best train station we got.
Rym: It is the amount of economic loss from people taking Long Island Railroad trains to Penn Station only to then have to transit back to Grand Central to get to the place they were trying to get to, to connect to the rest of the transportation infrastructure more reliably.
Rym: Just investing in what it took to make these trains go to one different place.
Rym: This is a story that is decades in the making.
Scott: When we graduated college, right, and I was working in, right, I would take the train to Grand Central every day, work day, right, to come to work.
Scott: And they were like, yeah, we're going to do this project.
Scott: So that was a fucking 6, 15 plus years ago.
Scott: It's like this was proposed in 1963.
Scott: When did they actually start digging, though?
Rym: Oh, not so actually a long time.
Scott: More than 10 years ago.
Rym: Definitely more than 10 years ago.
Rym: The story is so long that I'm struggling to scroll through this fast enough to actually find all the milestones.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But yeah, they ran a train.
Scott: You know, it's not ready yet, but they ran a train with passengers from Long Island to Grand Central.
Scott: It made it.
Scott: They got off at Grand Central.
Scott: Then they walked out to the street and it's going to be available to everybody next year at some point.
Rym: OK, so they start.
Rym: they started work and supposedly they started work in the 70s in 1975.
Rym: They canceled the whole thing because New York City was out of money in the 90s, 1990s.
Rym: So the late nineteen hundreds, a new set of studies showed that the majority of all Long Island railroad riders, which is one of the most used rail lines in the world, were trying to get somewhere closer to Grand Central than Defense Station.
Scott: There's more places of employment near 42nd and Lex than there are on 34th and like, you know, you go behind the Madden Square Garden unless you're working at the post office.
Scott: I don't know where you go.
Scott: It's like there's no big, tall office buildings back there.
Rym: To build this new terminal under Grand Central Terminal was one of the larger engineering projects in New York City's history.
Rym: And the scale is enormous.
Rym: The scale and the work involved in the 11 billion dollars is this was using mostly 1970s technology.
Scott: Let me dig a tunnel, play a train track, put a signal.
Rym: The technology to lay tunnels has been largely perfected.
Rym: The boring company has not really done anything novel in this regard because that is not the problem.
Rym: Just like how tech bros like to say, oh, I made a machine that can 3D print houses faster.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Building houses physically is not the bottleneck on housing people.
Rym: You don't say we could build houses for everyone in the world pretty much instantly if we wanted to.
Rym: That is far from the problem.
Scott: So let's let's let's just end this news section with a piece of shit.
Scott: news I saw today about piece of shit.
Scott: Ellen Musk.
Scott: The headline I saw said U.N.
Scott: says they could feed all the hungry people if they just had like eight billion.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And piece of shit.
Scott: Ellen Musk, you know, he could have said, here's the eight billion.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I'm just going to give it to you.
Rym: He wouldn't even notice having that losing that eight bill.
Scott: Of course not.
Scott: But you know what he said?
Scott: He said, prove it to me and I'll sell Tesla stock and give you eight billion.
Scott: It's like, yeah, prove it to me means you're not going to fucking do it.
Scott: What is going to be one of those things where, like, yeah, there is no proof, right, that he would accept.
Scott: He's just being an asshole.
Rym: Well, you know, if they proved it to him, he just called them pedophiles and not give them the money anyway.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: And also, I'd like to point out none of the other billionaires are, you know, giving eight billion either so they can all go fuck themselves as well.
Scott: If I had eight billion, even if eight billion was literally all the dollars I had, I'd be like, here you go.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I have zero dollars now, but there's no hungry people on earth.
Scott: So cool.
Rym: Eight billion.
Rym: The U.S.
Rym: Congress could just add that to the budget and not notice.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And they don't either.
Scott: So fuck them, too.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, fuck.
Rym: in particular, the forty one Republican senators that themselves represent 20 percent of Americans.
Scott: I think even if like, oh, yeah, they're dead.
Rym: They're definitely.
Scott: If every single U.S.
Scott: senator was a clone of Chuck Schumer, I don't think you would get the eight billion for the starving people either.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I bet you could get the eight billion for the starving people.
Scott: You would need a hundred AOCs in the Senate or sixty something, whatever the number is.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So I think this is old, but I found out about it recently.
Rym: It's called Orbis.
Rym: It is a free online Web site thing.
Rym: It's basically Google Maps directions for ancient Rome.
Rym: You choose the season, the modes of transportation, what you're prioritizing, like speed versus economy versus security, et cetera.
Scott: Avoiding barbarians.
Scott: Yeah, I was going to say security.
Rym: It'll outline like how much will it cost?
Rym: How long will it take you?
Rym: It's it's surprisingly thorough.
Rym: This application, this is I've been playing with this for a couple of days now.
Rym: It is really, really fucking neat.
Scott: And also needs to make a game on that.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: You could build it.
Rym: You could build a game just on top of this data, like straight up.
Rym: And it would probably be great.
Rym: In fact, I'm not going to say anything because I know I'm not going to do it.
Rym: Never mind.
Rym: OK, so what do you got?
Scott: So here's a really cool Web site called Famicom Party.
Scott: And someone's writing a book basically on how to make an NES and NES game in scratch from assembly in assembly.
Scott: So there's a lot of stuff out there about making games for NES and lots of old hardware.
Scott: And since the hardware is much simpler, doing it in assembly is feasible.
Scott: In fact, that's what they did it in back in the day.
Scott: But a lot of times, you know, you're going to use other tools, right?
Scott: I know there's an NES maker and a Game Boy maker tools out there that are quite good.
Scott: That will let you make a lot of games and actually output ROMs that will work on old hardware without having to learn assembly language, clearly, and not even having to learn any difficult programming at all.
Scott: So most people are not doing that.
Scott: And, you know, there are a lot of YouTube channels that are like teaching you specific things like retro game mechanics explained and whatnot.
Scott: But I haven't seen too many.
Scott: like ground up right here is literally everything, you know.
Scott: So this is really cool.
Scott: And I haven't actually started going through this yet, but it looks structurally like, yeah, you could come to this knowing, you know, I guess an amount about computers in general, but and then be able to make software that would run on an NES.
Rym: Not only that, but a lot of those videos that explain really deep glitches, really interesting speedrun stuff, just having read a little bit of this already, it would definitely make understanding those explanations very straightforward.
Scott: Right.
Scott: This could also be very useful to you, even if you don't develop an entire game.
Scott: If you want to like figure out some game genie code for a game or make a ROM hack, this would be very useful to go through.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because then when you went to go get a ROM and read it and, you know, try to, you know, mess with it, you would understand what the hell was going on.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: In the better moment, the GeekNights Book Club book, Tale of Genji, I paused it to read a shounen manga.
Rym: Going to be going straight back to Genji after that, because that shounen manga is shounen manga.
Scott: I'm reading Genji because I got the new Kindle Paperwhite.
Scott: It's pretty nice.
Scott: I'm reading Genji on it.
Scott: So there you go.
Rym: I also got a bunch of vacation time I got to burn, so I'm going to have a lot of time off doing like local travel for skiing and nothing.
Scott: Your October prediction is wrong.
Rym: My October prediction is wrong.
Rym: That was fair.
Scott: I was right.
Rym: You were right.
Rym: I think end of year is very feasible.
Scott: I am not working the week of Thanksgiving in the United States, which is, you know, one, two, three weeks from now.
Rym: I'm taking like three days off that week and I'm taking the whole week before the Christmas week off.
Scott: And I'm taking like after the week after Thanksgiving.
Scott: So Black Friday, obviously not working.
Scott: Weekend not working.
Scott: That Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, I work.
Scott: That Wednesday after Thanksgiving is December 1st.
Scott: That is the last day I am working in the year 2021.
Scott: Not working again until January 3rd, 2022.
Rym: Man, I got at some point I got to get out of an industry that never closes.
Scott: And I still have 10 vacation days rolled over to 2022.
Rym: Never worked in my life in a place that could like shut down or close.
Rym: It's either been factories or fabs or hospitals or capital markets.
Scott: My previous job and current job, the company just closes Christmas to New Year's.
Rym: If I ran a game studio, we would just close for that holiday season and we'd pick one like to like a month in the summer.
Scott: You know how much I would close?
Scott: I'd be closing on Jewish holidays, Muslim holidays, Chinese New Year.
Rym: I would definitely close the month of July.
Rym: The best summer times.
Rym: Why should anyone be working during the month of July?
Scott: I'd be closing on if there's a bank holiday in any country in which we operate, closed whole company.
Scott: Not right today.
Scott: It was like All Saints Day.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So people in France, I think, are not working.
Scott: If I had a French office and those people got off, I'd say whole world is off because it's All Saints Day.
Scott: Deal with it.
Rym: So I guess I actually have an anecdote around that because, you know, I used to work in a company where we had a subsidiary office in India, in Hyderabad.
Rym: And we worked with a lot.
Scott: I wonder what kind of cool holidays they got.
Rym: So you basically register what your religion is and then you get that set of holidays for yourself.
Scott: I'm letting everybody off every religious holiday.
Rym: So I do know for a fact, if you did that, your office would basically never open.
Scott: Good.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But that leads to other externalities if our whole society decided to stop working.
Scott: But are there that many holidays that there's literally a serious holiday every day for nearly every day?
Rym: Like kind of for real.
Scott: It would be a problem if you would think there would be.
Scott: there's got to be days where there's no holiday.
Scott: Not many.
Rym: If you earnestly engage with every major faith group and also all of the secular groups that have holidays in the world.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: You got to draw a line somewhere.
Rym: But anyway.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, the line I draw is much more simple.
Scott: The only ice cream day doesn't get a day off.
Rym: The only reason we pay people to do things is because otherwise they won't do those things.
Rym: So if people aren't doing the things we have to pay them more.
Rym: Somebody like my dad was a fireman.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Somebody's got to be a firefighter on like Christmas Day because a fire might happen.
Rym: You know, you do if you can't find people willing to work on those days.
Rym: You pay them a shit ton to work on those days.
Rym: And that's how you solve that problem.
Rym: Every other solution to that problem is unfair and capitalist.
Scott: Let's move on to the main bit.
Scott: Main bit.
Rym: Documentation.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Some listen.
Scott: The listener sent this one in on our forum.
Scott: So we've talked about documentation of us systems before, but never talked about documentation in general.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the first thing you got to know, what is documentation?
Scott: Documentation?
Scott: is you have some technology of some kind and there are going to be people who need to interact with that technology from some purpose.
Scott: And they there's no way, no matter how well designed your technology is, that the person is going to be able to just know everything they need to know to get the full use out of that technology and use all the features and everything without instructions.
Scott: You need to write in a human readable language or explain in a human spoken language or both for accessibility reasons, instructions on all the various possible ways that the technology works.
Rym: Now, we will specifically exclude simplistic and toy examples of things that have a 100 percent intrinsically self-evident user experience, because those things tend to be not useful examples.
Rym: Most things need some documentation.
Scott: Well, consider this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Think about a really simple Apple product like an iPod.
Scott: It's still an iPod.
Scott: I don't know if they still make any iPod things, but the iPod came.
Scott: You know, it doesn't need much of a manual because it's so straightforward.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it comes with a really tiny manual that tells you there's still some things that you're not going to be able to figure out, even from like the best possible design.
Rym: I guess I'm saying I've played some games that literally have zero documentation.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like even Mario, it's like you just need to be like, hey, forward goes, push the arrows direction you want to go, hold B, run faster.
Scott: You need to know that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because you're never going to figure that one out.
Scott: I think I did figure it out.
Scott: I don't think I understood that from a manual.
Scott: You could figure it out, but I guess the other point is not necessarily immediately obvious.
Rym: Well, you headed me off because my second part of that is a lot of things that appear to not have documentation have just embedded their documentation in a clever way that you don't recognize as documentation.
Rym: A tutorial pop ups that like guide you when you try to use a new thing.
Scott: I hate the guided pop ups.
Scott: I just want I always just ignore them all.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Like I even saw one recently that really pissed me off.
Scott: It was like the first is one of those little pop up tutorials.
Scott: And the first pop up said, all right, we know it was something along the lines of like, let's get this over with.
Scott: And I'm just like, if you know this is fucking bullshit, get this out of my fucking face.
Rym: Let me skip it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But let me have a skip all button.
Scott: They didn't have it.
Rym: For many purposes, even though it probably doesn't work as well as people think it does, and it's probably not complete.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I think complete documentation is increasingly rare across all technology domains.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Well, it depends.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the first with the documentation we mostly been talking about here is user documentation.
Scott: Someone who is going to use the technology needs instructions.
Scott: And those instructions should tell the person every possible way to and also warnings on how not to operate the technology.
Scott: What button does what?
Scott: Right.
Scott: You drive in the car.
Scott: Here's what the steering wheel does.
Scott: Here's what the pedals do is how to use the red buttons on the radio.
Rym: Cars are a good example that still come with what I would consider absolutely complete and thorough documentation.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The user manual that comes in the glove box, you know, the driver's guide or whatever, has complete user documentation for the car.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Not it does not have complete service documentation, but it goes way deeper into service than people, I think, realize or expect because most consumers.
Scott: It's all the user accessible service things, how to change tires, how to fill the fluids, how to check the oil.
Rym: All the what all these doable.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: It doesn't tell you like it doesn't give you a map of what where the check balls are in the transmission.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It doesn't tell you that.
Rym: But I think a lot of people forget the fact that the only reason that documentation is so thorough is due to regulations required by law.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Things that don't require that don't have that anymore.
Rym: So case in point, computers.
Rym: Before you could build your own computer, unless you were a turbo nerd, computers came with a giant manual, just like a car that went to about the same level of depth.
Rym: And no computer comes with anything even remotely like that anymore, nor do any computer components.
Scott: So when I was a kid, I had the stereo system and it was like, you know, it was all together unit, these two tall speakers, right, with several, you know, tweeters and woofers in them.
Scott: And then a main unit and the main unit on the bottom just had a storage area where you could put your vinyls.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then above that was the system which had two cassette decks and a FM radio at the turntable at the top and then equalizer in the middle there.
Scott: And it came with a complete circuit diagram of the insides of itself.
Scott: Right.
Scott: On paper, like where every resistor, every everything.
Scott: You don't see that anymore.
Rym: Never.
Rym: And I really like there are consequences of this to this day, even now, like Biosis will not Biosis, but the modern equivalent of Biosis are so poorly documented that Uefi.
Rym: Yeah, the Uefi that there are options that I do not know what they do.
Rym: And if I look at a different Uefi, there is a different option.
Rym: that looks like it's the same option.
Rym: And if you read the documentation that does exist, it's basically meaningless.
Rym: And if you go to the Internet or like ask people or like look for consensus and you end up trusting some guy who may or may not have figured out the exact correct behavior.
Scott: A lot of the problem there is.
Scott: a lot of the people who make that software or the hardware for the Uefis are not English as a first language.
Scott: So the language that's written in that software is not complete.
Rym: Coupled with the fact that companies are very unwilling to hire formal, traditional, trained technical writers.
Scott: It's not going to hurt sales.
Rym: Nor are they willing to hire technical localizers and like the people who would translate documentation.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: No one doesn't buy a motherboard because it didn't come with a 40 page manual that was written well.
Rym: They'll just figure it out.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, yeah.
Scott: So the user documentation.
Scott: now we've been talking about service documentation.
Scott: So service documentation is someone who's a user and or someone who's a fixer, right?
Scott: They're not, you know, they're going to.
Scott: their job is to fix the thing, you know, make it work, possibly even modify it.
Scott: But they have the things delivered to them, but they have to open it up and do something in the inside.
Scott: So now the documentation is sort of has this second purpose where it's not explaining the outer abstraction layer and how to interact with it.
Scott: It's explaining what is beneath the abstraction.
Scott: How does the thing work?
Scott: What does it do?
Scott: What are these parts?
Scott: Whereas the user documentation wouldn't even tell you what the parts work, right?
Scott: It's like you need to know what the parts were.
Scott: You just need to know how these buttons and switches work on the outside.
Rym: There's a big, big overlap in that space with a thing as a service platforms like software as a service platform as a service.
Rym: All a lot of the way modern companies interact with their customers where you have a product that you sell, but the product you sell is basically a Web site that you go to to do stuff or some APIs you interface with.
Rym: And there you have a service team that supports the people using your product.
Rym: They need documentation that explains the things.
Rym: you don't necessarily tell the people actually using your product specifically.
Rym: That's my world.
Rym: That's everything I've done for the last 15 years has been something as a service.
Scott: And then the final level is close to the final level, at least, is there.
Scott: You know, you're making something, right?
Scott: And you're making it with other people.
Scott: You didn't make it by yourself.
Scott: And you need to you know, all you're actually making this thing.
Scott: You need to have an even better level of understanding of the thing than people who have to fix the thing when it breaks.
Rym: So case in point, like I'll use an example from my company.
Rym: I just won't say any proper nouns.
Rym: We have a feature that's in a Web page that people use to do a thing.
Rym: So in that same Web page, we have an extensive user guide, like a fully written.
Rym: a team of tech writers wrote this thing.
Rym: It explains how the thing works.
Rym: Here's a table of shit.
Rym: Guess what?
Rym: We're actually going to tell you what each one of these fields means like full documentation, how to use the thing.
Rym: We have internally what we call a service run book or a service guide.
Rym: Companies call these different things.
Rym: That is the documentation that someone supporting a client or troubleshooting a problem would look at to understand.
Rym: Is this a problem?
Rym: How do I help the client?
Rym: Are there any outages I should know about?
Rym: How do I deal with situation X and I got locked or something weird like that?
Rym: But then what Scott described, this last one, the developers who made these things work on many different teams.
Rym: They move around between teams.
Rym: They move around between companies.
Rym: There are so many human beings that touched any feature that I'm describing that the developers have to have documentation that explains things like here's how it was architected.
Rym: Here is why we architected it this way.
Rym: This thing works weirdly.
Rym: We know it's weird.
Rym: Here's the engineering discussion around that.
Rym: And here's the link to the ticket where we all agreed.
Rym: someday we're going to re-architect this, but it's not worth it to do it yet.
Rym: All of those things need to exist.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you had something like, I don't know, a tunnel, right?
Scott: We talked about tunnels today.
Scott: What's the user guide for the tunnel walkthrough?
Rym: User guide for the tunnel is literally the signs outside the tunnel telling you like, yeah, no propane tanks, no commercial vehicles.
Scott: Here's how to turn on your head.
Scott: Turn on your headlights just in case.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: No, that kind of thing.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Say, all right.
Scott: The maintenance guide for the tunnel.
Scott: Wash the inside of the tunnel this way.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Every 10 years, get this kind of inspection.
Rym: Every 20 years, get this kind of inspection.
Scott: Every day, clean these vents in this way.
Scott: Here, change the filters in this way so people don't suffocate down there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Here's how to change the light bulbs.
Rym: Here's the basic run book of like typical problems and like what is our process to deal with them or who to call.
Rym: Usually it's who to call.
Scott: If the tunnel is flooding, stop letting cars in.
Scott: Here's how to stop letting cars in.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: But then the other one is, okay, we dug this tunnel and you see this thing here.
Scott: that looks weird.
Scott: We put that there because there happens to be a rock there underground or something.
Scott: You know, I don't know anything about tunnels.
Rym: The lane is four inches narrower for these hundred feet because of and here's pages and pages and pages of architecture, diagrams and explanations.
Scott: So if you come and you have to deal with this tunnel long after I'm dead because the tunnel will outlive me.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Here is.
Scott: here is why we made this tunnel in this way where you come and you're an engineer and you know your stuff.
Scott: You literally do know your stuff and you look at the tunnel and something will look wrong to you.
Scott: This is why it looks wrong to you.
Scott: There was a reason.
Scott: Now it makes sense to you because you know your stuff because no one's reading this.
Scott: Who doesn't know their stuff?
Rym: So imagine the people who work the tunnel on a day to day basis need that second documentation like the run book on how to run it.
Rym: That will include a lot of scenarios.
Rym: and what is the standard operating procedure, which like, oh, there's a traffic jam.
Rym: Do you do anything or not?
Rym: I think it's flooding.
Rym: Here's the phone number to call to trigger like the emergency response, like that kind of detail.
Rym: But if there's a big problem, sometimes that run book will say, call these people and people are going to come in who have to decide what to do for a situation where there is no run book, like a crack appeared.
Rym: All right.
Rym: There's a giant crack.
Rym: What do we do?
Rym: There's no run book to cover every possible crack.
Rym: So now you need experts to read the the deep documentation that Scott described and then use their expertise to decide what to do.
Rym: Meaning the more information they have access to, the better.
Rym: Right.
Scott: If they if you just hire a tunnel expert to come and look at your tunnel crack and there's no instructions about that particular tunnel, you're going to be looking at a lot more cost, a lot more time, a lot more danger, a lot more everything that's bad and not a lot extra.
Scott: That's good.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Something will do anything for the person who made the tunnel.
Scott: That second person who comes along 100 years later is going to be helped out a lot.
Rym: So if you're making a documentation of any kind, especially get back into the software technology stuff most of the listeners know about, then it really comes down to who is the audience of your documentation.
Rym: But you can still break those audiences down usually to those three groups we just described.
Rym: have user.
Scott: There are other groups, but those are the three main ones.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But if you most companies, in my experience, don't even break it down to those three groups.
Rym: So most likely you'll be the hero in your company if you even get them to the point of having those three groups.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So some other more specific things, right, is the question of, all right, you recognize the documentation is a good thing to have because you've engineered a technology of some kind, but it's not like it's free to make the documentation.
Scott: It takes time, effort, writing skills.
Rym: As a technologist, I also learned a lot about writing.
Rym: I'm a trained technical writer.
Rym: And the problem this presented in my younger career was I would document everything I did myself.
Rym: Always.
Rym: It took a huge amount of time.
Rym: I would spend about an hour writing documentation for every two to four hours of primary work I did.
Rym: That was just that was.
Rym: I assumed how everyone operated.
Rym: And then I got to a company where there wasn't any documentation of any kind because no one bothered.
Rym: And if I spent time writing documentation, I was admonished for wasting my time.
Rym: That's not my job.
Rym: That's the documentation team's job.
Scott: And the problem is that it's a fundamental problem in that a person who is most knowledgeable about the technology, right, is the person who could who has the skills to be building more technology, doing more engineering, and they may or may not have writing skills.
Rym: But even if they do have writing skills, the company does not want to pay a developer developer money to write documentation.
Rym: They want to pay documentation money, which usually is farmed out.
Scott: So even if you get an expert, someone who's a writer, as that person going to be, even if they're expert at writing, are they expert at this technology someone else made?
Scott: You're gonna have to have those people sit together and chat.
Scott: You know, it's like it's.
Scott: it's just a cost center.
Scott: And it's not.
Scott: it ends up not being worth it in capitalism unless it's a required by log, in which case, you know, you got to have it or be your technology is so big or so important that you're just you need to have the documentation.
Scott: Just practically speaking, it ends up being worth it to you money wise to have it because not having it would be disastrous.
Rym: That's more the world I live in today.
Scott: But so many places are building important stuff that a lot of things rely upon and documentation isn't written.
Scott: It isn't written well or it's not available or it's not available to the people.
Rym: We don't know the full story, but that card game with unique decks had a problem where no one seemed to know how their algorithm worked so they couldn't run it again.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Key Forge.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: We did an episode of that.
Rym: We talked about that on a Tuesday.
Rym: Go find the story.
Scott: The story seems to be that they had, you know, a system that had an algorithm to, you know, generate Key Forge decks and then run them through the printer.
Scott: And the people the rumor is they got ransomware.
Scott: So they lost all their software.
Scott: I guess they were really bad at software.
Scott: They didn't have it backed up anywhere or anything.
Scott: And now I guess with documentation, they could have at least had a new developer rewrite software.
Scott: that was equivalent.
Scott: But I guess they've just lost everything.
Scott: Some I don't know.
Rym: My advice to you out there is it really depends on the company.
Scott: But if you documentation is sort of a backup, if you think about it, I go one step further.
Rym: I treat documentation as a capital investment and an asset like having good documentation.
Rym: I consider it at least.
Rym: when I was in a C level position, which I am not now, I actually you know, I I went to a bigger company.
Rym: So I'm a smaller fish in a bigger company.
Rym: But when I was closer to like board of directors, executive work in a smaller company, I very much treated documentation as an asset that we would assign value to and high and treat as a priority.
Rym: That saved our asses so many times that it it.
Rym: I could say for a fact that it in the end made us money.
Rym: We profited by writing good documentation.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Let's talk about just end up here with some specific, real narrow things.
Scott: Something that always bothers me.
Scott: I read a lot of software developer documentation.
Scott: That's my job.
Scott: Right.
Scott: One thing that bothers me a lot is when the documentation is a not up to date.
Scott: You've changed the software since you wrote your documentation and you didn't update your documentation.
Rym: I look at the documentation and list five fields to put in the JSON.
Rym: I look in the example code.
Rym: There's six fields in there.
Rym: I copy paste that six field into the document.
Rym: It does not show up even once.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's a broken documentation is actually more frustrating than none, I think.
Rym: Oh, I. This is just me.
Rym: I treated software documentation like software issues and documentation is used as bugs.
Rym: If someone found a flaw in the documentation, there was a bug ticket, just like if there is a bug in the software and we treated it with the same level of severity.
Scott: Something else I really, really don't like is someone will write some software documentation and they'll give you an example.
Scott: First of all, you got to have examples.
Scott: I hate the ones where there's no example.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Don't just tell me what like, you know, oh, there's a function called this and describing what it does.
Scott: It's like show me an actual example of it in use.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So that's the first thing, because what I'm going to do, I'm going to look at the example first thoughts with it.
Rym: Then I'm gonna go back and read the rest of the documentation.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So you need to have examples.
Scott: But something that bothers me above that is incomplete examples.
Scott: For example, someone might have an example of how to use a function.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they'll have.
Scott: they'll be calling the function.
Scott: So function parentheses, parameter, parameter.
Scott: And they'll say, yeah, this will return X. Right.
Scott: With these inputs, it's like, OK, I see it.
Scott: But.
Scott: You didn't include where to import the function from.
Scott: It could be like from library import function.
Scott: You need to put that import statement in the example.
Scott: Otherwise, I'm like, OK, I see the function.
Scott: where the fuck do I import.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: So fixed protocol documentation, like a specification for a fixed API.
Rym: Same thing.
Rym: They will give you the most excruciating examples possible of the payloads, like full interactions.
Rym: So cool.
Rym: You've got all that.
Rym: They'll often leave out the headers and footers of those messages.
Rym: Meaning you're looking at a partial message.
Rym: Now, I'm a I'm a fixed expert.
Rym: I look at this.
Rym: I can infer what the headers should look like.
Rym: Doesn't bother me at all.
Rym: Ninety nine percent of people who read that documentation are going to send that raw message without the header because the example didn't have it.
Rym: It's going to fail in ways they don't understand because the fixed protocol breaks down badly without those message, without those headers.
Rym: And they're not going to understand what happened.
Scott: So you should whatever you make put it.
Scott: you should put an example on everything.
Rym: And also, if you example seems trivial.
Scott: To you and all of your examples should be one hundred percent complete examples showing you everything is happening.
Rym: Don't know if you're a fixed message.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So now, even though in this section of the documentation, only one part of that complete example is like the relevant part to what you're discussing, include all the parts and then just put the relevant part in bold so that they can see that's the part that's being discussed here.
Scott: But I can see it in the full context of the full interaction that is happening.
Scott: And now when I go to use that, I will be successful.
Scott: If you just give me only that bold part and you leave out everything else, it is not even there that I'm going to try.
Scott: It's not going to work.
Scott: And I had to go and figure out everything else.
Scott: So that's annoying.
Rym: In terms of user documentation, like not just developer API documentation, I think it bothers me the most.
Rym: The two things that bother me the most are one, when instead of having a written document, they have a YouTube video like fuck that.
Rym: That is the least like.
Rym: videos are good accompaniments.
Rym: They're good accessories to documentation.
Rym: They are fantastic ways to augment documentation.
Rym: They do not replace documentation.
Rym: Video is a very information sparse medium.
Rym: That is very difficult to search and scan through.
Rym: It is very difficult to take things from it.
Rym: I can't copy paste code out of YouTube video and put it in my editor while I'm.
Rym: videos are great when you need to teach someone a physical thing because you can show the thing happening, but they still should not replace written documentation that provides more depth, more context and other information.
Scott: Well, I mean, if you were like how for something like how to assemble an Ikea furniture, right?
Scott: A video could end up being better than the because the diagram might be confusing, but the video would be like unambiguous to see the pieces going to get.
Rym: But I don't want by you without the document and vice versa.
Scott: In that case, I mean, I definitely still want the document, but I'm just saying in some scenarios, as long as the video is accessible to you, video could be the preferable thing.
Scott: I like if I had the video and the paper, I'd go to the video first, even though it's slower, because for that kind of thing, it's a better.
Scott: you know, it's better.
Rym: Though they get to the first for most things, video is not better.
Scott: Well, even any information thing that's not a physical thing, video is not better or anything that requires is not as good or anything that requires a physical learned skill, like for like, for example, skiing.
Rym: There's documentation on skiing, like the right way to do specific kinds of turns.
Rym: That text documentation is very helpful to understand the mechanics involved.
Rym: But a video is also very valuable because it shows it in action.
Rym: You see what the result of those motions should be, but you also need.
Scott: you can also see the person that you're going to be trying to mimic.
Rym: Right now, it's hard to mimic a drawing of a person, but just trying to mimic the person without the explanation of the mechanics involved is a great way to hurt yourself badly.
Rym: The other thing that really bothers me is when user documentation goes overboard and documents all the things like it goes, it's dense and documents things that that are honestly 100 percent self-evident.
Rym: I've seen so many user guides, especially in more commercial software that explain this is a table.
Rym: A table is a way to see information from our system.
Rym: You can sort this table by clicking on the top with these error and it'll spend paragraphs explaining how to use a table every time a table appears in the documentation.
Scott: You don't do it every time a table appears.
Scott: You do it once in one place.
Scott: And as long as you organize the documentation, like it's not bad to have those things.
Scott: Yeah, it's just as long as the documentation is organized to put those things in their own area.
Scott: So it's like, you know, oh, yes, in this, you know, you go to look up, maybe you're going the index and you're like, all right, how do I do X?
Scott: You find the section about X. It involves a table.
Scott: And if you don't understand the table, there'll be a reference like see appendix X, how to use table like you have a section like that is okay.
Rym: That's like how we use tables.
Rym: So in all my things, whatever it is I'm selling to you, here is the documentation of just in case you needed it, how tables work.
Rym: I find the main reason a lot of user guides do this is, one, they hire poorly trained technical writers who are trying to fill space.
Rym: I see that a lot.
Rym: And two, you have people where they're documenting it.
Rym: in every place tables appear because the behavior of the thing is inconsistent, which is a more fundamental problem.
Rym: If the thing behave more consistently, you could make your documentation way simpler and put all the table documentation in one spot.
Scott: You also got to consider, even if you get someone to write documentation, are you hiring editors?
Scott: Are you hiring review?
Scott: People review the documentation.
Rym: It's like, you know, I have someone in engineering read the documentation that came out to make sure it's not wrong now.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So much stuff is going on.
Rym: But here's how I handle that.
Rym: We literally like we have a software release.
Rym: All right.
Rym: We have tickets and all the stuff to track that all the way out to go to market.
Rym: QA, UAT, go live.
Rym: The user guide goes through QAT, UAT and go live.
Rym: the service run book, QA, UAT, go live.
Rym: We don't do that with the engineering documentation.
Rym: I trust the engineers to document their own stuff because if they don't document their own stuff, well, that's their problem when it's undocumented.
Scott: Well, the thing is, right, is that's often a problem in that you don't as an individual, right?
Scott: It's not your problem because you understand what you did.
Scott: It's only you just only cause problems.
Rym: I guess I'm not an engineer anymore.
Rym: So I'm speaking from like a product perspective.
Scott: If an engineer doesn't document for the other engineers, they're only causing other people's problems.
Scott: It never caused them a problem.
Scott: Of course, someone else not writing documentation for them causes them a problem.
Rym: But I'll give you an example.
Rym: There is a pipeline.
Rym: This is my current job.
Rym: There is a pipeline that pulls metrics out of some runtime production systems and via multiple engineering teams.
Rym: This code makes its way into an analytics platform that then does stuff.
Rym: Nobody works at the company who designed that pipeline originally.
Rym: So I wanted to build a thing that used the data at the end of the pipeline.
Rym: So I have a very clear specification on how I want this thing to work.
Rym: No engineering team would take ownership of it because the pipeline crossed so many teams.
Rym: So they assumed things worked the way it worked and they made a thing and it didn't do what they expected at all.
Rym: Nobody, every engineering team one by one said, oh, well, we didn't write that part.
Rym: And they passed the buck to the next engineering team down the line until eventually they discovered that at no point had anyone documented how that thing worked.
Rym: Ever.
Rym: It was never documented by anyone because everyone in this chain thought this is obvious.
Rym: Everyone I work with knows how it works and I won't even be here anymore 10 years from now when some jerk like Rym tries to change something about this pipeline.
Rym: So one engineer who didn't write documentation like seven years ago fucked over like 20 other engineers and me.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So I guess that the most relevant thing, I guess, just to consumers is that, you know, this all ties in.
Scott: You know, we've talked about it mostly from like you're at work, you're an engineer or stuff like that.
Scott: But for consumers, the big deal is like all right to repair, you know, kind of stuff.
Scott: It's like, you know, things not being documented.
Scott: You buy a product and you can't make it do what you want, even though you own it.
Rym: That RTMP streaming box I bought, that just didn't work at all.
Scott: You buy a smart TV, it's spying on you, but they didn't document how you can put your own.
Scott: It's technically possible to completely replace the software on that smart TV with some other.
Scott: It's running Android.
Scott: So a lot of them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's nothing stopping you from installing some other software on there other than it's not documented how to interface with it.
Scott: If there was full documentation, you could open that shit up, flash it, go to town.
Scott: So, you know, but we only get that we're only lucky in some cases, like the famous, you know, Linksys WRT router.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You could put your own, you know, router software on there.
Scott: That's the GPL forced them to reveal or whatnot.
Scott: So that's, you know, nerds out there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Lack.
Rym: If we could force documentation upon all consumer, you know, especially electronic, but all, you know, but you pick a line and above that line, you require like there's a bunch of tiers of above these lines and set these lines based on common sense and smartness.
Scott: The whole John Deere tractor right to repair business going on.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If they were required to include with all the tractors, a complete, you know, service manual that showed everything in the tractor and how it works.
Scott: Now it's put together.
Scott: It's like, well, then you couldn't really prevent farmers from fixing their own tractor, could you?
Scott: Because they see it right fucking there.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And I could and I think we've gone on long enough.
Rym: Maybe we'll do a separate episode on technical writing in the future because we didn't even touch on what good documentation looks like in detail.
Rym: But what I'll link, we did.
Scott: It looks like good examples.
Scott: You cover everything.
Scott: You don't leave anything out.
Rym: I guess I could go a lot deeper.
Scott: You know, whatever language it is, you explain it clearly.
Rym: I guess as a technical writer, I could go a lot deeper into a lot of specifics.
Rym: But what I'm going to link to is a panel, a lecture that me and Scott gave years ago called Designing Game Rules, where we talked about game board game rules as documentation.
Scott: And obviously rules are just documentation for a game.
Rym: And we covered in extensive detail what makes good documentation in that panel.
Rym: You could take that panel and apply it to your software engineering job.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi McNicholallen, Joyce Linkeji, Dread Lily, Tanner Bryant, a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names, Chris Rahmer, Clinton Walton, Dex Finn, JustLikeADudeGuy, Shai Aye 85, Rebecca Dunn, ReviewMadBull34, Cowards, Ryan Perrin, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Hurl, Taylor Brown, The Iron Front, You Hold the Key to My Heart and a whole collection of individuals who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: Uh, yeah, show went a little long.
Rym: Uh, Scott and I sometimes just get going because it's been a while since we, uh, hung out.
Rym: So, uh, GeekNights, uh, we found the episodes are getting longer.
Rym: We're actually having to cut ourselves off, even though we don't have great ideas for Monday and Thursday shows lately.
Rym: Uh, but anyway, for right now, I'm too hungry to do anything else.
Rym: So, uh, I just simply leave you with...
Scott:  Have yourself a merry little Christmas  .
Scott: Let your heart be light  .
Scott: From now on, our troubles will be out of sight.
Scott:   Have yourself a merry little Christmas.
Scott:  .
Rym: Make the yuletide gay.
Scott:   From now on, our troubles will be miles away.
Scott:   Miles away.
Scott:  .
Rym: Here we arise in olden days.
Rym:   Happy golden days of yore.
Rym:   Faithful friends who are dear to us.
Scott:  .
Rym: Gather near to us once more.
Scott: Through the years we all will be together.
Scott:   If it's allowed .