Rym: It's Monday, June 7th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So the other day we are recorded GeekNights the last show that you probably listen to Like you do Scott sends me the audio.
Rym: if you listen to it You shouldn't but if you listen to the Thursday episodes So we finish it and Scott sends me the audio and usually I don't actually look at that until after I eat dinner do some Other stuff, but I'm like, you know what?
Rym: I'm gonna get it done now and I open it.
Rym: and You know, I'm a I am a skilled professional audio engineer I know my biz and when I open Scott's file, I see it looks wrong.
Rym: There's something wrong with it because the spectral display shows that I can see like mouth sounds from Scott Wiggling through that view like I can hear I could like I can look at it and see like lip and tongue action going on Right.
Scott: Well what happened was I had reinstalled windows for other reasons, which means I reinstalled audition Which means I got a clean install and then I made a new template because I guess I blew the old one away.
Scott: All right, maybe I didn't but I didn't want to bother finding it.
Scott: So I just made a new one.
Scott: So I was just like new.
Scott: I was like new and I saw that there were new options because I hadn't you know Seen any of this stuff before because I hadn't reinstalled audition in forever, right?
Scott: So it was like new and it said like podcast.
Scott: I'm like, oh that seems like a good idea Podcast.
Scott: and then I was like, okay, and then I saw that it made a bunch of tracks like host interview Like oh, it's trying to be clever.
Scott: Okay, so I just deleted all the tracks except for host which is me.
Scott: And then I was like, you know, I saved that as the nice template.
Scott: I'm like, okay apparently that template In places that I didn't look included effects and filters that I was not using.
Rym: Yeah If you're not familiar with multi-track audio editing on actual professional software, not like the audacity stuff Basically, you'll have a bunch of tracks and each track has an input like what physical thing or virtual thing is sending audio to it And an output.
Rym: where is that going which for most people is like main output?
Rym: But could be something else for the for my template for GeekNights.
Rym: It's actually something else.
Rym: I use a bunch of buses And each track has non-destructive effects.
Rym: It's literally like it's called the effects rack because it's almost like in the old days.
Rym: you'd have a rack with like a Compressor and then a reverb and then all the devices you needed and you just daisy chain that shit together.
Rym: So in audition You just literally have a list of all the effects and they are just applied in real time on playback to each track in order and you can enable disable the whole effects track.
Rym: and basically that template called podcasting which I looked I didn't realize that even existed because I didn't know existed either and I was just Like oh why not?
Rym: I ignore Defaults in audio because the one thing about audio engineering is that there's no such thing as intelligent defaults Unless you're in a calibrated studio.
Rym: Most people are not Like that even down to the like.
Rym: in my setup Every single vu meter you can look at on all my physical devices all the like cutout devices in audition.
Rym: Everywhere you could possibly see a volume.
Rym: They're all actually the exact same volume, but that is not true for most people's pipeline.
Rym: so if you have like a compressor or an auto leveler or something and You tell it to use the default like start compressing the audio above 10 decibels That is gonna work for like one dude and no one else.
Scott: So anyway, I removed it and I resaved the podcast and that problem was solved once you figured that out.
Scott: But in the course of doing this we figured out some other things.
Scott: one.
Scott: I was having that saving the metadata problem.
Scott: Yeah, it's apparently just gone now.
Scott: Mysterious what was causing it but I guess reinstalling all of Windows and audition solved it.
Rym: Okay, great, but the other thing for the longest time Scott would send me the audio and it was fine.
Rym: But there was a notch everywhere.
Rym: frequency was actually at because I can't open it.
Scott: basically It's a horizontal line.
Scott: like you look at the audio and you can see that it's like there's some sound Happening at a steady at a particular frequency and if you listen to just that sound it would probably sound something like D. You know something like that, right just this constant sound Coming from somewhere.
Scott: So it's like you look at the wave and it's me talking and then you look at this thing.
Scott: It's just always there.
Scott: It doesn't go away.
Scott: It's like what the hell is that?
Scott: But the thing is because it's a straight line like that.
Scott: It's very easy to edit it out because you can just say remove all sound at this particular frequency and there it's gone.
Rym: Actually, I'm a lot more clever than that.
Rym: But basically yeah I use a process where I capture up I take a part where Scott's not speaking Because the automation and audition like that's what you're paying for.
Rym: This is not an ad for audition It's just.
Rym: there's no better software to make a podcast and I use it a lot.
Rym: I've been using it for since it was cool at it.
Rym: I've been using this thing for like 20 plus years Before it was even owned by Adobe.
Scott: So anyway, the point is we got rid of it And then but in the course of solving the problem, you know, I was like, you know what?
Scott: I'm gonna finally figure out what the fuck this line is, right?
Rym: And the funniest thing is yes Scott records new audio and he's like the lines gone.
Rym: I don't see a line.
Scott: Yeah, so I'm like, well there must be you know, cuz I had thought So there's.
Scott: basically I'm using this device.
Scott: It's popular as the audio interface is the focus, right?
Scott: Scarlett - I - right I was you know, and apparently these focus right ones are pretty popular and Rym was like, ah, it's crappy He's right.
Rym: I was saying that it is not as high quality as what we use in the studio But anyway way better than any consumer device.
Scott: It's very popular.
Scott: There are alternatives though.
Scott: Anyway, and then I got the SM 57 or a microphone an old rely.
Scott: the problem is is that the dynamic microphone if I was using the Cardioid microphone that uses the phantom power, right?
Scott: That would be plenty good.
Scott: But the dynamic microphone is not loud enough for this little focus, right guy.
Scott: So I'd have to crank up the preamp in the focus, right till I get it to be loud enough.
Scott: Yeah, and when you do that, you're also cranking up the noise in the focus, right?
Rym: Yeah, and I could.
Rym: so that when we started using this new process, you know kovat times for over a year I've been recording remotely.
Rym: I could definitely see now This is where you know that the viewer talking about the spectral view, you know in movies where they do like a voice Analysis and they show this like pink and red looking thing.
Rym: That's what I'm talking about.
Rym: Anyway, you can always see there was a little more noise in Scott's recording then in then in my local recording But not enough to matter and you can see that little notch there.
Rym: There's just horizontal line just hanging out.
Scott: So so I went.
Scott: well I went and I said, okay, you know I'm cranking up the preamp in this focus right thing too much, right?
Scott: It's better if I turn it down because it's kind of noisy Right.
Scott: and I found I researched and I found out there's these things they sell.
Scott: the one I got is the fathead something And what it does is basically a pre preamp.
Scott: you stick it in the bottom of your microphone and Then you stick the XLR cable into bottom of that and what it does is it's like look your microphone is not using the phantom Power.
Scott: it's a you know, it's a dynamic mic.
Scott: We're gonna take that phantom power though because you have it right and we're gonna use it to amplify the signal from the dynamic microphone.
Scott: and that happens before You hit the preamp in your audio interface and therefore you get the amplification Right and you could turn the preamp way down and get less noise.
Scott: So this is you know, I got this thing and it was pretty great.
Scott: But when I got it, that's when the line appeared and that's when Rym was like, oh that thing sucks.
Scott: There's something wrong with that thing.
Scott: you got that.
Rym: Problems like that before.
Rym: they're easy to troubleshoot where free preamps in particular But also just noisy apps might have like a shielding problem or it might have internal noise and you'll get like a like noise At a particular notch.
Scott: not bad I mean that was yeah, so it was a possibility that this fathead thing was responsible for the line.
Scott: but I didn't really believe it too much because People online like audio engineer people on the internet were like, oh this thing's fucking great This is like the best thing and it was totally awesome Right, and I was like, hmm.
Scott: Why is everyone saying it's awesome and it's causing this line?
Scott: Well, we solved the problem.
Rym: apparently the culprit of the line in the audio was The ring light over here and the way we figured this out was because Scott sent video or audio again And the line wasn't there.
Scott: I was so that literally I was like what I was like, what's different?
Scott: I'm using the thing right now is different.
Scott: when I it was because it was after the show We weren't streaming.
Scott: the light wasn't on and that's why there was no line in the audio.
Rym: And what I asked Scott was what did you turn off any lights?
Rym: because one thing that I know is that LEDs especially cheap ones are Noisy as fuck in the RF world and they will cause audio interference and all sorts of equipment.
Scott: So what was actually happening is I did some tests and what I found out was that the the RF whatever Coming out of that light, you know radio wise that's you know It only gets picked up by the microphone itself, right.
Scott: so if there's no it's not the XLR cable It's not shielding on the interface.
Scott: It's not the little pre preamp, right?
Scott: Yeah, the microphone itself is the only thing that picks up that for you know signal from the light.
Scott: So if I don't have a microphone and I don't get Well, I cannot use the microphone right?
Scott: So what was actually happening was Without the pre preamp I had to put the microphone really close to the light for it to pick up that line And I could.
Scott: I could actually see it happening as I moved the mic closer to the light That the line was like appearing and disappearing right and the in the audition.
Scott: But once I attached the pre preamp it was boosting the signal.
Scott: So now even though the microphone is further away from the ring light You could still.
Scott: the line was still getting picked up because the pre preamp was amplifying the tiny tiny thing that the microphone is picking up.
Scott: So I turned the light off because the sun's shining in the window and the Sun sets not till like eight.
Scott: We're not gonna be podcasting around then so we'll see how that goes but in the winter It's still only gonna need a light and that is see me sitting here with my eyes closed.
Rym: That is like the kind of thing that honestly like if you're podcasting or doing anything with audio and like you're this this Conversation is interesting to you.
Rym: Those are the kinds of things that come with experience real just know.
Rym: like what could cause?
Rym: like if that notch was at 60 Hertz I know exactly what was causing it.
Rym: the fact that it was not at 60 Hertz implied It was interference or a noisy preamp.
Scott: Yeah, it's not worth it to me to buy a more expensive light that might not do this and a more expensive light might still Do it.
Rym: so because more expensive lights are still built with cheap components LED lights Especially like the kinds of stuff you'll use for a podcast or a video game stream.
Rym: They're just either not shielded at all or like violate all sorts of FCC rules.
Rym: They're just.
Scott: I'm gonna do an experiment though with some tinfoil and see what happens.
Scott: I might make a tinfoil shield result.
Rym: Yep, and the only reason I'm not having a problem with all the lights around me is one I buy a name-brand prevent like cool lights here but to my audio device is heavily shielded because it's really fancy.
Rym: but This is where like know you're know what you're doing.
Scott: Well, this is all my audio device isn't the problem It's only the.
Scott: the microphone is.
Scott: the is the weak point.
Rym: arguably the audio device should protect itself.
Scott: What do you mean?
Scott: it's not protect itself from what it's not written.
Scott: the single isn't coming from the light into the audio interface It's going into the microphone.
Scott: The thing is shielded.
Scott: It's if I don't if I take you know, the microphone far enough away I guess yeah right away from the light.
Scott: but the it audio interface is right next to the light Doesn't pick up the line.
Rym: Yep, unless you get a shielded microphone Oh, which is difficult or do what you're about to do or like like what I was doing Just put a notch filter in the way to get rid of that noise.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, that was we finally solved all the mysteries.
Scott: Thanks to reinstalling windows.
Rym: Yeah So there's a bunch of news.
Rym: we'll talk about a few of them.
Rym: There's one little one I actually want to talk about because this is.
Rym: I didn't realize this was a problem because I just didn't think about it.
Rym: So only recently like right now our Carriers like phone carriers going to start sending vertical location data elevation when someone calls 911 in the u.s.
Rym: Previously, they only sent like latitude and longitude like where's the address?
Scott: Oh, because that's all the GPS system will tell you to get the elevation You need to use other sensors in the phone to figure out how high up you are.
Rym: Well GPS can sort of tell it.
Rym: GPS can tell you elevation depending how many satellites you're looking at.
Rym: There's a bunch of.
Scott: I guess that's possible.
Scott: Yes
Rym: It's more than the problem was more that the system that was set up to collect this data Display it to like the people answering the phones is really complicated and very prescribed and it was basically an IT Problem to get everything in place to send this data and the carriers complained that they're having so much trouble doing this.
Rym: the FCC actually mandated to send Vertical like height information in 9-1-1 calls in 2015.
Rym: The deadline to do so was June 2nd.
Scott: Problem is right is that they meant that you know, that's the correct process.
Scott: right you come up with a standard.
Scott: Yeah, right you met you man you government mandates it, right?
Scott: Everything was done correctly, right and the carriers are just you know, taking their sweet-ass time.
Scott: And I think the problem is that you know, what's the penalty for them not doing?
Rym: Ah, that's.
Scott: I'm glad you asked that because the penalty for them not doing it was what they got fined a little bit or nothing Right up.
Rym: So the news is that this is going live quickly now because the June 2nd deadline was approaching.
Rym: AT&T T-Mobile and Verizon all Apparently independently of each other said that they needed an 18th my 18 month extension Because they had trouble testing this due to COVID.
Rym: The government's response was we fucking told you in 2015.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: so the FCC began an Investigation into these three companies in April this year to find out what was taking so long the three carriers.
Scott: They're just taking their sweet-ass time on purpose.
Rym: Yep, shit the three carriers Magically suddenly said yo yo yo, we'll get this done within seven days if stop investigating us And we'll pay a hundred grand each.
Rym: Please leave us alone.
Rym: So yeah, this is happening imminently.
Rym: And if you're not if you can't figure out why this is a big deal.
Rym: most people in America live in cities.
Rym: cities tend to be pretty vertical and If some random person calls 911 and they're in trouble and they can't say where they are in a building.
Rym: and you know The police the fire department whoever shows up at a 50-story building.
Rym: now what?
Scott: Even in a even in a place where there aren't skyscrapers right suburb, you know the an awful suburb, right?
Scott: It's important.
Scott: It could help you if you know that someone's in the basement or the second floor.
Scott: There's like a fire.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's huge, right?
Rym: Just like an office building that might be empty like the people at the door won't necessarily know that there's a problem inside.
Scott: You know that could be.
Scott: that could be the difference in life and death.
Scott: if the firefighters know you're in the second They check like the bedrooms first and then you happen to be in the basement.
Scott: you good You know, you're a you're a you're a nerd living in the basement.
Scott: They didn't know that.
Scott: It's like that could be it You know, yeah.
Rym: so this is an absolutely good thing and I'm glad the government turned the screws and While I wish the fines were bigger and the investigation continued the fact that they buckled Instantly under that little bit of pressure the good was done.
Rym: The government actually did what I expect the government to do.
Scott: so, you know.
Scott: if I was in charge though, you know The penalty should be right is You know, they always come with like these fines and stuff, right?
Scott: It's like, oh, we'll find you X dollars or whatever, right?
Rym: It should just be.
Rym: every time you fuck up the government takes a larger share of owning you.
Scott: No, no, no too complicated too complicated.
Scott: It's very simple.
Scott: You ready?
Scott: His is very very easy.
Rym: I'm ready for the Scott plan.
Scott: your deadline for doing the thing is reasonable amount of time, right?
Scott: As if you hit that deadline and it's not done.
Scott: All the service you provide to customers is free of charge until the point at which you fix it, huh?
Rym: You can't collect how GDPR works and that they find you.
Rym: There is no cap on the fines if you violate GDPR.
Scott: But don't bother calculating fine.
Scott: Just be like the service is free if you and if you bill anyone Right during that if you bill anyone even one cent any customer at all Even one cent during that time period at which we are mandating that you provide your service for free Right or you you do anything right you anything even one cent shady Like you hold back on a service call that you know, cuz someone's service is broken or you know Anything.
Scott: you cut back anything at all whatsoever in terms of your service level or you charge any customer even one cent.
Scott: CEO goes to jail until a time at which it is fixed.
Rym: well at least in this case that the key with that kind of the fine.
Scott: and oh not just the CEO all the board members have To go to jail - I think that's the simpler way is still and they don't go to easy jail They go to the.
Rym: the nasty Already put me in the home.
Rym: We'll put you in the crooked home.
Rym: We saw in 60 minutes.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: But I'm saying the GDPR thing works pretty well because the way it works is it's a percentage of your gross Global revenue.
Scott: Well, that's good because that's good because at least it scales.
Scott: I appreciate the fact that it scales.
Scott: You know, that's nice.
Scott: But I still I still prefer like the you can't charge anyone.
Scott: Provide your service at the top level.
Scott: You cannot decrease your service Providings and it.
Scott: you must provide your service for free and in fact, if you get a new customer, it's free.
Scott: I'm not just sign on for free.
Rym: But another thing that happens in Europe That's not in the?
Rym: u.s is certain job titles are regulated in a sense that the people who hold those titles for companies like this are personally liable for many kinds of criminal and civil infractions Irrespective of if they did it at the behest of the company,
Scott: you know I actually want to just someone come.
Scott: I forget where I heard this.
Scott: It might have been a podcast where I was listening to like Like an SEC lawyer or something like that, right and he was talking about how in you know The u.s.
Scott: Right the financial guys are always trying to deregulate right?
Scott: They want there to be less laws.
Scott: if there's less laws, then they can be evil businessman, right?
Scott: But and he talked about how he spoke with a French finance, dude Like a French evil business guy, right and the attitude of the French evil business guy was like look I love these regulations, right?
Scott: And the reason he loved them is because he had a moral compass.
Rym: Well, I saw a situation in the u.s Like with a car mileage requirements and how there was this right-wing talking point that the car companies don't want these stupid requirements.
Rym: But every interview showed that the car companies Affirmatively wanted those requirements because it makes a level playing field.
Rym: It actually makes it harder for them to be competed with it.
Rym: This is horses a moral compass on them.
Scott: Well, this is different and that the French guy had a moral compass, right?
Scott: Therefore.
Scott: He didn't want to hurt anyone.
Scott: He just right.
Scott: so because of the regulations He was like, look, I don't have to like my job is way easy.
Scott: I can do whatever the fuck I want.
Scott: I know exactly where the lines are, right?
Scott: Just don't do anything illegal Like.
Rym: I hit people all these different ways, but I can't hit like this You can.
Scott: I can just do whatever the fuck.
Scott: evil business I can come up with as long as I'm within these rules and I just stay within the rules.
Scott: All the you know, the regulations are there and I never no matter how evil I am within those rules I don't have to feel bad about it.
Scott: I can go home and sleep at night.
Scott: I don't have to give a shit Right.
Scott: It's like because I know that either you know a I'm not hurting anyone or B They're gonna.
Scott: if I do hurt someone they're gonna regulate and fix it in which case I sort of actually did a good thing by Exposing, you know, whereas in the US it's like if you're an evil businessman, it's like, okay If you have no moral compass, then you can just do whatever evil you want, right?
Scott: but if you have some sort of moral compass It's actually the deregulation actually makes your life difficult because you're constantly, you know, how do you sleep at night?
Scott: It's like all right.
Scott: Well, I want to do evil business you man stuff so I can make more money.
Scott: Did I overstep or didn't I right?
Scott: and you're so.
Scott: if you actually have some sort of conscience then the lack of regulation?
Scott: It can actually, you know give you a. you know a disturbance in your mind Or even if you don't have your mind can't be disturbed by anything But it still gives you a.
Rym: I can go full throttle within these parameters Mm-hmm, then of course the regulations have to be updated and changed to deal with the consequences of you know loopholes in them.
Rym: But that's a whole different conversation.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if the speed limit is a hundred right?
Scott: It's like you floor it and your car's going 100 you go Right, and you just you're just flooring it.
Scott: Yeah, but if the speed limit is like on no speed limit It's like am I going too fast?
Scott: Should I slow it down?
Scott: right, you can't just Mindlessly floor it and go we and not have to care, right?
Scott: Yeah, and that that that worrying about am I going too fast?
Scott: can take away from the thrill of just going fast.
Rym: So with some other news and this is Apple news not related to WWDC, but it's from June 3rd Air tags came out.
Rym: Apple air tags.
Rym: They're a pretty cool thing,
Scott: but I got some
Rym: yep
Scott: Shout out to the listener who through with the 3d printer who printed a thing so I could test attaching an air tag to a bicycle which is a Which is apparently when you set up an air tag bicycle is one of the choices for you know default Thing you are.
Scott: so Apple apparently thinks that that's an okay idea.
Rym: So I saw people.
Rym: it's like.
Scott: I say it's like there's no guarantees.
Scott: It's gonna like save you Like.
Rym: but my news will provide is relevant to that in some ways.
Rym: But also it's a mixed bag.
Rym: So Apple the problem with air tags.
Rym: Not to say that there is not other technology that already exists that you can just use to do this evil shit.
Rym: But air tags are very accessible way to spy on someone if you plant an air tag on them or their shit.
Scott: Right, but if they have an Apple device of some kind which is gonna do not?
Scott: most people Yeah, it depends but most people globally have Android phones Sure, but the the presence of Apple devices is actually what makes air tags work, right?
Scott: It's like if there are no apples if there are no Apple devices anywhere.
Scott: and let's say let's say I put an air tag in my in the inside of my Computer right case.
Scott: I tape it to like the you know, the back of the motherboard, right?
Scott: Someone steals my whole fucking computer and They drive away with it.
Scott: I don't know how they did this, but they do it, right?
Scott: If they go somewhere with that computer and there are no Apple devices anywhere near them and Right, it's like the air tag is now useless, right it did.
Scott: the air tags depend on an Apple device cut with you know that's updated enough with the proper radios coming near the air tag and Having signal at some point at which to sort of let the network know this air tag was in this location No Apple devices that this nothing's happening.
Rym: So Apple made a few changes pretty early on to air tags.
Rym: one of the changes they made is they update at an updated version of iOS that if it detected an air tag that wasn't yours that hadn't checked in with the original phone like the account that set it up and it appeared with you too often for Too long.
Rym: you would get a notification on your phone.
Rym: that said AirTag found moving with you and you can have options like make it make a noise Disable it like all this.
Scott: Yeah, so like right.
Scott: so let's you know.
Scott: Let's say I've got like in someone slip.
Scott: I'm at a convention and someone puts an air tag in my bag right and I got an iPhone.
Scott: and if that air tag is Now following me around everywhere I go, but it's not mine Apple's like.
Scott: hey, there's an air tag near you.
Scott: That's not yours.
Rym: So when originally it didn't do that at all the update of newest version of iOS does this but only iPhones will give you this Notification.
Rym: So if I spy on an Android user, they'll never get a notification But then they'd have if there's.
Scott: no if that person doesn't have any iOS devices near them You won't be able to track them.
Rym: But if anyone around them has an iOS device at any point the pings will pop up.
Rym: Yeah so the what I had the original threshold Apple set for this was three days and That's too long.
Scott: That
Rym: is way too long and I'll link to an article where a reporter like successfully used air tags to like Heavily spy on a bunch of people she knew and Part of what she found was that a lot of people don't even notice those Notifications or like don't think about him.
Rym: a lot of people don't update their iPhones Weirdly and wouldn't get the notifications.
Rym: Well half her friends.
Rym: I mean Android She would see.
Scott: I don't know about the.
Scott: a lot of people don't update their iPhones.
Scott: I mean, I'm sure there are people who don't or don't update them right away.
Scott: But the if you look at the numbers that like almost all iPhones and iOS devices even old ones are updated to the news.
Rym: These experiments on April 30th is when she wrote the article.
Rym: So we over the course of in April where the update that added this was pretty new full disclosure.
Rym: but the other problem was because she is friends with those people and would Have a good excuse to see them at least once every three days.
Rym: You could keep the tracking going forever and no one would ever get a notification.
Rym: Maybe yeah, I mean directly sure.
Rym: Oh, there's a whole article about it here, but she pulled it off.
Rym: So, uh Apple is changing this now.
Rym: So where they're not gonna say exactly when it'll go off because that'll make it easier for people to foil it But at some point between 8 and 24 hours of separation, it'll warn people that it's there
Scott: Mmm,
Rym: and they also announced that they are going to release an Android app.
Rym: I am confident the Android app will both expand their network to all these Android devices.
Rym: It depends but it also Primarily that the Android app is designed to tell Android users if a suspicious air tag is found moving with them.
Rym: hmm the other part of this is that the air tags will also start making sounds if They're already made too long.
Rym: And of course I found a YouTube video someone uploaded like right like a month ago that shows the Trivial hack to completely disable an air tag for making any sound forever.
Scott: Oh, you can just open it and cut the speaker.
Rym: Yep, or just open it.
Rym: There's a magnet in it.
Rym: Just remove this mode.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the magnet is the speaker.
Rym: Yep, just remove the magnet.
Scott: In fact, most of the air tag is the speaker.
Scott: Yeah, like if you remove the speaker entire.
Scott: if you redesigned it without the speaker, it would be way smaller.
Rym: So it appears the people who are excited about the like how easy it is to remove that sound seem to be two classes of people Creepy people is one like clade that I see like in the comments of this stuff.
Rym: But the other clade are all doing the same thing Pointing it on their bike so they can track down their stolen bike and steal it back and/or get revenge Mmm, and they don't want the air tag to make noise and inform the person who stole their bike that there's an air tag there.
Scott: Well, I think it's just.
Scott: you know, all of these same concerns exist, you know, there have been devices.
Scott: What are they?
Scott: What's the thing called?
Rym: Oh, there's that.
Rym: Yeah, there's the tile.
Scott: There's a bunch of tile one, right?
Scott: So the tiles was the popular one before but it wasn't the only one.
Scott: there's like Google glass.
Rym: Everyone was so mad about Google glass.
Rym: with a camera right there.
Rym: You can go on Amazon and buy for even back when Google glass came out for way less than a glass cost a tiny Tiny camera that you could put on like your lapel that no one would ever see.
Rym: that records 24/7.
Scott: Yep, it's like you're so upset of and it's like people are so upset.
Scott: if you have like, you know Try to take a photo of them, right but it's like dude.
Scott: you just walk past ten security cameras.
Scott: Hey, I guess what's wrong?
Rym: I'm glad to see that Apple took the obvious ways that air tags could be misused Seriously, and they have made like real privacy.
Scott: it privacy is their number one, you know selling point.
Rym: But they clearly take it a very powerful approach now to balancing the dangers with the usefulness and they seem to be taking all these dangers very seriously and that's Honest praise for me.
Scott: like And so that's the one thing they've been doing right, you know for the past like several years now all their keynotes Even even the one today, they're like privacy privacy privacy.
Scott: We don't sell your data.
Scott: Check this out.
Scott: We added even more blocking of ads to Safari and iOS.
Scott: Look at all the shit.
Scott: We're blocking right?
Scott: Yeah We're fucking over those ad people.
Scott: real good.
Scott: You know, we don't sell your data.
Scott: We're just selling new products for way too much money.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So the other thing going on is all the other Apple news cuz WWDC is like ongoing right now.
Scott: Yeah, so WDC this is usually, you know, it's a developer conference.
Scott: This is usually winning and you're gonna get your news about you know, the OS updates and such right and this year There wasn't any like one thing that was like big exciting like whoa, right?
Scott: It was lots of little stuff some of which interesting some of which may.
Scott: Most of it was the typical Apple thing that they always do that I always bring up which is some functionality that already exists that other people already have an Apple Makes it a new feature and act like they're so great.
Scott: It's like what for example they added basically, like a KVM kind of situation where you put your iPad next to your Mac next to another Mac and you can use One keyboard and mouse and move them all the way across everything, right?
Scott: It's like I have this mouse that borders thing and that's not even old right much older KVM ones.
Scott: It's like apps like that have been around 10-plus years that let you just move one mouse one keyboard one computer and control several Computers over the network.
Scott: Yeah, that's old technology.
Rym: What Apple brings adding table is if you got all Apple devices it all came.
Scott: Of course, it's only gonna work with all Apple devices.
Rym: But the fact that it kind of just works is I think it does just.
Scott: that is true.
Scott: They mean that's you know, they do, you know, the they do it better right?
Scott: The iPod was better than the existing mp3 players at the time They invented the mp3 player it's like.
Scott: no you didn't.
Rym: Penny arcade said you can buy an iPod or you could buy one of those ones.
Rym: That's just red.
Rym: mp3 is off of a CD R and cushion it with several hundred dollars in cash exactly.
Scott: So You know stuff like stuff along that those lines.
Scott: right, you know, yeah, they reinvented a wheel and you know, whatever.
Rym: They did announce one thing FaceTime is coming to Android in Windows, but back that off a little bit.
Rym: Yeah, it's coming to the web All right.
Scott: So what they're doing is You know FaceTime when they announced FaceTime originally.
Scott: you can watch that keynote, you know, Steve Jobs is like this is gonna be open source.
Scott: Right, we're gonna make it an open protocol.
Scott: So anyone can make face-to-eye message like open.
Scott: that was ended up being a bunch of bullshit.
Scott: Yeah, I did not to do that.
Scott: And in fact during the epic case They discussed well, you know, they were revealed Discussions about why they ended up not doing that.
Scott: Because they thought it would make it too easy for people to switch over to Android phones.
Scott: Right because they wanted I messaged to sort of keep people on iOS.
Scott: I think that they government should force them to.
Scott: you know, yeah You said you were gonna do it false advertising.
Scott: so you have to do it now too bad?
Rym: Yeah, anyway, but there's all these little minor updates like that that I don't think will materially change.
Rym: but what
Scott: they did do what they did do is be they added a feature to FaceTime where you can you know schedule a FaceTime and then get a URL link to the FaceTime and send it to everyone so that they can click on it at the right time to join the FaceTime which is you know standard functionality for video chat they didn't have because theirs is more of a phone thing, right?
Scott: You'd like start a call right, you know.
Scott: And now but you can send those links to somebody, you know, who isn't using their iPhone.
Scott: Just open it in their computer right and join the FaceTime on you know, the web web browser.
Rym: I don't think this will make FaceTime a viable zoom competitor at any point.
Scott: I don't think it will either.
Scott: but I do think that there will be times where like someone will you know?
Scott: Someone who's like a big Apple person right will start a FaceTime and you might end up getting a link to one You know once.
Rym: if you're not once in a while I will say I've pretty much like.
Rym: zoom has gotten a lot better to the point that I do use it now and I do Trust its security enough.
Rym: I pretty much use zoom and discord for that.
Scott: I Have zoom on the work computer.
Scott: I don't need it on my regular computer.
Scott: Yeah I need to be in.
Scott: What zooms do I need to be in?
Rym: Zooms for a couple of.
Rym: it's funny.
Rym: There's a couple of discord servers.
Rym: I made well, they'll have links to the zoom calls.
Scott: You're in a discord you have a disc.
Rym: No zoom has a lot of things that are useful that discord doesn't have.
Scott: That's surprising.
Scott: It's like, you know, if I'm if I'm any one of these companies, right?
Scott: He was working.
Rym: Just be a giant like arbors of them just eating each other's features, right?
Rym: It's like if I worked at discord or zoom or Google or Apple or I'd have someone who's old job was to use the competitors And tell me about the cool things they do.
Scott: I Would be literally like just open up all the other ones and copy all their features.
Rym: Every feature Does breakout rooms.
Rym: the way zoom does their zooms break?
Scott: I don't just score.
Scott: does any breakout rooms?
Scott: It's like I'd be like I'd be on like.
Scott: hey, they have breakout rooms and we don't do it do it now.
Scott: We need that.
Scott: Anyway, what are?
Scott: the one thing that Apple announced?
Scott: that was big for me, but I'm they didn't say too much about it and I'm cautious but at least it's it's.
Scott: I've been asking for it for a long time.
Scott: is I want to be able to make an iPad or iPhone app on my iPad?
Scott: I don't want it to buy a fucking Mac to do it, right?
Scott: So I wanted Xcode for iPad.
Scott: that does not exist.
Scott: They're all that exists for you know is They have this like what's it called like Swift?
Scott: Playground.
Scott: it's like a little app for iPad and iPhone that where you can learn the Swift programming language Right like tutorials and stuff and like if you're that always.
Rym: Swift is also the name of the global Transaction and like payments network and protocol its name of the iOS programming.
Rym: Yeah, I know but it's also the name of the thing that I work with a lot professionally.
Scott: Anyway, the point is they are adding the ability.
Scott: not there aren't making Xcode for iOS or iPad OS.
Scott: They are making the Swift playground app is going to have the ability to.
Scott: all they said was that you'll be able to make an iPad app an iPhone app and get it in the App Store Using just your iPad only and not anything else.
Scott: so that's Basically what I wanted.
Scott: the only question I have is it seems like you know It's part of the Swift playground tutorial.
Scott: kind of deal right babies first It might be only babies first.
Scott: Will you actually be able to make an app using any of the iOS?
Scott: Apis that are all you know the huge pile of them, right?
Rym: In the right direction even it is minimal because I'm absolutely gonna be making iOS iPadOS apps because the old man thing that we are both like insistent on like something the kids cannot let like fail.
Rym: The devices people use have to be capable of making software to use on set devices.
Scott: Yeah, well that is really important to the future of computing.
Scott: It's happening.
Scott: So that's good.
Scott: I just wonder it's like will you be able to make any Conceivable app using it out of wolf.
Scott: We'll find out right, but that's good.
Scott: They I Basically got half or most of my request.
Scott: I guess that I've been requesting for several years.
Scott: So I'm not gonna complain about that, right?
Scott: They seem to be pushing there.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: and other stuff.
Scott: They seem to be pushing their home stuff a bit more, you know in terms of like, you know Watching things on every screen, you know, you can now airplay to a Mac, right?
Scott: So if you got like an iMac is your TV in your room?
Scott: You can you know have your iPhone and say hey display this on the Mac instead of just Apple TV.
Scott: You know things of that nature.
Scott: Yeah, it's didn't sure.
Scott: all this stuff is gonna be coming down the line.
Scott: You know.
Scott: when iOS gets updated in September October and they'll probably have Even more announcements and the new iPhones and the new Apple watch and the new iPad will have you know Some of those features.
Rym: I'm keeping an eye out because as much as I'm deep in the Android ecosystem It's either the next Sony's Android phones are gonna be tiny or I'm just gonna fucking give up and I have to give I have to give up.
Rym: I'll probably just jump shit.
Scott: Well, we'll see if the tiny I've owned, you know, see if they make it.
Rym: Well, here's the thing.
Rym: It's gonna come down to the smallest newest iPhone Versus the smallest like worthwhile Android phone, whichever one's smaller is where I'm going.
Scott: Well, see how they go.
Rym: Who knows?
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so way back a while back like not even that long ago Scott had a thing of the day.
Rym: There was this channel that was like Soviet old Soviet cartoons without context and my thing of the day is a Soviet cartoon on a Twitter account called Soviet cartoons.
Rym: out of context Apparently the account Scott linked to which was this thing of the day is gone.
Rym: This is a completely unrelated account But I'm not linking to the account.
Rym: I'm actually looking to a specific video because it's only a minute and 26 seconds long.
Rym: You have to watch it.
Rym: It's as long as an anime opener and you never skip those.
Rym: It is a Soviet cartoon about a rocket launch.
Rym: It is called lift five.
Rym: It's a satellite launch.
Rym: It's called lift five and Halfway through it.
Rym: You'll realize what the joke was and then at the end you'll see the final punchline.
Rym: This thing is hilarious.
Rym: It is perfect.
Rym: I love it.
Rym: It's got such a good style and also I particularly appreciate the soundtrack.
Rym: the song is great.
Rym: Okay, I don't know what else I can say about this thing like just watch it.
Scott: So something I sort of knew.
Scott: but didn't you know, it took me as a shy Shockingly long time to realize this.
Scott: right but you know, you got some old DOS computer.
Scott: Yeah, you turn that shit on.
Scott: Let's say you take out all the hard drives and you turn that shit on.
Scott: First of all, right it posts and on the screen when it's posting is text like it's counting up the RAM and stuff, right?
Scott: Yeah, and then when it's done, it's if there's no discs.
Scott: It's gonna say no system disk or disk error on the screen.
Scott: Yeah so That's I mean your.
Scott: your current PC will probably do the same fucking thing.
Rym: if yeah, it's not.
Rym: It's all different but same same concept.
Scott: Yeah, it's UEFI whatever but there's no hard drives in there.
Scott: Oh How is it, you know, it's writing text on the screen.
Scott: Where where is that font coming from?
Scott: it's like You know, it's like you're going to you get a computer and it has no software no operating system, but it can display text.
Scott: It's like is that is the BIOS have a font in it?
Scott: It's like actually yes sort of it does.
Scott: If you ever use DOS, it's like, you know, you don't have fonts in DOS.
Scott: It's like there's just the one font that you have.
Scott: you love a DOS computer.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: there's the one font.
Scott: That's it Alright, it's like where the fuck does that little ASCII font come from?
Scott: It's actually.
Scott: where is it?
Scott: It's in your VGA ROM on your video card.
Scott: right in the in the ROM on the video card.
Scott: There is a font in there.
Scott: It's it's a low-res pixel, you know VGA font and pretty much every video cards got one.
Scott: So this dude He had a few different, you know He's apparently someone who really loves DOS and DOS programming even still to this to this day.
Rym: I can feel that because I've read the I was about to say man page.
Rym: It's not the man.
Rym: I read the documentation of mem maker yesterday just kind of random.
Scott: Anyway, it's a person who loves DOS and doing DOS things is still apparently programming Pascal stuff on DOS, right?
Scott: So But they apparently had old video cards for DOS and like ISA ones and those ones.
Scott: He really liked the fonts in those ones, right?
Scott: But he got a newer one a sang labs W32 I with two megabytes of RAM And apparently this is like an amazing DOS video card.
Scott: It can even play quake at 320 by 200.
Scott: Whoa All right, like a really good DOS video card but Really kind of meh font right meh fonts not not nice like the fonts II they had on their previous video cards.
Scott: So they got this tool and you the.
Scott: the tool is called fontraption.
Scott: You can just get it.
Scott: It's a this website whatever the link to fontraption is in this article and to basically Manually edit the font that was on the new video card right and overwrite the ROM Right with the new font in place of the old font Because you know taking up the same amount of memory.
Rym: I love just the first line of the of the the essay section.
Rym: quote VGA ROM fonts cannot be replaced.
Rym: that easy.
Scott: Yeah, so sort of an epic story about Replacing the font and a new video card with the font from an older video card.
Scott: Also, these fonts are totally my style.
Scott: I love these fonts.
Scott: I wish I you know could.
Scott: I'm always looking for a font that looks like this just to use in vim.
Scott: But the problem, you know, I guess fixed sys in Windows comes close.
Scott: But the problem is that you can't.
Scott: it's not realistic because they don't have enough characters right for the modern day.
Scott: We have a code right there ASCII fonts there.
Scott: You can't use them anymore, right?
Scott: But I just you know, I do like how they look.
Scott: so Yeah, you can learn about VGA fonts Which I also learned about from this awesome story.
Rym: Yeah in the meta moment, uh, we're hanging out.
Rym: The next convention will be at will be packs online or PAX East online 2021 where we were doing at least one panel We're doing a. we did a panel a long long time ago called Atari game design where we played a bunch of Atari games.
Rym: It's like talked about the game design live on stage while we played them.
Rym: We're gonna do a completely updated version of that and actually focus on a bunch of single-player games instead of just multiplayer games.
Rym: I think it'll be fun.
Rym: We may or may not do an additional panel or two, but stay tuned.
Rym: also Looks like the theme of this PAX East online is gonna be like a summer camp theme.
Rym: So we I Want to do something with that theme, but we'll see if we actually have the energy to do something with that theme.
Rym: Yeah, whatever you were the one sending me like Amazon links to fake fire.
Rym: We could buy.
Scott: That was.
Scott: it was your idea.
Scott: I was just showing you that it was out there.
Rym: Yeah, it is out there.
Rym: So we'll see.
Rym: Otherwise the book club book is still the tale of Genji.
Rym: Read it a little bit now that it's warm out.
Rym: I can just sit in the warmth and right.
Scott: I biked.
Scott: I biked too far and didn't read.
Rym: Yep I thought the problem is I thought cuz we biked to Poughkeepsie and I took the train home and I thought all right.
Scott: So I got a read on that train.
Rym: I thought it's two-hour train ride.
Rym: I'll read for like the first hour and then I'll fall asleep.
Rym: and I had just biked a hundred and two miles.
Rym: I got on the train and I immediately fell asleep and I woke up at Grand Central.
Rym: Well, that was that.
Rym: uh Otherwise just keep on keep it on follow CDC guidelines and Most likely the next convention you'll see us in person at The moat.
Rym: the one that's most likely is PAX Unplugged.
Rym: in November We'll see.
Scott: maybe I hope so.
Rym: I said most likely that's that's the one that has the highest chance of success.
Scott: Yeah, I think my you know, I think Rym said the same thing is like, you know, my policy is basically like look, right?
Scott: Would you get on a plane if they said all right everyone on this plane, you know Just in case we're gonna make you all wear a parachute the whole time or you're gonna get in a boat they're like gonna make you wear a life preserver the whole time just in case it's like.
Scott: I mean shouldn't the plane be safe enough that like not all the passengers need parachutes at all times Like, you know, maybe like under the seat or something, right?
Scott: But like just you have to wear it the whole time.
Scott: Is that risky?
Scott: Right, so it's like if you're gonna have a convention and you're gonna say that I have to wear a mask the whole time.
Scott: Well then in that case You're basically admitting that the convention itself is risky And therefore we need to take precautions the whole time in which case I'm not gonna go to that because it's risky.
Scott: I also could be.
Scott: the convention itself has to be safe enough Fundamentally at its core that I do not need to wear a mask the whole time.
Scott: I am there right For me to be willing to go to it now Even if you're not afraid of all that.
Rym: there is a much more selfish reason not to go to a con like that.
Rym: It's one thing like people who have to work like during this you wear.
Rym: you might wear a mask for eight hours with a break at lunch, but Imagine going to a con like packs and having to wear a mask the entire time from 9 a.m.
Scott: Midnight, I don't.
Scott: I don't buy that Matt.
Scott: wearing a mask is no great discomfort, right?
Scott: That's you know.
Scott: You're basically Get a better mask.
Rym: that doesn't do that Even with seals I just what.
Rym: but more importantly that would be Uncomfortable, you know, I can't just like drink.
Scott: while you're sitting in there You sound you sound like the Trumpy people like I don't want our mayor.
Rym: They still have to require masks.
Rym: Just don't go to any event that requires masks because if it's a mass event like that It's probably not safe to go to in the first place.
Scott: I just disagree.
Scott: the mass are uncomfortable in any way It's not.
Scott: it's no inconvenience to wear one.
Scott: But my only my only reason is I still if it's if it's so unsafe that one is required Then it's so unsafe that I'm not gonna go.
Rym: I'm saying I would find it very uncomfortable to wear a mask for 14.
Scott: The mass courtroom is face fucked up.
Rym: But I'll wear them while it's necessary.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: I won't do put myself in a situation unnecessarily.
Rym: where it's necessary.
Rym: I would not go to any convention that required masks at any point because like you said if the convention requires masks It's not safe enough.
Rym: That's right and Otakon is happening.
Scott: If it's not if it's not yeah If it's not so if the situation is not such that we can just safely have a no mass convention Then it's not safe enough for us to have a convention.
Rym: So Otakon is going forward with the in-person con in August beginning of August going to that.
Rym: they're requiring Masks for all attendees for the entire time.
Rym: They're in the convention center and there would be designated areas for eating.
Rym: So I'm not going anywhere near that.
Scott: Nope, I don't recommend anyone else.
Scott: go to that either.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: so, uh, we ended up talking a lot about news.
Rym: the show is 51 minutes long already Even accounting for the thing.
Scott: what happened?
Rym: We did.
Rym: we did a tech news roundup by accident.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I feel like we should save UX for a different Monday.
Scott: No, you're cheating.
Rym: It's either that or hey, I tried to get you to shut up and you kept talking about Apple But I didn't talk about that long.
Rym: Yeah, you did.
Rym: I have the matters.
Rym: I put a marker in the metadata for every topic.
Scott: It's not cuz the phone sure it isn't cuz the door rang.
Rym: the door ringing removed a grand total of.
Rym: So I can select this right now just trying to bail.
Scott: you should have bail.
Scott: mid show.
Rym: two minutes and 30 seconds was removed.
Rym: We have currently recorded 55 minutes before we stopped just now.
Rym: So do you want to go for 40 minutes 30 minutes talk about UX design for five minutes and call it a day.
Scott: I Guess I have to eat food and it's almost seven.
Rym: I guess we accidentally did a tech news roundup through no fault of my own.
Scott: Yeah, you cheated.
Scott: Okay, you can't do a tech news around him next year.
Scott: you lost it.
Scott: I'm just saying if we uh, if you go back to the audio, that's it March March 2022 No tech news.
Rym: There are numerous points where you hear me try to be like, okay Let let's can we?
Rym: we should know at and you Scott just kept going.
Scott: No.
Scott: All right, 2023 is the next tech news around.
Scott: You lost these petty or you got it.
Rym: You feel like this might happen again.
Scott: You got a loan you took a loan out and now you're in debt.
Rym: This Has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the patreon patreons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi McNichol Alan Joyce link Eiji dread lute teddy break Chris Reimer Clinton Walton, just like a dude guy program threat open speed undertake law adoption pierce absorb Rebecca Dunn review mad bull 34 cowards Ryan parent Sam Erickson Shervin von Horrell Taylor Braun.
Rym: You hold the key to my heart and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names live on the Show.
Rym: so uh yeah, we uh we plan to talk about user experience design But we went long on.
Rym: the news couldn't get Scott to shut up, so I snuck in another tech news roundup.
Rym: You are welcome to give feedback in the GeekNights forum or perhaps the GeekNights discord Reminding Scott that the tech news roundup format is actually very popular and that perhaps Monday episodes Would be easier to do if we just did this on a monthly basis, but I digress anyway.
Rym: enjoy your summer.
Rym: We'll figure out what we'll do on Wednesday since we haven't watched any new anime yet And I don't think Scott's gonna watch sweet tooth until he reads all of it and all of it's not even out yet.
Rym: So uh for now I leave you with.
Scott: and the very same goes for Ezekiel which brings us back to our starting point the nine tenets of constancy.
Rym: I Seem to have lost my place, so I'll start over.
Scott: Our sermon today is on Constancy and as much as the over by dint of our application of these principles we can learn of constancy You.