Rym: It's Tuesday, October 12th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we are talking about the number of players in games.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I did go into the office today and it's still nice out and also COVID time.
Rym: So when that happens, I always bike and I use the city bike because it's easier than going down to the bike room and getting my bike through the security area and taking it up and then get into the office and going through the bike parking area.
Rym: City bike for such a short ride kind of just works.
Rym: But this morning I go down and of course all the bikes are gone in the main dock even though I left early.
Rym: So no trouble.
Rym: So I walk around the corner to another dock and there's only two bikes on this dock.
Rym: And I look and all the city bikes are gone for some reason in the area.
Scott: So fine.
Rym: I go to get one bike and it just like fails.
Rym: And now I'm kind of in a hurry.
Rym: So crap.
Rym: So I go get the other bike and it works fine.
Rym: And I start biking and I make it exactly halfway over the bridge.
Rym: And then I realize in my haste I left my city bike key in the fucking city bike dock that also has it also has my house key and my Yuba key on it.
Scott: Oh no.
Rym: So I immediately turn around and I bike as fast as I can on a city bike which thankfully was there.
Rym: It was mostly downhill.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It was just there in the dock.
Rym: And I think if nothing else what saved me was one.
Scott: The dock was empty so no one was going to go to that dock.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: There's two things going on here.
Rym: One wall thing is if you lose something on the street like it's often just gone in New York you just got to live with that.
Rym: But generally the etiquette in New York is if you see something on the street that someone probably lost the best bet is to leave it there.
Rym: Because whoever lost it will probably come back trying to find it and cross its path.
Rym: Unless you're like in a venue where there's like a lost and found or security or something.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Subway.
Scott: You can take it to the booth on the subway.
Rym: I have taken things to the booth before.
Rym: I retrieved something from the booth before.
Rym: But if you find something like on the street like I've seen people's keys just like on the street.
Rym: And usually I just leave them there because I figure whoever it is is going to fucking come back like I did.
Rym: Imagining in their head the pain in the ass of losing your keys.
Rym: And it was there and it was fine and I biked back to work.
Rym: and that's the most exciting thing that happened to me today.
Rym: That's all I got.
Rym: My biking bit.
Rym: Got any gaming news?
Scott: Gaming news.
Scott: I mean the Metroid game came out.
Rym: But you got the Diana Jones award.
Scott: Yeah right.
Scott: So the Diana Jones award if you don't know about it.
Scott: I think we've talked about it on the show at least once or twice before.
Scott: We had to.
Scott: This award.
Scott: Yeah it's from like 20 years ago.
Scott: I think it's been around.
Scott: And it's basically this award where they constructed it out of like a piece of wood.
Scott: A burnt copy of an Indiana Jones RPG.
Scott: Like literally burnt set on fire.
Scott: And then encased the remains of the burnt RPG in some sort of like acrylic pyramid thing and stuck it on there.
Scott: So it looks like some sort of ancient artifact that Indiana Jones would maybe get somewhere.
Scott: And they have a committee that's a somewhat secret committee that just nominates.
Scott: It announces nominees and then at Gen Con it announces a winner.
Scott: Literally it's just for excellence in gaming annually and the award can go to anything.
Scott: It can go to a game.
Scott: It can go to a person.
Scott: It can go to a concept.
Scott: There was the year that actual play won.
Scott: Board Game Geek won it one time.
Rym: And in a way a lot of what they do is like how it's gotten.
Rym: We did a show a long time ago on award shows and awards and like nomination processes and everything.
Rym: This is more than a decade ago.
Rym: And we talked a lot about how if we made one we would just pick a bunch of people who we trust and they just fucking decide.
Rym: And we don't like do any weird drama or have an academy that just doesn't watch movies.
Scott: Dominion won one time.
Scott: Nordic LARP.
Scott: Just the concept of Nordic LARP just won once.
Rym: The 2001 winner was Peter Edkison.
Scott: Yeah, the first person.
Rym: Yeah, CEO of Wizards of the Coast.
Scott: The guy who founded Wizard of Watsi.
Scott: Yeah, famous person.
Scott: Anyway, so this year in 2021, the winner was Casey from Nib Card Games.
Scott: If you don't know about Casey, I was first found out about Casey at the first Unplugged.
Scott: I think there was some sort of.
Scott: I forget exactly what the involvement was, but that's right.
Scott: Somehow learned of his existence.
Scott: He's this dude in Nigeria and basically is like a one man show as far as board games are in Nigeria.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You can't imagine most of the board game companies in the world are, you know, especially with the supply chain deal, are not, you know, they're not shipping a thousand copies of ticket to ride to Nigeria.
Scott: So basically this dude, he, A, publishes board games.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Designs board games.
Scott: He has a board game cafe store place and he runs a convention.
Scott: He basically does every board game thing that needs to be done all in Nigeria.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Pretty much carrying, you know, Nigerian board games on his back over there.
Scott: And the Dana Jones Award recognized his excellence, which is very well deserved.
Scott: I would have also chosen Casey from amongst the nominees.
Scott: It's a fantastic choice.
Scott: I follow Casey on Twitter and he tweets a lot of good stuff.
Scott: So that's good.
Scott: The second news is a sadder news.
Scott: The the Diana Jones Award, unlike say, you know, well, like the Stanley Cup.
Rym: I was about to say this is our favorite kind of trophy.
Scott: There's just one.
Scott: They don't keep making new ones.
Scott: They don't have more copies of the Indiana Jones RPG to set on fire.
Rym: So we might need to start sourcing some.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: I don't know where you get it from.
Scott: But anyway, so there's just one of them.
Scott: And what they would do is they would just sort of if the person who won it was at Gen Con, they'd be like, here you go.
Scott: And if the person who won it, you know, wasn't a Gen Con, they'd like mail it to you, whatever.
Scott: So you basically get to hold on to it for a year.
Scott: They just, you know, just like here, hey, go have it.
Rym: Yeah, like here.
Rym: Here's here's the Stanley Cup.
Rym: Well, though, with an asterisk that is a little more complicated with the Stanley Cup.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So Alex Roberts was the twenty nineteen winner and Alex Roberts had it in Canada.
Scott: And the winner in twenty twenty was Black Excellence in Gaming, where they gave the award to like several, like a whole bunch of people all at once.
Scott: So they didn't actually Alex Roberts just held on to the physical object.
Scott: But at this year, they actually had a Gen Con.
Scott: So there was an attempt to mail the Diana Jones Award.
Scott: Alex Roberts went to the Canadian post office and mailed it to one of the, you know, Diana Jones committee people.
Scott: And it did not arrive.
Scott: And there's like no tracking and they don't know where it is.
Rym: It's the way you said that there was an attempt.
Scott: It's probably just gone.
Rym: It's like when we tried to mail that Animal Crossing poster from Australia to our friend.
Scott: Yeah, it's just gone, which is sad.
Scott: But, you know, the physical award isn't what matters here.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not, you know, they can keep awarding the Diana Jones Award without the Diana Jones Award.
Rym: Though, I would love, I hope that at some point, like a decade from now on GeekNights, we cover like, hey, somebody found the Diana Jones trophy.
Scott: Yeah, it'll be some way.
Scott: It's somewhere on Earth.
Scott: It's not like incinerated.
Rym: I highly doubt it is incinerated or crushed or something.
Scott: No, but what could happen to it is if it's like really lost in the mail, that eventually the whatever postal service, if it, you know, if they don't deliver it, it might be just trashed or something.
Rym: Or sold off at auction in a lot or something.
Scott: Stolen, you know, someone's just got it.
Scott: They know what they knew what it was.
Scott: They just got it.
Rym: Some nerd has to make a documentary just about the trophy and like try to track it down and probably fail and make a YouTube video about it.
Scott: It's really hard to find something that's lost in the mail.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So, I played the Actraiser Renaissance, the remake.
Rym: I got through most of the film.
Scott: So isn't it just the same as Actraiser 1, only HD?
Rym: Nope.
Rym: So I, being the kind of person that I am, and apparently you're the same way, I don't read reviews of games.
Rym: I play games myself and I review them.
Rym: So I did not read anything about the Actraiser remake other than all the stuff around the new soundtrack.
Scott: I saw the Nintendo Direct really announced it.
Scott: And that looked like it was just an HD remake of the original with also the option to go non-HD.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: So I did also that, well, the big news I was focusing on was that because Actraiser on the Super Nintendo had one of the bitchinest scores to like grace the Super Nintendo as a platform.
Rym: It was such a good soundtrack.
Rym: And the remake, as we talked about, has a recomposition, like an HD version of that score.
Scott: Yeah, well, you know, didn't we already talk about Yuzo Koshiro's comments regarding what he did on this?
Rym: We talked about that.
Rym: So I figured I was going to play it.
Rym: And what I expected was I'll play janky old Actraiser, but I'm just going to revive to the soundtrack.
Rym: Yeah, this is actually, they added stuff.
Rym: This is way different than the original Actraiser.
Rym: And honestly, it's just better in every possible way.
Scott: Well, how much money is it?
Rym: It's 30 bucks right now.
Rym: I would say it might be worth 30 bucks if and only if you have never played the original Actraiser ever.
Scott: I think that's most people.
Rym: I think it would be worth your while then to try this game out because despite the fact that the town part is not that great and the platforming is also not that great, there still is a dearth of games that have both the town and the side scroll.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: So what's different?
Rym: I'll talk about what's different.
Rym: Because having played it so far, I'm really enjoying it.
Rym: One, they really, like.
Rym: there's characters now.
Rym: Like the angel is a character with a lot of dialogue.
Rym: She's really cute.
Rym: You are this super hot god and they have like anime visual novel looking art for everybody.
Rym: They added a bunch of characters who are new, who interact with you and the angel.
Rym: And they're also heroes that will move into your towns and can be leveled up.
Rym: There's also tower defense of the towns.
Scott: That sounds fun.
Rym: The towns will like get attacked and you got to deal with that shit and you can use your god powers just like you do in the normal game, like drop lightning on them and stuff.
Rym: You can direct your town folks like the heroes where to go fight at doing the tower defense game.
Rym: You're building palisades and forts and things and like how much do you fortify your town?
Rym: If you got a lot of forts, that reduces how much the town produces.
Rym: And beyond that, it just has a ton of quality of life improvements that make the town bit a little more complex, like a little meatier.
Rym: There's a little more to chew on when you're playing it.
Rym: It's not just trivial.
Rym: Because I thought, "Oh whatever, they added a tower defense.
Rym: This game's so...".
Rym: and then I died.
Rym: I was like, "Wait, what?
Rym: What?
Rym: Game over?
Rym: What?".
Rym: I actually had to try a little bit in the early tower defense part.
Rym: So they added all these extra systems to make the town part not just a nothing game.
Rym: Because as much as I love the original Actraiser for being unique, the town part of the original Actraiser is kind of a nothing game.
Rym: It feels good when you first start playing, but there's so little there.
Rym: There are so few mechanics that it just pads out playtime before you go back in and do the side scroller.
Rym: In terms of the side scroller, it's pretty much the exact same game, right down to the janky controls.
Rym: But they added a few more combo-y attacks.
Rym: you can do that make it more fun and more like a modern side scroller.
Rym: And they added a backdash, like Symphony of the Night style, which actually makes it playable.
Rym: Unlike the original side scroller, which honestly, good for its time, not good by 21st century standards.
Rym: So, I don't know.
Rym: I'm enjoying it.
Rym: I'm going to give it a full review after I beat it because I don't know if it actually gets a lot harder or if more things come in.
Rym: But so far there have been enough changes to where it is a materially different game.
Rym: So speaking of which, how's that Metroid Dread?
Rym: I have not even started it yet.
Scott: I mean, the Metroid Dread is a 2D Metroid game, much like Super Metroid.
Scott: It's really good, right, in terms of anything you want from a Metroid game.
Scott: The new stuff is exciting.
Scott: The only thing is I think other people who aren't me could, and I totally agree, could say that it's the best Metroid.
Scott: It's even, you know, it's at the Super Metroid level.
Scott: And I could see why they would say that.
Scott: It's just that me personally, and this started a huge discussion today with our friends, right, is.
Scott: I'm not personally a fan of, you know, action video games that are Simon Says-y, right?
Scott: So, you know, you look at a lot of popular games these days, like in the action genre, like say like the Bayonetta types or the Souls types, right, where you're like doing these Simon Says fights.
Scott: We're like, oh, the bad guy does this animation.
Scott: That means at this timing, you push these buttons to roll out of the way, and then you attack.
Rym: That's kind of how, like even Actraiser is like that.
Scott: Yeah, or like you look at say like Breath of the Wild, it's like when you're fighting a Lynel.
Scott: It's like, well, when the Lynel does this attack, you gotta, you know, press A at the right time to counter, right?
Scott: It's like, it's a very Simon Says kind of play, and I feel like I've done a lot of that.
Scott: I enjoyed some of it in the past, but these days and for the past several years, I really do not enjoy that, right?
Scott: It's like when a game, if a game is entirely that, like just a straight up action game, I just don't play them, even if I might recognize that they're well made.
Scott: And what about how?
Rym: most of them, it's Simon Says, but there's multiple patterns you can do that all have this, that will all successfully deal with.
Scott: There are a lot of subtle differences between all of the games, yes, and some of them do it better than others.
Scott: You could probably spend days and days and days just talking about that specific, that narrow topic.
Scott: There's so much material there.
Rym: I mean, I'm still working on that panel of just looking at resource loops and threat levels of characters in team based first person shooters.
Scott: Yeah, but Simon Says in video games is huge.
Scott: It's so huge, it's actually difficult to imagine, like when you think about games without Simon Says, like, oh, the boss doesn't signal what attack he's going to do.
Scott: It sounds like a bad game, right?
Rym: Honestly, they usually are.
Rym: Usually, boss fights and things like that are not fun.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: But it's just like, you can't think of anything else in between bad game and just, like if I want to play Simon Says, I could play DDR.
Scott: See, I think you're oversimplifying, though.
Rym: It isn't just Simon Says.
Rym: There's a lot of different ways to react to things.
Rym: That's just skill.
Rym: Fencing is just Simon Says by that logic.
Rym: Literal real world fencing is just Simon Says by that logic.
Rym: You react.
Scott: But a literal real world person doesn't just have like five patterns.
Rym: Yeah, they kind of do.
Scott: They only have five moves.
Scott: They don't have any more.
Scott: They do them exactly the same way each time.
Rym: So what, you just want a harder boss that I feel like you would get even more frustrated with if it just acted like a real thing?
Scott: It's not about the frustration, right?
Scott: It's like I beat all these bosses, no problem.
Scott: I just don't enjoy the Simon Says pattern boss combat.
Rym: But what pattern do you want, then?
Rym: A fight?
Scott: I don't want a pattern.
Scott: I want it to be like I'm playing against a person where there is no pattern.
Scott: Like if you're playing a fighting game and the other person is just a person, who knows what the hell they're going to do.
Rym: But almost the entire skill of fighting games is reacting to slight movements and frame timing of the other player to then deal with their combos.
Scott: That aspect of fighting games I don't like.
Scott: But the aspect of the other person is a person.
Scott: And it isn't just a loop that says, "Randomly pick from this list of three
Scott: things.".
Scott: Alright, now pick from the same list of three things again.
Scott: And once you've taken enough damage, the list of things you can do expands.
Scott: Now pick from this list of things randomly in a loop.
Rym: So the only difference between what you're describing and a real world fight or a morgue is just how many things are on that random list.
Rym: And there aren't that many, even in real world situations.
Scott: Regardless, right?
Scott: Metroid, Dread.
Rym: I don't think you just don't like playing real time games anymore.
Scott: I mean, whatever.
Scott: With bosses of any kind.
Scott: We can discuss that later, but the point is, compared to other Metroid games, Metroid Dread really goes harder on the action, you know, Simon Says parts.
Scott: Ooh, that makes me excited, actually.
Scott: Alright, it's like, not only are the bosses very action game, right?
Scott: If you like those kind of games, which most people do, I'm the weird one.
Scott: You'll love the bosses in Metroid Dread because within that, you know, framework, they are excellent, right?
Scott: And not only that, but also, you know, in most Metroid games, the regular old enemies that are just around are like, just sort of decoration.
Scott: They usually don't do much, right?
Scott: You just sort of blow them away or clean them up.
Rym: Actuarizer is like that.
Rym: Actuarizer is basically just get to the boss, now there's a really hard boss fight.
Scott: In Metroid Dread, even if you, you know, I guess if you get really powered up, then the bad guys in sort of the early areas become really weak.
Scott: But in some of the areas, the bad guys are like actually, I guess until you get the Screw Attack.
Scott: The Screw Attack really lets you mess everyone up big time.
Scott: But before you get the Screw Attack, which is very late, you actually, the bad guys are like, yeah, you have to do like a timed hit on the bad guys to counter them to get more energy out of them.
Scott: Or there'll be some challenging regular bad guys who are just walking around trying to get somewhere and this guy gets in your way.
Scott: He's just a normal guy.
Rym: You know, I like that because a similar thing happened in, of all games, Final Fantasy IV.
Rym: Where the regular, like in the American game, they kind of nerfed the regular, like they nerfed the bosses and the regular stuff.
Rym: But in the original game, all the regular fights along the way were kind of moderately challenging puzzles or moderately difficult.
Rym: Separate, very different from a lot of earlier Final Fantasy games.
Rym: Like you couldn't just ignore those like regular old fights along the way.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, if you're not, if you're not me who doesn't like, you know, games, action, video game, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Then you might, I would, I would not, you know, disagree or I could completely agree with someone saying that like, yeah, this is like the best Metroid game there is.
Rym: You know what I got to do?
Scott: Even me, right?
Scott: I would probably put it second after Super Metroid and I'm, you know.
Rym: I was about to say, I got to go back because I have never actually played the Metroid Prime games.
Scott: Oh, well, you know, those are like in a different category.
Rym: Yeah, I know.
Rym: But I got, I have now played them and that's, that's one of my deep, like that's in the backlog near the top.
Scott: You should have played them in college when I did.
Rym: Yeah, but I was busy.
Rym: So I watched you play them and I was mostly playing Counter-Strike.
Scott: Didn't they put them out for the Switch?
Scott: I think you get them on Switch, right?
Rym: Yeah, but I just, since I got a Switch, I've been busy.
Rym: I haven't even started Metroid Dread yet.
Rym: I'm not the final boss.
Rym: In fact, I bought it and Actraiser at the same time and then Actraiser finished downloading first.
Rym: That's why I started playing Actraiser.
Rym: So, in one last gaming adjacent news, so we already said that we're not going to go to Pac South, not irrespective of COVID, but also for political reasons.
Scott: Like, Texas has done so many egregious things that, like, we can't even- We were already going to Texas before, but now we're definitely, it's like way over the line.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And it's not, it's not a Bugs Bunny situation where it's like, cross this line, I dare you.
Scott: Alright, I'ma cross it.
Scott: It's like, they cross the line, the end.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: So- You're not drawing another line, that's it.
Scott: Well, while the state of Texas has crossed several egregious dangers- So far, they can't even see the line if they turn around and look backwards.
Rym: Like, I will not visit Texas under any circumstances.
Rym: Like, full stop.
Rym: If my job told me I had to go there, I would threaten to quit.
Rym: Like, that is how bad this is.
Scott: The fact the earth is round puts Texas in danger of crossing the line twice.
Scott: Just how far they've gone forward.
Rym: Somehow, Texas, like, yesterday crossed a line that might actually prevent PAX South from even being able to happen.
Rym: So, the governor of Texas announced that the state has now banned vaccine mandates for any entity that does business in Texas, for both their customers or their employees.
Rym: So, the convention center, the Gonzalez-Sell-Whatever Convention Center, cannot require vaccination.
Rym: An event in the convention center, like the Penny Arcade Expo, cannot require vaccination.
Scott: I guess you could still require it if you're a private non-business, because if you're not a business- Nope, they're covering all private entities.
Scott: Well, you could- your house, right?
Scott: You know, a private place that is not a business.
Rym: But the convention center is not that.
Scott: No, the convention center is not that.
Scott: That is correct.
Rym: And considering that, you know, the PAX West happened, we weren't there, but they required a vaccine or a recent COVID test.
Rym: We know that Unplugged, coming up, which we won't be at either, has gone further and is requiring absolutely vaccinations and you can't come.
Scott: So- Wait, wait, hold on.
Scott: I just want to- this is going to be silly, but I can't not say it, right?
Scott: What if there is an industrial facility in Texas where masks are needed for, you know, because this poison gas or something like that, are they not allowed- No, this only blocks vaccination mandates.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: Now, there are other state rules that say that nobody has to comply with mask mandates, too.
Rym: That's a whole other line.
Scott: If I have a mask mandate for a non-COVID reason, can I enforce it in Texas?
Scott: Or can people come in and breathe poison gas and die?
Rym: I believe the latter based on my reading of all this news.
Rym: Like, for real.
Rym: It is ridiculous.
Scott: But this one- We should open up a poison gas factory in Texas and hire shitty people.
Rym: But considering that PAX Unplugged requires vaccination to attend, which, while we're not going to be there as GeekNights, like as attendees playing games or anything like that, it's still, like, I applaud that compared to lesser measures, if they're going to happen at all.
Rym: I can't imagine they would rescind their vaccine requirement just to continue to do a PAX in Texas.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: We'll see what happens.
Rym: So, I hope against hope.
Rym: there is never again a PAX South in Texas unless Texas becomes a, I don't know, a safe state to visit.
Rym: And at this point, we need to start helping people move out.
Rym: Like, if anyone wants to move out, we almost need a refugee program to, like, pay people.
Scott: No, we need people to move in to vote.
Rym: Yeah, but you can't say that someone has to move to such a dangerous place to be able to fix that place.
Scott: You gotta privilege people who can vote properly.
Rym: Do you want to move to Texas?
Scott: If enough people who were as privileged as I am, who were going to vote and we went together, I would go if it was going to work.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think we could get enough people to commit to that.
Scott: Well, I'm not going to just, you know, just go do it on my own and then say, "Hey guys, follow me," because no one's going to follow me.
Rym: In fact, there's other stuff going on right now where, like, banks can't hire employees there and a bunch of big banks can't even, like, they have said they won't underwrite bonds for the state of Texas anymore because Texas also passed a bunch of laws saying it is illegal to not service the gun industry and a bunch of banks don't want to underwrite, like, gun shit.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Banks are those?
Scott: because I want to be a customer of those banks.
Rym: Goldman Sachs just said, "Well, we're not going to underwrite any bonds in Texas because...".
Scott: Well, I can't get a checking account at Goldman Sachs, can I?
Scott: I mean, if you can get a credit card from Goldman Sachs, the Apple credit card, I don't think you can get a checking account there.
Rym: I cannot envision a world where the Penny Arcade Expo goes back on their vaccine mandate for Texas.
Rym: So I predict there will be no PacSouth in January, or if there is a PacSouth, it will not be in Texas.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So check this out.
Rym: You ever been on a boat or a ship and there's these big white canisters hanging kind of off the side with a bunch of ropes tied to them?
Scott: I've seen those on boats, but I've never been on a boat big enough to have them.
Rym: Oh, actually, the Seastrick Ferry to Sandy Hook has them.
Scott: If it has it, I didn't see them on there.
Rym: Yep, they're on the side because whenever I'm on a boat like that, I like looking at them because they're neat and they're complicated.
Rym: And what they are are life preservation vessels.
Rym: They're basically lifeboats.
Rym: But you might wonder how those things get deployed.
Rym: My Thing of the Day is a sped up video, 36 seconds long, that shows what one of those canisters does if you activate it.
Rym: And all I'm going to say is it is so much more impressive and complicated than you are possibly imagining.
Rym: They basically just throw that thing down into the water and magically there is a lifeboat with a cover and a slide and everything just there.
Rym: Like, magically out of nowhere like a Transformer.
Scott: Well, it's better than what Titanic had.
Rym: Nothing?
Rym: Are you sure you had lifeboats?
Rym: Are you sure it wasn't nothing?
Scott: They had some lifeboats.
Rym: They did have a few lifeboats.
Rym: Half of them were on the wrong side of the boat and couldn't be used.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: And they were the kind, I'm pretty sure, with pulleys that you had to lower down, right?
Rym: Yep, they were just literal small boats that had to be lowered down carefully.
Scott: There are still boats that I've seen that still have that kind.
Rym: Yeah, but this is like what a modern lifeboat actually looks like on a real ship.
Scott: Alright, cool.
Scott: Hope you never have to use one of these in a non-training context.
Rym: I was about to say, unless you're being trained or doing it for funsies.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, thing of the day.
Scott: So, my biological sister, I don't know, some people might be finding this out, is semi-famous?
Scott: I don't know what counts as famous these days, right?
Rym: There was a brief period when GeekNights was more famous than her because she didn't do anything yet because she was younger than us.
Rym: And then she became famous.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Some level of fame.
Scott: Definitely higher than our level of fame by a significant amount.
Scott: But she worked at Buzzfeed making videos, being in videos, and whatnot.
Scott: She doesn't work there anymore.
Scott: She's doing her own thing, I guess.
Scott: I don't know what's going on out there in California.
Scott: That place is crazy.
Scott: But she started a Patreon as of yesterday, maybe?
Scott: So, yeah.
Scott: You can go and check out her arts if you enjoy them and give her money so that she never comes asking me for money.
Scott: I don't think she has money problems.
Scott: She can still afford to live in California.
Scott: I think she's doing okay.
Scott: But, you know, when you're on your own, sometimes things don't work out.
Scott: Who knows what's going to be years down the line.
Rym: Her art's cool, too.
Rym: If I had to describe it without describing it, it is adjacent to topics discussed in Neon Genesis Evangelion.
Scott: I like the illustration she does.
Scott: that reminds me of Eternity from Marvel Comics.
Scott: It'll be something all colorful, some colorful cartoon land, but then there's like a spaceman.
Scott: A shape of a human-ish shape, but it's just outer space inside of that shape.
Rym: Stylized and psychedelic.
Rym: Interesting art.
Scott: Yeah, so she does a lot of stuff over there.
Scott: If you're giving GeekNights money, Jesus Christ, go give Sarah Rubin $5 a month.
Rym: Well, I mean, the GeekNights Patreon is giving five of its dollars to Sarah.
Scott: Oh, you can do that?
Rym: Yeah, but so the way Patreon works, my Patreon is also GeekNights.
Scott: But if you sign up for someone else's Patreon, it will take money that someone else gave to GeekNights and give it to the someone else?
Rym: It will.
Rym: It'll take from that.
Scott: It won't charge your credit card every month because I don't have a Patreon that I'm taking money in.
Scott: I'm only giving money out.
Scott: So it's charging my credit card every month.
Scott: Here's your statement.
Scott: Yours takes that money from the listener.
Rym: So you could go direct to the source here if you like this art.
Scott: So I think if that's the case, if Rym patronizing another Patreon simply redistributes the listeners wealth, you should sign up for so many Patreons.
Scott: Eventually, it evens out to nothing because you don't need the money, right?
Rym: I actually should have a Patreon game.
Rym: The problem is all the Patreons I subscribe to, I never even go to any of their content anymore.
Rym: I'm too busy.
Scott: Oh, see, every morning on my iPad, I open a Patreon app and I scroll through and I see because it's not too many that are posting content that regularly.
Rym: A guaranteed video has paused multiple times because they could not provide the guarantee that much.
Scott: Most of the people are not posting stuff that frequently, so it's really just a few comics-y things that are really posting a lot of stuff in there.
Scott: And a lot of people also might be posting frequently, but I'm sticking to the $1 tier.
Scott: You have to go to $5 to get actual lots of content.
Rym: Sometimes some people I'm a patron of primarily because I want to support their activism specifically, or like the thing that they're doing even if I'm not a fan of that thing personally.
Scott: Well, I mean, I think I am a fan of the thing or the person or the thing the person makes or both, but even if I was getting that feed of all that stuff, it's like I don't like the stuff that much that I needed to consume it daily or weekly even.
Rym: Well, there are marginalized streamers I support, but it's not that I don't watch marginalized streamers.
Rym: It's that I don't watch any streamers.
Rym: I don't watch streamers at all, ever, except AGD2.
Scott: For example, my recent thing of the day, the Cracking the Cryptic, the Sudoku people, if you sign up for their Patreon, you get extra puzzles and extra videos and it's like, "Whoa, dudes, you put up two YouTube videos a day plus more.
Scott: That's already way more Sudoku than I ever
Scott: need.".
Scott: Unless that was my primary geekery, I would not need all that stuff.
Scott: If I'm going to Patreon you, I'm going to do it at the lowest level because I'm not actually going to consume that much content.
Scott: I would have to sacrifice something else I care about much more because I don't have that time.
Rym: So, anyway, in the meta moment, the GeekNights Book Club book, which I slowed down.
Rym: I haven't read any since the last GeekNights because of business.
Scott: Well, I got held up by Metroids.
Scott: Yep, so we both got away with it a little bit.
Scott: I'm going to dispose of the Metroids today or tomorrow, I believe.
Rym: And the weather's getting chillier.
Rym: It's the time of the year when I can go sit in the park.
Rym: It's a little too cold to do a bike ride, but I'll just sit there and read.
Rym: Anyway, Genji continues to do his thing, but I haven't read it in a week.
Scott: He continues to say the same thing every time?
Rym: Yeah, because, I mean, can you spoil the tale of Genji?
Scott: I think that the statute of limitations is over for the first novel ever written by human beings ever.
Rym: Also, I dare anyone listening to this podcast, even if I said a specific spoiler about a specific character, to remember which character that was when you encountered them in the book.
Rym: Unless it's Genji.
Rym: Or maybe Genji's best friend, that guy.
Scott: Alright, also meta moment.
Scott: So, there is/was a GeekNights newsletter that at times has been sent frequently and at times has been sent infrequently.
Rym: It's fantastic.
Rym: Scott doesn't like people to praise him or anything we do, but he writes it all.
Rym: I don't have anything to do with it.
Rym: It's always been fantastic.
Scott: It's free, unlike Rym, who's charging you for extra work, right?
Scott: The GeekNights newsletter was run using a free web service called Tiny Letter, which is basically MailChimp's free mode.
Scott: They have it off to the side.
Scott: They don't think they update it or anything.
Scott: It's just been there for years.
Scott: I'm surprised they haven't shut it down.
Scott: So, it still exists over there, but I kind of felt uncomfortable with that platform.
Scott: Like, are they just going to delete this?
Scott: Like, what's, you know, right?
Scott: So, I went through all the trouble of making a new email template, and I set up a whole new email sending system, all the computer parts and everything, and it seems to work.
Scott: I just tested it.
Scott: The only issue I think that might exist is that if you use a weird email reader, the emails might look weird.
Scott: So, I copied over all the subscribers, a few hundred of them, right, from the old system to the new system.
Scott: So, if you're already subscribed, don't worry.
Scott: You're just going to get an email whenever I send one.
Scott: I got to write one first.
Scott: And if you're not already subscribed, well, we have a new URL, which I haven't typed anywhere yet.
Scott: So, you're just going to have to listen.
Scott: It's newsletters.frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: Or is it newsletter.frontrowcrew.com?
Scott: Hold on.
Rym: Careful.
Rym: One of those might go somewhere bad somehow.
Scott: It's newsletter.frontrowcrew.com/subscription/form.
Rym: All I can think of is tomorrow.org/blog.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: If you put a trailing slash after the form, it's not going to work.
Scott: So, that's just because I'm using some open source software.
Scott: That's just how it works.
Scott: It's not my fault.
Scott: So, yeah.
Scott: If you go there, you can subscribe to the GeekNights newsletter and you'll receive it whenever I eventually send it.
Scott: And also, I'm going to find some way to collect the old ones, back them up, back up the new ones, and I'm going to create some sort of more easily browsable archive.
Scott: Because otherwise, the only way to browse the archive will be to like find the email that you saved or click the like view on web link at the bottom of the email or something like that.
Scott: And I guess the privacy conscious people out there would probably like to know that since I'm hosting this ourselves, you know, there isn't going to be any privacy tracking nonsense.
Scott: And also, in the new version of frontrowcrew.com, which is partially underway, I'm basically decided I'm just going to remove all the Google Analytics and all that.
Scott: Just removing all that shit.
Scott: We don't need it.
Scott: We don't look at it.
Scott: Why should I bother you with that?
Rym: I barely even look at like the analytics I get from our YouTube channel.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, I'm just going to remove all that nonsense.
Scott: We're just going to serve up, you know, a normal quality web page when we get around to it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: It's like the old days.
Rym: Here's a website and there's content on this website.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: We're going to make us a motherfucking website.
Scott: So, look forward to that.
Scott: And if you know anyone who is really good at web design and HTML CSS parts that could make a motherfucking website that doesn't have a lot of bullshit JavaScript on it, mostly just really good at CSS is what we need.
Scott: And let me know because it took me like a long ass time just to make one email template.
Scott: If I have to make the whole website, it's going to be tough.
Rym: And before you ask, yes, we'll pay.
Rym: We pay real money when someone works for us.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That Patreon money before it goes to some other patrons.
Rym: What it actually goes to is like, well, like the new geek guys logos.
Rym: We hired a designer.
Rym: We paid them market rates.
Rym: That's how we brawl.
Rym: Like, we're not going to, if you actually are skilled and you can't talk to Scott and it works out and you make our website for us, you'll be making money comparable to the going like contract rates for that kind of development.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So we're riffing here.
Rym: This is a topic that we might do a panel on in the future.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But here's the thing, right?
Scott: So this is something that we've talked about in the past somewhat frequently, but always tangentially combined with other topics, not as the topic itself.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it sort of feels like something we've done, but we haven't.
Scott: Secondly, it's something I see people not understand on the Internet with great frequency.
Rym: People don't understand something on the Internet?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Looking at you, board game Reddit, you know, number one.
Rym: Ah, board game Reddit, where the most common post is, "Why is this game
Rym: broken?".
Rym: And the first response is, "Because you're not playing it right.
Rym: Here's the rule that you got
Rym: wrong.".
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: Well, those are just the ones I share with Rym the most.
Scott: But anyway.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No, I saw a discourse the other day on whether or not there is skill in poker.
Rym: This was months ago and it was just like, what?
Rym: Like, like, but the- There's a lot of luck, but yes.
Rym: But that's the kind of conversation that is usually like the discourse almost hurts understanding if you try to interact with people online about it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: And three, right?
Scott: The great game developer publisher, Amabelle Holland from Hollenspiel, right?
Scott: Who make a lot of great games.
Scott: You should check them out if you haven't already.
Scott: They tweeted recently and the tweet was something like there are one player ga-.
Scott: I forget the exact words of the tweet and I haven't been able to find the tweet again because searching Twitter sucks.
Scott: There's no easy way to like search tweets that I have liked or anything like that.
Scott: But anyway, the tweet was something along the lines of there are one player games, two player games, and there are three plus player games, right?
Scott: There's three different kinds of games.
Scott: And they were like, wow, you see, you know, people publish games that are like, yeah, for one to six players.
Scott: And it's like, wow, you made three different games.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, you know, what's going on there?
Rym: And we've talked about this, like you said, a lot, especially in those panels on like how to win at games or heuristics or any of that stuff.
Rym: Like we this is always like under like the baseline of a lot of what we talk about.
Rym: So maybe this can be its own topic.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So for the people who don't understand, let's break it down.
Scott: So you got.
Scott: first of all, you got to divide games into winnable games, the ortho games, as we have borrowed the term.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And ortho games.
Rym: Let's see if I remember the definition of the game where there is a set of players and agreed upon set of rules and a method by which to rank the players at the conclusion of the game.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So it's a. it's a game of winning and losing.
Rym: You can win.
Rym: You can lose.
Scott: Any other kind of game that's not about winning and losing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So is in another category entirely and is not that pertinent to this conversation.
Scott: So that's playing game.
Scott: Dungeons and Dragons, you know, anything else you want to apply the word game to.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Not a competition of winning and losing.
Scott: Doesn't?
Scott: we're not talking about those.
Scott: We're only talking about the winning and losing game.
Scott: So number two.
Scott: OK, so you've got a winning and losing game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And there are.
Scott: I guess Rym wants to talk about the special case where there are zero players.
Scott: I don't think that's worth.
Rym: So the Wikipedia page, which has had a lot of recent updates and I did not make these updates, actually has a lot of academic citations about the three classes of zero player ortho games.
Scott: OK.
Rym: There is.
Rym: what's interesting is this gets into other things we've talked about.
Rym: The three categories that are widely considered to be zero player games are one games of pure chance, which.
Scott: Candyland.
Scott: Yeah, I guess you could consider Candyland to be a zero player game.
Rym: Bunko, Snakes and Ladders, Bingo, Roulette.
Scott: You just find out who wins.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: OK.
Rym: But arguably, if we're talking about games that are ortho games as play, then me and Scott playing one of those games, we're still playing a game with ranking and winners and losers.
Rym: It's just we can't impact the outcome.
Rym: So it's arguable whether or not we're a player with agency.
Rym: Number two is interesting because this covers a lot of other games.
Rym: I don't know how to engage with this, but there's a lot of academic citations, games that are determined by their initial states.
Rym: A game that evolves as determined by its initial state, requiring no further input from humans is considered a zero player game.
Rym: Conway's Game of Life, Progress Quest, et cetera.
Scott: Yeah, I talk about those.
Rym: I don't think why I agree.
Rym: Pure chance is an interesting situation.
Rym: determined by initial state is a lot muddier and I don't think it's worth engaging with.
Scott: That's not something that's not a winning, losing ortho game.
Scott: Conway's, you know, win and lose at Conway's Game of Life.
Rym: Yeah, but players can be ranked.
Scott: There are.
Scott: well, can you be ranked at Conway's Game of Life?
Rym: There are.
Rym: I've seen meta rules for Conway's Game of Life to like have multiple colors or multiple boards and see which one evolves and whatever.
Rym: Anyway, it's not your main.
Rym: The third category is the one we were just talking about before the show.
Rym: AI versus AI games, where all human players have been replaced by AIs, arguably have zero players and the game is more of just an experience watching it play out.
Scott: Right, so if you have AlphaGo play against AlphaGo at Go and you just see who, which one of the two computers wins, right?
Scott: It's like you could consider the computers to be players, whatever.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think, you know, whatever.
Rym: And we're not talking about games that are not ortho games.
Rym: So arguably it doesn't matter if that's a zero player game because I as a player playing the game cannot win or lose because if I play the game it's no longer a zero player game.
Rym: So it's moot and I think we've covered zero player games sufficiently.
Scott: All that is is basically, that's equivalent like running a simulation, right?
Scott: So imagine if I ran a weather simulation, right?
Scott: It's just going to simulate the weather in a local area, you know, maybe try to predict it.
Scott: And I arbitrarily decide beforehand, thunderstorm is winning and bright and sunny means losing.
Scott: It's like that, so what?
Scott: You've made an arbitrary distinction just so that you can classify it as a game instead of a simulation.
Rym: I think zero player matters a lot more for non-ortho games, which are, that's such a broad wide topic that we're only going to touch on the idea of a non-ortho game briefly.
Scott: Okay, so ortho game with one player, right?
Scott: We're talking a solo game.
Scott: People need to understand this.
Scott: All solo ortho games are actually just puzzles, right?
Scott: It's sitting there with a Sudoku and trying to find the answer to the Sudoku.
Scott: is the only difference between that and say, playing pandemic by yourself?
Scott: is that pandemic has hidden information in it, right?
Scott: So you don't, it's not just like an automatically solved puzzle?
Rym: Arguably no single player game can be by definition an ortho game because you must be able to rank the players.
Scott: You're ranking yourself as either win or lose the game.
Scott: The opponent doesn't get a rank.
Scott: You rank yourself either yes or no.
Rym: It's a pass.
Rym: Yeah, but ortho games don't say against, they literally say rank the players.
Rym: So the player one always has the same rank.
Scott: Regardless of whether it's an ortho game or not, all solo games are puzzles.
Scott: Doing the crossword puzzle is effectively the same as playing one favorite board game's solo mode.
Rym: Yeah, playing like the one player variant is increasingly popular.
Rym: I think our point would stand that a board game that says one plus players, the one player version is just a different game that uses the same components.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you can play, you know, what's a good example of something here?
Rym: I mean all the interesting one player game examples I have are not really ortho games.
Rym: Like Hades, it's an experience.
Rym: It's an interactive entertainment for one.
Rym: I wouldn't even consider Hades to be an ortho game because you're not ranking players against each other.
Scott: Right, well consider this.
Rym: And winning this is a variable scale.
Rym: Did you beat the game?
Rym: Did you beat all the side quests?
Rym: Did you unlock everything?
Rym: Did you 100% it?
Rym: It's almost not even a relevant conversation.
Scott: Right, well you have chess, which is a two player game normally.
Scott: But one player chess would be chess puzzles, literally.
Scott: You're using the same pieces as chess and the same rules as chess.
Scott: And being good at one player chess puzzles might help you get better at two player chess.
Rym: That's a good point.
Scott: But playing one player chess, just here's a board, you know, find the checkmate or whatever, right, in one move, you know, that puzzle, is that activity in and of itself is an entirely different game from two player chess.
Scott: Although it shares many, you know, similar rules within it, a puzzle is not the same thing as playing against another person.
Scott: There are two different categories, right, so that's just how it is.
Scott: So when people are out there saying like, "Oh, I want a solo mode for this game," right, say you're playing Ticket to Ride.
Rym: Yeah, what you're saying is, "I want a different game that uses the same
Rym: components.".
Scott: Yeah, I want a different game, exactly.
Scott: And it's fundamentally not the same thing.
Scott: It's a different activity.
Rym: Even more interesting, some tabletop games add like mechanical AIs that will serve the role of a player and follow rules.
Rym: But even then, those things act in a way that is not the same as a real player in most cases.
Rym: And if it is the same as a real player, it's just a very simplistic human opponent.
Rym: It's really a two player game and one of them is an AI.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, that goes back to what I was saying about one player pandemic, right?
Scott: The difference being is like, yeah, there's two kinds of one player puzzles.
Scott: There's ones with perfect information and ones without perfect.
Scott: I mean, there's more categories than that.
Scott: But the biggest difference is the puzzles that are perfect information, like a Sudoku, and the puzzles with the hidden information, like, you know, pandemic by yourself, because there's a deck of cards that's face down.
Scott: You don't know what order they're in, or you might not even know the contents of that deck, right?
Scott: So that would be even more hidden information.
Scott: And the way you approach those puzzles is completely different, you know, but procedurally.
Scott: So if you like one kind of puzzle, you might not like the other kind, but they are still both puzzles.
Scott: It's a puzzle solving exercise, not a gaming, ortho gaming exercise either way.
Rym: Two player is honestly the most interesting space to me because two player games or two team games or races, we'll get into that.
Scott: Yeah, when we say players, we mean sides, right?
Scott: So even if there are like, you know, if you and all of your friends gather around a table and on the table is Klondike Solitaire, and you're all trying to play Klondike together, right?
Scott: Like, oh, you're trying to help spot the right move.
Scott: That's still a one player game.
Scott: That's still a puzzle.
Rym: That's why code games can take N players.
Rym: Like how many people can you fit around that table?
Rym: Because there's two teams.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Or, you know, you can ask for help.
Scott: You know, your whole family can sit around a crossword puzzle and try to solve it together or a word search, right?
Scott: Or just playing pandemic by the rules.
Scott: Is that a co-op game?
Scott: No, that's a one player game pandemic, right?
Scott: And many co-op games are one player games in disguise, right?
Scott: They say they're co-op, but actually they're just puzzles hidden information.
Scott: Some of them have a trainer mechanic thing, which makes them slightly different.
Rym: I almost said bad in most cases, but we've talked about that before.
Scott: And that's why you get the phenomenon known as quarterbacking because you're playing a puzzle.
Scott: And obviously if you're solving a puzzle, whoever is the best at solving a puzzle, right?
Scott: The person who knows the most trivia is going to do the most work on the crossword puzzle.
Scott: And the other is someone, if a child is there who doesn't know a lot of stuff, they're not going to be able to help that much.
Scott: So if you're playing pandemic, which is effectively the same exact activity as five people working on a crossword puzzle together, then it's, it doesn't matter.
Scott: It's not the rules fault.
Scott: It's not the player's fault.
Scott: Stop blaming the other people for the fact that the game has a quarterbacking problem.
Scott: The game's fault is that it's a one player puzzle trying to pass itself off as a co-op activity.
Scott: Co-op, you know, the, the quarterbacking thing is only natural, just like it would be natural with a crossword puzzle because the same activity, right?
Scott: But if you play Hanabi, right, which we've talked about a lot, that's not a single player puzzle, right?
Scott: That's actually a multiplayer game.
Rym: So also Hanabi doesn't really work with two players.
Scott: No, not at all.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So two player games are so unique and interesting that we did an entire podcast about two player games in 2019 specifically, which I'll link to.
Scott: Two player game is the purest form of game, right?
Scott: If you, it's not a puzzle, you're actually competing against another human being or human beings, right?
Scott: If it's teams or something.
Scott: But unlike the three plus player games that we're going to talk about next, there's no politics and there's no vote who wins.
Rym: I can't like sabotage Scott to let Joey Jojo win.
Rym: There's only Scott.
Rym: I'm always trying to sabotage Scott.
Rym: He's the only person.
Scott: It's two people, right?
Scott: Two sides.
Scott: And each side says, I'm trying to make me win.
Scott: And the other side says, well, I'm trying to make me win.
Scott: And you just test your skills at whatever the game is, whatever skill the game is testing, whether that's fighting in a boxing ring or, you know, running fast or, you know, being good at math or being good at memory or being good with your fingers in a fighting game or being good with your fingers in an RTS.
Rym: There's no possibility of king making.
Rym: There's no possibility of a poor player making a weird move that like messes you up.
Rym: You're just you're playing against one entity.
Scott: Yeah, it's, you know, there could be luck involved, but other than luck that could be in there, it's who, which of the two sides is best, right?
Scott: It's a you're measuring.
Scott: It's a true measurement, as true as you're going to have of who of the two sides in the game was better and or luckier at that thing.
Scott: At this moment, you get and you get an answer unless there was cheating or something.
Rym: These are some of the asterisk.
Rym: These are some of the only games that can have what I would consider formal matchmaking.
Rym: that is guaranteed over time with a sufficient quantity of players to accurately rank the real skill of those players.
Rym: These are also games that can devolve into nothing games, broken or solved games very easily or devolve to the point to where the skill that's being tested in the end between two advanced players is radically different from what is being tested among novice players.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But yeah, I think the point you made originally is that like, yeah, this is pretty much the only valid category for competitive games, right?
Scott: If you want to have a competitive game where you actually put some sort of value on the winning and losing, you're not just declaring a winner or a loser for fun, right?
Scott: Because you're playing games, you actually want to like award a trophy or a prize prize money, right?
Scott: Or, you know, make someone's entire career based on being good at this game or make important decisions based on the result of the game.
Scott: It has to be a two player competitive game.
Scott: It can't be any other kind.
Scott: It can't be a one player.
Scott: It can't be like you solve the puzzle, right?
Scott: It's like, what?
Scott: Who cares, right?
Scott: Many people solve the puzzle.
Scott: But as soon as you say, oh, well, see, I have two people and see who solved the puzzle faster.
Scott: Oh, well, now we got something, right?
Scott: It's no longer can you solve it.
Scott: It's who is faster.
Rym: Now, an interesting sidebar, all games that are non interactive, meaning players cannot affect each other.
Rym: They're effectively races that are independent, like a 5K run, for example.
Rym: I can't like shove the person in the lane next to me over.
Rym: Yeah, but then they stop the race and I probably go to jail.
Rym: So basically those games, it literally does not matter how many players they are.
Rym: They're the same experience either way.
Scott: But as long as they're not one, if you run a 5K by yourself.
Rym: Yeah, I could compete against myself, I guess, but that's not really previous time.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So in fact, you know what we do in the episode.
Rym: we did, I'm going to read the description from it on two player games, because here's what we said.
Rym: It's not on GeekNights.
Rym: We consider the unique nature of two player games in a non solitaire, non race game.
Rym: One, two, three, four plus players are radically different experiences.
Rym: Two player games are in a unique and fascinating space.
Rym: They devolve into chess, tic-tac-toe or rock, paper, scissors in most tabletop games.
Rym: Three player games are political.
Rym: Four player games are basically the same.
Rym: But two, two is a class of its own.
Rym: That's the description for that episode.
Scott: And that's exactly right, because when you have a race, right, you can have any number of players in a race and have it be a valid competition where no one can affect anyone else.
Scott: Everyone is doing a solo activity, right?
Scott: But you're measuring how well everyone did the solo activity against each other.
Scott: So everyone ran fast by themselves and then we'll look and see who ran the fastest and that's the winner, right?
Scott: Everyone will do a Sudoku by themselves.
Scott: Whoever solved it the fastest is the winner, right?
Scott: The number of players there doesn't matter.
Scott: It's a race.
Rym: So imagine a two player race that is interactive, like a foot race where Scott and I are running.
Scott: Two player is the only way that you can avoid having a race and have interaction with the other player.
Scott: You actually interact with the other person.
Scott: You hinder them, they hinder you.
Scott: You are in each other's space doing things to each other, but you've maintained the value of the competition, you know, the purity of the competition.
Rym: So if Scott and I are having a foot race, just the two of us, and it's interactive, if he trips me, well, he wins most likely.
Rym: But in a three player race, if Scott trips me, our slow friend, Joey Jojo is going to win the race, possibly.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So yeah, the three plus player games, any game that is three or more players, doesn't matter how many, it could be a million.
Scott: It could be two.
Scott: It can't be two.
Scott: It could be four, right?
Scott: Any game with three or more players or sides, if there is any way for the players to interact with each other at all, right?
Scott: Which could be, you know, direct interaction.
Scott: That's obvious.
Scott: Like, oh, you can just play a card that says so and so loses 10 points.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Um, you know, but it could be very indirect.
Scott: Like, oh, there's a board with, you know, 10 meeples on it.
Scott: And on your turn, you take a meeple from the everyone's taking from the same board.
Scott: It's like you're barely interacting with each other, but you're still interacting.
Scott: You might choose to take the meeple that helps someone else more than the meeple that helps you the most because it'll hurt them for you to take that meeple.
Scott: And you're sort of indirectly affecting them.
Scott: If there's any shared resource, any way for the players actions to have any effect on the other players actions in any way, and there are three or more players, you are playing a political game to some extent.
Scott: Some games are more political than others.
Scott: Some games are nothing but political, like diplomacy.
Rym: But in the end, if you play a three plus player game of any kind, it will either devolve into a perfectly solved solution where if everyone plays equally, you can predict the winner from the beginning, or it will literally just come down to the politics of the interactions.
Rym: Meaning, well, I hurt Scott a little bit and heared me a little bit, so someone else wins.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Now there are cases where the interaction amount, like the amount you can interact is limited by the rules and skill does matter such that someone who is very good can still just win, even if everyone else is trying to gang up on them intentionally, just because they're that much better than the other players.
Scott: A good example might be something like PUBG, right?
Scott: If someone's just really good at PUBG, they could probably win and be the chicken dinner against 99 Scrubs, even if all the Scrubs were just hunting that one person specifically and not shooting each other.
Rym: I have played in Counter-Strike gun games back in the day where everyone knows there's this one motherfucker who is better than everyone else, and everyone tries to gang up on them and it just doesn't matter.
Scott: Yeah, so that is possible.
Rym: But if everyone is maximally skilled, then skill no longer matters for those people.
Rym: Politics is all that matters, unless the game is solvable at that level.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So all three plus player games have this political element, if there's interaction, whether you like it or not.
Scott: And this is where the board game Reddit.
Scott: people come into play, right?
Scott: You see people and they're playing something that's highly political, like Root or Tigris and Euphrates or something like that, right?
Scott: And they're coming in with their two-player nonsense, right?
Scott: And they're like, "How many players do I
Scott: need?".
Rym: They're mad that Root is unfair, or "My friend made a bad mistake with the birds and now the cats ran away with the game and that sucks.
Rym: I should have
Rym: won.".
Scott: It's like, that is the game.
Scott: At three plus players, that is what the game is supposed to be.
Scott: That's what it's designed to be.
Scott: It's a political game intentionally.
Rym: If you don't like the fact that the interactions of the players determine who wins, you don't like games with more than two players.
Scott: Unless they're just races.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So they do.
Scott: let you in the rulebook play two-player Root.
Rym: It's not fun.
Scott: That is A, a bad game, in my opinion, and B, a completely different game.
Scott: It is in no way resembles three plus player Root, except in only these surface details of like, "Yeah, these are the actions you can take on the board and
Scott: such.".
Scott: It's just like a resource-gaining game as opposed to a political game.
Scott: What it takes to win at that game is unrelated.
Scott: I don't even know why they offer it.
Scott: It's like two completely different games with the same box.
Scott: Why is it there?
Rym: While I could say, and I think you'd agree, there is no formal difference between three and any number larger than three.
Rym: There's no formal differences between any of those games at this point.
Rym: But there are soft or informal patterns that we've definitely seen with certain player counts.
Rym: For example, four- and five-player games tend to be very similar to each other, but three-player games very commonly have a very specific pattern where two of the players will get ahead, one of the players falls behind, the player who fell behind is effectively eliminated from the game very early, and the game becomes effectively a two-player game, possibly with the spoiler kingmaker just hanging out in the background.
Scott: Yeah, because there's only three players.
Scott: You don't have a lot of political options.
Scott: And therefore, no matter what the game is, if you have a three-player political game, only after the early game, only two people are really just going to have a chance to win, no matter how well you design that game.
Scott: Can I think of any examples?
Rym: Here's an example.
Rym: If Scott plays a board game with the listeners who aren't crazy about games like we are, like a game Scott's good at.
Rym: So it's Scott and two other listeners.
Rym: If they believe that Scott is better than them at games, it is in their best interest to both attack Scott early to make sure he is effectively eliminated to increase their chances of winning to 50%.
Rym: It is almost impossible to avoid that situation in a three-player game mechanically.
Rym: Three-player games that don't have this pattern of interaction and aren't races are shockingly rare.
Scott: I think the only other pattern would be just one person runs away with it.
Rym: Yep, which I have also seen in some three-player games.
Scott: But for three people to all be in with a good chance of winning towards the end of a three-player game is very unlikely.
Rym: Even in high skill, like a three-player Tigris and Euphrates, even with three people who are extremely high skill and possibly even equal in skill to each other, one player is going to, either by chance or by minor politics, be set behind a little bit.
Rym: And there's like this negative inverse snowball once you're off the board where you can't get back on the board.
Scott: Yeah, you might even be playing like an 18xx, which is like, you know, probably one of the best three-player type games on a board.
Scott: that's a pro, right?
Scott: And it's like, you might be getting late in the game and everyone's like money is pretty close, right?
Scott: And it feels like, yeah, this is really close to three players, but really that small difference, whoever, someone is in third place.
Rym: The second to last operating round.
Rym: Oh, I'm only behind by $80.
Rym: The third to last, the next operating round.
Rym: Okay, now I'm behind by $3,000.
Rym: Next operating round.
Rym: Now I'm behind by $6,000.
Scott: It's just, it feels like you have three players who are in the game, which makes, which keeps the fun level up.
Scott: But the reality is that two players ran away with the game.
Scott: You just didn't tell because the numbers didn't separate that.
Rym: I wonder if I just use some sort of logarithmic or pseudo logarithmic function to look at our value in these games instead of the real number, if that would give me a better sense.
Scott: Yeah, probably.
Scott: Probably.
Scott: Depends on which one though.
Rym: So, but one thing I would say is that the problem that causes one player to fall behind or one player to steamroll ahead in three-player games, they're both actually just symptoms of the same underlying problem and it really just depends on the politics at the table.
Rym: One player running ahead usually happens.
Rym: Imagine me and Scott and Joey Jojo Shabbat who are playing a game and Joey Jojo knows that me and Scott are both good at the game.
Rym: Scott and I tend to fuck each other up to the point that Joey Jojo wins.
Scott: Well, yeah, because if you're good, you have no choice.
Scott: You know, one of the other players is also good.
Scott: You have no choice but to attack them.
Scott: But let's say you got a three-player game with three strong players, right?
Scott: You're still going to be looking at the board and since the game has an interactive political element, right, you're going to calculate at some point, whatever the game is, there'll be some action you can take and you'll recognize, say like Carcassonne, taking points away from someone else is
Rym: as
Scott: good as giving points to yourself.
Scott: They're equal.
Scott: So there's going to be a move that you're going to see.
Scott: that will be negative points for someone, right?
Scott: Maybe you block someone.
Scott: Maybe Rym's working on a castle and I block it, right?
Scott: Well, now it's me and the other person are now ahead and Rym is back.
Scott: It's just natural.
Scott: It's just going to happen.
Rym: My specific strategy I've used for decades...
Scott: Pretend you're losing.
Rym: Well, yeah, I do use psychological tricks, but let's assume I'm playing against you where that shit doesn't work.
Rym: Like, people where they can see right through me.
Rym: In that case...
Scott: Rym's like, "Oh, I'm done.
Scott: I can't win this
Scott: now.".
Scott: Ah, fuck this game.
Rym: Ah, look at me winning.
Rym: That works so well against people who don't know me.
Rym: It's kind of funny.
Rym: Anyway, it used to work on all of you, but you figured me out.
Rym: So, say I can't pull that shit.
Rym: Then my strategy is actually, in most 3-player games, I wait until some other player has taken an action that harms a player on the board who is not me.
Rym: Once that happens, I double down on destroying whoever they hurt a little.
Rym: Dog pile on.
Rym: Remember the Omega-Thon?
Rym: They were playing, like, boom blocks and the first player attacked Green just randomly.
Rym: The second player looked around, laughed, and attacked Green.
Rym: The third player was like, "Oh, well, Green goes
Rym: fourth.".
Rym: Attackin' Green!
Rym: So, Green was basically out of the game.
Rym: The first player comes around again, they attack Blue.
Rym: Blue was the second player, so Blue attacked them, and the third player actually won the game as a result.
Scott: So, the thing to remember here is that all 3+ player games that aren't races have a political element and are therefore inherently different from a 2-player game.
Scott: You cannot go into such a game expecting to win because you were the best.
Scott: You could play the best and lose because people might vote for you to lose, and it's a vote-who-wins game.
Scott: That is what the game is.
Scott: If you don't like that, don't play those games.
Rym: Even better, the skill of being good at a game like that involves trying to manage the politics.
Scott: Yes, indeed.
Rym: Like, for real.
Rym: Best with your friends.
Rym: Act like you're losing.
Rym: Psychology.
Rym: Do things in-game to protect you from politics if that is an option in the particular game you're playing.
Scott: One final note, because I mentioned PUBG before, is that when N becomes large, nothing fundamentally changes.
Scott: As Rym said before, the principles mathematically are the same, but there is a soft difference with very large numbers of players, like a PUBG, in that you're only really able to directly interact with people who are near you.
Scott: You can't interact with everyone in the game.
Rym: I'm stuck in a firefight with the eight people who landed kind of near me.
Rym: Meanwhile, Scott's on the other side of the island.
Rym: It might be all the shitty people are on the other side of the island, and I'm just boned.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So, even though it is fundamentally a vote-who-wins game, think about something like Tetris 99 on the Switch, right?
Scott: Yeah, you are choosing who to attack.
Scott: There is a vote-who-wins element there that ultimately determines a lot.
Rym: More players dilutes the effect of politics.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: It dilutes the effect of politics until the latest stages of the game.
Scott: Therefore, it ends up being not entirely a race, but more, it goes back to being a race, right?
Scott: It's like, yeah, if you play Tetris 99, at the end of the game, you're going to be left with, usually, most of the time, the people who are the best at Tetris, as if you had a Tetris race.
Scott: And then, amongst those people, they will have some sort of competition.
Scott: that is a combination of Tetris skill and politics together.
Scott: The other thing that happens- The politics are still present in the early game, but they're so weak, because there's so many players, you know, and- You almost have to bring enough skill to the table to be able to play the politics game at the end.
Scott: Like, if someone sucked at Tetris, they're just really bad at it.
Scott: Even if all 98 other players voted for that person to win and didn't attack them, they would probably just die on their own, right?
Scott: And even if someone was amazing at Tetris, and all 98 other players voted to take them out, right?
Scott: You can't coordinate that kind of attack, but if you could, you still might not take them out unless some of the other 98 players were good enough.
Scott: Because that player is so good, they'll just be able to clear if the attack isn't strong enough.
Rym: The other thing going on with larger player counts, and again, this is all informal patterns, not formal patterns.
Rym: They're not hard distinctions.
Rym: Is that the more players there are, the more likely it is.
Rym: there is a broader gradient of player skill, which leads to dynamics.
Rym: Like, in a three-player game, it's unlikely that I will be able to, like, farm the actions of the worst player to better myself in a meaningful way.
Rym: But if there's 100 players, there's probably 10 bad players.
Rym: I can go, like, in a deathmatch with 100 players, like a Quake deathmatch that somehow has 100 players.
Rym: My skill, the skill in a deathmatch with 100 players, like Quake 1, would be to find bad players and kill them as quickly as possible, and just let good players kill you so you can get back to killing bad players.
Rym: Like, dynamics can be different.
Scott: Local equilibrium can happen.
Scott: A lot of that depends on the specific rules of the game, right?
Scott: Something like PUBG, where when you kill someone, you get their stuff, right?
Scott: That matters a lot, right?
Scott: Something like Quake, where you instantly respawn, so dying is not that big a deal, right?
Scott: Chasing someone for a minute and not getting any frags would be worse than just dying.
Rym: But here's what I'd say.
Scott: Small player counts-- But another game where you can't really farm people so much, where there's no benefit to attacking weak players, that doesn't give you a benefit for that, well, then that goes away.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So think of it this way.
Rym: Small player counts, generally, the actual specifics of the game don't matter that much.
Rym: That pattern we talked about comes through almost no matter what the mechanics are in a 3-player game.
Rym: But in a 10-player game versus a 20-player game, there's more nuanced or complex patterns that can emerge that rely more heavily on the specifics of those individual games.
Rym: It's a lot harder to generalize about play patterns with higher player counts.
Rym: And we've already gone over an hour, so there's no way we can even begin to talk about player counts in non-Ortho games, which I think there is a topic there, but that's another hour.
Scott: The point is, stop complaining or saying wrong things when it comes to, "Oh, this game has a 1-player version, 2-player version, 3-player
Scott: version.".
Rym: Those are three different games.
Scott: That those are three different games, and that there are inherent properties of those games that you have to accept, whether you like them or not.
Scott: So if you don't like them, recognize that and just don't play them instead of saying something wrong like, "I don't like root because it's
Scott: politics.".
Scott: It's like, yeah, don't play root.
Rym: Go play chess or Eitan or something.
Scott: Yeah, just don't play that then.
Scott: Don't come ask, "How do I play root
Scott: solo?".
Scott: It's like, I'm sure you could take some of the rules of root and make a puzzle out of them, but that's not playing root.
Scott: Playing root is a political activity.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: You need three or more people.
Rym: Or to play against AIs, but guess what?
Rym: The AIs, even if it's random, they'll be randomly political.
Scott: Yeah, and also it's a puzzle.
Scott: It just looks like a book.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: So yeah, Bike Nights happens as often as it happens.
Rym: We'll probably do another episode on non-Ortho games on this topic.
Rym: I think we can make a panel out of it.
Rym: But anyway, for now, I'll tell you a secret.
Rym: There's a tiny chance I might show up at PAX Unplugged without Scott.
Rym: Not to attend.
Rym: Like, I'm not going to be there playing games or anything.
Rym: But I might roll in just to do a panel or two and then peace out.
Rym: So stay tuned on that.
Rym: I don't know how Scott's even going to feel about that.
Rym: And he never listens to the show, so he won't know.
Rym: Only you will know.
Rym: We'll see if it even happens.
Rym: But anyway, for now, I leave you with... [beatboxing].