Rym: It's Thursday, August 12th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: - I'm Scott.
Rym: - And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are talking about natural disasters.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, right, we are about to do the show on time.
Rym: You know, we haven't done a lot of shows lately because a bunch of, you know, travel and personal stuff we were doing.
Scott: - But this is-- - And no shows next week either.
Rym: Yup, next week.
Rym: So, uh, we won't be doing regular-- Which isn't out of the ordinary.
Scott: 'cause there is a PAX West next week, not that we'll be at it.
Scott: - Yeah.
Scott: - But we wouldn't have done shows next week normally.
Rym: But we were delayed doing the show today because I came home to find a copyright strike on our channel.
Rym: Which isn't that, like, copyright shit comes at us all the time, but it's worth noting that 100% of the bogus copyright things that have come to our channel in the history of our YouTube channel have been for anime.
Rym: Nothing else ever gets copied.
Rym: It's only anime stuff.
Rym: But in this case, it was an audio-only livestream review, like the live show where we reviewed Cells at Work.
Rym: And the copyright strike, not a claim, but a full-on strike, was for nothing.
Rym: It was for, like, a still screenshot from the show while we reviewed it.
Scott: Which is absolutely fair use to put up a still image from a thing that you're reviewing, right?
Scott: No, what I find, I'm pretty sure, so if you look on my channel, the only anime thing I've ever posted on my YouTube channel is the episodes where we did the Judge Anime by its cover, which contained still images from many anime.
Rym: - Oh, the Judge Anime from its cover from Anime Boston, and pretty much every anime review we've ever done, they have, not strikes, but they all have Sony or someone has monetized your video on them.
Scott: - Oh, I don't know, I haven't checked to see if that's the case.
Rym: - Every anime panel we've ever done has that.
Rym: The Judge Animes from the few conventions, we did them have that.
Rym: Every episode of our entire show has that, and nothing else on the channel has that.
Scott: - Let me just check here.
Scott: Content...
Rym: - But I guess that was annoying, so I actually had to deal with all the copyright strike stuff, because the problem is, even though it's clear, fair use, there's basically no upside for us to actually fight it.
Rym: - The actual answer here is that you basically just shouldn't ever do anime stuff on YouTube ever, because there's literally no upside for you.
Scott: - So the seven Judge Anime by its cover videos that I have on YouTube have no restrictions, no nothing whatsoever.
Scott: They're 100% clean, even though they contain many images from anime, but those images are in a box in the top corner.
Scott: They're not like a full screen, you know, I don't think I did too many full screen images, if any.
Scott: And also, I didn't put the names of any of the anime, I don't think...
Rym: - See, that's the key, because the videos that are getting these strikes have the name of an anime somewhere in the description, and it seems like we know, because Nintendo does this too.
Rym: Anime companies are just like, they do literal illegal things with copyright, but there's no recourse.
Scott: - I'm pretty confident.
Scott: what they're doing is they just go on YouTube and they search, in this case, they search for cells at work, right, a show that they own the rights to, and they just select select all and push claim, they don't actually watch the videos or anything.
Scott: And I think, you know, they could, you know, with, you know, obviously there's the perfect system, what they should do, right, but I think a minor change that they could make that would solve a lot of this would simply to be, when someone makes a manual claim like this, they should have to put in the time codes of the part of the video where the thing is and write down in text what the thing is in that time code that they're claiming against.
Scott: Like, ah, there's a screenshot of our copyrighted cells at work character at one minute and 20 seconds, right, it's just, that's it.
Scott: And if they, if we just require that minimum level and verify that they're not just faking that, right, just put like the minimum verification so they don't just like put one minute on every single, put the same time code on all of them without actually looking, force them to watch the videos, at least.
Scott: If they're forced to watch the videos, they can't just search for cells at work and click claim, claim, claim, claim, claim, right, that would become too onerous.
Scott: They would actually have to watch them all.
Scott: And if that was the case, they would have to, you know, or they would be focusing on the ones that were clearly easy to violate, be like, hey, this is literally an episode of our show that has been uploaded in its entirety,
Rym: just
Scott: the whole, you know, they don't have to click a time code, they can just click, say, whole video, it's our show, next, right, whereas for our video, which, you know, a video that's fair use is a lot, it can be a lot harder, you know, they're going to skip right over when they see just two talking heads there, right, they're not going to waste their time watching an hour of GeekNights to figure out where the the screenshot is up for, right,
Rym: yeah, because this one in particular was manually created, meaning it wasn't YouTube flagging it, they went and found it.
Scott: They let you know if it was like the automatic system that, you know, listens for music and finds a violation versus a human being whose job it is to search and click on things to find copyright violations,
Rym: but I guess that's
Scott: nice of them, they do let you know that.
Rym: They do, but I mean, obviously the only actual solution to this is the U.S.
Rym: Congress has to pass laws that radically reform copyright in fundamental ways and real protections for fair use, but that's not going to happen ever.
Scott: So in somewhat related, you know, news, Twitch is now just on their own voluntarily, giving people who are banned from Twitch more information about why they were banned.
Scott: It's not like, you know, to the level that it needs to be, but that is a, I think that is a positive step in the right direction.
Scott: It's like, we've banned you, right, why did we ban you?
Scott: You violated this rule and it was, you were streaming on this day, you know, at this time, this is where you broke the rule, this is just any explanation whatsoever, as opposed to you have violated our terms of service, you're banned.
Scott: the end, right?
Scott: Just a little bit of, you know, it's not full habeas corpus, right, which is not necessary, but it's, you know, along those same lines of, right, if you're going to try some, if you're going to punish someone, you have to tell them what they're being punished for, that core principle,
Rym: but I guess
Scott: it would be good if there was a law, probably won't be for many, if not for a long time, if ever, that, yeah, if you ban someone from your service, you kind of have to explain why,
Rym: right, you know?
Rym: But basically, because people don't want to risk their entire channel being deleted, they have no choice but to just accept these things and just let these companies take down their videos, give them strikes, etc.
Scott: I think what we could do, what I would recommend people do is, you know, if you're a nerd doing anime content specifically, and, you know, you have a channel like, you know, Rims, which has mixed stuff, make a separate channel for your anime bits.
Rym: Yep, because, like I said, this is something we've, I've talked about this in public and in many other places, but we haven't really talked about it a lot in GeekNights.
Rym: This is the reason we, as GeekNights, do not make a lot of anime content, like, we kind of, it is, it is a major reason, it is not the reason.
Rym: Well, it's significant reason.
Rym: It is the reason I have not made more antenna videos, because we would make more.
Rym: I have actually, like, had lawyers write things to keep some of those antenna videos up, and it's just not worth the hassle.
Scott: Like, I've never- We would make more than we do, if not for this.
Rym: Well, like, JudgeAnimePad's cover is super fun to make, and honestly, doing panels and anime cons is also super fun, but, like, here's the subtle thing.
Rym: If we go to a PAX, or a MAGFest, or, like, any other, any non-anime convention, and we do a panel, we can video that panel and put it on YouTube.
Rym: We cannot put any anime panels on YouTube.
Scott: We can do that, as long as we do an anime panel that involves only us talking, with no screenshots, and no audio, or any content from the anime whatsoever, and don't do any of the fun, awesome types of anime panels.
Scott: And then do not mention the names of any anime titles in our title or description on YouTube.
Scott: Simply say, like, I judge anime by its cover, right?
Scott: Do not include the names of any anime that would come into search, and don't put any videos or screenshots in the content of the panel, or, if you do, at the anime con, put the videos into your panel.
Scott: When you do the YouTube, edit them out, so that they're not there, right?
Scott: Put, like, a, you know, be like, you know, just put, like, a black box over it, and mute the audio, and put a subtitle that's, like, the opener to whatever is playing at this time, right?
Rym: But without that mixed media, I find that anime panels, especially at the level, like, the kinds of content that, like, we would like to watch, and that people like to see at cons, that's, that pretty much removes the things people actually want to see.
Rym: Like, it does remove, yeah, you, like, for example, the most popular anime thing we ever did was, like, well, at cons at least, were the anime openers from around the world type panels.
Scott: You can't do that.
Scott: You absolutely can't do that.
Scott: You absolutely cannot do.
Scott: Which sucks, because that content is, but that, but that is a great content, but it is literally just playing someone else's stuff that someone else made, right?
Scott: It's not something that we made.
Rym: With transformative commentary, though, it is clear.
Rym: It does have trans, I'm not, I'm not arguing against that.
Rym: Yeah, all I'm saying is that that panel, as presented, is clear, like, unambiguous fair use.
Scott: Sure, I'm not if you actually have something to say.
Rym: Oh, so here's another example.
Scott: We could make a panel that's, like, you know, the history of some such-and-such.
Scott: You know what panel, like, our gaming panels with slides and text and, you know.
Rym: You know what panel we did?
Rym: It was at one of the last Anime Bostons we went to that actually got, like, one of the biggest audiences we ever had in a room at an anime con was when we did that analyzing anime panel where we talked about Utena, and we, and the like 20 seconds,
Scott: and then we
Rym: spent 20 minutes talking about the allegory and the symbolism and, like, look, there's one cat, now there's two cats.
Rym: Look at this frame of animation.
Rym: What's going on here?
Rym: That is compelling content, and you literally can't put that anywhere.
Rym: It's just not worth the hassle.
Scott: You could remove the two minutes of clip from it.
Scott: Don't put the word Utena in the title.
Scott: Put, like, analyzing a cool anime from the early 90s and your title, and then you would put a link to, like, you know, to say, "Hey, yeah, this clip that you should watch here is Utena episode three.
Scott: Start watching it, you know, the third minute to the sixth
Scott: minute.".
Rym: Yeah, but you see what's going on here.
Rym: That is all a hassle, and that is why the end result of all this.
Scott: I'm not saying it's not a hassle, but you can do it.
Rym: But I'm saying the end result of that, just because I've never said this out on GeekNights, is that that kind of shit is why I don't even bother doing any anime shit other than reviews on the podcast.
Rym: Like, I gave up.
Rym: I made one AMV, never making one again, etc.
Scott: Just don't, just, you know, do anime.
Scott: Figure out something that you have.
Scott: If you have something to say about anime, if you have a lot of knowledge about anime, you shouldn't need to actually show the anime, right?
Scott: It's like if you take a Siskel and Ebert episode, right, and you just, you know, on that show, if you've ever watched Siskel and Ebert, they're both dead now, right?
Scott: If you've ever watched that old show where they do movie reviews, they do show clips from the movie in that TV show.
Scott: But if you edit out the parts with the clips from the movie, the parts that are just Siskel and Ebert chatting with each other are sometimes they're right, sometimes they're wrong, but that's a show on its own.
Scott: You don't need the clips.
Rym: But without the mixed media, it is far less compelling and a lot fewer people watch.
Scott: It is indeed, but you could just upload the talking part only.
Scott: You could do it and then they wouldn't come after you.
Rym: Yeah, but I'd say that defeats the purpose and ain't worth the effort.
Rym: So there's a lot of reasons why you're never going to see more of those Utena episodes.
Rym: Like, I'm just never even going to bother making that kind of content because that show, without showing a clip on the screen or a screenshot, there's no way to have the kind of conversation we're having because we're saying things like, "Look who's in the background in this
Rym: scene.".
Rym: So if you wondered why the Utena show is dead, that's pretty much it.
Rym: Some other news that a normal, more traditional GeekNights' met a open-y bit.
Rym: I biked home from work because I go to the office occasionally.
Scott: Have I made the news yet?
Rym: No.
Scott: We're already going long here.
Scott: Let's go.
Scott: I'm hungry.
Rym: We always go long because we don't do that many shows lately.
Rym: We also don't talk except during the show.
Rym: You don't need to talk about this.
Scott: Let's skip to the news.
Rym: No, no, no.
Rym: Because this is my news too.
Rym: This leads into my news.
Scott: Oh, it's also your news.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So biking home today, one is like 100 degrees and two, I encountered the worst car traffic I have literally ever seen or experienced in Manhattan in the entirety of my life today.
Rym: More gridlock than I have ever seen to the point that it was blocking bike lanes and it actually made my commute on a bike take almost 15 more minutes.
Rym: And for context, that is more than 100% increase from how long it normally takes me to bike home.
Scott: I don't think the U.N.
Scott: is in session right now.
Rym: Nope.
Scott: I think that's the worst I saw was when the U.N.
Scott: was in session.
Rym: This was worse than that.
Scott: It was only in certain areas because that, you know, in the detour zones that it was super bad.
Rym: And when I got home, I saw an article in the Boston Globe, which is my news, and it basically said that as of now, car traffic has reached or exceeded all the pre-COVID levels everywhere in America.
Rym: And it's very notable that as this has happened, one, New York City, and there's other articles about this that aren't my news, traffic here is actually the worst it's ever been in New York City history right now.
Rym: Just generally.
Rym: And air quality is at historic lows because the only time the air quality was ever good in New York was that brief window during the terrifying heights of the COVID pandemic when nobody was driving.
Scott: Cars have just- There were times, there was a time when air quality was good in New York.
Rym: Oh yeah, before the car existed.
Scott: No, it was- And before industry moved here.
Scott: Steam engines.
Scott: No, before then there were still horses and cows.
Scott: It's before then, before any white people came here.
Rym: That's why.
Scott: But what's interesting is that- It didn't stink until the white people came.
Scott: Pissed all over it.
Rym: The car traffic seems to be the cause of the far majority of the like human recognizable pollution in the air here.
Scott: In this area, yes.
Scott: The biggest polluting thing in New York City is cars followed probably by power plants.
Scott: But it's so hard to- I'm guessing.
Rym: It's so weird to remember that year recently where New York City just smelled like the world as opposed to smelling like pollution.
Rym: And now it smells like pollution again.
Rym: The air quality is bullshit.
Scott: Which leads right into my news that maybe with a new governor we could get the congestion pricing.
Rym: Finally.
Scott: So I don't know how if where listeners are or how much they know about what happens in New York.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: New York news is global news.
Scott: Sure, what country you're in, if you even understand.
Scott: New York is a state, right?
Scott: We're in the United States, but we still have a governor who is not the governor in the, you know, Britain pirate sense of governor, but is a governor as in effectively the president of New York.
Scott: It's like you're the executive, you know, chief in the state government, right?
Scott: The state, not New York City, right?
Scott: The whole state includes Rochester, Albany.
Scott: In fact, the capital is Albany.
Scott: New York isn't even the freaking capital of the state, even though the governor hangs out in the city most of the time.
Rym: People only go to Albany when it's time to do- Not that the governor listens to anything anyone in the city gives a shit about.
Scott: No.
Scott: But anyway, so the governor of New York has been Andrew Cuomo for quite a long time.
Scott: His father was a governor previously, not the immediately previous governor, but, you know, a governor a while ago.
Rym: He pretty much- He was well respected generally.
Rym: No, not the current one, his father.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Scott: Cuomo won basically on, you know, name recognition, which is very powerful in elections.
Scott: And also because, you know, when you're a Democrat in New York, you got to get elected by the entire state.
Scott: So even though maybe a lot of, you know, farther left people in parts of the city, as we could see with our mayor election, a lot of the city is, you know, center or, you know, even by some, you know, depending on where your scale is, conservative Democrats.
Rym: But if you go upstate, it's like, it is just like, I got guns and sail away.
Scott: So Republicans can't possibly win.
Scott: There's no chance for them in New York state, but conservative, if you're a conservative Democrat, right?
Scott: Then, yeah, you have a, you know, someone like the president of the US.
Rym: Because the entirety of the state outside of New York city will vote for that person in the primary and New York city will split across all the progressive candidates.
Scott: And also that person.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And thus that person will always win the primary.
Scott: But no one's been- There hasn't been anyone.
Scott: There just isn't a person in New York who has had the character, whatever, as a state figure to run against him and have any chance.
Scott: So it's like, even people like me reluctantly kept voting for this guy because what the fuck are you going to do?
Scott: Well, it's no chance.
Rym: Like, you know, who runs against the Democrat in governor races in New York?
Rym: Literal Nazis.
Scott: So he's been the governor, even though basically everyone votes for him.
Scott: And then it's just like, you know, we hate you.
Scott: I voted for you, but I hate you.
Scott: But there was no choice because the other guy's way worse.
Scott: There's no- So he's been governor.
Scott: He's been doing all sorts of evil shit the whole time he's been governor, right?
Scott: People forget that in the olden days, right?
Scott: Years ago, there was like this anti, you know, this group they formed, it was like a commission to find corruption in the state government.
Scott: And they actually found one of his friends was super corrupt and put him in jail.
Scott: Right?
Scott: What's his name?
Scott: What's that guy's name?
Rym: I forget.
Scott: What was the stupid guy's name?
Rym: I mean, Spitzer.
Rym: There's so many.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: That's older.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: Oh, Skelos, right?
Scott: Sheldon Silver, right?
Scott: And Skelos.
Rym: I forgot all about that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All those guys.
Scott: So basically that anti-corruption commission had a name.
Scott: I forget its name, but it was going after it was started to look into Cuomo, right?
Scott: It was looking into all the other state level people.
Scott: It started to look into him.
Rym: So we shut it down.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: No more anti-corruption thing.
Scott: He's like, yeah, we found the corrupt people.
Scott: We're good.
Scott: It's like, it's like he could have been done with that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But he, he survived that.
Scott: And he basically survived a whole bunch of other shit.
Scott: Uh, you know, during the COVID times, right?
Scott: He's, he put in a big show of looking good, right?
Scott: Not like the Florida governor looking bad.
Scott: He looked like he was, you know, he made it appear that he had his shit under control and was, you know, doing a better job than the other governors.
Scott: that turned out to be a facade.
Scott: When you look at the nursing home shit, that could have been the end of him.
Rym: The worst part is he was still doing better than most of the governors anyway.
Scott: He was the whole IDC thing.
Scott: People don't know about that.
Scott: Or basically he, you know, he had Democrats who voted with Republicans that were like on his side in the state legislatures that he didn't have to move to the left.
Scott: And then we voted them all out mostly.
Scott: So that undid that business.
Scott: Um, but yeah, so now finally what we finally undid him is like 10th scandal is that he was a sex pest.
Scott: No surprise to anybody.
Scott: You could just, you could tell by the guy's personality that he's that kind of person.
Scott: He'll just grab some asses.
Scott: Um, but he got called out by some very brave women who came forth.
Scott: Uh, and we, the attorney general came down on him.
Scott: Uh, and now he's finally was forced to resign, which is great.
Rym: Uh, and even, even better, it's sad that this is what it took, but, uh, there's so many other things we could have made him.
Rym: Now we have the first woman governor in the history of New York state.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So the new governor who was the person who was the deputy or, uh, Lieutenant governor, right.
Scott: You know, she's going to be governor and I guess in a couple of weeks, less than two weeks, she already now she's going to run for reelection when the cycle comes up.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So Kathy Hochul from Buffalo, interesting thing, right?
Scott: So what do you make of her?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, obviously better than Cuomo.
Scott: She's not grabbing any asses, right?
Rym: So that like Zephyr Teachout is like still too far right for me in terms of the governor.
Scott: Um, but yeah, she, Kathy Hochul is interesting because she is, you know, probably too far to the right for us.
Scott: She used to be even further right than she is now.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, she used to be like, you know, almost Republican, basically she has moved significantly to the left, but basically it's an improvement, but it's not enough of an improvement.
Scott: Uh, the good news is that when we get to the primaries, right, where she'll have to try to, you know, actually be elected, um, as, you know, governor instead of just, she was elected Lieutenant governor, but you know, whatever, um, you know, she's going to be running against, you know, uh, Jumaane Williams, who she beat in the primary last time.
Rym: So, but Jumaane's power only grows.
Scott: Jumaane's power has grown.
Scott: Uh, however, the person who took Cuomo down, Letitia James, also highly likely to run for governor and Hochul may have a very difficult time beating Letitia James.
Scott: So we'll see, you know, for me to choose between, it's weird because for me to choose between Tish and Jumaane, that's a tough choice for me, but apparently they don't like each other.
Scott: It's like, they're not big, they're not exactly friends, even though they, they were the past, you know, the current and former city advocates in New York city.
Rym: But hopefully if we don't like each other, unless we, unless the state votes to get rid of the rank choice thing, uh, the primary, but the primary for governor is still going to be not ranked right.
Scott: It's because it's not as, it's only as the rank choice is only a city thing.
Scott: So it'll be a difficult situation there come that time, um, which may advantage Hochul, depending on who's in and who's out.
Scott: Uh, but also what will be interesting to see is, uh, in a couple of weeks, right.
Scott: Or Hochul is going to have to appoint a lieutenant governor.
Scott: So that's going to be interesting, whoever that is.
Rym: Um, and in one last little news that is actually really relevant of all the COVID things going on.
Rym: One thing that's very important and I want to bring it up briefly.
Rym: We're not going to get into this in depth.
Rym: We want to get into the main bit, but, uh, for the future of things getting, looking better, the U S military, the Pentagon is going to require all service members to get the COVID vaccine, uh, basically within a month.
Scott: Good.
Rym: That's a huge deal.
Scott: Does that only include, does that only include people who are like straight up enlisted slash officers?
Scott: So it doesn't include like private company guy who's working on the boat.
Scott: He's not actually in the Navy, but he's just, he's on the Navy boat.
Rym: We don't know for sure because the official like thing is not out yet.
Rym: We don't know exactly who's covered.
Rym: We do know active service members are covered.
Rym: We also know, I don't
Scott: know if people realize like just how many like private citizens who work for private companies are like on military bases, on boats, provide, you know, the food service workers are not, you know, I guess sometimes they might be people who are in the military, but a lot of times it's like, that's a company they're hiring to do food service or, you know, whatever.
Rym: Here's why I want to highlight this.
Rym: federal employees, but there's a bunch of other news is like a whole bunch of universities are requiring the vaccine.
Rym: And so far all the whack jobs more and more
Scott: places are basically saying, if you're not vaccine, you can't, or at least have a fake proof that we, you know, we're going to try to verify
Rym: those nut jobs who tried to sue their university saying they didn't want to get the vaccine.
Rym: The court just smacked them down and said, Nope, there's universities rules.
Rym: Fuck you.
Scott: But I think the big thing, that's the big thing that there's a rude awakening for a lot of those anti-vax people is, you know, they try to fake the religious exemption.
Scott: And if you try to fake the religious exemption, when it comes right down to it, they're going to check to see if you got any other vaccines, which you probably, and it's like the only way you can fly, even if you're lying about your religion, right?
Scott: You're an atheist or whatever, right?
Scott: Even if you're lying about it, it's like, if they see that you've had another vaccination, then it's, it's to your, your, that's it.
Rym: I'm not a lawyer, but the way this has been described to me by lawyers in the past was vaguely that the government cannot litigate whether or not your religion is real.
Rym: Like, obviously that's just the way the U S is.
Rym: They can't be like, Nope, you made up, you made up the flying spaghetti monster.
Rym: That doesn't count.
Rym: They can't do that.
Rym: That's why Scientology exists.
Rym: But what they can do is say that if there's an exception or anything in the law, the thing they can litigate and test is whether or not the belief you profess is quote, sincerely held,
Scott: meaning if they
Rym: can show evidence that you're insincere, then they can tell you to go fuck yourself.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So like, for example, let's say a Jew, I'll talk about Jews since I am one.
Scott: That's fair, right?
Scott: Says, Oh, work.
Scott: You gotta let me leave early on Friday.
Scott: I'm a, I'm a very religious Jew, right?
Scott: They say, okay, leave, you know, Shabbos leave.
Scott: That's what you do, right?
Scott: This that's normal.
Scott: Um, and then, you know, you bring in pulled pork sandwich for lunch into the office, right?
Scott: Obviously we're not talking about situations like spying on you, trying to find out, you know, they're suspicious that, no, we're talking, you bring the pulled pork right into the office and you chow down and they see you doing that.
Scott: They can be like, uh, so you can come in on Friday.
Rym: It's like, yeah, maybe it is what I gather.
Rym: it might come down to that specific stricture.
Rym: So it, those two might be unrelated, but if say you went on a bunch of vacations, like you did, you didn't do the Shabbos thing consistently.
Rym: That's also true, right?
Scott: It's like your boss happens to run into you on Saturday at fucking Disney world.
Scott: It's like, and you're, you're lighting a fire and making two loops and eating the pulled pork sandwich.
Rym: It's like, you know, is that is the, uh, the Scott Pilgrim movie or like chicken parm isn't vegan.
Rym: No, but, uh, but anyway, to get it before the reason I bring this up, here's why I think the military thing for active service members is important.
Rym: And it's not something you would think of.
Rym: There are two things that people are not talking about with this that I think are way more interesting than the.
Rym: we're getting a bunch of people vaccinated.
Rym: One, the people in the military, their choice is not, well, I just won't get the vaccine.
Rym: It is either you get the vaccine or you are dishonorably discharged.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Or you could, um, try to find another way to get discharged in time.
Scott: You could try to get some other legitimate excuse to get out, which is not easy.
Rym: Dishonorable discharge from the U S military is almost like an anti recommendation.
Rym: The military is basically saying, fuck this piece of shit.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Basically if you get one of those, um, in, in the United States, then if you try to, after that, if you try to apply for a job and you put military on your resume, any employers, HR department is going to, you know, make like this, they just contact the military to get your, your service record.
Scott: It's just standard practice.
Scott: Like you put a college and they get your transcript, same thing.
Scott: And if they see a dishonorable discharge there, you're basically that they can absolutely discriminate and not hire you because of that easily.
Scott: And I've, you're very hard time getting a job basically anywhere.
Scott: If you have that also, let's say you say, okay, I won't put military on my resume.
Scott: First of all, you're gonna have a shit resume because he got high school diploma followed by nothing.
Scott: Um, and second of all, uh, they could do a background check, which is normal for not all employers, but many, and they'll know that you were in the military and they'll find the dishonorable discharge.
Scott: Doesn't be like the first thing they fucking find when they look you up.
Scott: Um, and then they won't hire you.
Scott: So, so here's why it's like, it's basically get a vaccine or have a hard time finding a job for a long time.
Scott: So
Rym: here's why I think that is very interesting because there's already some evidence that a lot of people who are very publicly against the vaccine, if their choice is the vaccine or their job, they suddenly just very quietly get the vaccine and shut up low or they stay loud, but they get the vaccine.
Rym: And I don't care.
Rym: if they get, as long as they get the vaccine, I do not care.
Rym: Otherwise I just want people to get that shot.
Scott: Now, this is what I'm about to say is obviously a very simplistic, generalized thinking that clearly is not a model for the world, right?
Scott: It's a broad generalization, but you know, the image of this that I see is that there's some people, right?
Scott: People with, with logic and reason, right?
Scott: Um, and they respond to logic and reason and carrot, right?
Scott: It's like, right.
Scott: And then, you know, and if you look Democrats, people on the left, right, we tend to be like anti punishment, anti prison, right?
Scott: We tend to be people who like, you know, look at people like water protectors who were like, they believe they're doing the right thing.
Scott: They'll go to prison for it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, Gandhi's and Martin Luther Kings, right?
Scott: People punishment does not, you know, change their mind, right?
Scott: And they're the same people who don't believe in punishment of people that it's wrong, that it doesn't help.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But meanwhile, on the right, you have people who very much believe in punishing others, right?
Scott: And they're like, yeah, you gotta punish people.
Scott: That's what gets people's behavior to change.
Scott: And yet they are also people whose behavior changes with punishment.
Scott: So they respond, they respond to stick.
Scott: So the people who don't respond to stick tend to not, there tends to be a correlation with people who they don't believe in using the stick to coax behavior out of other people.
Scott: And they also don't respond.
Rym: You stick somehow came to the thing, the thing I'm actually going to say.
Rym: you came to it from a similar angle, right?
Scott: People who believe in using the stick as a motivational tool, right?
Scott: Punish people to change the behavior of other human beings are people who themselves respond to stick.
Scott: So what we need to do is if what I'm saying in general is true, then I think it's starting to happen.
Scott: is we start with vaccine.
Scott: We started with carrot and it's like, we got all the carrot people, right?
Scott: It's like, if those people respond to stick, give them the stick, right?
Scott: You believe, right?
Scott: It's like, if that's true that some people respond to one thing and some people respond to the other.
Scott: There isn't one way to motivate all humans to, you know, behave a certain way.
Scott: Go to each person and customize the way you motivate them.
Scott: Oh, you're not going to get a vaccine, but you will if I threatened to beat the shit out of you.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: You're a person who responds to beatings.
Scott: You get beatings.
Scott: So if you don't behave, so you're a person who doesn't respond to beatings, I could beat you to kingdom come and you still would sit at the counter and wall greens anyway, because you believe it's right.
Scott: No beatings for you.
Scott: They don't work.
Scott: Instead, we're going to, you know, do something else.
Rym: Give you civil rights.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So we're going to give you what you want.
Rym: For the last thing I'll say on this.
Scott: That's all you respond to.
Rym: The reason I brought this news up is it's one level higher than that.
Rym: The US military, and I don't want to give, this could be a whole show, but we got to move on to the rest of the show tonight.
Scott: Well, the military only uses, well, they use metals.
Scott: I guess they have carrots.
Rym: Yeah, there's carrots there.
Rym: But here's my thinking.
Rym: I have a hypothesis and I'm really invested in this.
Rym: Like, I want to see if this pans out.
Rym: The US military has a problem in that not the majority, but there is a significant white supremacist presence within the US military for a lot of reasons.
Rym: There's a lot of...
Scott: I mean, it's, I think it's slightly, I think from what I've seen, it's lower than in the police.
Rym: Oh, definitely lower than in the police.
Scott: It's still a shockingly large percentage.
Scott: It's just not like 50%, you know, I don't know what the percent is, but it's not a tiny percentage, like one, and it's not 50.
Scott: It's somewhere in the middle.
Rym: So that is like, like step one, like assumption one, that there is a white supremacist problem within the US military, a subset of the US military, are dangerous white supremacists.
Scott: That's an absolute fact.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So let's assume another thing that we also know is true.
Rym: The overlap between people who affirmatively resist the vaccine for conspiracy reasons and people who are white supremacists, that Venn diagram starts to approach a circle far more so than other types of Venn diagrams in this space.
Scott: It's not a perfect circle, but it's approaching one indeed, yes.
Scott: Very strong correlation.
Rym: For white supremacists in the US military then, one of two things is going to happen.
Rym: Either they believe this stuff so much that they'll accept the dishonorable discharge and there will be fewer white supremacists in the military.
Rym: Not zero, but fewer.
Rym: Or the white supremacists want to remain in the military so much, they'll get the goddamn vaccine.
Rym: And guess what?
Rym: Fine, at least you got the vaccine.
Rym: One of the things you're doing shilly in your life is less likely to kill someone.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: If you want to kill other people, you have to kill them, you know.
Scott: You gotta kill them with guns and systemic oppression.
Rym: You can't kill them by spreading COVID to them without a vaccine.
Rym: So that is the thing that I think is interesting here.
Scott: It's a positive thing for sure.
Scott: And I think in general, I think that more places in our society, it's like, yeah, people are going to fake their vaccination record and some places aren't going to check as strongly as others.
Scott: But yeah, the more places that say, "No vax, not allowed to come in, period," I think that is probably sufficient.
Scott: stick that will get us, I don't think it's going to get us 99% vaccinated, but it's going to get us well over the line.
Scott: I think, just guessing, half the resisting people would probably be convinced by that eventually.
Scott: As soon as they wanted to do something.
Rym: Half of them get the vaccine and the other half get a stick.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: Well, the stick they get is, you're going to either have to get a fake thing or you're going to have... And I think put in some sort of a punishment for people who are using a fake or faking it.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: Well, if an outbreak happens and you're part of it and it's shown that you faked your vaccine, that should be a felony.
Scott: Yeah, a felony is fine.
Scott: There should be a severe punishment for faking it.
Scott: But I don't think we should go around trying to find people faking it.
Rym: It's not like...
Scott: No cops standing at bars checking everyone who comes in.
Scott: None of that nonsense.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So we're laying blades in the dark pretty regularly through this whole quarantine.
Rym: I fucking love that system.
Rym: We keep playing it.
Rym: And we interact with a lot of cults for a lot of reasons.
Rym: We're doing a lot of cult stuff lately.
Rym: So what I have here, my thing of the day.
Rym: This is a Warhammer themed, but it doesn't matter that it's Warhammer.
Rym: Warhammer happens to be a good avenue for this.
Rym: This is a cult random name generator.
Rym: And every single time you click generate cult name, solid fucking gold comes out of this generator.
Rym: Let's see right now.
Rym: The Sons of the Insatiable Twilight.
Rym: The Covenant of the Baleful Onsop.
Rym: The Descenders of the Perfect Sigil.
Scott: The Fraternity... Is it always the something of the something?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The Fraternity of Conquering Pleasure.
Rym: The Legion of the Nubile Beasts.
Scott: The Nubile Beasts?
Rym: So yeah, our blades in the dark game, every cult we encounter is just the next click in this name generator.
Rym: And it is delightful.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: So there is a human being who is an amazing person that doesn't get thought of or spoken about as much as they deserve.
Scott: And that person is Mr.
Scott: T.
Rym: Weirdly such a fixture in my childhood, Mr.
Rym: T.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: T was big in the 80s.
Scott: And then, you know, was still around.
Scott: He's still around today.
Scott: He's alive.
Scott: But yeah, Nod is not as popular now.
Scott: He's also old.
Scott: But he was a big deal in the 80s.
Scott: If any, you know, for example, I mean, you look at this video, that's my thing of the day, which is Mr.
Scott: T on Letterman in 1982.
Scott: This was, I was zero or one.
Scott: I wasn't even one yet when this, or even when this, when Mr.
Scott: T was on Letterman.
Scott: So this was the height of Mr.
Scott: T. This was Rocky.
Scott: Was it three that Mr.
Scott: T was in?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Um, as a Rocky three was coming out.
Scott: What's a Rocky three is as old as me and Mr.
Scott: T was on Letterman promoting Rocky three in that same year that I was born.
Scott: And that's what this thing of the day video is.
Scott: So if Mr.
Scott: T was at his peak when I was born, of course, he's only really going to be a fixture in the childhood.
Scott: He wasn't able to remain a prominent public figure longer than, you know, 10, 20, right?
Rym: I don't think people younger than us know.
Rym: I don't think people a generation younger than us really even know who he is.
Rym: Maybe they know one quote, but don't actually know like why.
Scott: I pity the fool.
Scott: Everyone knows that.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Everyone knows that even if they don't know where it came from.
Scott: Yeah, but Mr.
Scott: T is a fascinating, amazing, and incredible person.
Scott: And you can really, you know, see, this is like, you can see what he was like that, like, this is what, like, he was just becoming more famous, like at this time.
Scott: And you can see in this video, why he was able to become famous, like the, how the kind of person he was right.
Scott: Um, allowed him to achieve fame.
Scott: Uh, and yeah, I highly recommend, you know, I guess, you know, this was before fricking, uh, a team, right.
Scott: He wasn't on that yet.
Rym: Um, so yeah, you can, uh, a team ran from 1983 to 1987.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: He, the a team didn't exist when he, when this thing of the day video was recorded.
Rym: God, this was a long time ago.
Scott: I'm just as old as us.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So in the meta moment, uh, we got no cons.
Rym: Like we're not going to PAX for obvious reasons.
Rym: Uh, in fact, we're specifically not going to PAX because it's too soon for conventions.
Rym: Uh, but we'll see how things go for future conventions after this upcoming PAX West.
Rym: The panel we did at the most recent PAX online is just on YouTube with slides, Atari game design.
Rym: You can just watch it.
Rym: The GeekNights book club book remains the tale of Genji, uh, to do a brief checkpoint.
Rym: Cause I'm powering through.
Scott: I'm about a little over a percent.
Rym: I'm about, I'm approaching a third of the way through.
Rym: I'm like 31.
Scott: Let me check my Kindle percentage.
Scott: Cause I actually haven't read in a little while.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But, uh, I might have to catch up.
Rym: You might have to, but, uh, to checkpoint, cause you know, the last few episodes I said, look, I can just kind of sleep.
Scott: I'm only, I'm only 19%.
Rym: Oh, so, uh, now that I'm a little further, uh, the, the pedo thing just keeps that, that just bunny drops all the way through the rest of the stupid book.
Rym: 100%.
Rym: And, uh, too, now that, you know, there's the, there's the incident where a ghost kills someone, he is banging in a haunted mansion.
Rym: Like that happens pretty early on actually.
Rym: But, uh, it is very clear in retrospect, like getting further into the book that his every Genji has malaria.
Rym: He probably got malaria during that bit.
Rym: And cause you know, the people in that household were sick and then the woman died.
Rym: And then later he's seeing the wise man in the woods because he has recurring fevers.
Rym: Malaria was happy.
Rym: Like malaria was a thing in hand area.
Scott: I knew he was sick, but I didn't realize it was malaria specifically.
Rym: fevers that would come and go throughout the rest of his life.
Rym: It keeps coming up.
Scott: So I know that.
Scott: I just didn't know that, that I just didn't recognize it as malaria until you just said something.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like I just, I sort of, did you look, did you look that up?
Rym: Nope.
Rym: It just suddenly clicked.
Rym: when yet again, he's having fevers and isn't feeling well.
Rym: Just like, well, huh, that makes sense.
Rym: And also all the people who died in that house with the ghost and everything, probably also just malaria.
Rym: It seems that just seems to fit.
Scott: How come he hasn't died of it yet?
Scott: A lot of people live with malaria.
Rym: Like you can just survive.
Rym: And also he's only like 18 at that point.
Scott: Oh, that's true.
Scott: He's still kind of young.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Like he is, he is now about 20 as far as I've gotten in the book.
Rym: Like it moves pretty slow, but the only thing I'm struggling with, like the thing that I have the most trouble with reading this book, as I get further and further along, I'm used to a lot of the conventions that uses, but what I'm struggling with is how there will be like multiple paragraphs that are covering a span of like 10 seconds.
Rym: And then the next paragraph will be someone saying a line, but it is like a month later in a different place.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And there was no transition whatsoever.
Rym: And it's almost like, wait, who, when did this guy show up?
Rym: Oh no, no, it's a month later.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: I guess I see what's going on now.
Scott: Like it slows down.
Scott: It's like describe a scene in detail.
Scott: Like, ah, they're at the festival and so dances and then so-and-so dances and then so-and-so dances.
Scott: really well.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, and so the other people do a shitty dance and then it's like his excellency has something to say to Genji.
Rym: It's like his excellency was not at this party.
Scott: What the fuck?
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then it's like, you know, it slows down to detail on something and then it's like, all right, the next part of our story is, yeah, you know, Genji's off to it.
Scott: It's like, what?
Rym: But it doesn't ever say the next part of our story.
Rym: It's just the next, the next line someone says is months later.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And then you restart the paragraph.
Rym: And you're like, oh, okay.
Rym: I think I see what's going on here.
Rym: I'm glad the chapters all have a little bit like, here's, who's in the chapter and roughly how old Genji is.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Without that, I was just lost.
Scott: That's why you need this edition, the full unabridged, you know, uh, edition.
Rym: I mean, from what I've got, like, even if you're reading it in the original Japanese, it's such archaic Japanese that it would be like us trying to read early middle English.
Scott: I mean, Emily who, you know, speaks and reads Japanese, you know, way, I guess, is she technically, I don't know what counts as fluency, right?
Scott: She passed the test thing, right?
Rym: She's close.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: She says it's like, if you're, if you speak English, but you try to read Shakespeare, it's like, yeah, you read it, but you know, it's not, uh, it's not so straightforward, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I get the impression that Shakespeare is pretty easy to read relative to modern English compared to reading Heian era court Japanese.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's, I'm sure, I think it's, I think it probably is harder than us reading Shakespeare, but it's still the same idea.
Scott: It's, it's your, it's your language.
Scott: You know, those you've seen those words, but you read the sentence and your brain doesn't actually create an image of what the sentence means and you have to, you know, like for, you know, consciously force it.
Scott: But also it's like the difference between just breathing unconsciously and breathing on purpose.
Rym: But also, you know, Genji, it's easy to say like, wow, Genji just like cries all the time because there's so many.
Rym: you see where he just like, and then he spent the next three days crying and nothing else.
Rym: But, uh, got to remember he's like 17.
Rym: So that kind of tracks.
Rym: He's just this weepy teenager.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Let's get into the main bit.
Rym: Let's just dive right in because, uh, climate change plays real obviously, but, uh, what's
Scott: happening is the biggest one, but there are other things causing an increase of natural disasters of
Rym: all kinds
Scott: around the entire globe, but this has
Rym: accelerated significantly like to a degree that it is notable and this needs to be talked about more.
Scott: And even if, even if, even if, even if environmentalists take over the whole world, right tomorrow, there is to some extent, nothing we can do.
Scott: It's going to continue for a while.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: The conversation, uh, and again, the snowball is already rolling down the hill.
Scott: Our goal is now to slow the snowball, right?
Rym: Our goal is to prevent the worst future while simultaneously not preventing current harms and near future harms so much as mitigating those harms.
Rym: Mitigation is the best we can do for the decades to come.
Scott: A lot of people use inevitability like, Oh, yup.
Scott: There's nothing we can do about that at this point as an excuse to give up.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: Cause if we do nothing, this gets bad.
Rym: Even worse.
Rym: Like here's the difference.
Rym: Say, uh, you know, there's that YouTube video where the guy burns down his entire house in a live state as a water in the ceiling.
Scott: And it's like, well, I can't afford to fix the roof.
Scott: Might as well just let it leak.
Scott: And then the roof collapses on you and you're, you're crushed.
Scott: It's like, well, you could have at least put a bucket under it, right?
Scott: Or like put a piece of plastic on the roof or something.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: So, uh, what we're going to talk about today is not that so much as the natural disasters themselves.
Rym: And I guess what we're defining is the natural disaster.
Rym: climate and weather disasters count.
Rym: I, even though they are ostensibly, especially currently pretty much directly caused by humans, but that is different from like an industrial disaster or a dam like collapsing where often they are combined.
Scott: often they're combined, right?
Scott: One can cause the other, uh, you know, like an earthquake messing up your nuclear power plant, Japan or something like that.
Rym: But, uh, we're going to focus on like a natural disaster where there was not a discrete human cause in a direct immediate causal chain.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Well, the first natural disaster that I, at least the one I have the most experience with personally in my life is the hurricane, which if you live in the other side of the world is a cyclone.
Scott: It's just a huge ass fucking storm that spins its way over everything with crazy winds and rain.
Rym: Um, I grew up in hurricane Alec.
Rym: I grew up in a, in a tornado place where tornadoes that caused serious damage happen often.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But you didn't experience hurricanes.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Didn't experience hurricanes.
Rym: I am in my own life.
Scott: I am Sandy was the only hurricane you experienced.
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Rym: Cause the other hurricanes that hit New York, we were actually out of town during them.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So I experienced hurricane Andrew and some other ones.
Scott: I forget the name of basically in the nineties, you know, late eighties, early nineties, Connecticut, there were hurricanes that, you know, hit us in Connecticut.
Scott: And I remember the, the most damage I remember is most like trees coming down.
Scott: Uh, there was a, we had like a little shed that we would like put a lawnmower in.
Scott: It just got like blown away.
Scott: Um, I remember what during one hurricane might've been Andrew.
Scott: I think, uh, the neighbors across the street, obviously couldn't go to the store.
Scott: Uh, I put on a raincoat and I brought them.
Scott: I forget it was eggs or sugar.
Scott: I had to care.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, and it was basically like the wind was like pushing me.
Scott: I couldn't, it was hard to walk across the street cause of being pushed by wind.
Scott: Uh, and also there was so much rain.
Scott: It was like basically someone was hitting you, like shooting a fire hose and aiming at you on purpose.
Scott: Um, but it's interesting that wasn't even, and it wasn't even like at the level of, I could, I could see, I was able to successfully walk across the street.
Scott: It was not the level of like, you know, an even stronger hurricane would like just knock, you know, trees over.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Trees weren't coming down then, but it was still that bad.
Rym: It's interesting that, you know, you're living in Connecticut and then New York, me living in Michigan and then New York.
Rym: We just happened to have, for a lot of reasons, lived in places that have relatively few and relatively rare natural disasters.
Scott: Well, I was born in these places, but then choosing, I, once I was able to choose where I lived, uh, I intentionally chose to live in places with few natural disasters.
Scott: It wasn't the only factor, but it was a significant factor.
Scott: I, you know, if, if there weren't earthquakes and mudslides and fires in California, I may have been willing to go work over there.
Scott: in Silicon Valley, you know, before I hated the culture there.
Rym: And before I realized there's no mass transit over there.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I wasn't thinking about, but that, I wasn't thinking about the culture or the mass transit in the early two- Me either.
Rym: When I was young, like LA and New York were two big cities.
Rym: And now that I'm older, I realized that one is a hellscape and one is amazing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So when I, when I graduated college at that time, the natural disasters were like probably on the pro-con scale, like enough to tip the scale away from California.
Scott: Nowadays, they're just one of many things tipping the scale away from California.
Rym: You know, my family has been in the United, like on this continent for a very long time.
Rym: Like some of them were pre-revolution.
Rym: And the fam, the entire family converged from a lot, moving around all over to eventually be in the Midwest.
Rym: Partly because, like we know some family history, that region has very few natural disasters and is extremely stable and safe.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't know why so many people keep going to Florida.
Rym: Like Michigan, Ohio, Wisconsin, Ontario, like that area is honestly one of the safest places in the entire earth from natural disasters.
Rym: Like literally no joke, no exaggeration.
Rym: It'll be interesting as climate change accelerates natural disasters.
Rym: What happens?
Rym: because Detroit and Chicago and Buffalo and Toronto end up being the biggest cities that are in the safest zone on earth.
Scott: Yeah, but they're on the great lakes, but the great lakes are very safe.
Rym: The great lakes, not only are they very safe, but they are a supply of fresh water.
Rym: They're one of the largest, fresh water on earth.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: And the, the, the question though is, you know, obviously, you know, the melting ice caps, right?
Scott: But that's in the ocean.
Scott: That's not in the lake, right?
Scott: But that water, you know, can make it to the lake eventually, right?
Rym: If water, water will evolve with the great while the great lakes due to like the lock systems, like not to go too deep into the hydrology of it, they can be drained at a whim.
Rym: If they were, if they were rising to somewhere, you just drain it to the ocean.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: There's a way.
Rym: No, there's canals and blocks and shit.
Scott: I'm just saying it's like, you know, it's not a hundred percent perfect, right?
Scott: There could be depending on, you know, the rate of water level rising, right?
Scott: On the coast there, it definitely won't be as bad as on the coast.
Rym: Historically, the lakes were shrinking because of climate change, but now weather patterns.
Scott: that also gives you, that also gives you some time to, you know, some space there.
Rym: No, but a weather pattern shifted.
Rym: And honestly, because it would be easy to drain them compared to fill them, the fact that they're, oh no, I'm just saying the fact that I'm agreeing, it's pretty safe.
Scott: I'm just saying there's climate change continues.
Scott: that safety barrier, which will keep them safer than ocean coast places for quite a while will eventually also fall.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: But I'm saying for the foreseeable, like even like many, they have a much longer safe headway before it's just a flood than New York does.
Rym: Like that, if things get bad and the coast collapse, honestly, I go back to Michigan.
Rym: Like that's, again, I have the privilege of being able to just travel and escape things, but I mean, I can just, well, you gotta, you gotta get out here somehow.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But in terms of- Everyone's gonna go somewhere.
Scott: But also- Nothing stops me, I don't have family in Michigan, but it doesn't stop me from going to Michigan.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But in terms of- Not that I want to go there.
Rym: But in terms of like that aspect, like dealing with natural disasters, one thing that, and this is, this is like coming from a position of extreme luck and privilege.
Rym: Every natural disaster I've ever experienced in my, for my personal interactions in day-to-day life, they were positive or enjoyable because they didn't actually affect me materially.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That is an interesting thing to experience.
Rym: Like hurricane Sandy, to be really honest, knowing what like the horrors that were happening in my own day-to-day life, it was just a really nice break from work.
Rym: Uh, it was interesting weather.
Rym: I went biking around in a city that was completely shut down.
Rym: Like everything I did on a day-to-day basis was just novel, interesting, and fun.
Rym: So it's weird to think back and like, oh yeah, I could almost be nostalgic for hurricane Sandy.
Scott: Well, I mean, think about, you know, the, the, the most awesome of natural disasters, right?
Scott: The volcano eruption, right?
Scott: And the volcano eruption is like the perfect illustration of the duality in that if you live at the bottom of the volcano and your whole, you know, society is now burned away, that's the worst thing ever, right?
Scott: It's like, nothing worse can happen than volcano on your house, right?
Scott: I did know what natural disasters worse than that asteroid hitting your house.
Scott: No, cause you would, that would be a faster and swifter death than the volcano, right?
Scott: Volcano is terrifying.
Rym: It's like, you know, the pyroclastic, whatever would kill you pretty much instantly.
Scott: Like I would rather have a tornado hit my house than a volcano hit my house.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Rym: No tornado.
Rym: You'd probably survive in the rubble and then die days later of, of a thirst.
Scott: It depends.
Scott: But at least I'm hiding in the basement.
Scott: Whenever the volcano comes, you'll hide in the basement from volcano.
Scott: So, but if you are just far away from the volcano watching it, it's just, you know, it pollutes the sky.
Scott: Um, but it's like, it's just kind of awesome.
Scott: And you know, when it's, people will go up to erupting volcanoes and like check out the lava geologists and shit.
Scott: And it's like, you watch it in videos.
Scott: It's like totally cool, right?
Scott: It's like this awesome neat thing.
Scott: As long as it's not hitting a person.
Rym: Like when I was a kid, when I was in middle school, there was a blizzard, like a, like a dangerous, like super huge blizzard in Michigan.
Scott: Like it I don't know if blizzard really comes into the, I guess maybe because it's where I live.
Scott: There's so many nor'easters and blizzards.
Scott: It doesn't feel like it's natural disaster.
Rym: That's actually because the listener was talking about this in the chat too.
Scott: It's a weather, a weather event.
Rym: People who live in the Midwest and the East coast, like at like New York and Boston and places like that, blizzards, we barely treat as natural disasters because there is so much infrastructure, knowledge, expertise, skill, and just being used to shit about blizzards that if six feet of snow come down, we just fucking deal with it.
Rym: But meanwhile, go even a little bit south to like Georgia.
Rym: And if there is a quarter inch of snow, hundreds die and things are shut down for weeks.
Rym: But when I was a kid in Michigan in the middle school, there was a blizzard so bad that parts like Southeast Michigan shut down.
Rym: Like that is a big deal.
Rym: We had seven-ish feet of snow on our house.
Rym: Like we had, we could not get out.
Rym: We had to get out the second window and then dig out the front door.
Rym: And you know what my kid memory is?
Rym: No school for two weeks.
Rym: Fuck you.
Rym: Coupled with I'm going to go out and explore all day.
Rym: This is going to be awesome.
Rym: And then I'm going to sled from the roof to the street.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Actually my parents did not let me do that.
Rym: To this day, I'm disappointed that they would not let me do that.
Scott: Did you at least jump out the window into the seven feet of snow?
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: Even better.
Rym: I went out hiking through this, through the woods and everything.
Rym: It was such a good time.
Scott: Well, how could you even see the woods?
Scott: Wouldn't it just be snow?
Rym: Woods are way taller than seven feet.
Scott: You had to dig.
Scott: You had to dig to walk, right?
Rym: I just, when I got put on snowshoes and went out.
Scott: Oh, you what?
Scott: You stood on top of it all.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: Cause again, Sierra seven feet in the air.
Rym: I'm an outdoor type person.
Rym: My family's been outdoors.
Scott: You weren't, you weren't at ground level digging seven feet.
Scott: You were seven feet up walking.
Rym: I'm a Michigander.
Rym: If there's snow, I have snowshoes that I'm walking on top of it.
Rym: Cause I'm not stupid.
Scott: We didn't have snowshoe, but okay.
Scott: But that makes a lot more sense.
Scott: I thought you were like, I thought you're digging a tunnel.
Rym: That was a dangerous situation because that is a place where people do not prepare for a blizzard shutting things down because even once every century level blizzards can be mitigated very quickly.
Rym: And this blizzard was bad enough where we could not mitigate it quickly.
Rym: So no one was prepared for it.
Rym: But even at that time in my life, it was just a really pleasant week.
Rym: I didn't have to deal with any of the problems of the natural disaster.
Rym: I just enjoyed it.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Well, I mean, think about, you know, I mentioned earthquake, right?
Scott: In California, the buildings are designed around earthquake.
Scott: They have all sorts of earthquake protections on them.
Scott: So it's like, if an earthquake happens there, it's like, it's still going to damage.
Scott: It's not great.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, there's a certain level of, at least if it's above a certain severity level.
Scott: But you know, the buildings aren't going to like.
Scott: the big skyscrapers are very unlikely to just like fall down and cause, you know, Godzilla level destruction.
Rym: But if a real earthquake hit New York.
Scott: If you had a big, if you had a big earthquake in New York city where the buildings are not designed for earthquake, we are in deep shit.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Years ago, when there was that, that really, really minor earthquake that slightly shook New York, like a tiny bit, the buildings here swayed so much that people like, I was on the street and I did not feel the earthquake, but suddenly out of nowhere, people started yelling and running out of the subway.
Rym: And I saw people running out of buildings and all I'm thinking is what the fuck is going on?
Rym: What the fuck is going on?
Rym: Because I had no context for that because the buildings are so not earthquake ready and so old that if you're like on the 16th or 20th floor of one of these like hundred year old New York buildings,
Scott: and you'll feel it, it amplifies
Rym: enough to where people started running and yelling.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: So that's the thing.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: So we covered, we covered about volcano, hurricane, tornado, earthquake.
Scott: I guess there's sort of the, the, the thing that goes with earthquake, which is tsunami, which goes with, which goes with flood, flood really accompanies like almost everything.
Scott: It's like, you know, so many disasters are water related and like, you know, even something, even if you're far away from the ocean, like tornado can cause flood.
Scott: If it breaks a water main or a dam breaks or, you know, it's like.
Scott: floods are just like the, the, like everything.
Scott: they're all, all over the place.
Scott: Flood is actually even in the, even in the desert, you get flash flood.
Rym: Flood is actually one of the few natural disasters I actually have a like kind of specific plan, like continuously plan around in my actual life.
Scott: No matter where you are, you got to worry about flood situations.
Rym: Even if you live in the desert, like flash floods are actually way more dangerous in dry places than they are in wet places.
Scott: And I think they're getting more common as well.
Rym: They are.
Scott: I'm noticing that the flooding in New York city has definitely gotten worse.
Rym: We talked about this in real life.
Rym: We didn't talk about it on the show.
Rym: So there's a thing that happened during COVID.
Rym: New York city has this thing that's not common in a lot of places called alternate side parking, but it is in, it is a thing in other places.
Rym: Meaning on a few, a few days a week where if you're parked on certain streets, you got to move your car to the other side of the street.
Rym: And then the next day you got to move it back.
Rym: Like you can't leave your car somewhere.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, it's like between these hours, right from eight in the morning to one, you can't park on the left side of the street today.
Scott: And then tomorrow same hours, but you can't park on the right side of the street.
Rym: Now, naive people and car people have made an argument for a long time that these rules are archaic and they're just to discourage street parking, which is not true.
Rym: Those rules.
Scott: If we wanted to discourage street parking, we would just charge for it everywhere.
Rym: Those rules actually came from the New York city's like ancient, like it was a different organization at the time, but basically the department of sanitation and human welfare type stuff.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Because the only reason they do it is so they can sweep the streets.
Rym: And the reason they sweep the streets is so the streets aren't filled with garbage.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like, you might think, Oh, well just cleanliness, right?
Scott: We just want to keep the city clean.
Scott: We need you to move your car so we can clean the curb and all the filth that's piled up in the curb.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: It is for that reason, but it's also because when filth piles up on the street, it blocks all the drains.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: So during COVID that causes floods, the city decided to alternate street parking from twice a week to once a week and car people were really happy.
Rym: So they decided to keep it that way permanently because car people were happy.
Rym: And it turns out that is why we had so much flash flooding in New York now.
Scott: That's true, but there was even before COVID the, the, the flooding has been getting worse.
Rym: It was getting worse.
Rym: And then it went beyond the tipping point way earlier because we're not sweeping the streets twice a week.
Scott: We pushed it.
Scott: We pushed it a little harder by not sweeping enough, but the point is we're getting rained on harder, more rain, right?
Scott: The river, the sea is rising on us.
Scott: You know, and flooding is going to be a thing here.
Scott: If you live near the water, New York city is an island.
Scott: Manhattan's an island, at least
Rym: like, you know, you've got to like, my advice to you is you have to internalize the fact that for the rest of your life, even if we do everything right and things get better and we like correct this course as a species, which I'm, I'm hopeful we will, nothing is going to prevent the next decade of your life from being weird and there being more natural disasters, like more enough to where you have to start preparing for things that you have never had to worry about before.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Cause you think, Oh, up on a mountain, I won't get flood.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Up on the mountain where you'll get mudslide instead.
Rym: Right.
Scott: It's like, Oh, well I'm, uh, I'm out here.
Scott: And you know, it's like, well, you know, in the, in the woods, there'll be a fire in the woods.
Scott: Like, look at again, the West coast or everything's on fire.
Rym: Uh, at this point, I believe that is the second largest wildfire in the recorded history of North America.
Scott: But Greece and Turkey are on fire.
Scott: You don't think about those as places with crazy forests.
Scott: It's super bad.
Rym: Like Turkey is, the nation of Turkey is on fire.
Rym: It's barely even making the news because of all the other disasters happening.
Rym: Good.
Rym: Look at what's happening in Turkey right now.
Rym: It is terrifying.
Rym: And I saw that the best tweet.
Scott: Greece is the same thing.
Rym: The tweet that encapsulated this so well was like, it basically said, I'm paraphrasing climate change means that you'll be watching natural disasters on your phone with increasing, increasing frequency until eventually you're going to be the one recording it on your phone.
Rym: And that's how it's going to go.
Rym: No amount of money and privilege will protect you from this.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's, I mean, it's like, you know, no, even if you're like, I can't imagine you're Bill Gates or Jeff Bezos, right?
Scott: It's like, and that there's nowhere you can run or hide from natural disaster.
Rym: What can you possibly do?
Scott: You live on a boat.
Scott: That's not going to do it.
Scott: Hurricane will come and knock your boat over.
Rym: Now the two, because we've gone on long enough for the show, every show goes long because we don't talk to each other that much in real life right now.
Rym: So this is when we like get everything out.
Rym: that's pent up.
Scott: We'll fix that.
Scott: We'll fix that next week.
Rym: But next week I feel like a dam is just going to like burst out of my brain of me saying weird shit that I've been bottling up for two years or a year and a half.
Rym: But anyway, so I guess the two big takeaways to end this is one, don't like catastrophize and doom and gloom.
Rym: Like don't go overboard planning and preparing.
Rym: Like there's a line.
Scott: Do not be, do not be a prepper.
Scott: So for example, New York city actually has, what's it called?
Rym: Well, we have the evacuation.
Scott: There's like a whole, no, there's a whole department.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: Well, New York city actually is very well prepared to deal with natural disasters.
Rym: Like there are, there are contingency plans that can be triggered that are surprisingly well thought out.
Rym: Like there are ways to evacuate New York city.
Rym: Think about that for a second, what the scale of that kind of thing would mean.
Scott: That is the New York city, like department of emergency management.
Scott: It's like a whole thing specifically for emergency management in New York city, a whole department.
Scott: And you can go and they have websites and they have all these tools.
Scott: Like can follow them and get informed and they'll, you know, they help you out with like basically everything, right?
Scott: So, um, and it's, and it's not, you know, prepper level in the woods stuff.
Scott: It's common sense stuff, right?
Scott: Everything from like check your fricking smoke detector to if you, you know, what flood zone is your house in and where will you evacuate to and how will you know if it's time to evacuate and you know, whatnot.
Scott: So whenever, wherever you live, I don't know how your government or whatever handles those things, but there's going to be something.
Scott: If you have this enough technology to hear a podcast, you have some sort of emergency management, something.
Rym: Go learn what the deal is so that if anything goes wrong and like there's a disaster, you know what to expect and how much help could arrive when.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And learn the reasonable level of stuff.
Scott: that what you need to know, right?
Scott: Be, you know, don't go overboard, right?
Rym: Like I'll give you an territory.
Scott: You don't need that.
Rym: You want to know what my prep is?
Rym: Cause I can explain it very succinctly.
Rym: I have plans like real plans to survive, escape and deal with natural disasters.
Rym: only as far as could.
Rym: I get far enough away from New York city within about a day to where it's not a problem anymore and anything where that would not save me, I do not worry about.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like if there's a nuke, which is not a natural disaster and it's a natural disaster.
Scott: Um, but it's like, well, there's nothing I can really do about that.
Rym: Well, depends on what kind of.
Rym: actually, if it's a, if it's a non-thermonuclear nuke, they're, they're very specific.
Scott: You get the idea.
Scott: If I'm in like the incineration zone, it's like, I just call people and say, you know, I love you.
Scott: I'm going to die until the phone stops.
Rym: But, uh, but, but I guess what I've, what I've changed about those plans in the last year, specifically because of the acceleration of climate change related natural disasters, is I've added something to that plan that I never worried about before.
Rym: Being able to act, to get fresh water that is safe to drink for myself within a hundred miles of New York city if the water supply stops.
Scott: Oh, I just have, I just have water like, you know, in bottles.
Rym: So you want, actually I have, I have some extra life straws now if you want one to keep as a backup.
Scott: I mean, I don't think that's going to be necessary, right?
Scott: The water, the amount of water that I have in my fridge at any given time, if that's not enough water to get probably me and a few other people away from the disaster, right?
Scott: It's like, well, we're not going to get away.
Rym: Well, what I would say is you need, this is, this is my personal assessment.
Rym: If you're less athletic, you need more probably, or you need to go read some other expert things.
Rym: But my rule for myself and Emily, like together, because we hike a lot, is I would have at minimum one liter of water per person per, I don't know, 10 miles of difficult travel that would be necessary to escape.
Scott: I guess that depends if I can, if the disaster has prevented bicycling.
Rym: Yeah, because here's the thing.
Rym: In a disaster, you need to understand that cars don't work anymore and bikes that are not mountain bikes often might not work anymore either.
Rym: It depends on the disaster, but even traveling by foot, one, most people cannot travel more than 10 miles on foot in America without suffering effectively a casualty incident, meaning they cannot walk further after that.
Rym: For reasons, it's too much to get into.
Rym: That's an old New Yorkers, New Yorkers can walk for the Yorkers can, but the average American cannot.
Rym: This was something terrifying.
Rym: I learned from America's, this is all declassified military stuff in the fifties.
Rym: The US government had a thing where they were looking at what would happen if a city got nuked and they were looking at old baby nukes, not modern thermo nukes.
Rym: And they identified that the primary source of casualties would be that the average American could not walk five miles without suffering an event that incapacitated them.
Rym: And the event was blisters.
Scott: Even without the nuke, if you just got someone out of their house and be like, Hey, walk five miles, five mile, let's walk five miles right now.
Scott: Let's go walk five miles nonstop.
Rym: They couldn't do it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It is because blisters caused by the fact that most Americans do not walk that much in their daily lives.
Rym: Like it's, it's just a really terrifying calculus.
Rym: So the military and the US government made plans around the fact that a huge number of casualties, like unsavable, incapacitated, immobile people would occur even if they just asked everyone to walk 10 miles away from a place.
Rym: So, yeah.
Scott: So I guess that's, that's a reasonable thing you can do, actually, if you're worried about natural disasters of any kind.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Walk more.
Scott: Is just, you know, make your body more fit as, you know, you don't have to become athlete fit.
Rym: You don't have to be like me.
Rym: You don't, don't run a half marathon every weekend or something stupid like that.
Rym: Just be able to walk over the course of an entire day, 10 miles.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You should be able to walk 10 miles in a day.
Rym: Like eight or nine hours of walking.
Scott: Not unsupplied, not fast walking.
Scott: Throughout the course of the day with resting, eating, drinking, you know, you don't have to carry a heavy load with you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Just within a 24 hour period, you have covered 10 miles of distance on your own two feet.
Scott: If you can do that, then you can evacuate.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Even if, you know, all this is really bad news.
Rym: And that is the kind of thing that is prudent to do now, because.
Scott: In fair weather.
Rym: One, walking enough to be able to do that will be super good for you.
Rym: And two, that is something that you can, that is not a skill or an ability you can gain quickly.
Rym: You can't be like, well, I'm going to go buy the ability to walk 10 miles tomorrow.
Rym: Like, no, you got to work at it a little bit.
Rym: Right.
Scott: You could buy a gas mask tomorrow.
Scott: You could buy a water filter tomorrow.
Scott: You could buy a boat tomorrow.
Scott: You could buy a life vest.
Rym: You can't buy the ability to walk 10 miles tomorrow.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: You can buy a flashlight tomorrow.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And if you're really paranoid, again, don't go, don't be a prepper.
Scott: If you're really paranoid, don't be.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But the maximum planning I think anyone should do for this kind of thing in America, at least, is have the kind of stuff that people who go backpacking and camping have and know how to use it with a bare bare minimum of competence and be able to camp and make your way on your own for maybe a day, like a day.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Even that's kind of too far.
Scott: It's like you need water.
Scott: You need something to keep you above the water.
Rym: You know, you know how hard it is to carry enough water for a person without a camelback or an equivalent.
Rym: It's actually really hard for humans to do that.
Scott: I'm just saying you have water, right?
Scott: Even if it's just like just a gallon of Poland spring in the closet, you know, whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, you don't need like, oh, I need to, if you're not camping, don't go buy like a camping stove.
Scott: Or don't go buy like, you know, some fancy tent.
Rym: But like a LifeStraw, they're like 10 bucks and you know what they let you do?
Rym: Just stick this straw into any source of non-salt water out in the wild that is totally safe to drink.
Scott: It doesn't work on salt water?
Rym: No, you know, you salt water, nobody who is not already an expert in survival shit should even consider any possible means of getting drinkable water from salt water.
Scott: Just that is not worth your effort.
Scott: Oh man, I, that reminds me, we'll just end the show on this.
Scott: I think this will be my thing of the day.
Scott: So I guess you can google it in the future if you want to watch it before it becomes my thing of the day.
Scott: This dude did a YouTube video.
Scott: He went on a nuclear submarine and he showed two different ways.
Scott: Well, they had that, yes.
Scott: But he showed the two different ways they make oxygen and the machines that do it.
Scott: Well, machines in quotes.
Rym: I think I know.
Scott: He also discussed the desalinization and where they get the, you know, water from and stuff.
Rym: It actually reminds me, I'll leave.
Scott: Because they need water to get oxygen.
Rym: So I'll leave you with this.
Rym: This is like the light because it's a related thing.
Rym: that's cool.
Rym: You know the tragedy of the HMS Terror and the HMS Erebus where everyone went crazy and died in the Arctic?
Rym: We've talked about it before.
Rym: We read the book.
Rym: So they all went crazy because of lead poisoning.
Rym: The lead poisoning was because they, the boats, were very modern.
Rym: They had steam power so they could go through the water and they saved a shitload of space by not having to carry water because the steam could be used to, the steam system also desalinated salt water because they needed to be able to desalinate it to run the steam engine.
Scott: So it's a lot easier to desalinate when you have a nuclear power plant.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: Because the only reason that was a bad idea was that the entire thing was made out of lead.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, we have a nuclear reactor.
Scott: Oh, well we can desalinate all the water we want, can't we?
Scott: As long as your desalination machine keeps working.
Rym: Yeah, that's kind of the cool thing about nuclear reactors is that once one's going, like especially one in like a naval nuclear reactor, you put fuel in one of those and they just run for 10 to 20 years.
Scott: So it's like, yeah, it's like as long as all this shit works and doesn't break, it's like, it's pretty great.
Scott: So you know who's really safe from natural disasters?
Scott: Nuclear submarines.
Rym: Why do you think there's a lot of dystopian sci-fi stories where the last humans on earth are the people manning nuclear submarines hiding under the Arctic?
Scott: Usually I think the story these days is space station people.
Rym: Yeah, I've seen that too.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I think we're good.
Scott: Oh, there should be one.
Scott: Someone should make one.
Scott: So I actually just watched one of those Netflix's I watched was about that.
Scott: It was about like the world ends.
Scott: It seems to be nuclear war that ended the world and this one dude left up in the Arctic, right?
Scott: And he's, he's the last, everyone like evacuated the Arctic base except for him.
Scott: Um, and he tries to communicate.
Scott: It's, it's a George Clooney thing.
Scott: He's like, he directed it.
Scott: He's the star of it, right?
Scott: Everything.
Scott: And he communicates with this space mission that is returning from a Jupiter moon that is suitable, that is suitable for human life.
Scott: And he's basically trying to tell them, don't come back.
Scott: Uh, cause he's like, you're the last ones alive.
Scott: Um, but you just made me think it's like, Hey, you could tell that same story where it's space station and nuclear sub.
Scott: best friends are still alive.
Rym: Pretty sure that story has been written multiple times.
Rym: If we actually look for it and they communicate with each other.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I've read one a long time ago.
Rym: I don't know what it was called, but it was basically all the, all the great power, like the U S the UK, France, like all the countries that had nuclear submarines, all the people who manned all those submarines, like the Soviet union, everyone were the only people left.
Rym: And they slowly, they're all like, yeah, why even be enemies?
Rym: If everyone else is dead, let's all just meet somewhere and figure out how to rebuild society.
Rym: Oh shit.
Rym: It's only men because militaries are sexist.
Rym: The end.
Rym: It was a really good story.
Rym: I don't remember what it was called.
Rym: It was short.
Rym: It was not.
Scott: Are there, are there women?
Rym: I mean, we have no many, I don't believe there is any country where women are allowed to serve on nuclear submarines.
Scott: There has never been a woman serving on a nuclear submarine.
Rym: I don't believe so.
Scott: There weren't any in the video I watched on you.
Scott: Oh, this is my thing of the day.
Rym: I don't believe so, but I'm not sure.
Scott: What if they made an all woman nuclear submarine?
Scott: That would be awesome and we should, wouldn't we like win all the wars with that, that they would like, they would never lose.
Scott: Like, all right, I'm going to go.
Scott: You should want to know of the things on Netflix that I've watched that we could do a good show on.
Scott: There's a, the platform, it's a, it's a movie in Spanish, like Spain, Spanish.
Scott: It's a Netflix exclusive.
Scott: So it's, you know, go watch the platform so we could get a Thursday show out of it.
Scott: I will.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I'm going to go.
Scott: There's a TV show called the platform.
Scott: It's not that one movie called the platform.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Food time.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leaf for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion, news, and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution.
Scott: 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And before I read the list of Patrion patrons who want me to say their name on the show, I will let you all know if you didn't notice, if you're a patron that I have pause the Patrion collections for the upcoming month, primarily because we're skipping so many shows due to travel and stuff in August that I feel like we'll pause it a little bit.
Rym: Like you're not getting the normal GeekNights experience, but don't worry.
Rym: After next week, not this week, but next week, then the following week, we're pretty much going to be back on the normal GeekNights schedule for the foreseeable future.
Rym: So anyway, the Patrion patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi McNicholallen Joins Link, Gigi Dreadily, Tenet by Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex Finn, JustLikeADudeGuy, Kishaya85, Rebecca Dunn, ReviewMedBull, 34 Cowards, Ryan Perrin, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Harold, Taylor Braun, UndertakeLawAdoption, Pierce Absorb, Program Threat, Open Speed.
Rym: You hold the key to my heart and a whole bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: And now, tonight, the last show we'll do before our week away, I leave you with, sun.
Scott: it's not disgusting it's just reality.
Scott: take a deep breath.