Rym: It's Thursday, March 11th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: We are talking about seasons of life.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, I did just go outside and run, so anyone watching the stream, I'm literally, like, wearing my running clothes.
Rym: And I realized, now that I'm looking at the stream, that, uh, I'm wearing my running hat.
Rym: Which is, like, this Under Armour reflective running hat.
Rym: And it is fucking, like, the sun reflecting the spotlight on my face.
Scott: Oh, so it's, like, my head.
Rym: But, uh, so earlier today, I was just in a Twitter conversation with some games people, and they were talking about, like, Cookie Clicker-type games.
Rym: And, like, "Oh, I have this urge to play, like, a garbage game like that
Rym: again.".
Scott: So I've been playing this Loop Hero, and there's another game I can talk about.
Scott: I might talk about them a bit on Tuesday, but it is Loop Hero, and it's also a game on Steam I've been playing called Luck Be a Landlord.
Rym: Oh, you mentioned that multiple times, and I saw you playing.
Scott: We'll talk about it on a future GeekNights.
Scott: We'll talk about Luck Be a Landlord.
Rym: I think I gotta poke at that, but we will talk about that on a future GeekNights.
Rym: But, uh, yeah, so, uh, I remembered a game that we've talked about, we reviewed, we used to reference a lot.
Rym: A game called Candy Box.
Rym: So I went and looked up, like, "Oh, what's the current URL of Candy
Rym: Box?".
Rym: 'Cause I wanted to suggest to these people, "Hey, you want a clicker-type game to play?
Rym: This is, like, the err-clicker game.
Rym: Like, this is the ultimate
Rym: clicker.".
Scott: Yeah, man, it's definitely newer than Progress Quest, but I feel like it is.
Rym: But it did the most with that genre, I think.
Rym: 'Cause there was a real, there was a legit real game in there.
Scott: It's pretty much Cow Clicker, Cookie Clicker, Candy Box, and Progress Quest are, like, you know...
Rym: Yeah, Candy Box 2 almost went too far and added, like, too much of a game.
Scott: Candy Box 2, you can just put that in there.
Scott: It's not that exciting.
Rym: Yeah, but, uh, here's the problem.
Rym: When I went to look at Candy Box, I discovered that Candy Box had been updated a little bit.
Rym: Like, there's a little better UX.
Rym: It's still the same original game.
Rym: But, like, things just work a little bit better.
Scott: So, that's cool.
Rym: So, I poked at it a little bit, and I made my recommendation, like, "Hey, you should play Candy
Rym: Box.".
Rym: But then I left it open in a tab and didn't think about it, and I shifted to that tab later, and I had a bunch of candies, and I clicked on everything I could click on.
Rym: And I kind of kept playing Candy Box for, like, a day.
Scott: Did you beat Candy Box?
Rym: I got to the point where you fight the dragon, and then part of my brain said, "Rym, fucking,
Rym: stop.".
Rym: And I didn't beat the dragon.
Scott: So, Candy Box 1, at least, runs entirely locally in the browser and is written in JavaScript.
Scott: So, you can just open up your JavaScript console in the browser and just be like, "Change your number of candies
Scott: directly.".
Rym: Number of candies, number of lollipops.
Scott: Yeah, I just gave myself a zillion candies and beat the game in a few minutes.
Rym: You do still have to cast right spells in some places to get some things to happen.
Rym: Like, there is still a game there.
Scott: Yeah, basically, I just figured out, like, anytime I needed to do... Basically, I eliminated all the waiting.
Scott: At any moment, I gave myself as much resources as I needed, and then just figured out what to click on and what order to get the game to go towards the end.
Scott: And that's how I beat Candy Box.
Rym: I did when I first beat it.
Rym: I beat it
Rym: "legit.".
Rym: But the way I did it is.
Rym: I just got the game up to a state, and then I just left it running in a tab at work for, like, a week.
Rym: And I just came back to it, and then I had enough candies to literally do everything in one go.
Scott: You could have just saved a week of computing time.
Rym: I just left the tab open.
Rym: That computer was doing stuff anyway.
Scott: I'm just saying.
Scott: It's a little silly, isn't it?
Rym: Here we go.
Rym: Let's make Candy Box, but you have to mine cryptocurrencies to make candies.
Scott: Yeah, how about no?
Rym: So you got any news?
Scott: Do we have news?
Scott: Yeah, so here's a news.
Scott: I know it sounds like a K-pop news, but trust me, it's not.
Scott: It's actually related to my job somewhat news.
Scott: At least, you know, right?
Scott: So I work for a music publisher, but regardless, a thing happened.
Scott: There's a company called Kakao M that is basically the secret master of K-pop.
Scott: You can think of it that way.
Scott: Usually you think of these big K-pop companies.
Scott: They're like record labels, and they have the big groups.
Scott: But actually, almost everyone who's not in the big groups and some who are big as well are basically all under this one mega company.
Scott: that's like a distributor and an everything-in-one company, Kakao M, that they just own a large percentage of the K-pop world.
Scott: But regardless, the story is that they got into a fight with Spotify.
Scott: Spotify recently launched in South Korea.
Scott: Very recently.
Scott: This month.
Scott: Previous month.
Scott: Super recently.
Scott: And because the biggest streaming services in Korea, the biggest one I think is actually Melon, which is owned by Kakao M. So there's some shenanigans going on there.
Scott: But anyway, they got into a fight and the vast majority of K-pop was just removed from Spotify entirely.
Scott: So a lot of people got mad.
Scott: For example, Tablo, a famous K-pop dude, he was like, "What's up with this
Scott: bullshit?".
Scott: Two big companies get into a fight and presumably, Spotify is fighting on behalf of the users.
Scott: They want to keep the price of Spotify low because if they have to pay artists more money they would have to raise the cost of Spotify or reduce their profits.
Scott: Kakao M is fighting on behalf of the artists.
Scott: They want more money for themselves and the people who actually make the music.
Scott: There's no right and wrong really.
Scott: Artists are underpaid.
Scott: True.
Scott: Also true.
Scott: People aren't going to pay much more than what Spotify costs.
Scott: Spotify raises the price to 50 bucks a month, which is probably what it would take to pay artists fairly.
Scott: People aren't going to pay that and artists will have nothing.
Scott: They fight and Tablo is like, "Look, these two big companies fight and basically the people they're trying to help, the artists and the customers respectively, are both hurt.
Scott: The customers are without the music they want to listen to and the artists are now getting nothing for that duration because no one can listen to their music and they're going to go to YouTube or who knows where else to pirate.
Scott: who knows, right?
Scott: But they settled today for undisclosed terms and so now the music is back.
Scott: But I think it's just an interesting situation to think about, right?
Scott: Because usually when these battles go on we're coming in here like, "They're right and they're wrong and they're right and they're on this
Scott: side.".
Rym: The problem is, honestly, capitalism because we kind of talked about this when we talked about cryptocurrencies last week.
Rym: around there are some commodities that have effectively become valueless to the average consumer or if they have personal value the incremental cost of getting one versus another starts to approach zero.
Rym: for a lot of people music is like that.
Rym: They can listen to music generally and they use some services to listen to music but they don't think a lot about music.
Rym: otherwise it's not like they'll say, "Oh, well I really need to listen to this specific band so I'm jumping ship on Spotify.
Rym: I'm going to Kweeblo because Kweeblo has got this one
Rym: band.".
Scott: A lot of K-Pop people were like, "Hey, should we use YouTube Music or should we use iTunes now?
Scott: because Spotify was pretty much the place,
Scott: right?".
Rym: But now they're like, "Okay, it's resolved, they came
Rym: back.".
Scott: But if this had gone on longer you absolutely would have seen K-Pop fans leave, cancel Spotify and go to YouTube Music or Apple Music.
Rym: I think part of that is that K-Pop fans are, they're not monolithic don't get me wrong, but they are definitely semi-unique in the music fandom world for a lot of reasons we've talked about before as a group but also I think for most people if they move to one service or the other, not much changes because most services have most of the music that any given community will listen to unless there's a specific genre that is under or over represented on one versus the other.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: But all the mainstream music is going to be, the vast majority of it is going to be on all these services.
Rym: like I got a Sonos, I literally just type "meatloaf" and I don't even care where the meatloaf comes from, do I hear it or not?
Scott: I care where the meatloaf comes from.
Rym: But if I ever type something big mainstream, generic, old into one of my devices and no music comes up, I'm going to suddenly be very surprised and try to figure out why, but that basically almost never happens.
Rym: The music I want to listen to that isn't on Spotify, is not on really any service I'm going to subscribe to.
Rym: It's not on anything.
Scott: I just see there's a lot of parallels with this between some other things we look at like Apple versus Epic, where it's like Epic is nominally fighting for the customer and Apple is sort of fighting for the developer in a way.
Rym: Or in the old days with Amazon, Amazon fights for us, the jerk buying something.
Scott: Right, but Epic sort of is a developer, so it's a little hairy.
Scott: But there's these battles going on where there's no... It's not just good guy and bad guy.
Scott: It's like, is it two bad guys fighting?
Scott: Is it two good guys fighting?
Scott: Is it two good bad guys fighting?
Scott: Two gray areas battling each other.
Scott: It's like, oh no.
Scott: Two gray areas battle each other and you don't really know who to root for or what outcome you want, but as long as they battle everyone suffers.
Rym: But the incremental cost of listening to a song one more time is basically zero and the distribution of cost of that is also basically zero.
Rym: So we kind of destroyed how we fund new works being created and this problem is not going to get resolved in any field anytime soon.
Rym: It's not zero-sum, but it acts like zero-sum for all intents and purposes from a lot of angles.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So in some other news if you are looking for work or in some trouble financially right now and you're in New York but there are things like this going on in a lot of other places.
Rym: I'm going to link to one from New York.
Rym: So way, way back when I desperately needed some money in high school to afford to go to college I had a job working for the government and for the time it paid really, really, really well and it wasn't the kind of job that someone like me would have thought I could get.
Rym: That's how I got my first job ever working for the US Census.
Rym: And I'll tell you in the year 1999 and 2000 that job paid $10.50 an hour.
Scott: That was a lot in 1990.
Scott: That's more than I made working at the dry cleaner and way more than the summer camps.
Scott: I worked at summer camps several times and the way they worked is you would just get one paycheck at the end of the summer for the whole time and it was way less than minimum wage.
Scott: Part of it was that the compensation also included all this lodging and food you were getting and things like that.
Scott: So it's a little bit fair a little bit because you don't have to pay rent while you're working at a summer camp for example.
Scott: You would work eight weeks in a row not 24/7 basically with a few days off here and there and then at the end they'd give you like $3K.
Rym: It's kind of similar to how working at an amusement park often works for people.
Scott: The point is that $10 an hour is real good in 1990 whatever for a high school kid.
Rym: I got my first paycheck and it was like $400 something bucks and I was like I didn't know what to do with that much money.
Scott: On the one hand it's still criminally low.
Scott: The minimum wage should have been more than that even then.
Rym: Like the fight for $15 right now was obsolete.
Scott: But it was still better than average at the time and the circumstance.
Rym: So right now there are a lot of jobs.
Rym: these are temporary jobs.
Rym: You're not going to make a career out of this at least not working for the same place.
Rym: Managing all the infrastructure which is more substantial than you might realize around getting vaccines out to people.
Rym: The effort of getting vaccines out to Americans is one of the larger logistical projects that has ever happened in America.
Rym: This is on the level with big great depression era things that we did.
Rym: Like the CCC.
Scott: Even though it's ongoing you think oh they've already got everything.
Scott: It's like no we've only gotten some of the way there.
Scott: We're still giving them to only people who are like getting in New York just said okay you can make an appointment if you're 60 or over.
Scott: It's like when they open it up to 40 plus 30 any old adult.
Scott: there's going to be so many people.
Rym: And there are so many tasks that need to be done to make these things work.
Scott: Not just jabbing people.
Scott: There's a lot more jobs.
Rym: Think about a PACS.
Rym: How many enforcers at a PACS does it take to just keep lines together?
Rym: Now imagine keeping lines together that are an order of magnitude bigger who are not PACS attendees but regular ass people.
Scott: And there's a line.
Rym: And there's a pandemic.
Rym: so you still got to keep them like six feet apart from each other the whole time.
Scott: There's all kinds of problems going on.
Scott: And that's just one of the things you could be doing.
Rym: There are things like this all over but I'll link to one of these as an example.
Rym: In New York City right now there's a giant vaccine center at the Javits which is our terrible convention center.
Rym: It's a terrible convention center.
Scott: It's fine for vaccine distribution.
Rym: It is but it's not good.
Rym: It's a big empty room.
Scott: It'll get the job done.
Scott: You're not doing it.
Scott: It is perfect for this.
Rym: They are desperate for people to help them administer the vaccines.
Rym: They are paying $27 an hour and you can get shit tons of overtime if you're willing to just work like 12 hour shifts.
Rym: They'll pay you time and a half on top of that.
Scott: $27 an hour is I'd say like a fair minimum wage almost.
Rym: I'd say $27 an hour would be a good starting point for the new minimum wage in America.
Scott: Yeah it's close.
Rym: $15 is not enough.
Scott: $27 I'd like to.
Scott: I should do the math.
Scott: If you made $6 an hour in the 50s let me get my inflation calculator.
Rym: The last time I did something like that because the metric I used the last time I looked at this was something like what is the wage it took for one person to support a family of four and buy a house in the 50s.
Scott: Alright so actually I think $27 might only be halfway there.
Scott: Usually I hear old people say "When I was a kid in the 50s I only got like $5 an
Scott: hour.".
Rym: Yeah and somehow you bought a house and like married someone and had kids and sent both of them to college.
Scott: $5 an hour in 1955 adjusted for inflation with USInflationCalculator.com in 2021 would be $49 an hour.
Scott: so $27 is halfway there.
Rym: So the Javits they need people right now like if you call them up with your resume like there's a good chance you can get these jobs.
Rym: They need customer service people, vaccinator support.
Rym: they do need people who have technician training like they need pharmacists and licensed professionals.
Rym: but they also need people just to do shit like manage lines fill out paperwork.
Rym: One of these jobs is data entry just sitting at a desk typing data in from pieces of paper.
Scott: Yeah someone comes up.
Scott: you're like so and so got their first vaccine.
Scott: on this day you type it in right?
Scott: Who are they?
Scott: What's their name?
Scott: Where do they live?
Rym: And if you think you're not qualified for this kind of stuff.
Rym: that job I got for the US Census.
Rym: I'd never been trained in anything.
Rym: I went to high school in America.
Scott: If you know how to listen to a fucking podcast you know how to do most of those jobs.
Rym: My first real jobs were data entry and clerical work like payroll stuff.
Rym: One of my.
Rym: I sat there for four hours a day at one point looking at pieces of paper and typing numbers on those pieces of paper into a system.
Scott: I had a lot of jobs doing filing where there would be a stack of paper and there would be a big shelves full of filing folders and you would literally take a piece of paper look at the last name find the folder and put the piece of paper in the folder.
Rym: I did that at the end of the census.
Scott: You just do that over and over again and I got paid money for that.
Rym: I did that at RIT but they didn't pay me $27 an hour to do it.
Scott: If you're listening to this you can do that.
Scott: I'm sure you can.
Scott: If someone paid $27 an hour to do that I might rather do that than what I do now.
Rym: I definitely it's interesting where on one hand I like a really challenging job but on the other hand I do sometimes think back to when I had jobs that were mindless and how I could literally 100% compartmentalize them away.
Rym: And I miss it sometimes.
Rym: but then I also remember the reality of a job like that and how boring and soul crushing it was.
Rym: Really we just need a post scarcity society and communism but we'll get there.
Rym: Anyway in some news that is political news but it is a big deal and there's a reason I want to talk about this.
Rym: The American rescue plan like that giant covid relief bill actually was signed into law today.
Scott: Without the aforementioned minimum wage increase but with most of the other stuff.
Rym: We can talk about that in a second because actually removing the minimum wage from this bill was probably a good idea because otherwise the bill would not have passed today.
Rym: even if the minimum wage happened it would have taken like possibly months more to pass the bill for reasons like that's beyond the scope of the show.
Rym: But as an aside because you mentioned it most not all but most of the senators who voted no on the minimum wage issued statements saying they only oppose including it in this bill.
Rym: they are sponsoring the next separate bill that is the minimum wage bill.
Scott: We'll see about that.
Rym: Yeah we'll see.
Rym: but the thing about this bill that's important is that it passed for real like this is a law.
Scott: This is now the law of the land in the United States.
Rym: And if you haven't actually looked at what it does it's not just like that stimulus check.
Scott: Well it's enormous.
Scott: I'm not sure if there's anyone who knows everything it does.
Rym: No the only person who knows.
Scott: Not any one person.
Rym: There is one person who knows everything.
Rym: because part of the reason why it took so long to pass this bill is you know what the Republicans did like right at the end?
Scott: They made him read it because the procedural nonsense.
Rym: Yep they voted to force a reading of the bill.
Rym: What that means is every single word in this bill which is like 680 pages had to be read aloud on the senate floor.
Rym: the Republicans forced that to happen and then they all left.
Rym: And this dude had to sit there.
Scott: You should have changed.
Scott: you know it's like you get what you.
Scott: you know that's the procedure.
Scott: that's in the rules.
Scott: if you don't like it you should change those procedural rules to be like alright if there's a reading every senator must sit there for the entire reading.
Scott: Common sense rule if you think that having readings should be part of the rules in the first place then make everyone sit there.
Rym: Yep well like the filibuster fuck this idea that you can filibuster something by saying I'm going to filibuster it.
Rym: If you want to filibuster something you better fucking stand there and piss your pants.
Scott: Well you shouldn't have that either.
Scott: you should be forced to vote at some point.
Rym: Yep but well anyway we make fun of the monarchy because that came up lately but we have the filibuster and the senate so we got our own problems over here.
Rym: But anyway this bill is honestly like the best way to describe it is transformative.
Rym: This bill does a ton of really progressive stuff the benefits of which we're going to see for like decades and decades and decades to come.
Rym: There's huge tax credits for people who have kids.
Rym: there's lots of housing assistance.
Scott: it's like this bill is a big deal and the reason I bring this up It's not like what you're used to where it's like.
Scott: oh you know we're here to save the day by giving money to companies.
Rym: Yep like the previous covid relief bills that the republicans put through that didn't actually do much for us.
Scott: Yeah so but I don't want to get any relief.
Rym: Yep but this bill will like.
Rym: this is one of the biggest pieces of legislation America has ever passed in the modern era dollar wise.
Rym: Yep and also in terms of what it changes it's on par with the ACA.
Rym: you know Obamacare but the reason I bring this up as news is that the Democrats you know the not evil party I'm not necessarily saying the good party just the not evil party they are doing a very different strategy with this bill compared to what happened the last time.
Rym: they passed a big bill like this because in America they passed the ACA.
Rym: what you know is Obamacare which radically transformed America and got healthcare to a lot more people and honestly like just made America a better place.
Rym: it was a really good bill and what it did was actually very popular in America among all Americans.
Rym: even republicans were very happy with what the bill did.
Rym: the problem was they hated the bill.
Rym: that disconnect is a big part of why American politics got so broken and extreme so quickly.
Rym: the Democrats basically lost the house and lost a lot of representation and like lost on the issue of this bill being passed despite this bill being very popular partly because what they had assumed was that if they passed a bill that radically reformed healthcare for the better they would get credit for the fact that they had radically reformed healthcare for the better and would be able to build on that foundation.
Rym: but the assumption that because you did a good thing the people who benefit from it will understand what you did is false similar to the idea that if I make some good software like if I design a really good game of course people will play it.
Rym: it's a really good game.
Rym: why wouldn't they play it?
Rym: the reality is if you don't also market and like tell people about the thing people will never find out about the thing.
Scott: yeah people don't know and people are you know ignorant.
Scott: they're not paying attention.
Scott: they've got other things going on.
Scott: they've been lied to by someone else who's in their ear right.
Scott: there are so many reasons besides just being you know.
Scott: some you know you obviously are thinking of.
Scott: you know the stereotypical republican who lives in the hills listening to some right wing radio people right or watching the faux news.
Scott: but there's a lot of other people that you know don't.
Scott: for a wide variety of reasons.
Scott: you just will not learn or learn the wrong thing because you need to control right.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: is it propaganda?
Scott: yes but there's propaganda on the opposite also.
Rym: you know what there's a real.
Rym: if you don't tell your own story someone else is going to tell your story for you.
Scott: right and it's like.
Scott: the problem with propaganda is when the propaganda isn't true.
Rym: if your propaganda is all true what's the problem?
Scott: yup hey everyone get a vaccine they work and not having not putting out true propaganda you're just leaving a huge vacuum for false propaganda to exist.
Scott: you can't stop anyone else from doing it in a society with free speech exactly.
Scott: so you need to put the truth.
Scott: propaganda out there.
Scott: right and you know propaganda is a bad word.
Scott: but if it's true why is that bad?
Rym: and that's what's different here.
Rym: this is something i want you to internalize.
Rym: if you're thinking about american politics the the democratic party and i'm not saying this is a an unapped application to them has never been super good about getting its message out there for a lot of reasons.
Rym: and the big difference between right now and the last time they passed a big bill.
Rym: is they real?
Rym: like they've learned from their mistakes like they have openly talked about at length into too long?
Rym: yep they've talked about like.
Rym: why did we fail?
Rym: why did we lose the messaging battle on obamacare one of the most popular bills that ever passed and they took those lessons to heart and they are spending a lot of time like they're going to advertise the fact that this bill passed.
Rym: one of the things like they are really focused on making it clear that that people understand that this bill that is going to help a lot of people passed because of the democrats and that no republicans voted for it and you can see it starting to work.
Rym: multiple republican senators have praised this bill already and said oh yeah this is going to help my constituents and the democrats immediately started running ads and pushing the message out making it clear that you so and so voted against.
Rym: yeah you voted against this bill.
Rym: fuck oh you don't get credit for this.
Rym: you actively opposed us doing this mm-hmm.
Rym: this is a profound shift in how american politics has gone for the last like several decades.
Rym: i don't know if this will work but i want you to notice that like pay attention to how this messaging is different.
Rym: democrats ain't perfect but they are trying a different strategy.
Rym: if you're losing against hades over and over again in hades and you never change your strategy that's not you like if you're trying to make the sword and artemis work against hades.
Rym: that's real fucking hard like.
Scott: but also the propaganda angle right.
Scott: also the propaganda angle again right.
Scott: it's like we at least hopefully anyone listening to this right.
Scott: you can recognize that it's propaganda.
Scott: if you can think about it in the meta then hasn't it lost its power to just like mindlessly brainwash you like we talk about with ads?
Rym: i know it's an ad.
Rym: i'm immediately suspicious of it right?
Scott: so when you see the messaging coming you know whether it's from whoever it is the good people or the bad people or some other third party who knows right.
Scott: consider all of it in the meta circumstance the way we're discussing the strategy in the meta circumstance to keep your head in the correct place whenever a message is sent to you or like like given to you or you see propaganda like.
Rym: think specifically who is putting this message in front of me what are they trying to convey and what motive might they have?
Rym: like?
Rym: those are the three things to ask yourself because if you know the who you know the motive and you know the what you can evaluate this message and understand what's going on.
Rym: you can also protect yourself from bad propaganda and dangerous lies yep and you can also help spread the messages that might allow us to achieve better goals.
Rym: so if the who is democrats the goal is get people to understand that this bill helped them and the motivation beyond that is so that we can then pass more bills that are like this.
Rym: that's a message to share.
Rym: even though we didn't get everything we wanted like we still need the $15 minimum wage.
Rym: that's like a baby step.
Rym: we still need to fight for that.
Rym: but don't tank the messaging of.
Rym: we did do something because we didn't do one of the hundred things we could do alright.
Scott: so one of the hundred things we could have done that we didn't do was cancel the rent anywhere.
Scott: pretty much right.
Rym: we delayed evictions in some places I guess depending on your state the different lots of technicalities mostly we just take that can down the road of misery and it's going to be a bad situation.
Rym: still right.
Scott: so the bad situation is an example.
Scott: I want to highlight this example of the bad situation coming because it hits close to home.
Scott: right.
Scott: you know most of the cases in which people have said oh no this pandemic is going to cause me to go out of business.
Scott: right you know on the one hand obviously sympathetic someone losing their business is not good but if you think about it on the whole it's like okay.
Scott: you've basically just decided that instead of paying people's rent and letting them off the hook you're just going to have businesses go out of business and then when the pandemic is over people can start new businesses right from nothing and you know to like if your local pizza place goes away.
Scott: and then it's like okay well no one's buying pizza right now but in two years from now start a new pizza place and now we have pizza again.
Scott: right it's not like you know in the grand picture while it sucks for the previous pizza owner in the grand picture it's not you know.
Scott: like the worst yeah of course there's.
Rym: the asterisk of capitalism has made this all much worse than it needed to be obvious yes but here's an example where no right.
Scott: this is why we still needed to cancel the rent and why just saying oh go out of business and come back later is not a good enough answer.
Scott: so there is a place in New York and Chinatown called the Jing Fong dim sum.
Scott: right and now there's plenty of dim sums in New York City.
Scott: if you don't know dim sum it's like the greatest Chinese food experience you can have right if you've never?
Rym: you said you've never heard of it.
Rym: just find a place that has it.
Rym: go there on like a Sunday morning and have a grand old time.
Scott: that's right.
Scott: so there's some in Flushing there's others in Chinatown.
Scott: there's plenty.
Scott: we're not going to be without dim sum in New York City probably ever right.
Scott: we've been without it for a while but we're going to be going back into it as soon as it's safe.
Rym: I'm already hungry and I have not had dim sum since February.
Rym: no late January.
Rym: I'm salivating for dim sum specifically late January 2020. yeah late January 2020.
Rym: I had some dim sum.
Scott: I probably hadn't had it since 2019 but Jing Fong was it the best dim sum?
Scott: I don't think so but it was very good definitely good enough and I went there many times.
Scott: there are obviously people who went there way more than me.
Scott: I've gone there with like co-workers.
Scott: I've gone on dates there.
Scott: I've gone there with friends there.
Scott: I have a lot of memories going to there even though it's maybe been only double digit number of visits in my life.
Scott: right and the thing about that place is that it was just this enormous ballroom like in New York City.
Scott: you do not see a room this big often and it's like you would go there.
Scott: you would take an escalator up to the second floor and then they would seat you at these enormous circular tables.
Scott: you would usually be sitting with strangers unless you had a lot of friends with you and the room was just huge and it's like people would be going around bringing food everywhere and then it would also be like someone sitting at a desk just like in the middle of the ballroom and they're like taking reservations because people having birthday parties there, office functions there, award ceremonies, like any kind of event you could book, you only needed a portion of the room, you didn't even need the whole room.
Scott: sometimes they'd wall off a part of the room to have an event because it's like you don't need that much space, it was so enormous and it was just such a unique experience eating at this place and obviously I wouldn't be talking about it if they weren't shutting it down.
Scott: they have no choice financially because of the situation and not cancelling rent and a jerk landlord.
Scott: they have no choice.
Scott: it's like they're going down.
Scott: goodbye, it's closed, you can never go there again, you'll have to go get your dim sum somewhere else and it's like oh, just come back later.
Scott: it's like a place like this can't come back later, right?
Scott: you can open up a new dim sum restaurant in New York with the same chefs I guess, they make the same food but you can't get that ballroom back.
Scott: it's going to be carved up into apartments or who knows what the heck they're going to do with it.
Scott: turn it into something but you're not going to find another space to get that large square footage to have that same experience.
Scott: and the amount of money it would cost to renovate it and to get all those tables and the way the room was decorated it would probably cost six figures just to renovate.
Scott: even if you got a room just to renovate it to look like that.
Scott: probably we're talking cheap decorations.
Rym: I'm still talking seven.
Scott: those aren't actual gold dragons on the wall.
Scott: it's just like stuff painted with gold paint.
Scott: but the point is it's basically impossible unless a rich person bails them out because capitalism that's it.
Scott: there's no hope whatsoever.
Scott: no amount of crowdfunding would be enough.
Scott: they could not crowdfund enough to rescue this.
Scott: it would be so expensive.
Rym: this kind of story is going to play out all over America.
Rym: the previous topic about messaging and propaganda do not let the public consciousness forget all the things that we've lost that we don't realize we lost yet that we're going to discover that we've lost as we enter a post-Covid society.
Scott: we're not talking about replaceable things that were lost.
Scott: a local pizza joint went away and a new one came in.
Scott: we're talking about the unreplaceable experience here and it's just one place but there will be many such places.
Rym: it's a tiny thing but Burger Garage.
Rym: I don't think a place like that could come back to Queens like this part of Queens.
Scott: we lost Malu and that was way pre-Covid and no ice cream has been.
Rym: we got some good ice creams now nothing close to Malu that awesome nerdy dude who ran that shop.
Rym: I miss that dude.
Rym: we talked about him the other day.
Rym: Emily and I were actually thinking about what's going to be out there post-Covid.
Scott: we have Ample Hills which is really good ice cream and has lots of interesting flavors but it's not Malu.
Scott: it's still A+ tier.
Scott: we had that S tier ice cream and now we have a different A+/S tier ice cream but it's not that S tier ice cream.
Rym: as we enter a post-Covid society and we start to try to live our "normal lives" again we have to make it very clear societally what we lost and it has to be abundantly clear we need to talk about and make sure that message gets spread that we didn't have to lose those things.
Rym: most of what we've lost to Covid on this scale, I'm not talking about humans who died though many of those were also preventable.
Rym: a good chunk of the things we lost to Covid did not need to be lost but in America one political party forced us to lose them and the other political party didn't do enough to stop them.
Rym: don't let the government get away with letting us lose all these things.
Rym: remember that we could have saved a lot of them but anyway things of the day.
Rym: on a lighter note a while ago I did The Legend of Beavis and if you recall The Legend of Beavis reeked of effort, it was way higher quality than it had any right to be or even needed to be.
Rym: it was just so tightly done.
Rym: this is another one of those things.
Rym: it's from January of 2021. it's relatively recent.
Rym: it's called Life as a Bokoblin a Zelda nature documentary.
Rym: this shit is 20 minutes long.
Rym: it is a full BBC style documentary on the lives of Bokoblins.
Rym: the production values on this are off the charts.
Rym: we started watching it.
Rym: last night we watched a few minutes.
Rym: this is actually pretty good.
Rym: we watched the whole goddamn thing.
Rym: this is a trial.
Rym: you could put this on the BBC and it would fit in right next to a legit real nature documentary.
Rym: that is how well they put this together.
Scott: I guess they had a lot of time on their hands.
Rym: they made a four hour long the making of video.
Rym: it's an hour and a half long but it is how we made this.
Rym: this is a full on production.
Rym: this is crazy.
Scott: so we know that sports analytics has become a big deal over time and there are various sources of data that are more or less accessible to the general public.
Scott: but most of the analytics people in sports are trying to figure out things in relation to betting or scouting.
Scott: it's like what players are better than others who's improving?
Scott: who should you draft higher?
Scott: these sorts of player specific questions who's better than who?
Scott: or what team should I bet on tonight?
Scott: who's more likely to win in this matchup?
Scott: all these sorts of things are the questions people are trying to answer and they're not using the people whose job it is to do.
Scott: analytics aren't using the data necessarily to just answer fun, interesting questions that matter to people who are just generally interested.
Scott: occasionally journalists will do this but usually they're relying on the analytics people more, sometimes at least I know some journalists are putting in big efforts to learn the analytics stuff themselves and to up their own skills to make themselves better at their job which is kind of awesome.
Rym: I'm getting more into that deeper type of statistical analysis myself at work
Scott: but anyway some random person on Reddit decided to take the data from basically the entire decade of the NHL and they counted all the penalties all 105,639 penalties for all the teams and they arranged them to answer such questions as which penalty is called the most, which team gets called for each penalty the most which player
Rym: gets called for which penalty
Scott: the most, which player
Scott: they draw penalties the most the least, etc.
Scott: you know, which teams get penalized more often.
Scott: in total right, pretty much anything you can get that's interesting out of just knowing just a straight list of which penalties were called, what penalty was it against which player on which team and add that all up and it's all presented here just in a Reddit post for everybody to read with 2.8 thousand upvotes on it as you would expect and, you know, the interest a lot of it is just exactly what you'd expect like, yeah, the dirty player has the most unsportsmanlike conduct penalties common sense, but also you know, yeah, things we know like, you know, referees like to just sort of even up the penalties instead of just calling whoever deserves to be penalized you know, to sort of manage the game a bit and this you'll see.
Scott: the teams that are penalized the most often also draw penalties the most, right, the refs like to even it out there, right you know, these sorts of things.
Scott: you'll also see.
Rym: the penalties that don't get called.
Rym: spearing is the one I was going to bring up.
Rym: spearing
Scott: does not get called nearly enough right, but also these penalties that get called like once in a decade right, coach on the ice headbutting right, and then you can say hey, that penalty was called once, there must have been a special incident, and indeed there was, and then you can YouTube and find that special incident and learn what the story was.
Rym: I'm Miles Wood, possibly the only person ever to get called for.
Scott: butt ending in like the modern era right, and slewfooting which gets called way not enough but yeah, go ahead and take a look at this.
Scott: it is quite fascinating even if you don't care about ice hockey.
Rym: oh, interesting, it's funny, just looking at data like this, the things that just stood out to me are one, the Rangers actually are the leaders in boarding for some reason.
Rym: like they board people more I mean, you're adding up a whole decade, which is like, you know yeah, yeah in the meta moment still stuck at home, like I don't know what to say we're reading the tale of Genji again though it's happening.
Scott: yep I read some more.
Scott: last night some stuff happened, someone died which is, you know, it's like yeah, there's a lot of characters and it's a huge book.
Scott: that's not a spoiler.
Rym: yep, more characters will die.
Scott: the tale of Genji is the first novel ever written by human beings, ever.
Scott: how could you not read that?
Scott: it's like, have you seen the first movie?
Scott: you know, have you watched the first animation ever, I hope you have, right it's pretty short you know, it's like, if there's a first have you played the first video game?
Scott: right, probably, right space war, what, right, something like that?
Scott: yeah, space war pong, depending on yeah, depending on your definition or whatever, but it's like, if there's a first of something, I feel like okay, I'll read, if I'm gonna live this life as a human being I will read the first book.
Scott: I will do that, and I'm doing it now.
Rym: yep, and it's getting warm, I can do the thing that I thought I would do, where since I'm still stuck and I can't get the vaccine for a while I might just go bike out to a park and sit out in the middle of nowhere and read for a little bit, under the sun.
Rym: yep, because it was like 70 degrees today in New York.
Rym: actually, the high was 69, nice it was a little bit cold today, but still I opened the window I went out and ran shorts and a t-shirt.
Rym: okay, I think this weekend I'm gonna do a long bike ride.
Scott: we'll see, it'll be like it's gonna get colder, it's getting colder.
Scott: this is a temporary deal.
Rym: so, way back in the year of our Lord 2012 we did an episode of GeekNights called Seasons but in that case, not my Lord we reviewed a board game called Seasons.
Rym: we did another show which was more fascinating.
Rym: oh, when did we do this one?
Rym: We did this one in it's important the month, June of 2007 called Gaming Season and the episode description is tonight.
Rym: on GeekNights, we talk about why we're not playing any video games.
Rym: I actually went back, before the show we were looking at what was going on in 2007, that was basically like the literal rock bottom of PC gaming like, that was before, like Team Fortress 2 came out a couple months after we did this episode.
Rym: so, this was the era where like, I don't think either one of us was running Windows, like we both had Linux on the desktop, I bought that Mac.
Rym: like, we were not playing video games, like we were between consoles and like, the Wii had come out yet.
Rym: so we were like, past a generation of consoles, new generations hadn't come out.
Rym: we were never on board with like the Playstation 2, Xbox era.
Scott: so, we were playing Xbox 360, that was later than that.
Rym: I also had an Xbox 360.
Rym: I played Street Fighter on it, and then eventually I sold it to a co-worker.
Scott: I played a few things on it.
Rym: I think, Shadow Complex?
Rym: Or was that on the GameCube?
Scott: Yeah, that was Shadow Complex.
Rym: That was Shadow Complex.
Scott: So yeah,
Rym: but it was interesting, because looking at that old episode, I was thinking about seasons and seasonality of our lives because something we've complained about a lot as we left school, was that in our lives up until college and like, right at the end of college the seasons radically changed our life, like fall, go back to school, summer, summer vacation like, there was a.
Scott: there were two winter and I guess winter was always a holiday season but that's still true.
Scott: but basically fall through spring, it was pretty much either school or not school.
Scott: it wasn't like, you know that much of a deal, to go from winter to spring.
Rym: I guess winter to spring, for me, was always like, ok, it's starting to get warmer out but more importantly, summer's coming and school will end all of spring, I would just be thinking here comes summer vacation.
Scott: sure, the point is once you have a job, right in the adult world, it's like doesn't matter what freaking season it is your daily life routine doesn't change, right you might have things on your schedule throughout the year based on your life, right like we have packs on the schedule or we did, you know.
Rym: but for the most part it doesn't matter if it's 90 degrees summer like today, it was 70 degrees all day and beautiful, guess what I was doing sitting at my desk, working all day.
Rym: yeah, when it was freezing cold two weeks ago or whatever it was, sitting at my desk, working all day yup, but I was thinking about that in the context of my life still actually does have a lot of seasonality.
Rym: I'm gonna discard the COVID era, because this was a weird.
Rym: this was COVID season but the rest of my life and I'm curious I'll never forget that one time I saw
Scott: a ghost one time I saw a virus
Rym: but I was thinking about it and I realized that there is a lot of seasonality to my life still as an adult and it's actually gotten more defined as I've gotten older.
Rym: but it's not tied to the weather seasons anymore, but it's still there, there is still a seasonality.
Rym: but it doesn't help that the weather seasons have gotten all fucked the fuck up they have, and this is not, we talked about this on GeekNights, officially in terms of how the seasons work New York City is subtropical.
Rym: we live in a subtropical zone.
Rym: this is not a temperate zone.
Rym: we don't have four seasons like you think, because especially American listeners and a lot of European listeners spring, summer, winter, fall you realize a lot of places on Earth don't have those four seasons, like weather patterns are different.
Scott: they've got rainy season and not rainy season.
Rym: yep, or like Singapore has the hot rainy season and the windy rain, like there's two different kinds of rainy season that happen and New York is not like that.
Rym: we don't have four seasons.
Rym: spring is a weird almost vestigial season in New York now, there's like a rainy summer and a non-rainy summer are like our seasons now.
Rym: but I was just thinking about this a lot and I've realized that my life seasonality is actually pretty well defined, but it's defined by all these different clocks and not the weather anymore but the only seasonal weather clock that I still have.
Rym: and I've realized this happened to me by accident, when I was a kid.
Rym: my parents would always talk about spring cleaning.
Rym: "Oh it's spring, we're gonna do spring cleaning".
Rym: and I just ignored that, but my parents would be all busy and they would do all these things every year, like as soon as they got a warm enough to open the windows "I wonder where that term came from, we're gonna do some Google".
Rym: Gotta look that up?
Rym: Cause my impression of it was always "If
Scott: my feeling is that people do spring cleaning because of the phrase spring, like because you know the phrase you feel like that's the time that you should do some cleaning, and I'm gonna read the history on Wikipedia, which any listener could just do themselves and stop listening right now".
Rym: Some researchers trace the origin to the Iranian normas the Persian New Year which falls in the first day of spring.
Scott: another possibility relates to Passover "Yup, cause you gotta clean all the bread out".
Rym: Cause I grew up in Michigan, spring cleaning was definitely a thing, like all the parents would do it, but I think part of it was, it was so cold in the winter, cause you know we're in Michigan like winter's real cold, as soon as it was
Scott: warm enough
Rym: to be in the garage with the garage door open and open the windows and like go outside.
Rym: there's a lot of cleaning that we didn't do during the winter because it was cold, like we didn't take rugs outside and beat them, the rugs just stayed dusty all winter and in the spring, you take them outside.
Scott: It does say here that before they had a vacuum cleaner, March was the best time for dusting because you could open the windows like you just said, but not warm enough for insects to come in and the high wind would help.
Scott: and also, it was warm enough you wouldn't have to run your coal furnace and fill your house with soot.
Rym: So I wonder if it came out of that era and persisted as a cultural tradition as many of those factors were no longer present.
Scott: Yeah, I've never done, I've never followed the spring cleaning, not that I've.
Scott: I'm not saying, there are definitely times of the, you know, where I will say "Okay, it's time, and I'll do an extra cleaning".
Rym: right, like I'll super clean stuff I'll clean the windows Those aren't tied to spring, that's just like it's time to bleach the bathroom.
Scott: Right, I just do it like, when it's time I'll do this big clean but it's not necessarily spring.
Scott: I've done it, I'm sure I've done it, it's spring at least once, but like, you know, other times I will, you know, do different cleans.
Rym: So when I think back, yeah the things that my parents would do big cleans about were mostly things that required the garage door to be open like cleaning out the garage.
Rym: the garage basically didn't get touched all winter.
Rym: no one went in there, it was cold.
Rym: as soon as it's spring, and you can be in the garage comfortably, we would like clean the garage out, and deal with all the mess we made all winter, and that kind of thing.
Rym: and in my adult life now, living in New York I think there is a big difference between people who live in houses and people who live in apartments in this regard too, because the seasons don't change what we can do to our apartments as much as they change what we can do to our houses.
Scott: That's true, that's true.
Rym: But, I have taken up a lot of sports.
Rym: If you have a house, right?
Scott: Yeah, if you have a house, and suddenly it's warm out you can do like a gardening and there's all these things you can do with how you can fill your pool.
Rym: if you got a pool, there's a lot of money.
Rym: There's like house chores that appear There's chores
Scott: There's chores, but there's also things that you could just you know, not tasks even but just like, things you can do that you couldn't do when it was cold because if you got an apartment it's like the things that you can do pretty much the same.
Scott: There's one thing, I can go out on my balcony in the spring and summer, but I can't really do that in the winter Right, but it's like you can, you know and there's other things that you can do just sort of replace each other, right?
Scott: So it's like in the summer you can go to the beach and in the not summer you can go to the hockey game.
Scott: it's like, okay, but other stuff, it's just like, it doesn't matter.
Scott: you can do X and it's cold you can do X and it's warm, but it's the same X.
Rym: Yup, but one thing the main seasonality I find in my life is more around, what is the set of activities that consume my not like day to day life, but like week to week life?
Rym: but hockey season isn't like just winter because hockey season kind of gets long and weird and COVID also made it weird.
Rym: like there's a season of.
Rym: I go to a hockey game semi-regularly and I put hockey on like kind of regularly when I'm around the house, like there's hockey season and non-hockey season.
Rym: and the fact that hockey is there sort of informs how my life goes, like dirt when hockey is a thing many nights we'll cook dinner and have the hockey game on kind of while we eat dinner, maybe I'll watch the whole game, maybe I'll go play Overwatch.
Rym: but if I'm playing Overwatch, the hockey game's like on, on the other monitor I'm kind of paying attention to it and I notice it's lack when it's not hockey season
Scott: It is biking season and it is not biking season, some people that season doesn't end, they just bike no matter what.
Rym: I got a co-worker who like pre-COVID he bikes to work from further away than you would expect is reasonable no matter what I think I determined like 12.
Scott: yeah I think I determined that like 12 miles would be my absolute limit for a commute.
Scott: right, daily but I can't do weather that's too cold or any precipitation whatsoever.
Scott: I've been caught in the rain a couple of times, but if I see that it's raining I'm not going on purpose, right?
Rym: And my old job I used to, because I could show up to the office looking like a dead rat, it'd be fine.
Rym: but I can't really get away with that with my current job.
Scott: I was always caught in the rain on the way home, I was never caught on the way to work.
Rym: I biked home once from work and I got caught.
Rym: I thought I could beat the rain home.
Rym: the rain that came down on me, on the Williamsburg bridge was like, legendarily strong.
Scott: I've been hit, I think twice by the legendarily strong on the way home.
Rym: The point is I stopped biking because I couldn't see far enough ahead of myself and just stood there.
Scott: the point is that in the winter it's like in the summer.
Scott: I'm just checking for rain.
Scott: it's still biking season, in the winter it will never be a bike to work day in the winter even if it doesn't snow it's too cold.
Rym: so the seasons in our lives right now are things like that, like are there outdoor activities I can or can't do?
Rym: like I ski in the winter, I can't ski any other time.
Rym: I structure my life around skiing during ski season because it's something I can only do during this very limited window.
Rym: I don't structure my life as much around biking because I have a much longer bike season, it's like mid spring to late fall.
Rym: I can bike almost as much as I want.
Scott: Yeah I don't structure around the biking, you know the biking would just like fill in gaps.
Scott: I'm not doing anything this weekend, I guess we're going biking and or beaching.
Rym: Yup, but like in the winter it's like okay, there are only so many weekends I can ski.
Rym: I'm gonna ski every single weekend I can unless something gets in the way and I structure things around it like multiple PAX Souths, I would go to PAX South and then remember I would like fly home kinda early Sunday to get to a ski trip.
Rym: but living in an apartment added an extra weird seasonality to that that I never had to deal with because as a kid we lived in a house and in Beacon we had a house.
Rym: I don't have a lot of room for stuff.
Rym: so, nope I will store things some things I have to store in a way that I can get to them easily, like during biking season.
Rym: all my bike shit has to be like readily available, it can't be like buried under the bed behind suitcases.
Scott: Yeah it's like.
Scott: it'll take you if you decide to bike and you're gonna have to either the night before or the morning of dig a whole bunch of shit out.
Scott: it's like a huge pain in the butt and that'll probably.
Scott: that might even, just the difficulty of that will probably prevent you from biking like.
Scott: you will bike less whatever your hobby is, right if the stuff you have to do the thing is like not out like.
Scott: imagine if I had to tear down and put away all the podcast shit and then set it all up again.
Scott: I would podcast a lot less.
Rym: Why do you think we're doing a lot less video during COVID?
Rym: We have to put a lot of shit together to do a video, like way more.
Scott: If your shit is just set up and ready to go all the time you will do the thing, whatever it is more, so if there is a thing you do seasonally such as biking or skiing whatever that stuff is when the season starts set up the stuff and find a way to have it out and ready and available and then when the season ends put it into the deep sleep, right so it's out of the way and you make room for some other stuff and that way you will do the seasonal thing more than you otherwise would have.
Scott: and it's just basics, like hey your bathing suits are in a thing under the bed, now they're in with the rest of the shorts where the pants go and the jeans are under the bed you know, simple stuff like that.
Rym: so right now, ski season basically is over now, it's like literally 50 or 60 degrees up at even the nearest mountain I could get to.
Rym: so
Scott: ski season, done at least here it is, you can go to the other half of the world the bottom half, yeah,
Rym: and if it wasn't Covid
Scott: or the top half, depending on your point of view I might,
Rym: can't now, but yeah basically when ski season ends, now that I live in an apartment I really took for granted the fact that my family had a basement and a garage for basically my entire life, so if we wanted to go skiing.
Rym: I went into the basement, got my skis and they stayed in the same place year round, there's no reason to move them.
Rym: now, like, ski season ends, I have to Tetris all this ski shit that barely fits into my apartment like into the deepest corners of the apartment, as far and deep as possible, because I literally can't use them again until next year, so I can then bring out from those deepest crevices all the things I'm going to use in the summer.
Rym: and I do this like, there's three points in the year where I have to like shift all this crap around.
Rym: in the apartment.
Scott: you could get a mini storage thing but I've never done that because that's again, that would be really it would be great to have because the stuff just wouldn't be in my apartment at all, so my apartment would have like all this extra space in it and like you know, that would be so great and I wouldn't even if I was stupid and ended up, you know, feeling like I had all this empty space and I bought more shit, that shit would also go into the storage
Rym: facility
Scott: right?
Scott: So it's like it would free up space in the apartment and it would be nice, assuming you can afford the cost of it, but I imagine the difficulty of moving, you know it's like digging stuff out of the closet and putting stuff back in the closet, moving stuff from your apartment to another location back and forth once or even just twice a year.
Scott: just the hassle of that, just losing two days every year basically of having to, you know put stuff in and take stuff out, assuming I can only, I only do it twice, two times, it's like if there's something that I can afford to just not have for half the year and have it be in another place entirely, I can afford to throw that thing out,
Rym: just in
Scott: the garbage, right?
Scott: So that's why I do not, and I probably won't have some sort of storage place unless they open up like a mini store, like literally next door or across the street or something like that.
Rym: Yup, the problem is those tend to be way too expensive.
Scott: Yeah, but if that happened, it would be, it might be considered, but you know, cause the cost of going to it would be significantly lowered, but that has not happened, so no.
Rym: The other thing I was thinking about is, you know, that gaming season episode are in, like we'll have, like we will suddenly get into a certain kind of game and play that kind of game a lot for a long period of time and then like that'll ebb and flow and a different game will come in, we'll have like seasons of we're playing a lot of tabletop, playing a lot of RPGs, playing a lot of online games.
Rym: for some reason.
Rym: COVID time made a special season of a lot of async games.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, it's like when you have, there's some people who have only one or a few you know, really focused interests that they're big into that thing and not into other things.
Rym: Then their seasons become like it's Magic Tournament season, it's not Magic Tournament season.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: But it's like they're doing, that's the thing that they do, right?
Scott: Or the handful of things that they do.
Scott: People like us, there's so many things that I do, and they're constantly waxing and waning relative to each other, right?
Scott: I haven't really done a lot of baking recently.
Scott: I haven't, you know, maybe like six months since I like baked maybe something like that.
Scott: Photography I haven't done in like a year plus, right?
Scott: Because I'm not really, you know, I see other people who are like taking photos in their house or going out anyway and neither of those interest me, so.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But I'll probably explode on that front as soon as I can safely go outside, right?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And you know, just all the different hobbies, it's like, you know, someone like you'll have Gundams and it's like you'll go and you'll build like five Gundams in a row and then you won't build another one for months.
Scott: You know, it's just, it's a seasonal interest changes.
Scott: Right now, I'm watching a lot of anime suddenly.
Scott: I haven't watched it before.
Scott: Before, like a few weeks ago, I wasn't watching any anime for like months.
Rym: Yeah, and lately there's been a lot of part of it, sometimes it's because like there'll be more media of a certain type.
Rym: Sometimes it's just like that clock rings and it's time, but same.
Rym: I'm watching a lot of anime lately too and it's not like.
Rym: some of the shows I'm watching are a couple of years old.
Rym: It's not like ah, particularly good season of anime.
Rym: It was like, you know what?
Rym: I like anime.
Rym: I haven't watched a lot of anime recently.
Rym: What anime is out there?
Rym: that's good.
Rym: and suddenly watching a ton of anime?
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: You watch one and you're like, right, I remember.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: There was an era at RIT where I stopped, when I became president of the anime club, like when I had a lot more responsibilities on the eboard, I watched a lot less anime for like a year and a half, like the lead up to that.
Rym: And there was an era where like, I didn't like any of the shows that were coming out.
Rym: Like I'd watch them out of obligation, because I had to be able to speak to them and know about them and stuff, but like I didn't really like, I'd watch an episode of Scried, didn't really give a fuck about the next episode, but I'd watch it just because.
Rym: But like, then like, I'll watch it.
Rym: like recently, like I watched an episode of The Great Pretender, and that the anime gland in my body suddenly perked up and said, "Whoa, whoa, whoa, you should watch the second episode of that right now.
Rym: Don't wait.
Scott: Don't miss
Scott: it.".
Scott: If you keep doing that, and watching tons and tons of anime, eventually it'll just be like, "All right, I had enough of
Scott: that.".
Scott: Not consciously, but just like naturally, you'll move on to a different thing.
Scott: We'll be like, "All right, I remember that thing," and you'll start doing that other thing that you forgot about, and then you will just naturally take away the anime watching time from, you know.
Rym: Yep, it's almost like you have a stacked rank priority list of things, but they'll cluster together.
Rym: But one seasonality that changed a lot for us is convention season, because it used to be.
Scott: Well, conventions used to be a summer thing, yeah.
Scott: All the conventions, you know, San Diego Comic-Con, Otakon, these conventions were intentionally scheduling themselves in the summer, historically speaking, and their logic was sound, which was, "We will hold our convention in the summer when a lot of people are, especially students, are not working and have no obligations, and the weather is good, and people will come on vacation to our place.
Scott: You know, we can get, for example, summer camps could take field trips to our convention, things of that nature, and that will just be really great for our business.
Scott: If we hold our convention at another time of the year, less people will come, we risk shitty weather, right, and we'll make less money.
Scott: So conventions were all in the summer.
Scott: And then other conventions were like, "You know what, we can't be competing with these big boys in the summer.
Scott: Let's have our convention and not the summer, right, because we'll just lose to the big
Scott: conventions.".
Rym: Yeah, like the magfest over near New Year's.
Scott: Right, and so it's like now, and those conventions were somehow pulling it off, right?
Scott: Enough people were going regardless of the time of year, and they were making it work.
Scott: So that trend of all conventions in summer sort of ended, and there are just conventions all times of year, and your convention season ends up then being determined by which conventions you choose to go to and not go to.
Rym: As we backed away from anime conventions, and like basically everything but PAX and Magfest, because of how PAX and video game type stuff is clustered and board game type stuff, our convention season went from summer to all year to September through March.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much like it was almost like school season, right?
Scott: It's like you'd kick off PAX in Labor Day, like school starting, then there'd be more PAXes.
Scott: You know, PAXOS we only went to barely, but PAX Unplugged is now November times, and then you got South January, Magfest January.
Rym: Yep, PAX East would kind of like end it.
Scott: Yeah, East is usually in the spring, and then it's like, okay, summer, spring, summer break, no conventions till PAX West again, and they'd all be clustered into that school time of fall through early spring, and then summer, you know, nothing.
Rym: And it made me notice something, because whenever there's a seasonality like that in my life that persists over enough years, other things start to get attached to it, like it accumulates traditions and it accumulates expectations.
Rym: I would start to think of PAX West as the end of summer, specifically.
Rym: Flying to Seattle is the ritual that marks the end of summer.
Rym: The pre-Pax board gaming and dinner was like this moment that would loom large in my vision toward late summer.
Rym: I'd be thinking, well, summer's ending, that sucks, but, and I'd imagine sitting in the pre-Pax gaming hanging out, playing a quartermaster general before PAX starts.
Scott: Right, but it's like I'd get there and be like, well, I guess I'm not going to the beach anymore this year.
Scott: I guess, you know, biking's probably not too much more this year.
Scott: It's PAX time, hooray, but, you know, this other stuff is over, I guess, until next time.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So, I think that killed enough time, we actually did kind of a long episode, so I'll just stop right there.
Rym: I'm hungry, thanks to you talking about dim sum.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this particular episode of GeekNights, because I record this every goddamn time, it's currently March 11th.
Rym: Ellen Joyce, Hug Me Nick, Link Iggy, Dread Lou, Tenebrae, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Graham Finch, Just Like a Dude Guy.
Rym: Now go through the last year or so of podcasts and make Rym sing.
Rym: Wren from New Zealand, ReviewMadBull34, Cowards, Ryan Perrin, Shervin Von Horl.
Rym: You hold the key to my heart and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: Stay tuned for actually some Patreon exclusive content that's going to start appearing as I walk through production, pre-production and post-production processes and other cool things that I'm working on.
Rym: Utena still kind of working on it, but honestly, that's probably not going to really start up until after COVID when Scott and I can do it in the same room together.
Rym: But for now, I will leave you with...
Scott: Help!
Scott: The human's about to escape!
Scott: Get your paws off me, you dirty ape!
Scott: He can talk!
Rym: He can talk!
Scott: I can say Help me, Dr.
Scott: Zaius!
Scott: Dr.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: Zaius!
Scott: Dr.
Scott: Zaius!
Rym: Dr.
Rym: Zaius!
Scott: Dr.
Scott: Zaius!
Scott: What's wrong with me?
Scott: I think you're crazy.
Rym: Want a second opinion?
Rym: You're all so lazy.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: Zaius!
Scott: Dr.
Scott: Zaius!
Rym: Zaius!
Rym: Dr.
Scott: Dr.
Scott: Zaius!
Scott: Can I play the piano anymore?
Rym: Of course you can!
Scott: Well, I couldn't before.