Rym: It's Tuesday, October 26th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we are talking about Splitgate, its portal, and an FPS.
Rym: Deathmatch-y game.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, right around the beginning of quarantine, when we had to record GeekNights remotely, like fully remotely, as opposed to doing it in person, I didn't have like all the kind of equipment I needed, so I kind of just made do, but I eventually bought that backdrop and I got better lighting and I could sort of set everything up to do this pretty permanently.
Rym: One of the things I bought way back then was the shittiest possible LED USB powered ring light, like the $8 one that was just on Amazon.
Scott: That's what I got right here.
Scott: that's making my face look like, you know, the white sun.
Rym: That's what I got pointing at me right here.
Rym: I used to use it over the webcam, but over time I moved it to the side because I rearranged the lighting.
Scott: Mine has a thing for the webcam to go in the middle of it, so it's actually ring lighting properly.
Rym: Mine has that too, but I sit far enough away from my webcam and I'm lit from different angles anyway to where it's kind of moot.
Rym: So I moved it to the side to be like the spotlight.
Scott: It's also, you know, the sun, the earth is tilting backwards to the incorrect position, so it's getting dark now.
Scott: Whereas normally it would not be dark right now.
Rym: Oh, if it weren't for the rainstorm and everything, I often have to worry about.
Rym: the sun comes directly in about three quarters of the way through GeekNights.
Scott: Because of the time of year, also with my south facing window, it's like late in the day if it's not cloudy.
Scott: This is the time of year where the sun just comes right in the window.
Scott: It's like, ah, why don't you, if you're going to shoot me in the face with your bright lights, the part of you that I hate, at least make it warm, the part of you that I enjoy.
Scott: Nope, cold and sun in your face.
Scott: That's the worst convo.
Rym: So today, that ring light, the switch mechanism that controls all of its options just broke and it stuck permanently on.
Scott: Can't you just unplug it and plug it in?
Rym: Oh yeah, I can unplug it and plug it in, but because I was using that little control box, I actually have the USB.
Rym: It's not plugged into my computer because I'm just powering it.
Rym: It's actually run all the way down behind my desk and plugged into my power strip because my power strip, which is mounted to my desk, has a line of USB power slots.
Scott: Actually, so the outlets in this apartment, like a handful of them have USB in the outlet and I tested it and they totally work.
Scott: And there's two of them happen to be behind my desk and the ring light is one of the only things to use those because I don't trust them that much.
Rym: Yeah, so I bought power strips that I can actually screw them to the bottom of my desk so I can keep all the cables out of the way.
Scott: I got the cage thingy.
Rym: I'm gonna get a cage too, I think.
Rym: Anyway, so right now, all day, this ring light's been permanently on unless I climb back there and unplug it.
Rym: So I just ordered a new, much better solution.
Rym: I'm just gonna throw this thing away because it's falling apart in other ways too.
Rym: The clamp is starting to not clamp that well.
Rym: The clamps.
Rym: Yeah, these clamps that I've been using to clamp this ring light for two years.
Scott: That clamp?
Rym: So in some news that I was about to say only Rym cares about, but apparently other people care.
Rym: Advanced Wars, the coming remake, which remember is counting US releases because there's a bunch of Advanced Wars in Japan that honestly we do not need here in the US.
Rym: They are categorically inferior to the Advanced Wars.
Scott: I've tried to play a lot of those Famicom Wars, Game Boy Wars.
Rym: They're just not as good.
Scott: Using my emulation and such, and pretty much anything older than Advanced Wars 1, it's like you really don't need to play it.
Rym: Imagine a game that's just less fun and less polished.
Scott: It's a turn-based game, but you don't need to play it.
Rym: If you want to play what those old ones are like, play, oh god, what was it called, Desert Commander or something on the NES?
Scott: It's basically the same series, I think.
Rym: So anyway, this is Advanced Wars 1 and 2, which were the first two Advanced Wars that we got in the US for real.
Rym: And they were both fantastic games that are very different from each other, but neither one replaces the other.
Rym: They are both good on their own, and they're both worth playing independently of each other.
Rym: They were getting this remake, they're being remastered and remade just to work on the Switch.
Rym: That whole project is delayed.
Rym: They're launching in Q2 2022 now.
Rym: It's probably good, because I actually plan to stream these games heavily.
Rym: I even set up the pipeline and the video capture to do it from the Switch.
Rym: But I don't really have time for that shit right now, so it's kind of good that I got some delay before I start streaming these games.
Scott: So apparently Desert Commander in Japan, known as Desert Fox Tanks Colon Tank Strategy, does look a lot like Famicom Wars.
Scott: However, it is not in the same series as Famicom Wars and not made by the same company or anything.
Rym: What's fascinating is they're almost identical games, but what I would say is that that game feels very similar to the first two Game Boy Advance Wars.
Rym: that never made it to the US, just in how they play and the kinds of strategies you employ.
Rym: All of them had super broken APCs.
Rym: But yeah, this game's just delayed significantly, and like I said, I'm pretty fine with that.
Scott: Oh, so there was a Super Famicom Wars for the SNES that might be worth playing.
Scott: That one.
Rym: Ooh, I've never tried that one.
Rym: I tried the Game Boy ones and a couple other ones.
Rym: I've never played one that was SNES.
Rym: Now I'm a little curious.
Rym: So anyway, some other slightly bigger news.
Rym: As you know, Activision Blizzard is a troubled company filled with a significant number of dangerous people.
Rym: We've talked about this.
Rym: You can read about it.
Rym: Activision Blizzard is not unique in this regard.
Rym: Very similar stories have happened about Ubisoft, and pretty much every AAA studio has stories like this, though Blizzard and Ubisoft seem to have the most egregious of them that we know of, that I'm remembering recently.
Rym: The bar's low, is what I'm saying, for AAA studios.
Rym: So in that backdrop, despite the fact that Blizzard stock is way up because Call of Duty is selling fine and none of this stuff seems to have impacted game sales at all, they are canceling BlizzCon completely.
Rym: They issued a statement saying that there's no future date planned, they're not rescheduling it, it's just cancelled, and they're going to reinvent what BlizzCon is before it returns.
Scott: Well, I mean, that's not a surprise, because what was BlizzCon, right?
Scott: BlizzCon was just a very few things, right?
Scott: It was an esports event, right?
Scott: And a lot of their esports action has taken a hit, and even when their drama was barely starting, a lot of the people that were getting laid off there were esports people.
Rym: Or people were just quitting who were the ones who were instrumental in the success of their esports up to that point.
Scott: So other than Overwatch League, it really feels like that esports as a whole over there has sort of been neglected.
Scott: It's not like they're not doing it anymore, but they used to be all in on it, and they've been less so as time has gone on.
Rym: I have anecdotal, now full disclosure, this is an anecdotal of one person and my very limited feed, but what I can say is that in my media feeds over the last year or so, how often Hearthstone was talked about went from this baseline level of there'd be some chatter on a nearly daily basis to "I never see anyone talking about Hearthstone
Rym: anymore.".
Scott: That's because I was playing it, and then I stopped playing it, and that's why the amount you heard about it went down.
Rym: But you were not the only person I followed who would talk about Hearthstone, to be clear.
Rym: But I do think that is a factor.
Scott: That's probably the most significant factor.
Scott: So the other thing BlizzCon is for is for basically announcing your shit with your panels, right?
Scott: But A, the only thing they got coming is Diablo 4.
Scott: B, they just relaunched a bunch of stuff, because Activision Blizzard is one big umbrella, Losing so many people, a lot of their stuff is getting delayed, not coming, so they don't have as much to announce.
Scott: And a lot of the people who are probably involved in the running of BlizzCon, it's losing people disrupted, probably, the event itself.
Scott: So it's like, why spend all the money to have this thing, plus pandemic's not over, even if it's online only.
Scott: There's no purpose to this event.
Scott: Let's not spend our money on nothing and come back if we're going to have a convention.
Scott: Not every company has their own convention.
Scott: There's no UbisoftCon.
Scott: that I'm aware of.
Rym: A lot of companies have a game-specific event, usually because of esports, or because it's a very, very well-known property.
Scott: I guess QuakeCon, does that still exist?
Rym: I assume so.
Rym: I mean, I only go to PAXes and MagFests, so what do I know?
Scott: I don't know anything.
Rym: Or they'll either use existing generic gaming conferences, they'll have a game-specific thing usually around an esport, but the franchise company-type event?
Rym: I feel like the Nintendo Direct is how you do that in the modern world, or the Tim Apple Roadshow is how you do that in the modern world.
Scott: Yeah, Blizzard, to my knowledge, I've never seen them do that, so they could just have an Activision Blizzard Direct equivalent where they come out with a fancy keynote-type video every once in a while to announce their new shit on a regular basis.
Scott: And that marketing strategy seems to work, actually.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: I actually kind of like that marketing strategy, even though I hate ads, because it's not an ad that comes and interrupts you.
Scott: It's not an ad that's on something.
Rym: Well, it's an ad that I seek out.
Rym: I go to Tim Apple and I say, "Tim, tell me about your
Rym: shit.".
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: It's an ad, but there's in no way intrudes into your life in any way unless you purposefully go to watch it.
Scott: They don't try to shove it at you in any way.
Scott: And as an ad, it's not like a car ad.
Scott: that's trying to use psychology and repetition and all the advertising marketing techniques to get in your head.
Scott: All of those, right?
Scott: The Apple ones, with their magical, life-changing "get an Apple Watch so you don't die" stuff, they do a little bit of that.
Rym: At least I'm there like, "Yes, I do want to know what's up with Apple.
Rym: Sell it to
Rym: me.".
Scott: But yeah, it's mostly just, "Here are our new products.
Scott: Here's what they do.
Scott: You didn't even have to watch this.
Scott: You could have just read an article summary afterwards.
Scott: The end.
Scott: And we're going to do this again when we have more products to announce.
Scott: And if you don't care about our products, you wouldn't be even watching this right now in the first
Scott: place.".
Scott: So it's like, if you're a company, and even if I had my way, "Ban all ads on Earth,".
Scott: companies still need to announce their products somehow.
Scott: If you make something, you need to tell everyone, "Hey, I made this thing.
Scott: It's for
Scott: sale.".
Rym: But you know what this is?
Rym: This is one hand.
Rym: Old-style advertising that was in the early days before people did it.
Rym: the way they do it today, it was often just, "Here's a product.
Rym: It almost reads like a press release.
Rym: Here are all of its features.
Rym: Here's its price.
Rym: Here's how to find out
Rym: more.".
Scott: A Nintendo Direct is literally just like, "Here are the games coming out soon.
Scott: Let us show you them.
Scott: This one.
Scott: Also this one.
Scott: Check out this
Scott: one.".
Rym: But I think another thing that happens here, especially with an event like BlizzCon, gaming events like this tend to, once they get going, it's hard to start a new one, but once you've got one going, momentum almost can carry it forward with surprisingly little surprise or additional costs.
Rym: The incremental cost of making another PAX or another BlizzCon is so little compared to the cost of making the first one that it's easy to just keep going.
Scott: Once you have attendance, getting the attendance is hard, but once you have attendance, let's say you get an event and a thousand people show up, you have close to a thousand people who, if you have that event again next year, will show up.
Rym: It can't just be the attendance.
Rym: You also have the production pipeline, the system and bureaucracy that causes the event to actually occur.
Rym: Because some events have attendance and not logistics, and that is how you get a DashCon.
Scott: We talk about that all the time with anything that you want to do in the world.
Scott: You can do a thing by hand and handcraft a thing, but then that's it.
Scott: You did it once.
Scott: Alternatively, you can create a machine that makes the thing.
Scott: If you build a machine that runs a convention, that convention is just going to keep happening.
Scott: If you, on your own, make a convention happen with your will, you might do it.
Scott: You can't repeat that without hurting yourself.
Rym: In fact, we low-key would hurt ourselves dealing with the lack of logistics at certain conventions in the past.
Scott: If you want to make a movie, you could grab a camera and your friends sweat blood and tears and make a movie.
Scott: A lot of people have done it.
Scott: But if you make a movie studio, and you get it off the ground, which is the hard part, it'll just keep making movies.
Scott: As long as it makes a successful movie, it'll make another one.
Scott: It'll just keep getting contracts to make more movies.
Rym: It's that very powerful idea that the most valuable thing you can make is the machine that makes the machine, not the machine itself.
Rym: But the other thing that happens is once that ball's rolling, it has that momentum.
Rym: If you want to change something significant about your event, the risks are nearly infinite.
Rym: Imagine if PAX wanted to radically change some aspect of PAX.
Rym: How will the attendees react?
Rym: How will the logistics go?
Rym: Who do we need to involve?
Rym: We have less than a year to make this change because the last PAX just happened.
Scott: But anyway, Blizzard had a machine that made Blizzcons and they intentionally turned it off, at least temporarily, and we'll see what comes of that.
Rym: But it's the perfect time to do that.
Rym: if you're a company and a convention can't survive multiple separate disasters simultaneously.
Rym: There's so many things that make Blizzcon a bad idea.
Rym: It's literally the perfect time to just pause long enough to take that machine and try to rework it.
Rym: So we'll see what comes of it.
Rym: We'll also see what comes of the ongoing litigation around Activision Blizzard.
Rym: And I cannot stress enough, don't pretend that this is the only bad guy company out there, all these AAA game studios.
Scott: Every single one of them is the same, right?
Scott: Is it a company that makes AAA games?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Then I assume it is guilty of all the same crimes as Activision Blizzard.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So got a little, little news here.
Rym: I don't know why this was news, but it popped up in my feed from two different sources.
Rym: So I thought this was funny.
Rym: Multiple sources have confirmed that you can't use, quote, "rumble packs" or other accessories, unquote, with the new Switch-compatible N64 wireless controller.
Scott: That makes no sense, because the N64 wireless controller that you... So just so people are aware of what this is, right?
Scott: So if you get a Switch, you get Joy-Cons, or you can buy a Switch Pro controller, or you can buy a third-party controller, right?
Scott: Those are pretty much your options.
Scott: But if you pay for Nintendo Switch online service, right, you get those NES, SNES, and now if you pay even more, N64 games.
Scott: So they will sell you, if you have the service already, they will sell you an NES controller.
Scott: I have one.
Scott: And it's literally just a wireless NES controller, just like the ones from back in the day, but it works with your Switch with Bluetooth immediately and perfectly, and you can pretty much use it for the NES game thing, right?
Scott: It's not too useful.
Scott: You could try to play a Switch game with it, but it doesn't have enough buttons.
Scott: And they also sell a Super Nintendo one that does the same thing.
Scott: And now they sell an N64 one that does the same thing.
Scott: It's an N64 controller, except it's wireless and works with your Switch.
Scott: It's sold separately.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: Why would you want to use a rumble pack with it when it has rumble built in?
Scott: It's a modern controller.
Scott: It has its own fucking rumble.
Scott: It doesn't need a rumble pack.
Rym: And if you didn't think that was obvious, why would Nintendo in the year 2021 manufacture a new controller that didn't just use a standard rumble pack built into it?
Scott: And why would they bother to go through the hassle of making it compatible with rumble packs from the late 90s when almost no one fucking has one of those things?
Scott: Never mind.
Rym: What the fuck else do you think you're gonna plug into that thing?
Scott: And if it didn't have rumble in it, and it required people to get a rumble pack, and they weren't manufacturing new rumble packs, who the fuck would go- there'd be a run on old rumble packs, who the fuck would go and buy- get those.
Rym: But like what, are you gonna plug- are you gonna plug that like weird memory card into it, thinking you can transfer a save game from the Switch port, and like a real N64?
Rym: Like, what would- what does anyone involved in these stories think was going to happen?
Scott: Someone just asked a really foolish question.
Scott: It's like you know, if you really want to use an N64 controller to play the games on the Switch, the N64 games, go ahead and buy this thing, 'cause that's what it does.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Um, just don't ask nonsense questions.
Rym: I love how.
Rym: the first comment on this article is, "I was hoping to have double
Rym: rumble.".
Scott: Double rumble?
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I could- I could go with that, but if you want double rumble, just get the- the rez, you know, the famous rez thing.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And uh, one last little news, uh, so, the new Switch, the OLED Switch came out, and so far, it seems like outside of Japan, it's not actually selling that well.
Rym: Probably because everyone who wanted a Switch already has a Switch that works fine, is my guess.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, and even so, a lot of people who might buy a Switch, right, will go to the store, look at the Switches, and if you're not like a nerd, what do you care, fucking OLED for extra- it's extra money, right?
Scott: And you can't fucking tell the difference unless you're a huge nerd who knows what OLED is.
Scott: Um, so if you're giving it to a kid, why- why the fuck would you pay for the OLED ones?
Scott: You know, it still doesn't make- the old one is still there.
Scott: So, you know, it's- it- for the OLED, you want to eat into sales of the old one, you need, A, people who broke a Switch, like if my Switch broke, I'd probably buy the OLED one, right?
Scott: But, most people, who knows?
Scott: Or, extreme nerds who care a lot, and use their Switch a lot, and are way into it, will like, upgrade to that new one.
Rym: Yeah, but like, Nintendo's stock was down a little, and a lot of people were saying, "Oh, this is a miss from Nintendo,".
Rym: or like, "Hey, turns out people didn't care about the OLED,".
Rym: and everyone's forgetting.
Rym: They did not- like, Nintendo very clearly did not make this as, like, an upgrade to an existing, perfectly good Switch.
Scott: Right, it's not- it's not a fumble like with the new 3DS, where like, yeah, there were hardly any games, right?
Rym: This is just more like, alright, we're gonna use a better, more modern production pipeline to make an incrementally better product, instead of maintaining the pipeline that made the old one.
Rym: They're probably either saving money, or have better margins, there's a lot of reasons why they manufacture this.
Scott: Hardware has chipped, you know, new chips are out, you know, the world has changed, these parts are cheaper, right?
Scott: It's, you know, let's make this, you know, let's change our stuff at the factory, and we're gonna have to produce Switches differently, for reasons at factories, so now we're producing this Switch instead, hey, let's take advantage of that and market it as an upgraded thing because, yeah, we're using a different screen in there, you know.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: they went out and they said, "Ah, this is our strategy to make more money, we're gonna make this OLED Switch,
Scott: yeah!".
Scott: That wasn't the start of the, right?
Scott: That was the-.
Rym: If anything, I think it speaks to Nintendo's strength, that they are committing to a long lifespan for the extremely popular Nintendo Switch.
Rym: So, anyone who says this is bad news for Nintendo or for Nintendo gamers, is probably the same kind of person who thought that this was gonna be a 4K Switch.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So, this is a video of a match between Peru and Alemanias of Germany, and this is the Balloon World Cup.
Rym: If you've never played the game Balloon, it is one of the rare games, it's a sport, and it's a game and a sport, that has, it's one of the rare instances of having absolutely perfect rules where I would change nothing.
Scott: It is a game where you have two people and everyone just knows the rules as soon as they're born.
Scott: Yeah, like, every kid plays this.
Scott: You don't even need to be told the rules, you just know them.
Rym: In fact, if you watch this video, I defy you to make it more than five.
Rym: let's see, exactly, 'cause including every possible edge case, you will not make it more than three seconds into this video without knowing literally every rule to this game.
Rym: The game is, there's a balloon, not filled with helium, just filled with regular old air, and you hit it.
Rym: If it touches the ground, before your opponent hits it, you win, or you get a point.
Rym: And, you just try to keep this balloon in the air as long as possible.
Scott: This game is- And you alternate taking turns, hitting the balloon, and I don't know what happens if it pops, according to the rules.
Rym: I do also not know what happens if it pops.
Scott: I could look it up, though.
Rym: The rule we used as kids was whoever touched it last loses if it pops.
Scott: Could be.
Scott: Okay, acceptable rule.
Rym: The other rule that might not be super obvious is you can't interfere with the other person.
Scott: It's not a contact sport.
Rym: But you can hit this thing anywhere.
Scott: Yeah, sure.
Rym: So, I would love to see this just straight up be the omega-thon finale.
Scott: I guess you also can't, like, grab the balloon, right?
Scott: You have to strike it.
Rym: Well, I mean, volleyball has rules like that.
Rym: A lot of sports have rules where you can't carry, even tennis, you can't carry the ball in your racket, even though- Basketball pretends to have rules like that.
Scott: I will admit- Soccer does, too.
Rym: I'm gonna admit right now, I have cheated a little bit at ping pong in the past.
Rym: I was real good at doing a carry so fast that no one could see.
Rym: that's what I did.
Rym: I think if you went to real ping pong, you would be- Oh, yeah, they would catch me, but at a bar or something, no one would ever see that.
Scott: Yeah, drunken people, though.
Scott: Would that even help you, though, at ping pong?
Rym: Yeah, because what I can do, especially if it works against someone who's moving slow, is I can basically swing the racket around to catch the ball, push it forward, but while it's still in contact, rotate, and then push it down.
Rym: I basically do a straight, almost a straight down slam.
Rym: that doesn't look like it's gonna be a slam until the last second.
Rym: It's of dubious legality.
Rym: So, what do you got?
Scott: What do I have?
Scott: So, we may have used this YouTube channel before as a thing of the day.
Scott: They have lots of experts in various things and ask them questions, right?
Scott: Or have Twitter come and ask them questions.
Scott: I think there was a CIA guy on there sometime or something, right?
Scott: However, a video appeared, thanks to YouTube recommendations, from this wired tech support channel, and this time, the expert person was a poison expert, and it's like, "Whoa, I'm actually gonna find out for real about
Scott: poison.".
Scott: And, yeah, you find out for real about poison.
Scott: Some of the information is sort of obvious and basic stuff that you know.
Scott: isn't that fascinating, but some of the information is very fascinating.
Scott: And there were also many myths debunked or bunked, I guess would be the opposite term.
Scott: you know, I guess watching this video, you could I guess, you know, if you're very unlucky, this information in this video could help you or someone nearby you survive poisoning.
Scott: Or fall to poisoning.
Scott: Please don't poison anybody for real, but only joke about poisoning people like I do.
Scott: You'll never actually poison anybody.
Rym: Yeah, stay away when a weird girl tries to give you shaved ice as well.
Scott: One spoiler, I guess, is this person did answer one question exactly the same way.
Scott: I would have answered it.
Scott: They were asked, effectively, the question was, "How do I tell the poison mushroom from the real
Scott: mushroom?".
Scott: And my brain started saying, "If it's at the grocery
Scott: store.".
Scott: And then the woman said in the video, "If it's at the grocery store, it's a safe mushroom to eat.
Scott: Otherwise, don't eat
Scott: it.".
Scott: Did I say this
Rym: on GeekNights or just say it to you, but when we were hiking, me and Emily were hiking a few weeks ago, we passed a couple arguing in Russian, and the dude was holding up a big mushroom that he'd clearly picked, and it looked like he was arguing that they could eat it, and the woman was arguing with him that that is a terrible idea and trying to get him to throw it away.
Scott: Do not eat the mushroom.
Scott: Is that mushroom from the grocery store?
Scott: No?
Scott: Should you eat the mushroom?
Scott: Those questions have the same answer at all times.
Rym: There is no, I mean, I'm glad there are people who exist who we trust to do this.
Rym: for grocery stores, because I, there is no amount of research, study, and training I would do where I would personally eat a mushroom I picked under any circumstances.
Scott: Well, the mushrooms, also, the mushrooms at the grocery store are not harvested from the forest, right?
Scott: Some of them are.
Scott: At least, not where you live.
Scott: Not where we're here, right?
Scott: They're from a mushroom growing place that's growing them.
Rym: No!
Rym: A lot more mushrooms than you expect.
Rym: Not like creminis or anything, but like, I get a lot of mushrooms from Fresh Direct and from the grocery store that are foraged.
Scott: Mmm, how do you know?
Rym: They're specifically foraged.
Rym: A lot of mushrooms can't be grown in mushroom groweries.
Rym: I don't know what the term is for that kind of place.
Scott: That doesn't seem possible.
Scott: I could figure out a way.
Rym: There was just a SciShow episode on this like, a few months ago, talking about all the unfarmables that, basically, there are a bunch of foods, many of them are mushrooms.
Rym: You could be infinitely rich if you could figure out how to grow these as opposed to foraging them.
Scott: Just take one that already exists and shit all its spores all over some dirt.
Rym: Oh yeah, guess what?
Rym: Turns out that doesn't work.
Rym: Some of these only grow in a particular kind of tree that's beyond a certain age that only grows in certain soil and weird crap like that.
Scott: So get that tree in that soil and buy that land.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: If it were that easy, a lot of these things would be a lot cheaper, but they're not.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway, I do not trust mushrooms foraged by anyone other than an expert via a large commercial pipeline with lots of liability involved.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Poison is cool.
Scott: Let's move on.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, in the meta moment, the GeekNights Book Club book, which I have paused to read the first volume of a manga.
Rym: Stay tuned.
Rym: But, uh, the tale of Genji, as Genji just continues to sleepwalk and/or fuck his way through life.
Rym: It's the first novel.
Scott: You're gonna say that same thing every time there.
Rym: I mean, unless we talk about specific instances of it, which we should say for the book club book episode.
Scott: Uh, I think what I'm trying to do is I'm trying to basically, you know, as I'm reading, I'm trying to take a note just like, you know, there's what, 50-something chapters.
Scott: I'm basically trying to write, like, one sentence for each chapter.
Rym: That's a real good idea for a book like this.
Rym: Like, that's where the ghost killed a girl.
Rym: That's where he had sex with the wrong woman.
Rym: That's the other time he had sex with the wrong woman.
Scott: That's where so-and-so died.
Scott: That's where a bunch of people died.
Rym: But, uh, yeah, otherwise, our last panel is still just on YouTube.
Rym: It's our game design.
Rym: It'll always be on YouTube, but I guess you should watch it because we spend a lot of time making it.
Rym: Stay tuned for, I guess, Q2 2022 when I'll start streaming Advance Wars.
Rym: And, uh, yeah, we found someone to help us build our website.
Rym: So, if you were thinking about applying to that job, you can hold off for the time being unless things go horribly wrong in the near future.
Scott: I guess that's not impossible, but it doesn't seem likely.
Scott: We're gonna make some progress here.
Scott: I actually, if you go to, you can proof that I've worked on this, right?
Scott: You can go to beta.frontrowcrew.com, and you'll see the words beta.frontrowcrew.com there.
Scott: Uh, which I know isn't exciting, but there is actually a complex, yeah, there is actually a complex back end of technology with databases and such and whatnot behind that single tiny HTML file.
Scott: So, progress has been made.
Rym: Wait, I'm gonna break the law in red states.
Rym: I'm gonna view page source.
Rym: Oh, look at that.
Rym: Some HTML.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And if you go to newsletter.frontrowcrew.com, there is a live, new newsletter platform.
Scott: Uh, I switched us over from tiny letter, and I'll finish writing a newsletter at some point.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: This year?
Rym: Scott writes good newsletters.
Scott: A year?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Never?
Scott: But I just move it over to a new platform and then never use it?
Rym: Hey, but every now and then one comes out.
Rym: They're always good.
Scott: But it's live.
Scott: There's a thing.
Scott: I did that.
Scott: I did something.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That wasn't shit talk.
Scott: I successfully moved it to a new platform, so.
Rym: So, let's get right into it.
Rym: Splitgate is basically a free to play multiplayer first person shooter deathmatch++, because it has a lot of modes, crossed with Portal the game, where you can throw two portals anywhere in the world with constraints and just move between them.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, in Portal the game came out in a long time ago already.
Scott: When that game came out, everyone, the obvious thought was well, obviously.
Scott: 2007.
Rym: GeekNights had been running for less than two years.
Scott: So, the same year that we came out basically.
Scott: So, when that came out, the obvious thought was, oh, obviously, you're going to make a multiplayer FPS, where everyone also has a portal gun and a gun gun.
Scott: That's all I wanted.
Scott: That's such a brain dead thing, right?
Scott: Because Portal and Portal 2 were obviously just puzzle platform FPSs with no gun, no shooting and killing really.
Scott: And they even teased heavily that Half-Life 3 or Half-Life 2 episode 2, 3, whatever it was going to be, 3, I get the episode.
Scott: that never came out.
Scott: It was heavily implied that that would be a single player FPS, where you had a portal gun, presumably also the gravity gun, and gun guns.
Scott: But, of course, that never came to be.
Scott: And probably will never come to be.
Scott: So, this obvious idea for an amazing multiplayer game was just out there for free.
Scott: Anyone could do it at any time.
Scott: I believe there may have been prior attempts to do it.
Scott: But, until now, with the release of Splitgate, no one has, this is like the biggest, most for real attempt there has been.
Scott: It is a multiplayer FPS, where you have the portal gun, and you have gun guns.
Scott: And you shoot the other team.
Rym: Now, part of this might have been that the technology that drove Portal did not scale well to multiple players.
Rym: It was designed...
Scott: It could have been done.
Scott: There had to be a way.
Rym: I think it would have been a significant rewrite to make that happen.
Scott: Regardless...
Rym: The other thing is, Portal, the portals themselves were, while the technology that made that happen were cool, the real magic of Portal was the insane amount of detail that went into the puzzles and the environments to make the portals fun and interesting.
Rym: And, I just imagine the game design challenge of making it that polished for the multiplayer experience, especially a deathmatching multiplayer experience.
Scott: You never need to make it... I think that's the flawed thinking, right?
Scott: Don't let the perfect be the enemy of the good enough, right?
Scott: It's like, you could have just taken fucking Quake Deathmatch, not changed a damn thing, other than, oh yeah, there's a portal gun now in addition to the other guns.
Rym: And then just watch how people play it and see what happens and iterate from there.
Scott: Yeah, just fucking go for it, right?
Scott: It's like, come on.
Rym: I mean, how did Quake Deathmatch evolve?
Rym: They just made it, they threw it out there, and then they iterated on it as people fucked with it and enjoyed it.
Scott: So, Splitgate, what's the deal with Splitgate?
Scott: So, in Splitgate, the portal gun, the most important part, the way it works is you have two different buttons for the two different portals, right?
Scott: Just like regular Portal.
Scott: There are only some surfaces.
Scott: you can put them on, just like regular Portal.
Scott: You can see through the portal to the other side only if it's your portal.
Scott: You can't see through other people's portals, but you can walk through them assuming they're linked up and not just a half portal with no other end to them.
Rym: Yep, like you can throw one of your portals somewhere and then just not throw the other one until you're ready.
Scott: Or someone could erase one end.
Scott: We'll talk about that.
Scott: You can walk through the portal.
Scott: You can shoot through the portal.
Scott: Even if it's not yours, you can shoot through it.
Scott: You might not be able to see what the hell you're shooting on the other side.
Scott: You might be wasting ammo, but you can shoot through it.
Scott: So, for example, you can put one of your portals way high up in the level and put another one in a tiny room where you're hiding and now you can snipe at the whole level from a tiny room and if someone wants to shoot you, they can come find you or they can just shoot in this portal that's prominently above the whole level and that they can see bullets coming out of and killing their friend.
Rym: And that you're probably standing right in front of.
Rym: Your head's just right there.
Scott: Yeah, if they shoot at the portal, they're gonna hit you.
Scott: So, it's not that great.
Scott: It works, but it's not some unbeatable camping strat, right?
Scott: And then, as I mentioned, you can get rid of portals.
Scott: There's a grenade you have and the grenade doesn't hurt anybody, sadly.
Scott: But if you throw a grenade at a portal, whether it's yours or someone else's, it erases it.
Rym: And you can really wing these things.
Rym: You can wing that grenade all across the mat.
Scott: Yeah, kinda.
Scott: A little bit.
Scott: But, you know, it's like if someone's running away from you and there's a portal, they're running towards the portal.
Scott: just throw the grenade, they'll just bump into the wall and then you shoot them, right?
Scott: That kind of thing happens.
Rym: So, this game is pretty fun.
Rym: Like, we've been playing it.
Rym: Not a ton, but we've been playing it.
Rym: And, like Scott said, it's not perfect, but it does what we thought it would do.
Rym: It is an FPS where you're just doing multiplayer competitive with a million different modes with portals.
Scott: But, you have a little jetpack.
Scott: It's not like the tribes jetpack, but it's a little like a double jump.
Scott: It's like double jump plus, right?
Rym: But that's not in every mode either.
Rym: The interesting thing about this game is that it has a million, million, million modes.
Scott: Way more modes.
Scott: I think rather than try to figure out which mode was the best mode, they're just like, let's put in all the modes.
Scott: Let people vote and decide which mode they want to play.
Scott: Well, you know the story behind this game?
Rym: Because I think it's one oh four seven games.
Rym: It's a pretty small shop.
Rym: They made the original game with no funding.
Rym: Just by themselves.
Rym: And then they put a demo out.
Rym: People liked it.
Rym: They announced actually over the summer that it was going to be indefinitely in a beta state.
Rym: And they're basically tweaking it constantly as far as we can see, even now.
Rym: There's a significant update that just happened.
Scott: Definitely feels like it's sort of in that Rocket League category.
Scott: It's obviously not as popular and big as Rocket League.
Scott: And I don't think it's as fresh and amazing as Rocket League.
Scott: So I don't know if it deserves that amount of popularity, but it's that multiplayer competitive game that has some uniqueness and isn't AAA amazingness.
Scott: But if you load it up and start playing it, it's like, wow, this is a really polished kind of game here.
Scott: It's really got something going on.
Rym: I guess it's almost got too much going on.
Rym: that isn't the game itself.
Rym: So this game is a modern game, meaning it has a ton of cosmetic crap.
Rym: It has all these different ways to level up your character and your stats and all this nonsense.
Rym: It has quick play and competitive and a million modes.
Rym: But whereas AAA first person shooters tend to refine those down to a limited number of ladders and a limited number of modes, this is still just a proliferation of a million, million things.
Rym: And two, it is free to play.
Rym: Completely free.
Rym: You can just play it.
Rym: And as far as I can see, there's nothing you have to pay for that matters.
Scott: Yeah, they are not.
Scott: It's not pay to win, so that's good.
Scott: If it was, I wouldn't play it.
Rym: Not at all.
Rym: Wouldn't have even considered touching it.
Scott: But if you want to pay, there are a lot of ways you can give them money.
Scott: I haven't even looked at how many different currencies and different ways you can earn points and XPs and currencies and things.
Scott: And you can spend them on getting skins for your character, for your guns, just all kinds of things that you can skin up all over the place.
Scott: So much cosmetic microtransactions.
Scott: You're just like Team Fortress 2 with the hats, right?
Rym: It got to the point to where I consciously decided I won't even click on that stuff because clicking around it was almost too confusing.
Rym: There's just so much in there.
Scott: Half of the main menu screen, almost all the buttons on there have something to do with rewards or XP or skins or gun skins.
Rym: Oh my god, every time we finish a match, it's like, you got three achievements.
Rym: Here's three different beaters that all filled up.
Scott: Here's four different sets of stats.
Scott: Next, next, next, next, play again.
Scott: I'm ignoring all that biz.
Scott: I kept myself in the default skin.
Scott: I did try to figure out enough just to collect XP rewards.
Scott: because this is the annoying thing about this, is that this XP, obviously, which is like your ranking, how good you are, you're used for matchmaking, and like most games, that's separate from XP.
Scott: you just always get for playing.
Scott: And the XP you always get for playing, it doesn't unlock anything that helps you win, but it does unlock more game modes.
Scott: You can't just load this up for the first time and immediately play a competitive match in certain modes, right?
Scott: You have to play enough and you just get the free XP just by playing, you know, spending money.
Scott: I don't know if you can even buy XP.
Scott: Maybe you can, probably.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But there are certain modes you won't be able to play until you've played enough.
Scott: And then you can play all the modes.
Rym: Game designers, I beg you, stop doing that.
Rym: Just stop it.
Rym: I cannot deal with it.
Rym: Not a fan of that.
Rym: Even Smash was annoying that I had to do something to get all the basic characters.
Scott: Yeah, unlocking all the characters is like, I don't need that.
Rym: You can have your other unlocking like all the other like weird modes where people are going to collect a million me's and hats and things, like sure, whatever, but don't gate core game behind arbitrary leveling and especially not pay to win type stuff.
Scott: Yeah, I recently got to level 10 and I think that that basically unlocked almost all the things for me.
Scott: I can now like choose all the game modes and stuff, which I couldn't do before.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So I think level 10 is where you get everything.
Scott: So and there's another, there is a gotcha thing where like you can get crates or like gift boxes or something and open those up and the skins and shit in there.
Scott: They take so long to open.
Scott: I haven't even tried to open them.
Rym: You have to like do this portal thing for each one that take, it takes minimum like 15 or 20 seconds to open each one.
Scott: Oh, but yeah, I basically just did what you were doing with Overwatch.
Scott: I haven't opened any of them.
Scott: I get them and I don't open them.
Scott: You know, but I mean, I think that that's a common thing that games with loot boxes or crates do because they're trying to emulate the feeling, you know, you get from opening like a pack of baseball cards and like being amazed and, you know, even if you're getting ones you already have, right, it's still this up and down emotional casino-like rollercoaster.
Scott: And while I'd say, so that's why you don't want to make it an instant process, a computer could just instantly do it, right?
Scott: You want to have an animation and a presentation of like you're opening the thing, what's inside?
Scott: First up, this skin.
Scott: Case in point.
Scott: This skin you already have.
Rym: When I did the charity stream.
Scott: A moldy old piece of bubblegum that you're not going to eat.
Rym: When I did that charity stream because you all donated a ton of money to the Democrats and I agreed to open every one of those fucking loot boxes I had in Overwatch live on stream, it took hours and at one point I just left a book propped on my space bar and walked
Scott: away.
Rym: But on one hand it feels like gaming is so saturated with this stuff that it would lose all of its power to the point that if I even see a loot box in any game I almost like, I have this opposite reaction of I don't want to engage with it because I just feel annoyed that it even exists.
Rym: I'm so used to it being everywhere.
Rym: But on the
Scott: other hand if all of gaming, tabletop, video game everything, was only the kind of games that we like competitive skill games there were just the number of people, the size of the gaming industry as a whole would be like this tiny fraction of what it is now.
Rym: We can have lots of fun games in this broad ecosystem that are not that, but they shouldn't have to all have the same fucking addictive gotcha mechanic in them.
Scott: Right, so let's, now that we got that out of the way, let's talk about the actual game, the split game.
Rym: There's too many modes to talk about all of them, but we can talk a lot about.
Scott: I don't even know all the modes because unlock them all.
Scott: So first things.
Rym: first there's a small number of weapons and there doesn't appear to be significant like spread, like it's like it's a lot like older FPS's.
Scott: It doesn't feel like there's spread, it feels very halo-y in terms of the way the weapons work.
Rym: You can just click on heads from across the map and it pretty much just works.
Scott: Yeah, for example, we can't determine whether a sniper rifle is more accurate when you zoom in or zooming in just lets you zoom in.
Rym: I find I was getting more kills and also I was more effective with the sniper rifle if I never zoomed in.
Scott: Because you save the time, sometimes you save the time not having to zoom, but sometimes the guy's really far away.
Scott: So that's, you know, the sniper rifle basically kills in one shot.
Scott: There is, my favorite weapon is the plasma rifle, which is a lot like the one from Doom.
Rym: I like that, the assault rifle, the AR.
Scott: It's okay, it's pretty good.
Scott: There's an SMG that I barely ever get to use.
Scott: There's a nice like three round burst kind of, you know, rifle that you can get.
Rym: Yep, but the fun part about these weapons is they're very old style FPS and it's sort of just like hit scan, like click and it happens, but you have very limited ammo in most modes.
Rym: So you're not just spraying all the time.
Scott: Some of the modes you basically can keep getting more weapons.
Scott: And if you die, you get ammo again and weapons again, so it's not a big deal.
Scott: But if you're not dying a lot, if you're living a long time, then ammo can become a concern because you've fired it all.
Rym: But the way damage works, and again, we're generalizing a lot because every mode has a lot of like very specific changes.
Rym: Some of them are radically different from other modes, but generally, if you get shot, you don't die.
Rym: It's like the modern FPS construct of a cooldown, where you get hit, you get hit, you take damage, and if you take enough damage in a short enough span of time, you die.
Rym: So if you're under fire...
Scott: It doesn't take a lot, right?
Scott: A headshot from a sniper rifle will kill you.
Scott: The assault rifle, okay, digga digga digga digga, you're dead, right?
Rym: But if you like tag someone a couple times from a distance with like the SMG, they might make it to cover before you tag them the last time.
Rym: that actually finishes them off.
Scott: And then they'll get their health back, eventually.
Scott: There's some sort of like automatic, just there's no health packs or anything.
Scott: There's no healing, medkits, bandages.
Scott: It's like if you're not in a fight, if you run away successfully, you know, you go through a portal, use your jetpack, you just get away, your health will just sort of come back, and then you'll be good as new.
Rym: I like this a lot for this game in particular, because if you have a game like Overwatch, like a team-based FPS that's more goal-oriented and more focused, the concept of health that runs out and needs to be refilled is a way to control the ebb and flow of like the game, and like offensive/defensive zones, that kind of thing.
Rym: Old school FPSs would have the health as a, this is a finite resource you have to manage, the more damage you take, the more likely it is to die.
Rym: This, the way Splitgate does this specifically, gives you this very specific feeling.
Rym: You know in a movie, or you play certain FPSs where suddenly you come under fire from a sniper, and there's that moment where you're trying to figure out where the sniper's coming from, like where are they?
Rym: That feeling happens constantly in this game.
Rym: You're doing your thing, and you get tagged.
Rym: You've got like two seconds, maybe less, to figure out where that shot came from, or you're dead.
Rym: So, the game is a lot of run and gun, cover your friend while they run to cover, put a portal somewhere to cover yourself from behind, figure out where the sniper is, figure out how to corner them.
Rym: It's a feeling that I rarely get in competitive FPSs.
Rym: Like, PUBG, you can get that feeling sometimes, but this game is just that feeling distilled of taking fire, where's the sniper?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So let's talk about just a few of the modes, right?
Scott: So there's a shoddy sniper mode, where just everyone has shoddy and sniper from the start, and then you, so you have a close range weapon and a long range weapon.
Scott: You have two teams, just get to 50 kills, I think, to win.
Rym: Something like that.
Scott: For your team.
Scott: I like the team game.
Scott: It's almost all of them are team games.
Scott: There's the ball one, where there's a ball, and if you grab the ball, and as long as your team is holding the ball, your team is getting points.
Rym: We had an A+ strategy for that one.
Rym: We get the ball, we don't run into this tiny room on the one map we were playing, and we just hide in there with shotguns running in circles until the match ran out.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: They know where you are because there's like a little beacon on you.
Rym: Yeah, but it's like a blender of shotguns if they actually try to come in.
Scott: Yeah, well, and you can portal away if you have to, right?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So there's that one, and when you're holding the ball, you can only do a melee attack with the ball, but it's a one-hit kill, so you can get a lot of kills with the ball.
Scott: I got five ball kills on one map.
Scott: What other modes were there?
Scott: There's like regular just mode, just, you know, death matchy kind of mode.
Scott: There was a king of the hill type mode where your team is a zone.
Scott: You stand in the zone, and as long as only members of your team are in the zone and enemies are not standing in it, you're gaining accumulating points, and then the zone moves occasionally.
Scott: It's like a king of the hill thing.
Scott: There's just all kinds of variants on team-based modes that aren't necessarily like, you know, the catch of the flag style, right?
Rym: So in terms of the feel of actually playing, the game is pretty slow in a good way.
Rym: Like, you don't move that fast.
Rym: You can run.
Scott: It's not as fast as Quake, but it's a little faster than Counter-Strike, I'd say.
Rym: Oh yeah, it's definitely faster than Counter-Strike, and the portals are interesting because in our experience so far, there's like a good chunk of the player base barely uses the portals and just seems to play like an FPS.
Scott: It depends on a lot of things.
Rym: The map, the mode, your team, your own skill, how used to these portals you are, because they can be as disorienting as you expect them to be.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Sometimes the portal can help you and not hurt you or hurt you and not help you, and sometimes the map is just like, "Yeah, I want to use portals, but there aren't any of
Scott: them.".
Scott: You can only use them on certain surfaces, so it's like if there don't happen to be portal surfaces in the spot that's going to help you, it's like you have a jetpack and it's like, just go, right?
Scott: Why mess around with these portals?
Rym: We definitely see, like, barely use the portals and you kind of just, you just see where they are, portal behind them somewhere, and just shoot them, and that just works every time.
Rym: 100% of the time, it just works.
Scott: So times the portals do work, right?
Scott: Like, I already discussed the portal camping scenario, right?
Scott: Long range movements, like sometimes on the big open maps, you can see a portal surface on the other side of the map, and you can just cross the entire map in a split second.
Scott: That's very useful.
Scott: You know, portal in, like, the ceiling, right?
Scott: You can, like, put one up there, and then, like, put one in the side, right?
Scott: And then come down from the top, stuff like that, to reach high up areas, because, you know, you can fall out the top one, you still have the jetpack, right?
Scott: So you can, you know, reach some places with those.
Scott: So you're chasing someone, right?
Scott: So you could, for example, you can see through your own portals, but the enemy can't see through them.
Scott: So you leave a portal somewhere, right?
Scott: And then shoot one while you're running, run into the portal, and turn around.
Scott: Now you can see the enemy, if he's gonna come through that portal, you see him coming at you, and he can't, he's looking at a black wall, he doesn't know what's on the other side.
Scott: So you, it's sort of like a, you know, if you're just in a normal FPS, running from someone, they would just slowly murder you from behind until you died.
Scott: Here, you can use the portal as like a little break to be like, oh, and turn around and shoot him, right?
Scott: Which you couldn't do in Quake, really.
Rym: And watches the videos, I've seen people do really clever stuff when they're good at this game, like, throw a portal down when someone's right behind them while they're running, and the person falls into the portal.
Scott: Yeah, and if you put your other portal, say, above a pit of death, Yeah.
Scott: Right?
Scott: If they happen to walk across the portal's surface floor, and you make them fall into it, oopsie.
Rym: Yeah, but I guess the end result of all this portal stuff is that there's like, there are three, like, very clear clades of players.
Rym: There's the console players, who just are terrible, like, pretty much categorically.
Rym: The people who are pretty good at, like, playing FPSs competently, and using portals a little bit, like, they use the portals, but not, like, That's us.
Rym: We're relying primarily on our FPS skills, and we're sort of using the portals as best we can.
Rym: And then there's the people where the portal is their primary weapon.
Rym: That is how they fight, and they're invincible gods to people like us.
Scott: Well, I think there's also people where they're just very good at FPSs, and they'll just, you know, this game is headshot central, so they're just clicking on heads.
Scott: You basically never really see them.
Scott: You just die if they see you, right?
Scott: The end, so.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So, uh,
Rym: there's such a wide gulf of skill, and a wide gulf of how people play, yet, to this game's credit, the three, like, the three of us playing a bunch, just going into random quick play, like, not really thinking about it that much, we're matched with people that are around our level.
Rym: It's not like Star Wars, where we're always matched against people who are infinitely better than us, or That's because there's no one else at our level playing Star Wars.
Rym: I think we are literally the worst players in Star Wars Squadrons.
Scott: Anyone worse than us is not playing.
Rym: Yeah, they've given up, or they've never heard of an X-Wing.
Rym: So, but, the fact that just clicking quick play, and jumping into a game, is pretty fun, is a very high praise for a game like this, because it's very easy for an FPS.
Scott: It costs nothing, zero dollars, it's a somewhat unique experience, if you've been playing all the other normal style FPSs, it's a little bit different.
Rym: To get good at the portals, though, you would have to play this game a lot, and memorize maps, like, for real.
Scott: Yep, I mean, I've memorized some of the maps a bit, but not to the extent where, like, you know, I have this sort of, like, portal forethought, or, you know, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, I mostly throw in portals, either in a panic, or very thoughtfully, like, I see there's someone up there, I'm gonna put a portal behind them.
Scott: Yeah, sometimes like that, you know, and sometimes what I'll do is, if I spawn in this portal surfaces, I'll just put one portal there, and then, when I'm out in the map, I'll just, if there's a situation, I'll throw out the second portal, and basically go back to the spawn instantly, right?
Scott: Just to have that place to go to, regardless of where it is.
Rym: I've noticed you and me both are very non-dynamic with the portals, like, I'll put one in a place that's good, like a sniping spot, or I'll put one way up, like, behind myself somewhere, so I, like, so, and then I put the second one in front of me on a wall near where I'm sniping, so I'm sniping from somewhere on the map, but I can look through the portal and see everything around me behind myself to see if anyone's sneaking up on me,
Scott: and it's,
Rym: yeah, moderately
Scott: effective.
Scott: I tend to use, yeah, I tend to use the portals, you know, 'cause any FPS that's multiplayer, right, is sort of walk around, walk around, walk around, engage, engage, engage, right?
Scott: There's the walk around part, and the engage part, and I tend to be using the portals a lot during the walk around part, but once I'm in the engage part, I pretty much only am using portals that are, like, there already, I'm not, like, reaching for the portal gun while I'm engaging with the enemy, I'm reaching for the gun gun.
Rym: If I pull, if I throw a portal while I'm engaging with the enemy, it's probably because I'm losing this fight, and I'm trying to get away desperately.
Scott: Right, or, you know, I, somehow, you know, the rare instance where I think of it in advance, I go to engage with portal intent already prepared, right?
Scott: I can't, I don't have the instinct to in the middle of a battle, be like, "Portal, portal,
Scott: go!"
Scott: Right?
Rym: Though, in our last game, I started doing something that this game facilitates.
Rym: that's real fun, that I haven't done since, like, old, old multiplayer, like, Quake mod FPSs, like, that had grappling guns and stuff, where I started using portals, chaotically, just to move around unpredictably and quickly, like, I'm running, I just throw a portal to the side, I run further, I throw a portal somewhere else, I jump in it, or I don't, I'm just throwing portals and jumping through them a lot to lose people, or to obfuscate where I am, or just to kind of randomize where I am, but I'm not thinking about where it'll leave me, I'm just thinking about creating chaos and reacting to what I see on the screen as a result of that chaos.
Scott: Yeah, it becomes very, you know, if you start portaling in the middle of combat, it gets very disorienting, and yes, that can be used against you, you get disoriented and you die, but you can also use it to your advantage, disorient the enemy, either you don't die, or maybe you get really lucky and you kill them.
Rym: Yep, like, I got real lucky once, I threw a portal.
Scott: To do that, but to do that with some sort of intent, where, like, you planned it that way, is next level, I will never reach that level.
Rym: Yeah, I got killed by someone where, literally, they, like, threw a portal and jumped off a ledge, and I go over the ledge to look down, and they fell through the portal, popped up out of a different portal into the air, and shot me from above.
Rym: I am incapable of that kind of forethought in this game so far.
Scott: No.
Scott: So, yeah, if you are looking for an FPS that's different, and, you know, you don't want to pay to win, and you don't want to pay anything, I mean, if this game costs money just to play, like, it was a $50 game, even if it didn't have any microtransactions, it was just a $50 game, I don't think I would say to pay $50, but for $0, and, yeah, there's microtransaction bullshit, but it's all skins.
Scott: It's all skins, there's no pay to win.
Scott: Try it out, see if you like it, if you like it, keep playing it, if you don't, delete it, but I think it's worth installing.
Rym: Well, you know what it feels like, like, actually playing it?
Rym: A lot like the early days of natural selection, in that the game was changing, not in terms of, like, the engagement and the style, but early NS was really rough around the edges, and they kept making changes to that game, like, just constant evolution and changes, and this game feels like it's in that state where it'll keep getting updates, they'll keep refining it, and the people who are playing it will, like, how they engage with the game is gonna drive how it evolves, so it's got a small enough player base to where you'll be able to sort of follow this game and grow, so if you like it, I bet by this time next year, it'll still be around, it might not be a runaway hit, but if it survives and it's still around, I'll bet it'll evolve significantly and just be way better.
Scott: Well, now I just want to play natural selection again, so...
Rym: Yeah, yeah, I was trying to avoid that thought, but that thought came in as soon as I said those words.
Scott: Well, I'm installing it right now, we'll see if anyone's still playing it.
Rym: NS2, I assume, you don't want to go all the way back?
Scott: I don't know, I don't think anyone's playing that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, I do, I miss, but with a lowercase m, the old days were matches for like an hour long and I would just build a wall of OCs.
Scott: If I could go back and play that game as it was right now, I would enjoy playing that game right now.
Rym: Building a wall of OCs and just hiding behind them, jumping around was fun, but also stupid.
Scott: I'm in the mood to play NS1 right now if it was a full batch of players and whatnot.
Rym: God dammit, I am too.
Rym: I feel like we're only gonna be able to.
Rym: I feel like playing Quake 1 is the closest to that nostalgic experience we can get right now.
Scott: But also, even if I were to play you know, NS2 right now, and there were players, they're probably just all gonna come and fade and chop my head off instantly and I'm gonna be useless.
Rym: Yeah, we gotta play with our people so we can all be bad together.
Scott: We don't have enough people.
Rym: I know.
Rym: We don't have enough people.
Rym: The eternal conundrum.
Rym: If you want to play Splitgate with us, just hang out in the Discord.
Rym: I'll totally play it with you because I enjoy it.
Rym: I feel like I'll play it once or twice a week.
Scott: You know, I'm not like, this isn't a game that I'm actively playing.
Scott: I'm not sitting down and being like, "Oh, time to play
Scott: Splitgate.".
Scott: But it's a game where some friends are like, "Hey, let's play
Scott: Splitgate."
Scott: And I'm like, "Okay, I'll play
Scott: it.".
Rym: Like Overwatch, I play every day.
Rym: I sit down like, "It's Overwatch
Rym: time.".
Rym: I'm not doing that with Splitgate, but me and the Scots will play this when we feel it.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think I would ever play Splitgate on my own on purpose.
Rym: Nah.
Rym: But I would like to play not just with people I know on the same team, but against a team that is also people I know.
Rym: Because that is the purest, most fun in all FPSs, in my opinion.
Rym: I just think back to those lands with Quake 1 at a Magfest where everyone is in the land, so all the opponents are in the same physical room as you.
Rym: That's good biz.
Rym: But yeah, Splitgate.
Rym: Super fun.
Rym: It's worth playing.
Rym: It'll cost you nothing but your time to try this thing out.
Rym: It even runs on consoles, guys.
Rym: Like, you can just play it.
Scott: The end.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi McNichol, Alan Joyce, Link Egee, Dread Lily, Tenebrae, a bunch of people who don't really want me to say
Scott: their names,
Rym: Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex, Finn, JustLikeADudeGuy, Shaiai85, Rebecca Dunn, ReviewMadBull34, Cowards, Ryan Perrin, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Horrell, Taylor Braun, TheIronFront, YouHoldTheKeyToMyHeart, and a whole bunch of people who actually, for real, do not want me to say their names.
Rym: And now, tonight, I leave you simply with... Okay, we're gonna open it up with a little improv.
Scott: Somebody shout out a location.
Rym: This castle.
Scott: Okay, how about an occupation?
Rym: Usurper of the throne.
Rym: I think I heard usurper of the throne.
Rym: Now finally I need an object.
Scott: Here.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Rym: I didn't use that much poison.