Rym: It's Tuesday, March 23rd, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: And I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are reviewing a game you might have heard of called Golf.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, now that it's warm again, I'm going outside again.
Rym: Like, I ran a half marathon the other day.
Rym: But, I had a situation.
Rym: I assumed I'd be slower, 'cause over the winter, as much as I have a spin bike, and ring fit, and it is possible to exercise indoors, even in the COVID environment, even if I can't use the treadmill.
Rym: The reality is, I didn't do it as much as I wanted to all winter.
Scott: Oh, I biked on my stationary bike very frequently.
Rym: I did it frequently.
Rym: I did it a lot.
Rym: But I did not maintain the level of activity I maintained the other three seasons.
Rym: 'Cause I've never in my life maintained that level.
Scott: This is actually an improvement versus the... Because, before, I used to just lay on the couch in the winter, and now, I didn't lay on the couch in the winter.
Scott: And now it's gonna be warm, and I'll probably put it away when it's warm, right?
Scott: Or at least, it depends if I commute to work or not.
Scott: And then bring it back out when it's cold again, even when times are normal-ish again.
Rym: So, over the weekend, it was really warm, so I ran a half marathon, and I put on my Fitbit, so I could track my heart rate, and I did my whole thing.
Rym: And sometimes, the Fitbit will fuck up, or Strava will fuck up, my phone will fuck up.
Rym: Like, it doesn't happen that often, but every now and then, like, the GPS will get messed up, and it's usually really obvious, 'cause I'll be in the middle of the run, and I look to see my pace, and it says, like, "You're running one minute miles,".
Rym: and I'm like, "Nah, it's
Rym: busted.".
Scott: That seems wrong.
Rym: So, on this run, the GPS messed up in the most fascinating way possible.
Rym: The numbers it was showing me were plausible, like, at, like, the distance run, everything was really plausible.
Rym: But it was showing that I was running, like, nine and a half to ten minute miles, but, like, it lined up pretty well, especially because when I sped up my pace, it seemed to get better, and kind of track, and there's physical milestones along the way, and I hit a physical milestone at one point, and the mileage was only, like, a quarter mile off, and that wasn't that bad.
Rym: So, basically, the data was plausible enough to where I was using that pace information to pace myself, and I had planned to run a relatively slow half-marathon, just, like, for funsies.
Rym: But because I seemed to be going so slow compared to what I expected, I started running faster, and faster, and faster, and taking a more and more aggressive pace to try to, like, catch up to my baseline, and I was starting to think about, "Oh, did I really not work out that much over the
Rym: winter?".
Rym: And then I finally get to the end, and only then do I discover that not only had the Fitbit fucked up in this, like, odd way where the numbers were plausible, but based on the physical distance I knew I ran, because I run the same distance every time, I know where the finish line is on the half.
Rym: I got to the finish line, and it was the third fastest half-marathon I've ever run, because I was pushing myself and running harder because I thought I was just out of shape and running slow.
Rym: The moral is, I could have been pushing myself harder this whole time, and I just wasn't.
Scott: I biked up, I virtually biked up a 3,000-foot mountain that doesn't exist in the real world at all.
Scott: It took about two hours.
Scott: Out of the 200-something people, two to three hundred people that did it recently, I was, like, the eighth slowest, so not the slowest.
Scott: I just casually went up, like,
Scott: "Do-do-do-do-do-do-do-do.".
Scott: They put a lot of cool stuff up there.
Scott: There's, like, when you get to the top, there's, like, a big statue, and there's, like, a yeti, and there's castles, and then when you get to the top, you get to virtually bike down, which you can't do because there's no way to start at the top.
Scott: You can't be, like, "I want to start at the
Scott: top.".
Rym: You can only start at a certain-- Oh, that's a Super Meat Boy-style incentive right there.
Rym: Like, yeah, if you get to the top, guess what?
Scott: Yeah, you get to ride down.
Scott: So, you basically get to ride down virtually at 45 miles an hour, which is, uh, you know, I would never ride down, especially since the course is almost all hairpin turns.
Rym: I was about to say, I'm very comfortable going 45 to 50 miles an hour on my bike, not if I have to turn while going at that speed.
Scott: Yeah, it's, like, you're just, it's just virtual, and you can't go off course.
Scott: I'm just going 45 miles an hour, like, it's straight, and I'm going around a hairpin turn at 45, not slowing down to turn or anything.
Scott: It's just, like,
Scott: "Whoop!"
Rym: Like, it's telling, I will, like, I've tried, like, skiing, I'll take turns at 45 or 50 miles an hour, but there's a big difference between, like, night, basically long knives digging into snow at a soft landing versus a bike and these tiny thin little tires on asphalt.
Rym: Also, landing on asphalt if I fuck it up.
Scott: But, yeah, and also when you start climbing this mountain, the game, like, switches into, like, a different user interface that shows you, like, the segments and a map and everything.
Scott: It's, like, a special area.
Scott: And when you get to the top, they give you a prize.
Scott: I got some gloves.
Scott: Everyone's, like,
Scott: "Whatever."
Scott: Virtual gloves for my guy that they're not gonna wear.
Rym: So, there is some big news.
Rym: This isn't just gaming, but it overlaps with gaming heavily, and also it's a pretty big deal, so I think we'll talk about it today.
Rym: to start.
Rym: Discord, if you're not familiar, and I don't know how, but especially if you're listening to a podcast called GeekNights, but it's basically this, it's sort of social media, but it's more, like, a federated way.
Scott: It's just IRC.
Rym: Yeah, but it's a way to make a little community server, like, you can just spin one up free.
Rym: It's on someone else's computer.
Rym: They just host it.
Scott: And basically, I mean, Slack and Discord are basically the same thing for different audiences.
Scott: It's, like, "Hey, we're gonna make running an IRC server easier.
Scott: You just push your button and you have one.
Scott: We're gonna add a, we're gonna make it easier to connect to it with a special client and all sorts of easy features like streaming and voice chat and posting embedded tweets and graphics and all these things that IRC doesn't have.
Scott: And we're gonna make it free and, you know, come on in, set it up, have a good time, right?
Scott: Make all the servers you want.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And Discord really focused for a long time and still has a lot of features around gaming in particular.
Rym: Like, it makes it really easy.
Rym: Like, if I'm playing a game, I can just live stream it to whatever voice channel I'm in.
Rym: You can make, like, dedicated voice chat.
Rym: Like, it's a pretty slick thing.
Scott: The original intent of Discord was, like, you're a Twitch streamer, right?
Scott: But you want to have a community outside of your Twitch stream because you might not be streaming all the time.
Scott: And so you set up a Discord server and it integrates.
Scott: So it's, like, all right, people who subscribe to you on Twitch get into separate special channels on your Discord.
Scott: You know, you can, you know, or, you know, the Twitch chat is unusable, but the Discord chat may be over there.
Scott: Those are people who really care about you specifically and not just, you know, passers by in the Twitch chat.
Scott: So maybe you could actually get some, you could actually read that chat, maybe it's not just an emoji flood.
Rym: You also have a lot more control over that community.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So the idea, the original idea was you integrate it with your Twitch channel when you're a streamer and then you have, but now, you know, at first I was hesitant to use Discord because that was what it was for, but they really branched out and made it, you know, useful for way more use cases.
Scott: My favorite use case is if you subscribe to someone on Patreon and they link their Discord server to their Patreon account and you link your Discord account to your Patreon account and then you Patreon them, it automatically adds you to their Discord server community.
Rym: I was thinking about setting that up, I just haven't.
Scott: Yeah, just set it up.
Scott: Yeah, I appreciate it.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: So Discord is heavily used and one of the most important things about it is that there's history, like you can read about the history of Discord, but it primarily charges the users as opposed to selling the users to other people, which is a big plus.
Scott: Yeah, that's good.
Scott: And the problem is, again, is that it's, you know, you don't have to pay them anything, it's free, but if you do pay, you get some stuff just for you.
Scott: But their other way of monetizing is these server boosts.
Scott: So the idea is that, all right, listen, you know, you're a Twitch streamer, if you're big enough Twitch streamer, you've got fans who are big fans, they're willing to, like, subscribe to you to give you five dollars for nothing.
Rym: Yeah, get a hundred of your fans to boost your Discord server and now they all get more features in that Discord server.
Scott: So if you can get enough people to boost your server, because that's like their main community, right, those people don't need to boost their own accounts necessarily because, you know, how many other Discord servers are they going to?
Scott: That's their main home.
Scott: And if the server is boosted enough, then everyone in the server, even the free users, get advantage of the boosted server.
Scott: So that's a good model for that Twitch thing, but it's not a great model for the, you know, just group of friends hanging out server because you're not going to have enough people in there to boost the server.
Scott: So every individual person would have to pay for their own Discord to boost themselves, which is a lot of money.
Scott: So you'd get it there in that situation to get a mix of people who are paying to boost themselves because they use Discord on a lot of servers and people who are just free.
Rym: God, I'm in like 17, 18 Discords and I actively use about six of them.
Scott: I was in a bunch and then I just removed a ton and I really cut it down to just the ones that are, you know, meaningful or Patreon and such.
Rym: But the news, like Discord is super important to the general Internet social ecosystem and also to the gaming ecosystem.
Rym: And the news broke yesterday that it was looking like it was going to be sold for a lot of money.
Rym: The going number.
Scott: I mean, we knew you knew as soon from years ago that Discord's only future was being sold to someone else.
Scott: They don't have a stand up.
Scott: They never had a standalone future.
Scott: So that was not a surprise.
Rym: As far as I'm aware, they were actually profitable currently because they can be profitable.
Rym: Like how many people actually pay for Discord boosting compared to how many people have a lot of free Discord and how much does it cost to run Discord?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Video streaming going on and audio streaming going on.
Rym: We're recording gig nights in a Discord that's boosted and has higher audio quality.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like they're losing money.
Scott: They had to be losing money on this.
Scott: But yeah.
Scott: So when it was said, oh, someone's going to buy it, I was like, oh, I knew someone was eventually going to buy it, but I guess it's soon.
Scott: And my top pick was, you know, for who it is, is probably Microsoft.
Scott: That makes the most sense.
Rym: I wondered if it would be like Tencent or a game company.
Scott: It's possible.
Scott: Someone suggested Epic might do it, which makes a little sense.
Scott: Valve, but Valve's not a big buyer of companies.
Rym: Also, Valve has invested so much in their own social ecosystem.
Rym: I'm not saying it's good or it works.
Scott: Amazon makes a lot of sense because of the Twitch integration.
Scott: But Amazon and also Facebook, which makes almost as much sense as Amazon, are both in antitrust hot waters, hotter than at least the other big companies.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Microsoft got out of their hot water.
Rym: It wouldn't have been a good look for them if in the middle of all that, they bought one of the one of the most used like communications platforms during a global pandemic when people are relying on these things.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Like it makes sense.
Scott: Microsoft makes the most sense.
Scott: And it turns out the rumors were like, yeah, it's probably Microsoft that's buying it.
Rym: No one will comment from either company, but numerous outlets are reporting that it is very likely Microsoft and it is very likely ten billion dollars.
Rym: And it is in the acquisition conversation stage.
Rym: But it's not like confirmed or signed that they're going to do the deal there.
Rym: It's possible it could fall through.
Scott: Seems likely.
Scott: You know, it's probably the best, the best fit.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's interesting because there's no one else who can.
Scott: I mean, the list of people who can afford ten billion dollars is really small.
Scott: So it's not like there's a lot of, you know, you don't have to like guess far down the list.
Scott: It's like, well, no one else lower on the list has ten billion dollars.
Scott: There's a lot of companies.
Scott: And even Apple, who definitely has well over ten billion dollars, they don't want that.
Scott: What are they going to do with it?
Scott: That is not something they're going to do.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And especially like thinking about there's a lot of companies that could probably do some really fun stuff and make cool things.
Rym: You're having discord, but none of those companies could afford this company.
Rym: So it was moot.
Rym: Like, exactly.
Rym: So here we are.
Rym: I am glad it's Microsoft because I suspect they won't ruin it.
Rym: Or if they do, they will ruin it as fast as other companies.
Rym: We were legit talking about how yesterday, if it had been Facebook, I think we would have planned to shut down and migrate everything we do on discord somewhere else, like quickly.
Rym: Because Facebook does not have a good track record of not completely ruining things they buy.
Rym: Have Beluga.
Scott: Who even remembers that?
Rym: Beluga was revolutionary for its time and was super useful.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: I guess.
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: Discord kind of replaced it.
Rym: We actually we've replaced Beluga with like eight different things over the years.
Rym: And discord is just the current thing we've replaced it with.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So let's get through some other tiny news.
Scott: It's also Microsoft, right?
Scott: So if you have an Xbox, there was always this thing called Xbox Live, Xbox Live Gold, right?
Scott: And if you wanted to play your Xbox games online, you had to subscribe to it just like PlayStation Network, just like Nintendo online.
Scott: And it was like a monthly fee.
Scott: And I paid for it for a very, very short period of time back in the day when I had Xbox.
Scott: You know, and then I stopped, right?
Scott: Well, it turns out that there was a whole bunch of different things going on here.
Scott: But like at one point, they were suggesting they were going to raise the price, and they were going to do other stuff.
Scott: And then it's like, okay, we're not going to do that.
Rym: But looking like we talked about this run a recent GeekNights episode, like all the stuff that was going on with Xbox online services.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But what they're doing now is they're going to just get rid of the name Xbox Live because it'd be confusing.
Scott: because right.
Scott: And they're going to have a new thing called Xbox Network.
Scott: But it sounds like what they're going to the X that that service that is going to be called Xbox Network is going to provide some other stuff.
Scott: Who knows what it's going to provide.
Scott: But if you just want to play Xbox games online, they're just going to stop charging extra money for that nonsense.
Scott: I think it's what it sounds like, which is great because that's what you should have done from the fucking beginning.
Scott: It's like on your computer.
Scott: I don't have to pay extra to play my Counter Strike online.
Scott: It's like things feel extra.
Rym: And then it's like I can't play Nintendo games on my computer.
Rym: So I'd less like annoyed by it.
Rym: I'm still annoyed by Nintendo online.
Scott: It's like imagine if you play Counter Strike and Rocket League, if you've got a computer, you buy Counter Strike, you buy Rocket League and you can play them forever online.
Scott: If you're on Xbox and you buy Counter Strike and Rocket League, I don't even know if Counter Strike is an Xbox anymore, but Rocket League definitely is.
Scott: And you want to or Star Wars Squadrons definitely is.
Scott: And you want to play PlayStation only.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But you want to play it online.
Scott: In addition to buying the game and the console, you got to pay this monthly subscription.
Scott: That's fucking bullshit.
Scott: Microsoft getting rid of the bullshit hopefully pressures the Playstations and Nintendo's to also get rid of the bull.
Rym: So this is fascinating.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The article.
Rym: when we talked about this last in January, it was because Microsoft announced that they were increasing the price of Xbox Live Gold to make it cost.
Rym: Basically, it was a play around getting people to pay for the other service they were promoting the box.
Rym: What do they call it?
Scott: Xbox Game Pass Ultimate, which is Xbox Gamer Pass.
Scott: The gamer pass is a different thing entirely.
Scott: And it's actually not too bad if you think it's the way the Xbox gamer pass thing is, is it's basically you subscribe to it and then you get access to this huge library of games, almost like a Netflix of games, you know, especially compared to I don't know if it actually streams them to you or if you get to install them.
Scott: But compared to like the stadiums of the world, it seems to actually be like, you know, good, like a good deal.
Scott: If you got if you're going to play a lot of those games in library and you don't own them already, then it can work out.
Scott: But that's completely separate from paying money to be able to play multiplayer in a multiplayer game.
Rym: Well, what's extra fascinating is so I just took a course on like pricing and economics, like the economics of pricing things, which is like it was a modern course.
Rym: So it talked about like the current real world and a piece of something that I sort of realized in retrospect that I knew because I did this over the years, but I never said it out loud, was that a common thing.
Rym: that is a good idea is if you have a service or a product and you want to kill it, but people are still paying for it, but you honestly don't want to sell it anymore, just increase the price because then people who are price sensitive will just walk away, thus making it easier for you to kill it.
Rym: And anyone who's desperate to keep using it keeps paying you money and you just keep raising the price and raising the price and then cut it off.
Rym: That is the most efficient way to capture money from something that you want to end anyway.
Rym: I bet Microsoft did that Xbox Live Gold price thing as part of some strategy to lead to this moment, but I also suspect they had other goals and because of how poorly that first bit went, I think they changed targets and changed how they look at the market.
Scott: But I don't know, I don't know how many people know, I tried the Xbox gamer pass thing, there was a free trial.
Scott: I was trying to play with a free trial and it just didn't fucking work on my computer, there was some bullshit and I installed that garbage.
Scott: So, but I do have a friend and it's working for them, so all right.
Scott: All right, now just some tiny extra news, right?
Scott: So this is an indie game that I've seen a lot and I've played the first two of called Emily is Away.
Scott: It's basically this little visual novel where you, a little aim, a simulation of an AOL Instant Messenger chat window is there and you choose dialogue options and you're basically talking to your friends once a year through high school, college times and you're sort of, you know, seeing how your relationship with these different people you're chatting with goes and one of the people is Emily and like they're away, right?
Scott: And then they come, you know, they're not away, you talk to Emily and then Emily's away again, you get it.
Scott: But Emily is Away 3 has been announced, it's coming out next month, I think, like April and it has a Facebook user interface, so it's like it's updating to a newer, younger person.
Scott: Another tiny news, right?
Scott: The best Ninja Turtles video games are always the side scrolling beat 'em up ones and, you know, like the arcade one, for example, or the turtles in time one, the Super Nintendo.
Scott: They're coming out, they announced this Shredder's Revenge made by the same people who made the Scott Pilgrim side scrolling beat 'em up.
Scott: We're making a Ninja Turtles side scrolling beat 'em up, which is, it's good news because you can't miss with this, right?
Rym: That Scott Pilgrim game has a history, we've like talked about it a bunch of times because it disappeared and was on, you could not play it for a lot of reasons that were stupid.
Rym: And it was not the best side.
Rym: scrolling beat 'em up, but it was real good and it had a really good sense of style.
Rym: and that is the kind of thing you need from a turtle game.
Rym: The style matters probably more than the game mechanics, but the game mechanics have to be good, they can't be bad, it can't be like Castle Crashers where it starts strong and just peters out into nothing.
Rym: Like you gotta keep me interested.
Scott: Someone pointed out in the preview that all four turtles have running animations and how good of a sign that is.
Rym: Yep, that is the exact kind of thing I would look at and say, "Ooh, they thought about
Rym: that.".
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And one last tiny news, there is an action RPG that just went into open beta today.
Scott: It's based on the Magic the Gathering universe, it's called Magic Legends.
Scott: I guess it's Diablo-ish, but also involves deck building somehow.
Scott: And it's free and in open beta right now.
Scott: I don't know if it's good, I don't know if it's just Diablo click on stuff, but it's open beta.
Scott: Should we poke at it?
Scott: I installed it, I'm gonna try it probably tonight.
Scott: I might uninstall it after five minutes, but it exists now, it went up today.
Rym: All right, I won't have time to play it tonight 'cause I'm playing Blades in the Dark, but if you don't uninstall it after playing it, I will also install it this week and poke at it.
Scott: I feel like though Diablo 4 is coming, so it's like if you're in that mood to mindlessly click your way to hell and destroy Satan, then I feel like any other action RPG is just sort of like holding you off until then.
Rym: Let's say cards represent spells.
Scott: I feel like if you played another action RPG before Diablo 4, you might get out of the mood and then when Diablo 4 comes, Diablo 4 comes, you'd be like eh.
Scott: I feel like it's better to only play Diablo and not any other.
Rym: I don't know, we'll see 'cause it talks on this page.
Rym: I'm looking at at the bottom about what the cards do, like making a deck.
Rym: You basically make a deck of 12 cards, you have access to a hand of four at a time, and you randomly draw.
Rym: So it sounds like it's Diablo, but four of your actions are a cyclical random set of four from your deck of 12.
Scott: So it's like a MOBA where you have your 4 abilities on Q, W, E, R. But they keep changing.
Scott: You use ability Q, you use it, and rather than cooling down and doing Q again, it goes away into your deck and another ability comes in the Q spot.
Rym: I would want to hear from one of the game designers why they chose the number 12 specifically for the size of the deck.
Scott: I think it's 'cause you have four abilities?
Scott: is pretty standard for MOBA's and things like that nowadays, right?
Scott: You know, you got four fingers on your hand.
Scott: That's how games are these days.
Scott: And then three different things on each possibilities for each finger.
Scott: 'Cause two, I think it'd be like, okay, each slot is rotating between two things effectively, right?
Scott: But if you got three, now it's mixed up to the point where it's not overwhelming with too many different abilities.
Scott: Like you see up that one again, right?
Scott: If it's too many, you're like, what the hell is this?
Scott: You got to read every time you press a button, right?
Rym: But if it's too few, that mechanic just becomes meaningless and it's just the album.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If it's just two things, then it'd be like, you'd just be like, oh, well, I just want to get this other ability Q and then keep using, use all your abilities.
Scott: And then you're guaranteed that if you just use all four, you're guaranteed that the one you want will be in the next set.
Scott: So the, yeah, that makes sense.
Scott: But I'm gonna, you know, at least it's an interesting new idea and people will play it because of the intellectual property and it's currently free open beta.
Scott: So you, it's the cost of your time to install it.
Rym: And I'll see if you actually install it.
Rym: And if you don't uninstall it, I installed it.
Scott: I just don't know if I'll uninstall.
Rym: I mean, this could be the last, we got really into autochess for a hot minute back there.
Rym: And now that I have not ever launched that again.
Scott: No autochess went away.
Rym: You know, it had a good time and then a good time, but it was funny how much like, I remember we speculated, is this just a flash in the pan?
Rym: It flashed so hard and then disappeared so hard.
Scott: I think, I think the real problem was that the, you know, there was the original and then there was the standalone one made by the people who made the original dodo mod.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then there was underlords made by valve.
Scott: And then there was the other one made by the league of legends people.
Rym: And it, what happened was I don't remember which one was like, I remember the names of something, but I don't remember teamfight tactics.
Scott: Teamfight tactics was the legal legends one.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Uh, the, the, the, the, the one made by the people who made the original dodo mod was just autochess.
Scott: And then the underworlds is the valve one, dodo under worlds, underlords.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I think what happened is that the league of legends one, one that was like the one that won the battle of the auto chess is the, the teamfight tactics one.
Scott: And that was the one that I was least interested in and didn't care for.
Scott: And that's why I fell out.
Scott: If the underlords one would have won, I probably would have stayed in the hot pan a little longer.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: I wouldn't be in it now.
Scott: I couldn't see that happening.
Scott: Um, but I would have stayed a little longer.
Rym: Cause it definitely got a little repetitive and like it would take too long.
Rym: Like I'd see that I've lost and it was, I couldn't just like, well, like I lose, let's just play again.
Rym: Like the game had a lot waiting time.
Scott: I'll probably talk about this in the future, but I have, there's a, there's a, uh, a Japanese mahjong app I've been playing just for a couple of days.
Scott: And now that it's come up here, mahjong and auto chess are really fucking similar games.
Rym: I can see that.
Scott: They're really similar games.
Rym: Cause all the fighting and animation stuff you look at when you're playing an auto chess, that's just color.
Rym: That doesn't actually mean anything.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's really similar.
Scott: Um, but yeah, well I'll talk about the mahjong.
Scott: maybe, you know, two weeks from now.
Rym: A lot of video games do the same thing.
Rym: You ever notice how, when you watch like a modern, like mid budget movie or TV show, if there's action in like Mexico or central or South America, everything's always color graded, really yellow and orange.
Rym: And if it's set in like Europe, everything's always color graded, like really blue and stock.
Rym: Like the color grading is almost so predictable.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So this is a really good video that dives into the fact that there are times and places to do that.
Rym: And when that arose, like when early color grading started to be used, it was used to great effect to like tell good stories, create immersion, create difference between scenes.
Rym: But the argument this makes is that Hollywood, and I would argue video games too, have gotten whether they intended it or not really racist about how they use it.
Rym: And it makes a point about how, and we talk about this a lot in games and in all the GeekNights episodes about like all the topics, the technology made it easier to do this.
Rym: Like I can take film that was like footage I shot that wasn't even like shot to be color graded and color graded pretty well without a lot of work.
Rym: Like technology got really good at that.
Rym: So if I also have watched a bunch of movies, but didn't quite understand them, I might've internalized, yeah, Mexico looks like that.
Rym: France looks like that.
Rym: Norway looks like that.
Rym: And I want to make it a video game and it's, I'm a producer and it's set in, I don't know, Mexico.
Rym: I might just expect that we should color grade it to look like the way it looked in the movies and the movies made it look that way because they were aping other movies.
Rym: And the first movie that did it actually did it to make, to make a point and all of that nuance and context and intention was lost.
Rym: And now you have the technology and using this technology to get this effect without thinking about why you're doing it.
Rym: And it's led to this being like almost a like embedded racist trope of modern television and gaming and movies.
Scott: I mean, that's how, you know, art history is right.
Scott: One person makes like a really realistic looking statue and suddenly have a whole trend of people making realistic looking statues.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then, you know, you get someone who makes a noir movie and suddenly you get a whole movement of people making noir movies.
Scott: So color grading, it's like, yeah, it's a particular style emerges, right.
Scott: And then, you know, people ape that style for however long until it goes out of style, you know, fashion, all the different art forms, the same kind of stuff happens.
Scott: It just so happens that, you know, in a case like this, it can be a racist trope.
Scott: that is, you know,
Rym: because people a lot of people using this technology, especially in the kind of like the movies that an American would watch, tend to be using it to express distance and otherness of places that aren't the place where the movies set or where the American characters came from.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's they're applying the same technique even in non racist situations.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if you think about if you're playing a video game that's like in a horror scene, like like an old, you know, the old typical like like Ravenholm kind of town in Half Life,
Rym: you get like a curve a certain way, every like shadows or everything
Scott: is
Rym: into
Scott: everything's all gray.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, well, it's not racist to make a place all gray because it's a spooky castle.
Scott: That's just the spot.
Scott: What if every movie if that's your but if that's your artistic style and you go to a desert, it's like, yeah, it is a desert there.
Scott: And then it's like, well, I made the castle place all gray at night with the bats and the vampires.
Scott: I'll make the desert all yellow.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like it's a desert country.
Scott: It's like, yeah, but the whole country isn't just like that.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Well, especially when look at look at Counter-Strike, D.E.
Rym: Dust, come on, especially when it's real world places like even gray.
Rym: Like what if I think I've seen a trope where a lot of Eastern European countries get color graded, really gray and washed out.
Scott: Well, I think that, you know, I think there the grayness might be a problem, but I think the greater problem is that every story you're telling in Eastern European places is some sort of vampire horror story.
Scott: So this video tell tell a different story about Eastern European people.
Rym: That's not, you know, that kind of video gets into it a lot at a point because a lot of people don't travel.
Rym: Part of the weird thing that happens is there are people who then like eventually visit a place like Mexico and it doesn't look the way like it's always been portrayed this one stereotypical way.
Rym: They've never seen what it literally actually looks like.
Rym: Look at a normal photograph of a random place in Mexico.
Rym: Mm hmm.
Scott: If you are someone who has not gotten to travel much and you don't really know a lot about the rest of the world looks like other than, you know, like the, you know, photos that you would see in like, you know, of famous places.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like if you've seen a photo of the Vatican, but you know, Rome really looks like to be in Rome, you know, maybe you saw Roman holiday or something.
Scott: It's like go and use Google Street View and go to Rome for free right now.
Scott: You can't get covered this way, I promise.
Rym: And you'll see a lot of just like real stuff like how people actually live, like walking around, like what a friend Google like Google Street View.
Scott: Tourism is not a waste of time.
Scott: I do it occasionally when I'm bored.
Scott: I'll just go somewhere and be like, oh, what does this place look like?
Rym: I want to say I saw Drew Toothpaste has been like into that a lot lately on Twitter.
Scott: Yeah, it's not.
Scott: I wouldn't be like so just being big into this hobby all the time.
Scott: But it's like, you know, once in a while, I'll just like like I went to a couple of weeks ago, I just I was like.
Scott: I was like, you know, what is a fishing village actually look like?
Scott: Because whenever you see a fishing village, it's always like you just see the area where they're fishing.
Scott: I was like, I want to walk around the fishing village.
Scott: So I walked around the fishing village.
Scott: I found one.
Rym: So one thing that's actually really cool is because I have fancy VR with the index Street View in Google Earth with VR is shockingly high quality.
Rym: Like you would not believe.
Scott: Can you can you do a multiplayer, though, like hang out in a fishing village with other people?
Rym: Not in Google Earth itself.
Scott: No, that's a shame.
Rym: But there's other VR after someone could like make that environment.
Rym: You could hang out in it.
Rym: But sure.
Rym: But that isn't just like built into Google Earth.
Scott: It would be cool to like meet someone in VR walking down the street.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like someone could make that and make money with it.
Rym: I feel like that could be a one yet another like tool in the VR toolkit.
Rym: Maybe, but I've like I've gone to actually an early covid since we didn't go to Japan.
Rym: I used VR quite a bit to go to the places I'd planned to go to and look around.
Rym: And it was it was interesting.
Rym: It scratched that itch a little bit, but not enough.
Rym: But it's better than nothing.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: What do I have?
Scott: So, you know, something we like to talk about here on GeekNights a lot, you know, from time to time is the game theory, right, which is an actual field of, you know, economics, right, academically speaking.
Scott: And it applies into a lot of things in the world.
Scott: But it also does apply to competitive gaming, which is the reason that we had an interest in it whatsoever.
Scott: And in college, we took a few books out of the library and read them and mostly half understood them.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And we'd like to do a few other things now and then.
Scott: But we have no formal, you know, game theory, knowledge or training.
Scott: People are actually game theory people.
Scott: They know way more than we do.
Rym: Oh, absolutely.
Rym: Like I know, like combinatorial analysis, which is still baby stuff.
Rym: I know the applications and what is useful for and how to do it.
Rym: You can't do it.
Rym: But to actually do it myself would require me sitting with a lot of references and spending a lot of time because I do not have any of that stuff internalizing.
Scott: And we know that, you know, maybe you don't want to go back to college again and get a degree in it.
Scott: It's, you know, economics degree.
Scott: You probably don't want that.
Rym: I mean, if I didn't have to work and that was free and I had I could live, I would.
Scott: But what you can do is, you know, you can go to Yale, the university, Yale, the Ivy League school, and they have put online a game theory course for free.
Scott: So if you can understand the material in the course, you have the prerequisite knowledge available to you in your brain.
Scott: Here you go.
Scott: Free class.
Scott: You can.
Scott: if you took this class online, you would know more than game theory than I do by a lot.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So and I talk, I see a lot of talking points.
Rym: Like there's a whole one of the lectures.
Rym: There's twenty four lectures.
Rym: You can just watch like they're just here.
Rym: One of them is on credible threats.
Rym: We've talked about that a lot.
Rym: Mm hmm.
Rym: First mover advantages, aggression cycles.
Rym: This looks like I think I want to go through this.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I mean, you might have to watch some of these more than once if they're too high level.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, to get a better to get a full understanding.
Scott: But, you know, twenty four lectures.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: This gives you the syllabus, like all the course material, the lecture.
Scott: It's an online course.
Scott: What do you think it is?
Rym: The exam.
Rym: Cool.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you want to take the exam and to prove that you passed you, I don't think they have a thing where you can actually get like a any kind of certificate thing.
Scott: But, you know, you can certify yourself.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, you know, you know that you did it, that you that you're.
Scott: I mean, you know, anyway, you stop in the moment.
Rym: That clock rang.
Rym: We're reading the tale again.
Rym: Gee, yeah.
Rym: He's doing his thing.
Scott: And it's getting he is not a good warm out.
Rym: He is not a bad person, but he is a person.
Rym: And he gets into trouble.
Rym: And not all of it is his fault.
Rym: And it's hard to really like.
Rym: I got to read more to see like where the arc of his arrow is going.
Scott: Yeah, it's getting warm out and reading books.
Scott: If you're going to read books, why not start with the first book?
Scott: Well, first, not first book, but first novel, the first like ever narrative novel, the first novel ever written by humans.
Scott: There is no debate about this, that there was some other first novel.
Scott: This is the one, right?
Scott: It's volume one of novels written by humans.
Scott: Number one, where else are you going to start?
Scott: Right.
Scott: And so, yeah, that's that's the book club book.
Scott: We are going to talk about it at some point in the future, maybe by the end of the maybe by the end of the year, probably by the end of the year, because it may be, but it's not that long.
Rym: And again, my only advice to you, if you're going to pick this up and read it along with us, is that you might like not understand exactly what happened in like one specific part of what chapter.
Rym: My advice is to just roll with it.
Rym: And usually things start to make sense later.
Rym: if you didn't make sense right away.
Rym: And if a detail seems like it was dropped and it never comes up again, also, don't worry about it too much.
Rym: It's not that important to the narrative in the story.
Rym: Like you'll see what I mean when you read it.
Rym: It's the style is a little bit archaic, partly due to translation and also when it was written.
Rym: So a lot of things are referenced very obliquely.
Rym: And even with the translation, it is very easy to miss those references.
Rym: Unless I was taking a class doing lit crit, I don't know if it's worth it to you to like fully internalize every single detail and nuance of every chapter.
Rym: I would recommend trying to just enjoy the story and just roll with it.
Rym: I think you'll just have more fun with the book.
Scott: Yeah, I'm just trying to understand basically the big picture of what happened in each chapter, right?
Scott: The current state of things.
Scott: And also enjoy, there's a lot of poetry to enjoy.
Rym: There is.
Rym: It's good poetry too.
Rym: Even through translation, it shines.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So golf, gonna review golf.
Scott: There's a lot to say about golf.
Scott: You know, we could, you got the actual sport, you got mini golf, you got video game golf, you got golf like things that, you know, are effectively golf, but aren't right.
Rym: And golf is interesting in that it has both like huge positives and also extreme negatives ranging from cultures of and histories of racism to pretty egregious, like land usage and resource allocation.
Scott: The one of the best tweets I saw recently, maybe I'll find the link or not.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But someone tweeted, they said, maybe I'll stop using the term Western civilization and start using the term golf playing nations.
Scott: And they had a map that of the world and they highlighted in green, like, you know, golf courses, like per area or whatever, something along those lines.
Scott: And it was like, pretty much like US, UK, Europe, you know, a little bit of South Africa, Scotland.
Rym: And yeah, obviously that, you know, the whole island of civilization, six golf courses are literally like the national building of Scotland.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Like it's like, it's like, you look at where the golf courses are and it's like, oh, it's where all the white colonizers live and somewhat adjacent places.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Cause golf is also big in, you know, Korea, Japan, you know, and Singapore, I think also likes golf, but they don't have that much land golf course, plus two gold, Dubai, Dubai loves golf, right?
Rym: Culture bonus if adjacent to an entertainment complex.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, uh, so yeah, let's guess that's where we're on it.
Scott: Let's talk about the negatives of golf, right?
Scott: So it's this sport, but it's a sport that is extremely damaging to the world in terms of its environmental damage to the places where they make a golf course.
Rym: It requires amount of land area to be playable and right.
Rym: You can't really change that land area.
Rym: So you have to have a lot of different golf courses further exacerbating it.
Rym: And that land area has to be extremely carefully cultivated, which I don't think there's any way to do that without huge amounts of pesticides and, uh, intervention in local ecology.
Scott: It's also a very bad usage of land, right?
Scott: Even if you have, first of all, you've got a private country club.
Scott: That's already a huge problem.
Scott: You don't even need to go into that.
Rym: It's just, I got some things to say about public golf clubs, but we'll save that.
Scott: a public golf course is better than a private one.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: However, consider this, right?
Scott: Like, you know, up in the Bronx, there's, I think it's actually the oldest public golf course in the, in the country, maybe.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Uh, I think so it's, it's up there.
Rym: It is famous.
Scott: The one, the one we bike, the one we bike through.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the, but if you look at the amount of like square miles, the amount of space that that takes up, and then you compare that to, even if it's getting a lot of use, right?
Scott: Like every tea time is filled up with people using it, the number of people using it and like the amount of like, you know, I guess benefit to society that that provides those people playing golf.
Scott: Cause you know, you're playing a sport, right?
Scott: That's a Ben is benefit society as much as having public tennis courts or, you know, right.
Scott: But the amount of land and cost of that public golf course compared to benefit versus what that land could otherwise be used for since it is public land.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Especially if it is next to an urban center or major land could be, that land is so huge compared to like a tennis court.
Scott: If you used it for public housing or just a regular public park, that could be another central park, like just right.
Scott: It's like, and you're using it for a golf course that a relatively small number of people get to enjoy, even though it's public.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, that's not great.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And like compare this even to other high impact things like skiing, like not, I'm not going to try to defend skiing here, but downhill, you're not going to live on a mountain though.
Scott: You can't, you're skiing doesn't displace public housing display.
Rym: It has other environmental impacts, but indeed skiing mountains, like an East coast, like hunter mountain, for an example, it basically sacrifices one mountain and like local infrastructure around it.
Rym: But the sheer number of people using it, if you ignore the moral judgment of, if it's a good use of resources, the number of people per unit hour of enjoyment of that, of one like piddly ski mountain is probably better than golf.
Rym: It's probably more than like every golf course in downstate New York combined.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Obviously, you know, every different, you know, sport that uses like, you could, we could measure like how much damage does this basketball court do.
Scott: We just paved over some, you know, nature, right.
Scott: Even though it's a small basketball court.
Rym: Golf is the worst one.
Rym: You need enough space for like an entire community for one hole that like four white dudes are going to play golf on for like an hour.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Think about like, you know, there's a lot of like desert golf courses and they're like watering them.
Scott: And when you think about like, you know, they're wasting their water on that in like an Arizona desert, they have a golf, you know, stuff like that.
Rym: Now, a couple of this social impact the game, despite like good, cheap golf clubs exist, but the cost of actually playing golf is high enough to where most people can't actually do it, even if they want to.
Scott: It's not as bad as ice hockey.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: Ice hockey is way worse on that front, but it's still pretty bad.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, you know, which clubs you have probably won't matter unless you're a pro, right?
Scott: You just got to get some clubs, you know, it's like same thing with a bowling ball.
Scott: It's like, yeah, an expensive bowling ball is better if you're pro, but if you're not, you just got to be, you know, any ball will do right.
Scott: The ball from the bowling alley is fine.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: I'm looking to see how much you said it like cheap golf clubs costs.
Scott: You can get cheap golf clubs.
Scott: It's fine, but it's like golf is still expensive to play.
Scott: Even on like a public course, you have to get to it right with golf clubs, which probably requires like a car.
Scott: I've seen people with golf clubs on the subway occasionally, but you got to get there.
Rym: I can count the number of times I've seen someone with golf clubs on the subway who was not going to or from the airport on one hand.
Scott: It's always a hundred percent of the time as a white dude.
Scott: Uh, anyway, uh, you got to get there.
Scott: You can probably get to get there early.
Scott: It takes a very long time to play golf.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: You've got to have an idle, like half day on a weekend or not have a job that requires you have to have people to play it with.
Scott: You have to have like good weather, right?
Scott: It's like the circumstances for playing golf is like, it really limits it to just the privileged class of people on earth.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, you know, like soccer, which is get a ball, walk outside, play soccer at the end.
Scott: But the exact opposite.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So like under 300 bucks, you can get a full enough set of cheap golf clubs.
Rym: Like that's less than I paid for.
Scott: If you're buying, if you're buying new, I'm sure you can go on eBay and buy some used golf clubs that are fine as long as you're not bent or whatever.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: A couple of hundred bucks to get like everything.
Rym: I have known people who played with like a non complete set cause.
Rym: that's just what they had.
Scott: You need golf balls too.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But those you can just get.
Scott: also, I've gotten free golf balls.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I just, I've, I've, I've saw a clip from that episode of Beavis and Funhead recently.
Rym: Unrelated.
Rym: So, but there's also this social history, especially in America where country, a lot of golf courses were private clubs, many of which were white only.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: And on top of that, rich only.
Rym: Like a lot of them didn't even allow women to be members.
Rym: Some of them are effectively still like that today, even though that's illegal.
Rym: There happened to not be any non white, non male members.
Rym: Wonder what's going on with that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: These country clubs, which is basically just, you know, uh, it's basically just an estate where you would go to hang out with other people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you live in your, you're a rich dude.
Scott: You live in your, you know, mansion or whatever you live in.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then, but no one is coming to visit you.
Scott: There's a place you go where everyone else goes.
Scott: All the other rich white dudes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Uh, rather than going to like the tavern with the local folk, you don't do that.
Scott: You go to this country club where you pay for a membership.
Scott: No one else can get in because it's not open to the public.
Scott: It's only open to your exclusive, rich white dudes.
Scott: You go there and hang out.
Scott: And you know, that culture of having a country club, those country clubs all built golf courses on their land.
Scott: And so that the two things were, you know, inextricably tied to each other.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That culture of rich white dude, secret hideout and golf are, you know, at the hip.
Rym: And it is possible to have a country club that doesn't have these problems, but they're rare.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Just like social clubs have similar problems.
Rym: There are a lot of really racist and broken social clubs, but I can see a space for like
Scott: modern,
Rym: like nerd focused social clubs, like that have like a building that's almost like a federated, like this is an apartment that all the members of this club can hang out in to play games, but everyone's got to live somewhere.
Rym: Like there's a place for that kind of thing, but you cannot ignore the pernicious and longstanding history of what country clubs, especially golf related country clubs have been in the United States.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So, uh, yeah, let's talk about the game.
Rym: I don't like golf.
Rym: I've played it twice and I do not enjoy it at all.
Scott: It just, so golf on the one hand, right.
Scott: Is, is kind of boring.
Scott: It's like you hit the ball, you'll walk.
Scott: It's more like hiking than, than right.
Scott: It's like, you hit the ball, you'll walk.
Rym: So of the two times I've done a full golfing at like a full, like let's do 18 holes.
Rym: Like just go, just do the whole thing in my life.
Rym: Once in middle school, once in high school, I got to the point where I just wanted to do the holes as quickly as possible, like to get better at it.
Rym: And also you just ran to the ball wherever it was, but everyone else like took their fucking time.
Scott: Like a lot of the people who play golf, right.
Scott: Is if a you're not actually caring about the golf and this happens in mini golf and regular golf, you're there for just to have fun, get drunk and walk around with your friends.
Scott: You're taking your sweet ass time.
Scott: or B you actually care about winning the golf.
Scott: In which case, you know, pro golfers, they got to take their time to line up the shot and really concentrate and focus.
Scott: And it's, it's, you know, it's slow, right?
Scott: It's, you know, slower than baseball.
Scott: You got more time between strokes and golf than you do between pitches and baseball.
Scott: Um, you know, it's not a fast paced or thrilling thing.
Scott: It's a very slow, you know, plotting kind of thing.
Scott: Um, but as a game, it's actually not too bad from a fundamental standpoint, right?
Scott: The idea of, you know, you need strength and precision, right?
Scott: You have to cover distance and also accuracy, right?
Scott: To get this ball into that hole in as few swings as possible, right?
Scott: That's really challenging.
Scott: Uh, it's also has this added element of the environment, providing a challenge, right?
Scott: You're damaging the environment as we discussed already, but the environment itself as a challenger, you get sand traps, you got water, you got trees, you got wind, you got, you know, knows what's going on, right?
Scott: All these, you know, not a lot of the other sports out there other than like wind during like a football game when they're kicking.
Scott: It's like other sports, the weather doesn't come into play very, I guess football also could rain or snow on that and they don't cancel, but other sports are not affected by the environment much the way golf is.
Scott: And that's added excitement.
Scott: Plus the ruling golf of you got to hit it, wear a lie or take a big penalty, right?
Scott: So it's like if you hit it and it lands on a pile of rocks way off in the woods or something, or it's under a tree, it's like, you just got to deal with it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That's kind of exciting and fun.
Scott: Um, you know, for as, as rare as it happens to professionals, it happens to normal people all the time.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's also got a, like a, an equipment factor that is substantial, not in terms of like, Oh, the fancy golf clubs versus the cheap ones in terms of there are a lot of different clubs.
Rym: Like you're allowed to bring what 14 with you, but like there are more than 14 kinds of golf with which you're going to use.
Rym: And every club is kind of radically different.
Rym: And you have to have the knowledge to understand when to use all these different kinds of clubs for all these different situations.
Rym: And you're way more complex than you might expect.
Rym: It's not just like, Oh, the one word is the big one.
Rym: And the irons, the small ones, like each one has a specific purpose.
Scott: And you've got the thing is the specific purposes because golf provides lots of different challenges, right?
Scott: One second, you're trying to drive and you're just trying to hit the ball straight in that direction as hard as you possibly can to make it go as far as you can.
Scott: And the next second, like you're trying to chip, you want to, you know, you're chipping is like a separate skill and then putting is yet another skill.
Scott: So it's like, there's all these different things going on in golf all the time.
Scott: Uh, that, you know, as if you're just playing it and you can somehow deal with the slow parts, um, you know, as a game, it's actually kind of exciting.
Scott: That's why I think golf actually works really well as a video game because you're just doing the hitting part only.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's like the game covers the, because this game also requires an extreme amount of specific physicality.
Rym: And like you have to master these very specific and minute actions and control them in a way that is difficult to learn and difficult to teach.
Rym: And also as a technique diminishing returns after you get the basics down.
Scott: Oh yeah, exactly.
Rym: Like, um, playing golf to the point that you can at least get it on the green reliably.
Rym: It doesn't take that long to get that far getting to the point where you can drive it to the final green or like deal with a curve or something that takes a lot longer.
Rym: And then actually being good spend your whole life doing nothing and playing golf.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then if you manage to get really good at golf, you do make a lot of money because it might be out of scope for this conversation, but golf has a very mature and well-developed professional and amateur scene.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The money comes from obviously the rich, evil white people, but it's like, if you look, you know, like you look at like PGA tour, for example, right.
Scott: And you know, you can tell that golf, there is some luck and some weather and other things involved in golf.
Scott: So you don't see the same thing as tennis where like, it's so skill-based that the same person wins every time until they get old at the top.
Scott: But yeah, it's, there's a, there's like a subset of the pro golfers who are like usually near the top and then get bumped out by age and they get shuffled based on other factors.
Scott: You know, who's better at this course, whose style suits these holes, what's the weather like, who's in a good mood, that sort of thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But what you, what was I saying?
Scott: Oh, it's so it's, uh, the lock shuffles, the people love.
Scott: it's skill-based.
Scott: I forgot what I was saying before.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But if you look at the game mechanically, like there's the physicality aspect, then you break it down into.
Rym: there's the, the game of how many strokes does it take to get you close to the hole?
Rym: And then you play the close game, which is just mini golf.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So what I was saying before, there's the same set of people who shuffle near the top, but the P the number of people who have PGA tour cards is actually, it's not a huge number, but it's a substantial number.
Scott: A lot of people have PGA tour cards, who means you get to play in those tournaments, even though they'll probably never win one.
Scott: Um, and they're probably, you know, not going to be competing for the top.
Scott: But if you look at the payout structure, it's like, okay, you, you have a tour card, you play in a tournament, on some weekend and you came in 40th place in the tournament, right?
Scott: You, you qualified, you played on, I don't know, you, you made it to Sunday and you lost by a lot, right.
Scott: Or something like that.
Scott: You got out, you got eliminated Saturday or something, you know, who knows you make tens of thousands of dollars just for doing that just for one golf tournament in a weekend because that's designed to make sure there is an ecosystem to keep fueling professional golf.
Scott: And that doesn't, that doesn't count.
Scott: You know, it's like, if you have a PGA tour card, even if you're like a no name, you got sponsors.
Scott: Someone's paying you to use their clubs.
Scott: They're giving you the clubs.
Scott: Someone's paying you to use their balls.
Scott: So wear their hat, wear their shoes, right?
Scott: You're you make money just doing that.
Scott: And it's, that's why I was tying back to, it's so difficult to be good enough to get on the tour.
Scott: that it's like, there is a structure whereby if you do really love golf and want to spend your life doing it, there is a like payout at the end there, right.
Scott: To, you know, if you're successful.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So in terms of playing the game, like the reasons I find golf uninteresting is that it takes so much investment to be even competent that it's very hard to make it fun early.
Rym: And it's just not worth the investment considering that you can go do it.
Scott: You can go to a golf course.
Scott: That's like all par three holes.
Scott: And that's like a good place to start.
Scott: Um, but yeah, even there, it's like you could, you know, if you're just starting, you're shanking it off into the woods, even on a par three.
Rym: Now, when more people play and it's a lot more accessible, and I think it's a lot more fun game is mini golf.
Rym: because mini golf, if you've never played it is just that last phase of regular golf.
Rym: So imagine you're playing some video game where we all agree.
Rym: All right, everyone, let's skip the first world and just play one, four together, like in Mario, like we're just going to race one, four.
Rym: So you can zoom in on that one very narrow aspect of the game and then expand the problem space and possibilities of that part of the game.
Rym: And there's a whole as game in there.
Rym: That's real fun to play.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Mini golf, I think lacks the environmental aspects of golf.
Scott: The wind doesn't matter.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: There might be an obstacle that's artificial that kind of gets in your way, right?
Scott: But the obstacles add back some of that spice.
Rym: So many mini golf, those are often more luck based, but good mini golf, those obstacles have a skill component.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Uh, but yeah, mini golf is, is a whole lot of fun.
Scott: I think there's basically that fundamental core of golf, which is get a, you know, strength plus accuracy, get something from here to there, you know, in as few attempts as possible, that core structure you see applied to many other games and those other games, while they are not golf are effectively golf, right?
Scott: For example, scorched earth is golf, right?
Rym: How many shots does it take for me to hit Scott's tank?
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Mechanically speaking it's golf and that, that fundamental game mechanic of golf, it makes for a fantastic game and you see it used frequently.
Scott: Uh, most often in video games that like golf, but also in other, you know, in other games, but I guess anything where you're making attempts or getting closer to something, right.
Rym: Or, you know, anything, how few, you know, here's a video game, Pearl golf, dude, make us function, like make a Pearl script that does something and then take that script and make it smaller and make it smaller.
Rym: And who makes the smallest one?
Rym: Like iterate on that.
Rym: How many characters did it take?
Rym: It's kind of an inversion, but it's a similar principle, but we can't disentangle those mechanics from the culture of golf because one area where I think game mechanics wise golf and mini golf both suffered to an extreme degree, ignoring professionals, but regular people who just want to play these games is that culturally they both have a strong disconnect between people who try to win and people who are there for other reasons.
Rym: And I've seen that blow up in both situations constantly.
Rym: I see every time I've ever gone mini golfing.
Rym: If my group doesn't have a fight about someone trying too hard, some group has it.
Rym: Like it is so common that it's a thing.
Rym: And I've seen the same thing happen on big golf courses.
Rym: Usually it's a few people are pretty good at the game and are trying to win.
Rym: And a few people aren't good at the game and want everyone to slow down and not actually try to win.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, some people it's just a matter of attitude and which, you know, because it's the game provides actually many different things to enjoy, right?
Scott: It's enjoyable on to play it on multiple levels.
Scott: People enjoy it for different reasons.
Scott: And if they enjoy it for different reasons and play together, then you get conflict.
Scott: I talk about this all the time, how like the star Wars fan who writes fanfic and the star Wars fan who cosplays, maybe they can get along.
Scott: But the cosplaying one would probably get along better with cosplayers of non star Wars things.
Scott: And the fanfic writer would probably get along better with fanfic writers, other non star Wars things, because it, you, you get along with people.
Scott: you're in the same community when you enjoy things for the same reasons, not when you enjoy the same thing for different reasons.
Scott: So a lot of people enjoy golf, but for different reasons, some people might enjoy golf because it's a nice walk in, you know, a lush green place on the weekend.
Scott: They get, they're old.
Scott: They got nothing better to do, right?
Scott: Some people enjoy golf, uh, you know, cause they actually want to win and they they're trying to practice.
Scott: Some people enjoy golf because, you know, the, the socialization aspect and, uh, oh, we forgot to mention the culture of like business.
Scott: P I think it's lessened in recent years.
Rym: Definitely less than golf is in a steep decline.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: But in the eighties, nineties, especially there was a huge culture of business.
Scott: People do meetings on the golf course and make, get deals done there.
Rym: You'll see it a lot in sitcoms from the, from those areas, like working in capital markets and interacting with people from a lot of these different strata.
Rym: One thing I've noticed is that the current state of that is like
Scott: people
Rym: who are like around like my level of like working in that kind of industry, when there's a business deal conversation, it's usually like nice restaurants like that level, or if it's a hobby thing, it's like ping pong is really big.
Scott: ping pong is big in the city.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Uh, sometimes pool, but then the like rich ish people are golf, but the super rich people, it's all creepy stuff like big game hunting.
Rym: Like that's, that's a thing I've run into a few times of creepy rich people.
Rym: Like they will go big game hunting together and that's their thing.
Scott: I'm actually seeing with the, you know, the Rym level of rich people and Rym, this is the thing Rym does.
Scott: rock climbing is a thing, right?
Rym: But rock climbing is also a thing among, uh, freelancers in New York city.
Rym: Like all the rock climbing gyms have coworking spaces in them.
Rym: It's a weird, yup.
Scott: And then I've seen, I've seen the occasional, there'll be like a trendy thing.
Scott: Like the ax throwing was a trendy thing.
Scott: I don't know if it's still a thing now, but I hope it's fading.
Scott: cause it's not, I hope it's really bad, but it was a brief trend.
Scott: The, the ax throwing, but you can see things of that nature.
Rym: You can see that people who run mini golf places re recognize this problem because almost every mini golf place in America will have a five or six stroke limit, partly to keep people moving along.
Rym: But I'm confident a lot of that is because if there was no stroke limit, the scores among any given group would diverge even more and more wildly leading to even more tempers and fighting.
Rym: The six strokes both lets them shuffle people through faster.
Rym: And it also lets them like someone who's bad at this game will just six on every hole and have less of a fight than if they get like 39 on one hole along the way.
Rym: Cause I, one thing I've noticed with our group is whenever we've gone to play mini golf, there's a set of people who want to play without a stroke limit.
Rym: And there are a number of people who will often not only want the stroke limit, but not want anyone else to play without those limitations like around them or in the same space.
Scott: Well, I think that that's the last thing, you know, and to mention is that, you know, you have this sort of social conflict of people enjoying the game for different reasons.
Scott: And that also ties into like the, maybe the biggest barrier to playing golf is like, let's say you're a lone person, right?
Scott: And you can't, you want to play golf and you don't have anyone else to play golf with.
Scott: It's like you go to the golf course, you can't just play.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: if you can play golf when you're one person, they put, they put you with other people, depends on the golf course.
Rym: Like you can, you can often play golf by yourself at a lot of mini golf places are more than happy to let you play by mini, but regular golf, they're going to put you with people, right?
Scott: Who are looking for an extra person, right?
Scott: It's like you go to, you know, you got to get in the cart with three other people.
Scott: Um, you know, yeah.
Rym: Well, partly because it takes so long to play a hole and they got to get people through so they can make more money.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They're not, I don't, I don't know if any place.
Scott: let you just play golf by yourself alone, unless you're like a pro at your own country club or some shit like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, maybe there is, you know, what do I know?
Scott: But it's usually, it's like, you're getting, you're getting people together so that can keep a lot of people out of it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that, you know, there's.
Scott: no, it's like pick up basketball, you just go to the park and play basketball.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You don't need, you know, to play golf, you have to have people to play it with.
Scott: And that's a huge barrier.
Rym: Um, and I think that keeps a lot of people out, especially when the skill disparity, you can't like, you can't play golf at all until you practice enough to get to this like baseline level and you can go to a driving range for anyone around you.
Scott: Driving range is fun at least.
Rym: So I get, funnily enough, I know a lot, a lot of people, I've done this too.
Rym: I would go hang out at driving ranges, even though I had no interest in actually playing golf.
Scott: I did a lot.
Scott: when I was younger, I would basically, I had these golf balls that were like wiffle, wiffle golf balls, and I would just hit them on my own lawn.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Uh, I think I had those same ones.
Scott: And then I would go to like, you know, I would, I never played, you know, real golf, like walking around 18 holes, but we'd go to the, you know, when my dad and grandfather, they, you know, they were into golf in the nineties, I would go to, we would go to the driving range, right.
Scott: Um, and that would hit a lot of balls in the driving range.
Scott: And it was just a fun activity for like an hour or so.
Scott: I didn't take all fricking day, like real golf.
Scott: That's, and it was probably cheaper too, which is why they, and it had a limit.
Scott: You rent, you buy balls, you'd hit them all and you'd be done.
Scott: And that sort of like getting tokens at the arcade, right.
Scott: You spend them all and then you're done.
Scott: Now mini golf is a good thing to do with kids.
Rym: Mini golf does have a similar barrier to entry.
Rym: It's not as steep for reasons, but basically like if you've never played putt, like putted before.
Rym: mini golf is like stupidly hard.
Rym: Like you will not succeed.
Rym: There's a lot of knowledge and technique and skill you have to learn.
Rym: And I think that mini golf has an extra problem on top of golf because while the golf skill divide is much greater, it takes longer to get to that point of basic competency.
Rym: And it's easier to do so in mini golf people because mini golf looks small and ginsy and has the hazards and the kind of culture around mini golf.
Rym: I think a lot of people assume that mini golf will be relatively easy to get good at.
Rym: And thus that leads to some of the frustration because the game looks like it should be easy.
Rym: And then you struggle with it.
Scott: It's as hard or harder than actually putting in real golf.
Scott: It's the skill of putting an extremely challenging thing that professional people are not perfect at.
Rym: But then simultaneously people who play mini golf get really good at mini golf.
Rym: And it turns into a counter-strike situation where like they will just always get par no matter what and you're still hitting six literally every round.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The thing that I find I guess frustrating is like when somebody is like, you know, they want to do better, right?
Scott: You'll see it's like someone who doesn't care about winning.
Scott: It's like, okay, they don't care about winning, right?
Scott: And then you'll see someone who's frustrated, right?
Scott: They want to do better, right?
Scott: They're actually competitive.
Scott: They do care about winning and then, but they don't put any work into like changing their technique or anything.
Scott: It's like, you know, I learned how to hold a golf club properly, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, in my earlier days, how to swing it straight or how you're supposed to swing it and how to rotate your, you know, at least the very basics, right?
Scott: Nothing.
Scott: Obviously my swing is probably garbage, but at least I have knowledge of the basics and I'm, you know, holding the club away.
Scott: That is not a natural way to hold it, but it is the correct way to hold it.
Scott: Really.
Rym: I play golf left-handed even though I'm right-handed.
Scott: All right.
Scott: That's, you know, whatever.
Scott: But I see people will be frustrated, but will make no attempt to try to figure, change their technique or home or even to like the basics.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And if you try to, you know, you don't want to explain anybody.
Scott: But obviously if you do, they'll just get mad.
Rym: Mini golf definitely specifically has a, the cultural expectation of most people is that they, no one, like no one should treat it seriously enough to give advice.
Rym: And that's an aspect that I think is important to think about.
Rym: with games in general, the culture and setting around a game can actually set expectations that may or may not match the reality of the game.
Rym: And mini golf is almost a perfect storm of that.
Rym: Mini golf is an extremely high skill game that has the appearance of a random game.
Rym: And that disconnect can lead to the kinds of social angst that occurs on many mini golf courses.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And that same, you know, those same social things are tied in with the, you know, excluding people on a, you know, on a higher level.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's all part of the same deal.
Scott: Um, so yeah, golf is, is, is way too much going on in golf historically.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Uh, but the, I think the, the key positive of golf is that the fundamental game on a mechanical level of, you know, do a thing, you know, in as few steps as possible.
Scott: Uh, and having to use multiple different skills, right.
Scott: Strength and accuracy and FNS and such, right.
Scott: Um, together and not just like one skill, um, make for an exciting formula, but a lot of the things you put around that formula obviously are going to make a huge difference.
Rym: I would almost, I saw a joke video of this once.
Rym: I don't know if anyone has ever played this.
Rym: I can Google after the show, I would almost golf.
Scott: I just got to throw that off as fun.
Rym: I played.
Rym: first of all, I'd like to see what golf would look like if someone went for speed run strokes, don't matter.
Rym: First person to get the ball in the hall.
Scott: It would be.
Scott: the problem is it would then become just endurance.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The problem is it would become a, who is the best like mid distance runner.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: The golf part would say I would just, I would hit it.
Rym: Who cares where it goes.
Rym: I'd run over there.
Rym: Cause I'm a real fast runner and I just drag my putter along and take it right into the hall.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: But yeah.
Rym: Um, I will say I, uh, I want to play some mini golf after COVID, but I don't want to play real.
Scott: I do enjoy mini golf greatly.
Rym: Um, let's make a point of playing some mini golf and if we're lucky, maybe we can even live stream ourselves playing some mini golf.
Scott: Oh, with our phones.
Rym: I think that could be fun.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I did do, I did do that thing of the golf.
Scott: We could go to some of those.
Rym: We should.
Rym: I want to go to a good mini golf place because I could talk for hours, but we're at the end of the show around what is it?
Rym: I need, I need a good versus a poor mini golf place, but I think mini golf places would be its own show independent of the concept of golf as a sport.
Scott: We'd have to, you'd have to go to enough places.
Rym: I've been to maybe 50 mini golf places in my whole life.
Scott: I've been to, I remember, can I really re when was the last time I went to one?
Rym: I had to like, remember when I was in two times ago, I went to Wildwood.
Rym: last time I went to Wildwood.
Rym: I didn't do any mini golf.
Scott: The last time is I had to go to Cape Cod for some wedding and we played mini golf because we were there for extra time and there was a mini golf.
Rym: of the mini golf places.
Rym: I have specific memories of there are three and two of them are in Wildwood.
Rym: So, Oh, I guess there was putt putt at RIT.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Did we actually putt putt though?
Rym: I remember we did once or twice and we always said we wanted to.
Rym: The reason we didn't was it was either too cold during the day or it was too hot during the day or the mosquitoes were out.
Rym: The mosquitoes were the big thing.
Rym: That putt putt was just like that.
Rym: I remember the mosquitoes being a very specific problem for us.
Scott: We would, we would go to New Hampshire fun spot for vacation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And there was a mini golf near there.
Scott: It was pirate themed, but we always called it mosquito land.
Scott: Go there at night to play mini golf.
Scott: And it was just a big mosquito swarm.
Scott: And we played mini golf there anyway, despite that we would put on bug spray and we'd go in and play mini golf.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution.
Scott: 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patrion patrons for this episode of geek notes are Alan Joyce, how do you medical link EG dread Lily Tenderberry, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Graham Finch, just like a do guy.
Rym: Now go through the last year or so of podcasts and make room saying Ren from New Zealand review, mad bull, 34 cowards, Ryan parents, you're vulnerable Taylor Brown.
Rym: You will the key to my heart at a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: We'll see if that container ship gets out of the canal.
Rym: And now I leave you with.