Rym: It's Thursday, October 14th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we are talking about aliens, UFOs, and stuff.
Rym: Not the movie.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, hockey got off to an auspicious start for the Rangers.
Scott: Uh, yeah, they got destroyed.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: That was, that was, that was a...
Scott: That's how things go in New York.
Scott: That's what did you expect, right?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Uh, you know what?
Rym: I expected, honestly, exactly that.
Rym: And the whole game, like from the very beginning, all I could think was, wow, we're getting out, out, uh, played.
Rym: They're, we're not like, they're dominating.
Scott: Well, we didn't get outplayed in the first 30 minutes.
Scott: They just got some luck in the first 30 minutes.
Scott: So actually we had lots of shots.
Scott: We had, it looked like we had a lot of zone time.
Scott: They scored goals in, you know, their first few goals in very little zone time.
Scott: But then after those first few goals, I guess we stopped playing that same way.
Scott: And then they just took over the game after that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But the problem was, so that in the last, second half of the game, they had all the zone time, but also they could score pretty quickly when they had zone time.
Rym: And we just couldn't.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, you know, that's how it goes.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: That's hockey.
Rym: So, uh, we'll see how this game, this upcoming game goes.
Rym: The game that we gave the tickets away for.
Scott: We keep getting, well, you know, we have these tickets, we can't return them.
Scott: Uh, we can't, you know, get our money back.
Scott: So all, you know, it's like, that's a sunk cost, right?
Scott: So even if I give the tickets away for free, I'm not losing anything if I can't sell them and we're not, we don't feel comfortable using them.
Scott: If someone else wants to use them, I mean, you know, my risk calculus is I'm not going, but if someone else's risk calculus is not the same as mine, I'm not going to judge them or deny them.
Scott: It's not, you know, I don't feel I have to morally, you know, enforce my, you know, it's like, I don't, I'll tell people don't ski.
Scott: I suggest not skiing.
Scott: I won't ski, but I'm not going to go to like the ski resort and be like out there trying to stop people from skiing.
Rym: Well, like I'll even be honest, like I'm not that worried about my personal safety at Pax Unplugged.
Rym: Say the main reason I'm not going is that I did, there's a lot of other reasons why it's too soon for me to go to a convention like that.
Scott: I mean, there is, that is definitely part of it, right?
Scott: It's like, even, you know, I might feel that I might not get sick, but, you know, it's sort of like, you know, I recognize as someone who doesn't drive a car, that if you drive a car, you are the traffic.
Rym: Yeah, that the whole moral hazard situation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like, even if I drive, you know, if I'm in a car and I drive on the road, it's like, oh, this traffic, well, you, you caused that.
Scott: It's you, it's not some external thing, right?
Scott: So it's like, I think there shouldn't be crowded places, right?
Scott: Because crowded places are dangerous to all of us.
Scott: Now, there shouldn't be, we should try to avoid making crowds.
Scott: If I go, even if I'm not in danger in the crowd due to vaccination and discipline and mask wearing, I'm making a crowd and I don't think there should be a crowd.
Rym: Especially considering we're at this point now where basically from what everyone's saying, all these unvaccinated people are just going to get it and there's nothing we can do.
Rym: But eventually they're all either going to get it and die or get it and be at least a little immune for a while.
Rym: And that's what's going to drive the numbers down eventually.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, if the numbers were down to like the way they were in June, the numbers were down and I almost was like, you know what, it's they've been staying down.
Scott: They stayed down long enough.
Scott: Maybe I'll come outside maybe.
Scott: And then they went up.
Scott: And if it was like two more weeks, I would have just gone like, tore the mask off or whatever.
Rym: At least in New York, what's extra sad is that in New York City, the numbers are slowly dropping like at this very slow.
Scott: So, so tiny.
Scott: It's like it's like pretty down.
Rym: If you look at New York State or like almost anywhere else in the country, flat or up and in red states like I think I looked at Missouri and Mississippi and those places like skyrocketing.
Scott: Oh, let's talk about Missouri.
Scott: What a great place that is.
Rym: Missouri.
Scott: So this isn't.
Scott: this is a story that happens a lot.
Scott: We could have done this as a Monday news, but, you know, whatever.
Rym: I had it queued up as a Monday news.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So some journalist out in Missouri found out that on one of the state websites, you can read the details that if you view if you log in and view source on certain pages, there was like you could see people's Social Security numbers were in the HTML, even though they weren't visible on the page.
Scott: And that was a big information leak problem.
Scott: That's huge, especially from a state system.
Rym: Now, it's not a what that means is that their website was sending those Social Security numbers to anyone who looked on the website.
Rym: They just happened to people to people who shouldn't have been able to see them where they just happened to not appear on the screen in a regular Web browser, but they likely could appear in a lot of other ways.
Rym: You can look at that same data that they sent you.
Scott: Well, they were, for example, they were transmitted to the person's computer.
Scott: So let's say somebody visited that website who wasn't, you know, nefarious in any way, just honestly using it in good faith and never saw a Social Security number with their eyeballs.
Scott: Their browser cache is on their laptop or whatever is or phone is now full of Social Security numbers that are there and who knows how secure that device is.
Scott: So now they have to go to everyone's devices who are using this system and clear all those browser caches and then, you know, see what's what anyway.
Scott: So the journalist who discovered this went through all of the ethical and proper procedures for notifying disclose.
Scott: No, not disclosing the newspaper was like, well, we're going to write a story, but we're not going to publish it until you fix it.
Scott: You know exactly what you're supposed to do.
Scott: But of course, the people who run the state of Missouri, the governor, the attorney general, all Republicans, it's like whatever they have over there.
Scott: Yeah, all old white Republicans who, A, despise the media and think it's left wing conspiracy bullshit.
Scott: So they want to hurt the media.
Scott: and B, don't understand computers at all, have decided to like, you know, they're threatening.
Scott: They haven't charged yet, but they're like investigating and threatening this journalist, you know, with like hacking crimes and whatnot.
Scott: Which is like absurd, obviously.
Scott: But it's a whole thing.
Scott: And this is not the first time this kind of thing has happened.
Rym: This was a very common story in the late nineteen hundreds and like the the the aughts and late nineteen hundreds.
Rym: Some kid referred to the late nineteen hundreds like a month ago on social media complaining about millennials and boomers.
Rym: And not only did it strike me in my heart and destroy me and turn me into dust, but I felt like I had to spread it because I really liked the sound of that.
Rym: I grew up in the late nineteen hundreds.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Anyway, but this was like I neared.
Rym: like every few months there'd be a story of some high school kid gets in trouble because they went to a website and changed the URL and like saw secret biz because websites basically were all geo cities back then.
Rym: Like none of them were made well.
Rym: And apparently Missouri still has websites like that.
Scott: Like another really common thing that happens is not just the information in the HTML that you view source and you can see it.
Scott: But another common one is you look at the URL and you see some number in there and you change the number and now you're looking at someone else's account.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That happens all the time.
Scott: And it's like, can you consider that, you know, hacking?
Scott: That's I guess that's a Monday discussion.
Scott: Yeah, but you don't have overly broad laws covering these sorts of things, which is now a legal discussion.
Rym: I would argue that the definition is pretty simple.
Rym: Again, not the technology definition.
Rym: And we are not lawyers, but I always go with.
Rym: if it's accessible to a to a person using technology directly and they have not done something specifically illegal, it's fair game.
Scott: But anyway, so this is a big thing happens all the time.
Scott: It's some fucking bullshit.
Scott: So I guess there's nothing more to say about it.
Rym: So here's the other thing going on here.
Rym: What's crazy is that this is such an egregious breach that Missouri has probably itself broken laws.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Just just negligent in making a shitty system.
Scott: Yeah, for sure.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But especially because it is whoever's whoever's information was exposed could probably sue the state.
Rym: So it's so bad.
Rym: in the source of the page were a hundred thousand Social Security numbers.
Rym: It was a lot of Social Security numbers.
Rym: They were all just there because the site was extremely like.
Rym: I can't imagine how this would happen unless you were doing.
Rym: I didn't look at the code myself.
Rym: Unless you were doing something like have a I don't know, a form that's going to react to something you type and put all the Social Security numbers in the source to drive some aspect of that form.
Rym: Like it's that level of egregiousness.
Scott: That is this is just the fundamental problem we have and that we're running our society with computers and we do not have enough computer experts.
Scott: And even if you have computer experts, they are often not given enough time and resources to do things in the proper way, even if they know how.
Scott: And there's just systems, even simple systems that do something not too complicated functionally are still architecturally complex.
Scott: And you have to get a whole team of like expert people or otherwise it's a disaster.
Scott: I mean, a lot of this is built up and we've built our entire information society on these fragile, not perfectly made pieces.
Rym: But we also can't let all these individual states do all this stuff themselves because they clearly are incapable of it.
Scott: That's why if you look at the best technology stuff in the world, it's like it's annoying that we have these tech monopolies.
Scott: We don't like that.
Scott: We want more diversification, more choices.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We don't want everyone to be using Adobe or everyone to be using Microsoft.
Scott: But if there are if there's only so many people in the world who can make a video card driver, it's like, I guess we're all.
Scott: we're all better off using the same video card with the driver made by the people who know how to fucking do it.
Scott: Then there's 10 video card drivers and but nine of them are made by teams of people who don't know what the fuck they're doing.
Scott: It is because there are enough people to make 10 good ones that are all different.
Rym: Yeah, I guess what's most amazing to me is that I expect there to be vulnerabilities like this, especially in like to be kind of I don't.
Rym: this isn't big.
Rym: I expect this from red states more so than blue states.
Rym: And history has proven that to be true.
Scott: I respect it from also from the blue state.
Scott: The only difference about money is they won't go after you in this.
Rym: Well, also.
Rym: But the difference is when these things happen, usually it's it's more complicated, like it's a cross-site scripting attack or like a bad TLS.
Rym: Like it's usually a more difficult to detect and resolve problem.
Rym: This is the kind of problem that even in the late nineteen hundreds was really easy to avoid.
Scott: This is probably an old system.
Rym: Yeah, but it's amazing to have this degree.
Scott: Also, if someone else had discovered it, right, if it had been some white supremacist, right, the governor or the wouldn't be going after them, they would have done something different.
Rym: So, yeah, but it's that confluence of anti media and anti technology.
Rym: ideas tend to correlate to the newspaper.
Scott: Suddenly this excuse to harass the newspaper fell on their lap, so therefore they do it.
Rym: But it goes into a bigger thing.
Rym: So notice, remember how there were all these different social media platforms that came up around the time of the election and after Twitter and other media platforms started banning certain right wing like racist nonsense, then suddenly all these social media platforms come up.
Rym: And it turns out that it's very hard to hire enough Nazis to run any technology compared to hiring people who are just regular old unethical or maybe even ethical.
Rym: So you get this sort of concentration of places with conservative ideas also have broken technology more so than other places.
Rym: Not that the technology is not broken everywhere.
Rym: It's just so much more broken in a place like Missouri.
Scott: Well, because, you know, that just being authoritarian, right, of any kind means fighting against facts, right?
Scott: You can't be a fact based authoritarian, so therefore you're going to be with your authoritarian powers.
Scott: You're going to be against people who are smart because smart people believe in facts.
Scott: And thus the people who are working for you and are actually trying to make things that you want to happen happen are not fact based people, which means they're going to fuck up, right?
Scott: That's why, you know, you look at a lot of shitty countries that have, you know, authoritarian rulers and you'll see like how many big projects they have that are just like Pajamkin's villages and those sorts of things or even actually get anything done.
Rym: It might be a little too on the nose, but a big part of when the Nazis came to power in Germany in the 30s was there were a lot of professionals who were angry mostly because they were being overlooked for promotions or were not listened to or respected in their professions, especially in government.
Rym: And those are a lot of the people who ended up joining the party.
Rym: And when they affected their takeover, they got the positions of power they'd craved for so long and they mostly just fucked it all up.
Rym: And a big part of why the war progressed the way it did was that a lot of very incompetent people were suddenly endowed with absolute power.
Rym: Hermann Göring was a gigantic dumbass who was very bad at his job.
Rym: But that's not the image fascists like to show and portray, but that's the reality of how they end up being in civil service.
Rym: So in some really good news, and there's a lot here, we can't cover it all.
Rym: We are not experts.
Rym: Go read a book or talk to an old person.
Rym: So IATSE, the I A T S E, we talked about.
Scott: Not the five dice game.
Rym: No, the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees, basically the union that does everything related to most of the media you care about.
Rym: that are not games.
Rym: They threatened to strike.
Rym: They have very reasonable demands.
Rym: And the union voted recently.
Rym: We talked about on the show with 98 percent plus in favor of striking if their demands were not met.
Rym: They have now set a date and that date is real soon.
Rym: On October 18th, which is this coming Monday at 12.01
Rym: a.m.,
Rym: if they do not have their demands met, they are striking.
Scott: Good.
Rym: This might be the biggest strike in modern American history.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know how size is.
Scott: This is huge.
Rym: Also, I don't think this union has ever struck before.
Scott: I don't think it has.
Rym: This is a very old union.
Rym: It's one of the biggest.
Rym: It's very important.
Rym: It's not on the level of the AFL-CIO, but it's it's up there.
Scott: I mean, if the teamsters just went on strike and just no trucks moved, like just shut down the entire, you know, domestic economy of the United States because trucks aren't moving.
Scott: They could just ask for anything.
Scott: They could be like, you know, so you know what, if only they would do that.
Rym: So you know what?
Scott: Netflix and ask for good things.
Rym: Netflix and all the studios and everyone who rely on IATSE workers are doing right now is they are now forcing everyone to work double overtime to try to finish as much as they can before the strike happens.
Rym: And it's gotten to the point where the union is trying to help people like get hotel rooms to survive and not like drive home too tired after an 80 hour workweek.
Rym: And there's a whole like shit show going on to the point that we might have to have a lot of boycotts tied in with this strike, depending on how the union tells us.
Scott: You know, because, you know, it used to be easy to not cross the picket line.
Scott: It was physical, right?
Scott: It's in front of a factory.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In this day and age, the picket line is virtual.
Scott: So it's a lot harder because like you can't like deface the Netflix website and, you know, like put a thing up.
Scott: So nobody, most people like won't even know.
Scott: So that's that's a problem.
Scott: Number one.
Scott: And two, even if you do know, you got to figure out how communication wise.
Scott: Right.
Scott: What do the union want you to do and not do to help them out?
Rym: So, for example, complicated because some unions are legally barred because of really fucked up laws in America from calling for boycotts.
Rym: So they may want a boycott.
Rym: They cannot say that out loud or they're in deep shit.
Rym: So you have to just look what the union says.
Rym: You have to look at what closely aligned, but not formally aligned advocates and organizers say to do, even if they are not actually members of the union.
Scott: And sometimes those people aren't saying the same thing.
Scott: They don't get their message together.
Scott: And it's really it's hard to try to not cross it.
Rym: Sometimes the union has to say out loud, do not boycott, even though what they're actually saying is please boycott.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So another thing is that I'm seeing right.
Scott: We've been seeing this app slowly building up, but now it's really coming.
Scott: Not just this.
Scott: This is the biggest strike.
Scott: But Kellogg.
Scott: Kellogg's is still on strike.
Scott: The cereal company.
Scott: Right.
Scott: John Deere.
Scott: They got a strike going on.
Scott: That's UAW people, I think.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That just there's that the UAW strike like that's.
Rym: that's hot in the news right now.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Piezo Publishing, who makes Pathfinder the tabletop RPG.
Scott: There's like 30 people working there.
Scott: They're not striking, but they made a union for their little tabletop company.
Rym: So that's cool.
Rym: The as of today, the United Farm Workers have formally expressed their solidarity with the IATSE strike.
Rym: They have not called for their own strike, but that is a notable development.
Rym: And I'm going to keep a very close eye on any news related to the UAW.
Scott: Bread and circuses on the same team.
Scott: Watch out.
Scott: So.
Scott: So, yes, I think what's happening here, I don't know, might be too soon to say this or maybe too late to say it.
Scott: But, you know, there was an industrial revolution and then there was a huge labor movement after the industrial revolution.
Scott: that sort of made things a little better, a lot better, but not quite good enough.
Rym: But we have 40 hour, five day work weeks and a minimum wage.
Rym: Not nearly enough.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's the.
Scott: that's the part we were able to keep, because after that labor movement, they got so much and then gradually lost it all.
Scott: And then now we had the information revolution.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And now there hasn't been until now, it's taken a couple of decades here, a few of them to have another labor movement.
Scott: And the labor movement isn't even necessarily related directly.
Scott: These aren't computer people on strike here.
Scott: Some of them, I guess, are digital artists, maybe, and things like that.
Scott: But these are not information workers who are going on strike because what's going on here is information workers don't have unions, which is another problem.
Rym: But what's going on here is not even so much like the revolution of information so much as like that world.
Rym: It's more that the wages and conditions of labor have gotten materially worse as the depredations of capitalism globally have gotten worse to the point that we're reaching a weird crisis point where a lot of jobs are fake because there isn't enough work for people to do.
Rym: But at the same time, lots of necessary work is not respected enough to pay any real amount of money.
Rym: And the entire system is broken to the point that more and more people are starting to realize not working at all might be better for them than working a job that destroys them for almost nothing.
Rym: Coupled with the two big people have just died due to COVID.
Rym: and how many people don't want to reenter the workforce because it's not safe because of COVID.
Scott: Well, it's mostly.
Scott: I think it's more so, you know, the things that are putting pressure on working conditions are other countries, right, you know, the Kellogg strike, it's because they're going to move that that factory out of the U.S.
Scott: to like Mexico or China or something.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So it's because of fiduciary duty and like a race to the bottom on pricing and to automation.
Rym: So but there's more there, too.
Rym: The pricing race to the bottom is partly because society as a whole is poorer as wealth has become so concentrated that most people can't afford to buy things anyway and they have to force prices down to be able to sell to the dwindling middle class.
Rym: Thus, the people who make the things the middle class buy get paid less and less and less.
Rym: I mean, I'm a product manager professionally.
Rym: I've been doing product management as a formal discipline for 13 plus, like 15 years.
Rym: And the weirdest thing about my job and it's bothered me for like six or seven years now is that if I look at anything outside of the capital markets where I have a job, any idea we could ever have any job, any product, anything.
Rym: If I put on my product management hat, all I can say is there's fucking.
Rym: there's no way to make money doing that thing ethically.
Rym: Full stop.
Rym: If you follow the law, if you follow the law and make this product ethically, you literally cannot make a profit.
Rym: It is impossible.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Because other people aren't being paid enough to be customers.
Rym: There's a reason why we haven't started a company, because everything we look at would be impossible to do with even like the barest hint of ethics.
Scott: So, yeah, the last thing.
Scott: Well, you know, just the last thing here to note about labor that you can, you know, take home regardless of your labor situation is, well, I guess if you have a job of any kind right now is that you need to realize that inflation in the U.S.
Scott: this year was like 5 percent ish.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if you're if you get an annual raise and it's 5 percent, that actually means that you're just breaking even.
Scott: They're keeping your salary the same.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you don't get a raise of more than 5 percent, you're getting a pay cut this year.
Scott: So if they come to you and like 4 percent raise, that's a 1 percent pay cut.
Scott: So you should say something.
Scott: You should be like, no, that's actually 1 percent pay cut, even though.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, for example, if you made ten dollars last year.
Scott: And that allowed you to buy 10 pizzas, pizzas.
Scott: They were a dollar each.
Scott: And this year you get a 4 percent raise.
Scott: You got one hundred.
Scott: You got 14, 10 dollars and 40 cents.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You think you could buy 10 pizzas plus a fourth of a pizza, you know, four tenths of a pizza or whatever it is.
Scott: It's like actually because of the inflation, even though you'll get ten dollars and 40 cents this year, you'll actually be buying like nine and a fraction.
Scott: Pizzas.
Scott: You'll be making less pizzas this year, even with more dollars.
Rym: The other thing you should really internalize is that right now is a moment that will not last forever, where for all these reasons and more we didn't even talk about, labor is way more powerful today than it was at any point in recent history in America.
Rym: So if there are strikes and then those strikes lead to more strikes, potentially leading to a general strike, the more people are involved, the more powerful it is.
Rym: And labor's power right now means we have a moment to force change, even if the political system does not support other ways to get that change.
Rym: One person striking, one small union striking usually is just a risk and a danger to that small group.
Rym: But labor is at a moment where the risk is lower and the rewards are higher.
Scott: So it's also one of the only ways.
Scott: all these, you know, the inequality, the wealthy people, their money is mostly tied up in the stock market.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if we have enough labor go on strike, you can crash the market enough and that will actually.
Scott: that's like one of the only ways short of crimes and assassination or other ridiculous things that you could hurt such rich people.
Scott: Yeah, probably the only ethical way to hurt such rich people.
Scott: So there you go.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So check this out.
Rym: This is a short animated film from Yugoslavia in 1958 called The Great Fear.
Rym: And it's just a short minute and a half film about some dude reading a horror story, getting a little too into it.
Rym: And it's pretty funny and cute, but I don't think I've ever seen Yugoslavian animation before.
Rym: And I just stumbled upon this and it's really neat.
Scott: All right, so it's October, which is everyone's favorite because the anniversary of GeekNights' Month.
Rym: October 31st, what, 16 years now?
Rym: I forget how many years.
Scott: It's also the best holiday, Halloween, everyone's favorite holiday.
Scott: I feel like we've done a good job as a generation, the millennials specifically.
Scott: I'm going to give us credit for making other holidays, especially Columbus Day, less important and making Halloween, extending it for about 30 more days than it used to be extended.
Scott: You know, everyone hates to see, you know, we're going to see it.
Scott: November 1st is coming.
Scott: You're going to see a Christmas tree there on November 1st.
Scott: But we don't like to see that.
Scott: But we love to see a pumpkin.
Scott: on September 1st, even August 31st, I'll see a pumpkin.
Scott: Bring on the pumpkin, right?
Scott: No one's upset about that.
Rym: I love me, over the garden wall season.
Scott: No one complains about Halloween starting too early.
Scott: They complain, right?
Scott: So we're doing a good job, everybody.
Scott: So in honor of the Halloween, the ambassador of Halloween, the late great Vincent Price.
Scott: Let's find some Vincent Price things of the day because there's about 10 infinity of them.
Scott: Here you go.
Scott: The excellent movie from 1950. what?
Scott: What year was this movie from?
Rym: Oh, 1959.
Rym: This is one of my favorite movies.
Scott: Yes, it's an old movie.
Scott: Rym loves it.
Scott: There's a remake from 1950.
Rym: Yeah, like don't don't bother.
Scott: It's called House on Haunted Hill.
Scott: And you may not know this, but despite being from the year 1959, this movie is in the public domain.
Scott: You could do whatever the fuck you want with it.
Scott: You could read, you could take the credits of the movie and put your name on it and say, you know, you could say like, oh, yeah, the part of that character that was played by Scott Rubin, not Vincent Price.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: No one can stop you.
Scott: Public domain.
Scott: You just do whatever the fuck you want.
Scott: Remix it, re-share it, make your own edit, you know, whatever you want.
Scott: Go nuts.
Scott: But because of that, somebody has chosen to do one of the other things that is you're legally allowed to do with public domain works.
Scott: Just put them up on YouTube in full so you can just watch the whole goddamn movie on YouTube in full zero dollars because public domain.
Scott: And it's even like HD, a really good version.
Scott: I don't know if they upscaled it or scan the film or what they did, but looks great.
Scott: Looks great.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: For a black and white 1959 movie looks terrific.
Rym: This movie, if you've never seen it, all I'll say is that it's unintentionally really funny.
Rym: It is intended to be a 100 percent serious thriller, but it's got a skeleton.
Scott: and you might think you every time you love a skeleton, you know, we love a skeleton.
Rym: But the way this skeleton is one of my favorite skeletons and you'll see music with some bones on a on a rib.
Rym: Now, that's one of my favorite skeletons.
Rym: This is more of the skeleton keeps coming back.
Rym: The skeleton pops up more times than you'll expect.
Rym: And also this fucking house just has a vat of acid in the basement.
Rym: And nobody like every character is just like, oh, I guess that's just a thing in this house and they don't think too hard about it.
Rym: Chekhov's acid vat right there.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And I guess I'll just end by saying, you know, if there's a. if there's a strike by Yahtzee and they don't want you to, you know, if they tell us not to, you know, to cancel our Netflix and our HBO Max and our everything, you know, public domain YouTube doesn't make anyone any money.
Rym: In the meta moment, Geek Dice Book Club Book is still the tale of Genji.
Rym: We are powering through our last panel at PAX East Online 2021 Atari Game Design.
Rym: It's just on YouTube.
Rym: You can just watch it.
Rym: We will not likely be at any conventions in the foreseeable future.
Rym: And we're trying to do a bunch of stuff online that we're not talking a lot about until we actually deliver.
Scott: So, yeah, I don't really.
Scott: And I guess if you live anywhere within a safe range of Madison Square Garden and you would like to go to see New York Rangers hockey and we don't we still don't feel safe going.
Scott: There's a we have tickets to half the home games.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I can't go through the whole schedule right now.
Scott: But if you look at the home schedule, there's a 50 percent chance we have ticket to tickets to any of those games.
Scott: Let us know.
Rym: Yeah, just we're not using them.
Scott: It's better that someone else who's willing to go goes then just and no one's going to buy them will just know if those numbers go down enough.
Rym: Then, yeah, we're using all of them again.
Scott: But, yeah, I mean, a listener went to the game tonight, that game that starts in 20 minutes.
Scott: So, yeah, they're probably there already.
Rym: The one thing is, I get the impression because so many tickets are on sale, I wonder if it won't be crowded.
Scott: I don't know how crowded it'll be.
Scott: We're going to see it.
Scott: We'll see on TV and we'll ask the last the listener and let me know how crowded it was.
Rym: I mean, we'll see via the way that all New Yorkers know to watch Rangers games that I will not share on the podcast.
Rym: But if you live in New York, you've heard of it, you know, that's what we're watching.
Rym: So, yeah, when I was a kid, I 100 percent believed in UFOs and aliens.
Rym: I was so sure they existed.
Rym: I blame same.
Rym: I blame television.
Rym: I blame adults who did not disavow me.
Rym: I blame magazines, news, like the fucking real newspaper would have articles about a UFO sighting.
Rym: And I would be like, well, it's in the newspaper.
Scott: I don't remember the real newspaper having it.
Rym: So when I was a kid, because I grew up in Michigan, there was.
Rym: I don't it was this was like nineteen eighty six or eighty seven.
Rym: But a big thing happened in the sky one night.
Rym: And like all the papers were like UFOs.
Rym: Holy shit.
Rym: Like it was a whole thing.
Rym: Like and we saw him like everybody saw him.
Rym: Obviously, they were not UFOs.
Rym: But I was a kid.
Rym: I saw a weird light in the sky.
Rym: And the next day the newspaper was like aliens over Macomb County.
Rym: Holy shit.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Never mind the fact there's an airbase there and like military flights there.
Scott: There is one additional thing that I blame, which is that, A, I was a kid who didn't know anything about things that fly.
Scott: Yeah, obviously.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And B, I would look at the sky and I'd see lights at night during the day.
Scott: You could see it's a plane, obviously, but at night you see planes flying and you just see lights blinking in the distance and flying and all the different planes had different fucking lights.
Scott: So, you know, I'd be like, you know, sometimes you see a common light pattern.
Scott: I'd be like, oh, it's a plane.
Scott: But then I was a kid.
Scott: I didn't know shit.
Scott: So I was just so convinced.
Scott: I was like, that was like that one's blinking white, red, white, red, white, red.
Scott: What kind of plane fucking does that?
Scott: See, I never.
Rym: I never went down that road, but I think it's because because of what my family knew and because we live next to like a military like Air Force Base, I was used to seeing a lot of planes flying all the time, day and night.
Rym: So I never thought I saw one.
Rym: I just thought they existed because I trusted adults and I watched unsolved mysteries.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, that was mostly it also.
Scott: But yeah, just that one additional thing there also.
Scott: Right.
Scott: One another thing I would blame is that, you know, I go to the library because I was so interested in alien shit.
Scott: So I went to the library and I got like an alien book just in the library.
Rym: Oh, I had some of those books.
Rym: The last one, the last one that got me was written in 1968.
Rym: But I read this fucking book in middle school and like part and then I read it again.
Rym: I actually had a copy of it.
Rym: So we went to RIT by then.
Rym: I was I realized.
Rym: But Chariots of the Gods and all the books that cite it are like this cesspool of really plausible sounding stuff, especially if you're a kid before the Internet.
Rym: But that even one degree of research beyond this book, you find out that, oh, they just made shit up.
Rym: Oh, they got kicked out of Egypt because they figured something out.
Rym: Meanwhile, Egypt's like, yeah, we kicked these American nut jobs out of our country because they're nut jobs.
Scott: Yeah, but also even very good books that in no way were trying to make you into like a UFO conspiracy believer, something like, you know, contact.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I only saw the movie.
Scott: I didn't read it.
Scott: But even so.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Just, you know, the extraterrestrial idea in popular culture with a kid brain only, you know, affirmed my very wrong beliefs at the time.
Scott: Something else I did right is, you know, I saw so many Roswell things on fucking TV.
Scott: And in the early days of AOL, there was actually like a form you could fill out, like to make FOIA requests.
Rym: I did the same thing.
Rym: I asked for all the info on UFOs.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And the government actually sent me like a brown envelope with a stack of papers with redacted shit in it that I didn't actually read.
Scott: But I was like, oh, man, look at this.
Rym: Well, never mind.
Rym: In the 90s, this was like 1995.
Rym: Remember the alien autopsy?
Scott: Oh, yeah, I'd actually I knew about it, but I didn't actually watch it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So I. it was obvious it was fake to me even as a kid, like like a middle schooler.
Scott: I mean, it's even though I believe that there were UFOs and whatnot, I didn't you know, obviously I didn't believe everything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like I see National Enquirer type stuff.
Scott: Anybody else?
Scott: That's bullshit.
Rym: But don't let people gaslight like who are trying to back away from this who were involved.
Rym: That alien autopsy thing, when it was announced like before, like there were months of real news talking about it like it might be real before Fox television eventually like was here it is.
Rym: We're broadcasting it like it was a media event and a lot of people were treating this like it was an Al Capone vault situation.
Rym: It was an Al Capone vault situation.
Rym: I will be shocked if any of you are young enough to remember that people remember.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But I remember this alien autopsy and I knew a lot of people, including adults, who thought it was real.
Rym: And then when the autopsy actually aired, they didn't say, oh, I guess I was wrong.
Rym: They just never talked about it again.
Rym: And if you asked them, they'd be like, oh, of course, that was fake.
Rym: No one believed that.
Rym: It was just a publicity stunt.
Scott: Or they still believe it.
Rym: Or they still believe it.
Rym: They're trying to cover it up.
Rym: But, you know, they're they're shame.
Scott: Or people will say, oh, that was fake.
Scott: But I still believe, you know, it's like.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, the other thing that messed me up as a kid, just like you said, was that on one hand, I had adults and media
Scott: acting
Rym: like there is something to extraterrestrial life and UFOs coupled with being really deep into like astrophysics and space stuff and things like the Drake equation and things Carl Sagan would say would give me this plausible like, oh, yeah, statistically, even if they haven't come to Earth, they're definitely out there.
Rym: Like there's math 100 percent.
Rym: They're out there.
Rym: So you can see why the plausibility like snuck in.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You have to look at like the specific questions.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like, what is there?
Scott: Is it likely that there are other living organisms in the universe?
Scott: It's likely, probably.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It's like, well, there's some real talk.
Rym: So I recently watched a bunch of PBS specials on the current state of the art of astrophysics and this stuff.
Rym: And there's an interesting, relatively recent theory about that.
Rym: But anyway, go on.
Scott: I mean, you know, it's possible that we're the only thing, but it's it's you know, it's not impossible.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If someone said, oh, yeah, some bacteria on this other galaxy.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But like, I believe it.
Scott: Yeah, that's believable.
Scott: You know, there's nothing wrong with saying that.
Scott: Has it visited us?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Something you're telling me something out there, either A, has faster than light travel, B, some kind of wormhole travel or C, has been traveling for so long that it got here.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And some of those things are.
Rym: they always find a redneck somewhere and like harass him specifically while he's drunk in the middle of the night.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: None of those things are possible.
Scott: OK.
Scott: The government has somehow contacted them and but is is not revealing them to the rest of society somehow.
Scott: Not that's not.
Scott: there's no way.
Rym: What what what conspiracy has ever actually been kept for real secret where there was a secret to reveal for that long?
Rym: Never mind something so big.
Scott: Yeah, it's like that.
Scott: What would be the motivation of such aliens and the government in making some sort that kind of arrangement and that the other governments of the world, which are?
Scott: it's like, you know, the U.S.
Scott: government doesn't run the whole world.
Scott: You're telling me that like these aliens came and only went to the U.S.
Scott: They ignored China.
Rym: Why are the angels only attacking Tokyo and not any other place on earth for some reason?
Scott: Well, because there's something underground there.
Rym: Oh, yeah, of course.
Rym: But there was really a thing underground.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, Area 51.
Scott: It's like, yeah, the secret defense projects at Area 51.
Scott: Obviously, the government doesn't even hide that fact.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Everyone knows that.
Scott: But it's like, have they tried to make something like a flying saucer?
Scott: They probably tried because it would be really useful if you could make something that flies that way.
Scott: Yeah, that would be fucking sweet.
Scott: Better than fucking what we have now in terms of VTOL aircraft.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But has any of it been successful?
Scott: If it has, they haven't fucking used it.
Scott: And if if it was successful, they probably would have.
Scott: And they wouldn't be wasting trillions of dollars on F whatevers.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But I think what there's a generational divide here that I find fascinating, specifically in that we grew up in an era where cam good cameras were very hard to come by generally for most people.
Rym: Media was very tightly controlled and limited and very mass market.
Rym: There wasn't really an Internet.
Rym: So basically, for every whatever, all of American history, like up until that point, it was very easy for a message or an idea to be popular without anyone really having any good way to debunk it specifically.
Rym: So as kids, we'd see all this media and adults and all this stuff, and it would seem very plausible that this stuff is real.
Rym: But a kid growing up today, even if they read Fade magazine because their grandma had it under the coffee table like I did and they watched Unsolved Mysteries on YouTube, they could type a couple words into any computer on Earth and everything's debunked instantly.
Scott: Yeah, it is interesting how the Internet at first in the AOL days, all helps, right, help to affirm my alien belief.
Scott: In fact, one of the first when I was learning HTML, right, and like, you know, middle school times, I made I got like some alien animated gifs and shit, right?
Scott: I was making like an alien kind of Web page.
Rym: Oh, I was type.
Rym: I was about to say Googling.
Rym: I was all to visiting for information about ancient Egypt to figure out if this the Orion constellation was because aliens came to Egypt, because that was all plausible to my kid brain.
Rym: And guess what?
Rym: If I went on the Internet, real people didn't have Web sites yet, but crackpots had Web sites and crackpots over.
Rym: the Internet was full of crackpots back then.
Rym: But there wasn't any other source of information, unless except like the library or the encyclopedia.
Scott: that also said the library steered me wrong because I found alien books at the library.
Rym: My middle school library had chariots of the gods in the nonfiction section.
Rym: Like what the fuck?
Scott: If you if you just go and look for aliens in the card catalog, they books that that are about aliens, you're not going to find books that are like aliens aren't real.
Rym: So, you know, but then the Internet got better and suddenly it was very easy.
Rym: Like all the weird things I believed as a kid basically evaporated as soon as I had access to the modern Internet, pre-Internet, like Web 2.0, because I had access from like AOL metaphysics chat room, right?
Scott: AOL.
Scott: Well, that was too many gory's.
Scott: That one specifically, AOL had only a few different kinds of chat room categories, and some metaphysics is one of them.
Scott: And that's where, you know, crackpots.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then it's like as soon as you weren't on the AOL anymore and you're on the real Internet and then it's like the Internet got better.
Scott: It's like, well, I guess that was a bunch of nonsense.
Rym: Yeah, but now we've reached a point where the Internet is full of crackpots again.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The difference is people are on Facebook instead of on AOL.
Rym: But we're in this weird situation where we grew up in a world where we had a lot of false information.
Rym: It was lent a lot of credibility to us and we didn't have alternative sources of information.
Rym: Now we have access.
Rym: Then we had access to real information.
Rym: We figured a lot of stuff out.
Rym: Everyone has access to more real information now than we ever had.
Rym: We have more access to information than any humans have ever had in all of history.
Rym: And yet about 40 percent of the population actively chooses the crackpots.
Scott: So one other thing I want to add is that, you know, it wasn't just the information that was available.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was also just what is what was popular culturally.
Scott: So in the 90s, X-Files was the biggest fucking deal.
Rym: Everybody watched the X-Files.
Rym: No, young people have not experienced a world where literally everyone is watching the same show.
Rym: Like you think Game of Thrones was big?
Rym: No, no, no, no, no.
Rym: When we were watching X-Files as kids, every teacher we had and watched X-Files, our doctors, our orthodontist, anyone you met, someone who was not watching X-Files was a weird aberration.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Now, the shows that come out these days, there may be shows that have bigger overall viewership than those shows did just because the population of the world is bigger and things have more reach and they're in more countries around the world.
Scott: But in terms of like percentage wise, it's like if you have a group, if you take a group of 100 random Americans, just at random and say, and hey, like, all right, how many of you have watched Game of Thrones?
Scott: It's like, how many is it going to be?
Scott: It's not going to be 10.
Scott: But if you do the same thing in 1998, maybe, I don't know what year, 90 something, and like how many of you watch X-Files, right?
Scott: It's like it's going to be more than the Game of Thrones, even if you said how many what's the number of Americans that, you know, what?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Or back up further, like when X-Files was first on, like early 90s, like 94, like that's when that show started.
Rym: There was there weren't that many shows on at any given time.
Rym: Like there weren't that many new shows at any point in like TV history.
Rym: So there'd be a set of shows that would be on.
Rym: And around the X-Files era, alien UFO stuff was just very popular.
Rym: So it like it just filled out all of pop culture.
Rym: Aliens and UFOs were like an undercurrent.
Rym: that was just there.
Rym: And generally not saying everyone believed in aliens, but they were always like an easy topic of conversation you could have with anyone.
Scott: It was.
Scott: And also it goes back further.
Scott: You got My Favorite Martian going on.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You got all the pulp stuff in the 50s.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You got, you know, there's just so much of it.
Scott: And then in the 2000s.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not like there's no alien stuff at all anymore.
Scott: But these sort of extraterrestrial stuff, I think, was reduced a lot, I guess, maybe around, you know.
Rym: You know, it's hard to say because that's around the time when I saw the zombies, the zombies took over and they haven't let go.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: We did a show on this years ago.
Rym: We talked about like the era of aliens and how it shifted into the era of zombies and that vampires were big for a while.
Rym: And we were like, when's it going to be sexy werewolves?
Rym: Like, when's it going to keep going around?
Rym: And that trend just keeps continuing as we loop through what it's never got.
Scott: I don't think it's gone back to like.
Scott: aliens aren't a thing.
Scott: Like how many movies in the movie theater are about aliens?
Scott: There are some that are like, you know, alien predator like, OK, it's about an extraterrestrial thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, but it's it's not about.
Scott: It's it's not like a flying saucer, Earth visiting.
Rym: There's occasional ones like there's the one where the aliens are like teaching the woman the language like there's a handful of them.
Rym: But it's not like multiple long running pop culture sensation television shows constantly dripping it out there.
Rym: Also, the long tail of there's a wider variety of entertainment and people have fractured into various different things.
Rym: You don't have a monoculture of literally everyone I knew on Earth was watching The X Files in the early 90s while I was watching it.
Scott: But, you know, it's also just what are, you know, people these days.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like what do they usually, you know, you're trying to make?
Scott: this kind of stuff is usually in the horror zone, kind of.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's an overlap for sure, especially since it's October.
Scott: So aliens used to be a thing people would be scared of.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Whereas now you're more scared of, you know, AIs run amok and we see plenty of AIs run amok stories going on.
Scott: But also a big part of why Independence Day wouldn't really be a hit today, I don't think.
Rym: I think a big, big part of why alien UFO crackpot conspiracy nut jobs actually went on a steep decline.
Rym: But eating the horse paste and all this other stuff went on.
Rym: a big increase is partly that everyone has a really good camera now all the time.
Rym: And you see a direct correlation between how many cameras people have and how few photos of UFOs continue to come out.
Scott: So I always say, like, man, if there's a Bigfoot out there, Bigfoot must have this amazing anti HD technology.
Scott: I want some of that so that it can avoid surveillance.
Scott: Security cameras could only see blurry, Scott.
Scott: Like whatever Bigfoot has to always be blurry when people have 4K cameras in their pocket, like I want what Bigfoot's got.
Rym: So in terms of actual alien life, as in for real life that did not come from Earth, on one hand, like you're talking about earlier, there's an idea that it it's definitely out there, like 99 percent chance.
Scott: I can't say definitely.
Rym: Well, it's not like ninety nine point nine, whatever repeating chance just from the ideas spawning from the Drake Equation Conversations.
Scott: The idea that ninety nine percent on a bacteria somewhere that's not on Earth.
Scott: So something some, you know, might not be carbon based, but some sort of.
Scott: so something that I guess looks like the thing is.
Rym: the idea was that we can make some assumptions about, you know, the universe is so big because remember, we didn't even discover the fact that there's more than one galaxy until relatively recently in human history.
Rym: Like it's if you're if you're young, you might not realize that, like when they got that first photo from Hubble, like out in space or like the pale blue dot photo and all that, that was all new relatively recently.
Rym: And we did not know the extent of the universe and we still don't know it to a degree.
Scott: But yeah, it wasn't until the first year and Edwin Hubble discovers another galaxy Andromeda in nineteen twenty four.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So not even one hundred years ago.
Scott: So more than one hundred years ago, we thought there was only one galaxy.
Rym: And then we rapidly got to the point of, oh, there's billions, at least of galaxies, billions and billions and billions out there.
Rym: So the Drake equation was like, all right, let's do some Fermi calculations.
Rym: We have a rough sense of how many galaxies seem to exist.
Rym: And based on our own galaxy, we can say like, what if point oh, one percent of all those galaxies have a solar system that's even remotely like ours?
Rym: and then point oh, one percent of those have a planet that's remotely like Earth.
Rym: And you do these extremely pessimistic calculations.
Rym: Even then, there are so many galaxies and there's so much time that it puts the odds of life being out there like at ninety nine point like plus percent just by the sheer scale.
Scott: And that makes the pessimistic assumption also that the life will be similar to our kind of life.
Scott: It could be life that does not resemble our kind of life.
Rym: So the more modern data has made that a much more challenging conversation because the Drake equation got all the way down into the time in which it could take in the most pessimistic state for electromagnetic radiation to come out of one of those civilizations and the time it would take for it to reach us from anywhere in the universe.
Rym: And even then, the odds are that we should have seen something by now.
Rym: And that is a recent conversation that seems to be happening among astrophysics.
Rym: It's leading into this lonely Earth hypothesis.
Rym: It is weird that we've never seen anything.
Scott: And I just don't know how.
Scott: Don't know how is an interesting question, though, because there's something we don't know still that they can't reach us.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: So there's where that's where we start to talk about the idea of great filters, like is life actually common or not or is the bending of space keeping the signals from reaching us?
Scott: or is life using a different kind of signal?
Rym: or is life common?
Rym: And the fact that life is unlike is much less likely to get to a certain state of advancement.
Rym: But the weird part is that even accounting for all those things, we just look at our own galaxy.
Rym: We should have detected something like the horizon of how far out we're very, very connected, something and not recognized it.
Rym: Well, the idea the horizon of how far out we're pretty sure there is nothing is slowly growing.
Rym: And the data we have so far really fucks up our understanding of the Drake equation and the statistical odds.
Rym: The lonely Earth hypothesis is a new one that's starting to gain some track or not new, but it's gaining some traction and it's really leaning on the Anthropic principle.
Rym: And it makes one argument that a universe capable of creating observers must create observers.
Rym: Otherwise, that whole concept is moot.
Rym: We exist and we observe.
Rym: Therefore, it is possible for universes to spawn life like full stop.
Rym: And it's all the assumptions we can make.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: But it's important to say that out loud and agree on it.
Rym: to move on to all this other complex math.
Rym: So based on the data we have from our own galaxy and the galaxies we've been able to study, it appears that if we look at life like our own slimeball planets, which Earth was one, planets that are even remotely like Earth, capable of generating the kind of life that became us, Earth is likely one of the earliest of those planets to have formed in the universe, as in it's in the first eight percent of all of them that are likely to ever form.
Scott: So we just might be the first life and that like if we could wait a trillion years, there would be life all over the place?
Rym: That is power.
Rym: In the very least, we are early so that even if other life is happening, our signals are going to reach other civilizations before theirs could possibly reach us.
Scott: That is, I mean, it is entirely possible that if you had a universe, if you made a new universe and you made it so big and that with such odds of life and life was going to happen, there would still be a first life.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And on a galactic time scale.
Scott: Right.
Scott: How would that life know?
Scott: it was the first life if it was?
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: It almost turns into like not the halting problem, but you get into similar types of problems that there are no answers to calculate due to the scale and due to the unknowns.
Rym: But we have a pretty good idea that Earth like planets, our planet might literally be one of the earliest of them to form.
Scott: Could be it's possible.
Scott: Yeah, which sounds like it's but it's it's a plausible explanation.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: But there's other things we've learned.
Rym: The Drake equation almost wasn't pessimistic enough because we've learned some other things about Earth that make planets that are Earth like shockingly more rare than we had assumed for a long time.
Rym: And the two things that make Earth super weird are one, we have an.
Rym: we have an electromagnetic field that shields us from dangerous radiation.
Rym: We've learned relatively recently.
Rym: almost all the Earth like planets we've discovered when we were saying, oh, yeah, there's billions and billions of them out there do not appear to have that shield.
Scott: They're just so they have.
Scott: they've water.
Scott: They have water.
Scott: They're like a good distance or good distance from a nice star, but they're just getting blasted by the star all the time.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And two, Jupiter, almost no galaxies we have observed have a Jupiter like planet also there.
Rym: And Jupiter is the main reason asteroids don't constantly hit Earth even today.
Scott: Well, you want to talk about alien conspiracy.
Scott: I got to go watch hockey and eat food.
Scott: But let's just end on people always talking about that.
Scott: Planet X used to exist between Mars and Jupiter.
Scott: And now it's an asteroid belt.
Scott: It got some alien war, some shit.
Scott: That's an old story.
Rym: We would have detected that, though, by gravity.
Scott: I'd hope.
Scott: Yeah, if there if there used to be a civilization, if there was a planet there and it had a civilization, we would have seen artifacts on it with a telescope.
Rym: I guess.
Rym: Well, we'll end the show shortly.
Rym: But what I'll show the cool thing about the rare Earth hypothesis, like the next sort of interesting bit, is that even with all the pessimistic shit I just said, we know how fast life evolved on Earth.
Rym: And the thing that I didn't really internalize until very, very recently was how quickly on a galactic scale Earth went from no life to shit tons of life.
Rym: Earth turned into a giant slimeball like so fast.
Rym: It is unreasonable, which implies that any planet even remotely like Earth would almost inevitably rapidly be filled with slime life.
Scott: Well, but also how long does the civilization last, right?
Scott: If you look at a galactic time scale, right, if we end ourselves and Earth goes extinct from climate change or who knows what, then all life on Earth will basically have been a blip.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The dinosaurs were like an extremely short period of time.
Scott: It could have been dinosaurs.
Scott: They did go extinct.
Scott: If nothing came after the dinosaurs, if that was the end of Earth.
Scott: Think about how short that would have been.
Scott: So if there's a bunch of other planets, they could have all had really short periods of life.
Scott: And that's it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And there's how would we how would we detect those?
Scott: There could have been one hundred planets that all had dinosaurs and then went extinct.
Scott: And that was the end.
Scott: So we would have seen any of them.
Rym: We do have some ways to detect that.
Rym: there's some interesting ways that are pretty plausible.
Rym: But there's two big theories about that.
Rym: One is that there's some filter that we don't know about.
Rym: And then the debate is, are we before that filter or after that filter?
Scott: Like the four days, that kind of filter, I'm always going to bet on before.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But it's that's a complicated question.
Rym: There's a lot of debate around.
Rym: like one of the great filters might be the formation of eukaryotic life as opposed to prokaryotic life, because that might have been that one.
Rym: That but that might be a fluke.
Rym: It might be that life is really common, but eukaryotic life that can become more complex might be a extremely rare event like it happened once.
Rym: And we got really lucky that that one thing didn't die.
Rym: But the other complication of this is that based on that data about slimeball planets, Earth being one of them, we can see a lot of planets.
Rym: There's evidence of a lot of planets like in our area that for all we know should have been slimeball planets and we should have been able to detect signatures of some sort of life or some sort of metabolisms.
Rym: And so far, we have not found any evidence, not even the most remote evidence of a slimeball planet anywhere we can see, despite the fact that statistically, based on our own formation, they should be extremely common, like way more common than the Drake equation even implied.
Rym: And one theory, the lonely Earth theory, is that there that we as observers exist and it is extremely unlikely that observers could exist, not impossible, but unlikely, we must exist in a place that is rare in the universe.
Rym: The kind of place that can support life like us is rare.
Rym: But us being here is not weird because this is the only place we could afford.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you have a winning lottery ticket.
Scott: It's not weird that you have a winning lottery ticket.
Rym: Yeah, one in a billion, one in a trillion, trillion chances.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: If you already know you have a winning lottery ticket, then you know how rare that event was.
Rym: That's the theory.
Rym: We know we exist, so we might just exist in an extremely rare situation.
Rym: And I think that's enough alien talk because I would like to eat some food and watch a hockey game.
Scott: Good.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi McNichol, Alan Joyce, Mikegidred, Lily Tenerbrite, a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names, and Chris Reimer and Clinton Walton, Dex Finn, JustLikeADudeGuy, Kishiahigh85, Rebecca Dunn, Reviewed, Madbull34, Cowards, Ryan Perrin, Sam Erickson, Shervin VonHarl, Taylor Braun, The Iron Front, You Old, The Key to My Heart and a whole bunch of other people who don't want me to say their names.
Rym: So we just finished the last episode of season two of Lower Decks.
Rym: That show is a full on Star Trek and you should all watch it.
Rym: Scott hates Star Trek, so he'll probably never watch it or talk about it on the show.
Rym: But for now, I leave you with... This is a sub-manifold casting stone.
Rym: A what?
Rym: We can use it to broadcast our voices to other planets.
Rym: What's that good for?
Rym: Yeah, like what are we going to do?
Rym: Prank call Armis?
Rym: I wish I had someone to torture.
Rym: Hey, Armis.
Rym: You look like a big bag of crap.
Rym: Who said that?
Scott: Show yourself.
Scott: I am Armis.
Scott: This is my domain.
Rym: We already know you're Armis, dummy.
Rym: Come and find us.
Rym: We're catching your stuff.
Rym: What stuff?
Rym: Stop that.
Rym: When I find you, I'm going to kill you with a flake of my power.
Rym: I am a skin of evil mouth.
Rym: More like a puddle of... Damn you!