Rym: It's Wednesday, November 17th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are going to give our final spoiler-filled thoughts on the Rebuild Evangelion movies.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, as you all know, I hope by now you have two, at least two or one, if it was the Johnson & Johnson COVID shots in your body.
Rym: If you're in America, there's literally no excuse to have not gotten them unless you have a medical reason, of course.
Rym: But we're hitting into the booster season.
Rym: And at least in New York, they just changed the rule.
Rym: So any adult over 18.
Scott: So the rule is if you go ask for one, your doctor shouldn't say no.
Scott: And it's like, well, that doesn't help me, right?
Scott: It's like, you got to tell me.
Scott: It's like, yeah, I can get one now.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: But should I?
Scott: I need a doctor to tell me if I should.
Scott: It's like, you know, I don't know.
Rym: The New York guidance was pretty much if you're an adult over 18 and it's been six months, you can do it.
Rym: You can.
Scott: Can is different from should.
Rym: Yeah, I just will.
Rym: There's a surplus of shots available.
Rym: So it's not like I'm taking one.
Scott: I mean, that's not a problem, right?
Scott: But it's still, it's like, should you?
Scott: Do you need to?
Rym: Yeah, you.
Rym: probably there's a lot of evidence that immunity from all the vaccines wanes over time.
Rym: And that seems to be a big part of the rise in infections in Europe.
Scott: Well, then how come they don't just come out and say I should get?
Scott: they said I should I just go get it.
Scott: I'd be like, oh, OK.
Scott: But if they're saying you can, it's like, you know, well, now I don't know if I should.
Rym: Yeah, I'm pretty much going to get it because I can.
Rym: So I'm getting it next Monday.
Rym: I got an appointment.
Scott: I mean, I guess, you know, my doctor like the same policy I had.
Rym: I asked one medical, I asked one medical, like, hey, should I get it?
Rym: They were like, absolutely do it.
Scott: I guess I could ask my actual doctor.
Scott: But, you know, last time I waited and without any prompting whatsoever, my doctor was like, come get it.
Scott: And now, well, there's been no such promptings.
Rym: I have in my entire adult life never been to the same doctor more than once.
Scott: I'm going to why I went to this one doctor, like, I guess after I moved to the city.
Scott: So I guess oh, nine.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or maybe.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, I guess.
Scott: And that since late 2000s, I went to a doctor at this office, NYU office.
Scott: And then the doctor, like, was the best doctor ever saw.
Scott: Regular doctor, at least.
Scott: And then, like, I only saw him twice.
Scott: And then he went away to Florida to become like a big medical director.
Scott: And I was like, I guess he was too good a doctor.
Rym: Oh, what happened to me was every.
Scott: And then I just kept going to the same office and I just got shifted to another doctor in the same office.
Scott: And he's OK.
Scott: But I've been seeing that one doctor for, you know, many years.
Rym: See, I used to have an HSA like back when, you know, before Obamacare and ACA.
Rym: So I really never went to the doctor unless I was sick and I got a physical like every few years.
Rym: So every time I went to get a physical, whatever doctor had been my PCP had left the practice and I had to start all over with a new doctor.
Rym: And then I changed insurances and my doctor didn't take the insurance multiple times.
Rym: So that kept happening.
Rym: And then now in these times, I started getting a physical every year because I'm approaching 40.
Rym: And every single year, my PCP either stops being a doctor or like leaves the practice and I get a new doctor every single time.
Scott: Pretty sure my doctor is still there because he's still in the app from the office.
Rym: But even my doctor now said, yeah, you don't really need a physical every year.
Rym: There's nothing.
Rym: there is nothing wrong with you whatsoever.
Rym: She was like.
Rym: I was like, can I get a get a colonoscopy?
Rym: Like I'm approaching 40.
Rym: She was like, no, not at all.
Rym: There is literally no reason for you to do anything.
Rym: So, yeah, I might change doctors again just to get some.
Scott: I usually tell the doctor, you know, usually when I go to the doctor, they're like, I'm like, there's things wrong with me.
Scott: And they're like, no, there isn't.
Rym: Yeah, well, I don't know.
Rym: I have nothing wrong with me except some sports medicine stuff, but I have a separate doctor for sports medicine because of a program my insurance does.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But this is not to help you if you're sick or anything.
Rym: This is literally like medically driven sports, like athlete training stuff.
Rym: so I can get like my knee worked on and do running clinics.
Rym: I haven't done any of that because covid, but probably next year I'll start going into that clinic once a week to do like running studies and things.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, we got some news anime NYC.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Anime NYC is happening this weekend.
Scott: We're not going there.
Scott: No, it's in the Javits Center and is a lot of good stuff that's happening there.
Scott: There's like there's another Bell preview screening, but I think it's separately ticketed.
Scott: So you have to.
Scott: I don't know if you need an anime NYC ticket.
Scott: I think you do.
Scott: And then you need to get the Bell ticket in addition.
Rym: We have never been to anime NYC.
Scott: I think they've got a My Hero Academia music guy.
Scott: He's like a big guest.
Scott: People are excited about.
Rym: That's a big show that I kind of bounced off of.
Scott: But yeah, there's a. you know, if you look at the anime NYC like stuff, it's like, damn, this shit is for real.
Rym: We have not been to anime NYC, but we have seen how it goes.
Rym: We've I know people who have gone to it and we know a lot of people work on it.
Rym: We know a lot of people who work on it.
Rym: And it's basically like a who's who of who knows how to fuck to run a convention from like the world.
Rym: Like it's kind of amazing the team they got together.
Rym: So all indications are this is like one of the best top tier anime cons there is.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: But if you're a person who feels safe going to a convention in the New York City Javits Center this weekend, literally.
Rym: Yeah, the 19, 20, 21, you know, you got to be vaccinated, which is a plus and masking and like all the right stuff.
Rym: They're doing what they have.
Scott: It's right on the front of their website, all their policies and such.
Rym: So, yeah.
Scott: Yeah, there it is.
Rym: So in some other news, I'm not I'm still I'm not reserving judgment until I see it.
Rym: I'm going to watch the new Cowboy Bebop, obviously, so we can talk about it.
Scott: But something I held off my cancellation of Netflix just to watch that show.
Scott: And then as soon as I watch it, I'm going to cancel it because I'm on HBO Max right now.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Same.
Rym: I switched HBO Max mostly because of Dune, but there's a ton of other stuff I want to watch there.
Rym: So Netflix, as soon as I finish Cowboy Bebop and we're watching the last season of Lupin, not Lupin the Third, but Lupin, that French show.
Scott: Yeah, I was going to watch that.
Scott: But once I learned that it was like had more seasons, I'm like, well, I'll just go back to Netflix when it's all got more seasons and watch it.
Rym: It's real good, though.
Rym: And I think I think the season we're watching is the end.
Rym: I haven't checked, but it's good.
Scott: Oh, OK.
Rym: I'll confirm for you.
Rym: So you'll know because then you could binge it before you shut off Netflix.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: There's a lot of shows, for example, like Dragon Prince.
Scott: So I'm like, well, they said Dragon Prince is going to be eight seasons or so.
Rym: I can wait now.
Scott: That's like, well, I can cancel Netflix.
Scott: And then once season eight comes out, I'll turn Netflix back on and watch it, you know.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Because that's the thing is like I'm avoiding paying for cable TV.
Scott: If I sign up to eight subscription services all at once, I might as well get cable at that point.
Rym: Except cable doesn't have any of that shit.
Scott: Some of it.
Scott: But it's like I'm only really getting a good deal if I just go one at a time.
Scott: And as long as you know, there might be movies and things like that that they put up and take down from their services over time.
Scott: But the only reason to actually subscribe to one is for their exclusive shit.
Scott: And no one's going to take down their exclusive shit from their own platform.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That that live action cowboy beep boop is going to be on Netflix from the time it's ready until as long as Netflix exists.
Scott: Why would they ever take it down from the list?
Scott: There was some problem or something.
Rym: It's their show.
Rym: I generally.
Rym: we also like.
Rym: we rarely consume reviews of things like we were.
Scott: That would be like if Steam took Half Life 2 off of Steam.
Scott: Go get Half Life 2 on the Epic Store only.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That would be weird as hell.
Rym: But I tend not to read reviews of things like just in general because I don't read reviews of things either.
Rym: But it has been hard to ignore the fact that pretty much every review I have seen of the new Cowboy Bebop from any source, anime fans, non anime fans.
Scott: Well, I haven't seen any.
Scott: So I'm trusting you on this.
Rym: Small publications have ranged from mediocre to terrible.
Rym: And I have found zero positive reviews, which is a worrying sign.
Scott: So what I mean, it's not surprising.
Scott: I basically assume that all live action adaptations are met.
Scott: I think that, you know, if it is indeed met and what you're saying is true and the reviewers are correct and is bad, then that doesn't surprise me.
Scott: But what happened, what I do notice that I didn't watch too much of it, just like maybe one.
Rym: I watched the trailer and I went from the first trailer.
Rym: I got excited, like, wow, this might exceed expectations.
Rym: But the second trailer stylistically, it was amazing.
Rym: Like the style of how they shot it gave me all this hope.
Rym: But then when the actors started talking like the acting was really stiff, the dialogue was bad and stilted and it kind of sounded like a shitty anime dub.
Rym: Well, I mean, I didn't want to judge it based on that, but I like my danger sense suddenly started screaming at me like this is not going to be good.
Scott: I only watched one promotional item.
Scott: I don't know which of the many trailers it was.
Rym: Was it the one where Faye like grabs the frame around the scene and throws it away?
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: It was so long ago.
Scott: But what I did notice is other people who I know who were closely following all the promotional material.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Were clearly a getting hyped, having positive feelings and B were there was a clear attempt.
Scott: Even from someone who only watched a little bit of the promotional material, rationalization.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There was a clear attempt by Netflix to make people who are already fans of the original believe that Netflix and the people who worked on this cared about the original a lot.
Scott: And we're trying to honor it appropriately.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So and if you took them in good faith, that's a reason as a fan of the original, which is still an all time masterpiece artwork like Mona Lisa level.
Scott: It's like that.
Scott: the live action would not be like every other garbage live action anime adaptation ever.
Scott: But, uh, you know, I still have no idea.
Scott: I'm going to watch it and find out.
Scott: I didn't see any of these reviews that Rym is talking about.
Rym: So, yeah, what I'll link to is the most charitable review I could find, which was from the Atlantic.
Rym: What's lost when a classic anime is adapted by Netflix?
Rym: The charm of the original Cowboy Bebop and many other Japanese animated series is not just in its style, but its storytelling.
Rym: And my prediction about how Bebop will be, we'll see if I'm right or wrong, I'll put this out there, is that it's going to be shot really stylistically well.
Rym: It'll look beautiful.
Rym: The music will be fantastic.
Rym: But I have this suspicion the writing story and dialogue is just going to be still too bad.
Scott: I mean, I basically assume that of all live action television productions, period.
Scott: Especially from the United States.
Rym: You're weird, though, because you don't watch anything.
Scott: Movies.
Scott: I don't know what it is.
Scott: I still can't explain it.
Scott: But, you know, movie acting is not the same as the vast majority of TV acting.
Scott: There's something about, you know, TV production.
Rym: What was the last live action TV show you watched to completion?
Scott: I guess The Mandalorian was the last time this stood out for me.
Scott: Where it was like, yeah, this is not like a movie.
Scott: See, I took the opposite.
Rym: It felt more like a Star Wars movie than any Star Wars movie that's come out since like...
Scott: I didn't even watch past what we watched to do that show on it and I have no desire to ever do that.
Rym: See, this is why I don't trust your opinion on this stuff because you don't watch anything.
Scott: Which is why I think you have bad taste.
Scott: You just like trash.
Rym: Yeah, okay.
Rym: You can continue to watch whatever it is that you watch.
Scott: Whatever other garbage you play.
Rym: But you don't play any video games either.
Scott: Yeah, I have very high standards.
Scott: I have a very short life.
Scott: I'm going to be living.
Scott: I only eat the finest goods, right?
Scott: If something is kind of good, nope, that's not good enough.
Scott: Get it out of here.
Rym: So, uh, yeah.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So, this Twitter account is... I appreciate it.
Rym: It's funny but not funny in the normal sense.
Rym: It's called "Simpson Crap Memes" and it does something that I haven't really seen anywhere else and I enjoy it.
Rym: It's almost similar to like, there was the vaporwave movement, which is a real musical movement.
Rym: And there was the, like, weird subgenre.
Scott: I don't know if it's a movement as much as a genre.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I would argue, and I've seen some arguments since the fact that it was a movement but a small one.
Rym: A very small one.
Rym: But many movements are small.
Rym: But there was the subgenre of that that was Simpsonwave, which was a legitimate subgenre with multiple people making earnest content.
Rym: Which is crazy that that existed and that I'm saying those words, but I do stand by them.
Rym: But what this account does is they make fairly complex memes from The Simpsons that mash up extremely obscure parts of The Simpsons in ways that are, like, accurate and true.
Rym: Like, they're not a stretch.
Rym: They are accurate and true and funny, but they require a terrifying amount of Simpsons, like, deep knowledge and memory of extremely obscure parts of The Simpsons to understand at all.
Rym: And this is the kind of humor that I appreciate, but I also understand why very few other people appreciate it.
Scott: That's the idea, right?
Scott: An inside joke is funnier to the people, but obviously it's inside.
Scott: Most people, it's not funny to them.
Scott: So the more inside the joke is, you actually sort of this hidden gold that only a few people can taste this amazing flavor.
Rym: If nobody but you and one other person, or even just you get it, then it almost fails.
Rym: Like some of those Jackbox social games where you're trying to get one other person, or dicks it too, to figure it out, but not too many people to figure it out, but not nobody.
Rym: This is like straddling that line in a way that is deeply pleasing to my soul.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: Anyway, so there's this person, and their name is on Twitter, is Magiteknight.
Scott: Goodnight.
Scott: You know, like Final Fantasy 6.
Rym: Two underscores, probably to get away from some other account with one underscore.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But this person makes, among other things, I assume, dioramas.
Rym: Dioramas are a fantastic hobby.
Scott: And they were commissioned by somebody with a lot of money to make a very large diorama of- Oh shit, that's a banana!
Rym: I just realized how big this thing is.
Scott: Yeah, it's huge.
Scott: If you go on the Twitter thread, there's photos without the banana.
Rym: It weighs thirty-five pounds!
Scott: Yeah, it's enormous.
Scott: So yeah, they commissioned this person to make this very large diorama of the scene in Final Fantasy 6, where the Ultros attacks the party on the raft, and they, of course, I guess in accordance with the amount of money they were paid, which had to be a large amount, they did a large job, and you have to fucking see this thing, 'cause you don't have to pay for it.
Scott: Whoever's gonna keep it in their house can pay for it, and the rest of us can right-click it.
Scott: So, everyone's seen it.
Scott: You got all the same enjoyment out of it that the person who paid for it got.
Scott: They're just footing the bill for the rest of us, so don't miss your chance to look at this holy shit diorama.
Scott: You could've put this thing in any number of anime convention art shows and won all the prizes, and you didn't.
Rym: I imagine even at the height of the Otakon Artist Alley, like that giant art auction, this would've been the thing that had an infinite number of bids.
Scott: I also think that, yeah, the price the person paid for this, I'm gonna guess, is lower than what it would go for at auction.
Rym: Oh, absolutely.
Rym: Some rich nerd would pro-.
Rym: If I had to guess, a rich nerd would be willing to pay several thousand dollars for this.
Rym: I'm sure the person paid several thousand, but I think, for example, right now- A rich nerd being willing to pay seven or eight thousand dollars for something like this.
Scott: I think they'd pay, you know, at auction, I think that might be what, more like, closer to the price that was paid to commission.
Rym: Well, yeah, to your point, an auction.
Rym: Especially a charity auction.
Scott: If you auction this, it's gonna be tens, five digits at least.
Rym: Public auctions, if they're run the right way, will drive the price way higher than a direct sale would be.
Scott: Right, well, I mean, for example, right, Desert Bus is happening right now, and they have many, part of Desert Bus, they have many parts of it, but is they auction off items for charity, and they have both people who, A, spend the year planning a big fancy thing to craft to put up for auction as a donation, right?
Scott: And B, people who save money all year in order to purchase, right?
Scott: So, I saw somebody, what were they auctioning?
Scott: It was a cross-stitch, but it was a very high resolution cross-stitch, right?
Scott: Like a zillion stitches that took, like, months to make of a scene from the Sandman comic, and that thing went for almost, like, not 10k, but, like, maybe seven or eight, somewhere up there, right?
Scott: So, this thing's going for more than that, for sure.
Scott: I'd be really curious.
Scott: But, yeah, this is, you know.
Scott: Just look at this.
Rym: Real quick meta-moments, we can get right into it.
Rym: The Giganized Book Club book, Tale of Genji, ending by the end of the year, come hell or high water.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, high water might come.
Rym: High water might come, but I feel like even if high water comes, we will still finish that book and do the show on it.
Rym: I got a lot of batteries and 5G.
Rym: I will be at PAX Unplugged for a couple hours to do one panel, Rare Game Mechanics, on the Friday, December, whatever day that is, at 1pm in the Crab God Theater, I think.
Rym: It'll be on YouTube.
Rym: Don't go to PAX Unplugged if you're not already going to PAX Unplugged.
Rym: Like, don't go there just to see that panel.
Rym: I'm literally recording it.
Rym: I'm going to put it on YouTube before PAX Unplugged even ends.
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Rym: Let's get right into it.
Rym: Rebuild of Evangelion.
Rym: So, if you're new to Giganized...
Scott: Let's start with, you want to just start with the first one, or you got to do some general comment first?
Rym: I want to do a general comment that we are, we've done this pattern in the past.
Rym: We do it not that often now because we just don't watch shows to their completion that are worthy of this for a lot of reasons lately.
Scott: Same show to their completion.
Rym: But, we have this concept of a final thought show, as opposed to a review.
Rym: And the difference is, when we review a show, we review it without spoiling things, and without assuming you've seen it.
Scott: We're trying to tell you if you should watch it or not.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Since you haven't watched it.
Rym: So, that's what we already did for the Rebuild of Evangelion.
Scott: This show is for people who have already seen it and just want to enjoy talking about it.
Rym: So, we're going to assume you have seen the Rebuild of Evangelion, and...
Scott: Or you don't give a shit.
Rym: Or you don't give a shit.
Scott: Which is perfectly valid because I don't believe in spoilers either.
Scott: If I hadn't seen it, I would listen to this show.
Rym: You're not going to know what the fuck we're talking about when we start talking about the Kia Nebuchadnezzar and what that was all about.
Rym: But also, we're going to spoil, effectively, the original Evangelion, and the original movies, and pretty much every possible media related to Evangelion.
Rym: Except the manga, which we haven't read to completion yet, but is very similar to the show, and thus we're definitely spoiling that as well.
Scott: And the Playstation game stuff, where fans like to get a lot of lore from.
Scott: that's not canon anywhere else except the Playstation game and whatnot.
Rym: Yep, Evangelion 2.
Rym: If you watch these movies and then you try to go to the Ava Wikis to figure out parts that you didn't understand, you're going to bump into lore from that Apocrypha.
Rym: Which, honestly, doesn't change anything.
Rym: It actually just adds tiny amounts of irrelevant context.
Rym: Like, it gives you a little more about Adam and Lilith and the slight differences between them.
Rym: But, those are things that you could infer from the media as shown without those games.
Scott: Anyway, so, overall, I said this when we did a review episode, but the Rebuild movies are not a prequel, they're not a sequel, they're not a remake.
Scott: Like, what's a good example of a remake?
Rym: There's so many of them.
Rym: So, there was El Hazzard, which had an OAV, and then they remade that OAV as a longer television anime.
Rym: But it wasn't, like, a sequel, it was just a parallel universe.
Rym: Like, same characters, same basic story, but things go differently.
Rym: Tenchi Muyo did the same thing.
Rym: There was an OAV, then they made multiple different TV series that aren't in the same continuity, they just use the same characters and the same kind of story.
Scott: Okay, so a good example of a remake would be something like The Ring, right?
Scott: Where you had the original one, and then they made an English one.
Scott: Or there were several Oceans, were there two Oceans?
Scott: There's at least two Oceans Elevens.
Rym: I think there's three Oceans at this point.
Scott: They redid Planet of the Apes at some point, right?
Rym: Train to Busan is apparently getting a US remake called Last Train to New York.
Rym: Breaking news, I guess.
Scott: Yeah, but basically, you know, a remake is like, "Okay, that person made that thing, I'm just gonna make the same fucking thing
Scott: again.".
Scott: This is not what that is either, right?
Scott: So, I think it's really appropriate that it called it Rebuild, because upon watching it, it is sort of a, you know, it's none of those other things, right?
Rym: You could make an argument that, you could argue that it occurs in the same continuity of the show with a giant, complicated asterisk, but you could also just say that...
Scott: It's not a strict multiverse time loop thing, even though it's close to one.
Rym: But it's also not a Leiji Matsumoto verse of, "Yeah, it's just these same characters doing something completely
Rym: different.".
Rym: Imagine taking the original Evangelion, breaking it down into all of its component parts, like a Lego set, and rebuilding something from those same parts.
Scott: With some new parts.
Rym: And a bunch of new parts.
Scott: And some parts removed.
Rym: So, you buy the Space Shuttle Lego set.
Rym: You build the Space Shuttle.
Rym: It's cool.
Rym: You tear it down.
Rym: You buy the Ice Planet Hoth set.
Scott: Or not even tearing it down, but necessarily, like, just, it's so old that, you know, it's taken damage, right?
Rym: Take a few pieces away, take the Ice Planet Hoth set, and rebuild it bigger and different, but also the same.
Scott: Okay, so movie one, we don't need to spend too much time on movie one, except for two items, right?
Scott: Because movie one is identical to the television show, pretty much in every way, except for two things.
Scott: First thing is there is the scene where Masato takes Shinji down to the terminal dogma in the basement.
Rym: That happens way earlier.
Scott: And, right, so that scene was in the original, but in the TV, in the movie, it happens earlier.
Scott: And I think that it was just, it's not really any different, but it was necessary because it has to show both the audience and Shinji.
Scott: Like, you know, because up until that point in the story, Shinji doesn't really understand what's at stake.
Scott: Like, "Oh, the angels are trying to get to this physical place to bring about this apocalypse,
Scott: basically.".
Rym: Yes, if an angel touches this thing, everyone dies.
Scott: And that's what you're trying to prevent, Shinji, and also telling the audience, like, "Hey, that's what's happening here.
Scott: We're trying to keep the angels from reaching the
Scott: spot.".
Rym: Now, there are a bunch of other minor, like, plot beats from later episodes of the show.
Rym: that happened earlier and happened in the first movie, but they're not important like this one was.
Scott: But I would argue it is.
Scott: That was a significant difference, and the other significant difference is the very end of the first movie.
Rym: The last 30 seconds of this movie.
Rym: The last 30 seconds.
Scott: So, in the last 30 seconds, you see Kaoru on the moon coming out of a coffin, and there are many coffins, and some of them have lids on, and some of them are open.
Scott: So, clearly, they're showing you right here that, like, yeah, this has happened before, and it's gonna happen again.
Scott: We got a whole bunch of Kaoru's lined up, right?
Scott: This is the current one.
Scott: He's on the moon somehow, and he's looking at, basically, an Evangelion/Angel being constructed, right, which I think ends up being Eva 5 or 6 that he pilots, right?
Scott: There's so many Evas.
Scott: He pilots it at the end of the second movie, but basically, there's this Eva being made on the moon that he's gonna pilot, and he talks to it, and he says very little, but the little he says says a whole lot.
Rym: He basically says the equivalent of, "Alright, Shinji.
Rym: Let's do
Rym: this.".
Scott: Right.
Scott: He's sort of like, "Oh, you're the X-th number this time.
Scott: You know, the 12-th, or whatever.
Scott: You'd never change,
Scott: right?".
Rym: I thought at that point, at that moment, before having not seen the rest of the movies yet, what I thought was, those were all the Sele people, and then he was up there, too, and he was talking about Sele Chairman #3.
Scott: Okay, so we learned the deal with that scene in movie #2, right?
Scott: While in movie #2, right, Futski Friday and Gendo get in a rocket, and they go into space.
Scott: They're literally in space.
Rym: It's very similar to the scene in the original show where they go to the Antarctic to do the thing, but...
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: It's a replacement for that.
Rym: Because remember, and we're assuming you've seen these movies, after, from the beginning of the last 30 seconds of the first movie, the show goes off the rails.
Rym: After the second movie, it goes off of the concept of rails to, like, this new reality of space rails.
Rym: And then the final movie is, at this point, it's almost like a promare, like, ridiculous spectacle.
Scott: So anyway, so this scene where they're going up to the moon, right?
Scott: The movies keep what the TV show had, which is that relationship between NERV and Sele, where Sele is supposedly the big Illuminati organization that's running everything, and NERV is working for them, but Gendo running NERV has his own ideas.
Rym: Let's break it down.
Rym: From the original show, what we knew was NERV was the successor agency to Geherne, and both NERV and Geherne were created for different purposes by Sele.
Rym: Sele is pulling the strings of the UN, and all the other organizations involved are just chumps who don't know what's up and all get chumped.
Rym: But of course, the new movies, we see further evolutions, where Geherne failed for a bunch of reasons, became NERV, NERV splits into NERV and WIL.
Rym: Arguably, I would say WIL and the Wunder and all that, that's free will, like, that is the third path, or the fourth way, or when we get into bed and play.
Rym: I say the fourth way because you would get that inside joke.
Rym: The moon literally is trying to eat your soul in this fucking movie.
Scott: Right, so they go into space in a rocket, because I guess there's nothing, they know something's happening on the moon, but they can't see it, and there's no other way for them to see it, other than literally getting in a rocket and looking out the window.
Scott: And also, that just happens to basically make the plot work to where Gendo and Futsuki aren't on Earth during that angel battle.
Scott: So Misato has to take to run the show there.
Scott: But regardless, they look out the window and they see the thing from the end of the first movie.
Scott: They see the EVA being constructed.
Scott: And that's basically the EVA that they had no hand in making.
Scott: They had a hand in making all the other ones.
Scott: But that's the one that Seilei made on its own.
Scott: that's gonna carry out their opposition.
Scott: If we're gonna do our own deal and not necessarily do exactly what Seilei wants, we gotta go spy on their plans.
Rym: And I do appreciate how it kept that continuity of.
Rym: Gendo and Futsuki are trying to use NERV for their own purposes, and they're pretending to go along with Seilei.
Scott: Well, Futsuki is just sort of, I don't know if his purpose is just to help Gendo's purpose.
Rym: Well, I want to get to that.
Rym: I got a lot of thoughts on Futsuki because I didn't expect him to have his big moment at the end.
Scott: Is he a Futsuki fanboy?
Rym: I really like Futsuki as a character for a lot of reasons.
Scott: Oh, the old man?
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Well, partly because the manga actually gets way more into him.
Rym: That's one thing you're missing.
Scott: I'm sure it does.
Rym: And he's got an interesting deal.
Rym: Pretty sure he really wants it.
Scott: Sadly, the movies as a whole don't basically cut out so much Ritsuko action.
Rym: Oh, they cut out Ritsuko and they cut out the manga stuff.
Scott: She's there, but she's not really doing much.
Rym: But you do see her and Maya actually grow as characters and become interesting in ways that could not have happened in the original show because of what we know about Ritsuko's mom.
Rym: But I appreciate that Gendo and Futsuki were trying to use NERV for their own purposes.
Rym: They're going along with Seilei and pretending to work with them.
Rym: Seilei knows that Gendo's going to betray them and doesn't give a shit because they think they can prevent him from fucking them over.
Rym: And they know that he knows that they know.
Rym: This is all explicit.
Rym: But they need him to defeat a certain number of angels or their plan fails anyway.
Rym: So they have to let the person who they know is going to betray them do the work he needs to do.
Rym: And it's literally a prisoner's dilemma of who betrays who first and how.
Rym: And both Seilei and NERV think that they have got it under control.
Rym: And I love how well that translated into the Rebuild movies from the original.
Scott: You know, I think this just comes from playing too many board games.
Scott: I can't help but look at these movies in terms of that, right?
Scott: In both what you just pointed out, but also, you know, if you play a game like Dune or any political game, we always have that scenario where it's like so-and-so's going to win on next turn unless you stop them.
Scott: So-and-so's going to win on the next turn unless you stop them.
Scott: And basically movie one doesn't really fall into that.
Scott: But movies two, three, and four basically all end, all of them.
Scott: The end of movie two is it's about to happen, right?
Scott: It's about to happen unless you stop it and they stop it.
Scott: Movie three at the end is going to happen unless you stop it.
Scott: Someone stops it.
Scott: And movie 3.0 plus 1.0, it's going to happen unless you stop it.
Scott: And then it just sort of happens.
Rym: Well, but arguably the end-end movies are the coalition of people who want the thing that will actually end the game.
Rym: Gang up and end the game.
Scott: Alright, so the rest of movie two.
Scott: Alright, so movie two- It starts out introducing, you know, Mari, right?
Rym: The new character.
Scott: We should talk about her.
Rym: And also, you know, showing us- She basically replaces a lot of what Asuka did in the original Eva, but not all of it.
Scott: And also, what's the, you know, the kid who dies in the first- Yeah, Koji.
Scott: You know, he's in the movies, but Mari takes a lot of his stuff too.
Rym: Well, what I like is that the first movie was just the recap up until the preview.
Rym: Actually, we got to talk about that too.
Rym: I love that every one of these movies, after the credits, has a preview of the next movie just like it's the original TV show, even with the same music.
Rym: Well, of course the last one doesn't.
Rym: But every one of those previews shows you things that are so fucking ridiculous and cannot be parsed based on what you just watched.
Rym: I can't imagine having watched 3.0, seeing the preview for 4.0 or 3.0 plus
Rym: 1.0. 3.0
Rym: plus 1.0.
Rym: And having to wait from 2016 to 2021 to see how that happens.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay, so Mari comes into the picture.
Scott: She's a new Eva pilot.
Scott: And where she came from was, I guess, like this other place.
Scott: Oh, I love this.
Scott: In the original TV show, they basically do tell you, like, yeah, there are other nerve bases with other Avas in America.
Rym: There's an American nerve in Nevada that disappears.
Rym: It's a plot point in the original Ava.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And there's also the episode with the lava in the original TV series, right, where the Ava goes in the lava.
Scott: And I'm pretty sure in that episode, they're working with some, you know, other...
Rym: Yeah, remember, Asuka was at Asuka on Unit 02, where a transfer from that other organization.
Scott: They came from the European branch or whatever, right?
Scott: So, but here, they're actually showing us the other branch, right?
Rym: Oh, even better, while the movies kind of gave up on Fuyutsuki's full deal, and they didn't follow Ritsuko and all that stuff.
Rym: What they did do is show you, remember in the original show, Kaji was up to something, but they only show you tiny pieces of what he was up to.
Rym: In this movie, they show you what Kaji was up to pretty heavily.
Rym: But my favorite moment was at the beginning of that, when Mari and Kaji and all them are doing their European thing to stop that angel from escaping.
Rym: And the Ava self-destructs, and Kaji's like, "I hate to use a kid for my plans, but this is real
Rym: important.".
Rym: And he goes off to do his thing, probably with the Kia Nebuchadnezzar.
Rym: But Mari then is floating in the escape pod, and she's like, "Ah, I hate to fuck over an adult for my secret plan, but you gotta do what you gotta
Rym: do.".
Rym: And then, in the third movie, basically what she was trying to do at the end of the second movie was, as far as I would say, merge with the Ava, using the backup codes to unrestrain it, and trigger the impact herself and become a god.
Rym: It feels like that's what she was trying to do, and she got interrupted by Karu and all the other nonsense.
Scott: So yeah, at the beginning of the second movie, they're at this Bethany base, which is not the Japanese nerve we're used to.
Scott: And at this Bethany base, the third angel is locked up.
Scott: It's not dead, it was sealed.
Scott: And I guess that happened before even the first movie.
Rym: You get all this mechanical lore and all this really fun sci-fi nonsense about how they deal with the angels.
Scott: You enter both the TV series and, I presume, the manga and these movies, they all start when Shinji is brought into the picture.
Scott: All the stuff that happens before is a mystery to the audience and to Shinji.
Scott: So, in the TV show, the only things that really happened before Shinji showed up was all the stuff at the South Pole, pretty much.
Scott: But in the movies, there's this other stuff that happened before, including trapping this third angel.
Scott: And so what happens there when Mari is fighting the third angel with this makeshift, shitty Eva that's available there.
Rym: It's like a big provisional, like she's not even in the final plug suit design or anything.
Scott: Yeah, but basically, it's implied that Kaji sort of let that angel loose to steal the key of Nebuchadnezzar for Gendo.
Scott: And the battle is a distraction, so you can get away with it.
Scott: So, why does Kaji want to steal the key of Nebuchadnezzar and give it to Gendo?
Rym: Yeah, well, remember the original show, Kaji was kind of playing both sides.
Scott: He stole the Adam embryo thing and gave it to Gendo instead of the key of Nebuchadnezzar.
Rym: Yep, to give to Gendo, so Gendo could graft it into his own body, so he could then, as Adam, merge with Eva.
Rym: Well, merge with Lilith via Eva as a vessel, which was embodied in Rei, which was a clone that had the salvaged soul of Lilith, to then trigger the third impact himself, become a god, reunite with you.
Rym: Like, that was his specific plan.
Rym: The original show is very straightforward about what he was trying to do there.
Rym: And he's basically trying to do the same thing, and Kaji is letting this happen in both that and the rebuild, because he has his own goals, and I still think his main goal was that he wanted all of this bullshit to fail and humanity to survive.
Rym: I think that's all he actually cared about.
Scott: Well, yeah, because in both the movie and the TV show, right, he's always planting his watermelons and whatnot, right?
Rym: But planting the watermelons was, look, the whole point of this is so that we can have lives.
Rym: That's the only reason we're fighting.
Rym: Remember that.
Rym: And in the movie, it brings that back, like Shinji comes to, just like in the original show, because he remembers the smell of the ocean that Kaji showed him in movie two, and he remembers the smell of the earth, and he remembers that maybe humanity is worth saving independent of the cosmic space nonsense.
Rym: Maybe humanity is not ready to destroy itself and become something different.
Rym: Maybe we're still very young.
Scott: In the original TV show, right, you get sort of those famous scenes that I love so much, where it's a quiet, empty city with cicada noises, all the people have left, right?
Scott: Eventually, it's like NERV is just hollowed out, except for the few people that are left there, which are the main characters of the show.
Rym: Humanity has died out, the room of golf was empty and sealed, and in the original show, what were they even fighting for at the end, when there weren't even that many humans left?
Scott: Yep, presumably there were, just far away from Japan.
Rym: But look at that contrast in the Rebuild movie two, because movie one was kind of rushed because it tried to condense so much, just to set the stage for the differences, but movie two spent so much time showing you humans, the dense, smelly mass of humans.
Scott: Things of people working at NERV, something you didn't see before.
Rym: But even outside of NERV, just living their lives, like, there's kids going to school.
Scott: There were a lot of scenes of showing the city's buildings going up and down through the, you know, and, like, all the people who lived in the city.
Scott: There was never that sort of evacuation point, really, where the city's empty.
Rym: And even, like, in the later movies, you see Paris and all the other cities that were just like that, like, there's this feeling that humanity itself, as it is, is worth saving and cherishing, independent of the whole Adam and Lilith situation out in space.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, there's, you know, Shinji basically was like, you know, in the TV show, all he had as, like, you know, motivation to win.
Scott: It's like, it's like, you know, you have that, like, the scene, right?
Scott: Where Misato comes down is like, yeah, see, the angels are trying to do this, which will destroy everyone.
Scott: It's like, oh, okay, well, that's bad.
Scott: But if there's no humans left, if everyone's, there's almost nobody left, it's like, I'm really just fighting for what, this handful of people?
Rym: Yeah, well, I'm fighting for my shitty dad to be shitty forever as a god, or I'm fighting for a bunch of old men running against conspiracy theory to be gods.
Scott: In the movies, they keep people around in some, you know, they show you both, you know, apocalypse, lots of people dying, like, the whole bottom of the planet.
Rym: But then they always show you, there's still some humans hanging on, like, humans are surprisingly resilient, and that is an overarching theme.
Scott: They actually, those humans were there in the original TV show, but the camera never really went to them after a certain point.
Scott: You just didn't see them.
Scott: In the movies, they keep showing you all the people that are still there, and also the ones that have been obliterated by half-apocalypses.
Rym: Like, I really like, in the end, like, where you see the village, where everyone is, like, there's still humans, even after the near-third impact, like, just living their lives.
Rym: And you get that whole side story of Rey, like, a clone Rey who didn't know shit, living a life among humans and, like, getting it 100%.
Scott: Yeah, and then being, you know, rather, she chose to continue living that life with humans and then disintegrating, rather than to go back to what she was doing before.
Rym: Well, what she was doing before was, it's very clear that the dummy plug systems of the thousands of Ava and Ava-like things that are out there in the second two movies, they're all powered by memoryless clones of either Karu or Rey, and this is just one of those infinite sea of clones.
Rym: But, remember, when she died, you get a tiny little cross, just like when any Ava or any angel gets destroyed, but also, 'cause one thing that was added to the movies that was very important was the rainbows.
Rym: Those little rainbows that occur, concurrent to the crosses appearing, 'cause sometimes crosses happen without rainbows, and sometimes crosses happen with rainbows, sometimes rainbows happen on their own, and toward the end, rainbows become halos.
Rym: Every time a rainbow appears, it's because a soul was involved, and it's very important that when Shinji sees that Rey die, there's the tiny little cross, just like an angel died, and there's a tiny little rainbow around that cross.
Rym: That little Rey had at least some soul there, which-- Some left.
Scott: Well, a soul at all-- It's really reminiscent of Ghost in the Shell, when you're copying people's cyberbrain system.
Rym: Yep, the degradation of ghost dubbing.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Rym: But I think that's really important, because this show does act-- the original show got into the room of golf, and that's where souls come from.
Scott: We talked about the room of golf in the movies a little bit.
Rym: In the rebuild, the rebuilds actually get into the science fiction aspect of, "Nope, those doors can be opened by this set of situations,
Rym: specifically.".
Rym: Adam and Willis have their own rooms of golf, probably.
Scott: Well, yeah, because they're in the big spheres.
Scott: The rest of the second movie is mostly just angel battling, but unlike the first movie, it's battling way different angels.
Rym: It's battling different angels, and always in the context of, "Remember what you're fighting
Rym: for.".
Rym: The human life around it is what you're fighting for.
Rym: It really focuses on that, and it also has all the same beats as that second part of the original show, but they're all remixed.
Rym: An angel takes over an Eva, but it's Asuka piling it instead of Toji.
Rym: The same things happen, but different people are involved, so I kept seeing, "Oh, the thing I expect is going to happen,".
Rym: and then, "Wait a minute, it's going a different
Rym: way.".
Scott: So, at the end of the second movie, what's going to happen is an impact is coming, right?
Rym: I love that so much.
Rym: It's like Sele and Nerve.
Rym: Imagine if everyone who is planning all their bullshit, and then somebody just suddenly triggers a victory condition way early in the game.
Scott: Exactly, so in the original, in the TV show, Unit 1 eats the core of that one angel, right?
Rym: Pretty late in the show.
Scott: Right, and that's how it achieves god levels of power, but it doesn't become a god at that moment.
Scott: It doesn't have the keys.
Scott: Right, so it takes a little bit longer.
Scott: Here, it all happens at once, right?
Scott: The core, the angel, and I think the core of Unit 0 gets absorbed into Unit 1, and the wings come out right away.
Scott: It compresses that whole thing all into one, and then it's like, "Well, here comes the impact at the end of only Movie 2,".
Scott: and you know two more of these movies are coming.
Rym: That was the moment, watching the show, watching that movie, because you'd already seen it when we talked about it.
Rym: I was just like, when I watched it, I remember thinking, "All right, so this must have been why Scott was freaking
Rym: out.".
Rym: So, the third impact is about to happen, and then, out of nowhere, spare vlog-a-doos from the sky.
Scott: So, that's after the credits.
Scott: That's the one thing.
Scott: If you just end the movie before the credits, you don't see the very, very important scene afterwards.
Scott: You would end Movie 2 thinking, "Third impact, go watch Movie
Scott: 3.".
Rym: But also thinking, "What could possibly happen in a third, let alone a fourth movie, if this is the third
Rym: impact?".
Rym: Because the third impact in the original was the entire end of the show at once.
Scott: So, after the credits, there's a very, very brief scene where Kaoru comes down from the moon with the Eva that was being made on the moon, this whole moon thing, and he takes a lance.
Scott: You don't know which one yet, right?
Rym: Well, which one?
Rym: There was only one in the original show, so already we're in uncharted territory.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He lances Shinji to basically pause the third impact to stop it right there.
Scott: And that's what allows Movie 3 to even exist.
Rym: So, and I can't stress enough, Movie 2 came out in 2009, Movie 3 came out in 2012, and then Movie 3, when it finally came out, alright, it's been 16 years.
Rym: Shinji was de-caporialized inside of that Eva that entire time.
Rym: There's space shit going on, there's all these other people, Misato betrayed NERV.
Rym: There aren't rails anymore, we're on the Galaxy Express, and we're past Metallia and heading off into the...
Scott: Going into Movie 3, it starts out, it reminds me a lot of some Gundam movies.
Scott: There's something at a space satellite that someone's trying to steal.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, what the hell's going on here?
Scott: I just saw a third impact that was paused midway.
Scott: What is the state of the world now?
Scott: You have no fucking clue what the state of the world is now.
Scott: How are we even continuing from that point?
Scott: Are we just going to start over again?
Scott: I thought Movie 3 might have just started over from the beginning.
Scott: again, Shinji on a subway.
Rym: Yeah, because like you said, all those characters on the Wunder and everything, they feel so much like Gundam seed-type characters.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, they've created this new, completely new territory here at the beginning, slowly revealed to you over the course of the third movie, where NERV has split into two groups.
Scott: Right, the Will group and original NERV.
Scott: Original NERV is basically just Gendo, Futski, Kaoru, and Rei.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: There's no one left.
Rym: And whatever's left of Lilith's soul and...
Scott: And whatever's left of the equipment that NERV still had.
Scott: A large part of the Earth is destroyed in the half-third impact.
Rym: There's little pockets of humanity living on top of giant...
Scott: Not everybody.
Rym: But they're living on top of like giant, complicated-looking sphere of longaners looking like pyramid things, or they're living in like these handful of zones.
Rym: Ava technology is off the charts.
Rym: There's Ava's fucking everywhere.
Rym: Everybody's got AT fields, and it's just like space nonsense.
Scott: Yeah, so the Will organization, which is, you know, basically everyone else, right, Masato mostly, but everybody else, is basically fighting against NERV somehow, and is also fighting to preserve whatever humanity remains on Earth, right?
Scott: Gendo doesn't seem to care too much about that at all.
Scott: No, he didn't.
Rym: Gendo gave zero fucks about any human being on Earth except Yui from the beginning.
Scott: Pretty much.
Scott: So Will is, you know, fighting for humanity.
Scott: So they rescue Shinji from space and, you know, incorporeal-ness.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: You know, they have Asuka and they have Mari, right?
Scott: They don't have Rei.
Rym: Asuka's back.
Rym: She's got an iPad.
Rym: She's an interesting character.
Rym: She's like a lot how Asuka from the original would have been if she was more fully realized and not destroyed by the psychological damage of the angel that invaded her brain.
Rym: And this is also the movie that gets a lot more into, the second movie does too, when they talk about plug depth entry and contamination.
Rym: In the original show, they don't actually address too specifically from a sci-fi angle what that means.
Rym: In movies two and three, that is like a big part of the plot is exactly what that means.
Scott: Okay, so they rescue Shinji, right?
Scott: They confirm that it's him, but they put this thing around his neck like Battle Royale.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: That'll explode.
Scott: so they can kill him and control him because he's basically super dangerous.
Scott: Like if he pilots an Eva, it could cause the apocalypse again.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: They don't want that to happen.
Scott: It's like they want to have Shinji, but they don't want to let him do anything because it's too dangerous.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: So Shinji sort of, you know, you see, he sees the positives and the negatives of the will side, and then he gets, goes over to the nerve side.
Scott: It's a very sort of, you know, cliche thing where, you know, you have a character, you know, you have two sides opposing each other and you have a character who, you know, goes from one side to the other and possibly back and, you know, sees the good and the bad sides of each of the two sides.
Rym: I got to say nerve.
Scott: Sort of a neutral perspective.
Scott: Nerve felt a lot.
Scott: I feel like a lot of stories have done this.
Scott: A lot of movies have done this.
Scott: I just can't think of any other examples right now.
Rym: Nerve on the moon and all the nerve bullshit from like the third movie and the fourth movie.
Rym: They reminded me a lot of Zybok, like that empire from Escaflowne compared to the rest of the world in Escaflowne.
Rym: It was like this black pyramid technologically driven like robot society.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know if you remember that too much.
Scott: Not too much.
Rym: But yes, I do enjoy both the cyclical parallelism that happens in movie two.
Rym: Shinji actually grows a lot and is a much better person and much more assertive.
Rym: and everyone's happier.
Rym: because at a few points along the way, Gendo says good job.
Rym: Misato explains something.
Rym: Like all along the way, Asuka admits something.
Rym: Like there are like five moments where someone explains something to Shinji, where in the original show they didn't say shit.
Rym: And as a result, Shinji is just a better person.
Rym: And you see everyone is doing better as a result.
Rym: Shinji works hard to just help Rei like live a better life and be happy.
Scott: I wasn't going to talk about any of this stuff until the end, Dan.
Rym: Oh, I wanted to talk about it because in the third movie.
Scott: That's the whole point of the whole thing.
Rym: But in the third movie, now you see Shinji realizes, it's clear he realizes that this isn't like the same Rei.
Rym: But he tries to do the same thing again.
Rym: But he gets more and more despairing because he's failing because she doesn't have that connection.
Rym: She doesn't actually come around until living with the humans in that refuge later.
Rym: And you see her almost come full circle and then the clone of Rei that Shinji tried to rehabilitate based on his experiences with the first Rei ends up being the one who rehabilitates Shinji.
Rym: I really like how that played out.
Scott: So Shinji is playing both sides here, right?
Scott: I forget.
Scott: Does he get like rescued by Nerve or like Rei comes and he goes with her by choice?
Rym: He leaves, he goes back with Rei by choice.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But anyway, so at Nerve, you know, he sees Kaoru there, hangs out with Kaoru, right?
Scott: He, you know, he doesn't see his dad too much, right?
Rym: Well, because his dad at that point is already grafting the key of Nebuchadnezzar into his soul.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: But basically what happens is they got the Mega Eva there.
Scott: What unit number is it?
Rym: Well, Unit 13 is like the super one.
Rym: Got to get a full of a wiki at this point.
Rym: There's so many Eva's and they're all like specifically distinct and you could literally do a 20 or 30 minute podcast.
Scott: But 13 is the one.
Scott: basically in the original TV series, you had the DDR episode, right?
Scott: Shinji and Asuka having to, you know, work in concert here.
Scott: They take that idea to the next level.
Scott: Shinji and Kaoru have to.
Scott: literally it's a dual plug, you know, Unit 13.
Scott: They have to go in together.
Rym: Well, because you need two souls to trigger the, I guess, now the fourth impact.
Scott: Well, yeah, and you need the two spears, right, Cassius and Longinus to do what Gendo wants to have happen.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So this is basically, you know, that this is the, you know, Unit 13 as opposed to the, you know, the one that was made on the moon, which was six.
Scott: I think I said I don't remember five.
Rym: No, it wasn't five.
Rym: I fucking I got to pull up the wiki.
Rym: There's so many of these things now.
Scott: Yeah, but that one, the one that Kaoru piloted to stop Shinji in the post credit scene of two is still basically down there.
Scott: Hold, you know, keeping right at the keeping things at bay.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Well, even before that, actually total aside, but I did notice this in the end.
Rym: It's basically apparent that to trigger the full on like ascension impact nonsense.
Rym: You need four avas or four things to make it happen.
Rym: There's four atoms.
Rym: They need the two.
Rym: They need the four ships at the end and all that stuff from the last movie.
Rym: But there's that organization with the Vatican treaty that says any given country can only have three avas.
Rym: It's very clear upon seeing the last movie, three avas was the limit, because if you had four, you could do what nerve is trying to do in the third and fourth movies.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So, yeah.
Scott: So movie three.
Scott: Right.
Scott: How does this thing fucking end this?
Scott: So they're piloting the mega thirteen together.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Right.
Rym: And they're going along with it to save humanity.
Rym: But what?
Rym: the only thing that bothers me about this is they go down to do.
Rym: they go to do the thing to pull the spears out of the thing that is clearly an ally with body.
Rym: Like I don't want to get too much into the cosmology because then we'll have to like look at the wiki to use all the right proper nouns.
Rym: But there's a moment where some unexplained things happen right at the last moment.
Rym: Jinji's ready to do it.
Rym: And cowards like, wait a minute, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, hold up.
Rym: Those spears are not the right spears.
Rym: Something's wrong, which is that is that is the moment that happens in the original show where Kaoru goes all the way down to the bottom of terminal dogma, where that what the what.
Rym: the whole time, Masato, the show, everyone has told the viewer, told Shinji, told say everyone believes that what is crucified in terminal dogma is Adam.
Rym: And Kaoru shows up.
Rym: And one of the most like the biggest moments in all of the original Evangelion show is Kaoru looking at it and saying, wait, what?
Rym: Lilith, what the fuck's going on?
Rym: That's not Adam.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that's a good point.
Scott: Brings back how this is a rebuild where it has that same point.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But completely different.
Scott: Instead of him.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Where Kaoru recognizes that there's a sham going on.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And so now that he recognizes that, well, doing this is not what he wants to do.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Is it going to achieve his angel ends?
Scott: He just kills it.
Scott: You know, well, he got Tringy to trust him earlier by taking off the battle royale thing and putting it on himself, the nothing.
Scott: And then he just kills himself with it.
Rym: He gets decapitated, just like in the original show.
Rym: That's a that's one of those like inviolable beats of Evangelion.
Rym: That character.
Scott: So they were starting that, you know, they were restarting the impact again and then they didn't have the impact.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And I like how, like I said before, you're about to win the game.
Scott: We stopped you in the post credit scene.
Scott: You're about to win the game.
Scott: All right.
Scott: We stopped you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because Kaoru noticed and he stopped you.
Rym: And then the end end, we we almost come full circle of.
Rym: the world is even more fucked, like so much more than it was after the near third impact.
Rym: And yet humans are still hanging on.
Rym: Technology has advanced even further.
Rym: Like, so I really like that opening for where they go down to Paris to reactivate something European nerve had been working on to nullify anti-AT fields.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Scott: So what's happened is in the in the sort of not complete, you know, whatever number impact.
Scott: it was at the end of the fucking third movie.
Scott: There's a lot of impacts.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The world is covered in red shit, just like at the original end of Ava movie.
Scott: But it didn't finish the job.
Scott: So obviously, if you're human and you go out in the red shit, well, that's you're going to become just, you know, LCL or whatever happens.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But if you they've created some sort of protective shields, they can keep it out of certain areas.
Rym: I like how that technology was not explained specifically, but was used consistently in many, many parts of the movies.
Scott: And it makes perfect sense even given a movie, you know, the original end of the Evangelion movies.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It makes sense even given that.
Scott: You made it fit.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So that oh, that red stuff is just.
Scott: Yeah, it literally is just what it is.
Scott: So and because the Ava pilots are different, they're not they don't age.
Scott: They're all special children, whatever.
Scott: They can go out into the red stuff with Ava's or not and fight and set up, you know, safe areas.
Scott: And that humans can move into those safe areas as long as they maintain the equipment that Will has set up and such.
Rym: And it's just that a lot of it is just this humanity using technology and perseverance to continue to just fight to survive.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So you get this whole.
Scott: it's a lot like, you know, there's that angelic days, like spinoff non-canon thing, whatever it is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But this sort of is kind of like that.
Scott: It's like, hey, we made it.
Scott: You know, here's a town where people are living and, you know, living life for reals.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, you can experience it and get your shit together.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's just really weird to see this kind of thing, because Evangelion, all of it up until this point, takes place in space cities alone in military base type places.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It never once had a town like location with just people chilling, doing town stuff until this point.
Scott: So that's really something.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And you see Asuka and all these characters living kind of what the best life they could live given the circumstances.
Rym: And it's really just a story about humanity being worth saving and worth like it's unique in the universe, in the cosmology of Eva.
Rym: Because remember the cosmology, like what's happening if you've seen the first show, like it's actually pretty explicit.
Rym: Well, in ancient times, something, a seed of life from deep space crashed into Earth.
Scott: And that was Adam and Adam at the South Pole.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Well, it came in and Adam came in a bit.
Scott: It was like a big sphere.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And inside the sphere was Adam and well, Adam and a sphere of Longinus.
Scott: And disease scrolls, basically all this equipment.
Rym: And what Adam was going to do is populate the Earth with life driven from the fruit of life, which is the S2 engine power, infinitely powerful godlike beings.
Rym: That's Adam.
Rym: They don't have free will.
Rym: Like there's no culture.
Rym: There's a whole thing about them.
Rym: Undecipherable space things.
Rym: All the angels are basically life forms derived from Adam.
Scott: And presumably in a, in a, you know, 2001 Space Odyssey like fashion, there were many seeds of, you know, that were spread throughout the universe and galaxies that landed on various habitable places.
Scott: Similarly, just like Adam did and populated those planets.
Scott: But alien race that sent these out also sent out seeds of knowledge.
Rym: And they had a rule.
Rym: And the rule was you can never have these two kinds of life in the same place at the same time.
Scott: And that's a biblical story, right?
Scott: It's like Adam and Eve couldn't eat from the tree of knowledge.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: You get one life or knowledge.
Scott: Pick one.
Scott: It's the story of Genesis, right?
Scott: You, God is like, you can live in this paradise and live forever and everything's amazing as long as you don't fucking know anything.
Scott: You don't even realize that you're naked.
Scott: Right?
Scott: And as soon as Adam eats the apple from the tree, right?
Scott: God's like, what the fuck?
Scott: Now you know things and you're powerful.
Scott: That makes you like me.
Scott: I can't have that.
Scott: I'm the me.
Scott: I'm the God.
Scott: Not you.
Scott: Right?
Scott: I have power and knowledge.
Scott: You only have one or the other.
Scott: Fuck you.
Rym: So the plot of the original show of Evangelion, and this is extremely specific and straightforward.
Scott: It has the word Genesis in the title.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So what happens is with the first impact, the fruit of knowledge, Lilith, the other kind of life, crashes into Earth by accident.
Scott: In Japan.
Scott: It happens to land very- Well, it's by accident, but in the movies we learn that actually that happens every time.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, at least it happens every time to Earth.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Earth always is the place where that gets to and it's never supposed to be to.
Scott: So this ritual of the impact ritual is actually just like this safety mechanism.
Scott: like that, you know, God, the alien gods put there.
Scott: Like, oh, if two of these accidentally land on the same planet, they'll destroy each other in like a massive apocalypse.
Scott: And that way there won't ever be any godlike beings out there.
Rym: Only one will survive.
Rym: So what happens is the spear- Or none.
Rym: So arguably the spear of Longinus comes along as that safety, like, that's like.
Rym: the spears are almost the enforcers of these rules.
Rym: So when Lilith crashes, there's only, in the original Eva, there's only one spear, the spear of Longinus.
Rym: Now we don't know in the show if that was atmosphere or Lilith's spear.
Rym: All we know is that when Lilith crashes, the Earth gets covered in Lilith life.
Rym: And as a result, the spear basically stabs Adam and says, "Well, there can only be one, so this is Lilith's planet
Rym: now.".
Rym: And that's fine.
Rym: The second impact happens when Sele and Nerv and all these fuck-ups go to the South Pole, find Adam, pull the spear out- Yeah, they fuck around, they pull the spear out, and now there's two, and that's a problem.
Scott: Now angels start coming, right?
Rym: So Adam wakes up, they then use the spear to reseal Adam with the spear, they get rid of Adam life.
Scott: The angels are the Adam life, right?
Scott: So the angels are now coming to attack Lilith to end the Lilith life.
Rym: So basically what happens is they wake up Adam, they kill him again, they take an embryo that they took from him, like they take this piece, and that's what Kaji steals and brings back to Nerv for Candidoo's bullshit.
Rym: But in that moment, Adam basically said, "Yo, there's a problem
Rym: here!".
Rym: And all the angels come to fuck up the Lilith life and give the planet back to Adam.
Rym: So what were the angels actually doing in the original Evangelion and in the remake?
Rym: They're coming to kill Lilith and everything that spawned from Lilith, including- Which is all humans.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Kill all humans.
Rym: It's a pretty straightforward sci-fi story.
Scott: Yeah, it's just they never explain it to you in words outright.
Scott: You have to, you know, you watch it and then eventually- No!
Rym: If you watch the original show with the extended versions of episodes, what, 23 and 24?
Scott: They explain it a little bit more.
Rym: They explain it enough more to figure a lot of this out on your own without reading a wiki.
Scott: And I think the point of it is that all that stuff, like what is actually happening?
Scott: Why are it, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, that stuff actually doesn't matter.
Scott: No.
Rym: Because the moral of Ava is humans talk to each other.
Rym: It's painful.
Rym: The separated existence is painful.
Rym: But human life is special.
Rym: The fact that we are all individual and can never fully know each other is what makes the diversity of life on Earth so unique in the universe.
Scott: And so, right, the movies and the TV show, right, so basically, did I say this when we did the original episode on the movies?
Scott: But they're both saying the same exact thing, right?
Scott: Is I could make a story, you know, like an Aesop's Fable, right?
Rym: It's literally called the Hedgehog's Dilemma.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I can make an Aesop's Fable called Tortoise and the Hare, and the message I want to get across is that slow and steady wins the race, right?
Scott: So in the original Aesop's Fable, obviously, the hare, right, doesn't win and the tortoise wins, right?
Scott: But you could tell the same story, right, and just flip the script but still have the same moral.
Scott: And that is what the movie does in the original TV series, right?
Scott: The moral is just talk to each other and they show you what happens when you don't talk to each other.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Right?
Scott: It sucks.
Rym: But the movie, too, is so, so specifically like, "Hey, what would happen if people actually talked to each other a little bit?
Rym: Look, look how much happier literally everyone
Rym: is.".
Rym: Even Gendo is closer to being happy.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So in Tortoise and the Hare, they show you the tortoise being slow and steady and then winning.
Scott: You could do the same thing and have the tortoise not be steady.
Scott: The tortoise give up and lose.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: And that would give you the same message, right, which is slow and steady wins the race.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: You could have won, tortoise.
Scott: Same message.
Scott: Talk to each other.
Scott: You just show the positive and the negative side, right?
Scott: They did it and it was good.
Scott: They didn't do it and it sucked.
Scott: Either way, same message.
Scott: Same story.
Rym: Zooming all the way out but taking into account, because what I like about Evangelion is the same thing I like specifically about Shoujo Kakame Utena.
Rym: It's relatively rare to have a large work like that where a literal reading of the events as portrayed is equally compelling to a purely allegorical reading of the events as portrayed.
Rym: And I appreciate that.
Rym: That's one of the things I like more than almost anything in media.
Rym: So taking the literal events as they're portrayed, the sci-fi aspect of this, I would say that the fundamental story that these Rebuild movies tell is that in the cosmic universe there's the Adam life and the Lilith life and humanity is almost an accident that comes about in this weird situation.
Rym: And the moral at the end is the Wunderville, the third spear, is that humans are unique and special enough to where they should break the cycle of these rules of the gods and become their own thing.
Rym: They are a free willed, free spirited, new kind of life that arises from this intersection and they should overcome that instead of trying to become Lilith or Adam style gods.
Rym: Because Gendo, Sele, all these groups, everyone who's trying to use Evas are using them to try to merge these powers together and become gods playing by the rules of the gods.
Rym: But there's this side story of humans are scarily capable by themselves.
Scott: Somehow, even though, how did humans make all this shit?
Scott: This goes back to Evangelion as a whole.
Scott: just being, this guy Anno is a real big fan of Godzilla and Ultraman and all this old robot fighty stuff.
Scott: And most of the show, yeah, it's just robot fighty stuff because he likes that sort of thing.
Scott: You see in all of these movies, lots and lots of scenes of just huge battles that aren't really contributing to the story.
Scott: It's just Anno's a nerd who likes big robot battles.
Scott: I'm a nerd, I like big robot battles too.
Scott: But in all of those stories, Ultraman, Godzilla, et cetera, all of those are stories about some huge catastrophe coming to squash humanity and humanity combines its efforts and organizes and cooperates to develop, usually by technology and science, some amazing effort to not get destroyed.
Scott: And so in the original Evangelion and this one, but in this one even more so, always showing you, look at this amazing shit that all these human organizations were able to make with their science.
Rym: The gods are fighting.
Rym: And meanwhile, under the gods, this tiny ragtag band of humans have made spaceships powered by AT fields and somehow have survived.
Scott: This angel that's mysterious alien thing with ridiculous powers that's enormous is coming, right?
Scott: And somehow this robot that some humans made is going to fight it and win.
Scott: That carries on from episode one of the TV show to the last second of the last movie.
Rym: And it comes all the way around to Shinji now having ultimate power and the spear of Ville, like the literally human free will.
Rym: And he decides, unlike all the alternative decisions he has made in various iterations of Eva, you know what?
Rym: The problem is Eva's.
Rym: The problem is humans are still evolving and still have a lot of room to grow.
Rym: It is not time to give them the cosmic space seeds and destroy them.
Rym: Let them continue to evolve and see where they go.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So at the end of the last movie, right, they give you, it's like, what could they do in Eva, right?
Scott: That is like the equivalent of like, you know, the terrible secret of space, like the thing, right?
Scott: It's like they have Gendo and Shinji sit around and chat.
Scott: It's like you couldn't put more, what bigger payoff could you get?
Rym: The biggest payoff in the whole thing was you get the scene of Shinji talking to himself, you know, same as End of Evangelion.
Rym: But then when it's Gendo and they're just talking and he's like, "Gendo, why are you
Rym: sad?".
Rym: And then Gendo's like, "Oh, I'm sad because of
Rym: XYZ.".
Rym: And it's like, hello?
Rym: You could have just said this to each other in the real world.
Scott: Three movies ago and 26 episodes ago.
Rym: And none of this apocalypse shit would have even happened.
Scott: Well, Sele might have just went out then.
Rym: Yeah, or, well anyway.
Rym: But basically you see that all the mysterious bullshit that all like, "Ooh, Gendo's up to something.
Rym: Sele's up to
Rym: something.".
Scott: No, Gendo just- Gendo's just a really messed up dude who just only loves this one woman and otherwise didn't love people at all before then.
Rym: Gendo, same as Shinji.
Rym: Just a human who's fucked up by the world.
Rym: Sele?
Rym: They're just fucked up old people.
Scott: Or are they?
Scott: Is Sele even people?
Scott: That's a separate issue.
Scott: It's implied that Sele might be one person or some AIs or they used to be people who were uploaded in the computer.
Rym: Yeah, because notice when they're all being killed in the movies, you see this flash of a nervous system fading out in those coffins each time.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's a little HAL 9000-esque.
Scott: I think it wasn't someone pulling something out of a wall or something.
Rym: Anyway, that's not relevant.
Rym: I would say that my best guess as to what Sele is based on all of the Eva stuff is they are humans who figured this stuff out and tried to follow the script, like the instructions from the Dead Sea Scrolls, to make all this happen, knowing that it would happen anyway, but to survive it somehow and/or become gods.
Rym: They didn't give a shit about humanity.
Rym: They individually wanted to like John Malkovich into an Eva and become gods or at least survive the apocalypse.
Scott: So, Shinji's talking to his dad finally.
Scott: It's like, what bigger payoff could you have?
Scott: The thing that was not allowed to happen ever before in an Eva thing.
Scott: They finally give it to you.
Scott: They chat.
Scott: They say everything that needs to be said between them.
Rym: And then much like his dark materials.
Scott: Well, just like the original End of Evangelion, Pure Heart for You, it goes meta.
Scott: Pure Heart for You, you get this sort of fourth wall destroying shots of the movie theater, Anno giving his middle finger to the fanboys who didn't like the original TV ending.
Rym: Oh, you didn't like my metaphysical ending?
Rym: You didn't want to worry about feelings?
Scott: You didn't like abstract art?
Scott: Okay, fine.
Scott: I'll go even more abstract.
Rym: Deal with it.
Rym: Oh, you wanted to know what happened to Masato in the real world because you cared about the physical plot of the show and not about the metaphor?
Rym: There you go.
Rym: She's dead.
Rym: Fuck you.
Scott: Yeah, so much like that fourth wall, we then we again break the fourth wall, right?
Scott: But this time in the fourth wall breakage, you have this sort of, you know, duality of no more Avas, right?
Scott: It's the no more Avas that Rym just explained of Shinji saying, yeah, no more Avas.
Scott: Let's let's get our human on here.
Scott: Yeah, but also no more Avas in this real world.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: I made it right.
Rym: I made it like four times.
Scott: I rebuilt it.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I made it.
Scott: It was a thing, you know, and then I rebuilt it and now it's done.
Rym: I mean, it literally ends with like the credits.
Rym: It's a drone shot of a real city.
Rym: Like how much more on the nose could you get?
Rym: Right.
Scott: Much like.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Stop watching the, you know, get out of the cartoons and get back into the real world.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, much like in the show, there's some sort of a time loop of this thing happening over and over.
Scott: But even if that's true, in the real world that we in the real human world that we live in.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's implied that Arno has basically been just Ava has been coming, you know, in his life over and over.
Scott: He's had to do Ava over and over, even after, you know, that it was done in the 90s.
Scott: But he's had to keep Ava-ing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like it was so he was so tied to it.
Rym: Look at all the the infinite pile of Ava.
Rym: Like you could say if you want to be a nerd about it, you can make a very strong argument that this loop has been happening forever and that the original show was just one of the failed loops.
Rym: And this is the final loop where everything lines up the right way.
Rym: But you don't have to read it that way.
Rym: And it tells the same story.
Scott: But what is definitely final is that in the real world.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The, you know, Hideaki Arno's loop of having to Ava over and over.
Scott: It's like he rebuilt it and now he has escaped.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The human being has escaped the Avas.
Scott: He doesn't have to Ava anymore.
Scott: He can now do other things instead with the rest of however long he lives.
Rym: I do.
Rym: I do actually.
Rym: Some people critique this, but I did enjoy the uneven style of these four movies because I liked how radically different they felt.
Scott: Like they were all the same.
Scott: That would be kind of boring.
Rym: The fight scenes in the last ones almost felt like like a promo kind of like ridiculous overwrought situation.
Scott: But I mean, every just about every movie that says, you know, it's like, what are you going to complain that, like, you know, Star Wars, the original trilogy, all three were different styles.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Indiana Jones, three different styles.
Scott: You know, only three.
Scott: All these Lord of the Rings, you know, I guess they were closer.
Scott: The three Lord of the Rings movies.
Rym: They all they all felt the same.
Scott: That was that they still had a little bit of difference.
Rym: I don't think they actually did.
Rym: They did not it.
Scott: Not as much as the other examples.
Rym: That's actually one of my main complaints is how Back to the Future.
Scott: Very different.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The most different.
Rym: Well, especially because Back to the Future was a weird like when it was physically just talked about alien.
Scott: So different.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But Back to the Future, the first movie was made in the pre VFX era.
Rym: The third movie was made in the VFX era.
Rym: And the middle movie was made in like this Roger Rabbit era of the early VFX mixed with practical effects.
Rym: And it was like this weird time in cinema.
Scott: And that contributed to actually seeing the second one, the least only maybe one or two times.
Rym: You should watch the Captain Disillusion thing where he breaks down how they did the special effects and Back to the Future to specifically because it is nuts.
Rym: Absolutely bonkers.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So anyway, see, that's the end of the the fourth movie.
Scott: So these movies, I mean, I like that.
Scott: they exist because in existing right.
Scott: The original I said this before, the original TV series is enhanced just because these are here.
Rym: Oh, do you know how hard I want to watch the original show again?
Rym: Just bearing in mind everything I've experienced from these movies.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The TV show that already existed, that without editing it whatsoever by simply creating these other movies.
Scott: Those twenty six, twenty eight episodes right of anime are now better than they were before these movies existed.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Because I can watch the original and I can contrast the beats between the original and the new one in either direction.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But are these movies, though, are the movie?
Scott: I don't think the movies are as good as the TV show.
Rym: No, I like them a lot, partly because they did wrap up a lot of the sci fi and I was interested in because once they got a lot of fan service, they got a lot of fun stuff.
Scott: But they also have a lot of issues.
Scott: Just, you know, it's like you can't.
Scott: really can you watch these without having, you know, knowing anything about Ava?
Scott: Yes, but no, it'd be hard.
Rym: But you know what I would say?
Rym: There's an easy answer to that.
Rym: Generally, with very few exceptions, the best way to experience media like this, where there's like a complicated situation, watch the thing in the order it was published.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: So watch the show, all things, watch the Ava movies, watch the rebuild movies in that order.
Rym: That is the best way to experience all of this, because it's the best of experience.
Scott: I say that for everything, no matter what, because the movie like, oh, no, you got to use a weird order.
Scott: And I'm like, no, do the order published?
Scott: order for everything ever.
Rym: The only one I ever disagree with is I think if someone wants to read the culture books, read player of games first before you.
Scott: Well, I don't think those matter too much.
Scott: They're not as.
Rym: Well, I would say that Consider Phlebas is very different from the rest of them.
Rym: And it also happens to be the first one published.
Rym: But it's that's that's.
Rym: Did you read that one?
Scott: Most of it.
Scott: I didn't finish it.
Rym: Yeah, it's the least good one, honestly.
Scott: They were going to some planet to find a, you know, a computer ship brain.
Rym: Yeah, like I would read that one after you read a bunch of other culture books, but that's the only like situation where I think I could make a case.
Rym: But I would say that the show is like fantastic on its own.
Rym: The movies are lesser if you haven't seen the show because there are scenes in the movies that are interesting and good.
Rym: But like when Asuka agrees to pilot the test, Ava, that is so much more profound to you as the viewer.
Rym: If you know how that went down in the original movie or the original show.
Scott: Like there's a lot of things that you can understand just on a base level what's happening.
Scott: But there's a lot of things in the movies that lose a lot of their meaning.
Scott: And wait, if you have it like, you know, how big a deal is it of Shinji and Gendo talking to each other at the very end?
Scott: The ultimate climax of the whole thing.
Scott: That's how big a deal is a deal if you didn't spend 26 episodes watching them not talk.
Rym: In the second movie, when Gendo agrees to go to the dinner party that Ray is hosting.
Rym: One, if you saw the original Evangelion and I said those words, you would be like, what the fuck happens in those movies?
Rym: But two, the fact that Gendo...
Scott: It's a lot less strange for him to say yes.
Scott: It's still a little strange for him to say yes to that.
Scott: But if you haven't seen the TV show, it's less strange.
Rym: But if you've seen the TV show, him agreeing to go to that dinner party or Asuka trying to learn how to cook are as big a deal as another sphere of longaners coming from space and preventing the third impact.
Rym: Like it is weird and crazy to the viewer who knows.
Scott: It's like there's these two magnets and they had the opposite poles pointing at each other and never touching.
Scott: And it's like, there's no way those can touch.
Scott: And suddenly they're touching.
Scott: It's like, holy fuck.
Rym: So I'm glad they were made.
Rym: I'm glad there'll be no more.
Rym: I like the message.
Rym: I'm glad that it just compliments the original show.
Rym: But the original show stands alone and does not need these movies to be understood and appreciated.
Scott: It's better because the movies exist, but it's like, I'd rather watch the original show.
Scott: The movies are like, do you need to watch these again?
Scott: I guess you could.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the GeekNights Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi McNichol, Alan Joyce, Link Ege, Dread Lily, Tenebrae, and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their names, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Dex Finn, JustLikeADewGek, Shiai85, Rebecca John, ReviewMadBull34, Cowards, Ryan Perrin, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Horl, Taylor Braun, The Iron Front, you hold the key to my heart, and a bunch of people who actually don't want me to say their names.
Rym: So yeah, funny story.
Rym: We did the show.
Rym: As you know, a water in the ceiling incident occurred right at the end of the last GeekNights.
Rym: And my mom was listening to the show after we recorded it, not during the livestream, and she DM's me and she's like, "Oh shit, is your apartment okay?
Rym: What
Rym: happened?".
Rym: So yeah, that's it.
Rym: I hope you didn't listen to this episode.
Rym: if you haven't seen Ava, 'cause I'm sure none of that made any sense to you, but for now, I simply leave you with... What's done is done, it feels so bad.
Rym: What once was happy, now is sad.
Rym: I wish that I could turn back time 'cause now the guilt is all mine Can't live without the trust from those you love.
Rym: I know we can't forget the past.
Rym: You can't forget love and pride.
Rym: Because of that, it's killing me inside.