Rym: It's Thursday, September 16th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we are talking about beverages, like soda or pop or water.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, because of the nature of my desk, like the desk I've just been using for a long time, it's one of those desks that has, like, the top surface that's a little higher than you'd want, and then it has the little tray that you can put the keyboard and mouse on that comes out.
Rym: So I can push that out of the way.
Scott: Not a fan of the tray.
Rym: I really like the tray, because I'd like to be able to get the keyboard and mouse out of the way if I'm using the desk for something.
Rym: Like, there's a lot.
Rym: It just works out really nicely.
Scott: I just have more desk than we use.
Scott: a different area for the...
Rym: Yeah, because my desk is in the tiny room, and the big, big room is the bedroom.
Rym: So anyway, I used to just have a little mouse pad, but the mouse pad was, like, kind of an awkward size having a full-size keyboard down there as well.
Rym: So eventually, I ended up acquiring, through PAX, I didn't pay for it, I just got it.
Rym: You got it from Tableton, I think, that My Little Pony Luna card game play mat.
Rym: that happens to be the exact size of that little tray.
Rym: So I can put my keyboard and mouse on it.
Scott: Card game play mats from, you know, collectible card games are really good as under-keyboard mouse mats.
Rym: They're basically the same...
Scott: They're that same material, right, where it's, like, I forget what it's called, and that has the stitching, the stitched, like, textile on, like, on top of it.
Scott: It's basically just a big... They're literally just big mouse pads.
Scott: Same exact thing, so...
Rym: Yep.
Scott: They're cheaper than... If you go looking on the internet for, like, "I want to buy a giant mouse pad," they're expensive.
Scott: You know, they're all gamer ones.
Rym: Oh, so even worse, I was doing some research on this because I was like, "Oh, I'll buy a good gamer one or see what the deal is,".
Rym: and even not talking about price.
Rym: There are basically, like, most of the sites, even like Logitech, that sell those things don't have any way to search by size or even see the sizes unless you, like, click on a prod and go all the way in.
Rym: Like, they just assume you don't care about the exact size of this thing.
Scott: So... They probably only sell, like, one size.
Rym: Yeah, so I dug in more, and it seems like that industry did, in fact, standardize.
Rym: They just don't say it.
Rym: Like, everyone just, like, they just assume everyone knows these sizes, but...
Scott: It's usually, like, large and extra large.
Scott: I think they're not really, you know...
Rym: There are four sizes that pretty much every company sells, and none of them are even close to the size I would need or could use for this tray.
Scott: Well, you're looking for a real... You're trying to get a specific size.
Scott: I think most people just have a desk, and they just plop it on, and if it's too... If there's extra desk or if it's, you know, it's like... It fits on the desk.
Scott: They don't give a shit if it's the exact inches.
Rym: I did.
Rym: So I looked into that.
Rym: Most of the... You're just really particular.
Rym: Oh, no, I just... The space I have is exactly 24 inches wide, and...
Scott: No, that's also... I think most people have gotten... The drawer is a very old style.
Scott: It's, like, a 90s style, you know?
Rym: Yeah, I think it's a good style, though, for... Especially the kind of stuff I do with my desk.
Rym: I like that drawer a lot, but... So, basically, all mousepads... Most people have a pad just for their mouse.
Rym: The people who even put their keyboard on the pad are pretty rare, and the people who want that, the ones they sell, are actually... They're only, like, a foot tall, and they're super wide.
Rym: Like, 48 inches.
Rym: Like, ridiculously wide.
Rym: And that seems to be...
Scott: If they're gaming type ones, yeah.
Scott: Like, meant for computer PC gaming.
Rym: But if you look at card game playmats, 24 inches is a standard size.
Rym: Like, the 24 inches is...
Scott: Yeah, I mean, we got ours from, like, one of those custom... The places where you can send them a JPEG, and they'll print you a mat of, like, you know, various sizes and stitching, you know?
Scott: And their whole business was not catering to video games, but was catering to card games.
Scott: So, we got these big ones.
Scott: We have one on each desk, and it's, like, you know, you put the keyboard on the left, mouse on the right.
Rym: So, of all places, I went to Inked Gaming, which primarily is for... You want to make a custom one for yourself, either for, like, your card game or the board game you play, or for whatever reason.
Scott: Several companies that do the same thing, they all seem to be just as good as each other.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So, I went to them, and I just was like, "All right, 24 inches is your standard
Rym: size.".
Rym: I got some art from the Utena movie.
Rym: I just slapped it into their template, made sure...
Scott: They say don't send us copyrighted stuff, but they will totally print copyrighted stuff.
Rym: Unless it's, like, literally just Mickey Mouse, they don't give a shit.
Scott: They may or may not.
Scott: Mine is actually... I took a photo of the murals outside, and then I cropped the JPEG and sent it to them.
Rym: Yeah, I just got this, like, that thing in Utena, the movie, on the top of the whole Dueling Tower area, where there's, like, the roses and the weird cut-out tower.
Rym: So, I just put that on there.
Rym: It's absolutely perfect, but the funniest thing was I just ordered it, like, didn't even make an account.
Rym: I just ordered this thing, like, that's it.
Rym: I'll use this thing for 10 years.
Rym: The only reason I even replaced the My Little Pony one is that that one was so old that it wasn't made out of that new modern material.
Rym: It was the old style mouse pad with the plasticky stuff on one side and that, like, sort of squishy material glued to the back of it, and the squishy material had absorbed grease from my hand over time, and then suddenly, over the span of, like, three days, started disintegrating under my wrists.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah, the Netrunner mats I have, you know, are definitely, like, thinner and sadder than the fancy big one that I had, you know, custom made, which has, like, you know, like, the Netrunner one, it's, like, clearly, like, the fabric was just, like, you know, glued onto the, you know, the surface of the whatever rubbery stuff is.
Scott: It's really thin, like, maybe a millimeter thick, and then they just, like, cut it out, right?
Scott: This one actually has, like, stitching all around the edges, but the edges aren't just, you know.
Rym: And it's, like, a unified bonded one-piece thing.
Rym: It's not, like, old mouse pads that were literally two different materials just glued together, so
Scott: it's great,
Rym: but the funniest thing was, so then they sent me an email, this company, and they're, like, "Hey, make sure you tell us which influencer told you to buy it so we can credit them,".
Rym: and I was, like, "What?
Scott: Fuck?".
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: I've never heard of that.
Rym: I bought this from a store.
Rym: I didn't even, like, make an account with you, WTF.
Rym: So, I think what I'm gonna do tonight is just be, like, "Yeah, those GeekNights guys really sold it,".
Rym: and see if they come to us and see what happens.
Rym: It was a weird email that I got from them.
Rym: It almost looked like it was written by hand.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: I feel like that is a world that we just don't see because of our aggressive ad blocking coupled with our issuing of that entire, like, I don't watch streamers who are, like, in that influencer class.
Rym: Like, the streamers I watch are doing, like, it's the other guy watching people playing a game.
Scott: They're focused on the game they're making.
Scott: They're playing.
Rym: Or making.
Rym: A lot of times I'm watching someone who's, like, playtesting a game they're making, but, yeah, I'm not watching the popular streamers.
Scott: Like, you know, sometimes I might watch someone who does have a sponsor, but, like, they really don't talk about the sponsor much at all, right?
Scott: Except for they're just, they're talking about the game they're playing.
Rym: Also, I've gotten to the point on YouTube, if I'm watching, like, SciShow or any one of those, like, YouTube channels, they're like, there's the moment where they haven't started the ad read yet, but there's a different cadence in their voices for, like, oh, the ad read's coming and I got to the part where I can just stop the video before the ad read.
Scott: Even Sausage Guy is, like, this Will It Blow is brought to you by, and I'm like, pause, skip, unpause.
Rym: SciShow is funnier.
Rym: They're like, ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba, and there's this slight pause that's longer than normal, and then they're, like, speaking, like, from a script, and suddenly they're, like, speaking of blah ba blah, and they're immediately going to talk about whatever fucking direct-to-consumer bed.
Rym: they're advertising.
Scott: There is a website, there is a website out there where people, uh, I think it's a, like, a plug-in for your browser or something, where people crowdsource the timings on particular videos of, like, when the ad is.
Scott: Oh, that's like old school ad block.
Scott: Right, one person watches the video, they put in the time codes of, like, ad starts here, ad stops there, and now if you've got the plug-in in your browser, it looks it up every time you go to watch a video if there's any, you know, shared time codes and it will auto skip for you.
Scott: And if you're mostly watching really popular stuff or people think things that are popular with people have that plug-in, then it's going to work really well for you.
Scott: It has quite a lot of users, so it's, but I don't use it.
Scott: I just know it exists.
Rym: So, in the news, we'll get right into this, because this is a huge deal, and what's fascinating to me is I am not seeing people talking about this outside of this industry right now, but if what we're about to talk about actually happens, this is a, like, this is a foundational change type issue if it occurs.
Rym: If you're not familiar, there is a union called the IATSE.
Rym: Nazi?
Rym: Yeah, you'll see.
Scott: Five, sixes, baby!
Rym: So, if you're in the entertainment industry or the convention industry, we'll get back to that, this could cause a pax to that.
Scott: Pretty much anything that involves stages, performances, etc.
Scott: Yeah, this is an old-school union from the, like, this is one of the, like, like, if you see the logo, you'll be like, hey, I've seen that somewhere, probably at the end of a movie down near all those other logos.
Rym: Or you've seen it at convention centers when you're, like, at a theater.
Scott: So, it's all, there are a lot of people.
Rym: Founded in the late 1800s and affiliated with the AFL-CIO, which, if you don't know what that union is, I don't know, take a, take, take fifth grade social studies, because what the fuck?
Scott: It's the first one.
Rym: That's the, that's, like, the one you learn about in American schools.
Rym: But the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees, Moving Picture Technicians, it's a whole long thing.
Rym: Like, this covers a lot.
Scott: It includes, like, you go to a concert and, like, someone, you know, let's say you go to a music festival, there's that giant stage they build and then take down when the festival's over.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All the people who put that shit together.
Rym: Or the people who, like, deal with the cables to mic up a stage or run cameras or plug shit in in a convention center or set up the stage for a Broadway play, it's all this one union with over 150,000 people.
Scott: Projectionists, you know, everything.
Scott: Audio, lighting, screens, all this stuff.
Rym: So, this union is real close to striking.
Rym: Like, yeah.
Rym: This has been simmering for a while.
Rym: In fact, I queued this news up from September 8th to talk about it, because it was such a big deal.
Rym: There's updated news today that the union is now mobilizing and planning the strike to be ready to do it at a moment's notice as they await the final response from, like, the producers and all the Hollywood companies that they're negotiating with.
Rym: They're basically deciding relatively imminently whether or not they're going to strike.
Scott: And what that would mean, it wouldn't be as bad as, like, when the sanitation workers go on strike and the street is literally covered in shit, which happened.
Rym: But this is, like, an order of magnitude worse for the, not worse, I shouldn't say worse, because it would be a good thing if they strike.
Rym: This would be an order of magnitude more impactful than the writers' strike, which some of you might be old enough to remember.
Rym: Where, remember when American TV pivoted to a lot of reality, like, a lot of reality TV?
Rym: That's because the writers were all on strike.
Scott: Yeah, well, so this is the thing that's happened, right, is that when you have a strong union, right, like the baseball union, I always use the example of the strong union.
Rym: They're a real good.
Scott: this is a lot of baseball players, right, they play a lot of fucking baseball.
Scott: If they go on strike, you know, they can't really play baseball when it's cold.
Scott: It's like you're losing games, you're losing money.
Scott: Most, a lot of the money comes from people going to the stadium, right?
Scott: You know, that's a big deal.
Scott: But when football players went on strike, they just got some fucking replacement football players, right?
Scott: They're just like, "Scabs, come on
Scott: in.".
Scott: They did replacement refs too, and everyone hated it, but they did it anyway.
Scott: And so the NFL's unions are weak, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, going on strike wasn't enough leverage to get people kept watching the football, even, you know, in some ways people complain so much about the shitty refs.
Scott: It's like, well, that means you're watching the game.
Scott: You saw how shitty the refs were, right?
Scott: So that's why, you know, that's what it turns out.
Rym: That doesn't matter that much to how the money gets made, right?
Scott: But when the writers went on strike, you saw, like Rym just said, strong, but not as strong because they came in with the reality shows that aren't written, right?
Scott: Necessarily, right?
Scott: Under at least the same, I don't know how they define that.
Rym: Yeah, and let's stay away from the fact that the video game industry is so non-unionized, despite many of the people in that industry doing the exact same kinds of jobs that these union employees in the Hollywood and television and convention industries do.
Scott: But if Yahtzee goes on strike, depending on exactly which people go on strike for how long before you get into that.
Rym: So the witch right now is of the hundred and fifty thousand members of the end of this union.
Rym: There is unanimous backing from the executive board.
Rym: The initial strike would be sixty thousand of them, primarily the West Coast locals.
Rym: Not to like I'm not going to explain how unions work to you.
Rym: Read a book or take fifth grade social studies.
Rym: That's more like Hollywood.
Rym: That's like seventh grade.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Social studies.
Rym: But usually unions are actually organized a lot political parties in America in that there will be a national union that basically just coordinates and organizes.
Rym: But the real power is the locals, meaning you watch old movies.
Scott: If you live in the United States and you've driven around or walked around anywhere, you've probably seen like some house that has like some logos and it says like local number, number, number.
Scott: It's like that's a union headquarters for the local branch of whatever unions.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're all over the place.
Scott: Even in this neighborhood, there's plumbing ones, electric ones.
Scott: The electric one always has a cool logo.
Scott: It's like a hand with a bunch of lightning bolts and stuff like that.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So they're negotiating with the Alliance of Motion Picture and Television Producers, which basically their argument is they are treated like shit and paid nothing from an industry that makes billions.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: Literally.
Scott: All the money goes to the big name actors and the producers and whatever.
Scott: And they always do shenanigans in Hollywood to mask how much money is really being made.
Rym: Despite the fact that, you know, forget star power.
Rym: There are very good actors a tear down from the A-listers that could do probably a fine job at that part of moviemaking.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But that Hollywood argument, the Hollywood argument is like, you know, hey, if we got a different, you know, that top name actor, right, at least they believe that the top name actor is with selling the tickets right to the show.
Scott: And if they switched out all the lower actors or if they switched out the whole crew, people would still come see the, you know, some Marvel movie.
Scott: It's like, well, as long as you have all the actors for the superheroes that are famous, we could change everyone else and we would sell just as many tickets.
Scott: So also that's the producer Hollywood added.
Rym: But I go further.
Rym: It's kind of moot because even if that is true, those people are not as important to make the movie at all as these union people are, because exactly.
Scott: That's why you need the union, because without a union, it's like, OK, well, it doesn't matter which camera guy I have, the movie will sell as many tickets.
Scott: Well, but what if no camera guy will work for you?
Rym: And sure, you might get a scab for a camera guy.
Rym: There's a million YouTubers out there and like amateurs like I'm a pretty good videographer, like for real.
Rym: However, the skill set to be a good camera worker on a Hollywood movie or a sports broadcast or a concert, that is a difficult skill.
Rym: I would do a materially worse job than the shittiest union camera worker.
Scott: Right.
Scott: What you'll have is if you do hire a scab who isn't as skilled and I can't imagine someone having the skill and not being in the union, that would be a strange like that would be a rare person.
Rym: Let's say somehow I am better than like the worst unionized camera worker, but worse than the rest of them.
Rym: Even then, I wouldn't walk through a. I would not be a scab because I have that skill and I have solidarity with those workers, of course.
Scott: But, you know, you if you go if you're a director, right, and you're trying to make a movie and you have to deal with a scab camera guy or a scab lighting person and you're like, you know, you tell the lighting people like, hey, do this kind of lighting set up and then you come back, expect ready to shoot the scene.
Scott: And the lighting is not what you just said.
Scott: Yeah, you lose, you know, much time and money you're losing from having to tell them to change it or having to do it yourself because the director knows.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The director, obviously, you know, went to film school.
Scott: They could figure, you know, they could like to give them more specific instruct.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: But here's the thing.
Scott: But that losing time and money.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It would be in deep, deep shit.
Scott: You would be better off.
Scott: You know, you still have to pay the scab something.
Scott: You'd be better off, you know, paying the pros.
Scott: You'd actually save money by giving the pros a higher salary.
Rym: But also, there are a lot of jobs that have to be done.
Rym: So even someone thinks, oh, the process that makes non-unionized YouTube and Twitch content might be good enough for like not Hollywood, maybe, but for a lot of other things.
Rym: The problem is that pipeline, which is similar to the pipeline Scott and I have, it's not that complicated.
Rym: And people who are very good at that lack knowledge and lack the knowledge that they lack the knowledge of all the parts that go into even a slightly bigger production.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So basically, if they went on like when we did that fucking late show at PAX in ancient times, we lacked the knowledge of what we lacked.
Scott: We lacked the staff.
Scott: There was people that they didn't show up.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But that wasn't that.
Scott: But we had other problems as well.
Scott: I don't want to say that was our only problem.
Rym: What I'm saying is that that staff has a material impact on being able to make anything.
Rym: And that is the staff that is invisible to a lot of people who do small productions because they think, oh, smart people can just do this.
Rym: They don't realize, like, how many people do you think it takes to light a stage for a concert?
Rym: It is way more than you're guessing.
Rym: Like way more.
Scott: So anyway, if these people go on strike, what's going to happen most likely is a lot of things that are coming soon from Hollywood, Netflix, you know, your HBO maxes, all your streaming services, all your movie theater stuff, TV stuff that comes from California, right?
Scott: Any shows that record regularly in California, right?
Scott: I know some of the late shows are in New York, some are in California, things like that.
Scott: All kinds of stuff out there will either be delayed, a hiatus, you know, canceled maybe completely.
Scott: Things that, like, haven't started filming yet might never start filming.
Scott: And then when the strike's over, eventually they might choose to film something else instead.
Scott: Like someone might have their whole, you know, movie that was going to get made.
Scott: Well, I guess someone else's movie's getting made now instead just because bad luck of timing, you know, that my thing was going to start, you know, shooting when a strike happens.
Rym: But also, though all like that gigantic impact would just be if the first 60,000 strike, if the rest of the union strikes, if the entire union goes on strike, I want to share with you what the IATSE Local 11 does.
Rym: That's an East Coast local iteration of this union.
Rym: They run the BCEC and the Hines.
Rym: No Anime Boston, no Paxis.
Scott: Well, they could run it with scabs, right?
Rym: I don't think they could.
Rym: I don't think they would be capable of doing that.
Scott: But there are certain parts of it they could run with scabs, certain they couldn't, right?
Scott: And things they might mess up, right?
Scott: It might be run poorly if they did try to get scabs in there.
Scott: Also, I wouldn't attend a convention if there was a picket line of the convention center workers, that's for sure.
Rym: Oh, but you know what else they run?
Rym: Fenway Park, Gillette Stadium, TV Garden.
Rym: You talk about how American society only survives because of bread and circuses.
Rym: Well, this would cut off a lot of the circuses, and it would cut them off instantly because this is a union you don't fuck around with.
Rym: They know what they're doing.
Rym: They've been around for over 100 years.
Scott: Yeah, and you know, things like if there might be like a music festival that was scheduled, a band that was touring that was coming to your town on a particular day.
Scott: Well, if that band just happens to be unlucky and the strike is happening while they were in a particular town, they're going to lose a lot of tour dates and a lot of money, right?
Scott: So that band is going to want to go to, you know, the producers who are making the deal and be like, "Hey, why the fuck aren't you paying the...".
Scott: Right?
Rym: So, so far, like you can read these articles.
Rym: I'll link to a bunch of things to give you the history and context of this because if you are not unionized, figure out why, if there is an activist movement in your industry and try to be part of it.
Rym: If you are a union, make sure you're involved in it and understand what it's doing and try to lean on it.
Scott: And keep it from being corrupt.
Scott: Make sure it's doing good stuff like this.
Rym: Especially because this is a sign of something bigger because this is not the first bit, like Nabisco workers are on strike right now too.
Rym: Aside, don't fucking buy Nabisco products, especially not those Pokemon Oreos.
Rym: Like, there are times and places where someone can cross a picket line because we live in a cruel and evil world and like we live in a society.
Rym: But don't cross a picket line for an Oreo cookie.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's one thing.
Scott: if like, you know, let's say you live in a town and the Walmart workers are on strike, which really they should have been doing that decades ago.
Rym: But you gotta eat.
Rym: And if there's literally nothing else in town...
Scott: But it's like if you live in a town where the only fucking thing is Walmart, it's like you don't have much choice, right?
Scott: You can go and get food, but you don't need Oreos.
Scott: You can buy Hydrox if they still have them or you can just buy fucking, I don't know, make cookies, buy sugar in Toll House.
Scott: Is Toll House Nestle?
Scott: Oh no, Toll House is Nestle, so it's not Nabisco.
Rym: Nestle is a piece of shit company too, but they do not have...
Scott: Nestle is a piece of shit too, but it's not on strike right now.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: But this is a sign of something bigger and this is a topic for another show.
Rym: or maybe you listen to some people who are experts in labor and not two white guys doing a podcast.
Rym: But this is because on a fundamental level, due to a confluence of factors ranging from hyper capitalism to low taxes, the extreme wealth disparity in America and COVID, labor is extremely powerful right now.
Rym: Labor holds all the keys to the kingdom because for all the tech automation and everything out there and the things that like me and Scott do for a job, our entire society grinds to a halt if the people who do the actual physical labor decide not to.
Scott: And you mentioned COVID, right?
Scott: The sad reality, a lot of people who did physical labor are dead.
Rym: Yep, because we forced them to keep working in inhumane, unsafe conditions to keep the circuses going and to keep the bread flowing.
Rym: Imagine a society where we paid the people who are keeping grocery stores stocked like quadruple wages during COVID because they were literally risking their lives so we could eat food.
Rym: So yeah, it is so weird to me how little press this is getting outside of industry circles, which means if they strike, I think this is going to be shocking news to the vast majority of Americans who have no idea.
Scott: It'll only be shocking news to them when they start realizing it, which might take a little while depending on which person it is, right?
Scott: Some people won't give a shit at all because their circuses are who knows what, something else is unaffected.
Scott: Some people might be heavily affected, like they had their hearts set on going to a thing and, you know.
Rym: Yeah, imagine if my packs got canceled because of this.
Scott: Yeah, my hope is that we can get out, that the strike happens sooner and we can get out of our hockey tickets.
Rym: So you got any news?
Scott: I do have a news.
Scott: So in New York City, right, a few, well it's not just a New York City problem, but it came to New York City a few years ago, there's this bug insect, literal insect, called the spotted lanternfly.
Scott: And if you see one, it looks like a really fucking interesting kind of beautiful insect that like belongs in a, you know, like a zoo or something, you know, in the whatever.
Scott: But they're not.
Scott: They're really bad.
Scott: They're so bad that literally, right, normally you're like, oh I don't want to kill things, I'm a vegan or whatever, right?
Scott: And it's like, you know, okay, literally every environmentalist, you know, plant people, insect people, like yeah, you know, if you're like in New York and you see these things, fucking kill them.
Scott: Like basically what they do is they, the most dangerous, they do a lot of bad things, but the most dangerous thing they do is they eat the sap from a lot of plants and trees and in eating all the sap, those plants and trees now become, are not protected anymore, because I guess the sap is a protection mechanism.
Scott: I don't know too much about plants, but this is what I read on the internet.
Scott: And so if these things, which, you know, are not from here, right, they were, you know, what's the word for it?
Rym: I mean, these are just full-on invasive species that reduce the resiliency.
Scott: Someone brought them here by accident.
Scott: And it's basically all the trees and plants and shit will die if we don't get rid of these things, right?
Scott: So if you see one, it's really easy to spot one.
Scott: They're not that small and they're really distinct.
Scott: So you're not going to be squishing something else by accident.
Scott: So you don't have to be afraid.
Scott: You're not going to be worried.
Scott: Like just look at one picture and you'll be like, oh, there's no way you could miss one of those.
Rym: But also check out this article.
Rym: If you do murder one of these things that you should report where you saw it when you killed it.
Scott: So that they can come in and see if there's more in that area, right?
Scott: Nesting or some shit breeding.
Rym: Part of what they go after is there's a particular kind of tree that is extremely common in American cities on the East Coast, especially New York City, because it is very hard to have a tree that can grow in this environment.
Rym: And this one tree is extremely resilient and good at growing in a place like New York City.
Rym: And they attack that tree fucking specifically.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And so if all these trees die, the climate damage from that is real bad.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So never mind.
Rym: Like I like there's a lot of structural racism in New York in terms of where people are forced to live and what they have access to.
Rym: But generally, the fewer trees there are in a neighborhood anywhere in New York, the hotter it is in that neighborhood.
Rym: Like literally it is hotter if you are outside.
Scott: And anyway, if you see this bug probably and not just New York, but probably anywhere in the United States, I'm guessing make sure that it's.
Scott: it's probably an invasive species.
Scott: wherever you are listening to this.
Scott: It's like most likely not, I guess, not guaranteed.
Scott: Check with experts.
Scott: But yeah, you probably want to kill these if you see them and you'd be like, oh, well, what difference does it make if people kill them when they see them?
Scott: Well, it turns out that historically.
Scott: way back in the day, you know, like feudalism times there was a there was a thing where they would I don't know how true this is.
Scott: I read it on the Internet, but I believe it for now where they told peasants, right, the peasants intentionally went out to kill certain kinds of insects.
Scott: And they did such a good job that certain kinds of birds ran out of food.
Scott: And that met and those birds also ate the locust.
Scott: So the locust came back.
Scott: Humans going out and intentionally squishing bugs like in mass is effective if we enough people are doing it, especially in a place where there's people walking around like New York, even though there's less people walking around now than there used to be.
Scott: So I think especially in a city.
Scott: So, yeah, learn what they look like.
Scott: Figure out if they're invasive in your area.
Scott: And if you see them, squish them and don't feel bad about taking life.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So one last little news.
Rym: We're not going to talk about this long because we do want to get into our main bit, but I just want to and I'm not talking with this on Monday because the technology aspect of this is not interesting.
Rym: Ars Technik has an article, a ton of leaked documents prove something that Facebook had been up to.
Rym: that explains a lot of Facebook's bad behavior and the ill effects it's had on society.
Rym: There's another article that had a different problem that broke recently.
Rym: I was talking about on Twitter.
Rym: This is not that.
Rym: This is an unrelated bad Facebook thing.
Scott: Basically, it's one of those situations where like everybody knew this deep down, everybody knew.
Scott: And now the documents came out.
Scott: What do you know?
Scott: We were right all along again.
Rym: Short.
Rym: The short version is again, again, Facebook has rules like you can't say something super racist, like they have they have an ostensible set of rules and they do to a degree enforce them by deleting posts and removing accounts.
Rym: Like a lot of people get that enforcement happening upon them.
Rym: You can tell by looking at right wing blogs and people freak out their Facebook accounts get deleted.
Rym: But there was a list of five point eight million special people.
Scott: who is that many special people on earth.
Scott: That seems like a high number.
Rym: Yeah, it does.
Rym: That's actually part of why these documents are fascinating.
Rym: Facebook kept adding to this list of people constantly to the point that as of when these documents leaked, there were five point eight million individual human beings on this list.
Rym: And any account that was on this list, basically, even if a Facebook moderator was like, whoa, shit, delete that.
Rym: The platform just wouldn't.
Rym: And Facebook would go out of its way to make sure those accounts were not hindered in any way.
Rym: And the arguments for why they did this were to avoid drama and to avoid appearing partisan, because one aspect of this that's not talked about that much in this article, but is very commonly talked about.
Rym: And if you read the following articles and the links from this, you'll see it more.
Rym: It's mostly conservative voices that are deemed for takedown, but are also deemed too important and thus not taken down.
Rym: If Facebook actually cut off everyone who posted racist shit, they'd cut off a huge percentage of American conservative politicians.
Rym: And they're afraid of the government coming down on them.
Rym: But they're also afraid of like, if a soccer player says something anti-vax, they're afraid that if they delete that soccer player's account, like all of Europe will rise up against them.
Rym: Like, literally, that's one of the examples that happened.
Rym: I don't have a lot more to say about this, except Facebook is literally a company that has done material harm to society in the world, not just by accident, but also by design.
Rym: And I urge you to delete your Facebook account.
Rym: Like, I say that a lot, but Facebook is literally objectively worse than any other non right wing social media platform on Earth.
Scott: And this goes straight to the Zuckman, right?
Scott: It's like there were quotes in some of these things that were like, he basically was like, you know, you know, like, yeah, we should, we'd let you know, let's not do that.
Scott: if it's going to damage, you know, our monies.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's going to hurt.
Scott: It's going to cause, you know, that someone would suggest to him, like, let's do this to increase safety.
Scott: And he's like, he's like, well, you know, let's maybe not because it's going to damage our wallet, our engagement, whatever other metric was more important than safety.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: That other article we're not even going to talk about around the algorithms driving engagement and the objectively proven harm those algorithms cause specifically and primarily.
Scott: I don't understand who thought the algorithm, like, I don't understand when they started with the algorithm business.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was like, just put everything.
Scott: everyone just wants every, if I follow someone, I'm friends with them.
Scott: I want to see everything that they post in chronological reverse chronological order.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: That's all anyone ever wanted.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The algorithms have never solved anything for anyone other than the companies, the users.
Scott: There's no user.
Scott: I think that finds any benefit from any algorithm managing their feet.
Scott: The algorithm has been invented as of today.
Rym: The algorithms don't exist to make anyone's experience better.
Rym: The algorithms exist to drive people to engage with the platform.
Rym: Regardless of how they engage with the platform into clicking on it more and typing on it more full stop.
Scott: Also, just on the most basic level, right?
Scott: Let's say you do do reverse chronological order and you only see things from people you follow.
Scott: And that's it when you know.
Scott: what happens is the same thing that happens to me on Twitter, because that's what I see on Twitter.
Scott: I see reverse chronological order when I see people I follow and I don't see any ads.
Scott: because I don't, I don't see ads.
Scott: So, uh, what happens to me is I scroll and then I hit the end, the end, and then I'm done.
Scott: And then I close that shit and I don't come back to it for quite a while because it's not filling up that fast.
Rym: I read the whole Twitter.
Rym: Like I pointedly don't file.
Rym: If I ever get to the point where I'm not reading my entire Twitter feed, I start unfollowing people.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's no, there's no doom scrolling because it ends.
Scott: But if I open up Instagram, which I do rarely, right?
Scott: You scroll, you scroll, right?
Scott: And it's like, you're seeing some things from people you follow, not everything.
Scott: And it's not in the, it's not in the same order as last time.
Scott: And there's always something new because there's something they've held back that you haven't seen.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's always more.
Scott: And then if you really go to the end and they've got nothing left to show you, they just start showing you stuff from people you don't even fucking follow.
Scott: There's ad, all kinds of stuff in there.
Scott: Like you can scroll forever.
Scott: And it's like, uh, that's a problem.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But uh, yeah, Facebook is objectively harmful to society to the point that we should destroy it.
Rym: Like the evidence is overwhelming at this point.
Scott: Or at least take it and, you know, turn the algorithm off and enforce all its rules.
Scott: Enforce, enforce rules they don't even have also.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Or also just enforce your fucking rules.
Rym: If important it was a lot, not all, not even the majority, but a lot of the harms Facebook causes would disappear instantly.
Scott: They also have that oversight.
Scott: They also had that oversight board and some of this stuff was, some of that stuff was hidden from the oversight board.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: It's like the oversight board was hobbled to an extreme degree to the point that they could be in it.
Rym: Kind of like when New York had the ethics board.
Rym: that, uh, was basically directed by the people who were violating the ethics the most.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Um, but anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So, uh, check this out.
Rym: I did not think I would ever talk about a new doom mod in my life, unless I made one myself.
Scott: If you said there might be a new doom mod one day we're talking about, I'd say, yeah, that makes sense.
Rym: I just didn't expect to cause it's, uh, it's, it's, uh, it's actually kind of a lost art.
Scott: It is, it is extremely, there's definitely a community around making doom mods.
Rym: The community is bigger than I thought because after seeing this, I went and dug into the tools they use.
Rym: Someone made a modern version of dehacked that doesn't require like the DOS command line to function.
Scott: The tools have gotten better, but, uh, yeah, these things all have communities around them that wax and wane.
Rym: Doom modding is the only modding community I actually got actively involved in back when doom was a thing.
Rym: Like I made a lot of doom mods.
Rym: I like know that engine inside and out.
Rym: And, uh, very recently, in fact, on September 24th, that's, uh, the reason this is coming out.
Rym: Like I recommend you wait until December, September 24th and then play it.
Rym: There is a doom mod that, and the story of this doom mod is it is called, uh, Thatcher's tech base.
Rym: Margaret Thatcher's tormented soul is trying to escape from hell and you have to make sure she fucking stays in hell.
Scott: That is the plot.
Rym: It's a full on doom mod with a bunch of maps and a full new soundtrack and all this fun stuff.
Rym: And also Margaret Thatcher is an absolute monstrous person.
Rym: We are better as a society that she is no longer around.
Rym: It's a shame that she ever held power.
Rym: And I encourage you, if you don't understand the depth of her depravity, to go find that video from a recent anniversary of her death, where, uh, I think it was actually during her, it was during her funeral, some reporter asked the Scottish woman, like, don't you think it's disrespectful to like protest her existence on the day of her funeral?
Rym: And the Scottish woman's response is beautiful.
Rym: It is delightful.
Rym: And it is true.
Rym: Fuck Margaret Thatcher.
Rym: And I encourage you to play this mod.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: Uh, so, you know, I've been watching some factory type videos on YouTube because everyone loves watching factories.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: That particle board one was real good, but the plywood one, not the particle board.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: That one was good.
Scott: Uh, so I guess, I guess, yeah, I've been watching them recently.
Scott: So YouTube keeps recommending more, right?
Scott: But uh, there we go.
Scott: There's an algorithm that's doing something.
Scott: Get out of here, YouTube.
Scott: Um, this one, it might be one of the best I've seen.
Scott: It is from the lodge cast iron factory, right?
Scott: Everyone, at least most people know lodge cast iron cookware.
Rym: Um, it's the only brand I can name off the top of my head.
Scott: Oh, there's, there's Le Creuset and there's Staub.
Rym: And I've heard of Le Creuset.
Rym: I've never heard of that other one.
Scott: Staub.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, I don't know if mine is larger of mine is unbranded because I got it at that weird outlet store in Atlantic city so long ago.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: Anyway, anyway, uh, it's a really fascinating view of the factory because it's not just like most factory videos, just showing you footage of all the parts.
Scott: This is like a really detailed walkthrough of every step from literal pile of scrap metal sitting there to, you know, pots and pans being put into boxes.
Scott: Like literally every step.
Scott: There's a guy walking around, who's the YouTube channel dude, and a person who works at the factory explaining, you know, they're zooming in, they're showing you carefully.
Scott: So you can really see how each part works.
Scott: They make the molds.
Scott: This is the most fascinating part to me.
Scott: They make the molds out of sand, right?
Scott: They pack the sand so tight into a mold shape.
Scott: Then they put the cat, the iron into it, right?
Scott: Then the pot or pan comes out, they wash out, and then the sand just collapses.
Scott: And then they make a mold out of sand again, repeatedly just reusing the sand until eventually.
Rym: Because my hobby is not watching the how factories make stuff videos, but the post-mortem on factory disaster videos that come from the.
Rym: I've learned a lot about that sand process because it's not uncommon in a lot of this type of factory work.
Scott: The other thing is that, you know, they were really something about this particular video because they're talking to all the people in the factory.
Scott: The people are great.
Rym: Like every one of them had a lot of fascinating input.
Rym: It's like, I like the guy wearing that really cool Dragon Ball Z shirt.
Scott: But the people in this factory were just so happy, right, to like be working there.
Scott: I guess that's because, you know, it's a film of the cameras on, right?
Scott: So who knows if the working conditions are crappy.
Scott: They didn't look crappy to me.
Rym: Oh, well, again, because of the videos I watch, this factory looks pretty on top of things compared to the videos I've seen of factories that had incidents.
Scott: But the thing that really stood out to me was how like proud and happy the people were to work there.
Scott: Not because of the conditions, but because they're reminded like, hey, I just made this pot or pan, right?
Scott: Like someone's going to be making dinner with this in like a week, you know?
Rym: It's almost like, getting back to that union conversation, there should be dignity and a living wage in all labor.
Scott: So there's a lot of dignity and pride in this labor of making cast iron cookware that you don't see in, you know, a lot of other videos that sort of enhance the experience.
Scott: You also feel like you've just learned like enough to work at this place because go into such detail on everything.
Scott: It's like, oh man, I could work there, but I wouldn't because still really dangerous, hot melted iron.
Rym: But imagine a society where we paid like real, honest wages for this kind of labor.
Rym: This wouldn't be a terrible job compared to a lot of other jobs out there.
Rym: It
Scott: also makes you, the one last thing is it makes you feel good about buying from them because in the video you can see how particular they are about rejecting anything that's like, yeah,
Rym: when they're in front of the scrap thing and you see like a pan just comes down while they're talking and they go look at
Scott: it.
Scott: And it's like a perfect, looks like a freaking perfectly good pan.
Scott: They're like, nope, something was wrong with that one.
Scott: So we sent it back and they just melt it down again.
Scott: It's cast iron.
Scott: It's like, they'll just keep using the same metal over and over again until, you know, they get a good pan.
Rym: My favorite guy is the guy.
Scott: So they're still losing a lot of energy in the melting process, right?
Scott: They're not energy, I don't know how energy efficient they are in terms of the furnace, but materials wise, they're not, they're, you know, they're doing their best.
Scott: Just keep using the same iron until we get a good pan, right?
Scott: So they're buying as little iron as possible.
Rym: Also, thankfully iron, unlike a lot of other metals as a pretty low working temperature.
Rym: So it doesn't use as much energy as you think compared to like aluminum or uranium or something.
Rym: But two, my favorite guy is the one who is sitting there burning off the little drip at the end.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: The drip oil, the oil guy.
Scott: Cause they show you the, uh, the seasoning process, right?
Scott: That's really good too.
Scott: I like the, yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Cause they used to sell them back and then he unseasoned and now they season them before they send them to you.
Scott: And he's like, yeah, this is how he seasoned the pans.
Scott: And it's like, aha, if that's how they season them, then I know, I didn't know how I could season them.
Rym: If that's how they season them, it ain't gonna work in my like residential oven.
Scott: Well, you don't have a conveyor belt, the hook where their pots hanging.
Rym: Well, what did they say?
Rym: They, they only cure, they only season them for 15 minutes with that oil, but I did, I don't think they said the actual temperature, but the way they talked about it, I think my oven would struggle to be at that temperature.
Scott: Oh, I think my oven could reach the temperature.
Scott: It was four or 500 Fahrenheit, something like that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, really good factory video, lodge cast iron.
Scott: If you need cast iron cookware, I recommend them.
Scott: unless you want the enameled kind, then you're going to have to pay a lot more money from someone else.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: In the meta moment, geek dies book club book, which we are both actively reading the tale of Genji.
Rym: Uh, follow along with us.
Rym: We've picked the next book.
Scott: I read some yesterday.
Rym: I'm going to read a lot.
Rym: I'm thinking I'm going to read a lot this weekend because last weekend do a knee issue that I've since resolved.
Rym: We didn't do a long bike ride.
Rym: So this weekend I have a two hour train ride in the morning before a bike ride.
Rym: That's a lot.
Scott: Lodge does have some enameled cast iron, but I've never, usually they're known for their non enameled.
Scott: So I don't know if it's any good or not, but it is obviously more money if you get enameled.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Uh, otherwise they didn't pay me for this.
Scott: I just recommend them honestly.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Our, uh, our most recent packs panel from packs, uh, east online 2021 is on YouTube.
Rym: You can just watch it.
Rym: Uh, I'm working on a couple of panels, like the research that's required for the future.
Rym: So stay tuned.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I doubt we will be at physical conventions in person anytime soon.
Rym: Like there is no universe.
Rym: Gen Con is happening right now and hell no, even though there seems to be very little evidence of spread or significant spread.
Scott: at least one person went to Otakon and then was sick after.
Scott: I don't haven't heard of anyone who was at Connecticut on who was sick after yet.
Rym: There's a people posting their negative tests weeks out.
Rym: And so far no one said, but again, that's all Anic data.
Rym: So why MMB?
Rym: But, uh, two, regardless of anything, the next con is coming up PAX Unplugged seems like one.
Rym: I haven't heard anything yet.
Rym: So who even knows if it'll happen?
Rym: Uh, magfest, they did announce all their measures and while I applaud them for requiring vaccinations, I don't trust going to conventions yet.
Rym: So I is very unlikely we'll be at magfest.
Rym: And even if somehow things are safe enough for us to go to like a magfest, there is no way the state of Texas will be safe enough to go to a convention in January.
Rym: I can't imagine PAX South happens this year.
Rym: Nevermind.
Rym: Oh, next year.
Scott: I'm not going to Texas, even if COVID like goes away.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: The problem has to do a lot of other fixing before I go.
Rym: Texas has done so many dangerous and egregious things legally just in the last six months that I can't in good faith travel to that state again for any purpose.
Rym: Like it would be unethical for me personally to go to Texas for any reason.
Rym: So even if it's somehow safe to go to PAX South, you will very likely not see us there for those reasons.
Scott: I would go to PAX South if it moved to a better state or Texas somehow miraculously fixes itself and COVID somehow quote ends.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I don't think it'll end like the way smallpox ended, but it'll end in such a way that no masks or any special precautions are needed anywhere in general public society, uh, ends.
Scott: So yeah, beverages.
Rym: We haven't, we've done a food show a while and somehow we've never done this as a topic and it's Thursday and I haven't watched anything non-animated for some time.
Rym: So we don't have anything to review.
Rym: I guess I should watch some of those movies you've watched just so we could do a review show at some point.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I've watched, I've watched and read a lot of things that you have not watched or read that you could or, and played that you could watch, read or play to get a show.
Rym: Uh, try, you know, so I mean, vice versa could be true too, but at least there's a lot of animation that we're both going to watch or have watched that we have a pretty decent backlog of Wednesday shows.
Rym: But anyway, I digress.
Rym: Beverages are a broad topic and we're not going to like get in.
Rym: We're not, this is not the podcast.
Scott: I feel like we did this show already and you deleted it.
Scott: or maybe it was a show we did and it failed.
Rym: I looked for the words juice, beverage, bev, drink, alcohol, pop, soda.
Rym: Like I dug around.
Scott: I feel like we did shows on it.
Scott: Like we had to have done, but I guess we somehow haven't.
Scott: or maybe it was a show I do.
Scott: We thought we would do and we didn't do.
Scott: or we, I don't know what happened, but if we can't find, maybe someone else can find it.
Scott: That's okay.
Scott: But yeah, it's fine.
Scott: We can't, if we can't find an episode cause room deleted it, then I guess we'll do the episode.
Rym: It's a fun topic too, because if you're, if you haven't listened to geek, like if you're, if you're a long hauler who'd been listening to the show for a long time, one thing you know about us is that there are very few liquids Scott will put in his mouth.
Rym: And meanwhile, I drink a wide variety of liquids though.
Scott: I will eat most foods.
Scott: The only exceptions of foods like this, I don't like all foods, but I like a lot of foods.
Scott: I say more than average person.
Rym: I've seen you try foods that you know, you don't like.
Scott: just to see like, yeah, like, you know, I don't like lobster and someone had lobster and like, couldn't believe I didn't like lobster while I ate the lobster again and I still didn't like it.
Scott: You know, it's like, okay.
Scott: Um, sometimes I'll even eat a whole meal if, even if it's not the meal I would choose just cause it's the meal that's there, even though I don't like it, I'll eat it anyway.
Scott: Cause I'm an adult.
Scott: So I'll do that.
Scott: You know, not, you know, not have allergy.
Scott: allergy would stop me from eating it, but the only things I won't eat, some allergies won't stop.
Rym: Like there's that, there's an article a long time ago, there's a long form podcast and like NPR, this dude, who's definitely allergic to shellfish once a year, he eats a bunch and then just checks himself into the hospital.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I think I'm like, we, I think we discussed, I have a tiny apple allergy.
Scott: I'm eating apples.
Scott: It's apple season.
Rym: I have the, the oral, I have a serious OAS with apples where my throat will swell up a little bit, but apples are also delicious.
Scott: So anyway, but, uh, I'll eat almost any food other than unethical things.
Scott: Like I won't eat, you know, like a monkey brain or a shark fin or a octopus.
Scott: I don't like to eat, you know, Takoyaki is a big deal, but like octopus is too smart.
Rym: I can't be, I avoid it.
Rym: I try to minimize pork consumption.
Rym: Similarly.
Rym: These are real smart.
Rym: Uh, if you're going to go down that road, just saying, just saying, you opened a door, I can open it a little further, but I'm not claiming I'm not hypocritical.
Rym: I'm just saying society, but, uh, I'm not going to drink when it comes to beverages.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: When it comes to beverages, there is a very limited range of beverages that I will, let's say the breath of beverages that I will drink is narrow, but the depth is large.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So it's like, nevermind if we get into the method and manner by which you consume these beverages, which is also a conversation.
Scott: So it's like the only things that I will drink are water.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Uh, but he won't drink fancy waters.
Rym: Like Scott will avoid.
Rym: like mineral water, fizzy water, just regular ass fucking water, tap water, or maybe like filtered water.
Rym: is the extent of what Scott felt.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like a, you know, a bottled water is fine, but no, right?
Scott: No special, I won't eat the, what's the thing of the green bottle, right?
Scott: That mineral shit, whatever that is.
Rym: I love that stuff.
Scott: Oh, that's awful.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: Um, so water is my primary beverage.
Scott: I will drink dairy based, uh, beverages, milkshake, milk, uh, mango lassi yogurt type drinks.
Scott: Um, I will drink, uh, wait, wait, so what, uh, and juice, right?
Scott: Something that is fruit-based, but it has to be, sometimes I'll drink a fruit juice that is not really juice.
Scott: That's corn syrup or sugar.
Rym: It's funny because that's something I really won't drink.
Rym: I'll only very, it's very rare.
Scott: Most of the time I demand that it be actual fruit, right?
Scott: That I'm drinking and like an, you know, an orange juice where someone squeezed a fucking orange, right?
Scott: And not, you know, a bunch of sugar water and some orange flavor.
Rym: And while orange juice is fundamentally just sugar water for reasons that are beyond the scope of the show, I still love it.
Rym: And it's good for me because I need galleries.
Scott: Well, I mean, I used to drink orange for a lot of my life.
Scott: I drank pineapple orange slash orange juice, like every single morning, no matter what.
Scott: And sometimes even more than that.
Scott: But lately, like I cut that out years ago.
Scott: Now in the morning I drink, you know, uh, fiber because I'm an old man.
Rym: If I am active, like during the summer and there's orange juice in the house, I will drink like, I'm not even joking, like a full pint of orange juice just immediately when I wake up and I'll probably drink another pint of it before lunch.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean like.
Scott: I will drink orange juice if it's around, but I don't, I don't buy and always have orange juice like I used to.
Scott: It used to be like a mandatory thing to have in the fridge.
Scott: Now, extremely rare that I will have the orange juice.
Scott: But if it's there, I'll drink it.
Rym: Up until now, I'm the opposite.
Rym: Like I would drink almost as a kid, I would drink fucking anything and I drink more soda slash pop than you can possibly imagine.
Rym: Like I would.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So, right.
Scott: So the, so the inverse right is I don't drink.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, I mean, I guess I'm, oh, I'm not opposed to drinking tea.
Scott: I've just never liked it.
Rym: You have an allow list of drinks.
Rym: You'll get into your gullet as opposed to a denialist like I have.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But I won't drink.
Scott: I haven't found any tea that I like, you know, boiled leaf.
Scott: Even though if I found one that I liked, I would drink it.
Scott: I would be okay with it.
Scott: I don't drink coffee of any kind.
Scott: I really don't drink any, any caffeinated beverage period.
Scott: I won't drink.
Scott: I won't drink any alcoholic beverage and I won't drink any carbonated beverage, which is those things alone.
Scott: That's most beverages that people drink.
Rym: So as a kid, like on the opposite side, I like, I liked wine and alcohol even though I was a little kid.
Rym: Like I wouldn't get access to it often, but I loved the shit out of it and sought it out just for its flavor.
Rym: Not even it's intoxicating.
Scott: I mean, I've had wine and every time I had wine, I was like, this is grape juice with poison in it.
Scott: I'll just drink grape juice.
Scott: Why would you want to drink this?
Rym: Cause when I drink it, it's like, Ooh, this is good grape juice and good poison.
Rym: Like it just, the poison tastes like poison.
Rym: Outside of GeekNights, we have this conversation a lot.
Scott: Forgetting about all the other problems of drinking alcohol for a moment that it's, you know, the cause of all societal problems.
Rym: Forget all that.
Rym: I specifically enjoy the flavor of alcohol.
Scott: I do not enjoy the flavor of alcohol.
Scott: It tastes like I'm drinking something from the science lab.
Scott: It's awful.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Like I'll drink a non-alcoholic beer because I like the things in beer, but an alcoholic beer tastes different.
Rym: And I like that taste.
Rym: I would drink alcohol if it had zero intoxicating effects.
Rym: So, but as a kid, I would drink soda, as I say now, cause I've lived in New York for like 15 years, but a day, like literally zero exaggeration, six to eight cans of mostly Dr.
Rym: Pepper and a little bit of Coca-Cola, some Mountain Dew sometimes, a squirt, jolts, all that nonsense.
Rym: Like I just drink so much soda that it was shocking as a kid.
Scott: I mean, when I was young, I obviously understood that soda existed.
Scott: It was hard to not know that when you watch TV in the nineties.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Um, so I was aware of the existence of Coke and Pepsi, but it was, you know, years into my life before I just ever had any.
Scott: Um, and there would be occasions where it would be annoying that, you know, I'd be like at a party or something.
Scott: And that was the only beverage that they had.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And I wouldn't drink it, but I did try it.
Scott: at one point when I was young, I had like a can of Pepsi or something and I tried, I was like, Oh, okay.
Scott: I can't just say it was like, I, you know, I tried it and I tried it maybe a couple of times after that, you know, you know, different Coke or whatever, and it tasted.
Scott: it's even, I'd rather drink it like beer than drink soda carbonated.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So the car, so that's the two had two bad things.
Scott: Number one, it tasted like shit.
Scott: And like, I understand it, look at the bottle and it says, this is mostly corn syrup.
Scott: And I'm like, why doesn't this taste like delicious candy?
Scott: It doesn't, it tastes awful.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then two, the carbonation just hurts.
Scott: I'm like, I like in theory, you, I imagine the carbonation as being refreshing.
Scott: That's what the commercials tell me.
Rym: That is my experience.
Rym: It is object.
Scott: It makes sense.
Scott: I imagine bubble.
Scott: I imagine bubbles in my throat tingling and that imagination.
Scott: I imagine refreshment.
Scott: Like I, my throat wants bubbles, but if I actually tried to drink the bubbles into my throat, I only feel pain.
Scott: And I'm like, that was not what I was expecting.
Scott: This is not good.
Scott: Why didn't you do what you're supposed to do?
Scott: Get the fuck out of here.
Rym: But see, that's what I always find so fascinating.
Rym: It is literally a refreshing feeling to me.
Rym: I seek it out.
Rym: I'll drink carbonated, unflavored water, just soda water.
Scott: I mean, if, if I, if I felt the refreshment that I imagine I would feel, I would also drink and prefer carbonated water to regular water.
Scott: So one thing I'm curious about, I've attempted to drink sparkling beverages of various kinds over many years.
Scott: Not once have I felt the, the feeling that I believe I'm supposed to feel.
Scott: I only feel pain.
Scott: Like, you know, I guess it's not as bad as if I drank a Drano, we'll say like diluted Drano.
Scott: Like, like there is some burning sensation in my esophagus and it's not good.
Rym: So what I'm curious, the thing I'm curious about is one carbonation also imparts a flavor because of the acidic nature of carbon dioxide.
Rym: Like it actually does.
Scott: Well, I wouldn't know that, but okay.
Rym: So it makes a flavor, but two, you can nitrogenate beverages instead of carbonating them.
Rym: Those bubbles are smaller and less like fizz fizzy.
Rym: And I wonder if you would have a different or the same experience if you tried a nitrogenated beverage.
Scott: I have never attempted to drink a nitrogenated beverage.
Rym: Nitrogenated beverages also don't impart a, nitrogenization does not impart a flavor on the beverage.
Rym: Whereas carbonation does.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Well, I mean, I've never noticed the flavor on the carbonated one.
Scott: So get me a nitrogenated beverage.
Scott: I'll try it.
Rym: The problem is as long as it's not, you know, there are really only two classes of beverages that get nitrogenated.
Rym: There's really only two, you know what you just said, there's only two kinds of beverages that they nitrogenate.
Rym: Number one is coffee.
Rym: And number two is beer.
Scott: Well, so, and I can't think they're canceled on other merits.
Rym: Now we could manually nitrogenate orange juice.
Rym: Like I could, I could get some equipment and make that happen.
Rym: It's not that hard.
Scott: No, that's all.
Scott: If you're so dedicated to that, I really don't care.
Scott: I'm open to it.
Rym: I'm like 1% dedicated right now.
Rym: So the odds are pretty low.
Scott: I do not care enough to go seek it out.
Scott: I'm just open to the possibility.
Rym: Oh, a listener is like asking about what about nitrogenation because the stream is delayed from the chat.
Rym: So they don't realize we just talked about it.
Scott: So, uh, I never, I actually never heard of nitrogenation before just now, although it makes perfect sense.
Scott: So all that aside, uh, I've heard of liquid nitrogen nitrogen involved, but for to make cold beverages.
Rym: I literally drank over a thousand calories of soda a day from like fourth grade until like well into while I was at RIT.
Rym: But at RIT, partly because I was busy and I didn't have access to like my bike and a lot of the exercise I used to do when I was living like in high school with no responsibilities, uh, we can only play DDR so often.
Rym: I didn't need as many calories.
Rym: So I basically lost all desire to drink soda while I was at RIT because the main reason I drink soda prior to that was because of all those calories I needed and use those calories.
Rym: Like I'm skinny.
Rym: I'm still skinny.
Rym: So, uh, once I didn't drink soda much, what I discovered when I tried it again after like not really having it for a year and a half is that it tasted like shit to me like absolute shit.
Scott: But you also drink Red Bull instead.
Scott: I won't drink.
Rym: I think Red Bull is absolutely delicious.
Rym: I love energy drinks.
Scott: I won't drink any weird energy drink either.
Rym: So I will drink Red Bull as an energy drink, but I will not drink Monster and all those other things.
Rym: The difference being one, they taste different.
Rym: Like Red Bull tastes good to me.
Rym: Like that flavor profile is good.
Rym: But I also still like, well, I don't like pop soda, like the pop culture soda that normal people drink.
Rym: I do like like proper old colas that are taste more medicinal and weird and aren't as sweet.
Rym: But Monster and all the energy drinks that a lot of people drink, they're just like concentrated Mountain Dew.
Rym: Like they're the same high fructose corn syrup, just more concentrated with a bunch of fake vitamin crap in them.
Rym: Red Bull at least has a radically different flavor profile because it's not high fructose corn syrup.
Scott: I tried Red Bull once.
Scott: It tastes like shit.
Scott: I didn't drink it.
Scott: But I wouldn't drink it anyway.
Rym: It might taste like shit.
Rym: I actually just was drinking one right now.
Rym: I've got it here just as a no surprise.
Rym: Finish that off.
Rym: One, Red Bull's not that many calories.
Rym: And two, it tastes radically different from other energy drinks, even though I respect that you might not like either.
Rym: It does taste very different.
Rym: So Monster tastes like garbage to me.
Scott: Even if it tasted good and I liked it, its energy nature would make me not drink it.
Rym: Ah, but it's energy nature.
Scott: I would need like the no energy version.
Rym: But the thing is, I need that energy.
Rym: Part of my life as I've just, especially during the quarantine, it got to the point to where I have fundamentally changed my relationship with food and calories by the nature of how much I work out and do exercise.
Rym: I struggle to get enough calories into my body in a day, partly because you know what food I can't eat, which is on the scope for this show?
Rym: Most food that bodybuilders and athletes eat to keep their calories up, I often find that food flavorless or disgusting.
Rym: So trying to get the five-ish thousand calories I need a day in the summer.
Scott: Like those people that eat like 10 chicken breasts or whatever.
Rym: I can't do that.
Rym: My stomach's not big enough.
Rym: And also that's just bland food.
Rym: Making fresh food and the kind of food I like and the kind of food that we eat just in our day-to-day lives, the sheer amount of it I'd have to eat is too much.
Rym: So I supplement that with a lot of energy drinks, a lot of sugar, a lot of cookies, a lot of snacks.
Rym: I have a whole thing I got to do just to get to my minimum calorie targets.
Rym: So I drink a lot of energy drinks.
Rym: I also eat energy goo when I run, even though it's just disgusting.
Rym: But it's a tool.
Scott: I don't do that.
Rym: It is a tool.
Rym: It is not something I drink or eat for enjoyment.
Rym: I would not eat or drink those things if I did not have a specific need.
Rym: But anyway, that aside, I also very much enjoy the flavor of cocktails.
Rym: Like cocktails are some of my favorite beverages on earth to the point that I seek out non-alcoholic cocktails to scratch that itch because I don't always want to be drinking alcohol.
Rym: Even if I crave the flavor of, say, a Negroni or an Old Fashioned, I do not necessarily want the intoxicating component of that flavor profile.
Rym: But it is almost impossible to get that flavor profile without alcohol because the flavor of alcohol literally causes some aspects of those profiles.
Rym: So there's a lot of mixology I'm deep into.
Rym: that's a little too much to talk about in this show, but suffice it to say, that's a big part of my beverage life.
Scott: I do respect and actually have a lot of appreciation for the whole cocktail science.
Rym: It's real easy to make a real shitty cocktail and it's real hard to make a good one.
Rym: And the simpler a cocktail is, the harder it is to make.
Rym: well.
Scott: Right, but not only is there the art of figuring out a good combination of liquids and other ingredients to create a beverage that otherwise does not exist as a single ingredient, like the juice of a fruit or water from a water source, right?
Scott: It's also, you can tell, right, that cocktail people are doing extra stuff or doing stuff in a particular way because it's fun.
Scott: And I agree, it looks way fun, right?
Scott: Like shaking up, shaking up something in a weird shaker, making an ice cube that happens to be smooth just because.
Rym: Don't even get me started on my weird ice cubes, we've talked about that before.
Scott: Using a funky looking glass just to make it look cool.
Scott: It's like, you know, I respect that as a visual art, right?
Scott: And as an activity, as a hobby, right?
Scott: It's totally awesome.
Scott: It's just that even, you know, limiting to only the non-alcoholic beverages, right?
Scott: There has basically been, I've tried, you know, there's been quite a few times, not recently, where I've gone into like a bar, there's like a party at a bar I can't avoid or whatever, a company holiday party or something, right?
Scott: And, you know, the bartender agrees to make a non-alcoholic thing, right?
Scott: And they mix up all whatever stuff I'm willing to drink, and it doesn't taste good.
Rym: Well, because I've realized something just in this conversation.
Scott: I'm like, you have orange juice, you have water.
Scott: I'm like, that's what I'll take from you.
Scott: You don't have anything good back there.
Rym: You universally do not seem to like beverages that are savory or that are not in some way sweet or completely neutral.
Rym: Like you like the flavor of orange juice, but I don't think you'd like the flavor of just orange without the sugar.
Scott: Well, no, I drink, I have actually trained, you know, most of my not drinking orange juice has been replaced by just eating fucking oranges instead.
Rym: Ah, but those are also extremely sweet.
Rym: I'm saying you have to remove the sugar and like just eat orange zest.
Scott: Orange zest is delicious.
Scott: What are you talking about?
Scott: I put it in like cookies and stuff all the time.
Rym: Yeah, but just eat it like, okay, because that's how you make good non-alcoholic cocktail is those kinds of flavor profiles.
Rym: Citrus flavors are awesome.
Rym: There's a brand.
Rym: Now, this is not an ad like don't even think that this is, but Seedlip, they basically, it's a company that makes botanicals to use to make cocktails that are not alcoholic and that are designed to be able to make good cocktails.
Rym: Like, for example, one of them, you know what's in it?
Rym: It's basically just like water with some orange peel, lemon peel, lemongrass and ginger, but zero sweetener of any kind.
Rym: And you use like teaspoons or tablespoons of that mixed with other beverages to together make a flavor profile that would be good to drink.
Rym: I'm really curious if you would like a Seedlip.
Scott: It's like a little slightly fancy, you know, I mean, like.
Scott: I really like it when you get like a cucumber water, right?
Scott: It's like, I obviously would prefer like a, you know, a lemonade, right?
Scott: But, you know, if you just put a slice of lemon in a water, it's like, that's not bad.
Scott: You know, you know, cucumber water at the hotel, that's good.
Scott: Celery water, I like a celery water.
Rym: I don't like the tomato drink.
Rym: That's too, you know, I'm not a fan of V8 is just tomato soup in a different can.
Rym: It's the same.
Scott: And while I enjoy dairy based things and, you know, fruit based things, even like celery cucumber, when they get like those, like the smoothies, like, you know, your Jamba Juice type action where you got like lettuce in there and shit.
Scott: I can't drink that.
Scott: I can't do right.
Scott: So part of what's going on there is that even carrot, like I love carrots in carrot cake, carrot juice is too much.
Scott: I can't drink a carrot smoothie.
Scott: It says too much.
Rym: So with cocktails, the conventional wisdom is generally the simpler, older cocktails are just better because there's a reason they've persisted so long and it's harder to fuck them up.
Rym: Really complex cocktails, 90% of the time are garbage designed by someone who has no idea what they're doing.
Rym: So a complex cocktail that's good is relatively rare and a place that can make a complex cocktail that actually tastes good and doesn't just look fancy.
Rym: That is like, that's like when we go to a restaurant and they have a pastry chef with a name as opposed to cheesecake and chocolate cake on the menu.
Rym: Like that's one of those, like the opposite of a red flag.
Scott: But I mean, it makes, it makes sense.
Scott: A cocktail is at its heart, right?
Scott: You're mixing some beverages together or ingredients together that will still be liquid.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And can be just whiskey is not a cocktail.
Rym: That's whiskey.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: But if you mix things, it's like, it's really hard to, you know, any flavor is going to overpower another flavor.
Scott: It's like you had a glass of fucking, you know, it's like lemonade.
Scott: It's like, all right, you can add a lemongrass might do a little bit to it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like, it's like, you're either going to overpower the lemon with too much other shit.
Scott: And like, you're not going to taste that hint of mint you tossed in there.
Scott: If you got too much other crap in there, it's only a limit to go in or like, or even just the craft of it.
Rym: and like balancing everything in old fashioned with one is sugar cube in.
Rym: it tastes fantastic.
Rym: One and a half sugar cubes tastes like sweet garbage.
Rym: less than a one sugar cube tastes like just poison.
Scott: One thing I have seen people do that obviously I haven't partaken of is they'll make like these layered drinks by making sure that the ingredients are like densities.
Rym: Those are good to drink.
Scott: But what I, I am my, my imagination is that, you know, if, you know, you're basically, you're just putting three beverages or however many in the same glass and you're drinking one after the other.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that at least of, you know, you get some fanciness to it, right.
Scott: And the flavors won't overpower each other.
Scott: Cause they're not actually mixing.
Scott: You're just, it would be the same as if you had three separate glasses and drink one, then the next one, then the next one.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So it's actually worse than that.
Rym: So I actually applied to be a bartender at that bowling alley.
Rym: that later got the DDR machine at RIT, you know, cause I know a lot about cocktails and I always have, and I like cocktails and I can make them well.
Rym: And they asked me like in the interview, they asked me some questions and they asked me what a puss cafe was.
Rym: Cause I didn't know about them.
Rym: That's what that kind of drink is called.
Rym: They're literally designed for show.
Rym: And generally imagine if someone very, if someone orders one, it is one of those red flags at a bar where the person ordering it is telling the bar tender that they are a piece of shit.
Rym: who doesn't understand the labor of a bartender and is trying to impress some third party with their knowledge of cocktails.
Rym: It basically is telling the bartender charge this fool, a lot of money for something that's going to taste like garbage.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: But two, they're primarily used by bartenders to show off themselves.
Rym: So a bartender will sometimes offer to make one for fun.
Rym: Like if they got some free time or like.
Rym: there's a lot of reasons someone to make one, but they never taste good.
Rym: It is impossible to make them taste good or at least so challenging that it's, you know, but like most of them are designed to be very striking visually or craft wise as opposed to, to be drunk.
Rym: But a lot of times they involve flame and other like weird, like fun.
Rym: And once you get into that kind of beverage, like the beverages that use liquid nitrogen, if made properly, flaming beverages like that are on fire when you drink them, kind of, but imagine if it was still on fire.
Rym: or beverages that literally have liquid nitrogen in them.
Rym: It is possible to make those so that they can be drunk safely.
Scott: However, if you fuck up, you hurt people.
Rym: If you fuck up, you can kill people.
Rym: So of course you never drink a beverage that involves an alcoholic beverages that involves flame because alcohol flames, if they're still burning are often invisible.
Rym: You cannot see them.
Rym: You will burn yourself before you realize it.
Rym: And the liquid nitrogen drinks can just fucking kill you and it'll be too late.
Rym: You'll drink it and you're dead.
Rym: And bartenders fuck these up a lot.
Rym: No ethical bartender will make that shit for you.
Scott: That that's the only make it like the bartending competition or whatever.
Rym: But non-alcoholic keg tails get even more complicated because one thing I've noticed having cooked a lot of vegan food over the last couple of years is that to make food that involves any meat is almost like easy mode cooking.
Rym: It's kind of hard to fuck up most meat and it's really easy to salvage meat if you don't cook it that great.
Rym: And meat can just save a dish.
Rym: If you can't lean on meat and you're working solely from vegetables and things, it's harder to make a really good flavor profile.
Rym: You're doing a lot more.
Rym: like it takes a little more skill.
Rym: Cocktails are kind of the same way.
Rym: Alcoholic cocktails lean heavily on the history of cocktails and on alcohol.
Rym: So it is actually a difficult skill to design a non-alcoholic cocktail that's good.
Rym: Most bars have half-assed bullshit non-alcoholic cocktails because they don't make any money off of them.
Rym: So if you find a bar that has good non-alcoholic cocktails, that is like an S rank bar.
Rym: Their alcohol cocktails will blow you away.
Rym: And they're also very rare.
Scott: So the show's getting a little long I think.
Scott: I'm hungry.
Rym: You want to cover one last glass of drinks?
Scott: No let's do like best beverages right?
Scott: So best beverage.
Rym: Like do you want to do it by class?
Rym: By weight class?
Scott: Eh just whatever.
Rym: Top five?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: My number one is still slightly cool tap water.
Rym: Like that is the number one beverage for me on earth.
Scott: The best possible water would be water directly from an actual natural spring.
Rym: I've drunk that on many occasions in my life.
Scott: That is cold as fuck.
Rym: Okay okay if we're going down that route I agree with you.
Rym: That is my favorite drink on this earth.
Rym: Not just my favorite water but my favorite drink.
Rym: There is something pretty high up there.
Rym: There's something that feels so magical about drinking water like from the ground in the wild knowing confidently that it is safe to drink and just tasting it.
Rym: Like what a. uh it's hard to get past that.
Scott: It's even better than New York tap water somehow.
Scott: I don't know how.
Rym: My favorite all right cocktail like my one of my favorite beverage is honestly an old-fashioned cocktail of just very well-crafted old-fashioned cocktail.
Rym: Other than the fact that it would kill me if I did this I would just drink them all day.
Rym: I don't because I the physics and biology limit how many of those I can drink.
Rym: So I don't drink them that often.
Rym: but a proper old-fashioned is one of my favorite things on earth to put in my mouth.
Scott: Not yet.
Scott: uh you know don't drink alcohol kids.
Scott: It causes cancer.
Scott: no joke all right.
Scott: Uh I guess also an amazing beverage that I will also would order much more often if a more places made it properly and b it cost less and c was healthier to drink is a milkshake of some variety.
Rym: I'll just see right.
Rym: I with my calorie needs milkshakes and ice cream.
Rym: uh we'll just talk about the beverages.
Rym: I will drink milkshakes all the time just to get to my calorie and protein needs for a day and I can correct.
Scott: a properly made milkshake will be made with you know obviously high quality ice cream high quality milk but in a tall metal glass with the mixing machine.
Rym: You better give me that fucking metal thing so I can fill my glass after I drink the first half of the milkshake.
Scott: Exactly if they just give you a cup it's like you got screwed.
Scott: they were supposed to give you the tall metal thing.
Scott: then you pour it into a glass and it stays in it right.
Rym: Remember that scene in Pulp Fiction where the guy's like wait that milkshake is that expensive and it's alcoholic?
Rym: yeah a good milkshake will cost as much as an alcoholic beverage and be that good.
Scott: Yeah it'll be like seven dollars or plus to get a milkshake usually and also the milkshake if it's flavored which often it is.
Scott: it should only be flavored with a real vanilla right extract.
Scott: none of that fake vanilla flavoring syrups or any kind of bullshit like that.
Scott: b real fruits of some kind actual strawberries actual banana slices something like that right d some.
Scott: if it's chocolate it has to be fox's.
Scott: you bet chocolate syrup?
Scott: no hershey's bullshit right.
Scott: and if you want to do cookies and cream you can't use oreos because Nabisco on strike.
Scott: so wait until they're not and then Oreos in there.
Rym: So you're talking about that.
Rym: that's like that's A tier A plus tier edging into S tier but for me S tier not just the mango lassi which is one of my favorite beverages.
Rym: mango lassi's S tier but you gotta sometimes they don't make it as good oh no but uh even a shitty mango lassi's S tier the secret tier above S because this is traditionally only for certain kinds of celebrations.
Scott: the rose lassi holy fucking shit if you know that's that's edging into the tea territory where like you're eating like flowers.
Rym: basically rose lassi's are so so good.
Rym: caveat i love the flavor of rose.
Rym: anyway i'm like homer hiding the bathroom.
Scott: you just love eating flowers.
Rym: in general flowers are delicious and roses are particularly delicious.
Rym: i will just eat them.
Scott: candy flowers are for looking at.
Scott: never had a candy rose but i've eaten plenty of flowers.
Scott: they never tasted good.
Rym: uh i i make a lot of cocktails with violet and lavender extracts.
Rym: yeah i know in terms of juices it's uh it's tough because orange juice is like my standby.
Rym: but my actual favorite juice might have to be if you can get it mango juice but that kind of edges into being a smoothie depending on how you get it.
Scott: and sometimes when you get it it's actually nectar and it's like got a lot of.
Scott: you know it's not just squeezed mango which i like nectars a lot.
Scott: but uh apple cider is the king right you can't beat apple cider.
Rym: um so in america apple cider is not alcoholic right.
Scott: so we had i guess we had to cover this right.
Rym: so this cider which obviously i'm not drinking because it's alcoholic if it's uh thin and yellow you got juice there fella if it's taking.
Scott: in the united states there's a thing that we call apple cider which is literally just pressed apples into a into a jug.
Scott: um and you know it's all brown and has sort of so good it's floating in it.
Scott: i think a lot of other places on earth call that apple juice because that's what it is.
Scott: it's a juiced apple.
Rym: and when they say apple cider they mean for men.
Rym: they basically mean apple beer not really but they mean alcoholic apple juice.
Scott: right then there's a third thing that is called apple juice in the united states.
Scott: that is basically apple cider that has been filtered and may be concentrated and watered down again.
Scott: it depends but it's like a clear yellowish thing.
Scott: it doesn't taste bad although it's i don't like it brand you get.
Rym: i liked it.
Scott: some are it's always worse than apple cider slash right um but there are some brands that are better than others.
Scott: i used to drink it a fuck ton but now i basically don't drink it rarely if ever i don't drink apple juice at all.
Rym: as a kid there's a stop.
Rym: when i was young i loved apple juice and over the course of a week at one point in my young childhood i drank so much apple juice that it made me moderately seriously ill.
Rym: but uh i uh apple cider and the year the the british definition i prefer to american apple cider because i do like that bite of the alcohol in it.
Rym: and the further extreme of that is something called apple jack which i think is almost exclusively american.
Scott: that's like that's like apple vodka so the way apple jack used to be made.
Rym: they don't make it this way anymore because it's moderately dangerous to make it this way.
Rym: yeah apple cider take it.
Rym: now you take apple cider and you do something called uh freeze just different terms for it like freeze jacking.
Rym: you just freeze the barrel turn it sideways cut off the ends thought freeze it again.
Rym: turn it sideways cut off the ends thought yeah that's smooth.
Rym: that's how you make you know it's actually moderately safe to make it that way.
Scott: compared to using three x's on the side of that barrel that's only two x's.
Rym: do it.
Scott: yeah two two x's because both your eyes will go blind.
Rym: it was relatively recently legalized to like make legit apple jack in the u.s.
Rym: there's only a few places that can do it.
Rym: uh i get it when i can.
Rym: it's so fucking delicious.
Rym: oh i like it.
Rym: i prefer it to whiskey.
Rym: i'm just gonna be blunt.
Scott: so i love me a grape juice.
Scott: uh but the best grape juice is basically when you take fancy wine grapes and you just don't make wine you just squeeze them and that's it.
Scott: uh and i there's a few places you can buy it from one that i buy from on occasion and they basically make two different kinds a white kind and a red kind and they're both delicious.
Scott: uh and i always have some in the in the little cabinet over there.
Scott: yeah that's excellent.
Scott: a plus beverage.
Rym: in terms of hot beverages i really like the.
Rym: i like coffee.
Rym: i do.
Rym: i really like tea especially matcha like proper like.
Scott: i think the only hot beverage i drink is hot cocoa and nothing else like a hot cocoa.
Rym: but i really like coffee a wide variety of coffees.
Rym: i like every possible coffee drink good ones bad ones everything.
Rym: i just love coffee.
Scott: but i something else i don't drink.
Scott: that's i know could be a whole episode on its own or all the boba teas that whole category.
Rym: i love a boba uh.
Scott: and then something else i definitely won't drink are any of those like kool-aids or high seas or any of that.
Rym: as a kid we drank a lot of kool-aid.
Rym: it was funny when i was a kid for all the garbage soda i would drink.
Rym: my line was sunny d sunny delight tastes like pure poison if it even touched.
Rym: i think i've tasted it once and i agree it was like all my friends like they had that in their fridges.
Scott: i wouldn't drink capri sun that shit's poison.
Scott: i wouldn't drink that.
Rym: i like ecto coolers and all that crap.
Scott: nope did not like that shit.
Rym: i would just make kool-aid all the time and just drink like i wanted real.
Scott: i wanted real juice.
Rym: also as a kid you know we drank a lot of the mcdonald's orange drink.
Scott: i did not drink orange julius.
Scott: i like though even though that's fake as i like an orange julius i miss an orange.
Scott: i like orange julius.
Rym: yep and i think we have killed this topic.
Rym: we could go on for another hour but uh you get the gist.
Rym: uh i think we're done.
Rym: let's stop it right there.
Rym: i literally said it on that.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music cat lee for web design and brand ok for the logos be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech mondays gaming tuesdays.
Rym: anime comic wednesdays and indiscriminate thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the patreon patreons for this episode of GeekNights are hidey minical allen dress link kiji adrenaline littler kris rimer clinton walton decks fin just like a dude guy.
Rym: kishiai 85. rebecca dun review bed built 34 cowards vine parents sam erickson sherman harl taylor run under gram pro law.
Rym: ado pierce right seat.
Rym: f thread open.
Rym: you hold the key to my heart and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: uh yeah we'll be doing uh the evangelion movie show review next week on wednesday and a to be determined monday show.
Rym: if you have a good monday idea let us know.
Rym: otherwise we'll probably do it on sleep modes and hibernation in computers because frankly even in the year 2021 they don't work for shit.
Rym: but uh for now i leave you with solidarity forever.
Rym: solidarity forever.
Rym: solidarity forever for the union makes us strong.
Rym: oh when the union's inspiration through the worker's blood shall run there can be no power greater anywhere beneath the sun.
Rym: yet what force on earth is weaker than the feeble strength of one?
Rym: but the union makes us strong.
Rym: solidarity forever.
Scott: solidarity forever.
Scott: solidarity forever for the union makes us strong.