Rym: It's Tuesday, May 4th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we're reviewing the game you might have heard of, Super Mario Bros.
Rym: 3.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, yeah, got my second COVID shot.
Scott: Okay, me too.
Rym: Yeah, it was an interesting experience.
Rym: I got Moderna.
Rym: I'm not going to pretend I didn't get side effects.
Rym: I had a pretty rough day.
Scott: But I didn't have my arm hurt.
Scott: Yeah, it felt like someone punched my arm and like it was a bruise there, even though there wasn't.
Scott: And then that lasted not very long.
Rym: Yeah, it's fascinating.
Rym: That was a wide spectrum of like levels of side effects ranging from nothing to like two days of like bad feelings before you're good again.
Scott: Like, you know, some of my coworkers reported like they were.
Scott: they were blah.
Scott: And then suddenly it went away after like, you know, a day or whatever.
Scott: But, yep, nothing happened to me on either shot.
Scott: I just took both and I was just like, OK, my arm hurt.
Rym: Yeah, I had a really strong reaction for the first like thirty six hours after my second shot.
Rym: But it was almost fascinating because it was like it felt bad, like real bad.
Rym: But at the same time, I knew I wasn't sick.
Scott: You should lie.
Scott: And, you know, I mean, I don't lie, but you should because then you're going to.
Scott: people are not going to want to get it because they're pretty side effects.
Scott: You should be like, oh, it was great.
Scott: It felt like I was high.
Scott: I felt like I was doing things.
Rym: The problem is then there's a disconnect between like when dare said, hey, kids, don't do drugs, drugs suck.
Rym: And then they tell you about drugs.
Rym: And the way they describe me, you're like, wait, drugs sound awesome.
Rym: And then they're like, no, but the weed will kill you.
Rym: And then when a kid finds out that weed might not be great for other reasons, but it won't kill them, they question everything else.
Scott: Hmm.
Rym: So I don't want to lie.
Rym: Like I had pretty bad side effects.
Rym: But the feel like once the side effects passed, like a day goes by, I gave up a Sunday.
Scott: The feeling of liberation, even despite the fact that I'm not going to get it, honestly, should have gone on a Monday or a Friday.
Scott: So you don't lose a weekend.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, knowing that the side effects are possible, you should go in a weekday, do it on a weekday, make work, pay for the shit.
Scott: My work said, you know, if you're going to go get vaccinated, don't even use vacation days or sick days.
Scott: Just fucking go whenever you can go.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And if you have a side effect, all right, just don't work and then just wait.
Scott: And don't worry about sick days or vacation days.
Scott: Just don't work.
Rym: Because frankly, like I'm being real, the side effects, even if you get the worst case side effects, they're not pleasant.
Rym: They go away.
Scott: It's better than losing your taste and smell or coughing to death or whatever else COVID is going to do.
Rym: I would rather go through a month of feeling the way I felt than losing my sense of taste and smell.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: Like also, and I'm not changing my life radically like post shot.
Rym: Like there's a very slow reentry into society for safety reasons and a lot of reasons.
Scott: I'm waiting.
Scott: I'm looking at the numbers.
Scott: I'm just going to play a numbers based game.
Scott: And now that I have a vaccine, I'm vaccinated, I'm going to wait for the numbers to go down enough to where it's like, oh, now I'm just going to trust that number.
Scott: There's some threshold at which I have not yet decided, but we're definitely not under it yet.
Scott: Whatever it is.
Scott: Not close.
Rym: But despite not changing anything immediately, it still is a weirdly like strong and profound feeling of relief to have that second shot.
Rym: Like just knowing that I'm pretty much into this thing is a really good feeling.
Scott: I don't really have that feeling.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I mean, you're welcome to not have that feeling.
Rym: I definitely have that feeling.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I mean, like, you know, it's like if I got a, you know, I was I was saying even beforehand, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, if you get a tetanus shot, right, you know, and then you step on a rusty nail, you still are worried, right?
Scott: I'm immune to tetanus.
Rym: The only tetanus shots I've gotten, because the way you're supposed to get a tetanus shot every 10-ish years, at least that's the last time I checked.
Rym: Maybe it's less now.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: But usually what happens is I injure myself.
Rym: I go to the doctor.
Rym: They ask me, hey, when was the last tetanus shot?
Rym: And I think back and I'm like, I'm not 100 percent sure.
Rym: And the way doctors point is, if you're not 100 percent sure, they give you one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the point is, I had one in 2012 in Australia, right?
Scott: If I would have stepped on a rusty nail in 2014 when it was definitely still effective, I wouldn't have felt like, ha ha, I'm totally safe from tetanus.
Scott: I got that tetanus shot.
Rym: I would have literally felt that way.
Rym: I would have been like, ha ha, I only have to worry about this gaping wound and not about a deadly disease.
Scott: Yeah, I would not have felt that way.
Scott: I would have still been worried about tetanus, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, if you give me a vaccine for some STD, I'm not going to go banging people with no protection, right?
Scott: Like I'm like, I'm immune.
Rym: Well, it depends.
Rym: It depends.
Rym: A lot of like in the tetanus vaccine in particular is so extremely effective.
Scott: I know.
Scott: But I'm just saying is that even if you tell me it's ninety nine point ninety nine percent effective and there's studies to show it and such and such, I still I can't feel like it's.
Scott: you know, I still can't act like I'm totally safe from it and run around with people coughing and breathing in the area.
Rym: Oh, yeah, that's the difference.
Rym: Like if I step on a nail, I feel 100 percent good because I know my last tetanus shot was within the last 10 years.
Rym: I actually can't remember exactly what it was, meaning whenever I hurt myself again, I'm going to have to get one again.
Rym: But if I go on the subway, I'm not going to go find rusty nails to step on.
Scott: No, but if I go on the subway and someone cough in there, I'm not going to be like, oh, I'm vaccinated.
Scott: I'm good.
Scott: I'm like, oh, shit, got to get off this car.
Rym: I'm not going to be like, let me let me go lick your hands.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: Save the hand licking of strangers till like twenty twenty two sometime.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: We'll get back to that.
Rym: The licking one's hands.
Rym: That's the traditional greeting it packs.
Rym: Nothing bad's ever come of that.
Scott: OK.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Have any other actual news here?
Rym: There's a bunch of news.
Rym: So we'll start with something.
Rym: But it's this is a game.
Rym: So we're going to talk about it just in case any of you nerds decide that you think this is not a game.
Rym: But there's a game you might have seen called hockey.
Rym: And in that game, air hockey, ice hockey.
Rym: The best hockey is one of the upper hockey up there.
Rym: But in ice hockey, ice hockey is a weird sport in that fighting up to a certain point within certain weirdly like defined parameters is expected and to a degree accepted.
Scott: And this.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So over over time it is.
Scott: Over time it has decreased significantly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But there is basically this toxically masculine culture in ice hockey whereby there is some sort of unwritten codes or rules such that, you know, the people who actually enforce the game, the referees in the league don't actually enforce everything.
Scott: And instead, the players engage in some sort of barbaric self enforcement where, you know, it's like, yeah, you're allowed to hit people in the game.
Scott: It's part of the game.
Scott: Maybe that should be removed.
Scott: But that's for another time.
Scott: But, you know, if you hit someone too hard or hit the wrong person or hit someone in the wrong way, whether it may or may not be legal within the rules of the game out there, you'll have other players who will then, you know, fight you, you know, to be like, you know, to sort of keep the other team in line so they don't just beat the shit out of your team and vice versa.
Scott: And also sometimes just get in a fight to sort of, you know, theoretically rile up the blood and get your team, you know, adrenaline pumping because, you know, they see you fighting.
Scott: And, you know, this is toxically masculine attitude of, you know, OK, this my team saw me fight.
Scott: Now they'll get the breathe some life into them and they'll play better.
Scott: That stuff's all nonsense.
Rym: But an example of where that like there's a rule called roughing in hockey and the way roughing works is if you hit someone in a way that has no rules associated with it, like you just sort of rough someone up
Scott: and you weren't fighting, but you you weren't actually all out fighting, dropping the gloves, having a boxing match.
Rym: Like if the whistle blew and Scott was on the rival team and I skated by him and I just like elbowed him, that's like that's roughing.
Scott: Well, there's an elbowing rule, but like, you know, you grab someone, you shake them up a little bit, you know, and you're like, but you didn't really, you know, maybe you didn't like start throwing fisticuffs back and forth.
Rym: It usually involves things that happen after the whistle.
Rym: But again, there's a lot of weird like blurred lines.
Scott: It's sort of like, you know, how you have like first degree murder.
Scott: It's sort of like second degree fighting is called roughing.
Rym: But fighting is like a whole different thing.
Rym: So anyway, there's a dude by the name of Tom Wilson who's basically, at least in hockey, a piece of shit
Scott: because he's notorious, like he is, you know, there's always these players who have like a history of, you know, getting called and punished or for, you know, being extra violent.
Rym: Like ask anyone in the NHL who the bad people are, who like hurt people on purpose.
Rym: Everybody knows the list of names.
Rym: It's the same list of names that everyone.
Scott: So on the one hand, there's this sort of thing where, you know, somebody, you know, maybe they ask, you know, because sometimes it happens by accident.
Scott: Just you do something, you're on ice, right?
Scott: It just looks bad.
Scott: You hurt.
Rym: There's some players who are very large and they might execute a perfectly legal check that hurts someone.
Rym: And that's a difficult situation to resolve because they did, they followed the rules of the game, but they're gigantic.
Scott: You can get this sort of bad reputation that may or may not be undeserved.
Scott: And then something happens along the lines and you get a punishment that's greater than anyone else because you have this history.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And because of this reputation that may or may not be well earned.
Scott: You suddenly are now the target.
Scott: And it's like, are you actually bad?
Scott: You know, you can find things that other people have done that look just like that who are considered good, good sportsmen.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, and, you know, stand up, not dirty players.
Rym: An incident happened last night that brought this up again because this person has a history of doing egregious, objectively wrong things.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And, you know, yeah, and have been, you know, it's like repeat offender.
Scott: But if you watch the footage, it's like, you know, and then compare which times it was enforced and which times it wasn't.
Scott: It's like, yeah.
Scott: And then if you actually watch the person and the way they behave, you can tell these basically are barbaric.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: Someone in the thread talking about this.
Rym: Someone used the big dog thread.
Scott: There's so many threads the whole Internet is talking about.
Rym: But it was like Tom in the safety penalty box.
Rym: Rawr!
Rym: Tom appealing his suspension.
Rym: Please don't hurt me.
Rym: I'm just a hockey player.
Rym: So last night there was a hockey game that did not matter.
Rym: Like it could ostensibly determine if the caps have like the number one seed or the number two seed.
Rym: But like doesn't matter that much.
Scott: It wasn't zero percent mattering.
Scott: It was like a barely mattering game.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So the game, we expected it to be a game where like none of the star players are playing.
Rym: Everyone's kind of just trying not to get hurt.
Rym: Like there's an agreement that no one's going to try too hard.
Rym: But then people started trying really hard for a bunch of other reasons.
Rym: And then there was a big pile up of people in front of a net.
Rym: And Tom Wilson is on top of a player.
Rym: Butch.
Rym: It was Butch, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And just drills him out of nowhere long after the whistle.
Scott: He's holding his.
Scott: he's holding Butch's head down right with his stick across the back of his neck.
Scott: So Butch is just laying there just like, well, someone's on top of me holding my head down to the ice.
Scott: All right.
Scott: And then while Butch's head is held down to the ice, Tom Wilson punches him in the head.
Scott: Now, which is against the ice.
Rym: If an equivalent assault happened in like an NBA game, there would be charges pressed.
Scott: Well, there's a thing called the Malice at the Palace.
Scott: I don't know if you know about this.
Rym: We've talked about this on GeekNights like 10 times.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But they didn't go to jail for the Malice at the Palace, I don't think.
Scott: They just got suspended for a very long time.
Scott: And this is, you know, this sounds ridiculous.
Scott: You know, because like hockey fights is such a thing.
Scott: But it's like, why when you get into a hockey fight, aren't you just arrested on and taken off the ice and charged with assault?
Scott: I don't understand.
Scott: I'm not even exaggerating why you got into a you fight someone on the street in that exact same way.
Scott: The cops would come and at least you spend like a night in a little little pokey.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or something like that.
Scott: Something would happen to you.
Scott: They might even take you in and let you go.
Scott: But, you know, it's like you can't have a fight of that nature.
Scott: But if you have it on the ice, it's like, oh, OK, you can have that fight.
Scott: It's like what?
Scott: Yeah, it's like, but this is so.
Scott: if I was the coach of an ice hockey team or the GM, I'd be like, if anyone fights even one time, you are off this team and I'm calling the police.
Scott: Also, if anyone comes and tries to fight you, you are to run away and try to get them penalized without you like during the big brawl, Panarin just rightly turtled.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So so after Butch's punch in the head, obviously, because of this code and the refs, you know, not doing anything like the ref didn't even react to the hit and like.
Rym: Right.
Rym: It looked like other players pummeling him too.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You have to sort of stand up for your team.
Scott: It's like you don't have a choice in that bad system.
Scott: It's like that's sort of what you have to do.
Scott: So they go.
Scott: The other players who are not fighting top plate type players.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You got Panarin, who's one of the best players in the whole league.
Scott: You know, you had to realize he's as tall as me and he only weighs maybe like 10 more pounds than me.
Scott: Only he's obviously has no body fat and is all muscle, whereas I have a bunch of flesh.
Rym: I can't.
Rym: Tom Wilson is six foot four and weighs two hundred and twenty pounds.
Scott: And he's got like 50 pounds on the ice by his neck.
Scott: He has 50 pounds on Panarin.
Scott: So Panarin comes, you know, to sort of defend Butch Nevich and so does the rest of the team.
Scott: And a fight ensues that is not the normal kind of hockey fight where two guys, you know, go, OK, let's fight and drop the gloves and have a little fisticuff.
Scott: This is like we are defending our teammate and then the Capitals players are then like defending their teammate.
Scott: And it's like it's an actual fight.
Scott: Like if, you know, two groups of people, you know, on the street got into a fight thinking they were actually defending their friend from people actually trying to hurt them.
Scott: And in the process of this, Tom Wilson basically like ragdolls Panarin in a way that he could have, you know, his helmet came off at some point.
Scott: It looked like he could have just slammed Panarin's head into the ice, killing him, ending his career potentially.
Scott: He ended his season, which is not, you know, there's only a few games left, but he thankfully is a lower body injury, they're saying.
Rym: But here's the deal, not to go like forever on this, because we could do a whole show on this and there's hockey podcasts that will just watch the footage yourself and decide for yourself.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: But here's the salient points.
Rym: One, the NHL doesn't actually have at least currently enough like power and rules to deal with this kind of situation.
Rym: The maximum fine they can give him unless they change the rules is five grand.
Rym: They find him like NHL players.
Scott: The players union in their union contract says you can't find any one of us more than five thousand dollars.
Scott: So the players union is OK with this.
Scott: Also, the player union rep at the Capitals is Tom Wilson, the barbarian.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Which says everything.
Rym: Even further, Tom Wilson has been suspended for shit like this before, fined for shit like this before.
Scott: He was suspended earlier this season and afterwards he was like, OK, I got to change up my game.
Scott: He didn't change shit.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And after this fight, when he was issued a game misconduct and there was likely there was a fine, it was clear the NHL was reviewing.
Rym: He gets up in the penalty box and starts taunting the people he fought.
Scott: Yeah, like he's some sort of like, you know.
Scott: He should be ejected from the league.
Scott: I mean, at the very least.
Rym: Make an example of him.
Rym: If you're going to make an example of anyone, there is no more deserving person than Tom Wilson to be kicked out of the NHL.
Scott: I've posted this comment all in all places of the Internet.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But my comment is basically, look, baseball permanently kicked out.
Scott: Pete Rose from all of baseball permanently for betting on games.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So right.
Scott: And while that's clearly bad to bet on a game that you are participating in.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And in, you know, it's all different from grabbing someone by the neck and slamming their head against the ice.
Scott: It's detrimental to the integrity of the game.
Scott: Clearly, you know, betting on games that you're playing in.
Scott: But, you know, violently attacking another human being in the course of a game, you're hurting another.
Scott: How is that not worse than gambling?
Scott: Right.
Scott: How is that not worse than gambling on the game that you're in?
Scott: It's got to be worse.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Being a violent barbarian and, you know, beating the shit out of someone else that doesn't warrant being permanently banned from the game.
Scott: But gambling on it does.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That makes no sense to me.
Scott: Right.
Scott: As far as I'm concerned, anyone who has ever been in a hockey fight.
Scott: Should be permanently banned from hockey.
Scott: It's like, don't fight.
Scott: It's like, you know, you know, it's like, come on.
Rym: But especially these.
Rym: There's the weirdly consensual hockey fights.
Rym: And then there's this kind of fight.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But it's like, OK, there should be a debate about this kind of fight at all.
Scott: We've got, you know, it's like we've reached a point where it's like, listen, you know, boxing was a thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like we don't need to continue to have boxing.
Scott: If you really want to see boxing, you can just watch Muhammad Ali.
Scott: There's this video.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You can watch Mike Tyson.
Scott: We don't need more.
Rym: We said we don't need more fights.
Rym: Right.
Rym: It's 2021.
Rym: We can end, you know, MMA.
Scott: It's like, why do we have that?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Get rid of that shit.
Scott: It's like we had enough, you know, violence.
Scott: We don't need violence anymore.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Football.
Scott: It's like we've had it.
Scott: We've you know, we got plenty.
Scott: Now it's over.
Scott: We've learned.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We don't need to keep doing this anymore.
Scott: If you really want to see it, you can see it.
Scott: And we don't need to have it anymore.
Rym: Specifically, we don't need them for the game.
Rym: There are enough YouTube videos of great hockey fights to sustain you for the rest of your life.
Scott: Formula One is better without people dying in car crashes.
Scott: You know, funny how much better with them surviving after it saved someone's life.
Scott: Like, oh, yeah, exactly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like we don't need violence.
Scott: We don't need the sports to have physical violence where you're hurting the other players ever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Any sport where that's a thing.
Scott: Other than, you know, we can still have things like Greco-Roman wrestling.
Scott: You can have Olympic boxing.
Scott: You can have Taekwondo.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Kendo.
Rym: Arguably, many of those are not less safe than MMA, but are definitely safer than boxing as it was.
Scott: I'm just saying is like there is.
Rym: I'm just saying don't call out MMA specifically if you're gonna give a pass to all those.
Rym: The line is a lot blurrier than you're implying.
Scott: I'm just saying is that we can have, you know, there is a line where we can draw to where we can have an acceptable combat-esque sport.
Rym: Here's an easy line to draw.
Rym: A sport that doesn't require like that level of violence should excise that violence.
Rym: Non-consensual hockey fights should be unambiguous.
Rym: Like there should be zero debate about that.
Rym: Like that's a place to start.
Scott: It's like I want something more extreme than that, but it's like that's just obvious, right?
Scott: It's like if you have a hockey fight that wasn't, you know, two guys agreeing to fight, it's like that's it.
Scott: You're done.
Rym: So can you imagine if there was a fist fight at an esport?
Rym: Like someone would get arrested.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: That has happened.
Scott: Obviously.
Scott: So what's the difference between that and a hockey fight?
Rym: Yeah, they're both just games being streamed on some internet service.
Scott: It's like baseball, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, baseball also in the, in the pitcher, you know, sometimes you hit the batter by accident because it happens.
Scott: But if you do it on purpose, it's like why you just do a baseball at someone at like a hundred miles an hour, you could have killed them.
Scott: You should be banned from baseball permanently.
Scott: That's worse than what Pete Rose did.
Rym: So yeah, that's really all we can say about that.
Rym: Go listen to a hockey podcast if you want to learn like the excruciating details.
Scott: Don't listen to a toxically masculine hockey podcast.
Rym: Yeah, don't, don't listen to, stay away from Barstool reporting on this.
Rym: Follow like Shayna or something to see what happened.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: All right.
Rym: So some other news.
Rym: Oh yeah, this Ravenloft thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So Ravenloft, you know, people who know the old D&Ds have some sort of memories of Ravenloft, which is the vampire slash horror campaign setting for the D&Ds.
Scott: You know, with your, what's the vampire's name?
Scott: Count Strahd.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Strahd.
Scott: Chris of Strahd.
Rym: Generally it's a world where like in old D&D, the way it would work is you'd have a campaign in some other world and then you'd be like a fog comes in and you transport your PCs to some other campaign setting and have them do one long adventure there.
Scott: Or you could do a Planescape.
Scott: You could do a Planescape.
Rym: Ah, actually Ravenloft was canonically, I don't know if this has changed, not accessible from Planescape.
Rym: It's its own thing.
Scott: What the fuck do I know about D&Ds?
Rym: Ravenloft is its own hidden shadow dimension potentially created by some bullshit with Vekta, but don't quote me on if that's still canon or not.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: But anyway, the point is like many D&D campaign settings, such as Al-Kadim, right?
Rym: Oh God, Al-Kadim.
Scott: It had a lot of, it had a lot of, Dark Sun, right?
Scott: Had a lot of problems in the racism and sexism and other departments of not good, right?
Scott: So trying to play a Ravenloft game by the book in 2020 isn't great.
Rym: Yeah, Ravenloft had issues that were obvious in the 80s.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, you know, I guess props to WotC.
Scott: You're still far from perfect.
Scott: You got a lot of issues, but there's a new Ravenloft book and it seeks to correct and get rid of many of those very bad things in the Ravenloft campaign setting.
Scott: And obviously I have not read this book.
Scott: It just came out or it's coming soon.
Scott: You should be able to get it.
Scott: And I believe that they may have succeeded based solely on the fact that when I look at the credits on this book of who wrote it, who is involved in it, it is top tier peoples who I know of, or know, at least one of which I've played games with and trust to make this not shit.
Scott: So if you want to play, if you're still playing D&D for some reason and you want to do some Ravenloft or you just enjoy reading D&D books, which is perfectly cool.
Rym: I spend more time reading D&D books than playing D&D until I hit late middle school.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I think I can recommend to you this book, despite never having read anything other than this section of who was involved in the creation of this book.
Scott: And if you are doing any Ravenloft action, I would recommend going by this book and throwing out all the old books for a better Ravenloft time.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And I scrolled through like all the all the details of what they changed.
Rym: And it looks like it's really mostly some of it is just positive in that it removes harmful.
Rym: stereotypes like the Vistani as a "race" were deeply problematic.
Rym: But also they've made some aspects that were drawing like naively and vaguely and incorrectly from like ancient Egyptian culture and made them more just fantasy sci fi interesting and less tied to real peoples and histories and cultures.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, that's good.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Not only are you getting away from, you know, racism, but it's like you actually just made it more interesting and better.
Scott: It's like so regardless of whether you're you know, even if you're a racist white dude, for some reason listening to this show, I don't know why.
Rym: We've had a few over the years we've excised.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you are, fuck you.
Scott: But you I guess you'll also benefit from this improved Ravenloft.
Rym: Yeah, you can play your Ravenloft now.
Scott: It'll be a better game than the other one, whether you care about, you know, that other shit or not.
Rym: So briefly, we didn't talk about this because happened a little while ago, but in April wasn't that long ago.
Rym: But Twitch did a thing and we haven't really seen the full ramifications of it yet.
Rym: They basically identified seven point five million accounts that they believe were breaking the terms of service by follow botting and view botting.
Rym: And they took action against all of those accounts.
Rym: And they even warned everyone in advance that they might see their subscriber counts drop because these bots were likely part of botnets designed to fake viewership numbers.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So if you don't know, view bot follow bot is basically make a fake Twitch account.
Scott: And normally if you make a fake Twitter account, you're doing it to like tweet right to tweet spam and stuff like that.
Scott: If you make a fake Twitch account, you might not be trying to run a fake Twitch channel or go into chat and spam.
Scott: You might just be following someone else on Twitch to increase their numbers because Twitch rewards people for having bigger follower numbers, bigger subscriber numbers.
Rym: There's an incentive to have more followers.
Scott: And it's like if I made if I made if I made a thousand fake Twitter egg accounts and all they did was follow me just to make it so that I have a thousand more followers than I do right now.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I just want to make the number go up and people know this gets really complex.
Scott: is the whole world that I want to get into.
Scott: But not only will people make view bots to get their own numbers up to help themselves out, you know, Twitch career wise, but also they'll do it to attack other people.
Scott: It's like, hey, that guy's, you know, thinking they're more popular than they are or they're getting in trouble because they've got, you know, bots following them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it looks like they're trying to be, you know, to get their own numbers up when actually.
Scott: It's me doing it to them.
Scott: It's really complex scenarios what people do with all these bots.
Rym: I saw one thing here.
Rym: There's one famous-ish account.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm not going to name it because I don't know if it's a good account or not.
Rym: A lot of Twitch accounts are bad news.
Rym: But there's a bunch of screenshots in this thread showing how this one account that is genuinely popular lost almost three million subscribers when they did this purge.
Rym: Instantly three million subscribers disappeared from an account that that wasn't three million.
Rym: They lost one point five million of their three million subscribers.
Scott: OK, so half their audience.
Rym: So half their audience.
Rym: This account is legitimately big, but it was also literally twice as big as it deserved to be based solely on these fake accounts.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now, this is a good thing, but I don't know if this is a battle that can be won because much like with denial of service attacks, there is no real like objective way to tell the difference between a fake person watching your thing and a real person.
Rym: There's naive heuristics, but bots can be more clever.
Rym: And the real problem is that Twitch really drives all of its monetization based on this number.
Rym: that is easily gamed.
Scott: I'm basically constantly.
Scott: this is a problem I'm always thinking about, but there's no answers, obviously, of how can you make an application?
Scott: It doesn't have to be a Web application, any application whatsoever, some software.
Scott: that where people make accounts.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you can verify that it's one account per real human being.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And it's easy to do that.
Scott: That's so far.
Scott: You can.
Scott: This is very easy to do, but is not arduous for people to make an account.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Is not like prohibitive, is not discriminatory, is like and now suddenly becomes impossible to do this.
Rym: But coupled with putting the Twitch has a vested interest in showing very high numbers of users.
Rym: Twitch has a vested interest in showing very large numbers of subscribers for popular accounts that they monetize.
Rym: And Twitch has gated access to all of its monetization features on people juicing those numbers on their own, thus creating kind of like how a lot of banks got in trouble.
Rym: Because while the bank didn't tell their junior bankers to do crime, they did tell the junior bankers to achieve literally impossible targets.
Rym: And those junior bankers, fearing being fired, did dubious and likely and oftentimes literally illegal things to juice those numbers.
Rym: At no point did anyone say do illegal things, but they incentivized it.
Rym: Twitch, by the nature of how Twitch works, incentivizes viewbotting.
Rym: Doesn't mean they want viewbotting, but the system incentivizes it.
Rym: You always have to separate.
Scott: But the fact that they fought it off, at least they did a big purge is good.
Rym: Twitch making a big purge is a big deal because a lot of services refuse to make these big purges because it'll hurt their numbers.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: So I support Twitch in this.
Rym: I hope they continue it.
Rym: Mm hmm.
Rym: In some other little news, we're not going to talk about Epic Games versus Tim Apple, because that...
Scott: Yeah, we talked about it when it started.
Scott: And it's now.
Scott: all you have to know is that it's now rolling.
Scott: And as a result of its rolling in court, there is, you know, because court stuff is public.
Scott: Everyone can see what's happening in our, you know, courts.
Scott: That's our government, right?
Scott: We're supposed to know what's happening there.
Scott: Lots and lots of previously secret information is being introduced to the record as evidence and is becoming public.
Scott: So even though you might not be able to report on the result of this case for a while until it finishes, every time there's like evidence released, it's like stuff we didn't know before.
Scott: And it's like these other unrelated news stories about Epic and or Apple come out.
Scott: And one of them was of particular interesting notes.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So what's going on here is some people have numbers now on things like what was Epic's revenue.
Rym: And it was like five point seven billion dollars in twenty eighteen.
Rym: It's down to like five point one billion dollars in twenty twenty.
Scott: But I still keep in mind that's revenue though, not profits.
Scott: That's revenue.
Rym: Ninety seven percent of that was Fortnite in twenty eighteen.
Scott: That's obvious.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Eighty eight percent of it was still Fortnite the following year.
Scott: OK, so they managed to actually a good sign because it means they are diversifying their income sources away from Fortnite.
Scott: So they're not just a one trick pony.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So at least in twenty nineteen and twenty, not enough.
Scott: Eighty eight percent still way too high, but they're getting they're making progress.
Rym: In twenty nineteen to twenty twenty, despite that revenue, they were not profitable, losing one hundred eighty one million and two hundred seventy three million in twenty nineteen and twenty twenty.
Rym: just on EGS specifically, which gets to the final interesting point.
Rym: The Epic Game Store that we have poo pooed.
Rym: A lot of people have poo pooed where they try to trick you in with free games.
Rym: We have the numbers only seven percent of all the people who have installed the Epic Game Store at any point have bought even one game.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I mean, the vast majority of it's something we already knew, but now here's absolute proof.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And with legal documents that submitted to court as evidence, you know, under oath.
Scott: You can't otherwise be fake.
Scott: evidence tampering is that, yeah, people who installed it were either a playing Fortnite, in which case they're probably just playing Fortnite.
Scott: And as with all free to play games, most people playing Fortnite are paying no money.
Scott: And it's probably supported by whales, although there are probably a large number of whales because the user base is large.
Scott: And then there are people who installed it to get a free game because they gave away so many free games.
Scott: But people installed to get a free game.
Scott: So only seven percent of those people went on to buy some other game.
Scott: They were just installing the Epic Store to get the free games and never buying anything.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And the epic, you know, people basically admitted.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's documented.
Scott: They basically admitted that the whole thing is just a price predatory pricing operation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Where they're like, you know, it's they're on purpose losing money in order to try to get people away from steam and away from other stores over to their store.
Scott: It's completely intentional.
Scott: And the problem is, is that the actual predatory pricing, you know, is technically illegal under certain circumstances.
Scott: But the law on that in the U.S.
Scott: is really, really weak, which is why everyone keeps everyone keeps getting away with it.
Scott: Uber, Amazon, everyone's doing it.
Rym: It's also complicated because ostensibly steam had for a long time a near monopoly on online game distribution.
Rym: GOG and other things have filled in like there's a better ecosystem, but steam still is like the Uber place to buy.
Scott: But they're not suing steam.
Scott: They're suing Apple for the Apple Store.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And at the same time, if they try to like use this pricing to get people to move to their store, their store kind of sucks.
Rym: Like from the consumer, having multiple stores is just worse because it doesn't bring prices down.
Rym: It doesn't.
Rym: it actually gives you a worse experience.
Rym: You have to triage between all these differences.
Rym: Where do I buy this game versus that game?
Rym: So from a consumer standpoint, like I buy every game either on the Nintendo store because it's a Switch exclusive or I buy it on steam because I do trust that I will be able to play my steam games in 10 years.
Rym: I don't think the Epic Game Store is going to exist in 10 years.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: But yeah, there's definitely that does speak to a larger issue of something that's happening.
Scott: You know, I guess it's been happening for a very long time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But real stores, physical brick and mortar stores do this, too, where they try to make it.
Scott: So, you know, use various tactics to make it more convenient for you to keep shopping at the same store, even if there's some other store that has what you want, maybe even at a lower price.
Scott: You know, it's like, you know, things like loyalty cards store, you know, brand credit cards, you know, all customer loyalty programs.
Scott: I guess that's the same thing.
Rym: Oh, those things do something even more insidious that I didn't know about or at least didn't think about.
Rym: But it's obvious in retrospect because I got a bunch of training.
Rym: I've learned a lot of.
Rym: I've had about a formal training on the current science of pricing lately.
Rym: And one of the one of the things those loyalty cards, while what you said is true, that is definitely a reason they're used.
Scott: The primary reason they're used is track all your purchases.
Rym: No, no, no.
Rym: It's so much more sinister that there's different terms for it in different industries.
Rym: But effectively, it's proof that that person, the person who deals with the bullshit of the loyalty program is very price sensitive.
Rym: They're willing to give up time to get benefits or slightly lower prices.
Rym: People who ignore the loyalty programs are willing to pay whatever price you publish because they value their time more than their money.
Rym: There's some data to back this up.
Rym: So generally, loyalty programs are how you identify the people who might need to be given discounts or incentives to keep them in your ecosystem and to keep them paying you.
Rym: And you can tell how price sensitive they are by how many arbitrary and meaningless hurdles you can put them through and they'll still do it.
Rym: Meanwhile, people who ignore the loyalty programs, you can just raise your prices on them.
Rym: They'll probably pay it.
Rym: They value your service and they specifically avoid time wasting nonsense.
Scott: That's a good point.
Scott: But yeah, so real stores try to make themselves sticky for customers, right?
Scott: But digital stores selling software or music or whatever have it even better and that it doesn't really hurt you too much to go from one grocery store to another.
Scott: It's a plenty of location, right?
Scott: But if you have Steam, to install another store on your computer, it's just like, ugh, how many stores am I going to fucking install, right?
Rym: I already got a Blizzard specific app just for Overwatch.
Scott: And you got the Microsoft store comes with Windows.
Scott: It's like you don't want more stores on your computer.
Scott: Ideally, there would be some sort of store that comes with the operating system, but that store should be forced open, right?
Rym: I was about to say, it can't be the Tim Apple store.
Scott: Right, exactly.
Scott: The Tim Apple store is sort of that good solution.
Scott: We're like, yeah, there's just one store.
Scott: No bullshit of having 10 stores and hurting the customer.
Scott: Apple wants to protect the customer, but yeah, now they're using that one store to sort of hold the other end, all the app makers over a barrel, right?
Scott: It's a very one-sided deal, the same way Amazon treats the customer very well to hold people selling products over a barrel, right?
Scott: So, yeah.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I don't know where this is all going to go.
Rym: We're not going to talk about it a lot.
Rym: You can make a whole podcast just around this fight.
Scott: It'll be a huge news when there's some sort of decision made.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Never mind.
Rym: And that decision is totally orthogonal to this whole conversation about whether or not Epic Games business model even makes sense or is ethical, independent of their fight with Apple.
Scott: This is going to be a nonstop fountain of news until it's over, and it's going to be a huge news when it's done, whatever is decided.
Rym: This is as big for gaming as that whole Java situation was.
Scott: It has ramifications, I think, for everyone, whether they realize it or not, but obviously, technological and tech people and gaming people are paying the most attention.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: So, I have a rule.
Rym: We both have a soft rule.
Rym: We try not to just use the same account, or we'd both be like, "Oh, I got another lock-picking lawyer for you.
Rym: That's the best thing I saw
Rym: today.".
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you find a YouTube channel that's got good videos, like the one I had the other week with the animations made with wool, right?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You can't just be like, "Well, this YouTube channel is amazing.
Scott: All its videos are terrific.
Scott: It has 10 videos.
Scott: That's 10 things of the
Scott: day.".
Scott: It's like, "No, it's not.
Scott: It's one thing of the
Scott: day.".
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So, I've used Worth It Kids before because they made some great animations, and then they made that clown thing that was above and beyond.
Rym: They have somehow exceeded expectations yet again.
Rym: They uploaded a video on April 30th called "Captain
Rym: Yajima.".
Rym: It looks like stop-motion.
Rym: It looks like it was made in Blender.
Rym: This is CG, like computer animation, but it looks like old-style stop-motion.
Rym: It is eight minutes long.
Rym: It is a full episode of a fake anime-looking television show.
Rym: It looks like a '60s anime.
Rym: Very well done.
Rym: If you didn't know anything about what they were parodying and you just watched this, it's legitimately good, honestly funny, has real characters.
Rym: This is amazing.
Rym: If they turned this into an actual show, I would watch it.
Rym: Watch all eight minutes of episode one.
Rym: I doubt they're going to make more.
Rym: I'm pretty sure this is a standalone one-time thing, but the character names alone will make it clear that this is amazing.
Rym: Just watch it.
Rym: I'm not even going to say anything else.
Scott: In 2004, when we were close to leaving college, the furthest thing from our non-TV-watching minds was the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame induction.
Scott: I can't think of a more boomer organization than the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame.
Scott: I guess we could rant about Hall of Fames in general, but that's off-topic.
Scott: Anyway, at the 2004 Rock and Roll Hall of Fame induction, a legendary performance occurred, and I didn't know about it until recently.
Rym: I didn't know about it until you sent me this link.
Scott: Right, but obviously other people, I'm sure, who were more in tune with that music world would have known about this for the past 14 years.
Scott: I only found about it just this week, right?
Scott: But, you know, what happened was is that the producer of the 2004 Rock and Roll Hall of Fame induction ceremony, like, program, right?
Scott: This guy, I think Joel Gallin, some, like, movie director of some kind.
Scott: I don't know anything about him.
Scott: I just got his name from the internet.
Scott: He took that legendary performance and he put it up on YouTube after remastering it.
Scott: The new director is cut, and that's why this is in the news again.
Scott: So you need the backstory to understand how amazing this is.
Scott: So what happened is that year various people were being inducted, right?
Scott: And one of the inductees was George Harrison, who was at the time deceased, you know, from the Beatles, right?
Scott: And also Prince, who is now deceased, but at the time was not, and some others.
Scott: And one of the performances, the one in this video, is they're going to perform the Beatles song "While My Guitar Gently Weaves" by George Harrison, right?
Scott: A famous song.
Scott: You know the song.
Scott: If you don't know the song by the name, as soon as you hear it, you're going to know it.
Scott: If you still don't know it, what the fuck?
Rym: If you saw Kubo, they use a cover of it in the closing credits.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: And on stage, they have such people as Tom Petty, right?
Scott: They got Jeff Lin, the ELO guy, right?
Scott: You got Steve Winwood from Traffic.
Scott: You got Danny Harrison, George Harrison's, you know, kid, right?
Scott: And Prince.
Scott: And you got this other guy, who I forget his name, and he's off to the side.
Scott: And basically the original idea that they had for this performance was that, you know, Prince, legendary guitar player, would play those little guitar solo bits.
Scott: You know, that are like, you know, throughout the song.
Scott: And then there's the big solo towards the end of the song, right?
Scott: So that like Prince would do that part.
Scott: And they went to rehearse.
Scott: And when it came time to do that part, and Prince is going to play it.
Scott: This other guy, I forget his name.
Scott: He goes and plays it and he plays it.
Scott: And it sounds exactly like the original.
Scott: This is some, I forget the dude's name again, but he was some guy that would play with like, you know, George Harrison and his wife back in the post Beatles days, right?
Scott: He was like close to them.
Scott: That's why he was there, right?
Scott: And that's why he was able to play that so perfectly because he's been playing it for who knows how long.
Scott: So then basically, you know, Prince at the rehearsal, they're like, ah shit, Prince isn't going to come back, is he?
Scott: It's like, we told him he would do this thing.
Scott: He didn't do the thing.
Scott: And Prince basically is like, yeah, don't worry.
Scott: I got it covered, right?
Scott: He's like, let that guy play the first few and I'll just, I'll come in at the end, right?
Scott: So in this performance, you can watch what happened.
Scott: No one really knew what was going to happen, I guess, except maybe Prince.
Rym: I feel like that has happened at multiple points in Prince's career.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So they come, you know, this huge, this, it's one of those stages like full of way too many musicians that don't need to be there, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, you got basically almost, I guess, all or most of the heartbreakers, right?
Scott: Because Tom Petty's there, you know, they're all amazing musicians, even the, even the weird guy.
Rym: It's the kind of stage set that is designed to attract like the boomer audience for a rock and roll whole thing.
Scott: It's a special, you know, it's a special ceremony.
Scott: So let's put together like this huge, amazing, you know, crazy group of people, right?
Scott: So you see Prince, you know, Prince is coming, but you don't see him.
Scott: He's not there.
Scott: They're playing the song.
Scott: They're playing it very serviceably, right?
Scott: And, you know, Prince isn't there.
Scott: You don't see him on stage and then he's there and then he is there until the ending part.
Scott: And you, if you want more details about what exactly went down, you can read the same shit on the internet that I read to get even more details.
Scott: But this is very much well worth your six and a half minutes.
Scott: Don't try to fast forward to when Prince shows up.
Scott: Don't, don't end it before it's over.
Scott: Cause it's legendary up until the literally the last second, um, legendary things are occurring.
Scott: And I guess the best part of this is not necessarily the performance itself, although that is incredible.
Scott: It's that you look at the people up there and most of them are just like, you know, just doing it right.
Scott: What they're like, it's their job, except for Danny Harris and George Harrison's kid who was looking at Prince and is like, do you see this shit?
Scott: And it's like, it's like, you're like, you just feel yourself.
Scott: Like Danny Harrison is like the, the avatar for the audience of like, Holy shit.
Scott: Everyone else is not Holy shitting when they should be, you know?
Scott: And then Prince is, you know, feeling himself.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So in that moment, nothing's new.
Rym: Got our shots, but it's still COVID time.
Scott: So, uh, that's right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No cons coming up.
Scott: The book club book is still the tale of Genji.
Scott: The first novel ever written by human beings in the history of human beings that is known to us.
Rym: I got a little busy the last week.
Rym: Didn't read much more, but it'll be warm enough for me to read on the balcony.
Scott: And the reading speed has accelerated above zero, but is not, uh, at a hundred percent.
Rym: We didn't hit lift off velocity because we had a lot going on.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Uh, I, you know, I think, you know, I will never say that as the book club continues, we will never have, you know, cause you look at history, there's no way I can promise that we will read all the books promptly in the future.
Rym: Right?
Scott: Some books have taken us like a month and some have taken us a year.
Scott: Uh, this book has already definitely taken us longer than any other book ever.
Scott: I can't promise that we won't have a slow book ever again.
Scott: That will take us a very long time, perhaps months.
Rym: But to make it clear, COVID really changed our lives to the point that reading this kind of fiction long form is like low on the priority list.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I'm not, I would like a lot of those book club books I read on my phone on the subway.
Scott: I'm not taking a subway anymore.
Rym: I would read a chapter on the way to work and every day on the way home from work.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, I'm home.
Scott: Why am I real?
Scott: But anyway, I can promise that when we eventually finish this, when, as long as we survive, I got the next book picked out.
Rym: Uh, we'll read it pretty quick.
Scott: I think that no future book will take as long as this one.
Scott: It might be one day less.
Rym: Oh, Nostradamus here making a bold prediction.
Scott: No book club book in the future will take as much time as this one.
Scott: They will all take at least a day less.
Rym: Now I want to read my next book, The Count of Monte Cristo, and just see, I'll read it.
Scott: I'll be able to read that faster than I'll be able to read.
Rym: Unless there's another pandemic or something.
Scott: Barring some ridiculous circumstance like that, yes.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So let's get right into it.
Rym: Uh, we've never actually talked about Super Mario 3 on GeekNights before.
Scott: Well, at least not by itself.
Rym: We've talked about Mario World and other Mario games, but also I recently just beat it for a lark like over the last week.
Rym: Like I just idly played it until I beat every single level and every single normal secret.
Rym: I didn't get like every coin ship or anything because frankly I was never that good at Mario 3.
Scott: I believe you're not.
Rym: The first coin ship is pretty easy to get, but I struggled even as a kid when I cared a lot about getting all the coin ships.
Scott: I only know how to get the first and second one.
Scott: I can get the first one more reliably than the second one.
Scott: The second one I can get maybe like 25% of the time.
Rym: I got the first one when I did this replay.
Rym: I used a couple of save states because I'd miss one coin.
Rym: I'd be like, nah, fuck it.
Rym: I'm not going to die and do that again.
Scott: But yeah, so I would just want to set the context for anyone younger than us who doesn't really understand, right?
Scott: So if you're in the US at the time, you don't have a lot of information about what's happening.
Scott: You have magazines if you even have those, right?
Scott: So you got Mario and you know, Super Nintendo's don't exist yet.
Scott: There's no Super Nintendo's.
Scott: They might be in Japan, but they're not in the US, right?
Scott: And then you've got Mario one and Mario two comes out and it's different.
Rym: And you hear rumors that there's a different Mario two, but you don't know about making it up.
Scott: You don't believe that you do not know about the doki-doki panic thing.
Scott: You have no information whatsoever.
Scott: As far as you're concerned, Mario two is Mario two.
Scott: And all you want is more Mario like Mario one, right?
Scott: It's like that was, you know, even though it's only been a few years of your life, you know, Mario two, it's still, it feels like a different thing.
Scott: You have nostalgia for hitting the question block, even though that was only a year ago or two years ago.
Scott: You don't have the shy guys and, you know, versus the goombas.
Scott: Like you don't have the feeling for the shy guys you had for the goombas, right?
Scott: It's like Nintendo to make more Mario would be a thing.
Scott: And then this movie, the wizard comes out, right?
Scott: And you see at the end of the movie, there's Mario three in the movie, which was actually the reveal of Mario three in the U S right.
Scott: And you're like, Holy shit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I, that is a big fuck.
Scott: I want that so bad.
Scott: And then it's like, when you realize it's real and it's like, there was no like firm release date like there was for things today.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, when is it coming?
Scott: Is it coming?
Scott: When can I get it?
Scott: Where are you?
Scott: Like you didn't really, it's like eventually you're going to go to toys and rest and it'll be there, but you don't know when it could be next year.
Scott: You don't fuck.
Scott: You don't know.
Rym: All you had to go on was if you were Nintendo power, which was catalog in the newspaper, right?
Scott: Sears catalog, JC paint catalog, something like that.
Scott: You'll see it listed in there.
Scott: Maybe you knew it was coming at this point.
Scott: You just didn't know when it's like another Mario game that not only is it just like Mario one, but the question blocks, you know, the real Mario, right?
Scott: Not the Mario two nonsense, but also Mario can fly is still fire flowers, but he can also fly.
Scott: It's like with the, with the tail.
Scott: It's like, Oh my God.
Scott: It's like, this is the greatest thing you've ever seen.
Rym: It was, I think at the time the best selling game period in the history of the NES, all told it was the third best selling game ever beaten only by now.
Scott: This is why I've got Mario one and duck hunt.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The two games that beat it were duck hunt and super Mario because they were bundled with the early consoles on a single.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: But yeah, Mario three is like, didn't come.
Scott: I think you might've, I think it might've come if you bought a top loader.
Rym: And if you bought the way later NES as it was bundled, they sold might've been some.
Rym: that has been, they sold more than 18 million copies of super Mario three.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That might not sound big today, but it was, this game was enormous.
Rym: Tetris on the NES sold 8 million copies.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Mario three was the thing, right?
Scott: So, uh, and I, if you look at any as games now, you know how many hold up?
Scott: It's like Mario three is a game that can hold up forever.
Scott: Right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And I just played it.
Rym: It holds up.
Rym: I have minor gripes, but those gripes are all just.
Rym: game design has gotten better as a craft gripes.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: But like, so the other thing that happened is when you finally got it, which was hard to get.
Rym: this game when it came out costs either 65 or 79, not late eighties dollars.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I might've told this story on the show before, but I'll tell it again.
Scott: I got it for Hanukkah one year, I guess the year it came out.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And my, my parents gave it to me.
Scott: It was in this box that was not shaped like an NES game and I unwrapped it and it's a Jay-Z penny on it.
Scott: Like there was clothes inside.
Scott: And then I opened that and then inside the tissue paper was the Mario three.
Scott: It was such a big deal that my parents, you know, felt it was necessary to, you know, pull a gag to, to deliver it.
Rym: as another piece of context.
Rym: That's worth knowing is that Zelda two, which was similarly anticipated because we didn't know what it was going to be like.
Rym: interested.
Rym: Oh shit.
Rym: Another Zelda game.
Rym: It came out almost around the exact same time.
Rym: So this was like a particularly important era for just gaming globally.
Scott: This is peak NES Mario three Zelda two.
Rym: And then when you, if you got Mario three, the first time you turned it on, it, the scope of that game dwarfed pretty much anything that had ever been on the NES before.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: If you, you know, it used, was the MMC three, I think whatever what it, right.
Scott: So there was a chip that you could use in an NES cartridge.
Scott: I think Kirby's adventure also definitely used it and maybe some other games on that I can't think of right now, but the games that had that chip in the cartridge, right.
Scott: Were just beyond, you know, what the other games were graphically, you know, sound wise.
Scott: I don't know if they were actually better sound wise, but you know, the music that was in Mario three is a lot better than the music of Mario one.
Rym: And to talk about that, the MMC one chip is what allowed any as games to be not like, I don't know, balloon fight like to get the NES to be better than an Atari 7,800.
Rym: The MMC two chip, like the next evolution was used for one game.
Rym: Mike Tyson's punch out.
Rym: And the MMC three was the next revolution.
Rym: All the, all the later mega man games used it and Kirby's adventure used it.
Rym: And then stuff after that enabled like maybe Castlevania three and like fire emblem games and all sorts of other nonsense.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the point is Mario three was like one of the first, one of the earliest games to use this chip and was there for, like it looks like it came from a different console than the other Nintendo games before it because it was so much more advanced.
Rym: Like you had in Mario once like, all right, I got depending on the nomenclature was kind of weird and shifted, but you had like stages and boards or boards that you had like worlds, like your two worlds.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And levels.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Or boards.
Scott: People use different, he will use different words for it, but the official words I believe are worlds and levels.
Rym: I've seen that world one level times, partly because when Mario three came out, the world concept got a lot bigger.
Scott: Well, Mario world was just one world.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So Mario three has eight worlds.
Rym: So you had a world with a bunch of levels in it, but you could navigate this map and choose how you progressed through that world.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That sort of overworld thing, which Zelda two also kind of had, but not quite the same was really a sort of a newish invention.
Scott: I don't want to say Mario three invented that, but Mario three like polished and cemented it the same way that like, you know, uh, the iPod wasn't, the iPod wasn't the first MP3 player, but like, you know, it might as well have been right.
Scott: Mario three, it wasn't the first for a lot of things, but it might as well have been because it was the first to do a lot of these things well enough and polished enough to sort of set the standard that exists to this day.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Lolo two came out in 1990.
Rym: So this was definitely the like earliest days of that construct, especially for a game that was a platformer when you got into the actual levels.
Rym: And the other thing that was fascinating about it was it had so many secrets relative to other NES games up to that point.
Rym: Uh, like Mario one, like what secrets were there?
Rym: Find a mushroom block, find a one up block, find some coins in a pipe, find the war zones, warp zones.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Mario three, like you'd be playing like you're a kid, you know, you're dumb.
Rym: You don't have the internet or anything.
Rym: you're playing.
Rym: And then all of a sudden you find a tanuki suit.
Rym: What the hell is that?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You get hit and it's gone.
Rym: You have no idea how to find it again.
Rym: And you're obsessed with finding it again.
Scott: There was stuff in the game that was not in the instruction manual.
Scott: If you bought the legendary, you can get a PDF of it online for free.
Scott: I think.
Scott: Oh, we had that book, the strategy guide, which had like cardboard pages.
Scott: The card stock was so thick.
Rym: I had that thing memorized.
Scott: It had full screenshots of every map in the whole, every single level in the whole game, just showing you everything where it was in every single question block.
Scott: It's like it showed you 100% of the game like full on.
Scott: No, nothing was hidden from you.
Scott: If you had the strategy guide, which I had, uh, it was like the only strategy guide I had.
Scott: cause I was right.
Scott: And it's like that revealed to you, it's like, you didn't know there was a hammer suit unless you had that strategy guide or you got it.
Rym: And getting it was unlikely.
Scott: And there was all sorts of stuff levels.
Scott: You could fly up into the sky and it'd be a secret stuff.
Scott: There was duck on a white block long enough and go behind the stage to exit and get the whistle, which we learned from the wizard, right?
Scott: Pipes that go to weird places.
Scott: It's just like, you know, the level in the desert world using the hammer to smash a block at the edge of the map to go off the screen into where there's a hammer bro that you couldn't see normally.
Scott: Just like all this stuff that like, it really felt like a, you know, as a kid playing it, not knowing anything, not having internet, it really felt like this sort of, you know, like just this world of like mystery of like, Oh my God, there's just so much stuff in this game was huge compared to other games.
Rym: It felt like it would go on forever, especially till you got a warp whistle and like you could go to the end, but you'd see how many worlds there were.
Rym: And then when you get to them, the cool thing about the game design is they put so much work into this.
Rym: Every world is radically different in how it plays and how it feels.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And there were so many, every different thing you were, it wasn't like Mario one where it's like, okay, another night world, another flying fish world, another water world, right?
Scott: It was like each place you went was like, like a whole new thing.
Rym: It's like a giant world.
Rym: The goomba is literally as big as full size Mario.
Rym: What the fuck?
Scott: Right.
Scott: There was something, every place you went, it's like every few levels.
Scott: there would be something new and magical to experience.
Scott: Like I'm suddenly, I'm going into a pyramid, I'm climbing a tower and I get to the top of the tower and now I'm in a cloud world.
Scott: at the bottom was a ground world.
Scott: I can get the tanuki shoe, right?
Rym: Currybo shoes going on up there, which the game doesn't even like, no one tells you like, no one understood what that thing was as kids.
Rym: We were all obsessed with trying to get it out of that one world you could get in it with.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I really wanted to take it with me and the game wouldn't let me.
Scott: Right.
Scott: These, you'll get to the last world, these hands come out and grab you.
Scott: You do all this stuff, fighting all these tanks.
Scott: And suddenly it's like on the third screen, it's like world eight one after you've already gone through all this hell.
Scott: It's like, here's eight one.
Scott: It's like, what?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's like, I thought this is going to be, you know, it's like, oh my God, the sun that comes down from the sky.
Scott: It's like, you're just every place you go is something new and exciting.
Scott: Just keep you, everything felt fresh.
Scott: It's not like games today where like the beginning of the game is fresh and then it's scat Gulch and there's a big ending.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like the whole game is fresh.
Scott: Every level, every world, something new to do some new enemies, some new kind of special thing is happening.
Scott: It's just like, you know, every different Koopa kid bosses is slightly different doing something different.
Scott: It's ridiculously challenging.
Rym: It's not hyperbole to say that Mario three for a lot of people, a huge number of people, they sold 18 million copies, but a huge number of kids played these games, this game in particular, and had an awakening about what games could be because it was so far beyond what they were used to.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: When it came out, it was like just be compared to the other games that existed at the time.
Scott: They just all looked like nothing, you know, next to Mario three.
Scott: And for a long time until Mario world, pretty much there was, and honestly, Mario world almost did the same thing all over again.
Scott: Sort of, you know, Mario world, I actually think the gap between Mario three and what came before it was bigger than the gap between.
Scott: I would agree with that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Mario world has got more than Mario three, obviously because he has a super Nintendo came later, but it's like Mario three felt like the real revolution in Mario world felt like a, I don't want to say just an increment, but just like a big increment on Mario three versus the revolution that Mario three was.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So, so I, one of the thing in Mario three that no one talks about, right.
Scott: Uh, is the two player mode.
Rym: I have a lot to say about that two player mode.
Scott: Cause my brother and I don't know in Mario, if you played Mario one, two player, right.
Scott: It would just be like, you know, okay, Mario, then Luigi, Mario, then Luigi, you can game over independently, whatever.
Scott: Uh, or, you know, and other games at the time that were two player would be directly competitive, like a sports game or a fighting game.
Scott: Mario three was one of the first games to have a two player mode.
Scott: that was interestingly, sort of not competitive.
Rym: It was cooperative competitive together.
Scott: Sort of the way it worked is Mario or Luigi.
Scott: It'd be your turn, right?
Scott: So you'd be on the overworld and you choose a level to go to.
Scott: And if you do it, okay, you did that level.
Scott: If you succeed or fail, well, now it's the other guy's turn, right?
Scott: You know, the other Luigi's turn now, but in what you could do is instead of, uh, doing an, a level, you could go to wherever the other guy was standing and you would play against them in original Mario brothers, not super Mario brothers.
Rym: And there were a bunch of different versions of that Mario brothers that you could play.
Scott: And whoever won it would.
Scott: basically now, if you won that battle, you would, it would be your turn to play a Mario three.
Rym: And you stole one of the other players cards that you use to collect sets to get one ups.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Oh, that's right.
Scott: The game also introduced like having an inventory of items that you could activate before entering a level.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: I didn't even think we'd try to catalog all the unique and novel things that Mario Brothers 3 did.
Scott: So many unique novel things.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: Just incredible.
Rym: Um, but so that mode, like here's how, like the immersion, like I don't know what they intended for that mode to be because sometimes my friends would use those cards on purpose to align.
Rym: Like if I had fire flowers and one star, like a fire flower and a star, I try to knock the star out of myself so he could pick it up cause he had two stars like that kind of thing.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Scott: Clever.
Rym: But also say there was a mushroom hut that we both knew could have a tanuki suit in it.
Rym: Uh, I would refuse to play any level that would let him get to that mushroom house.
Rym: He would refuse to play any level that would let me get to that mushroom house.
Rym: I would go into this mode and die on purpose to make it his turn and we'd escalate or I would like threatened to just go fight the boss and give up on that mushroom house.
Scott: unless there were, there would also be situations on the map where I, I don't remember a hundred percent if this is true, but I feel like it's true where if you beat someone in the Mario Brothers game, they would get sent back to the start of the map.
Scott: Is that right?
Rym: They would get sent back to, I think the last level they beats, I forget exactly how the logic works.
Rym: So if you would like, if they had like used a cloud to skip over a level, you could force them back behind the hard level.
Scott: If there was a cloud, rock or pipe situation, I wonder if it was possible to send someone back and therefore like get away from them.
Rym: Yes, you definitely could.
Rym: I once sent, hit my brother, he used a cloud to get past a hard level and I used a cloud to also get past that hard level.
Rym: Then I fought him and sent him back before the hard level.
Scott: I'm going to go see if there's any 2P speed runs of Mario.
Rym: I feel like the 2P speed run, I don't know.
Rym: I'd like to watch one of those on an AGDQ.
Scott: Yeah, any sort of 2P anything.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: But the game overall, like I played the whole thing just recently, like last week, every single level I beat them all.
Rym: I used save states occasionally, but not much.
Rym: And I didn't cheat otherwise.
Rym: I didn't get everything like every coin chip, but the game not only hold up, held up super well, but I'd forgotten about a lot of things until I got to those levels and memories came flooding back hard.
Rym: But I think this game is worth playing even if someone has no nostalgia for it whatsoever, has never played it before, literally like never even touched an NES.
Scott: There's not a lot of platformers as good as this even today.
Rym: But the points where it falters, where game design has progressed is one, it commits the sin of giving you extremely rare items with a random chance of getting those items.
Rym: But those items are also so ephemeral that you all, even a very skilled player is unlikely to get to use them even a little.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So like there's the P wing, which, you know, I think is one of the things that maybe not, not be in the instruction book.
Scott: Maybe it's the most important item.
Rym: It's the most powerful item by far.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The P wing just lets you fly over a whole level, like permanent P for the whole level.
Rym: As a kid we'd save those up to fly over those stupid tanks and airships at the end of the game.
Scott: My strategy for beating Mario 3 as a kid was using warps, not beating every level.
Scott: I couldn't do that as a kid.
Rym: I had a path to minimum number of P wings to get past all those ships.
Rym: And then I'd teleport to the end.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: I would use the whistles in such a way.
Scott: And I figured out where some P wings were before I had the strategy guide even, and such that I would collect enough P wings to skip, or in clouds, to get over all the levels I had a hard time with, like especially the air force level.
Rym: Clouds were risky though.
Rym: Don't die.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: And then I had strategy of which levels to use the P wings.
Scott: And I couldn't just whistle straight to the end of the game.
Scott: I wasn't good enough to beat it because I wouldn't have enough items to do it with.
Scott: I needed those P wings.
Scott: I would like beat level five and then P wing to level eight.
Scott: Because when you beat the sky world, which I could do, you get a P wing.
Scott: And that was the last P wing I needed.
Rym: One of the P wings is in a random hammer brother.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: There's all kinds of stuff going on.
Rym: But it's interesting because when I played it as a kid, on one end I was trying to beat the game.
Rym: And I successfully beat the game pretty early with warps.
Rym: Didn't really have this urge to 100% it.
Rym: My kid brain just didn't quite care.
Rym: But my interest in the rest of the game was mostly to explore it.
Rym: Because it felt like there were secrets hidden everywhere.
Rym: And I wanted to find every weird thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like even if someone told me there was a coin ship and how to get it, it's like I want to see the coin ship.
Rym: I didn't necessarily trust them.
Scott: I want to experience the coin ship.
Rym: And the game did shit.
Rym: like you get to world five and there's a normal looking world and you play it.
Rym: But then at the end of the world there's a weird tower.
Rym: And you actually go up the tower inside the tower.
Scott: I already talked about the tower.
Rym: But then when you're in the cloud world, you can actually fuck up and fall back down to the regular world.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: You could do that.
Rym: And if you would use clouds again to like skip some stuff, well guess what?
Rym: Now you're all the way back down there and you're going to beat all those hard worlds.
Rym: you skipped again.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It wasn't a game that was trying to be easy, right?
Scott: It was exactly the right amount of challenge I think to where.
Scott: it's certainly beatable.
Scott: But it's not easily beatable.
Scott: You know, at least by someone who's not amazingly good.
Scott: But it's not like you're never going to beat it.
Rym: I beat it within a month or two of getting it using warp whistles.
Rym: Like that was pretty straightforward to do.
Scott: If you keep trying and you maybe figure out where some secrets are, you're gonna beat it.
Rym: The only thing I would suggest is honestly...
Scott: You get plenty of lives, you know.
Rym: Well the game, like if you even play like reasonably well, you'll have like 30 or 40 lives by the time you hit like world 4 if you're trying to beat everything.
Scott: Now to keep in mind, as a kid to beat it meant beating it in one save.
Scott: Yeah, you couldn't save your game.
Scott: You could not save this game.
Scott: So that's why it was very hard to beat as a kid.
Scott: But today, even if you don't use cheating save states, you can still just save your game from the world map and you'll beat it eventually.
Rym: And especially if you use warp whistles, it's like you'll beat it pretty quick.
Rym: You don't have to 100% it.
Rym: But it is eminently worth exploring every world in this game semi-thoroughly.
Rym: Like you'll just see some things that you didn't know, didn't expect.
Rym: You'll find them interesting, secrets in weird places, novel concepts that even sometimes didn't really get used again in later Mario games.
Scott: World 1 is normal Mushroom Kingdom world, right?
Scott: And then World 2 is a desert world.
Scott: And then World 3 is the water world.
Scott: Everything's really different.
Scott: World 4 is the giant world, which is even more ridiculous.
Rym: As kids, we were obsessed with giant world.
Scott: Yeah, 5 is the sky world.
Scott: 6 is the ice world, where you can actually melt ice with your fire flowers.
Scott: It's like really out there.
Scott: 7 is the pipe world, which is a crazy maze going down.
Scott: And then 8 is the lava hell world at the end of the game.
Scott: And then Koopa's Castle is really out there, way at the end of that.
Scott: Koopa's statue shooting lasers at you.
Scott: All sorts of out there stuff that makes it really feel special.
Scott: You're always encountering something new you've never seen before in the game.
Scott: And it brings the Bob-ombs from Mario 2.
Rym: So, I would recommend, unless you're gonna get mega into it, save states are fine.
Rym: Especially, use save states to get the good items from mushroom houses, because that's just RNG, there's nothing you can do.
Scott: Even strategy guide is fine, because some of the secrets are kind of not.
Scott: You don't need to get a coin ship.
Scott: To learn how to get a coin ship is like you will never just discover.
Rym: Yeah, you would literally never figure out how to get a coin ship on purpose.
Scott: Before I knew how to get it, I got it once or twice as a kid by accident.
Scott: It suddenly appears, and you're like, "What is
Scott: that?".
Scott: You have no idea how you got it.
Scott: And White Mushroom House, you will never figure out how to get White Mushroom House on your own.
Rym: The first time I got a White Mushroom House by accident, my brother and I were looking at it.
Rym: We called our friends, they literally didn't believe us.
Rym: They didn't believe there was a White Mushroom House.
Scott: Why would you?
Scott: I wouldn't believe it.
Rym: If someone called me and was like, "Yeah, it's a White Mushroom
Rym: House!"
Rym: I would have just assumed they were lying.
Rym: The same people who lied and said that in Mario 1, you can warp to the Secret World 9.
Rym: All those made up kid rumors.
Scott: Yup, it's like, no, there really is a White Mushroom House that you can get to appear and get stuff out of it.
Scott: It's really good.
Scott: Good luck finding it.
Rym: But the controls feel tight.
Rym: The platforming works.
Scott: I like the controls in Mario 3 better than the controls in Mario World, and better than the controls in Mario Maker, even though those are both great.
Scott: Mario 3 for me is the best controls of any Mario, like any platformer even, maybe.
Scott: Period.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: There is one thing I don't- They should have just kept them that way.
Rym: I think what I don't like so much is using a tail to knock out a block that is one high as opposed to zero high requires oddly fiddly timing.
Rym: that could have been made easier because that is one of the most common blocks you want to break.
Scott: Yeah, you press A and B at sort of the same time.
Rym: Yeah, that could have been made easier considering how often you want to do it.
Rym: But other than that, we've already illustrated all our complaints.
Rym: There aren't that many more.
Rym: This game is one of the greatest games ever made.
Scott: Yeah, Mario 3.
Rym: So if you've never played it, go play it.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know why I haven't played Mario 3.
Rym: There was that live streamer who was a young kid who had never played any NES games, and his shtick was he was playing every NES game in alphabetical order with not reading anything.
Rym: He would start the game cold, and he would play until he got a game over and then never play that game again.
Rym: And he would end the stream immediately.
Rym: That was his whole shtick.
Rym: And he got to Mario 3, and that was the kid from which I have that famous line.
Rym: I like to quote a lot of the observer just saying, "Please pick World 4.
Rym: Please pick World 4.
Rym: Please pick World
Rym: 4.".
Rym: And he does indeed pick World 4.
Rym: He game overs in World 1 in Mario 3.
Rym: 'Cause he didn't know how Mario games work.
Rym: Like, how would he?
Rym: Never played NES games.
Scott: He's young.
Scott: He only Mario 1 before Mario 3.
Rym: Yeah, he game over pretty quick in Mario 1, too.
Rym: And Mario 1 is so great.
Scott: He actually engaged with Mario-- All the way up until M or S if he considers it to be an S for Super.
Scott: He didn't play any platformers and get good at them?
Rym: Nah, didn't look like it.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Also, Mario 3 introduces a lot of interesting things.
Rym: that if you'd only ever played Mario 1, and you didn't have, like, the ga-- I don't know, the desperate gamer trying to understand this game impetus, I see why he failed at the things he failed at.
Rym: Like, Mario 3 introduced the auto-scroller to Mario.
Rym: That wasn't a thing before.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: And auto-scrollers, even when I was a kid, were terrifying.
Rym: When I first went into World 1-4, I died almost instantly.
Scott: 1-4 is a very hard level, which is why-- 1-4 is a rite of passage.
Scott: Notice how well the game is designed, though.
Scott: World 1-4 is entirely skippable.
Scott: You do not have to do it.
Scott: But if you do do it and do it so well, that's the way to get the first white coin ship, right?
Rym: But you can skip it and beat World--.
Rym: you can beat a different World in World 5 and also get that Mushroom House.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: You can beat World 1-3 to get to the Mushroom House.
Rym: You can also skip that whole wing and go straight for the castle.
Scott: Yep, you can skip the whole thing.
Scott: You don't want to get the Mushroom House.
Scott: Such a good game design there, right at the beginning like that.
Scott: One last thing, just to emphasize how significant this was.
Scott: When Mario 3 came out, the Mario Bros.
Scott: Super Show was airing and being watched, right?
Scott: So this is like the height of Mario as a kid's thing in the '80s, '90s time, right?
Scott: And the Mario Bros.
Scott: Super Show, the cartoon that they showed during it, had to transition from being based on Mario 2 stuff and characters to being based on Mario 3 stuff.
Scott: Mid-cartoon.
Scott: Like, suddenly there were leafs in it and Mario was getting there at Coontail.
Scott: Yup, which wasn't in the cartoon prior to that.
Rym: Oh my god, that reminds me.
Rym: It's a total aside.
Rym: We can end because I'm getting hungry.
Rym: But you saw that thing where we found some answers as to why the Zelda cartoon was the way it was?
Scott: No, I didn't see that thing.
Rym: Official reports of specific decisions that were made and why about that show have made it to Twitter, like in the last couple days.
Scott: I don't know if they're believable, but they'll probably be fun.
Rym: They're pretty vetted.
Rym: And the one thing that was notable, because I wonder how much that was true for Mario 3, most of the people involved in the show did not have NESs.
Scott: Makes sense.
Rym: In fact, one of them said they rented a console so they could at least play the game to know something about it.
Rym: Most of the cartoon was designed based on the Zelda 1 instruction booklet and the instruction booklet alone.
Scott: Makes sense.
Rym: Which actually explains a lot if you look at that instruction booklet.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: So I would love to know how many of those people in the Mario Super Show played Mario 3 versus read the instruction booklet to Mario 3.
Scott: I would also just like to point out one thing.
Scott: If you want to watch Mario 3, the person is Mitch Flowerpower.
Scott: Mitch Flowerpower, the famous Mitch Flowerpower speedrunner, is basically, I guess, considered among if not the best Mario 3 player there is.
Rym: And his dreams are a delight to watch.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So if you want to go to YouTube or Twitch, find Mitch Flowerpower, and you will see the pinnacle of Mario 3 skill play that there is.
Scott: There's also Mario 3 Randomizer and all kinds of stuff coming down in the Mario 3 communities.
Rym: But don't worry about that.
Rym: Just futz around and explore the surprising depth of this relatively early Nintendo game.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Early.
Scott: It was towards the end of the NES.
Rym: I said Nintendo, not NES.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: Nintendo the company.
Rym: Like this was a transformative step for Nintendo, the company, and game design, but this was basically the height of the NES.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon Patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi McNichol, Alan Joyce, Link Eiji, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, Chris Reimer, Clinton Walton, Crane, Patek, Old Man, Saved Desp, Peacock, MindSnack, just like a dude guy,
Scott: Kashyaya85,
Rym: Rebecca Dahn, Ren from New Zealand Review, MadBull34, Cowards, Ryan Perrin, Sam Erickson, Servin Von Horrell, Taylor Braun, you hold the key to my heart, and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: I'm feeling pretty good, despite being a little down from that shot.
Rym: I look forward to hearing from all of you, slowly getting your vaccines.
Rym: Hopefully we'll all meet in the real world in a pack someday in the future, but for now, before I go off and have some food and maybe go to bed a little early, though you might see me playing a little bit of Overwatch, I want to see if I can get out of Bronze and DPS before the end of the season, I leave you with...
Scott: Hello?
Rym: I'd like to order a butt.
Scott: Like, is this thing on?
Scott: Woah, that sounds cool.
Scott: Hey Beavis, is that you?
Scott: I'm in the drive-thru, dumbass.
Rym: Get out here, this thing makes you sound really weird.
Rym: Really?
Scott: Cool.
Rym: I'll be right with you, thank you drive-thru.
Rym: Ow!
Rym: This is gonna be cool.
Rym: I'm sorry, what was that again?