Rym: It's Monday, October 4th, 2021, I'm Rym.
Scott:  And I'm Scott.
Rym:  And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we're talking about social media and that big Facebook outage.
Scott:  Let's do this.
Rym:  So did something, there's a, there's one kind of milestone in life and that's a milestone of doing something you've never done before.
Rym: But there's another milestone that a lot of people don't think about until they get older and it's doing something you've done before, but doing it for the first time as an adult where you are the sole person responsible for the entire thing, like having a pet as an example.
Rym: We had dogs as kids.
Rym: I didn't do 100% of the dog work as a kid.
Rym: Like there were vet things that happened and nail clipping and stuff that my parents would just do.
Rym: And sometimes I was involved, but there was someone else to take up that slack.
Rym: But like having a pet for the first time here, we had to do literally everything.
Rym: If there was something we didn't know to do, we're just effed.
Rym: Like that's an adult thing.
Scott: So this past week-- - I mean if you're a kid and you wanna go and like, you know, say to an amusement park, all you do is say I wanna go to the amusement park and then somehow you're there.
Scott:  Yup, and meanwhile, you're like oh yeah, I've heard it done.
Scott:  You gotta deal with the transportation and the tickets and the food and make sure nobody dies.
Rym:  Yup, like there's a difference between I wanna go to PAX and see Markiplier and how the fuck do I get four badges to this convention in Seattle?
Rym: How do we, when do we even fly there?
Scott:  Yup.
Rym: So this past weekend, Emily and I, she had never done this thing before and I have never done it as an adult and that thing is,
Scott: for real-- - The one thing you have done before is the GeekNights thing where you don't say the noun of whatever the thing is until the last possible second.
Rym:  Is that a thing that a podcast like this might have done in the past?
Scott:  Well, you know, maybe so.
Scott:  So we were camping.
Scott:  I don't think this is your first time as an adult withholding the noun to the last second.
Rym:  It is, in fact, not my first rodeo.
Rym: Actually, I have never been to a rodeo.
Rym: Anyway, so if I ever go to one, it would be my first, fuck rodeos.
Rym: Unless it's just clowns getting hurt.
Rym: Anyway, so we went camping, like proper backpack camping.
Rym: And Emily had never been camping in the woods before ever, but while I had been camping a lot and I'd learned a lot about camping, that was pretty much like Cub Scouts up until early Boy Scouts.
Rym: And from like mid-high school onward, I never went camping.
Rym: So this was the first time I ever went camping where I actually had to handle all the logistics to the point where if I fuck it up, we're gonna have a real bad time.
Rym: Like don't have enough water or it is literally too cold to survive the night out in the woods or don't have light, don't have food, like that kind of problem.
Rym: And super success, it was super fun.
Rym: And I gotta say, I forgot how fun it is to go out into the woods and completely under your own power with just a backpack and your own two legs and sleep somewhere without going home and just be fine the next day, like waking up in the middle of the woods at dawn.
Rym: It's kind of amazing.
Rym: I missed it.
Scott:  Just do, why don't you just sell your apartment and then live in the woods?
Rym:  Oh, because, so sleeping in the woods-- - Find a woods with internet.
Rym:  Sleeping in the woods, there was no internet.
Rym: Literally, I had no internet access.
Scott:  There are woods with internet though.
Scott: I know that one doesn't have it.
Rym:  Yeah, well like when most people think of camping, what they think of is people drive a car up to a campsite, they pitch a bunch of tents in a campsite that's right there, they have a cooler and like all this stuff.
Rym: This is more like I'm carrying the not most comfortable bed with me 'cause I have to be able to physically carry it 10 miles over mountains.
Rym: So while I like camping, I also very much like being back in my own bed in a nice apartment in New York with internet at the end of camping.
Scott:  You don't say.
Rym:  Just like I like visiting upstate New York, but I like being in a place where I can order Korean food at 3 a.m.
Rym: if I want to and it will show up.
Scott:  It's like picking up a heavy rock and then picking up the not so heavy rock.
Scott: Like ah, I feel so strong.
Rym:  Yup, but it also really gives you an appreciation for like this kind of camping.
Rym: Something that I did not appreciate as a kid was water.
Rym: Having enough water to cook and drink and wash and everything that is safe.
Rym: One, it's a lot easier than it used to be.
Rym: When I was a kid, we were like putting chlorine tablets and bleach and water and drinking the foul concoction.
Scott:  You can carry the water, but water is heavy as fuck.
Rym:  So we carried on this trip, I carried a 33 pound bag and Emily carried a 30 pound bag.
Rym: And fully a third of that weight was water and that was barely enough water to make it two days.
Scott:  Yeah, I mean, let's see.
Scott: If you have eight, a gallon of water is like eight pounds.
Scott: So if you have a 33 pound bag, that's like a 25% of the weight is just water.
Rym:  Yeah, it's hard to carry enough water.
Rym: So I actually also carry filtration systems to just get water in the woods.
Rym: But this time we also carried a bunch of water on our own to not have to rely on that.
Rym: 'cause I've never used in the woods for real in a survival situation, modern water filtration techniques either.
Rym: All the ways I knew from Cub Scouts.
Scott:  But you also have to find such a water source.
Rym:  Ah, that is actually easy.
Rym: So where we camped in Harriman, there's.
Rym: technically you're not allowed to camp there unless you're a thru-hiker, unless you camp within 300 feet of one of the lean-to shelters.
Rym: So there's areas you can camp.
Rym: So I found a website where someone was like, for each one of these areas you're allowed to camp, here are the places on the map where there is water in order of best water to dodgiest water.
Scott:  And someone put in a lot of effort to make that website.
Rym:  Oh yeah, because if you're a backpack camper, that is the most important thing.
Rym: That is the thing.
Rym: You get to a campsite and the first thing you do is figure out-- - I was telling that one other person a lot.
Scott: I could just make such a website full of lies.
Rym:  Yeah, you could.
Rym: The thing is, in Harriman Park at least, there's actually a lot of safe water to drink, assuming you filter it.
Scott: So actually-- - Well, I mean, in New York State in general, we got plenty of water.
Rym:  Yeah, like if the springs were dried up or inaccessible, there's a lake within like two miles hike in any direction from like any point that I would more than gladly come up from.
Scott:  It's also not like, pretty much anywhere in that park, you could walk to, there's a civilized part of the park you can get to very easily.
Rym:  With the caveat that you're either doing that on unblazed, often impassable trails or climbing over mountains.
Scott:  Well, it depends if you don't have to go straight, right?
Scott: But like, you know, Bear Mountain Park has like, you know, has stuff.
Scott: There's like employees and buildings and, you know, basketball, you know, that's not that far from pretty much anywhere in the park.
Rym:  Yeah, like we could hike out--.
Scott:  So like, if you exit the park in pretty much any direction, you're gonna be in some kind of town, houses, you know.
Rym:  Well, if you exit the park in certain directions, you will literally never find civilization because the Appalachian Trail goes through there and that's part of what we were hiking on.
Rym: You could just follow that down to like Georgia.
Scott:  Yeah, but it's like, you know, if you look at like satellite view, it's like, you know.
Rym:  I mean, it only took, we did a big loop, so while we hiked nine and a half miles-- - Well, I mean, there's the town of Harriman, right?
Scott: There's the town of--.
Rym:  Well, like if you get to the Anthony Wayne Center, you could probably get ahold of rangers from there to get help.
Scott:  There's something berg on the south to bike through.
Rym:  The south would be too far to hike to, but anyway.
Scott:  It depends which part you're in.
Rym:  Yeah, so we were in a part where we hiked about 10 miles to get to the campsite over multiple mountains, but there was a continuing route that was only like five more miles that would get us back to where the car was, so about five miles was the maximum we would have had to hike to get help if we actually ran into trouble, but hiking in the dark is extremely dangerous and difficult if you've never done it before.
Rym:  Just wait till the sun comes out.
Rym:  I might have, on the last Australia, two Australia trips ago, had to climb out of a gorge in the middle of the night in the pitch black.
Rym: It took me a couple hours to get out of there.
Scott:  Wait till the sun comes out.
Rym:  No, I was more willing to just climb out rather than wait, considering where I was and the fact that I didn't have a shelter.
Scott:  Anyway.
Rym:  Anyway, it was a super fun time.
Rym: So there's the news, there's a big news.
Rym: If you didn't notice, with the full disclosure, I didn't notice until some people told me and even in my Twitter feed, no one was really talking about it until people started making fun of it.
Scott:  Until everyone, yeah, no one was talking about it until everyone was talking about it, which, of course.
Rym:  Facebook is just fucking--.
Scott:  That's how things happen.
Scott: Before the thing happens, no one talks about it, then the thing happens, then everyone talks about it.
Rym:  Ah, but when the thing happened, I still didn't see people talk about it right away because for whatever reason, the people in my feed seemed to not use Facebook.
Rym: So the first indication I saw that something was wrong with Facebook was not someone saying, oh shit, Facebook is down or even Facebook trending, it was someone tweeting, ha ha ha, fuck Facebook, they're fucked now, and I was like, what?
Rym: Is this about the whistleblower?
Rym: And then I discovered, oh no, there's like three Facebook newses happening.
Scott:  Yeah, 'cause the whistleblower's been news all week.
Scott: They're still down, it's--.
Rym:  Oh yeah, Facebook might not come up anytime soon, actually, that's-- - We'll see how many hours.
Scott: How many, has it been, maybe it's 10 something, maybe it went down, I wanna say?
Scott:  Yep.
Scott:  There might be approaching eight hours by now, I'm guessing.
Rym:  So here's the news, and this is like breaking now, like dateline, 5.43 p.m.
Rym: Eastern time on October 4th.
Rym: We don't know a lot more than you do, but basically, Facebook made some change internally.
Scott:  Well, you listening in the future probably know way more than we do.
Rym:  Yep, which will be really funny.
Rym: I love, like during the election cycle, like after every election, I love to go back and listen to pundits to see how fuckin' wrong they were about everything.
Rym: once we actually know what went down.
Scott:  And if you hear someone who's fuckin' right, be like, whoa, who is that person?
Scott: Let's listen to this--.
Rym:  Case in point, though, make sure that person is right at least three times before you elevate them too much, otherwise you get an eight silver situation.
Rym: They gotta be right multiple times.
Rym: So yeah, Facebook went down.
Rym: The best indication we have right now as to the root cause is an error that Facebook made in an obscure part of the internet that I'm gonna try to describe succinctly, 'cause I am ostensibly well-versed in this, but I'll give you a bunch of caveats in a minute, but a thing that determines how traffic gets routed over the internet itself, like core internet infrastructure.
Rym: Facebook fucked something up so badly that they basically told the entire world they don't exist, and that seems to be the state of it.
Rym: Facebook has disappeared.
Scott:  So if you try to get packets routed to an IP address on Facebook's network, the internet is like, there's no route there.
Rym:  And when Scott says the internet, he means the internet with a capital I, the entire internet.
Scott:  Right, the routers at your internet service provider and all the other internet service providers and all the switches and all the everything around the whole world are like, yeah, there's no such place.
Scott: It's like if you send a letter somewhere and it comes back, no such address.
Rym:  I think the analogy I gave at another Discord, but I'm gonna repeat it here, because this is the best way I can describe this.
Rym: Imagine if I called everyone I knew on the phone and said, yo, if you ever get a call from this number again, it's not me, do not trust it.
Rym: Also, never call me again, this is no longer my phone number.
Rym: So now, okay, I've done that.
Rym: So now, I realize, wait, I fucked up, I shouldn't have done that.
Rym: And I try to call Scott and be like, Scott, don't cut me off.
Rym: Scott's not gonna listen to me.
Scott:  But I already removed you from my contacts.
Scott:  And he blocked the number.
Scott:  I have a setting on my phone that says, if you're not in my contacts, my phone doesn't ring.
Scott: And now, you can't call me.
Rym:  Yep, so the technology where the problem lies, this is a deep part of the internet.
Rym: And it's one of those things that's both extremely simple and extremely complex.
Rym: And anyone who does Linux or network administration probably gets what I mean.
Rym: BGP, Border Gateway Protocol, I think is what it stands for.
Scott: I'm going off of like-- - Border Gateway Protocol is one of those things that you've heard of it, but you don't know it.
Scott: Only a few people know it.
Rym:  I learned it at RIT.
Rym: Like, I had to learn it fluently.
Scott:  Could you do a job where that's your job?
Scott: Could you fix what's wrong at Facebook?
Rym:  So, when I was younger-- - Could you do it now?
Rym:  Now, fuck no.
Rym: But I could have dealt with a problem like this.
Rym:  Anyway.
Scott:  Circa around 2003 through 2008 was about when I-- - But it's one of those things where you don't know it, but if someone brings it up, you know you're fucked.
Rym:  Yep.
Scott:  It's like, you don't, it's not, right?
Scott: It's like-- - It's like if you're a big company.
Scott:  If you're at the mechanics, right?
Scott: If you're at the mechanic and it's like, you know, you don't know how a transmission works, but if they're like, "I think the problem's in the
Scott: transmission."
Scott: Well, you know your wallet's gonna get hurt real bad.
Rym:  Like, if someone asks about the status of the generators at your data center, that's a way scarier conversation than to ask about the power, so.
Scott:  You go to the doctor and it's like, oh, you don't know what the spleen is, but they're like, "The problem is in the spleen.
Scott: "You know that's a bad
Scott: prognosis.".
Rym: (laughing) - Listen, we're gonna talk about your duodenum right now.
Rym: (laughing).
Rym: So, basically, BGP is an old routing protocol to the point that when I took classes on it in 2000 and 2001 at RIT, I treated it as something archaic that I didn't need to care that much about.
Rym: It was also extremely simplistic.
Rym: Most people, including myself, who have a working understanding of BGP, have only ever used it practically in toy networks or inside of networks that they have a lot of control over.
Rym: BGP actually has two different ways it works.
Rym: It's used internally within your network for your routers to basically agree on how to route packets to any arbitrary IP address that they get told about.
Rym: And this is literally how the entire routing table of your entire network gets formed.
Rym: There are often other routing protocols that are used within that system with or without BGP helping, and it gets complicated.
Rym: But eBGP is how your entire network tells the rest of the world that it exists.
Rym: And the big reason this is a big deal is that the protocol is actually extremely complicated to the point that, in my experience, in a large network or a network where you don't control all the nodes, it is hard to predict the outcome of a particular change you might make to the actual behavior of the network.
Rym: I mean, the rules you put in a BGP configuration are actually pretty simple.
Rym: They basically boil down to things like this quality level of connection is available for any traffic routed to IPs in this range.
Rym: And for all that traffic, these are all the ways you could possibly route packets that could get to that network eventually.
Rym: And it's not really worth explaining more, you can try to read the Wikipedia page, and unless you have a deep understanding, not just a piece of BGP-- is like the number one Wikipedia page today.
Rym:  I would not be surprised.
Rym: I was actually refreshing myself on it 'cause it's been a while.
Rym: I have not touched this protocol since like 2005.
Rym: So yeah, Facebook's in deep shit.
Rym: This is not the DNS outage.
Rym: everyone thought it was originally.
Scott:  Well, it just so happens.
Scott: their DNS is behind their routing, so you couldn't reach their DNS.
Scott: But you could reach the Instagram DNS.
Scott: Instagram apparently has their DNS on Oz still, which shows even the biggest companies like Facebook don't have their shit together in terms of unification, but they apparently don't have their shit together in terms of single points of failure either.
Rym:  Yup, but it is shocking that Facebook is down so hard right now and has been for so long, partly because Facebook is both hugely important to a huge percentage of people in industrialized nations and a lot of non-industrialized or industrializing nations, especially outside of the US, where in some cases it is the sole way a lot of people talk to each other.
Rym: But in the US, there's an interesting dichotomy between people who rely heavily on Facebook and people who avoid Facebook at all costs.
Scott:  Well, there's a lot going on there, right?
Scott: So we always talk about antitrust.
Scott: So here's a problem, is that by allowing computer companies to combine so many things together and under one roof, whether that's a physical roof or a company roof or whatever, you now put too many eggs in one basket.
Scott: And this is a good argument why we shouldn't have allowed Facebook to get Instagram and WhatsApp and all these other things.
Scott: If they hadn't, then only one of the things would be down and not all three.
Rym:  Yup, and Facebook, unlike, say, SMS, things like SMS, there are governments that force those things to keep working and there's a lot more engineering due diligence.
Rym: An SMS outage would be similarly catastrophic.
Rym: And guess what?
Rym: There are rarely SMS outages.
Scott:  Right, well, here's the thing, right?
Scott: So Facebook, we don't care that Facebook is down.
Scott: We don't like Facebook.
Scott: But we don't like WhatsApp and Instagram that much either.
Scott: But WhatsApp especially is like an essential communication mechanism for a lot of people, especially people with like foreign relatives or certain countries.
Scott: WhatsApp is like the number one way to communicate in certain countries.
Scott: So if you're in those countries or know anyone in those countries that you communicate with often, your basic communication has been cut off, right?
Scott: Like you can't talk to your relatives in India, for example, like you just don't know what's up with them right now.
Rym:  Oh, just now the Facebook website is reachable again.
Scott:  Wow.
Rym:  Literally just now.
Rym: I've been refreshing it off and on.
Scott:  It's not loading for me, but you know.
Rym:  It just loaded for me.
Scott:  It's doing something, it's doing something.
Rym:  Just now.
Scott:  Again, a white page.
Scott: It's slowly coming up.
Rym:  I can't log in and check 'cause I don't have a Facebook account.
Scott:  Oh no, it worked.
Scott: It just really slow.
Rym:  Damn it, I was hoping it would stay down.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott:  Yep, well that's sad.
Scott: But regardless.
Rym:  That's a shame.
Scott:  So the argument is A, antitrust of course, but B, even if WhatsApp was its own company still, just completely standalone, if it reaches the point where it's such an essential communication mechanism.
Rym:  It should be nationalized.
Scott:  It should be nationalized ideally, but if not, it should at least be regulated as utility because it's essential.
Scott:  Yep.
Scott:  But here's the other problem is, it's an international utility.
Scott: It's not a single nation utility which make things complicated.
Scott: Is there even a precedent for regulating an international utility?
Rym:  There absolutely are precedents and treaties and lots of ways to regulate international services.
Rym: It just takes a very, very long time.
Rym: And often those things get blocked entirely by frankly, countries like the United States that try to prevent regulation of tech companies that it cares about.
Scott:  Yeah, well and there's also every, certain countries are always gonna do something.
Scott: weird, right?
Scott:  Yep.
Rym: So there's a lot going on here and it's interesting.
Rym: Facebook is finally coming back online it looks like, which I guess is good for the people who rely on it.
Rym: But the underlying problem is Facebook should not and cannot remain as powerful as it is right now.
Scott:  Well, but you don't even talk, right?
Scott: So Oz is not just Amazon, but everyone who uses Oz, which is, imagine if Oz itself, all the regions and all the zones were down.
Scott: This is a complete global outage for Facebook.
Scott: Literally every Facebook thing was out, period.
Scott: So Amazon Web Services, you think that won't happen 'cause they have so many regions and zones and all this stuff going on that only some of it could possibly be down at once.
Scott: And it's never all gone down at once, but is it possible that they could fuck up similarly and have all of Oz go down?
Scott: Not only would every Amazon thing be down, Twitch, their video game.
Scott: they just came out with, buying stuff, right?
Rym:  Yep.
Scott:  You know, everything, all the Whole Foods, you wouldn't be able to get groceries, right?
Scott: The point of sales at the Whole Foods would be down.
Scott: But also every company that hosts their shit on Oz would be down, right?
Scott: Like half the services on the internet would be down.
Scott: Instagram would be down still, even if the Facebook didn't fuck up.
Scott: So should that even be, like we've basically just accepted that risk because of the cost-benefit is, you know, and basically everyone individually made the choice for themselves.
Scott: Like yes, it's worth it for us to put our personal eggs in this basket, you know, and all those choices were probably correct on a cost-benefit ratio, but nobody considered the cost of everyone putting their eggs in the same basket.
Scott: We all put our eggs in the one basket.
Rym:  Yep, well kind of like how we look, we as a society like to look at the cost.
Rym: We talked about this on GeekNights a while ago.
Rym: The cost of coal power versus nuclear power in terms of dollars and like all these types of things.
Rym: But we often ignore a lot of the real costs like human misery or risk.
Scott:  Well, externalities, yeah.
Scott: So let's hope all of Oz never goes down 'cause that would be way worse than this.
Scott: It also shows you, right, you know, there's other angles to take a look on this, right?
Scott: So the other angle is like, yeah, Facebook's actually, you know, one person wrote an article this morning actually.
Scott: I think it might have been before they went down and they were like, yeah, actually the way I see this is Facebook's in deep trouble, right?
Scott: You know, look at the, you know, the whistleblower, right?
Scott: And Facebook's trying to do all these scams.
Scott: There was that thing about them like trying to get like kids to use Messenger on play dates and stuff.
Scott: Like targeting kids.
Scott: Why are you targeting kids?
Scott: 'Cause they know all their users are old and are gonna die.
Rym:  Yep, there's those internal studies we'll talk about with the whistleblower thing specifically showing that they knew and had documented evidence of material harm caused to teens, especially teen girls, using Facebook, like suicide.
Rym:  Instagram.
Rym:  Horrible, yeah, and Facebook as a whole, both.
Scott: And-- - You could interpret this as like, you know, it's just another example of, yeah, actually Facebook's not doing well.
Scott: They're not that strong.
Scott: The other tech companies look a lot stronger when you put them side by side.
Scott:  Yep,
Rym: and you wonder if part of it is, 'cause I know, I know for a fact Facebook is trying to hire a lot of people recently because I've had the recruiters coming after me a bunch and recruiters trying to recruit on their behalf and then I find out it's Facebook and I tell them to go away.
Rym: I know a bunch of people who have quit jobs in capital markets relatively recently to go work at Facebook.
Rym: And I would wonder and suspect, but again, do not know, I am not defaming any particular company or anything here, but what if they're losing a lot of good people?
Rym: What if people are leaving Facebook and the talent pool inside is weaker?
Rym: That can be the kind of thing that leads to an outage like this.
Scott:  Well, the funny thing I said that no one else, I think I said it first 'cause I didn't steal it from anyone else, was Facebook contributed to the global pandemic being worse than it could have been.
Scott: The pandemic in turn caused Facebook to have employees working from home and not at the data center and then something went wrong at the data center and there weren't employees there to fix it for this particular problem.
Scott: They needed to actually be where the computers are 'cause they couldn't reach them over the internet.
Rym:  Yep, so even funnier, we know based on people--.
Scott:  Facebook destroyed itself in this way.
Rym:  Based on Facebook people.
Scott:  Heard the backend part.
Rym:  They reported that internally pretty much everything was down.
Rym: The company couldn't do anything.
Rym: People couldn't email each other.
Rym: They couldn't open conference rooms in some situations.
Rym: There's a bunch of reporting.
Scott:  I mean, that's what happens when you have everything powered by the net, every single thing you have requires a network connection which is why, and I see people doing this, right?
Scott: Is like people get their smart homes with their Nest thermostats or whatever, right?
Scott: It's like I get as few network-dependent devices as possible, right?
Scott: Any device I get, it's like, does this need to connect to the network?
Scott: No, then it's not going to, right?
Scott: The only things that connect to the network are computers and a Nintendo Switch that needs to download games, phones, tablets, which are basically computers.
Rym:  I was about to say, those are just computers.
Scott:  Just computers.
Scott: Nothing else I have connects to the internet or any kind of internet at all.
Rym:  I got one Sonos device that connects to the internet to stream music.
Scott:  I wouldn't get an internet-connected fridge.
Scott:  Nope.
Rym: If I did, I would not connect to the internet.
Scott:  I would be happy to get an automated programmable fridge that has a computer in it, but I would never connect to the internet.
Scott: I would just program the fridge.
Rym: So we'll see what fallout there is from all this, but it is fascinating that this literally happened on the day that America was waking up to all the reporting on the whistleblower for Facebook going public, the 60 Minutes episode airing, and everyone's just starting to talk about this Facebook problem, and then suddenly Facebook is down globally.
Scott:  Yep.
Scott: All right, so really tiny news.
Scott: This research group, they came up with this algorithm/software tool, and the goal of the tool is to
Rym: find
Scott: out who really owns a company, because a lot of countries, they have these laws where you can have a shell company, and then another company owns a thing, and then there's a subsidiary, and all that kind of nonsense.
Scott: offshore this, but the countries themselves do have databases full of all the registered companies, right?
Scott: The information is there.
Scott: The data is available, but to be able to go into the data and say who owns this company is a, to do it by hand is slow as hell, because you could be like 100 layers deep, who knows, and to do it with the existing algorithms was also.
Scott: they weren't that efficient, so they came up with a new algorithm called something, I don't know, they gave it a name, like something icon, I guess, alpha icon, I don't know, but yeah, they applied it to some company data from I think the UK or something.
Scott: You have a database of 4.2 million UK companies, and let's see, correctly determined the ultimate owner in 96% of the cases, right?
Scott: Which is, and the competing algorithm that already exists only was correct and found the right answer 89% of the time, so that's a pretty significant difference.
Scott: So this is really useful, 'cause now we can take databases the governments have and find out who actually owns evil company X, and I think this has large consequences for justice, right?
Scott: Some company commits a crime, we can do, if they're in that percentage that wasn't being found, we can now find who the real owner is and go after them, if there is political will, which there usually isn't, but hey, one less excuse.
Rym:  So in one more news that is also a really big deal, we didn't even get to talk about this yet, just on the heels of the iPhones 13 coming out and still having a lightning adapter, Europe has announced that they will require basically all electronic devices that charge via any sort of cable, like USB, anything that's battery powered, there's a whole thing, it basically applies to smartphones, has to use USB-C.
Rym: USB-C is going to be the standard for the entire world.
Scott:  That's a good environmental move, 'cause it's like, hey, everyone use the same fucking cable, let's stop wasting time on all kinds of weird cables, everyone use this one, the end.
Rym:  It's absolutely huge news, because USB-C, the cable, the physical specification, is an extremely durable, capable specification that will probably survive decades, and that's the kind of spec you want to be the official standard.
Rym:  I'm sure
Scott: if they can get this law passed, considering how old USB-C is, which isn't that old, really, in the grand scheme, if they can update their laws this quickly, then I'm not worried that when USB-D comes out, they'll be able to update again, to re-standardize, if it ever becomes necessary, but USB-C will clearly be able to carry us for quite a long time, I mean, the regular USB, the rectangle one's been around since the late 90s, and it's still here, and still not gonna completely disappear.
Rym:  Also, USB-C as a physical standard is a little bit complex, but it is extensible, and it's smart enough to deal with, you can upgrade it a lot, while still conforming to whatever these regulations eventually are, like now, you can plug any old, any devices just work, if you plug 'em into pretty much any USB-C charger, regardless of what the device
Scott: is.
Scott:  I can't really imagine an improvement on it, unless someone finds a way to make it way smaller, which seems unlikely, or B, just wireless, in which case, this law doesn't apply, so who cares?
Rym:  Well, arguably, wireless should, it's not clear if wireless will be banned, or can only be supplemental, because wireless actually introduces significant losses in efficiency.
Scott:  It does, but it also, significant gains in terms of, you don't have to have cables, material savings.
Rym:  Yep, so we'll see how that goes.
Scott:  Trash savings, you're not throwing out cables when they break.
Rym:  Yep, but it's really sad, Apple has just persisted, Apple is really mad about this news, and they've issued a bunch of statements how they're gonna fight it, where we remain concerned the strict regulation mandating just one connector stifles innovation, rather than encouraging it.
Scott:  I just, the thing that bothers me about that, is like, you know, that's clearly not a good faith argument.
Scott:  No.
Scott:  Right, it's like, right?
Rym:  USB-C exists.
Scott:  Right, it's like, Apple, you keep, first of all, you keep switching your devices to USB-C, you love USB-C, right?
Scott: You made your, you just came out with an iPad Mini that was USB-C, when before it didn't have it, right?
Scott: You keep switching things to USB-C from Lightning, so, but, so why are you so insistent on, it's like, you could just switch it all over now, what, you know, what, why are you waiting for even without this law?
Rym:  Yeah, like, why Lightning?
Rym: Lightning has zero material advantages, they make a big deal about how Lightning was how they made the iPhones thinner, I don't buy it, because these-- - Lightning is not, if you put 'em next to each other, the size difference is pretty small.
Scott:  Yep.
Scott:  You know, it does not, I don't understand, you know, why, I guess, you know, they probably would have to change something in their designs, right, to accommodate this, and they don't wanna do that on the timetable set by some government, right, they wanna do it on their own timetable, but at least, you know, if you're gonna argue against it, tell us the good faith, real reason, right?
Scott:  You know, be like, yes, we don't want that because we make more money on Lightning cable licenses, you know, than on-- - What is the innovation Lightning has?
Rym: that USB-C does not, that materially affects.
Scott: but like, you know, it could just be in general, like maybe Apple's got another kind of cable in the works, like, you know, they already have Lightning and Thunderbolt, maybe like, I don't know, what's more than that?
Scott: Ball Lightning, maybe they got the Ball Lightning cable.
Rym:  The plasma cable.
Rym:
Scott: Yeah, there's something, who knows what they got, maybe they got some other cable in the works, now they're gonna have to call that whole thing off, right, well, it's like, say that then, right, and then tell us how that's better, you know, it's like, don't lie and be like, stifle innovation with a bad faith argument.
Scott: If you want a government to not do something, at least just present a good faith argument of the real reason you're opposed, right, don't give a bullshit reason.
Rym:  Yep, so the proposed EU regulations apply to smartphones, tablets, cameras, phones, portable speakers, handheld video game systems, all of which have standardized on USB-C, except Apple smartphones.
Scott:  Yeah, I mean, all of those things are not even a problem, I can't, every camera now has USB-C, so yeah.
Rym:  So I wonder how Apple's gonna react to this, I feel like the directions they're gonna go are either--.
Scott:  They're already moving everything to USB-C, if they're forced to, they'll either, A, stop selling for a short time, B, move up their timetable, right, who knows, you know, if they got enough money, they can fucking deal with it, right.
Rym:  I can see them trying to go to completely wireless, and then the EU having to regulate that away.
Scott:  They'll fight the government, and then they'll see what happens, win or lose, and--.
Rym:  At least what I'm excited about most is that it's the European government, which can move a lot faster than the US government, and it's a market that's too big for Apple to just ignore, so they're gonna have to deal with it one way or another.
Scott:  But meanwhile, you just bought an iPhone, and now you have a lightning cable.
Rym:  I know, I just bought like four lightning cables to put in all the places.
Scott:  You could just use the wireless part, though.
Rym:  I guess I could, but that does charge slower, and is less efficient.
Scott:  Mm, that's true.
Rym:  Yeah, I'll talk about my iPhone, 'cause I switched, the hardware is good, other than that stupid lightning cable, but I'll talk about that another time.
Scott:  No, I mean, lightning cable would be fine, if even, lightning could have been USB-C, there's.
Scott: no, you know, it just wasn't, because Apple.
Rym:  All right, anyway.
Scott:  It's just inverted, basically, right, the pins, it's on the inside, and the pins stick out as opposed to a ring.
Rym:  And lightning has a bunch of features that arguably you could just do with USB-C.
Scott:  You could do every feature that, they're almost equivalent, I just think lightning doesn't have like the high-speed, high-power modes.
Rym:  But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So this is a Twitter thread, a while ago, like not even that long ago, people were making, there was a photo making the rounds at a hardware store somewhere, and it was a porcelain toilet, but the porcelain toilet was in the shape of a skull, like a big skull.
Scott:  It looked cool, I thought 50/50 it was Photoshopped, but you know, whatever.
Rym:  Yeah, but it was real, and it was just a thing, like all right, the skoilet.
Rym: So this Twitter thread, someone decided not just to track this thing down and figure out what it is, because apparently there is a whole world of skull toilets, there are multiple companies that compete in the skull-specific aesthetic of a toilet industry.
Rym: It is part of a luxury industry, this rabbit hole.
Scott:  Yet the people who have the skull toilets are not showing them off at all, 'cause we haven't seen them on the internet prominently until now.
Rym:  Yep, so this person's like, wait, here's Skull Pot, one of the companies that makes all sorts of skull toilets.
Scott:  If there's enough companies making skull toilets that it's a competitive market, there should be a lot of them out there, and the people who have them, I guess, are secretive people.
Rym:  So the other big one in France, there's a company, it's not clear what the company is, but the toilet they make is called The Water Throne, and it is designed to look like a floating black skull.
Rym:  Awesome.
Rym:  And the eyes light up when you open the lid.
Scott:  Maybe we just haven't seen it 'cause they're not on French internet.
Rym:  Maybe not.
Rym: These seem to be primarily of interest in Europe and the Middle East, and basically everywhere but the US.
Scott:  I just mean, if I'm making a haunted house, I'd put a few in there, right?
Rym:  Yep, it's hard to say what the demographic is if people are into this, but it seems to overlap with fart cars, and big bass, and nightclub life in particular.
Scott:  It would be really funny if you had one of those farms that made a corn maze hayride haunted house in October, but your toilets are there year-round, so you get all skull toilets, and then during apple picking season, this is in September, there's skull toilets.
Scott: Someone comes to pick something in the spring to come and get some whatever, and skull toilets.
Scott: It's like, yeah, those are for October, but there are toilets, so.
Rym:  So yeah, if you want a skoilet, this thread will show you all the luxury options you can pursue this dream of being able to poop and/or pee into a giant fake ceramic skull.
Scott:  All right, so my thing of the day.
Scott: I may have used this YouTube channel as the thing of the day a super long time ago, 'cause it seemed really familiar when YouTube recommended it to me.
Rym:  I'm already subscribed, so I'm pretty sure that's true.
Scott:  Yeah, but I got back into it, so it's called, it's Cracking the Cryptic.
Scott: If you haven't heard of it, you may have.
Scott: It has 400,000 subscribers, but it's like these puzzle experts, and they mostly solve Sudokus and do other things.
Scott: They were streaming Baba Is You, which is very puzzle adjacent, right?
Scott: But I know me, and also Rym, who likes puzzles even less than me, right?
Scott: But even me, I don't really like, I never really respected Sudoku that much, right?
Scott: I always felt like, you know, Picross is similar in that, yeah, you're just following this algorithm to solve the puzzle.
Scott: You're not developing an algorithm when you solve the puzzle, so it's just a process as opposed to a logic exercise.
Scott: And also, when you're done with the Picross, you got what, a grid of nine by nine numbers?
Scott: At least with the Picross, I mean, at least with Sudoku, you just have a grid of numbers.
Scott: With Picross, you get a nice picture.
Scott: There's like the surprise at the end.
Scott: It's a little more fun in that regard.
Scott: But on this channel, I discovered, I was like, oh, yeah, these people are like the best puzzler type people in the world.
Scott: Their whole community is puzzling.
Scott: They're Patreon puzzling, right?
Scott: It's sort of like lock-picking lawyer, right?
Scott: He picks a lock every day, and they solve a Sudoku every day, right?
Scott: Same kind of deal.
Scott: But regular old Sudoku's not enough for them, clearly, right?
Scott: They have taken the Sudoku to the next, the high, all the levels, right?
Scott: And I didn't, once I watched their videos, I was like, oh, and now my respect level went from negative to infinity positive.
Scott: Now it's like, whoa, I don't wanna do regular boring Sudoku, but I sure as hell wanna do those.
Scott: Basically, the way it comes down to is you have a Sudoku, and in normal classic Sudoku, mathematically, there has to be a certain number of pre-given numbers.
Scott: Otherwise, it's unsolvable, right?
Scott: There could be more than one possible solution to it.
Scott: So what you do to make Sudoku harder is you remove a bunch of numbers, and then you come up with some other rule set in addition to the regular Sudoku rule set, right?
Scott: They've got all these other ones.
Scott: They got, in this particular video, there's an XV rule set.
Scott: There's some that have thermo rule sets, arrow rule sets, cages, combinations of all of the above, all kinds of unique extra rule sets so that you often start out with no numbers at all or just a few numbers, and then you get really amazing puzzles that
Rym: are well worth it.
Rym:  Oh my God, this XV thing, I see what that is now.
Scott: So the XV one, I pick this one for the thing of the day, although the whole channel is kind of the thing of the day, not because this is the best puzzle that was on the channel.
Scott: There are some other really, really good ones, but because this one involves Louis XV and is really amusing as well as being an amazing puzzle.
Scott: The last thing I wanna say about this channel is that the people who are on the channel solving the puzzles are, I wanna say, even better than lockpicking lawyer.
Scott: Maybe the best I've seen on YouTube in terms of doing a thing and explaining the thing they are doing at the same time.
Scott: It's like when he does, some of his videos, he'll do just a normal Sudoku in like 10 minutes, and he explains it in such a clear way.
Scott: You can totally follow all the logic, right?
Scott: And he matches his explanation to the level of difficulty of the puzzle.
Scott: And they also give you links in the video description so you can try the puzzle yourself first always.
Scott: And they make all their money.
Scott: Their business model is great.
Scott: They're selling puzzle apps that they made.
Scott: They got Patreon, which gets you puzzles, right?
Scott: It's like this is, I think, maybe, a lot of people, like I said, lockpicking lawyer, others are following this business model, but I think this is the perfect iteration of the 21st century business model, what they're doing here with these puzzles.
Rym:  Yeah, for sure.
Scott:  If you've got some kind of business going on that's any way like this, you wanna sort of copy what they're doing business-wise.
Rym: In the meta moment, the GeekNights book club book that we are powering through is "The Tale of Genji" as Genji sleeps and fucks his way through life.
Scott:  Hmm.
Rym:  That's pretty much what that book is about.
Rym: The longer you read it, it's just when and how.
Scott:  Yeah, moving right along, and I'm going outside less, reading more.
Scott: It's gonna happen.
Scott: It's been years.
Scott: There was a pandemic in addition to other issues.
Rym: Pandemic materially made us read a lot less because we're busy, and most of our reading was during travel.
Scott:  I do wanna say, though, that when this is done, maybe it might not be Rym's optimistic October, but I'm likely not going to work in December at all, or much at all, so December seems maybe likely, and then we can start fresh in 2022 with new books, and what's strange is that taking so long to read this book has given me guilt about reading any other book, and so, but I've had a hankering to read other books 'cause I've only read
Rym: this one book.
Rym:  I'm not looking as my book club book, which I think I shared with Scott already.
Rym: It's a good book.
Scott:  All right, so I think once we finish this, I foresee, A, not picking such a long book again, picking but easier and fun, shorter books.
Rym:  B, no new global pandemic.
Rym: No brand new global pandemic, hopefully.
Scott:  Yeah, just the existing one.
Scott: So I foresee basically a rapid uptake in book club books, many of them, and then eventually we'll get back to, not that the rate was ever high, but the number of book club books per month of GeekNights, the rate will get back to where it was, we'll regress to the mean.
Rym:  But also don't forget, the entire book club is just online, like the episodes where we talked about the books, the full talk, even the forum threads, so you can pick any old book from the whole run of the book club up to this point.
Scott:  Yeah, if you haven't read some of the old book club books, you can go back and listen to the episodes, they're timeless.
Rym:  And we 100% support necromancy in our forum.
Rym: So if you read, I don't know, Player of Games, go find a forum thread, and if it's so old, it's only in the old forum, just make a brand new forum thread and keep the conversation going.
Scott:  Yeah, and link to the old one.
Rym: So yeah, otherwise, no conventions really coming up.
Rym: for obvious reasons, there's a global pandemic going on.
Rym: And today, with Facebook's outage, it's a good time to talk more generally about social media.
Rym: And I want to remind you about the leopard in space 2001, or 2001, colon, a space odyssey.
Rym: We talked about this when we did the book club book, is why I was thinking about it.
Scott:  Oh, look at that, look at that.
Rym:  Yeah, I'm bringing it around.
Rym: But the movie kind of left this subplot out, like it left out the detail that I think was very relevant to this conversation.
Rym: Because in 2001, the book, spoilers, I guess, the proto-humans learn how to use tools and weapons and hunt for the first time.
Rym: Now they have meat, they have more supplies of food.
Rym: And what happens?
Rym: A leopard breaks into their cave and almost kills them, almost ends this grand experiment in advanced technology.
Rym: A new technology brought definitive, objectively agreed upon boons, they had more food.
Rym: And it also brought unforeseen, unexpected, and new dangers.
Rym: The leopard actually came into our fucking house, that's never happened before, what do we do?
Rym: Social media is the leopard.
Rym: right now, just like in that book, AI was the leopard if you didn't get part of the main plot of that book.
Rym: So here we are, in the year 2021, it is very hard for anyone in the world to say that social media has been primarily a positive impact, especially even just on American society.
Scott:  Yeah, it's been a mixed bag, right?
Scott: So the way, the narrative that I see, 'cause I lived through all of it.
Scott:  Literally all of it.
Scott: We used Orca, the first one.
Scott:  I'm qualified to say what the fuck happened, 'cause I was there the whole time, paying attention the whole time, is that in the 20th century, right, well I guess starting with the printing press, you finally had the ability to disseminate information widely, right?
Scott: And not just by word of mouth, and not just to a few wealthy, well even with the printing press, still just literate people, but eventually a lot of people were literate.
Rym:  It slowly democratized, it slowly expanded, it became ubiquitous.
Rym:
Scott: Then you had your radio, your TV, all kinds of stuff, but even with all that in the 20th century, most of the 20th century, the ability to broadcast information widely was in the hands of a few, and it was still, even though there was freedom of speech, you needed, in order to broadcast your speech loudly, you needed a bigger megaphone, which cost money, and was regulated and centrally controlled to some extent.
Scott: You could have a local radio, but it's like, that's still, it's only broadcasting locally.
Rym:  There were people doing these things, they were very much niche, like public access television, early live streams that were using not off the shelf, semi-bespoke technology, all these things were possible.
Scott:  Zines, someone copying their own VHS tapes, someone making mixed tapes on cassettes, but you couldn't, it was very hard to get wide distribution without, say, a record deal, and a giant company make prints a bunch of records for you.
Scott: In the late '90s, we got the internet, and finally, anybody, absolutely anybody, all you needed was a computer and an internet connection, which was much lower bar, could broadcast information and make it available to the whole world, but it was still difficult to do, you had to have specialized knowledge, even a GeoCities page, or a Myspace page, took some amount of skill and knowledge and effort, and something you want, right?
Rym:  You have to imagine, when we were in high school, kids would teach each other HTML because they were like, I'm gonna make a website and post my thing, and that was secret knowledge that would be passed around.
Rym: I'm talking eighth, ninth, 10th grade for us.
Scott:  Yep, you can make a podcast, but who the hell was gonna listen to it?
Scott:  Yep.
Scott:  You can make a video of yourself, but it was just hosted on a web server, and someone would have to find it, and then download it.
Rym:  Moog recorded his Mega TF rant that only people who are in that one forum heard.
Scott:  Yep, so social media was basically, hey, we're gonna basically do the GeoCities thing, only make it way easier.
Scott: Facebook and whatnot, these things are actually kinda old.
Scott: Facebook came out when I was in college still, but at the time, you could only really use it with a big old desktop computer.
Scott: You had to know how to use it.
Scott: You couldn't do it wherever.
Scott: Maybe a laptop you could use it with maybe at the time.
Scott: Wi-Fi was a thing then.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott:  Sort of.
Rym: I remember, I couldn't afford a laptop, but I was in college.
Rym: Laptops were still pretty expensive to the point that-- - Oh yeah, I didn't have one, but other people did.
Scott: People had Power Mac G4.
Rym:  If I was on the other side of campus, and I wanted to get ahold of someone, we didn't even all have cell phones yet back then.
Rym: I would have to go to a lab, log in to AIM, and hope that whoever I wanted to talk to was also sitting at a computer.
Rym: Logged into AIM.
Scott:  So, and there were newsgroups, and forums, and BBSs, and all those things that were effectively social media of some kind, but they were only accessible to people who put in effort, right?
Scott: There were email, forward, newsletter things, all kinds of stuff, but their reach was still not that large.
Scott: It was people with the means, and the desire to seek them out, and get with them, so even though you could have, there were plenty with lots of misinformation, and other bad things going on, you know, it wasn't en masse, right?
Scott: It wasn't affecting all of society, and then the mobile phone came out, the smartphone, right?
Scott: The regular mobile phone had been around, and Twitter originally, the original Twitter, their idea, 'cause smartphones weren't a thing, was that it was SMS powered.
Scott: It would be a SMS thing, like you would tweet, you would send a text message to tweet to everyone who was following you, and they would get a text message, so you basically group texting, and then you would be getting all these group texts from one phone number, but everyone you followed, every time they texted, you would just get a text.
Scott: That was the original Twitter.
Scott: They thought it would be powered entirely by SMS, and it wasn't, it was thanks to basically, not just the iPhone, but the iPhone 3G, when they added the App Store, they could have a Twitter app, and then that's when they said, okay, you know, the SMS started to fade, and it was just app-based social networking.
Scott:  Yup, and back then, like I didn't even use Twitter, but social media-- - It took me a little while to use it, but I used it still pretty early relative to most people.
Scott:  But
Rym: we're at this point now where there are very different kinds of social media, and I almost don't wanna talk as much today about like YouTube Twitch style live streaming compared to like the social media that's mostly built around a person's actual identity, like social media as in Twitter, Facebook, those kinds of equivalents where all of your communication is around an identity that many people, most people, tie to their real person.
Rym: Like not as much a brand, it's like Facebook.
Rym: is you on the internet, not me, 'cause I don't have a Facebook account, and I remember when Orkut first appeared.
Rym: It actually was the first social network like that.
Rym: It predated Facebook, and it was new.
Rym: I remember Scott and I and all of our friends were in college, and Orkut debuted in like January of 2000, what, five, four, I think it was four, and we were like, "Wait, what?
Rym: "So I can just have my identity online, "tag all my friends, "and now we can have groups and share information.
Rym: "and like share photo albums and all this stuff.
Rym: "all into one place?
Rym: "Hell yeah, sign me up,".
Rym: and it was awesome.
Rym: For like six weeks, and then spam appeared on it out of nowhere, and then the platform just collapsed almost immediately.
Scott:  But it didn't collapse in Brazil, 'cause most of the spam was from Brazil.
Rym:  Yup, but basically, all these early social networks, Facebook and Orkut are the ones that are the most important to talk about.
Rym: They were both made without any thought as to how people would actually use these platforms when they were used by a wide range of people as opposed to a very small number of people.
Scott:  Right, well, I mean, Facebook's original goal was just like, "Hey, let's date college, "let's get college people to fuck," right?
Scott:  Yup.
Scott:  That was the goal of that.
Scott: It was college, when I saw Facebook for the first time, I think even when I made my account, it was like, "You could only sign up "with an EDU email address from a college.
Scott: "You had to be a college student, "otherwise you just weren't even allowed on Facebook,".
Scott: right, it wasn't open to the public.
Rym:  And I thought, "Well, I already have an Orkut, "why would I use
Rym: Facebook?".
Scott:  Right, and then the Orkut was just like, "Hey, we're just making this fun thing.
Scott: "so you can have fun with people, "either gathering with people you know "or people around a particular interest.
Scott: "with this fun little user interface," right?
Scott: Like Myspace, when they make those things, they didn't have a goal in mind, it was just sort of like, "Hey, this is a fun
Scott: application.".
Scott:  Yup.
Scott:  "Let's chat with people, right?
Scott: "Let's do
Scott: stuff.".
Rym: So fast forward, what we learned from these networks, mostly, was that they did work okay without any guardrails or controls, as long as the communities and interactions within them were still very relatively segregated, but as they converged into a mass media type situation where everybody can see everything and everyone's interacting at scale, all these weird, unexpected, horrific, well, in many cases expected, but the people who expected them were ignored when they raised red flags and raised warnings, that there was this compounding of negative impacts, many of which we foresaw, many of which no one foresaw that are only accelerating.
Scott:  Yeah, I mean, you've just given the power that used to be only to broadcast information widely, something that was not possible for anyone who wasn't wealthy and/or regulated in the 20th century, and you just gave that ability to literally everybody, right, some teenage kid who just has a phone can now broadcast something as powerfully as the New York Times could in the '50s, right?
Rym:  Yep.
Rym: So couple this with-- - That's dangerous shit.
Rym:  So these platforms let anyone post anything, so of course, you've got the horse-paced eaters like posting their pro-horse-paced stuff now during COVID and anti-vaccination nonsense, but you also had a confluence of a lot of other technologies that really made this a problem, like algorithmic feed curation, like the advertising technology.
Scott:  Right, well, the original idea, right, 'cause it came from our Google Reader, right, it's like, okay, you have a lot of things you follow, right, and it's too much of a pain.
Scott: I used to go and be like, all right, web comics, open all in tabs.
Scott:  Tab, tab, tab, all right, there's 10 blogs.
Scott: I read, open all in tabs, is there anything new on this one, anything new on this one?
Scott: It's like checking every single, you know, your mail constantly, it's a pain in the butt, right?
Scott: Notifications and just combining them in one place is much more convenient, so Google Reader solved that problem, RSS solved that problem.
Scott: It's like, all right, I go to this one page, I refresh, and there's new stuff at the top.
Scott: Great, if some blog doesn't update for a month, I don't even go to it for a month.
Rym:  Yep.
Scott:  Perfect, so not only did the social media subsume sort of the, you know, replace like chatting, it also replaced, you know, not only the feed, but also the blog, right?
Scott: It's like, well, if I'm just gonna, you know, go on Twitter and put a link to my blog, I'll just make a Twitter thread in the first place.
Scott: Now I don't need the blog or the aggregate, right?
Scott:  Yep.
Scott:  So now you just go on to Twitter or Facebook or whatever you're using, and you follow everything you're interested in, and you doom scroll it, and it constantly updates, and you're getting all your info in one place, which is a good application.
Scott: That's what we want, right?
Rym:  Yep, but even if we forget the machine learning thing, so in the early days, before there was this algorithmic curation, and I saw there were a bunch of papers that showed this seems to apply to any kind of network, that Twitter was a good example that has the concept of retweeting or resharing.
Rym: The studies seem to show that if any one member of the node, like one node in the network, reshares something, then that thing materially becomes more likely to be reshared further because it got a boost, more people saw it.
Rym: But what that would mean in practice is that a small number of things, by mostly random chance, would become extremely widely shared to the exclusion of most other things, and this happens even if you make a fake network like Twitter, where every single fake account randomly decides what to like and retweet, you'll see the same effect.
Rym: A small number of things, like say, some of the early YouTube streamers who got really popular solely because of this effect.
Rym: probably, they randomly just get promoted by the fact that they happened to get promoted early, and were lucky in the random sea of the semi-random retweeting and resharing that happens.
Scott:  Well, that's the thing, is that the Google Reader, just the feed functionality, didn't have the resharing functionality.
Rym:  My reader was for me to read all the things I care about, not to share it with Scott.
Scott:  You personally choose what you want to see with intent, and you see only new content on channels that you have specifically chosen.
Scott: This is what we've wanted.
Scott: even before there was, we wanted to pay for cable TV and say, I want these channels, I only want to pay for those channels and I want any of the channels, right?
Scott: That's what we've always wanted, but that doesn't make anyone any fucking money.
Scott: You can't make money with that.
Rym:  So how does social media make money?
Rym: By pretty much selling your data or selling ads.
Scott: That's mostly it.
Scott: The thing is, is that even if you made what I suggested, you only follow things, most people wouldn't follow that many things.
Scott:  Nope.
Scott:  People would follow their family and friends, and if your family and friends aren't big time posters, you're not gonna get a lot of content.
Scott: Only maybe a photo gallery now and then when someone has a party.
Rym:  Yep, so you're more likely to follow some celebrities and bigger topics.
Scott:  And the old Facebook days, the very old Facebook days when my family was on there, but it wasn't algorithmic yet.
Scott: Many years ago, it's like, I would open up Facebook and there would almost be nothing new 'cause I only followed my family and no one really posted anything.
Scott: So if no one's posting anything there, how often are you checking it?
Scott:  Yep.
Scott:  You're not, really.
Scott: And most people, so maybe you have a couple things you're interested in.
Scott: How often are those posting new content?
Scott: Maybe you like metal and you follow five metal bands.
Scott: How often does a metal band's album come out?
Scott: How much are they posting on there?
Scott: And if one of them starts posting too much, maybe of the five metal bands, four of them post when they have a new album and they're promoting it.
Scott: Okay, cool.
Scott: And one of them posts daily updates of in the studio, everything they're doing.
Scott: Suddenly, you're following 30 things and one of them is taking up 90% of your feed.
Scott: 'cause it's not algorithmic.
Scott: It's just chronological, everything you follow in order.
Scott: And your whole feed is this one metal band.
Scott: You're like, shut the fuck up, one metal band.
Scott: I can't see my mom's whatever.
Scott: It got buried.
Scott: So you unfollow that, right?
Scott: And so that's that scenario of what happens when you only have things you follow in reverse.
Scott: chronological order is not a lot of activity, people unfollowing things that are too active, people, if there's not a lot of activity on your feed, you don't need to open the app that much.
Scott: Maybe what, once a week, right?
Scott: How often you got, you can't sit there doom scrolling 'cause there's not a lot of stuff going on.
Rym:  And if they make their money via ads or selling your data, they need you to engage with the platform a lot in order to make that money.
Rym: So they're gonna do things to cause you to engage with the network more.
Scott:  Right, so the re-sharing is a huge one because now things are showing up in your feed that aren't things you follow.
Scott: There's something someone you follow follows and they've taken it from a feed that's two steps away and moved it all the way over to your feed, right?
Scott: So Rym likes hiking and I don't and he retweets a hiking thing 'cause he follows a hiking guy and now it's in my feed even though I don't give a shit about hiking, right?
Scott: And now suddenly my feed, 'cause I follow 20 things that I care about, is now filled not just with the 20 things I care about but the 20 things times 20, right?
Scott: So that's 400 things, right?
Scott: Yeah, 400?
Scott: Yeah, that's 400 things in my feed even though I only told them that I care about 20 things.
Scott: And now suddenly I can doom scroll.
Rym:  Yep, they gotta get you to the point to where there is more content than you can consume so you won't think that much about.
Rym: did I miss anything?
Rym: Is something overrepresented in my feed?
Rym: And they wanna get you to like and retweet or whatever those options are.
Rym: they have for you to engage because the more you interact, the more data they get about you, the more engagement they have to tell advertisers like yeah, look at all these eyeballs and the more your activity gets other people to doom scroll and repeat the process.
Scott:  Yep, now the second thing is what they're doing with the algorithms is not just sort of making sure there's always something to show you every time, getting as much stuff into your feed as they can so there's always something for you to look at.
Scott: In Instagram, which doesn't really have the retweet kind of thing, but also others, you get to the bottom, right?
Scott: You've seen everything.
Scott: And when you get to the bottom, it just starts giving you suggestions, right?
Scott: And Twitter tried this with like.
Scott: here's people you should follow.
Scott: We recommend you follow the president.
Scott: We recommend you follow your favorite local sports team.
Scott: We recommend you follow your news anchor, right?
Scott: But that doesn't really sort of give you a sample of what following that person is like.
Scott: Instagram's just like oh, you've reached the end and it just starts showing, you can just keep scrolling and it's showing you shit you don't follow.
Scott: It's just giving you things the algorithm thinks you might like and it hopes that when you see a funny post down there, you'll follow it, right?
Scott: To increase what you follow and then learn more about you.
Scott: It doesn't just end like.
Scott: that's the end.
Scott: It's never the end.
Scott: There is no end.
Rym:  Now this all leads to, on one hand, as a user, these are almost dark patterns.
Rym: I'm being guided into behavior that I dislike that is unhealthy for me that I do not want.
Rym: Like the royal eye, I guess.
Rym: Like that's what, they're not catering to the users of the platform.
Rym: They're catering to the users of the monetization model of the platform.
Scott:  Yeah, if you're a user who's not paying anything, you're the product.
Scott:  Yep.
Rym: So if we back away from that aspect of it, just societally in general, I think what we've seen and people are talking about this more and more.
Rym: I've seen big threads lately that I'm not gonna address now of there was some zennial who was talking about like here's what millennials don't get about the internet.
Rym: and the funny part was they seem to think that no millennials ever use the internet.
Scott: Like they seem to really, they have really an undue misunderstanding of like where technology actually is, - I mean, as a millennial, I'm gonna resent anyone else's opinion if they think that's how generations work, but at the same time--.
Scott:  This thread is right about something.
Scott:  Right, they definitely, being younger, they see it differently and I don't know how they see it and the way they see it is not invalid.
Scott: So I do wanna hear how they see it.
Rym:  So a big, a side part of that thread, one small part that did resonate is what they said was effectively we're the first generation to grow up online, but that's not what they meant.
Rym: What they actually meant was we're the first generation with social media because the big difference between our childhood and their childhood is literally we didn't share anything about ourselves online at all.
Rym: Like the online world was a different world.
Scott:  I mean, I did, but it was like GeoCities and I didn't share like that much, I would like share my--.
Scott:  I'll put it this way.
Scott:  I would write stupid opinion things about video games or whatever.
Rym:  Oh yeah, I did stuff like that, but guess what?
Rym: Four people in my high school knew my GeoCities page existed.
Rym: My friends online, most of them didn't know what my real name was or where I lived.
Scott:  Yeah, I didn't write any, out of fear of the danger, I didn't write online.
Scott: Like you'd go into AOL chat rooms, they'd be like ASL.
Scott: It's like you might ASL, but you would never write my name.
Scott: is this, here's my address, right?
Scott: Or like, you know, like ASL was like the limit.
Rym:  But like, I would also-- - And the L would not be specific, it would be like U.S - When I was online-- - Connecticut.
Rym:  Depending on the context where I was online, I had different identities that were not traceable back to me.
Rym: No one could go find--.
Scott:  Not easily.
Rym:  Oh yeah, not easily.
Rym: It was definitely possible, but difficult, and also no one cared that much back then.
Rym: So whatever stupid crap I said, or bull viseo was bullied at school, that didn't follow me from the real world into the online world, and nothing I did in the online world followed me back into the real world.
Rym: That is not true for the generation after us.
Rym: The online world is right in their face, even if they're offline, and anything they do offline follows them online.
Rym: They can't escape from it.
Scott:  If Twitter came out in 2007, right?
Scott: If you're 14, 13, you could be tweeting right now, and Twitter is older than you.
Rym:  I already graduated college.
Rym: I already was at my second major job by then.
Rym:  Yeah.
Rym:  So now these kids, it's not that they're online.
Rym: It's that they grew up in a world where anything they do or say online is kind of tied directly to their own personal identity, that they are pressured to share things online, to not be left out of the way society functions,
Scott: and the
Rym: consequences of this have been terrifying and drastic and very difficult to understand so far.
Scott:  Yeah, I mean, there are people who, it's like, you can think of it as like, you know, it's like this Twitter account, or whatever your social media account is, it's like on the one hand, it's this tool that's giving you that Google Reader feed.
Rym:  Yep.
Rym:  Right?
Scott: But it's also letting you know what all the people you care about are up to, and it's also when you post things, the collection of the things that you have cared enough to say and/or re-share, right, are now a stand-in, basically that collection of stuff is you, that is your avatar on that particular platform.
Scott: It's not an avatar like, you know, a 3D model.
Scott: It's an avatar, it's a whole feed of tweets.
Scott:  Yeah, they're-- - If someone comes and reads that, they're getting an image of you.
Scott: based on that, right?
Rym:  There was a Rym, and like a Necromancer14, and a Mephistopheles who had Final Fantasy V, all these different personas that were, like avatars that were out there.
Rym: Now, there's Rym Twitter.
Rym: That is just a Rym that's out there.
Rym: People know that's Rym.
Scott: That Rym Twitter is just there for everyone to interact with and see for-- - And has some relation to the real Rym, but it's not the real, it's, you know, right?
Rym:  But it's a lot closer to the real Rym.
Scott:  You can't tell how, it's a lot harder to tell when that one's lying, at least.
Rym:  But it's also a lot closer to the real Rym than anything I ever did online before 2005 was.
Scott:  Yep.
Rym:  So, that aspect of it is interesting, and we can't go too much longer.
Rym: This is gonna be too long.
Scott:  If you don't post anything, then there is no presence of you on the internet, which could be advantageous, but it's also disadvantageous in that, you know, you're sort of like a non-person.
Rym:  Well, I'll say this.
Rym: The game designers I am friends or acquaintances with who use Twitter, I talk to a lot and am very aware of what they're working on, even if we're just like mutuals or whatever.
Rym: Game designers who don't post a lot on Twitter, unless I go read an essay, I have no idea what the hell they're up to.
Scott:  Right, well, it's not just that, but you don't know, if you have two friends, right, and they're both close friends from school 'cause you're just some kid, and you, it doesn't matter how much you post, well, maybe you post a lot, okay, and you have another friend who posts a lot, and the second friend doesn't post a lot.
Scott: You spend time in person together, so you're pretty close, but you're gonna be closer with the other person who posts a lot because you have this whole, not only are your real selves interacting, your internet selves are interacting.
Rym:  Oh, my friends who don't use Discords.
Scott:  You're learning more about each other.
Scott: You know more about each other, right?
Rym:  Yeah, anyone I know who's not engaged with all the online social media I use, I just talk to way less in my life, full stop.
Rym: I even talk to my dad less than my mom 'cause my mom's more online than my dad.
Rym: Like, that happens.
Scott:  Yeah, it's like, I have friends who I care about a great deal, but who just aren't online as much, and I'm like, is that person still alive?
Scott: What do they, I don't know what they're up to, right?
Scott: I don't know what they're doing these days, you know, unless I talk to them old school style, you know, I have to make an effort, or if they happen to reach out once in a while, right, it's just like a mystery.
Scott: But then the friends, even friends who I barely interacted with in real life, maybe like a convention friend.
Rym:  Well, like Daryl Surratt, like I talk to him a lot online.
Rym: I haven't seen him in person since like 2013.
Scott:  Right, some convention friend who happens to be more active on the same social activities as me and have mutual follows, right, I know what they're up to.
Scott: I grow closer to them, you know, because we're both active.
Scott: So when you're not active, you become, right, like you're not as connected.
Scott: But if that's your only human connection, right, then you can get in like this dark world of loneliness where you're only having these sort of superficial internet human connections.
Rym:  Or even worse, parasocial internet relationships.
Scott:  Yeah, as opposed to actual ones, right?
Scott: Like say, okay, your two actual friends follow each other on Facebook and message all the time.
Scott: Okay, but now the only, but if you're really, your only people you follow are celebrity type people, Twitch streamers, who knows what, right?
Scott: So web comic artists, and you follow and tweet at them and not anyone else, right?
Scott: And that's, you're getting this sort of, you know, substitute human interaction that way.
Scott:  Yeah.
Scott:  That's real bad.
Rym:  Oh, you could, that was the perfect opportunity to use one of my favorite words, Airsats.
Rym: (laughing) So.
Scott:  Airsats human interaction.
Rym:  But the last piece of all this, Airsats human interaction is actually kind of what I want to get into.
Rym: This is the broader, I think the fundamental thing, and I might be wrong, this is my personal opinion.
Rym: You may even disagree.
Rym: I don't think we've talked about this much.
Rym: I think the primary, well, one of the primary problems with social media right now, aside from the fundamental problems of capitalism, is that because social media is one big platform or a series of effectively one big platforms all next to each other, all conversations are decontextualized from communities and now have to weather the storm of every fucko online having an opinion about some random thing you said.
Scott: So.
Scott:  It depends on which network you're using.
Rym:  Yeah, but say you're on Twitter and you post.
Scott:  And how you're using it.
Rym:  You post a picture of, you cooked a nice meal.
Rym: You cooked, I don't know, I made bibimbap.
Rym: Like, I just made a bibimbap.
Rym: You'll get people.
Rym:  A vegan comes up and is-- - You'll get a vegan who comes in and says, "Hey, that's
Rym: unethical.".
Rym: You'll get someone who says that cooking that food is appropriative at face value.
Rym: You'll get someone who says you cooked it wrong.
Rym: You'll get someone who says you cooked it right.
Rym: You'll get someone who says, "Well, what you're not talking about this other kind of food, are you
Rym: racist?".
Rym: You'll get all this stuff decontextualized from the conversation you would have about that same topic among a group of people who have at least passing familiarity with each other and a passing marginal sense of good faith among those people, which is why I think a lot of younger people have backed away from a lot of social media networks and are increasingly going into
Scott: walled
Rym: off communities in discords where forums used to be.
Rym: Because then that's like social media where you have a community that itself is talking about topics, tends to behave very differently from social media where you have the world talking about topics publicly.
Rym: I don't have a lot of opinions on that about what to do about it or where to go next or anything.
Rym: I hate the fact that forums disappeared and got replaced by discord because it doesn't solve the same problem.
Rym:  But the subreddits, subreddits are just forums.
Rym:  But subreddits are still public in that the community is about the topic.
Rym:  Our forum's public.
Rym:  Yeah, I think our forum was for a long time until forums started to decline and a lot of the cool people left and we brought them back via discord.
Rym: Our old GeekNights forum was an example of a community that is a generic community that is ostensibly on one thing but then has other conversations in the context of that community as opposed to having conversations free of all context or conversations with the sole context of the specific topic.
Rym: Neither of those two other ways I think produce productive conversations online today.
Scott:  Also the small community doesn't give you like, note with the small communities, nobody has this power of extreme broadcast.
Scott:  Yeah.
Scott:  If the whole internet world is divided into a bunch of discord servers and like that or subreddits, it's like you can't post, maybe there's a big subreddit but like you can't post something onto every single subreddit at once the way you can tweet to the whole world.
Scott: Now of course you tweet, not everyone's following you but there's that retweet.
Scott: that can happen.
Rym:  Well like one of the Yahtzee locals retweeted my support of them and then a whole bunch of people started interacting with me because of that today.
Rym: That doesn't happen in the world we just described.
Rym: But what does happen then is that you have a network of, I know something, say we have some conclusion about some political thing in our little like sharted off community, each of us are in multiple communities, we talk about that in those other communities and you have a more traditional grassroots spreading of information.
Scott:  Yeah but there are downsides to that also, right?
Scott: So let's say you're in the tech community, right?
Scott: And it's like okay, the big thing you work on is database stuff.
Scott: so you're in the Postgres community big time, right?
Scott: But you also, you happen to code in Rust, that Rust language, right?
Scott: But you're not like into Rust, it's just the language you use.
Scott: You're not like in the Rust community but like if all those communities are like really strongly separated which they kinda are a little bit.
Scott: but there are also like tech news feeds that are just like fire hoses of everything going on in the world of tech, right?
Scott: So you're finding out about all this other stuff going on, right?
Scott: Like if there's a new language, you would never hear about it if you're only in the Postgres community, right?
Scott: So you sort of, sometimes you need that worldwide broadcast aggregation because even though it's giving you a bunch of crap, it's also if you were in little silos, even if you're in many silos, that increases your odds but you're just not gonna get some of those golden nuggets that are only in the giant fire hose feed.
Rym:  Yup.
Rym: So what does your society do?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Social media is more dangerous than most people anticipated.
Rym: It's under mostly the control of very large corporations that do not have your interest at heart.
Scott:  They only have a capitalist interest at heart.
Rym:  Yup.
Rym: Governments have almost no interest in doing anything about any of this.
Scott:  I think there is some interest in some governments but not enough political will.
Rym:  Yup.
Rym: And meanwhile, the governments who are taking the most actions are actually doing the opposite and suppressing very good conversation that happens to be critical of their regimes.
Scott:  Yeah, so I think that number one, the ability to broad, for anyone, literally anyone, to broadcast information very, very widely, especially dangerous information, right, I personally think needs to be regulated despite freedom of speech.
Scott: And also, I personally, I know that the law doesn't agree with this.
Scott:  Shut up all you lawyers, I know.
Scott: But I personally feel that under the existing idea of shouting fire in a crowded theater, right, a lot of things that people, if you tweet something, right, that's the same as crowded theater.
Scott: It's the same as shouting.
Scott: And if it's a lie and it's a dangerous lie, that seems to meet the criteria in the book of God.
Rym:  Yeah, I agree.
Rym: I would argue that commercial speech is not free and should be heavily regulated, which already eliminates like a third of the problems with social media.
Rym: 'Cause like the horse paste stuff, you know where that came from?
Rym: People selling the fucking horse paste.
Rym: Commerce, not free speech anymore.
Scott:  You could also argue that since your tweet is being used for commercial purposes by Twitter, that even though you tweeted it because Twitter is using it for commerce, it's therefore commercial speech.
Scott: Legal arguments I don't care about.
Scott: I'm just saying in principle, right, I think there should be regulation of speech that is broadcast so widely that it could be dangerous.
Scott: There needs to be regulation on that.
Scott: I don't care about free speech purism in that case.
Scott:  Two, hate speech.
Scott:  I'm not saying put someone in jail because they're racist.
Scott: I'm saying stop them from saying things that are broadcast widely if those things are dangerous lies.
Rym: Like case in point, all this COVID stuff.
Scott: Two, essential communication mechanisms like we said during the news.
Scott: If something is so big, it becomes an essential communication mechanism.
Scott: The only way my family can talk is with WhatsApp.
Scott: That needs to be nationalized or at least regulated as a utility.
Scott: It shouldn't be something run by a company with a capitalist interest.
Scott: If we need Twitter to get the news, then Twitter needs to be at least regulated to the point like the FCC regulated the news on television.
Rym:  Yep.
Scott: And for you-- - I think that alone goes a really long way.
Rym:  And how about for you day to day?
Rym: My only advice to you out there using social media is really simple.
Rym: Block any account that even looks at you crosswise and never regret it.
Rym: That is probably the single most important thing you can do for whatever social media platform you use.
Rym: You gotta racist uncle, block 'em.
Rym: Just block 'em and walk away from their Facebook interactions.
Rym: You got a friend who's eating the horse pace, block 'em.
Rym: And if you do that, social media will be a lot less toxic for you personally.
Scott:  If you go to Reddit, Reddit's a shithole.
Scott: But you know what I do?
Scott: You make an account and then you unsubscribe from every single Reddit that's on there.
Scott: So you get a blank homepage and then you subscribe only to the Reddits that you really care about.
Scott: You're really into K-pop?
Scott: Okay, Reddit K-pop.
Scott: I really like BTS.
Scott: All right, well there's a Reddit BTS.
Scott: You can get that one in there too.
Scott: And then you really like Minecraft.
Scott: So get the Reddit Minecraft.
Scott: That's it, stop.
Scott: As soon as you're done with things you care about, don't add any more, right?
Scott: Minimize, these days--.
Rym:  What the fuck?
Rym: There might be breaking news about Taiwan, but keep going.
Rym: There's some shit going down.
Scott:  We'll check that after we're done with this.
Rym:  Taiwan is preparing for a potential war with China after a series of increasingly aggressive military actions.
Scott:  Yep, what else is--.
Rym:  That's breaking news right now.
Rym: DVD on what's going on there.
Rym: I'm gonna do some reading after the show.
Scott:  It's 'cause Facebook went down.
Scott: They couldn't, the communications broke down.
Scott: So yeah, just to end the show before there is a war, World War III or whatever.
Scott: I hope that's not a prescient end to a podcast.
Rym:  Yeah, I hope not.
Rym: I hope this news is not nearly as big as what my feed is implying right now.
Scott:  Feeds, exaggerating a lot, right?
Scott: There was a lot of hoo-ha that was wrong about the Facebook thing today in the feed.
Scott: If you believed everything you read, right?
Scott: But yeah, I recommend unfollowing.
Scott: I've only been unfollowing lately and not adding new followers.
Scott: I've been unsubscribing and not adding subscribers.
Rym:  Every time my Twitter feed gets too long for me to just read all of it, with obvious exceptions, like if I'm in the woods for a weekend or something, I just start unfollowing people until I can read the whole thing.
Scott:  My current criteria is basically, let's say I'm following something like a Gundam account.
Scott: I like Gunplas, I like Gundams, and I have a bunch up there behind me, but how often do I really build those?
Scott: How into it am I?
Scott: It's not my top five geekeries even, right?
Scott: I'm not into it that much.
Scott: So, unfollow it, right?
Scott: I don't need a constant feed of Gundam stuff.
Scott: I'm not that into it.
Scott: Once in a while, but you know.
Scott: Bicycle stuff, on the other hand, is one of my top two, maybe top three at worst, right?
Scott: Maybe even number one.
Scott: But a lot of bicycle stuff, I was following it, okay, good, but it wasn't, it's like, was it helping me?
Scott: Was it bettering my life?
Scott: It's like, I already have all the bicycle equipment I need.
Scott: I don't need to be sold anything, and there's nothing for me to learn.
Scott: I'm not trying to be a pro cyclist.
Scott: I don't need bike coaching, right?
Scott: Or I don't care about fitness nonsense.
Scott: So, none of the bike information feeds had anything to offer me.
Scott: They weren't bettering my cycling.
Scott: I didn't need any more stuff.
Scott: So, I just unfollowed almost every bicycle thing, except for the ones that are like, fuck cars.
Rym:  One thing I will do-- - That's what I need, to fuck cars.
Rym:  In the destroy them sense, not in the planes, online, internet poisoning sense, I hope.
Scott:  Oh, maybe both senses, but regardless, right?
Scott:  Depends on the car.
Scott:  I recommend you strongly just go through all your things.
Scott: I've been doing this, I'm gonna do it for my third time, and just really cut back big time.
Rym:  But too, as an aside there, when there's an emergent event, like right now, the IATSE strike that's coming, or when the Black Lives Matter marches in New York we're constantly organizing on a daily basis, I will often follow a lot of activists or people related to something I'm trying to help with or interact with during a crisis or an incident, and then I'll unfollow them later, or curate that feed back down later.
Rym: Like right now I followed a whole bunch, I followed all the IATSE locals, 'cause I really wanna stay on top of the strike that they voted to approve.
Rym: actually today, that's other big news we didn't get to talk about, to the point that the words breaking news are trending on Twitter because of all this shit that's happening today.
Rym:  Well-- - But seriously, unfollow and block like anything that looks at you crosswise or makes you unhappy and your life will be a lot better, and we as a society are gonna need decades to sort out whether or not humans are capable of using social media safely.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott:  Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym:  Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym:  And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Heidi McNichol, Alan Joyce, Link Egy, Dreadlily, Tenebrae, Chris Rimer, Clinton, Walton, Dex, Finn, JustLikeADudeGuy, KaShiHi85, Rebecca Dunn, ReviewMadBull34, Cowards, Ryan Perrin, Sam Erickson, Shervin Von Harl, Taylor Braun, UndergroundProLaw, Ed O. Pierce, RightSeed, EbbThread, Open, You Hold The Key To My Heart, and a ton of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: Yes, as many of you reacted, I did, in fact, get an iPhone.
Rym: I'm using one right now.
Rym: Pretty much the same as Android at this point.
Rym: They fixed all the things that made it different, and the hardware's better because Sony doesn't make small smartphones anymore.
Rym: So yeah, I'll talk about what it was like to shift at some point, probably a future Monday episode, but for now, I leave you with.
Rym:  This can all be over if you just tell me what your bridge crew did.
Scott:  We can't tell you.
Rym:  Why, why?
Rym:  Because we don't know.
Rym: We never know anything.
Rym:  We're lower decks.
Rym: No one ever tells us what's going on.
Rym:  We're not important enough to have anything to lie to you about.
Scott:  You're Starfleet.
Rym: Surely you must be briefed on every contingency.
Scott:  Yeah, I wish.
Scott: The senior officers don't always have time to keep us up to speed.
Rym: Hell, sometimes they don't even know what's going on.
Scott:  Impossible!
Scott: Human lies!
Scott: You are the best of the best!
Rym: Your senior officers are always in full control.
Rym:  No, they're not.
Rym: They mess up all the time.
Rym: Like whenever Q shows up.
Rym:  Shut up.
Rym:  Voila!
Rym:  Damn you, Q!
Rym:  There he is.
Rym: Hey, buddy.
Rym:  We're half of Ransom's alien dates that he doesn't do any research for.
Rym:  You are so funny, Marianne.
Rym: How about we keep this party going in my quarters?
Scott:  Hey, hey, Jack.
Scott: FYI, you're hitting on a salt vampire.
Rym:  Yeah, right.
Rym: Nice try.
Scott: Salt vampires died out more than a century ago.
Rym:  All right.
Rym: Cool, be safe.
Scott:  Come on, Marianne.
Scott: Let's get out of here.
Scott: I'll give you the tour of Casa de Ransom.
Scott:  Ah!
Scott: Salt vampire!
Scott:  You're making this up.
Scott:  Nah, I read all their logs.
Scott: They're stepping in it all the time.
Scott:  Captain.
Rym: Captain, someone's replacing everyone on the ship with imposters who claim not to know me.
Rym: We might be in a parallel dimension.
Rym:  And you are?
Rym:  Uh, wait, is this, is this not the Cerritos?
Rym:  This is the Alhambra.
Rym: Did you get on the wrong ship?
Scott:  (beep) They all look the same.
Rym:  Why are you doing this to me?
Rym: I need you to tell me that your senior officers are infallible heroes.
Rym:  Well, they're not.
Rym: And that's okay.
Rym: We all joined Starfleet to dive head first into the unknown.
Rym: We're explorers.
Rym: Of course we don't always know what's going on.
Rym: Did Picard know about the Borg?
Rym: Did Kirk know about that giant Spock on Phylos?
Rym: Did Dr.
Scott: Crusher know about that ghost in the lamp thing from the Scottish planet that she hooked up with that one time?
Rym: That whole thing.
Rym: You clearly want us to say that the captain and her crew messed up, but we simply don't have the full story.
Rym: And that's the truth.
Rym: Whatever they did, I guarantee you it was all for good.
Rym: You have shown no evidence that they're guilty of a crime.
Rym: In fact, I find you guilty of trying to take them down with the sham of a trial.
Rym: Drumhead!