Rym: It's Monday, January 4th, 2021.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are talking about outages apropos of nothing.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: Oh, finally back from a very long, uh, breaky.
Rym: Oh, I gotta work.
Scott: Even though it feels like I'm back from a long break because today was my first day of work.
Scott: But actually we did GeekNights up through, we only skipped one GeekNights, a Thursday, right?
Scott: So it's actually not that long a break for the listener.
Rym: Yeah, and we only skipped that one because it was the actual New Year's, like New Year's Eve.
Rym: Yeah, okay.
Scott: So we chat talk a whole bunch about what we were going to do during the break.
Scott: What the fuck did we actually do?
Scott: We played some video games.
Scott: Podcasted.
Rym: Yep, I played a lot of video games.
Scott: Played a lot of video games.
Scott: So the one thing I actually did sort of work on a little, uh, you know, get the ball rolling on us.
Scott: for some reason, I think partially because of the advent of code thing, um, was I sort of like, you know, remembered why I like programming computers a little bit.
Scott: Because when I'm at work, the computer programming is Python Postgres, right?
Scott: It's, there's a web page, it sends in some stuff, you make some queries, it's SQL, you send out some JSON or whatever, right?
Scott: It's, you know, it's a lot of the same stuff and it's very high level programming.
Scott: There's no algorithms you got to worry about usually, right?
Scott: It's already implemented by someone else.
Scott: You just make, you know, you just take the magic words and put them in the right order.
Scott: That sort of thing.
Scott: And that's not that interesting, right?
Scott: That's not, you know, what makes you, you don't become a fan of computer programming doing that kind of stuff that businesses need using modern tools.
Rym: I'm sure there's someone out there, like.
Rym: I've met people who are weirdly passionate about that like type of weird enterprise-y technology stuff, but there aren't many.
Scott: Anyway, so I talked about before how I was, you know, I took my old computers off the shelf, right?
Scott: My Mac Plus and my Apple IIGS.
Scott: I upgraded them a little bit more.
Scott: I made them easier to use so I don't have to use old school floppy drives even though I have them and they work.
Scott: And they're working perfectly.
Scott: I upgraded them both.
Scott: It's amazing.
Scott: And basically I was like, well, what can I actually do with these things, right?
Scott: Besides, the only things you can really do with them are use the software that was created for them.
Scott: And some of those softwares you might want to use, like it's like, man, I could use like, you know, Microsoft works for a Mac and that's like from 1990 whatever.
Scott: That's actually kind of fun, but it's like, and it's kind of nice compared to the word processors we have today, like even Google Drive.
Rym: It's so weird to think back.
Rym: Like I, there was a time when I had a 486 that wasn't connected to any network, like couldn't even dial up yet.
Rym: And I would just sit there doing something on that computer for hours on end.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And like there are games for it, but the games for these things.
Scott: It's like Carmen Sandiego, probably the best game on the Mac Plus, I guess, that you can play.
Scott: Even with the four megabyte of RAM upgrade, a screen is black and white, right?
Scott: SimCity, I guess it plays.
Scott: SimCity one, you know, and it's like, even with the upgrades and everything, it's like, they're not that convenient and nice to use.
Scott: So with the upsides of the good feelings that you can get from some retro software, the difficulty of using them, it's like, even if I did use them, it's like getting the data that I even I wrote, like I wrote something.
Scott: Getting that writing off of that computer is a little bit of a hassle, not a huge one, but hassle enough, right?
Scott: What do you actually do with them is program them, right?
Scott: That's what you can do.
Scott: You can like make something, make them do something cool.
Scott: And that's the exciting activity you can do with these old computers.
Scott: And of course, though, in doing so, it's like, oh, right.
Scott: That's also kind of a hassle.
Scott: Not just, you know, learning the language, learning the architecture is fun and great.
Scott: You know, read, get an old Apple two GS assembly manual, read it.
Scott: It's like, you know, figure out its quirks.
Scott: That's not a problem, but it's like, all right, now go get that program into that computer and make it run it, debug it without, you know, it's like, you know, I complain about IDEs, but it's like, this isn't even like, you know, Vim shell situation.
Scott: This is way worse, right?
Scott: This is like, you can only see a few lines of text at a time, you know, with a basic listing situation.
Scott: It's not, it's not great.
Scott: once you've had modern conveniences.
Scott: But I sort of wanted, you know, I still got the feeling to like, hey, I want to make, you know, you know, if you think about making like modern software, like, you know, is not so exciting, right?
Scott: I want to make the old software, but I want to have the convenience while making the old style software of my current, you know, just at least shell and terminal and text editor, right?
Scott: Like it's 2020 or whatever.
Scott: And I went looking around and I was like, you know, there's those, I don't know how many people, there weren't too many like well-used programs outside of business that use these things.
Scott: Because I think most people at home who had DOS were like playing games, right?
Scott: Or using Windows 3.1 or whatever.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: There were very few non-game applications I would launch in DOS like on its own.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like in DOS, there were applications that sort of had a Windows-like GUI that was made with the ASCII characters.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: I had a lot of things that would like configure stuff that would do that.
Scott: For example, when you installed Wolfenstein 3D and it told you to choose what sound card you had, that sort of interface, right?
Scott: Or if you wanted to edit a text file, you edited your autoexec.bat using edit.exe in DOS, that thing.
Scott: And I was like, you know, there are a lot of programs that had that sort of DOS text UI.
Rym: Like a kind of ASCII character set UI.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: And I know that nowadays if you want to make that kind of UI, you would use like ncurses or something along those lines, right?
Scott: But those ncurses UIs, they don't look and feel the same as the old DOS ones.
Scott: They're not all blocky.
Scott: They're technically blocky, but they don't have that same feel.
Scott: So I was like, what did they use to make those, right?
Scott: That was before my time.
Scott: You know, I never made one of those.
Scott: They must have used some library to make those.
Rym: The closest I ever got is I made, I would make like command where it would ask you to like type an answer to something to do something.
Rym: But they were still just like, blah, blah, blah, yes, no.
Rym: And I type Y and then my script would continue.
Scott: So there were two things that people used that I found to make those in the DOS days for DOS specifically.
Scott: Those text-based GUIs that still had like file menus and status bars and desktops and windows and dialog boxes and all that shit, right?
Scott: One of them was something I never knew existed, which was Visual Basic for DOS.
Scott: Visual Basic for DOS came out after Windows Visual Basic came out.
Scott: And it's pretty amazing.
Scott: And the only thing I could find with it.
Scott: that was a problem, I got it to run in a Windows 3.1 DOS virtual box, no problem.
Scott: It totally works great.
Scott: The problem with it is that the applications it produces are not great to run on like a current computer, right?
Scott: So that was sort of like, that was like a really hopeful discovery.
Scott: That was sort of also a dead end, right?
Scott: You can't like, you know, put those on like your Linux box and run them.
Scott: So the other thing I found was, and this is the answer, this is my opening.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Was a thing that I knew the name was familiar, but I never, if you said ask me, what is the thing I'm about to say?
Scott: And then I could say, well, that's a thing I've heard of, but I don't know what the fuck it is.
Scott: It must be some programming thing.
Scott: It was a thing called Borland.
Scott: Remember Borland, they used to exist.
Scott: Borland TurboVision.
Rym: I think I've ever heard of that.
Scott: I've heard of a thing called Borland TurboVision, but I didn't actually know what the hell it was, right?
Scott: Borland TurboVision is a library Borland made for making those text based UIs.
Scott: If you Google image search Borland TurboVision, I guarantee you will know, at least someone your age, will know programs that look just like that.
Scott: And if they look just like that, they were made with Borland TurboVision.
Rym: Oh wow, the Pascal version was distributed alongside Borland Pascal.
Scott: That's correct.
Rym: On a bonus disc.
Rym: It was never released under a free license.
Scott: Indeed.
Scott: However, somebody on GitHub has a repository, TVision, which is basically an implementation of Borland TurboVision C++ library.
Scott: But you can compile and run it on Windows, Mac, or Linux and get your programs to build, no matter what, because it just relies on... It'll basically link to end curses or whatever the local text based GUI library is, but then you code as if you're coding Borland TurboVision C++ in 1990, whatever.
Scott: And this is very well... Borland TurboVision is very well documented.
Scott: The books are now just PDFs online.
Scott: They were probably really expensive books back in the day, or they came with the expensive software.
Scott: And I found all the example code online.
Scott: I found like everything.
Scott: So I haven't done C++ in a long time, but I found some good free C++ books that were probably really expensive back in the day to help remember what I haven't done C++ in like 15+ years.
Scott: Just gotta remember some syntax here and there and see what's changed since then.
Scott: I think they're on C++ version 17 now.
Scott: But I'm not aware of.
Scott: for anyone else who's like, "I don't want to speak too soon and shit talk," right?
Scott: But I feel like there's a lot of programs.
Scott: I've actually made some programs, but they don't have UIs, right?
Scott: It's just the processing part.
Scott: And it's like, if I really master this TurboVision thing, that could be my thing.
Rym: That could be your shit, like the wet bandits or the sticky bandits.
Scott: I can make games and all kinds of stuff.
Scott: Imagine you play like a HypnoSpace Outlaw, right?
Scott: I can make a game, but it just looks like Portland TurboVision instead of looking like HypnoSpace Outlaw.
Scott: And it's a lot of fun.
Scott: It's way more fun than my job.
Scott: And if I'm stuck inside, check it out.
Rym: Obviously the news that gave us the idea to do the show, everyone came back to work after the holiday and Slack wasn't fucking working this morning.
Scott: Yeah, at first I thought it was just an artifact of the fact that because I haven't used my work computer in a while, I was logged out of the single sign-on.
Rym: I think a lot of people took a while to realize that it was actually down for similar reasons.
Scott: So I tried to log into the single sign-on again and get Slack to open again.
Scott: The Slack windows app is just like one of those Electron web things.
Scott: So I clicked on a link in it to go to the Slack status page, but then the whole app was stuck on that page.
Scott: There was no way for me to reload or escape from that.
Scott: So I had to uninstall the whole Slack app because I couldn't clear its cache because its menu wasn't appearing in the app.
Scott: And then I figured out, yeah, all of Slack is down.
Scott: It was down for several hours.
Scott: It was completely 100% down.
Scott: And this totally reminds me of that time where Blizzard launched a Diablo game, I think it was Diablo 3, and then they went down.
Scott: I said this, we were talking about it earlier, I worked at a website called Broadway.com.
Scott: We knew during the Tony Awards, we're broken Broadway.com.
Scott: That's our time.
Scott: That's the time for us.
Scott: We know what business you're in, you know what your time is.
Scott: If you're working at NFL.com, you know the Super Bowl is your fucking time.
Scott: That's your time that you don't go down.
Scott: You don't mess with shit.
Scott: You add extra servers, you increase your whatever you gotta do.
Scott: You know when your time is.
Scott: Stop uploading code.
Scott: This is January 4th.
Scott: The first day people come back to work after a break.
Scott: And Slack knows who they are.
Scott: They've been around for years.
Scott: They're not brand new.
Scott: They know that they should know.
Scott: this is your day.
Scott: Nobody is using their vacation day today.
Scott: Everyone has a lot of messages from the past month they haven't read stacked up.
Scott: So when they log in, they're gonna need to load a whole bunch.
Scott: And they fucked it up.
Scott: And whoever is responsible deserves, you know, they deserve negative consequences.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see.
Rym: But we're not gonna get into outages because that's the main bit that we'll talk about in detail.
Scott: No, we're talking about this outage.
Rym: But this outage, things like this happen not that often actually in the modern world.
Scott: They're happening less.
Scott: Like back in the early days of Twitter, they'd be like "the whale", right?
Scott: I think the only site that's had a lot of outages more recently is Reddit.
Scott: Reddit has problems.
Rym: Yeah, I guess I've noticed that.
Scott: And there was like a brief YouTube outage somewhat recently.
Rym: It was a weird outage because of the way it manifested.
Rym: It seemed like YouTube was working, but then videos would like play a little bit and then peter out.
Scott: Yeah, but outages like these are getting increasingly rare.
Scott: And this one was long and complete.
Scott: Like, mega.
Rym: Yeah, but I guess one takeaway you can think about is think about how many companies you wouldn't otherwise think about use Slack for something critical and how many people literally just cannot do their jobs without it.
Scott: Yeah, it took a while for my coworker to figure out we could use Google Chat.
Scott: And I think other people did the same thing as well.
Rym: We actually have like fallback plans of like, if X is down, here is like the two other tools in order that people will like devolve to.
Rym: And that works okay.
Scott: I mean, we really needed to.
Scott: We could have emailed, right?
Rym: Just pick Google.
Rym: That's cheap.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But yeah, I was actually surprised, but also I was disappointed and surprised in this outage because the Slack status page.
Scott: Companies, I complain about this all the time.
Scott: They have status pages that are always up.
Scott: I've never seen a status page go down, so they're doing a good job with that.
Scott: But the status pages always seem to A, update late, right?
Scott: Relative to when the outage happens.
Scott: And B, under report, right?
Scott: They'll have like a yellow triangle when it's clearly red X, right?
Scott: You know, Amazon is the worst at this.
Scott: Like S3 will be down.
Scott: And you'll go to the Amazon 3 status page and they'll be like, S3, yellow triangle in like one region.
Scott: And it's like, no, I don't even work there.
Scott: And I know that you are red X in all of this.
Scott: I've already figured this out, right?
Scott: You're lying.
Scott: And are you 10 minutes later, they still have an update.
Rym: There's a bunch of reasons for that.
Rym: And some of them have to do with like contract stuff where depending on what you say, like there can be Clovax and contracts.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, if you fuck up, then get Clovax.
Rym: At the same time, what if your site is oversensitive and it says there was an outage that there wasn't, someone could still claw back saying you officially notified us that there was an outage.
Scott: Well, there must have been some sort of problem if it did that, even if it's overly sensitive.
Rym: I think false positives in enterprise monitoring are more common than false negatives.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: That's a gut feeling I have.
Rym: I don't have anything to back that up.
Rym: That's a gut feeling.
Rym: Also, my perspective is heavily skewed by being in capital markets, which is its own world.
Scott: Even so, I saw Slack, A, during this outage, they were slow.
Scott: I knew that they were out completely everywhere with everything.
Scott: And their status page was showing the yellow triangle for, or actually showed nothing for a while.
Scott: Then it showed the yellow triangle.
Scott: But they did eventually go to, I guess they don't have red X, they have red circle with white line in the middle.
Scott: And they eventually did go to that across the board for all of their little, you know, app.
Rym: Well, Slack also, they went public recently.
Rym: I don't think that affected their stock.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm really, really curious what they messed up to be down, not only on the critical day, but for such a large amount of time with the amount of engineering resources they must have.
Rym: It's like no one put out a patch or pushed out some code to production like New Year's Eve.
Scott: And if you look at their status page, there might be new information.
Scott: I haven't read before the show.
Scott: But if you looked at their status page, where they updated every half hour as to what they knew, like the first four updates, they didn't know a damn thing.
Scott: So that was two hours, they just didn't know what the hell was going on.
Rym: Verge only has two updates on the story.
Rym: The first one saying they updated to say that it's a full outage.
Rym: And then another one saying the service may be returning to some users and then nothing.
Scott: You know how I'm going to.
Scott: there's two.
Scott: there's two ways I tell if something is down.
Scott: Well, three ways.
Scott: There's a website is up dot me.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Which is a good website.
Rym: But at the same time, I have seen people who don't really know technology go to that website and make really, really like ridiculous assumptions from what they see there.
Scott: There's down detector, which which is where people self report, like a thing is down for me.
Scott: And if enough people self report, then you can sort of infer that like it must be down for a lot of people if it is this many people.
Scott: And it's pretty accurate, actually.
Scott: And then there's Twitter, where I just search Slack down or YouTube down.
Rym: Twitter is my go to for that unless Twitter's down.
Scott: I sort by latest.
Scott: And if I see that there's a lot of recent tweets saying that a thing is down, it's probably down.
Scott: So with that in mind, if I'm a company, right, what I'm going to do is I'm going to set up some sort of thing that monitors Twitter and searches for the name of my app down down.
Scott: And if it suddenly sees over a certain threshold of tweets saying is my thing down in the very least, like opens a ticket for someone to go take a look.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Like if I'm if I run Gmail, I'm at Google.
Scott: And if I see a lot of tweets that say is Gmail down and that I'll see what the baseline is when I know we're up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then I'll set a threshold.
Scott: And if the number of tweets saying is Gmail down goes over the threshold, that's how we know.
Rym: So you want to know something funny?
Rym: Because we don't like Scott, I don't talk about our jobs that much.
Rym: We talk about the tech we use, but not like our actual jobs.
Rym: Most of my career has been around that kind of monitoring and alerting of outages in large enterprise environments.
Rym: Like that's what I was doing from IBM onward is that kind of thing.
Rym: And in my professional opinion, most companies on earth have garbage for detecting problems, let alone correcting them.
Rym: Nobody has good monitoring.
Rym: No one.
Rym: Only I basically my life.
Rym: I'm not going to lie that I thought basically adequate monitoring.
Rym: And you know why they had adequate monitoring?
Rym: They spent way more money than they should have.
Rym: If they'd spent less money on that monitoring, they probably would have been fine.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: We have basically more than, you know, we have basically okay monitoring, right?
Scott: It's like we basically set up at work.
Scott: We have some software as a service monitoring thing.
Scott: We install it.
Scott: We set it up.
Rym: What do you use, like New Relic or something?
Rym: I forget what all the options are.
Scott: I think it's a different one.
Scott: But basically it posts on Slack in a channel when things go over.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Whatever they're supposed to be.
Scott: And then people actually do.
Scott: It's calibrated pretty well.
Scott: So that like you don't usually ignore when it posts in there.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Because that's the cardinal sin of that kind of monitoring.
Rym: If it's noisy, no one will ever pay attention to it.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: Something's really down.
Scott: Pretty much anytime something gets posted from the bots, the monitoring bot in the Slack channel, I see like other people being like, hey, so and so, what's up with this?
Scott: That's right.
Scott: They take action on it.
Rym: I mean, my like guiding force is like the statements of how to do good monitoring are very simple.
Rym: Alerts must be actionable.
Rym: They must be stateful, meaning if the problem resolves itself, they clear.
Rym: They must be accurate.
Rym: They must have a high signal to noise ratio.
Rym: And if you can't meet all of those four things, that is not something you should be alerting on because you don't understand the problem sufficiently.
Scott: And then we have whenever.
Scott: we basically whenever I set up anything on Oz, I set up CloudWatch.
Scott: And we sort of I sort of set up two levels of CloudWatch.
Scott: There's the level that's for, you know, the monitoring and the Slack posting and the actionable items.
Scott: And then there's like a debug level that doesn't obviously alert anyone about anything.
Scott: But that way I can go and check it because I have to make the software work and have to see that.
Rym: The real key to all that these days is like in the old days, people would set up that monitoring software, but they pick like specific indicators and make rules about it.
Rym: The modern way to do it that very few people are doing, like it's an area where machine learning could and should be applied, but weirdly isn't in most cases, is just to detect anomalies and not worry about what those anomalies are and use that to determine if things are down.
Scott: So just basically here's every single metric.
Scott: OK, I guarantee for you here is a sample of data for all metrics that is stable.
Rym: Here's my last year of operational data and I flagged where there were problems.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then if you see anything out of these that's out of the ordinary for this data, let me know.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Let a human know whose job is to decide if there's a real problem and decide what to do.
Scott: And if they say no, then don't alert about that amount again.
Rym: Well, that's the use of train the model.
Rym: That will literally be input into the model.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Unless it's statistically significant from whatever they said is OK already.
Scott: You know, like there were two database connections for the whole year.
Scott: We added a third thing that connects to the database and alerts.
Scott: There's a third database connection.
Rym: You know how much of my career has been telling people to do what I just said in the course of my life?
Rym: Machine learning has been around for a long time, and this is a pretty easy application of it with like baby's first M.L.
Rym: algorithms, like stuff you could have written in Python.
Scott: Let's Google to see if anyone does that and then see what they're up to.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But anyway, moving on to some other news that's actually really, really important and we should pay attention to this.
Rym: A whole bunch of Google employees just unionized.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: A Silicon Valley union.
Rym: This is a big goddamn deal.
Rym: It is a ridiculous myth.
Rym: And in fact, it's almost like propaganda coming from tech companies telling people like the line is usually you don't deserve a union.
Rym: Look how much better you're paid than like a coal miner.
Rym: Like that is the typical like propaganda of why you shouldn't unionize.
Scott: But a lot of anti-union propaganda.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Unions are pretty much a benefit to society for almost like I cannot stress to you enough.
Rym: Every reason why you don't just die on the job today is because there was a union.
Rym: at some point if you live in America.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much like five day work week, 40 hour work week unions basically busted skulls to get that kind of literally.
Scott: And we can get more.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, they should get more.
Scott: Those were those are compromises.
Scott: We can get more than that if we would just unionize again.
Scott: But yeah, when it comes out, just no matter where you work, whether you work at a little tiny place with, you know, or you work at a big company, almost every company in the United States is some sort of autocracy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They're not usually democracies.
Rym: There are very few companies that are just like a co-op.
Scott: There's some employee owned companies.
Scott: There's some co-ops.
Scott: They're not many.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's usually there's some kind of boss who has literally all the power or shareholders that have all the power and employees are basically just you.
Scott: You're not a slave.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because you can obviously quit.
Scott: You're not being treated.
Scott: Don't even try to compare it to slavery.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not even close.
Scott: But you're basically you have.
Scott: you have a choice.
Scott: You can continue to work there or not.
Scott: You're free to go.
Scott: And if you choose to stay, you and you want to continue to stay and get money, you got to do what they say or they could make you leave against your will.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then that's your choice.
Scott: So you have no power if your boss says sweep the floor and you say, you know, I only want to clean dishes.
Scott: I don't want to sweep floors.
Rym: I was working at the bellows in Rochester in college because I was desperate for money, making like seven bucks an hour.
Rym: And one day someone, I think the technical term is caused a shitstorm in the toilet.
Rym: And I walked in and saw it and I walked out and I told the manager and basically he was like, all right, go clean it up.
Rym: And I said, I'll quit if you actually make me do that right now.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And he went to someone else and he basically no one is willing to do it.
Rym: So finally he was like, anyone who cleans that bathroom is allowed to leave as soon as they're done and will get paid as though they worked 10 hours today.
Rym: And one girl was like, I'll do it.
Rym: But yeah, I would have quit and I would have had no recourse if I didn't want to do that.
Rym: They could have fired me.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Scott: I mean, they could fire you anyway.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Most states you can be fired for any non-protected reason at any time.
Rym: You can be fired because someone doesn't like you.
Rym: And that's totally legal.
Scott: Even if your job is fantastic, like my job is fantastic.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, relatively speaking, it's not.
Rym: I mean, relatively speaking, my job is also fantastic.
Scott: I have way less complaints than pretty much everyone I know.
Scott: Everyone else has more complaints about their job and valid ones than I have.
Scott: basically none of those complaints.
Rym: All my complaints are things that capitalism cannot accommodate, like I want to work less.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: You know, so the point is that even in my workplace, it's like, well, you know, somebody asked, right, the CEO of like the last meeting, like, how about a four day work week?
Scott: How's that sound?
Scott: And he was like, nothing's off the table.
Scott: That's the kind of, you know, they gave that sort of not answer answer, right?
Scott: He didn't say yes, didn't say no.
Scott: But if we had a union, we could instead say four day work week or a tough shit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's what we could say.
Scott: So and we even at my work where you can say things like, how about a four day work weeks, Mr.
Scott: CEO?
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, we have that level of goodness where I am.
Scott: We can't say give it to us or else.
Scott: But if we got a union, then we could say that.
Scott: Even though our situation is so good, union just makes it better because you're always getting screwed out of something in capitalism as long as the boss is, you know, just in charge and has power.
Rym: That said, there are a lot of outward problems with unions that are really just reflections of capitalism and cronyism and such like.
Rym: the example we always use is convention centers where because of union rules, like I can't plug in my own camera without paying them $150.
Rym: And then I'm not allowed to operate my own camera.
Rym: A camera person who is paid by the convention center by law has to operate my camera.
Rym: If I operate my camera, I can get sued or kicked out and all sorts of problems.
Scott: So that's not a problem with.
Scott: that says like, oh, unions are bad.
Rym: That's a problem where the government in that area is making up jobs from nothing to try to avoid the problems of capitalism with the corrupt convention center build in the first place.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And, you know, the union itself, you know, has to operate, you know, they were in back in the day.
Scott: And I think this actually is what also hurt not only the propaganda, but also what hurt a lot of unions was the unions relations with organized crime.
Rym: Well, also weird stuff, like a lot of unions in the past four years were against Medicare for all for reasons that boiled down to the union got their workers good health care.
Rym: So why should we push for something different than the union to get us anything?
Rym: That's a terrible argument.
Scott: That's also there used to be more solidarity of, you know, unions and all people instead of this sort of competitive, you know, competitive greed, you know, not caring about other people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They were just.
Scott: we're trying to get as much as they could for their people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They didn't care about anyone else.
Scott: That same that same idea hurts all of our society, whether that idea is held by a union or by an individual.
Rym: There can also be very dysfunctional unions like that can happen because if you've ever done local politics or, say, volunteered for a convention or been on a board, like people are just so full of ridiculous drama and incompetence that it's kind of amazing sometimes.
Rym: And that same thing will happen with unions.
Rym: Like there's no way around that.
Rym: That's just how people are.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Scott: But that doesn't mean that unions are bad.
Scott: It's a Google having a union.
Scott: if they get way more people to sign union cards and such to where to get to the point where they can collectively bargain with the executives of Google.
Scott: I think that that will have actually, depending on the numbers and what that bargaining deal looks like, that could have a huge impact on the whole world.
Scott: Because suddenly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: No longer will the search engine that powers the earth or at least a lot of the earth, I guess not in Russia, they use what Yandex and in China, they got their QQ or whatever.
Rym: I mean, Google should be broken up.
Rym: That's a whole separate conversation, obviously.
Scott: But a very large thing that is so powerful.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That no one person should be allowed to control it.
Scott: It should be democratically controlled, will be more not democratically controlled, but more demographically controlled, and that more people will have a say.
Scott: In its functioning.
Scott: And that will be for the benefit of all people.
Rym: But all that said, honestly, unions are still just a Band-Aid over the root problem, which is American capitalism.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much like unions are just a Band-Aid over these far more fundamental structural problems that are topic for another show.
Rym: Do you want to talk about the deep use?
Scott: We can talk about deep use another time.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Then it's time for.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: So, you know, on YouTube, we love that lock picking lawyer, right?
Scott: Picking all them locks, channels interest, making us interested in watching lock picking, even though that's not a hobby that I'm personally interested in.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I'm not even interested enough to, like, go buy one of those practice locks or anything.
Rym: I'm moderately interested.
Rym: I wish I was picking.
Rym: I was picking the lock on my office at IBM a lot because I was bored.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You know, if I bought one, it would just.
Scott: it would just go next to the harmonica.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So at least, you know, at least it's small, I guess.
Scott: Anyway, but it's really interesting to watch.
Scott: I learned a lot about locks, which is fun and fascinating for a nerd to learn about.
Scott: But we can't use lock picking lawyer for thing of the day again.
Scott: So instead, what I've got is this other channel with a video that has six point three million views.
Scott: So you've probably seen it already.
Scott: But if you haven't, this person on this stuff made here YouTube channel made a lock that is, perhaps, unbelievable.
Scott: Unpickable in quotes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because as lock picking lawyer says, nothing's unpickable.
Scott: It just means I can't pick it yet.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But the principle and the fundamental principle is one that even I thought of just watching lock picking videos is that when you're picking a lock.
Scott: Right.
Scott: What you do is you're trying to line up pins or cylinders or disks or levers or whatever it is in a particular configuration.
Rym: They're basically a password.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's basically a password.
Scott: The key is a thing that moves the.
Scott: you know, whatever they are in the lock, whatever kind of lock you have.
Scott: Into a certain position so that they're just unlocked.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And if you're picking a lock, what you're doing is manually moving each one into the right position until the lock unlocks.
Scott: And the way that you figure out when they're in the right position is basically you bind the lock.
Scott: So you like if it was a key lock, you would try to basically apply turning, you know, some, you know, some tension.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Try to turn the lock.
Scott: And that way you turn the lock, you move the pins up and down.
Scott: And you can tell if you've got it in the right spot because when they line up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The locks are not machined so perfectly.
Scott: You know, you turn a little bit and it's like the pin will sort of rest on the edge there.
Scott: You can turn it a little bit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And all you need to do is turn it a little bit.
Scott: And that just creates a space for the pin to sort of sit on the ledge.
Scott: And eventually you get all the pins to sit on the ledge and you can turn it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you could somehow in my thinking was like, well, just make a lock that's so precisely machined that you can't turn it even one micron.
Scott: And that way you could never know if the pin was in the right position unless they were all in the right position.
Rym: Or at that point you make a purely electronic lock.
Rym: that's literal just modern cryptography and no access to any components.
Scott: People do do that.
Scott: Those locks are great.
Rym: And also the way most people attack a door is not to pick the lock.
Scott: Obviously.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: That is also true.
Scott: The physical security is and lock picking lawyer doesn't hide that from you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So what this person did was even more ingenious in that, you know, when you're picking a lock normally.
Scott: You can pick.
Scott: you can figure out one pin at a time.
Scott: So that would be like, imagine if I had to figure out your password and I could be like, is the first letter a, how about B?
Scott: How about C?
Scott: Right.
Scott: I'd only have to guess 26 different, you know, I guess in plus numbers, plus whatever.
Scott: But I would get the first letter pretty quickly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then I've got that one locked in so I can just go to the next one and actually won't be that many guesses until I get it all right, because I can do one letter at a time.
Scott: But that's not how passwords work on a computer.
Scott: You have to get all.
Scott: it's either all or nothing.
Scott: You have to get everything right or you just get a wrong.
Scott: You can't.
Scott: It's not like friggin, you know, Wheel of Fortune here.
Scott: It doesn't.
Scott: it doesn't work like that.
Scott: This lock he made is basically the anti Wheel of Fortune lock.
Scott: You basically raise the pins.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then you turn the lock, but they pass through a gate that's far away from where you lifted them.
Scott: So while you're doing the lifting, you can't tell if you've lifted them the right amount.
Scott: You have to lift all of them to the correct amount before they'll pass through that gate all the way to the side.
Scott: And there's no way that I can think of at least for you to know.
Scott: So you have to get them all right.
Scott: You can't be like got the first one, got the second one.
Scott: You can't do that with this lock.
Scott: Very fascinating.
Scott: You can see the struggles they go through to produce the lock, which is there's no way I don't think this can be easily mass produced.
Scott: At least no one's someone have to make like a new kind of machine to do it or something.
Rym: There's a reason why a lot of the, quote, unpickable locks are bespoke.
Scott: Yeah, this is definitely bespoke, but very fascinating video here.
Scott: And I recommend watching at least, you know, one video about like, you know, basic normal lock functioning before watching this one.
Scott: It'll it'll mean a lot more.
Rym: I love watching the locksmith actually try to open this lock because he's basically just like trying to rake it, trying to bump it, like all the basic stuff.
Scott: He's doing all the things that would work on a normal lock.
Rym: Because most locks, like any lock in any random house, you can probably just bump key with zero problem.
Scott: Yeah, that locksmith that they call to come and pick the unpickable lock, you know, is a skilled locksmith.
Scott: Yeah, maybe not lock being lawyer level, but they know what they're doing.
Rym: So, uh, my thing of the day, this, I ran into this kind of randomly and it was, it was a topic I knew a little bit about because my grandpa, his job, like after World War, after the World War and all the nonsense, like he was back home and got a job like in the civilian community.
Rym: He worked as a typesetter at an old fashioned newspaper, the Macomb Daily.
Rym: So his job was literally to set the type and like do the press work for an old style newspaper.
Scott: Old school metal bits.
Rym: It was obsolete by the time I was old enough to see it in person.
Rym: And in fact, I remember he took, he and the family, like we went to the Macomb Daily ones as they were planning to shut it all down because they want to take a bunch of pictures with him because he was like the last living person who did this job.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, sure they switched to a digital process, right?
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: In fact, I remember this very like poignant moment when I was a little kid and I came home from school and I showed grandpa this essay I had written.
Rym: This was in like third grade.
Rym: I want to say maybe fourth grade.
Rym: I read it on a computer and I printed it at school.
Rym: I brought it home and I showed it to grandpa and he said that literally just put me out of a job forever.
Rym: That is amazing.
Rym: But basically in the 19th century, so the 1800s, you might notice if you look at newspapers, there's a lot of ASCII art all of a sudden, even though ASCII didn't exist yet because typesetting was complicated.
Rym: And basically people started to be clever and they do things like submit a classified ad to the paper, but the type they would submit was ASCII art that would make an ad that was way bigger than the single font size they were allowed to use.
Rym: And it was a whole thing.
Rym: So this tweet has a bunch of like amazing examples.
Rym: Like one of them is a picture from the, what is this?
Rym: This is like, what year is this?
Rym: This is the December 6th, 1880 edition of the Brooklyn Daily Eagle.
Rym: And you go to the classifieds and there's like this giant ad in the middle of the classifieds that is composed of like 20 different smaller classified ads that all link together in a big ASCII art.
Rym: And there's an article I'm also going to link to.
Rym: that sort of gets into how and why this happened.
Rym: And it seems to come down to.
Rym: there was like one company, Brooklyn Furniture Company, that did it first.
Rym: And then everyone else was like, what?
Rym: We could do this?
Rym: And started being a giant pain in the ass to all the newspapers after that.
Rym: And it was made obsolete by this concept, which I'm not going to explain, called hot metal typesetting.
Rym: But it was basically, it was the next form of typesetting.
Rym: There were multiple competing versions after the like just loose like characters thing.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know anything about it.
Rym: Basically, it meant you could have more font sizes and like it was easier to do like more complex layouts, meaning this kind of thing was obsolete.
Rym: But there was a brief time when people were making ridiculous high quality ASCII art in newspapers to game the system.
Rym: And it's kind of amazing.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: In the meta moment, it's 2021 and guess what?
Rym: We're still stuck at home.
Scott: Well, hopefully we'll only be stuck at home for maybe half of 2021, maybe a little bit more than that.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I'm currently, my current estimation is that two thirds of the way through the year, I've got a better than 50% shot of going outside.
Scott: 51%.
Scott: That's my estimation right now based on.
Rym: Because once I'm vaccinated, like I'll still wear a mask in public because I could spread it and like there's a lot of.
Scott: You got to get, you got to get, you got to get daddy too.
Scott: One is not enough, right?
Scott: I'm not, if I get the one, I'm not going.
Rym: But when I am vaccinated, as in fully vaccinated, I got the full course.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: I got to get number two and then I got to wait a few weeks.
Rym: But then I'm only going to get together without masks in private settings with other people who have also gotten the full course.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And people who I trust not to be morons.
Rym: And that is when ReviewCon will happen.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then I think maybe it would have to be very late 2021, like maybe PAX Unplugged earliest possible.
Scott: And that's even a shot.
Rym: Because the problem is a convention might happen when vaccines are available and a lot of people are vaccinated.
Rym: But there's a lot of Americans who don't want to get vaccinated, which is a big problem.
Rym: And as a result, it will mean that we also have to wear masks to protect these idiots who refuse to get vaccinated.
Rym: But during that time period, if there's a convention and it requires masks, I wouldn't go because it's not safe to the people who are stupid and refusing to get the vaccine.
Rym: And also, can you imagine how much of a pain in the ass it would be to wear a mask for like an entire PAX?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, it's not.
Scott: I mean, you know, medical people wear masks all day.
Scott: People work in mines and stuff.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: But if I'm like getting board gaming con rather than wear a mask all day, I'll just stay home and play board games with people.
Rym: I don't need to wear masks around.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's, you know, it's not.
Scott: I think it's, you know, I just don't want to make mask wearing like a big deal.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: It's like requiring masks.
Rym: We got to get to the point to where masks are no longer required to protect society.
Scott: But if it's so dangerous that I have to wear a mask, why would I risk going there in the first place?
Scott: That's the thing.
Rym: The first cons we go to will be cons where it is safe to attend without wearing a mask.
Rym: Until that time, I'm not going to any big events.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So you can see if you can stay home, you can read the book club book, which is A Tale of Genji, the first novel ever written by human beings that we have not continued to read at all.
Rym: I'm reading more and more nonfiction right now.
Scott: I'm reading C++ book.
Rym: I'm also reading the rest of Chainsaw Man so we can review it on Wednesday.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Ooh, spoilers.
Scott: Wednesday episode of GeekNights, Chainsaw Man, the manga.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So let's get right into it.
Rym: There is the outages, the slag, it gave us an idea.
Rym: Now, funnily, the listener pointed out right away on the stream, they've misread the title of this episode at first as Outrages and were excited about it.
Scott: I don't know what tech outrages are.
Rym: I mean, that could be a good Thursday show.
Rym: The concept of outrage.
Rym: Things that outrage us.
Scott: A lot of things anyway.
Scott: But no, we can talk about outages in a more generic sense.
Scott: So you got your computer systems and you fuck something up and now they're just like not fucking working.
Rym: Sucks.
Rym: But it's fascinating because like this is a relatively like for normal people who do not work like in factories or in technologist places where like this is a thing.
Rym: For a long time until relatively recently, technology outages did not impact most people.
Rym: Like the impacts were very localized to like a particular business or the effects of the outages were delayed.
Rym: Like there'd be a big problem somewhere.
Rym: And as a result, my RAM is more expensive for two months.
Rym: But it was like there weren't that many people using social media.
Rym: There weren't like Netflix's and YouTube's and all these things online.
Rym: And a lot of corporations still use mostly internal or homegrown or analog solutions.
Scott: I wonder historically, I don't know historically, right, where the first outages must have been like water supply outage, like a drought or like a power outage.
Rym: I mean, I guess we could consider a drought an outage.
Rym: Like all the Mattawan reservoirs dry.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's still like the system as just completely stopped.
Rym: A technology, a practically applied technology system used by the average citizen that is now not functioning due to an acute and temporary problem.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And, you know, you could think of an outage is like my one.
Scott: TV broke, but that's not really.
Scott: that's just a you know, it's not big enough.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But like TV, like during broadcast TV days, the broadcast antennas messed up like TV is out.
Rym: I remember there were TV outages like I remember when I was a kid, like one of the local networks just went down for like three days.
Scott: The telephone network is not working.
Scott: You can't make a phone call right now.
Scott: It's not your fault.
Scott: Like there's an out like the whole system that applies to many people is broken in such a way that it is completely nonfunctional, not just like a little messed up.
Scott: But like it is just might as well not even exist right now until it's fixed.
Scott: Something is mad messed up.
Rym: Now, one thing that's really changed in this space in the like the current era is that previously most systems that a normal non specialist person interacted with were designed and managed to a degree by engineers, often with regulations and certifications and rules.
Rym: And most Internet things have no like.
Rym: the word engineer barely applies to what that like what is done to make those systems work.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And that's not to say that like, you know, everyone working for like, you know, your local power utilities on the grid is some sort of, you know, genius, amazing engineer, even though many, many are.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, you know, there's a they have all sorts of procedures and protocols and things they've learned and, you know, the things that they follow.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Like I used to work in factory automation, like I worked in a fab, like there were like very clear procedures for outages and failures of that machinery.
Scott: And since the outages are such a big deal and the system is so old, however old it is, depending on where you are.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like they really got their shit together.
Scott: Outages are really rare and only happen if there's like somewhat extreme circumstances.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Like trains don't crash into each other often in America and haven't for a long time.
Rym: They're starting to again because their infrastructure is falling apart.
Scott: Yeah, they do too often, but once is too often.
Scott: But yeah, it's not that often.
Rym: And then there was remember the great Northeast power outage?
Scott: Yeah, that was.
Scott: But it's like since then, how many outages have there been?
Scott: I don't think I've had at least in my apartment, even during.
Rym: I've never lost power for even a second in the 10 years I've lived here.
Scott: Yeah, we've lost power, I think a little bit in Beacon, I think.
Scott: But I don't think we've ever, I've never lost power.
Rym: There's a photo you took of me reading a Penny Arcade comic with the light, like I was holding up a flashlight and reading a Penny Arcade comic in the dark.
Scott: But yeah, in New York City, I've never had a power outage.
Scott: There have been times where the lights have flickered or like a little mu.
Scott: I guess that counts as a brownout, but like a one second brownout.
Scott: That's not a big deal.
Rym: I've had a couple of localized service outages where like my router was dying, but that only affected me.
Scott: Oh yeah, sure.
Scott: Stuff like that.
Scott: There have been some internet outages that they were kind of brief, even with shitty Spectrum.
Scott: I've never had one with FiOS.
Rym: But I guess this concept, like to talk about it in a practical way, there's a few lenses to look at.
Rym: One lens is, are you on the inside or on the outside?
Rym: Like if you work for a power company or like Slack and something goes down, that is one lens of an outage compared to I'm some jerk trying to turn on my light and the light doesn't work because the power's out.
Rym: And then the other lens is, what is the scale?
Rym: Like the server that runs.
Rym: the spreadsheet stuff that you use to manage your local business only affects your business and maybe like your local customers.
Rym: But Slack going down affected the entire world for several hours.
Scott: Yep, yep, yep.
Scott: And yeah, but the point that Rym was making before, Slack doesn't have, you know, I'm sure they do have their procedures and things set up.
Rym: But they do not have like formal engineering practices.
Scott: I don't, they could, but I doubt it, right?
Rym: I highly doubt that.
Scott: I'm talking engineering.
Rym: the same way that electrical and municipal engineers have certifications and practices.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They're not set up in that way that the power company is, and that's why they can have a several hour outage.
Scott: They're also not a, the kind of thing where, I mean, I guess lives are sort of indirectly on the line, but not the same way that they're on the line of the hospital.
Rym: And that's why I like don't do, I don't, we're not saying that every internet service needs to have that level of formal engineering and processes and procedures, but that line is a big gray area.
Rym: And sometimes the consequences of an outage in something that you wouldn't think is consequential can be scarily broad or dangerous.
Scott: You can also see, you know, just from what I know about tech companies is that, you know, Netflix always talks about, they have this thing called the, like the chaos monkey, where it basically randomly intentionally goes around their production infrastructure, just wreaking havoc, right?
Scott: All the time.
Scott: And then what they did is over time, they would design, you know, basically their production infrastructure to basically survive, even while the chaos monkey is running.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like they turn on the chaos monkey.
Scott: It goes and turns servers off.
Scott: It blocks network connections.
Scott: It does all sorts of, it fills up hard drives.
Scott: It pretends like hard drives.
Scott: It does all sorts of ridiculous stuff.
Scott: And Netflix doesn't go down even when they're intentionally trying to make it go down with this chaos monkey.
Scott: and Netflix doesn't have a lot of outages.
Scott: So there do I, you know, from my, in my professional opinion, they're doing, they're doing something right over there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, uh, I guess Amazon doesn't have outages either, but YouTube has outages.
Scott: Slack has outages.
Scott: Facebook has some Twitter.
Rym: Twitter's gone down every now and then.
Rym: And my instinct is always to try to go tweet about it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Twitter used to go way down.
Scott: Remember the whale?
Scott: The whale is a big deal back in the day.
Scott: Twitter people nowadays don't know about the whale.
Scott: Reddit has a ton of outages.
Scott: They're awful.
Rym: Let's go from the inside first.
Rym: Cause you know, this is Monday GeekNights and a lot of you are probably technologists or wannabe technologists.
Rym: Like you want to have jobs similar to what me and Scott do.
Rym: So we can, we'll go from like small scale to like large, like in your house outages all the way up to like enterprise service provider outages.
Rym: Cause there's like the types of concerns you have.
Rym: If you work for a company like that are radically different depending on the scale of that company's operation.
Scott: Like, I mean, you know, anything small enough to where it can wait till you get back to work is basically no big deal.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And a lot of businesses operate that way.
Rym: Like, Oh no, the credit card processing system in our local store is down.
Rym: We have a backup process to charge credit cards.
Scott: Cash only.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Or, or I don't know if they still require it, but for a long time.
Scott: I'll use the, I'll use the square app on my phone.
Rym: Well, I was about to say, I don't know if it's still required because I can Google it during this episode, but for a long time, businesses had to have that, uh, the old, uh, impression system to take impressions of the credit cards as a backup.
Rym: Cause they had to be able to take the credit card, even if the system was down.
Rym: But I don't, I think some of that got deregulated and changed over the years.
Rym: I, I don't, I'm not an expert in that like local space, but if you work for a company like that, it really comes down to, does it impact like your job or the company's bottom line right now, or will it impact it later?
Rym: And then it's around, do you detect these problems automatically?
Rym: And do you know what to do to correct these kinds of problems?
Rym: And honestly, that's the kind of situation where you are probably the only technologist in that entire company.
Rym: Like small companies will have like one tech person who handles all of that.
Rym: So it's really in your best interest, like in those situations, you don't have to worry about all this enterprise nonsense.
Rym: You don't need like a website hosted somewhere else that'll tell like the people who might come to your submarine sandwich shop that you have an outage or anything.
Rym: You pretty much just got to come up with like processes to make sure that you are not personally woken up in the middle of the night by anything.
Rym: And that is it.
Rym: Like that is your only goal is to not get woken up at night and never be called when you're not in the office.
Scott: When I was responsible for setting up such systems and making sure they're not down, I pretty much set them up perfectly, like handcrafted perfections that nothing would ever go wrong and nothing ever went wrong.
Scott: Because I absolutely would not have anyone messaging me when I was not at work.
Scott: And I left at five every day.
Scott: I did it right.
Scott: Even though we did not use all these engineering practices or whatever, we just basically relied on my knowledge of how to set it up in a way that didn't suck and trust in the things that we were using from third parties that they would be high quality and several layers of fallbacks.
Rym: Pretty much comes down to knowing where are the critical links and the thing you're responsible for and what are the things that are likely to go wrong with them.
Rym: And then you've got to have just a broad enough IT and computer science and just computing and technology knowledge to know what kinds of ways you could mitigate or detect that stuff.
Rym: Like, do you know how to use SNMP to like detect to like?
Rym: have your Postgres server send out a track?
Scott: You and your SNMP.
Rym: SNMP is a pretty solid protocol that shockingly just works from a lot of things, especially like operating system level problems.
Scott: Yeah, I think most people don't do SNMP directly and are using some other software.
Rym: Oh, definitely.
Rym: SNMP is definitely like old school nonsense at this point.
Scott: People will just use some monitoring package of some kind.
Rym: A lot of those monitoring packages, weirdly, aren't really set up to detect specific issues.
Rym: very well, I've found.
Rym: A lot of them are kind of half-assed or they generate a lot of metrics, but not a lot of actionable events and they're kind of noisy.
Scott: You get what you pay for.
Scott: It's on you, right?
Scott: You have to customize for your thing.
Rym: But if you're a coder, when in doubt, log everything and then figure out what kinds of log lines mean there's something you got to deal with.
Rym: And write a script that like tells VAR log messages and emails you whatever like certain lines appear and come up with a system around that.
Scott: That's okay.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Then you get more like to middle level, like bigger companies, like Scott's companies, like there's a lot going on.
Rym: There's a lot of systems.
Scott: There's kind of a lot going on, not really.
Rym: But there's like external customers, there's internal users of things, there's more technology infrastructure.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But yeah, you know, the biggest problem that you have usually is that, you know, depending on your, even if your company is big enough, right?
Scott: The resources devoted to different things might not be enough, right?
Rym: Yup.
Rym: A good rule of thumb, if you're not investing about 20-25% of like the assets you have into protecting yourself from outages and attacks, you're probably going to have a big outage at some point.
Scott: But the thing is that if you don't have outages, right, you're probably not spending a lot of time defending for them, right?
Scott: You're usually spending more of your time focusing on like making new stuff, right?
Scott: Or adding, you know, doing other things.
Scott: So it's like you do a good job and you're not then protecting all the things that come.
Scott: And then when an outage happens, suddenly your whole company is like, "Oh, we got to do a bunch, we got to stop what we're doing and go back and work on defending ourselves and shoring up the...".
Scott: Right?
Scott: It's like you wait for after the flood before you build a dam.
Rym: Which, honestly, often is the right approach if it's not going to destroy the business to have an outage.
Scott: Well, but that's the thing.
Scott: It usually doesn't destroy the business until it does, right?
Scott: It's like you have a flood, it didn't destroy the business, we fix it, it won't happen again.
Scott: It happened again because there was something else, we were wrong, right?
Scott: Okay, now it still didn't destroy the business.
Scott: Something else happened.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: And then the fourth time, it destroyed the business.
Scott: Oops.
Rym: But this is where you get into the level to where it's not just one tech person who has to deal with everything.
Rym: There's often like development people and then separate DevOps or operations people.
Rym: DevOps is a relatively new concept.
Scott: Yeah, well, DevOps is basic.
Rym: It existed but was not called DevOps for a long time.
Rym: Big companies just called it operations, usually.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I think what happens is you've got, you know, your IT people are mostly like set up server, make sure hard drive doesn't get full, set up network, right?
Scott: All that kind of stuff.
Rym: Monitor to see if server I'm responsible for is at max load for too long so I can go yell at somebody.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Software people, they make a software and they make it work on a server and they configure the server, but then you have this sort of in-between like, okay, the software we wrote, you IT person who knows nothing about the software we wrote because you're an IT person.
Scott: It's your responsibility actually to make the software we wrote run on that server, but actually we could do it better than you could.
Scott: But it's your job though.
Scott: We're not doing it and we're not responsible if it goes down.
Rym: That was basically my job for a long time.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it's like, you know, it's sort of tough there.
Scott: You got to have real good communication, right?
Scott: It works better if your software, your IT people understand software or, and the problem is like for a lot of other reasons.
Rym: But your software people have to understand IT too.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: So many developers like don't fucking know how to install a database.
Scott: A lot.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But yeah, being a person who knows both like me, usually I'm the one who's sort of, you know, doing that between biz.
Scott: And it's like, if they just gave me that IT job, like those responsibilities, like I could just do both.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I'd probably do it better than the people who are supposed to be doing it.
Scott: But I'm not letting anybody call me after five o'clock, so I'm not going to do it.
Scott: And they're not paying me more, so I'm not going to do it.
Rym: I used to do on-call stuff, but they paid me enough to where it was worth it for a while.
Rym: And it was a rotation.
Rym: Like every seven weeks I had one week, or if anything crazy happened overnight, I would get notified.
Rym: But you know what I dedicated my entire working life to when I was in the office while I worked at that company?
Rym: Making sure that thing never fucking called me ever.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: I think I got woken up maybe 10 times ever in that entire time.
Scott: That's a lot of times.
Scott: I don't think I've been woken up 10 times in my life.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But a lot of what that came down to was whoever your DevOps or operations people are, like that cannot be underestimated.
Rym: That's also a career that they don't tell you about in school.
Rym: You think, "Oh, I'll be a computer
Rym: programmer.".
Scott: It didn't exist.
Scott: It didn't really exist so much.
Rym: Yeah, it only existed in big enterprise companies, and school guidance counselors don't even know that stuff exists.
Rym: IBM had that practice forever.
Rym: That's what I was doing at IBM in 2003.
Scott: Right, so we're talking like your job as a DevOps person is going to be stuff like install Nginx and Postgres and configure them and get the software running.
Rym: And understand what that software does and figure out how to monitor this whole ecosystem.
Scott: Yeah, and set up a system for it to automatically deploy to help the developers get their... We've talked about in previous episodes, like CI/CD, like actually set that up.
Scott: Because developers aren't setting that up.
Scott: They're just coding.
Scott: You've got to set that up for them to use the tools that they need to get their job done that aren't just on their computer.
Scott: You have to set them up on the servers.
Scott: They're not the developer servers.
Scott: They're your servers.
Rym: But the key to a job like that, like to get a career that could lead more toward like what I do, is you really need to have a very broad and holistic understanding of technology to where it doesn't matter what the software is doing.
Rym: It doesn't matter what the OS is.
Rym: It doesn't matter what the hardware is.
Rym: You can Google all the fiddly details.
Rym: You need to know stuff like, "Huh, the load on a server is really high suddenly.
Rym: What are the kinds of things that could cause that?
Rym: What would I do to figure out what's causing
Rym: that?".
Rym: Those soft skills are very hard to teach and usually people learn them on the job, but get very siloed and very narrowly focused and tend to assume things or problems they've seen before.
Rym: You really need to like... If you don't know what all the different directories in the file system of Linux mean, you will have a very hard time doing DevOps.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: But think about it.
Scott: I've only ever...
Rym: Like Docker fails.
Rym: Who the fuck do you look for logs to figure out why Docker's having a problem?
Rym: If you don't just know that, you might not know, "Oh, where does Docker
Rym: log?".
Rym: But you should know all the types of places Docker is likely to log on any given server, no matter what OS it is.
Scott: And you have to create a mental model of what your systems architectures are and know them or learn them or create them.
Scott: It doesn't exist.
Scott: We need these applications and you need to be able to create a systems architecture.
Scott: Well, I'll set up things this way and install this here and configure them this way.
Scott: It's like I've only ever set up in my life like a Postgres, a MySQL.
Scott: SQLite doesn't count, right?
Scott: I've never set up an Oracle in my life.
Scott: I've never used an Oracle.
Scott: I've never done a single SQL query.
Scott: I've never set up an Oracle.
Scott: I've never seen an Oracle.
Scott: I've never done a single SQL query with an Oracle server.
Scott: I've done my Microsoft SQL server.
Scott: I've never installed that.
Rym: I was using Postgres and making my own binary replication scheme with DRBD back before.
Rym: Postgres did all that for you.
Scott: But I'm saying I've done connections to Microsoft SQL, but I've never installed it.
Scott: But I've never touched Oracle.
Scott: I just know it's this database that exists.
Scott: But if someone hired me and said, "Scott, here is Oracle.
Scott: Here's the software.
Scott: Here's the license key.
Scott: Here's where to download it.
Scott: It's legal.
Scott: We paid for
Scott: it.".
Scott: Set it up.
Scott: It's going to be used for X, Y, Z. I am 100% confident that I could do that job.
Scott: I can absolutely do it.
Rym: If I have an internet connection.
Scott: If I have an access to an internet connection.
Rym: We haven't mentioned RIT yet.
Rym: The school we both went to, the Rochester Institute of Technology.
Rym: But one thing, and this is relevant because I'm going to get back to an anecdote.
Rym: The one thing I can say about RIT grads that has been consistent both when we were there and in my entire career whenever I meet them professionally.
Rym: For whatever reason, RIT teaches people these broad skills that a lot of other tech schools just fucking don't.
Rym: And I don't know why.
Scott: Did they really teach me those broad skills?
Rym: Well, I don't think RIT taught it.
Rym: I think it was the co-ops coupled with the kind of vague lesson plans.
Scott: I learned a co-op.
Scott: I think I learned most of that stuff just by most of that stuff.
Scott: I learned because I would mess around trying to set up my own web server.
Scott: And I ran Linux as my primary OS during the time period where that made sense to do.
Rym: Making that Counter Strike server work like the real one we ran.
Rym: I learned a lot making that work.
Rym: I had it monitored.
Scott: Setting up DNS in our house.
Scott: Doing that, it's like the stuff you do at a company is basically the same only bigger.
Rym: I wonder if it's partly that RIT, there's this culture of that.
Rym: Especially in IT more so than CS.
Rym: A lot of our classes would have a class that was worthless.
Rym: Like, oh, if you don't know what Active Directory is, we're going to teach you and it's going to be terrifying and boring and most of you are going to skip it.
Rym: But then the class was graded in a lab where the lab was, by the end of the quarter, we're going to come into this room.
Rym: And in this room, across these five PCs you have access to, you have to run these ten services providing these forty different capabilities.
Scott: I didn't have that.
Rym: And then hackers are going to attack it and it's got to stay mostly up.
Rym: Like, those are the kinds of classes we had.
Scott: That class I had, the hacking class.
Rym: That class was super fucking fun.
Rym: But anyway, I was on defense and they actually forced us to install old versions of stuff because otherwise no one could hack in.
Scott: I was on offense and there was a message, because that lab wasn't connected to the internet.
Scott: And there was basically, I read a news on Slashtide that talked about a vulnerability in Microsoft Messenger, MSN Messenger.
Scott: So I basically downloaded the files for it onto floppy disk, three and a half inch.
Scott: And I went to that lab and sure enough, I could open Microsoft Messenger, right?
Scott: And I had the patch, like the patched version, I was able to try applying the patch to the EXE.
Scott: But the problem was that because the lab didn't have an internet connection, I couldn't log in to the MSN Messenger.
Scott: But it's like, if I could have, it absolutely would have worked because I tested it at home first.
Scott: And I would have just, if I ran it at home, I was able to open up a root CMD, you know.
Rym: But it forced this fundamental understanding of how to make basic things work on any kind of computer.
Rym: So when I got my first co-op at IBM, one of the first things they did is they were like, "All right, we have a problem you can help us with.
Rym: Here is all the installation media for some fucking ancient version of WebSphere.
Rym: Get it working on this server and deploy this Java application to
Rym: it.".
Scott: We ain't even talking about outages anymore.
Rym: But I guess the point is being able to do that kind of thing holistically will make you like a top tier DevOps person who can handle pretty much any outage that gets thrown at you.
Scott: All right, one off-way topic, but let's have one last thing I want to talk about.
Scott: the outages, right?
Scott: Is when there is an outage, right?
Scott: You know, how do you deal with it, right?
Scott: And then how do you not only deal with it in terms of fixing it, but also deal with it in communicating with the people who- Yeah, that's a good topic.
Rym: Question one, can you fix it before anyone notices?
Rym: Ask that first.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Because if you can fix it and no one notices, you fucking win.
Rym: That is like winning your job.
Scott: If no one notices, there wasn't an outage.
Scott: If a tree falls in the woods, no one heard it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Okay, so you had an outage and someone noticed, right?
Rym: Well, I'd say point two.
Rym: If you have an outage and you think people are going to notice, can you at least tell them before they tell you?
Scott: That's also a good thing to do, yeah.
Rym: If your user knows there's an outage and you don't, that is a big problem.
Scott: Like today?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Okay, so next thing, right?
Scott: So what do you do?
Scott: You got to fix it, right?
Scott: So you got to figure out which area the problem is in, because like we talked about, IT people, software people, devops people.
Scott: One or more of them is going to be the ones to call.
Scott: If it's full hard drive, your software person is going to be like, "I didn't do shit about
Scott: that.".
Scott: And if it's bugging the code, IT person can't fix that no matter how much resources you give them.
Scott: They need the software person to figure that out.
Scott: But you might not realize that's what it is.
Scott: So you need to sort of get everyone to take a look and see if they're the problem.
Rym: Unless you're above a certain scale where that is a waste of everyone's time, you, if you're a devops person, should have figured out a triage process to where it's very easy to narrow down what the most likely problems are.
Rym: So you can stop wasting your time looking everywhere else.
Scott: Yeah, you know, that's definitely good.
Rym: But it's really hard to, like, that's a hard skill to teach, because it really requires that holistic knowledge I was talking about.
Scott: Especially since things that first appear to be one thing could be another thing.
Scott: And the better your systems are set up, when there is a problem, the harder it's going to be to figure out what the hell it is, because you rule out so many things that you're defended against.
Rym: And you can tell devops people and operations people who never got that sort of formal or at least holistic education in technology, but only learned on the job, because they will persist in trying to say the problem is something that they've seen before without, like, understanding why it could not be the problem.
Rym: You'll see that a lot, especially in enterprise.
Scott: Yeah, you can usually, figuring out what the cause of the problems is very similar to figuring out problems with, like, your local computer.
Scott: Like, using process of elimination, understanding how things connect to each other, saying, "Oh, well, I'm getting an image on the monitor, so the video card is
Scott: working.".
Scott: Right?
Scott: But it could be, "Let me try the monitor on a different
Scott: computer.".
Scott: Right?
Scott: That same thinking process is the same thing that you use to figure out what's causing the outage.
Rym: The important server that's having a problem has a link light, like, I'm looking at it, and there's a link light, even though no one can connect to it, and it's powered on, so at least some of the circuitry in there is working.
Scott: It's got to be in a higher level of the OSI model.
Scott: It's not in the hardware layer.
Rym: Yep, but see what you just said, the OSI model.
Rym: That is foundational, broad knowledge of computing.
Scott: You have to have a model of the system's architecture in your brain, just like you have to have a model of a working PC in your brain to be able to use the process of elimination.
Rym: I still remember when I worked at Pipeline, we had 23 demons, mostly written in C, that did the things, and I still know, like, the path of data through all these different demons.
Scott: Usually the hardest problems to solve are when your mental model is at a certain abstraction layer, and the actual problem is beneath, right?
Scott: So it's like, okay, I understand how this, you know, program works, right?
Scott: It's written in, like, Python or something, and the actual problem is in, like, C library that you're importing or some shit.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You're not thinking on that level, right?
Scott: You're thinking of this, like, blob.
Rym: Or, like, networking.
Rym: You're thinking, alright, IP addresses, routers, all that stuff you know, but there could be a problem of a mismatch in your physical network between Ethernet 2 and 802.11.3.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, all my IP addresses are right, what's wrong?
Scott: Two things have the same MAC address, baby.
Scott: So you didn't know how that happened.
Rym: Someone fucked around, or you got...
Scott: Very, very, very unlikely for that to happen.
Rym: Unless someone fucked around with cloning or something.
Scott: They found out.
Scott: Okay, so now, you got the outage, right?
Scott: You know you got people on it, they're fixing it, right?
Scott: You're gonna do the best you can to fix it.
Scott: Hopefully, you have backups, so worst case... Outage means you lose time, you might lose money, but if you lose data, that is the worst, right?
Scott: You cannot lose data, you gotta have the backups, even if you're out for days, if you still have the data, it's like, thank god, right?
Scott: If YouTube goes down and comes back, okay, if YouTube goes down and comes back, and half the videos are gone forever, just shut it all down, that's it, it's done.
Rym: And I think we did an episode on disaster recovery, which includes such things as starting your business back up in an entirely new physical location because literally everything burned down.
Scott: But the data is the thing, as long as you save the data, everything else can be redone eventually, even if it sucks and you go out of business in the meantime.
Scott: Do not lose the data, that is always number one.
Scott: Alright, so coming back, right?
Scott: What do you tell people?
Scott: First of all, you gotta be honest with the customer, whoever the client, or whoever it is.
Scott: You don't wanna be like, oh no, everything's just fine, problem must be on your end.
Scott: No, don't do that, that just makes people, 'cause they know you're bullshitting, they can tell you're bullshitting right away, they got Twitter.
Rym: So, in my experience, once you get way up this chag to big enterprise companies, usually what happens is both sides will bullshit and say the other side is at fault, and ask them to prove it's not them, because they're still trying to figure out the cause of the outage.
Rym: I say that a lot.
Scott: That's fine, if you don't know the cause, if it could be someone else, then don't admit it's you.
Rym: But if you know there's an outage, be honest and tell all the people who could be impacted in the most succinct way possible as soon as possible.
Scott: And tell them the truth about how they will be impacted, so that they can make appropriate plans.
Scott: So like, if you're gonna be down for hours, you gotta say, hey, we're gonna be down for quite a while, you might wanna do X, Y, Z, 'cause we're not gonna be available.
Rym: Stock exchanges will do that, a stock exchange might go down and officially announce to the market, sorry, we're fucked, please send orders elsewhere for the rest of today, we cannot deal with you, we're done, we're down, sorry.
Rym: We'll be back up tomorrow.
Scott: If you have, like I just said, the worst case, if you lost the data, you just gotta fess up and say you lost the data and give them all your money, give them money to replace the data, you fucked up.
Rym: Yup, and this is where you run into like big company stuff of SLAs, service level agreements, you might have customers where you sign contracts guaranteeing certain amounts of uptime, clawbacks where a client can literally get refunds from you or cash payments for outages.
Rym: Like, it gets really messy in a hurry, this is why business people get involved, you know, there's always like that VP who keeps calling into the line when there's an outage and they're always like, can I get a status, what's going on, have you fixed it yet?
Scott: Yup, they're nervous about the wallet, if you're out too long, they lose money.
Rym: So back to the Slack outage, their website said that it was a localized partial outage for a long time.
Rym: It sure did.
Rym: While Twitter said it was completely down.
Scott: It's 100% down for everybody in the universe.
Rym: But at the same time, it did come back up pretty quickly.
Scott: After hours, hours is not good.
Scott: Minutes is eh, right?
Scott: Many minutes is bad.
Scott: Hours is real bad.
Scott: Frontrecruit.com doesn't go down for hours.
Scott: It's when I'm sleeping and then as soon as I wake up, it just takes a few minutes.
Rym: Yup, I mean, our process is basically, I'll be like, I'll just message Scott and be like, hey, I think the database is broken.
Scott: We have better uptime than Slack.
Rym: Actually, for the 15 plus years we've been doing GeekNights, we got pretty good uptime.
Scott: And I've never lost data ever.
Scott: Not once.
Scott: And that's just one person operation.
Scott: So what excuse do you have?
Rym: But that's it.
Rym: It comes down to honesty, openness, problem solving skills, and a holistic understanding of your technology and technology overall.
Scott: And promptness.
Scott: Don't be delaying.
Rym: And then when you do fix it, right?
Scott: Tell everyone what the fuck happened.
Scott: The technological details.
Scott: Because even though most people...
Rym: The post-mortem, we don't have time to talk about that.
Scott: Yeah, you gotta write one and make it available to everyone who knew about the outage.
Rym: And if you're a big company like Netflix or Slack, I'd love for there to be a little more openness.
Scott: They usually are pretty open.
Rym: They usually are, but not always.
Scott: That's like.
Scott: the only thing that they're kinda open and good with is the post-mortems on the outages.
Scott: Because those are great for not only customers to see that you're not bullshitting, to see exactly what went wrong.
Scott: They can have their tech people look at it and go, "Mmm, mmm, mmm,
Scott: okay.".
Scott: And then everyone else can learn and not fuck up the same way.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: You're adding to the body of human knowledge so someone can Google for a weird outage.
Rym: Find your post-mortem because they pasted a log line that happens to be yours.
Scott: You go online, there are places that collect all these.
Scott: You can go read them and learn how people have fucked up.
Scott: so you don't do it the same way.
Rym: I have written so many post-mortems over the years.
Rym: That's been one of my jobs.
Scott: Yeah, you know.
Scott: We don't usually write them because, A, we don't have that many outages, really, of any significance.
Scott: And also the only users are internal, so it's like they don't care.
Scott: There's no technological audience for outages.
Rym: Also, our systems are so federated to where there's like five different ways to download GeekNights if any one of them is down at any given time.
Scott: Oh, for GeekNights, I basically tell people.
Scott: I just tweet or something and be like, "Yeah, we're down because of this,".
Scott: or whatever.
Rym: And capital markets, there are industries where some of this stuff does not apply because there are laws, regulations, rules, and governments involved that make things weird.
Rym: That's the asterisk for, "But, but, but, I work for a military
Rym: country."
Rym: Like, yeah, dude, I know.
Rym: I know what that's like.
Rym: I've been there.
Scott: Alright, I'm hungry.
Scott: I'm gonna have a stomach outage.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this 2021 episode of the GeekNights Podcast are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Link, EG, Graham Finch, You Hold the Key to My Heart.
Rym: Now go through the last year or so of podcasts and make Rym sing.
Rym: Clinton Walton, Wren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, ReviewMadBull34, cowards, Dread Lily Tenebrae, JustLikeADudeGuy, Chris Reimer, Finn, Shervin Von Harl, and a bunch of people who do not want me to say their names.
Rym: Stay safe out there.
Rym: Get the vaccine as soon as you can.
Rym: Hopefully we'll see you at a convention at some point once enough people are vaccinated and this horrible nightmare comes to some sort of conclusion.
Rym: But for now, I leave you with...