Rym: It's Wednesday August 1st.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We bring you the long-awaited Otakon 2007 con report.
Scott: Let's do this Warm today.
Scott: No, I don't want to start with that.
Rym: You don't want to start with that.
Scott: I want to jump right into it cuz the show or be long otherwise true it will.
Rym: for all of you new listeners It's finally the night where we're going to do that Otakon con report.
Rym: You know that con that we went to before the week of awesome the con that I almost forgot about.
Scott: right Let's talk about it, but first there's some news.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: this news is actually about the Otakon.
Scott: Apparently there was some car some fansubbing group doing a panel at Otakon On fansubbing did actually do their panel.
Scott: I think they did do that.
Scott: They did do their panel normally and successfully All
Rym: right,
Scott: however, they put a press release on their website, you know on Saturday July 21st and they actually kept updating it updating it through the 27th that told a farcical tale of police coming and arresting them at their fansubbing panel and their fansubbing panel being renamed and you know in order to let the police know where they were and such and such and such and Such
Rym: uh-huh.
Rym: I don't recall anything like that happening at all.
Scott: There's nothing like that did happen at Otakon.
Scott: this fansubbing group in order to I guess attract attention Made up this story and put it in an actual press release that was constantly updated daily on their website To get some attention after the con.
Scott: And if you actually highlight all the their web, you know You drag and you select.
Scott: you can see that in white on a white background.
Scott: at the bottom It says YHBT at the bottom of their press release, which means you have been trolled.
Rym: You know, all I really have to ask about that is what's the Nubian?
Scott: Yeah, so wait.
Scott: So Otakon on their website today put up a press release that says response to data bios falsified press release.
Scott: We've gotten comments about the press release earlier this week.
Scott: just to tell you their panel went fine.
Scott: Police and lawyers were not part of their panel nor was anyone arrested at the bottom of their press release.
Scott: the latest YHBT The press release is a complete fabrication not amusing.
Scott: We are sad.
Scott: and they had to stoop to such a level to get quote.
Rym: street cred quote good game Otakon.
Scott: Otakon said street cred in I guess a semi-official press release Man, that's why I love Otakon.
Rym: But anyway, yeah Kind of silly, you know on one hand I somewhat respect someone trying to do something crazy to get noticed but on the other hand, you're a fan subber.
Rym: what you're doing is Vaguely illegal.
Scott: to begin with yeah Otakon gave you a panel.
Scott: your panel was just fine There was nothing wrong with it and you're making trouble for Otakon Partly.
Scott: what's with the stupid people believing the obviously phony press release?
Rym: I mean, it's not like that wouldn't have been in the news somewhere other than there.
Scott: I know right?
Scott: Come on.
Rym: I think we're some of the last human beings on earth who whenever I see any news That's too good or too bad to be true.
Scott: I look for at least one other source and one other source that isn't just a blog post linking to the first source.
Scott: Yeah Hopefully some blog post linking to the blog post that links to the blog post that links to the only source.
Rym: The worst is when you find what a real legitimate or semi legitimate press outlet That has a story that at the end they just credit some blog that they got it from.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty bad.
Rym: So what's your news?
Rym: Right?
Rym: Well a while ago Emily took me to see Toki wo kakaru shoujo in the city Which it's the girl who left through time or the girl who runs through time and it was a freaking fantastic movie.
Rym: I highly recommend it.
Scott: It turns out that DC Comics CMX division has picked up the rights to the manga to Toki wo kakaru shoujo Yep, the CMX if you don't know is just basically it's DC Comics and I think Jim Lee has something to do with it.
Scott: I'm not sure but they publish the mega Tokyo's and the tenjou Tengaze and This book I actually just bought called samurai command mission something.
Scott: I'm gonna read it and let you know how it is probably next week or something.
Scott: and So this is just one there's.
Scott: actually you know I was kind of looking down on them because they were only publishing crap manga and crap non manga And harsh I know and now they're actually starting to get some things that are slightly interesting.
Scott: So in addition to keeping your eye on the Viz and the Del Rey and the vertical not the keep your eye on the CMX As well.
Rym: Oh and the dark horse who can forget that Excited about this partly because according to the press release here, which is probably not a troll These are pretty much directly based on the original 1965 novel which the movie was also based on.
Rym: Yeah, the movie is really neat and that it kind of gives nods to the novel But it is its own story and I really want to read that novel now But I don't think it's in English.
Scott: This is something that I've noticed.
Scott: they've been bringing a lot of the novels over, you know And at first I like.
Scott: the first one I ever saw was that when I went to the comic book store regularly before I ordered online I saw this FMA book on the shelf and I was like, I'm buying FMA I gotta buy this book.
Scott: and I picked it up and it was a novel inside and I was like what the fuck.
Scott: and I Put it down.
Scott: and then a vampire hunter d1 came and I was like, oh, oh, it's a novel what the fuck.
Scott: and I put It down.
Scott: It was like what the fuck's a novel do to the comic book store.
Scott: But now, you know I hear about like these great days actually awesome animes and mangas that were Originally based on novels not novels that came after but novels that came before.
Rym: that's what I'm interested in.
Scott: I'm like, so I've been looking for like a trigon, you know, and and these all these old Japanese sci-fi novels We've been looking for a trigon for a long time.
Scott: What's it's?
Scott: um, I keep forgetting the Jeff way to say it in Japanese, but it's called undersea battleship and It's basically this Japanese sci-fi novel from 1899 that I is out of print and impossible to fix
Rym: somewhat World-renowned and it's super Japan renowned and there was a mediocre anime based
Scott: on it.
Scott: I take gunkhan.
Scott: That's why I would said if anyone has a copy of the original novel Kaita gunkhan in English or Japanese.
Scott: We don't care from English or Japanese or any other language from 1899. this thing's public domain people and I can't get it.
Scott: It's a crime.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I'm gonna put a bounty on it.
Rym: I'll give you 50 bucks.
Scott: If you send it to give you a hundred bucks for the full text.
Rym: That's on any language.
Rym: All right, so that's already 150 bucks on the line.
Scott: Yeah of kaita gunkhan the original novel by Shunro, Oshikawa.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: It's so bad that the anime was not so great.
Rym: They really need to.
Scott: well that was super attrigon.
Scott: There was also the live-action movie which included kaiju as well as other.
Rym: I heard that that was great But not for the right reasons.
Scott: exact Yeah.
Scott: But my point is there's a bunch of awesome Japanese novels that I want translated to English and there there are translating novels to English but not the ones I want.
Scott: Where's like the twelve kingdoms at?
Rym: Oh, there's an update here.
Rym: CMX also announced that they're gonna release Shirley, which is a companion piece to Emma.
Scott: Oh good for you on it.
Rym: Uh, yeah, I want both of those because Emma is my favorite manga right now.
Scott: All right, I'll keep an eye out Things of the day.
Rym: so you all know that my second favorite kind of prank is Japanese TV show launches someone naked into some sort of zany situation.
Scott: Oh, man.
Scott: Do you have one of those?
Scott: I haven't seen one of those in a while.
Scott: That was new.
Scott: See.
Scott: No, I don't because ah, what do you do?
Scott: Do you build it up and then letting down for while?
Rym: that is my second favorite kind of prank?
Rym: My favorite kind of prank is the prank that isn't a jump out boo or anything like that.
Rym: It's where you set up a situation.
Rym: That's so weird that the people involved.
Rym: It's not like oh you got me It's a prank, but they're just kind of freaked out and unnerved bonus points.
Rym: If you never tell them it was a prank.
Rym: Yeah Well, this is just one such video and I was taking it back.
Rym: I saw the link on dig and I thought okay This is gonna be one of those boo boo.
Rym: Ah, we got you candid camera things.
Rym: So I watch it and they set up the situation of guys gonna get sucked into a jet engine on a tarmac and a woman's gonna see it and freak Out.
Rym: and while that happens that is not the prank.
Rym: That is not the prank at all.
Rym: And all I have to say is the guy who kind of looks a little bit like Michael Keaton It's a good night for flying.
Rym: That guy makes this prank.
Rym: Good God.
Scott: It is an excellent prank and of the highest caliber.
Scott: However, I am disappointed that I do not get to see if and when they ever tell the person about the prank because their reaction Would be also the priceless.
Scott: However, it's basically like they made a gem of gold and then I know there's another gem of gold waiting But they deny it to me.
Rym: It's a gem to.
Rym: the woman starts losing it and it's like a scene out of a movie and she's starting to doubt her own sanity.
Rym: and What I'm going to assume because they did not show us the end result is that either this was all staged from the beginning Which I doubt.
Rym: I think they actually pulled this on the woman.
Rym: I'm going to assume that they never let her in on it.
Scott: Yeah, okay, that's fine.
Rym: then because if that is true, this is perhaps the greatest prank ever pulled.
Scott: But then I hope she sees it on TV or the internet.
Rym: You know what I hope she never does.
Scott: I hope everyone could be an actor.
Rym: I hope everyone she knows and ordered and or was ever loved sees the video But she did it for does and then on her die on her deathbed.
Rym: Someone shows it to her to get the maximum fullness of the joke.
Scott: Okay, so that's right killer, um, are you an anime fan?
Rym: deathbed Kind of.
Scott: have you ever actually watched?
Scott: Astro Boy ever?
Rym: I saw a clip from Astro Boy on the youtubes, right?
Scott: So Adult swim of all people on their website has a full entire episode of the old Original Astro Boy, it's not the first episode and it's not subtitled with Japanese.
Scott: It's the English one, but there it is and I watched it and you should watch it.
Scott: if you don't watch it They just stop being anime fan.
Scott: don't listen to Wednesday.
Scott: don't listen any anime podcast.
Scott: don't watch any anime.
Rym: you gotta know your roots.
Scott: This episode it's basically I feel the same way about this as I feel about like old corny superhero Comics from the 70s.
Scott: you watch it and you're like, wow, look at this.
Scott: There's actually this hard Sci-fi plot about a ship a ship with a crew going to Mars not Trusting Astro Boy as the captain because he's a robot A guy who was a mutiny on the last mission who was actually right about alien invaders.
Scott: The aliens are really cool and there's actually a Not the super complex plot but way more complex plot for a children's show than you're gonna see.
Scott: But the delivery is mad corny.
Scott: The dubbing is way bad.
Scott: You can't blame that on the Japanese No, but you can name the the poor poor animation.
Scott: I mean they pretty much This mouths not moving while this talking which I'm not sure if there was originally talking or not because it's a dub.
Rym: It seems like a lot of American dubs of things especially older ones are really bad ones.
Rym: Just add all this extra exposition when people aren't talking because Americans are too dumb to get it.
Scott: but basically like the drawing is like awesome Tezuka like characters are drawn like awesomely and such and It's even though it's black and white.
Scott: but the animation is the horrendous which the poor movement of things.
Scott: but yeah, it's like watching a Tezuka manga and With bad dubbing see at least we've come a long way.
Rym: Hina Tori looks like Tezuka, but it's also animated beautifully Yes.
Scott: so if you've never watched the Astro Boy watch the Astro Boy because it's worth it and you should.
Rym: so Otakon 2007. we were there.
Scott: we were there.
Scott: Were you there?
Rym: Actually a lot of you were there.
Rym: We ran into a lot of GeekNights listeners.
Rym: I was happily Surprised and apparently there were GeekNights listeners there.
Scott: who?
Scott: Saw us and they didn't say anything.
Rym: There was one group of two girls who I wasn't sure but I ran out of a panel and I was bolting toward a bathroom.
Rym: Cuz I had to pee.
Rym: I had to pee like I've never had to pee before.
Scott: it happened to me twice at the con.
Scott: I had to pee and I couldn't.
Rym: yeah, cuz we're on a panel or something.
Rym: Yep So I've run run into the bathroom and I hear two girls go higher and I was like There's no way.
Rym: they were saying hi to me and I just kept running and I peed and it was that one guy
Scott: on Friday like early in the day where you're just walking back and forth across the con because there's nothing to Do and we were walking down the stairs and he was like your Rym and Scott you guys are awesome.
Scott: And that's all he said, you know what?
Rym: That's the kind of thing I like because I have done that to people or guests at cons that I've liked in the past.
Scott: I have also done that to people.
Scott: I've actually waited in line at people's tables to say you're so-and-so.
Scott: You're awesome.
Rym: Bye, that was the primary thing I do with the mocha is go to every artist I like and be like man.
Rym: I really like your stuff.
Rym: See ya.
Rym: Yep, or maybe well you sign the book I just bought from you.
Scott: I don't really care about signing but I'll usually buy stuff from them.
Rym: I only go for the signature if it's someone who will draw something in it on the fly.
Scott: See, I'll just go for my pirate book in that case.
Rym: Yeah The pirate book that you didn't really do much with it Otakon there wasn't so much that looked like I wanted to do.
Rym: That was like the best artists alley ever.
Rym: there were a lot of amazing artists who could have drawn some piratey action and none of them really Suited my fancy.
Rym: I'm sure no notice.
Scott: I didn't buy much in the artists alley.
Rym: The only reason I didn't buy much is because I already own more art than I have wall space for.
Scott: yeah I you know the artists alley while the artists alley.
Scott: Okay, let's the artists alleys.
Scott: Well, let's start with Thursday and then move on.
Rym: All right, so I bring this part up.
Rym: I mean I don't want to get into all the meta stuff about the crew and what we did when we weren't at the con and all That business and the road trip down because well, that's fun That's not really nota con con report and we got enough to talk about as it is.
Rym: We'll talk about all that tomorrow.
Scott: So the red line.
Scott: well before
Rym: that normally our tradition has been to get to Baltimore by noon on Thursday Check into the hotel, even though we can't get our rooms Make sure we get the exact rooms we want, you know next to an elevator on the pool floor Next to each other with the doors open between them and all that business.
Rym: and then we nap for like three hours.
Rym: This year we were tired and we decided to leave a little later.
Rym: We didn't actually get into Baltimore until about 2 30.
Rym: I requested early check-in so we could still check in right about then Getting to Baltimore later than 2 30 pretty much fucks you at this point because the hotels just it goes from Perfect empty hotel where I walk up check in get exactly what I want to.
Rym: Line of otaku all of whom have problems getting their hotel room.
Scott: Mostly they don't have problems getting their hotel room.
Scott: There's problems with them.
Scott: is the problem.
Rym: They end up having Getting their hotel rooms because they either they're trying to pay with cash or their credit cards maxed out or they're there early But the friend who got the room isn't there yet.
Rym: or they're stupid or they don't understand that There's a hotel tax and they're wondering why the hotel room costs more.
Rym: Yeah, that happens a lot.
Scott: Yeah, it's basically problems with them.
Scott: there's nothing wrong with the hotel.
Rym: the hotel is operating normally But this year we decided to since we had the fancy-pants Marantz Go to the absolute front of the line the reg line that was lined up.
Scott: Oh, I forgot about this.
Scott: you forgot about this until just now.
Rym: The people lined up to get their badges on Thursday, and this is something Otakon does every year.
Rym: It's a great thing.
Scott: I highly recommend your pre-reg and get your badge Thursday Unless you're the kind of person who goes to work Friday and then goes to Otakon.
Rym: However There is no reason to line up before this line starts moving.
Scott: There's no reason to be in this line at all.
Scott: I mean basically the line this year was open from 5 p.m Until what 10 p.m?
Scott: So?
Scott: and the line for Otakon's reg.
Scott: they are so damn efficient.
Scott: It moves so fast right that even if you're at the end of the crazy line, you'll be inside within the hour Guaranteed.
Scott: so we showed up at the line at what like eight six seven six seven eight something like that.
Scott: We just walked right in got badges and walked out.
Scott: Well, that's not really what happened.
Rym: We would we were had we not been panelists We would have gotten our badges in less than eight minutes pretty much.
Scott: So if you don't like waiting in lines because I mean if you're the kind of person who says I'm gonna wait in the line To have fun go nuts wait in the line to have fun waiting in line.
Scott: But if you don't like waiting in line There is no reason to ever wait in a line at Otakon.
Rym: if you go Thursday I mean, I don't cuz a lot of people lined up.
Rym: I'd say thousands and thousands perhaps at least a thousand people lined up and they waited there for hours for no reason because once the reg line opens it takes About an hour to churn through all the 80 to already in line.
Rym: Then there's just no wait for the rest of the night because there's like no more hours of walk in and get your badge Immediately time.
Scott: and so by the same token anyone who ever complains about the pre reg line at Otakon They were they were allowed to complain in years past but since last year complaining is all over.
Rym: Yeah, I'm gonna say it straight up if you think that line is as bad you're an idiot.
Rym: Yeah, that's the best icon line could ever be.
Scott: I mean the line isn't perfect because it was perfect.
Scott: Everyone would immediately get their badge and there would be one reg person for every single person who wanted a badge.
Scott: I never have one badge and personally handed to you, but that is the best reg line of any convention probably in the world.
Rym: Okay, so so we went before right before they opened the doors like at the final hour to the very front of this line To see what kind of crazy wacko had been waiting there now.
Rym: We recorded two little interviews.
Rym: I'm gonna start with the second person in line Because he gave the answer that I expected someone to give and it's not that interesting But at the same time at least he has a fairly legitimate reason for being there.
Rym: So we're here at the front of the pre reg line to Otakon.
Rym: we are and what is your name?
Rym: Zach strange, so how many hours have you been standing here or sitting here?
Rym: I have lost count.
Scott: I got here at midnight Midnight midnight.
Rym: now why?
Rym: that's the kind of the open-ended question.
Rym: Why are you here?
Scott: That's a good question.
Rym: um, actually I come out to hang out with the other fans that show up early and That way I can sit under sit under the cover.
Rym: So I'm not getting rained on and sitting in the Sun.
Rym: So So you're gonna get into the count obviously early tomorrow.
Rym: What's the first thing you're gonna do when you get in there?
Rym: I don't know until I see the schedule.
Rym: I Will be.
Rym: I will be planning that tonight.
Scott: Are you aware the schedule is online before the convention?
Rym: Yeah, but things always sometimes change at the very end.
Rym: So I like to look at the updates.
Scott: I don't like to plan ahead too much because they usually end up changing something or another up.
Scott: Are you aware that if you just showed up at like 8 p.m Tonight you just be able to walk in and get your badge without waiting.
Scott: probably Been I wouldn't have been able to stand around talking to all these guys.
Scott: That's the right answer.
Rym: now The person in front of him.
Rym: I don't know if I should say what this was about or if we should just let the interview speak for itself.
Scott: I think we'll just let the interview speak for itself and say Much to our surprise the person who waited in the front of the line for no reason We thought for no reason to get into Otakon and get their badge stupidly early Was not there for no reason and they were not so stupid.
Rym: All I hope is that when he I hope that he told the people at Otakon what he was there for because I'm sure They would have at least done something nice for him.
Rym: Yeah, and to I hope he doesn't die.
Scott: So And what time did you get in line?
Scott: 4 p.m.
Scott: Yesterday.
Scott: Yes, are you aware that the line is gonna be open from 5 p.m.
Scott: To 10 p.m.
Scott: Tonight?
Scott: Yes, the sheer irony of it all is though.
Scott: I won't be actually going to Otakon Friday.
Scott: I ship out 7 a.m.
Scott: In the morning, so Why are you waiting in line so long if you're not going to the con?
Scott: To show my dedication to Otakon That's a pretty strong statement right there.
Scott: damn All right, let's move on.
Rym: I think the sentiment there speaks for itself.
Rym: that is a man who was dedicated to his anime.
Scott: So a couple hours later after hanging out in the pool or before hanging out in the pool I don't remember we went to get our badges and Which would have taken
Rym: probably
Scott: five minutes because he went in at like seven or eight and we just would have walked in and walked Out.
Scott: BAM, but we were panelists and they had a problem with their crazy Microsoft registration system.
Rym: now Funnily Gerald walks by while we're in the problem line.
Rym: Yeah, and we're like, yeah, there's a problem with panelist badges But he decided to get the press badge which I don't think is worth it still because I looked at the privileges the press get and That is totally mitigated by the fact that you generally have to interview uninteresting people who may or may not show.
Scott: Yeah they have these press events you get to go to which is like you go to a room where some guests show up and you Talk to them and no one else is there but the press and I really don't care about going to those.
Scott: And press badge doesn't seem to get you anything else other than I guess you're allowed to go into a few places in order to Question people out.
Rym: but there was one time it would have been useful.
Rym: We wanted to interview some people in line for the dealers room and the staffer wouldn't let us through because we weren't press.
Rym: Yeah, that was about it, but totally not worth it.
Rym: though I guess we could get the press badge and then just blow off.
Scott: Get the press badge.
Scott: I would like to get every badge sort of have like the Otakon God badge like a staff badge.
Rym: Just be Jim Vowles badge, I don't know.
Scott: I'd be I'd be staff I'd be a normal registrant I'd be a panelist I'd be an in the artists alley.
Scott: I would be a dealer and a press person all at once.
Scott: Do you think I could manage doing all those things at once?
Rym: We could get a table in the dealers room.
Scott: I mean all we have to do for some of those is spend money right so it shouldn't be that hard.
Scott: Okay, so we had a problem.
Rym: the problem was abated Quickly, you know suffice to say every year.
Rym: for some reason.
Rym: panels and I mean this year there were panel problems.
Rym: We'll get to that.
Rym: but even in past years It's never clear how panelists should get their badges or how they're gonna get comped or what's going on.
Rym: It used to be that they just gave you an associate's badge and I gotta say I really think they should go back to that System.
Scott: Well, I don't necessarily think that we need a special different badge than other people.
Rym: Well the idea that back then when you were a panelist you didn't have to go through registration You just went in to panel ops found the panel's dude, and he had a pile of badges.
Rym: He talked to you And if he believed that you were the person who was supposed to be there He gave you as many badges as he saw fit and that was the end of it.
Scott: I think that I think that is a good thing is if Because they have problems with panelists not showing up panelists being late panelists not knowing what to do panelists not being prepared Forcing every panelist as they arrive to the convention to go to panel ops to get their badge Right allows panel ops to check up on them.
Scott: make sure that they're the real deal they'll know if a panelist doesn't show up they'll know all these things and I I think that alone would be a good thing to just force the panelists to show up to panel ops so that Panel ops could connect with them and make sure everything's cool and be on the level.
Scott: We don't need a special different badge But panel ops should just have the badges of all the panelists with their names already on them and then hand them out And I think that would be a good thing.
Scott: Now barring that and I don't say that because I want to skip in line either cuz line takes five minutes I don't care.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: even though we ended up having to stand in the trouble line, which took forever
Scott: Until someone finally came and triaged it
Rym: Yeah They really needed more triage in that line to walk because most of the people in that line either were dumb and just screwed up the online web form or didn't actually pay or Were us who had a legitimate problem?
Scott: Yes I think all they need to do is since the reg moves so fast You can make like a few more problem lines than just one and you can also have someone permit like Constantly triaging the problem line and that would take what two extra people not a big deal.
Scott: Yeah Especially when after an hour or two all the reg people are just kind of sitting around like yep Someone else is handling all of it.
Rym: Or in the very least if they could have set it up if they didn't do the special badges instead of making every panelist say they're gonna pay by check and then not pay and ghetto eyes it.
Rym: it shouldn't be that hard to add a Compt button to the system and you just click pick like I am a panelist and then someone on the other end says yes They are or no, they are it here.
Scott: You're deleted.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right granted I think the best system at least from I mean not from a con perspective But from my perspective is still ConnectiCon where I walked in and said hi I'm a guest and they said here's your guest badge.
Rym: Yep, and they didn't even ask me who I was.
Rym: No, if I was the shady person, I probably could have gotten a badge Probably.
Scott: but they then they asked, you know What are our names?
Scott: and gave us our itineraries which if we were not guess we would have not have gotten our itinerary.
Rym: Sure, they would have said hey, you're not guess yoink, but still I'm reasonably certain that I personally maybe not Some guy off the street could have talked my way into a badge easily could have talked my way regardless.
Rym: I don't think I've gone to a con in recent memory where I didn't get a comp edge for legitimate reasons.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So that's the end of the con page.
Scott: They spent too much time.
Rym: Well, they had con badge designs this year were much improved over last year.
Scott: Yes They definitely spanned all genres as opposed to last year where they were mostly anime No one cared about in very few genres.
Rym: Yes of props to them I took the paprika badge as I also took the paprika.
Rym: everyone who was smart.
Scott: There was a rule.
Scott: There was another respectable badge.
Scott: I just forget what it was.
Rym: Well, there's the Raza found one.
Scott: No, it was alright.
Scott: I don't know why they pick Rosamond sort of an old show.
Rym: I'd rather than pick Raza.
Rym: fine that people at least know.
Rym: then whatever crap anime some industry guys try about this Gundam badge Gundam there was a Gundam seed badge.
Scott: once I have it.
Rym: Well, I am of the mind that Otakon should Regardless, I mean make a deal about an astro boy bad.
Rym: There should always be one Gundam badge.
Rym: I don't care what Gundam it's from but there should always be a Gundam badge.
Scott: It should always be a Tezuka badge.
Scott: that should always should be a Dragon Ball badge.
Scott: There should always.
Rym: you know that it's not maybe not Dragon Ball but shonen fighting of the decade whatever show it is There should be.
Scott: you know, you gotta do one of each.
Scott: I know that they go through some sort of process to determine what badges to make.
Scott: that involves getting rights for the pictures and Such and that it's not always easy.
Scott: But I mean, come on.
Scott: There should always be one Studio Ghibli badge.
Scott: Get with the program people.
Scott: All right, regardless.
Rym: There's nothing wrong with the badges worked out.
Rym: Just fine.
Scott: Yep, just fine.
Rym: We had our GeekNights pool party in the pool, which was awesome.
Rym: Yep, and then we retired to our non overbooked semi-private hotel rooms.
Rym: I'll talk about that on Thursday.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah Thursday, but suffice to say I'm well beyond the.
Rym: cram as many people into a hotel room as I can to save money.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: All I can say is that in the college days when you're poor and you care more about money than anything else because that's your Most limited resource you want to cram as many people into a hotel room as you possibly can without getting in trouble to save Money.
Rym: Oh the other thing Thursday, we were able to check in for our artist alley table.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that was cool That was fantastic.
Rym: And the fact that if we'd wanted to we could have fully set up the artist alley table that night.
Rym: Mad awesome, very awesome.
Scott: I wonder why they don't do that.
Scott: I guess they do do it for the dealers room to some extent.
Scott: but then why does the dealers room open so late Saturday?
Scott: I mean a Friday.
Rym: I mean I think part of the reason is to get people into the con and all that first and of course the dealers room line.
Rym: that Keeps a lot of weirdos out of the way of the rest of the con.
Scott: Well, I'm gonna talk about.
Scott: let's talk about that right now.
Scott: They changed the layout of the con this year.
Scott: what they did is because they didn't have the arena available to them.
Scott: They needed main events that could handle the cosplay and there was a big main events.
Scott: Thus they moved main events from the upstairs where it usually is to the downstairs.
Scott: Thus they had to move the dealers room to a different Location downstairs and also move the artists alley to where the dealers room used to be.
Rym: a lot of people at the con didn't realize Anything had moved.
Scott: well people didn't realize something had moved because they you know They weren't so familiar with the layout.
Scott: But people had been there for many years and observant people noticed like we did and people had never been there before didn't know a thing Changed at all.
Rym: Now.
Rym: Here's what I have to say about that.
Rym: Oh to con.
Rym: I'm saying this directly to you Don't change what you just changed.
Rym: It was great.
Scott: Do not change it at all.
Scott: This layout.
Scott: even if main events was at the arena This layout was a thousand times superior to any previous layer.
Rym: Yes, keep them the secondary main events as a backup main events or something.
Scott: keep make more panel rooms or video rooms I don't know.
Scott: But do not change the layout.
Scott: keep the dealers the main thing.
Scott: the reason this layout was so great Right is number one.
Scott: The artists alley usually has like all its tables and all its art show and then it sort of has this dead space The artists alley this year because it was in the slanted former dealers room room.
Scott: It used all of its space effectively and was awesome.
Scott: Secondly because the dealers room was in a new space The entrance to the dealers room was not directly next to the exit.
Scott: you pass through the dealers room from one end to the other And the exit to the dealers room was under the ridge space, which is a very much Unused space at the cons.
Scott: so anyone leaving the dealers room Was going into an area that basically had zero traffic and con traffic flow was improved Exponentially now
Rym: not just because now there's this better flow But also that space was now open for con goers to be in and that space while it wasn't that big There were a lot of people just chill in there and it kept them from chilling in the way of other people.
Scott: It was a. basically there was a spot in the giant Convention Center That was unused that was now used and that this makes things better all around.
Rym: also just the dealers room layout worked better.
Rym: The artists alley layout was perfect.
Rym: There's
Scott: only one thing I can say bad about this layout is that because the dealers room was the dealers room layout was great But because of the way it was done There was one sort of dead spot in the dealers room Where there wasn't so many people going and the dealers there were kind of like girl No one's are over in this area because we're sort of in the dark corner girl.
Rym: Yeah, but that's such a model that was like ten dealers.
Rym: Maybe from a fan perspective.
Rym: No one cares.
Scott: Yeah, exactly, but from Otakon perspective worst case actually the last unicorn guy was hidden over in that area.
Scott: So I wonder if he was happy or sad about that.
Rym: Yeah, but seriously Otakon don't change it.
Rym: It was perfect.
Scott: Do not change.
Scott: All right.
Scott: so Friday morning Friday morning We were very glad to have that artists alley table because for us at least there wasn't much in the way of events at the We were interested in doing.
Rym: we tried to go to a bunch of panels and they were all already full to capacity or Uninteresting to us.
Scott: I mean we probably could have gone and should have gone to the OZ remix panel Which sort of opens the con and it was really fun last year, but for whatever reason we just didn't go to it.
Rym: Well, plus we had to meet Aaron and Noah and that's right.
Scott: We had to meet people and Gerald Yeah.
Scott: So we sort of got out on the one thing that would have entertained us Friday morning at the con.
Scott: The only problems Friday morning at the con were number one.
Scott: We discovered that you know Some of the escalators were out of commission and were not allowed to be used as stairs Which they do have legitimate reasons for doing that but still annoying.
Rym: Basically, though the way it worked out is they base all the escalators in the middle of the con to get between the levels.
Rym: We're closed off.
Rym: as a result There was basically this super highway on the upper floors to get across the whole con if you wanted to go anywhere.
Scott: And of course as the same case last year the convention center people seem to have a problem Understanding that when the con opens the con opens and there's not just one door that you're gonna let all these people into.
Scott: the con Is open.
Scott: let me and I have a badge, you know Obviously early on Friday some of the entrances need to remain closed because of the registration line of people who did not get their badges Or the forming dealers room line, which we'll talk about.
Scott: Yes, but there are some entrances Especially the harbor, you know food court mall side skyway entrance.
Scott: open it up immediately Goddamn.
Rym: every year Otakon says it'll be open and every year There's some BCC guy in a red shirt getting kind of angry and telling people constantly to go away.
Rym: You can't come in this way.
Rym: Why do you people keep coming to this door?
Scott: It's like a few hours until they finally straighten that out and they let people in that entrance, which they should be doing.
Scott: Also, there's the entrance, you know, there's the part I forget what I should really learn the lobby names, which everyone uses but there's the outer beam.
Scott: Yeah, I know that I know the names but I don't know which one is which see thing is the real names are the registration Lobby and the cosplayer lobby.
Scott: No I'm talking about the lobbies like in the middle where the street goes through the convention center and you can cross.
Scott: you can cross the Street under the sky under the mid mid convention center skywalk to get from one half the convention center to the other.
Rym: Well pro that that little Street there on Friday they blocked it to traffic and that was fantastic.
Scott: Well, they blocked it to traffic for some of the time right which is good.
Scott: But then later in the convention it was open.
Rym: it seemed like most of Friday it was closed But then Saturday the road was open again and then at one point it was open, but they had a really awesome Crossing car.
Rym: Oh, I forgot about that guy.
Rym: There's some BCC guy who was directing.
Scott: He was actually a traffic cop.
Rym: No, he was wearing the red BCC thing.
Scott: I think he was wearing an orange thing.
Scott: Whatever Who he worked for he was awesome.
Rym: He had an orange vest over his BCC uniform, whatever.
Scott: He was an awesome traffic directing guy.
Rym: He was really getting into it and the crowd was cheering for him and I wanted to interview him and shake his hand.
Rym: I just never got around to it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: All I got to say is I saw him like four hours later.
Rym: He kept that energy up all day.
Scott: Awesome You gotta have fun with a boring job like that.
Scott: but that Crop the ability to cross that street is very important because if you do not have that ability The only way to get from one side of the Convention Center to the other is to go all the way to the top floor Cross and then come.
Scott: so if you want to get from the downstairs of one side to the downstairs of the other side It sucks if you can't cross that street, so Obviously, you can't have that open early Friday when the red line is still in effect.
Scott: But as soon as the red line is over that needs to open immediately and stay open now.
Rym: The problem wasn't that they didn't open it right away.
Rym: The problem was that it seemed like randomly throughout the days on Friday Saturday and Sunday The BCC would just suddenly close that door for no reason and not let anyone through for an hour Open it and close it and open it and close it.
Scott: I would prefer if that street remained closed for the entirety of the cons open hours.
Scott: Well, even if the street were closed if the doors were open the doors need to be open when the red lines not as soon As the red line is gone.
Rym: I asked a couple BCC people and off the record They said that it was some union problem with like hours were seems like a lot of things are always union problems.
Rym: Yeah, but of course we can't blame Otakon for that at all.
Rym: They have no say.
Scott: no but I think what the problem is communication because Otakon obviously wants what we want.
Scott: as far as I can tell.
Scott: it just needs to I think better communication between Otakon and the BCC in the openings and closings of doors.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I have this feeling that Otakon probably communicates properly and the BCC just doesn't care.
Scott: Well, then it's communication between.
Scott: you could yell at a wall all day.
Scott: The wall needs to be better.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know which end is failing the communication But the communication is failing.
Rym: regardless of which end though speaking of unions there was always been the problem with the BCC with the food was always like outrageously expensive and for business travelers and really really crappy and There's rules against bringing and the food was not food that we wanted to eat.
Rym: Well last year at Otakon Jim made a big deal about all right, we got him to lower the prices.
Rym: They're gonna work with us and they tried.
Rym: they lowered the prices.
Rym: It was still way too expensive for what you got and kind of crappy this year.
Rym: It was fine.
Rym: The prices were perfectly reasonable.
Rym: the food was pretty good.
Scott: It wasn't perfectly reasonable.
Rym: Yes, it was.
Scott: It was a little bit.
Scott: It was like baseball park prices.
Rym: It was less than that.
Scott: It's a price that you're willing to pay But it's still a lot more money than going to the food court and a real food place.
Scott: It wasn't really.
Rym: I don't know what you're thinking.
Rym: It wasn't nearly four dollars for a ramen.
Rym: Eh, the ramen is marked up.
Rym: However, like the normal snacks two dollars for a pocky Two dollars for a pocky is not that bad.
Scott: That's pretty bad.
Rym: Not really.
Rym: Yeah, it's like a dollar ninety in the grocery store.
Scott: No, it's not a dollar.
Rym: It's a dollar ninety in our grocery store.
Rym: It doesn't matter.
Scott: The prices are fine.
Scott: They're better than they've ever been and they're fine.
Scott: They're fine, but they they're still not the price of the grocery store.
Scott: They're still not the price of a food court.
Rym: Nothing's gonna be the price of a grocery store and the prices for the food were actually really close to the prices at the food.
Scott: Yeah, they're still.
Scott: I won't be a hundred percent satisfied unless the prices are such that I will not leave the Convention Center Because the price is so reasonable and the prices were not that I actually ate a lot of the food and I thought the prices Were perfectly fine.
Scott: $4 for a ramen.
Rym: a ramen a is marked up.
Rym: That's a completely separate $4.
Scott: I can get two cases of Robin.
Rym: Yeah, but you know what.
Rym: you could buy a soda for practically nothing.
Scott: I'm just saying that's they're not a hundred percent reasonable.
Rym: The only thing that was unreasonable was the ramen a that was marked up.
Scott: it was all Too many dollars for a hot dog.
Scott: I forget the exact price wasn't that much money.
Scott: It wasn't that much money, but it was too much.
Rym: several meals in the Convention Center.
Rym: The prices were far less than I pay for food at a baseball game.
Scott: They weren't far less than a baseball game.
Rym: They were.
Rym: yeah, you didn't even go to any of those places.
Rym: You don't even go to the food court.
Scott: I should have taken a picture of the the food price sign as I did last year.
Rym: You didn't even go to those places and eat like I did.
Scott: I saw what the prices were.
Scott: it didn't matter.
Rym: Uh-huh What were they?
Scott: I forget?
Scott: Yeah, I remember the ramen a was.
Rym: Regardless of what Scott says I think the prices are fine and Otakon did a really good job.
Scott: They did do a really good job of getting the prices lowered.
Scott: I'm not denying that.
Scott: I'm not denying the prices are lower than they've ever been and that some of the prices were so low I would have been willing to actually pay them.
Scott: But they are still not low enough for me.
Scott: to actually eat in the con and not leave and get what you want is Unreasonable and unattainable, uh, the same price I pay at the grocery store.
Rym: I don't Scott You're not gonna find no store other than a grocery store sells food for grocery store price price.
Scott: I pay at the food court.
Rym: The food court's food is actually really overpriced and expensive.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: five dollars for a whole meal.
Scott: That's not bad That's.
Scott: that's pretty much what.
Rym: yeah, you get that crappy like China Bowl, whatever.
Scott: I like that.
Scott: It's good stuff nasty food, whatever.
Scott: The food in the Convention Center is better, right?
Rym: Yeah, actually I'd say so it's better than that one China Bowl, whatever.
Scott: I like.
Scott: that wok plays.
Rym: that's really bad Chinese food.
Scott: I like it.
Scott: It's really.
Rym: I stopped eating there like four years ago because that food is just garbage.
Scott: the Italian place over there is actually good.
Rym: No, it's super overpriced.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: It's like three bucks for a slice of cheese pizza.
Scott: It's like two dollars for a slice of pizza.
Scott: three dollars for a stromboli if I remember which is a crappy strombo Strombo.
Rym: That's like Sbarro's pizza.
Scott: Okay, whatever Let's let's continue.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Well, what do you want to continue with hotshot?
Scott: Well, we see.
Scott: Oh, yeah Friday the morning not so hot.
Rym: What are you talking about?
Rym: The morning was great.
Scott: We went straight to our luxury box in the artists alley and hit there Exactly because there was nothing exciting to do for us Friday morning early in the con because we skipped the OC remix panel.
Scott: We ended up spending a lot of time in artists alley before it opened up and that was a lot of fun because ah Relaxing quiet
Rym: at the con to me Even if you're not selling anything in the artists alley and you don't even want to be there Paying for an artist alley table, which is
Scott: what $75 is 70
Rym: I think is basically paying for a luxury box at Otakon a place to go hide a place to sit relax and eat your food.
Scott: Yeah, so even though our artists alley table was kind of eh, you know because we weren't even doing art We were just giving away free flyers and doing other stupid shit.
Rym: Granted I think it was actually far from Ed because a lot of people came and talked to us Especially Saturday after the gecky got panel.
Rym: that happened Friday night.
Rym: the number of people who came to us Specifically to tell us how awesome our panel was was staggering.
Scott: It was however It's good times just sitting there.
Rym: Just going ah Hanging out with the other artists.
Rym: There were cool people on both sides of us.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: All right, so I think in next year We're gonna get all of our friends and try to reserve either half of or possibly most of one of those artist alley islands.
Rym: We'll
Scott: figure out how many tables we're gonna get and we'll get them all adjoining and we'll basically get a whole mess of tables And all the podcasters and all the front row crew peoples will have like this giant artist alley like row Like an alley within the alley of awesome and we can do awesome stuff in the middle, too.
Scott: If we if we get that much space, it'll be pretty cool.
Scott: All right What else is going down?
Scott: Well, I didn't write to our panels Friday.
Rym: We did three of our four panels and it was a light panel load not like the seven we did at Connecticut.
Scott: Yep, especially since we I didn't have to do much for one and a half of the panels.
Rym: Yep, there was the podcasters roundtable, which was alright.
Scott: Yeah I mean basically we the ninja consultants did this panel and all the podcasters got up on stage.
Rym: I will say I think too many people were on stage and I agree much smaller.
Scott: we should have had maybe six people at most.
Scott: I'd say yeah, but basically, we went around and talked about podcasting for an hour and the audience said stuff and we had a good old jolly time, you know Talking to each other on stage.
Rym: credit Most of it was like Scott Dave and Joel talking to each other and ignoring the panel.
Scott: cuz me Dave Joel and Gerald were all Sitting on the way end of the row and we only had one microphone between us So we could say things without them being heard.
Scott: So we were all whispering to each other and making jokes while everyone else is being serious about the panel and it was fun times Though I got to admit my favorite awkward moment was when that she basically asked everyone.
Rym: So, uh, what anime or manga comic or video game?
Rym: Whatever related podcast you guys listen to or like and Dave and Joel are like nothing.
Scott: and then we're like Derek the Bandits out of public.
Rym: That's not anime related damn straight.
Rym: I gave a shot Byzantine emperors.
Rym: I gave a mad shout out to 12 Byzantine emperors And they're like, but don't you like any anime podcast?
Rym: I'm like no Except for us animal order and Dave and Joel.
Scott: Yeah, and then you consultants are like, you don't like us.
Scott: And I was like I listen to you.
Scott: sometimes I do listen to them.
Rym: sometimes, you know, I've never actually listened to them.
Scott: I'll be honest They don't put out too many shows and some of their shows I'm not interested in.
Scott: but when they do put out a show that I'm interested in, you know I check their website maybe once every couple weeks.
Rym: I've never listened to the ninja consultants.
Rym: I listened to our five central once.
Scott: when Gerald I Listen to wants to figure out what it was about I might listen to it - I guess he didn't know to con report or he's gonna.
Scott: so I'll.
Scott: maybe I'll listen to that.
Scott: I'll pretty much listen to any Otakon report podcast.
Scott: So if anyone out there has a podcast with an Otakon report, I will listen to it Except this one because everyone recorded the panel.
Rym: We probably have the best audio of anyone because it was just people putting the recorders in the middle of the table.
Scott: Yeah, they put like their eye rivers and their creatives ends like on the table and push the button and we put our Marantz on The table and push the button.
Rym: now I will say this isn't really a complaint about Otakon.
Rym: But I gotta say while the people who do all the sound and audio-visual setup for all the rooms do a fantastic job There's a company called DSL and at Otakon that Otakon basically pays this company What must be a hajillion dollars, right?
Scott: And this company provides all of the audio-visual equipment for everything at Otakon from main events to the lowliest panel room And they do a good job.
Rym: These guys know their stuff.
Scott: They're worth what Otakon pays them.
Rym: Yeah So I got to say anytime you see a panelist at Otakon who has trouble with their audio or trouble with their video and their Laptop, it is their fault and not Otakon's because Otakon's got their shit together.
Scott: Well DSL has their shit together and Otakon just says DSL handle it.
Rym: Otakon By proxy has their shit together exactly.
Rym: but DSL for two years running does not have the ability to give me a feed from their equipment to record every year.
Scott: I say they do it's just low-quality.
Rym: No, they don't they don't.
Rym: not low quality not exist in quality every year.
Rym: They say hey Here we'll give you a mono feed.
Rym: is XLR okay, and I think oh great.
Rym: and then I plug it in and I discover that the signal-to-noise ratio is to the point that you Can't hear anything but static.
Scott: I think the problem is is that the equipment DSL uses is meant for you know being PA in a room and Making a loud noise that everyone turning a quiet noise into a loud noise.
Scott: So a lot of people can hear it and their equipment is used heavily shipped around a lot It's it's beat up and old and they basically don't replace anything unless they absolutely have to And it's not working.
Scott: So the if the the feature of being able to record the feed to recording device is not something they care about at all And thus a lot of their mixers are old and slightly combusted and will provide very noisy outputs for recording Especially since there's a lot of amplification going on which is their primary purpose is amplification.
Rym: Yep now the best part was the guy was like well you sure your Equipment's good because I think I can given you a fine signal and I am absolutely certain that the guy was giving me nothing But said yeah, I was giving.
Rym: you said he tried to play it off Like you should put a pad in front of it.
Rym: My signal might be too strong for you.
Rym: That is slightly possible.
Rym: No, it's not.
Rym: I I humored him and tried it and of course all that did was make the static 20 decibels quieter.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Anyway, the only complaint I can have about the AV at Otakon is that in a lot of the rooms?
Scott: They have speakers in the front turned up way loud so that the audio can be heard in the back.
Scott: the result is if you sit in the way back you can hear but you can't see and if you sit in the way front you Can see but hearing is kind of bad.
Scott: plus it there's no stadium seating anywhere at Otakon so you can see.
Scott: But if a tall guy with a cosplay sits in front of you forget about it.
Rym: All they need to do is stagger the chairs.
Rym: They need to stagger
Scott: the chairs and even if it costs a lot more money It's worth it to pay to put speakers in the back and possibly the sides of the larger rooms So that the volume is even throughout instead of you know, normal versus my ears hurt well.
Rym: at the same time the real problem is that the vast majority of people who do anything at Otakon don't know how to use a Microphone and they either get way too close to the market.
Scott: more about video rooms.
Rym: with the audio I avoid video rooms, but I heard those complaints.
Rym: but in terms of panels Everyone like grabbed the microphone and tried to swallow it and as a result everything was booming and loud and echoing and horrible.
Scott: There really needs to be some sort of thing where people use microphones properly.
Scott: I mean at the podcasting panel, there was some guy sitting next to us who I didn't know.
Scott: He's the only guy in the panel I didn't know and I was trying.
Scott: every time he talked he would lean up on the table to get into the microphone.
Scott: I'd be like dude just sit still the microphone is close enough pretty much ignore told him like three times Listen I started pulling the microphone away from him and he just kept leaning further and further over the table.
Scott: I don't know what his problem was.
Scott: Was he just deaf?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: He's a podcaster.
Scott: He can't be deaf I don't know.
Rym: I've listened to a lot of podcasts in my day.
Scott: Oh All right, so that was that panel.
Rym: yeah, it was alright it was fun.
Scott: Yep, did they do the anime club panel, which did not involve us actually.
Rym: Well, it involved me.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is I'm our friend Scott Johnson ran it and he's you know He's been a new type before.
Rym: he knows his shit when it comes to running anime clubs.
Scott: He does know and actually comes turning anime club.
Rym: after all of our prodding.
Rym: He has finally started to work on his website to tell everyone exactly how to run an anime club because he pretty much knows Exactly how to run an anime club down to every single detail.
Rym: Yep, but I will say Through not much fault of his own the anime club summit that was run at Otakon was pretty damn piss-poor And I was kind of embarrassed to be on it.
Scott: Yeah, I was sitting there in the audience kind of playing my DS and going "errrrrrr".
Rym: I was sitting to the side like far away from everyone else kind of lounging drinking something that looks suspiciously like water but might not have been.
Rym: and Basically, it was He'd say something.
Rym: the other panelists would kind of sit there or they'd kind of mumble a little bit or they'd ramble a Nonsensical story for a while and then I'd be like well Here's the deal and I'd tell the whole deal and the whole crowd would laugh and then Scojo would say something all crowd would Laugh and everyone else was just kind of there.
Scott: Yeah, basically the people there were kind of nervous not quick on their feet.
Rym: I know that they know their stuff.
Rym: They just they they need to.
Rym: I'm gonna be perfectly honest.
Rym: They need to be better at speaking and speaking.
Rym: Yes, the panel should have just been me and Scott Johnson or just Scott Johnson.
Rym: He alone could have done that panel.
Scott: Yeah a lot of those people on that panel are there because they run big anime clubs and they have lots of experience and knowledge.
Scott: but Public speaking skills preparation for the panel not so much.
Rym: Yes And I was so bad because I could tell Scojo would say something like blah blah blah.
Rym: and we've run these panels before expecting someone on the panel to pick up and continue the thought and they just kind of sit there and then everyone would look at Me and I'd be like well and talk for 10 minutes.
Scott: You could have done the panel on your own.
Scott: We did the panel.
Scott: I think excellently.
Rym: a kinetic I gotta say that the anime club panel Scott and I ran in Connecticut was probably the best anime club.
Scott: Scott Johnson, yes this Scott.
Rym: Yes, though if Scott Johnson had been there the panel would have only been better because he does know his stuff.
Scott: Yep I think that the key is to get one person someone on the panel who knows enough and knows what topics to discuss Right and is good at public speaking.
Scott: and if there's someone with the knowledge who isn't good at public speaking Then the public speaking person can manage them and get them to reveal their knowledge in a good way without having them ruin the panel.
Rym: The other thing is and Scott and I did Scott Johnson and I disagree on this don't let the audience talk They're just gonna ask stupid questions or try to plug their own club or plug their own stuff or try to sound smart.
Rym: if you Want to take questions from the audience in a panel like that have someone with a wireless mic.
Rym: go around like I did in the kendo Panel talk to the people off the microphone while the panels going on find out what their question is and then decide if they are Going to be given the mic or if you're going to ask the question for them.
Scott: That should be done in every panel ever period.
Rym: now were I Otakon I would find people.
Rym: hum I wonder who?
Rym: I wonder who's volunteered to do panel stuff for Otakon for the last four years?
Rym: Yeah, find people who would be willing to go to a bunch of panels take the wireless mic around moderate officiate MC and take questions for the panelists.
Rym: because I got to say Almost no panelists at Otakon who aren't industry know anything about dealing with the crowd.
Rym: they might know their stuff and do a good panel, but they don't know how to take questions from a crowd.
Rym: and Actually, there were a lot of complaints about just that at the con feedback session.
Scott: Another problem is that actually a lot of panels they take questions from the crowd without a microphone at all.
Scott: So no one can hear what the crowd is saying at all Like when you were asking questions at the Bandai visual panel.
Scott: I've watched the video recording of the Bandai visual panel on anime news network.
Scott: Well, I skimmed through it.
Scott: I didn't watch the whole thing and You couldn't hear any audience question at all because they never gave the audience the microphone to ask questions.
Scott: They just yelled it out and not everyone is loud.
Rym: We should probably talk about that panel briefly All right.
Rym: So Bandai visual did their thing.
Rym: then of course pretty much everyone in the room was there Specifically to call them out on the pricing again.
Scott: So, you know Bandai visual is a American company that releases Anime, they're pretty new.
Scott: They're not the same as Bandai entertainment.
Scott: They have nothing to do with like the Gundam seed release the cowboy bebop release or anything like that.
Scott: They're there.
Scott: they're releasing basically these awesome mostly awesome anime shows that are kind of old and that we really like like the gun buster and The what other ones I forget but mostly gun buster now as well as other awesome animes.
Scott: pat labore Yeah, I forget but they're releasing many awesome animes that we want to watch.
Scott: the problem is they're releasing them in a freedom Obviously, they're releasing them in a format which we don't give a shit about.
Scott: they are releasing them in like super HD super high-quality Amazing whatever's for like 40 bucks for two episodes.
Scott: It's yeah to Chris.
Rym: now There have been famous panels and other cars where people called this guy out.
Scott: Yeah at Sakura con They called this guy out and basically when he this guy the same guy was doing the same panel and he's like yeah at Sakura con I had a trouble blah blah blah and he pretty much said we will not change the price.
Rym: Yep, but the question was asked like four different times at the panel and he kind of just basically said yeah We know there's nothing we can do about it.
Scott: I mean the question I asked was You know, I understand you're not going to change the price But you understand that there are other anime companies which are selling like 26 episodes for $30 and you're selling five episodes for $50.
Rym: you understand this five episodes more like two.
Scott: Well, there wasn't one disc in particular.
Scott: They were selling five episodes for $50.
Scott: I think it's one of their cheaper discs actually and I'll take you understand this right.
Scott: and he was like, yep Yep, we under I'm like, all right I'm Netflixing your shit and not buying it.
Rym: Yep, but I asked a question about Renting and a Netflix and all that sort of thing and he didn't really understand it.
Rym: He answered a different question.
Rym: But yeah, the thing is a lot of people give this guy grief and he's doing the best He can.
Rym: it's not his fault.
Rym: He's a pretty nice guy.
Scott: He is the head of Bandai Visual though.
Rym: Yeah I have a feeling that the company realizes that they have possibly made a mistake and for whatever reason can't back down now.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Maybe they've already made some decisions and it's too late.
Scott: whatever The point is Bandai Visual rent all their anime.
Scott: if an anime is put out by Bandai Visual rent it and watch it.
Scott: Don't buy it unless it gets really cheap in a bargain bin.
Rym: I recorded the whole panel.
Rym: I'm not gonna bother.
Scott: you can watch the whole panel on anime news network in video.
Rym: Yeah, mostly I recorded just about everything at Otakon not for you guys, but just for our own reference.
Scott: Yep Okay, so now let's talk about the important panel.
Rym: So Friday night after the podcast immediately after the podcast Yes as an 18 plus and we had an awesome staff or who helped us work all that out.
Rym: Yep, I fall.
Rym: I wish I knew that guy's name.
Scott: Let's talk about 18 plus to the con for a second.
Scott: All right at Otakon There some events are 18 plus which means you need to be 18 years or older to get in.
Scott: Usually these are hentai panels and such.
Scott: In order to get into these panels You can't just show up at the panel with your ID.
Scott: The reasoning behind this is that they don't want to have someone at the door checking ID because it takes forever.
Scott: They would rather have you check ID at some other point in time at some other place.
Scott: Then they give you a wristband and then it's really easy to check wristbands.
Scott: It's like yes.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yes Yes, yes and the panel rooms can go smoothly.
Rym: the other reason is that pretty much without fail all of the 18 plus programming because it tends To be Friday and Saturday night when everyone's itching to do something Already are gonna fill and a lot of people are gonna be turned away.
Rym: So anything you can do to streamline the process and
Scott: not have a giant line at the door
Rym: If someone didn't plan ahead and get their wristband to get in There are a lot of people who would probably rather see the panel than the one person who decided the last minute to go walk Into it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So those are the reasons they do it that way.
Scott: I personally think there could be a better way But I'm not sure how.
Scott: I'm not sure what it is and it does solve some problems.
Scott: I also do think that maybe they could.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: but whatever It's also I mean it is widely Publicized that you need to get the wristband but not widely publicized enough.
Scott: It could be done a little bit better.
Rym: I think they just need to have one big warning in the con book.
Rym: Their priority is I didn't read it There is it's not it's not super big But they need at least one big sign at the registration line saying maybe they could say something to you when you get your badge ah Or maybe you could get certified badges or something.
Scott: Yeah, like when you get your badge they could be like are you planning to go to any 18+ events and they you already show Them your ID when you get your badge, right?
Scott: So why not like, you know put a thing on the badge?
Scott: when I guess you can't put a thing on the badge It has to be a wristband because you could just give your badge to a kid.
Rym: Yeah, regardless it works Well enough as they do it.
Rym: Yep So they cleared the room out.
Rym: the staffer warned everyone like a bunch of times that it's gonna be some sort of horrible offensive panel Like these panels always are.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now I'm gonna tell you all our secret.
Rym: originally We'd planned to just do this Scott and I just like we done at Connecticut and We wanted to make it 18+ Just to guarantee ourselves the awesome Friday or Saturday night time slot and we weren't planning to do anything really horrible.
Scott: Well, the other thing is that we had noticed that in years past the 18+ panels at Otakon filled up to the brim with people.
Scott: So we said hey our panels don't usually fill up to the brim.
Scott: if we made it 18+ Even if it didn't need to be 18+ Maybe a bunch of perverts would come and then we could do a double switch and educate them when they thought they were gonna be titillated.
Rym: of course Gerald really wanted to do this panel with us and we like Gerald.
Rym: So we decided to actually go with the 18+ content and let Gerald do whatever he wanted.
Scott: Yes The idea was we'd lure them in with this awesome 18+ content and also educate them at the same time.
Scott: So it would be humorous pos- I don't think titillating but humorous.
Rym: Well, I hope not titillating.
Scott: No, it would be humorous and sexually charged and violent and educational all at once so that people would leave our panel being Entertained shocked and educated and generally have a good feeling about it.
Rym: now on that front I think we succeeded because not only did we get a full-on standing ovation and not only did only Three people walk out of the panel in disgust.
Scott: I didn't even I wasn't paying it.
Scott: That's one thing.
Scott: when I'm doing a panel like I look at the audience But I'm not paying attention to people coming and going.
Scott: or how many people are there?
Rym: So it's oh see I actually I say I count people in the panel room.
Rym: I count how many people come in late accounting people leave.
Rym: I can't keep an eye on everyone in the panel and see if they're interested.
Rym: Anyone looks like they're trying to say something.
Scott: if anyone looks like they're not having a good people trying to say something I usually notice because they'll raise their hand or they'll go up something.
Rym: But of the three people who stormed out in disgust one of them stormed out right away And I think he just he thought the panel was about something else.
Scott: I think I didn't realize this at first, but we titled our panel get he got putting the man back in manga.
Rym: I think a lot of people thought it was a yaoi panel.
Scott: I didn't even realize that like.
Scott: it didn't even occur to me that it could be misconstrued in family panel.
Rym: two different people came by the artist alley table and said man I thought you guys were running yaoi panel, but what you ran was awesome.
Rym: So I stayed.
Scott: yep, but yeah next time We'll just come up with a better name for it.
Rym: The other two people who walked out in disgust were actually good friends of ours and they walked out at the very end.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, so man a lot of people on the Internet's were actually oh that girl sitting in the back and I was like That was my friend.
Rym: Yeah, so many people came up to us and we're like man.
Rym: I hope no one complained about your panel that that girly rock walked out.
Rym: She seemed super pissed and I was like, she's a really good friend of ours.
Rym: Don't worry about it.
Rym: Yeah Actually, I was kind of sad.
Rym: I wish she'd made more of a stink because I totally wanted to go Orlando Calrissian on her.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway We ran this panel and since we failed to bring any visual aids basically me and Raim gave our educational talks about the history of manga the history of Gekiga Osamu Tezuka and all these awesome manga because they're full of Politics and Yakuza and things like that.
Rym: It was basically the same panel.
Rym: We ran at Connecticut only I Wasn't tired and exhausted and there were a lot more people.
Scott: Yep so we did that and Interspersed with that Gerald showed the awesomest scenes from Kazuo Koike mangas Awesomest being a relative term exactly.
Scott: basically if you read something like sanctuary, right sanctuary I'd say 90% of the pages perhaps 95% of the pages in sanctuary involve Yakuza drama politics or something or something along those lines.
Scott: But 5% of the pages contain some sort of eroticism, you know Sometimes rape sometimes a tree hookers an eyeball sometimes people getting shot and your crazy things happen.
Scott: and That's just the style of these manga.
Scott: is that there is you know, very I guess not realistic But wanting to be realistic plots and they combine it with.
Scott: you know, when sex happens when violence happens They don't hold back and illustrating it.
Rym: so basically was the three of us being educational for a while and then Gerald showing the choice bits from Kazuo Koike manga.
Scott: So if you read.
Rym: watching the crowd react to these scene was amazing because basically the crowd would be like ha Laugh laugh laugh laugh even louder.
Rym: Laugh riotously Laugh quietly and nervously.
Rym: Yeah go.
Rym: Ah.
Rym: But then start laughing.
Scott: cuz if you read a Kazuo Koike manga that isn't lone wolf and cub, right You'll notice that you know, it'll be this very serious Usually historical, you know sort of melodrama.
Scott: That's pretty awesome.
Scott: And then a kid when there's a crazy scene will happen Kazuo Koike just goes all out and does the craziest most rapist Violent fucked up thing.
Rym: you can imagine which is kind.
Rym: I mean, that's gecky god.
Rym: That's part of it.
Scott: That's part of it.
Scott: It's not necessary to the I guess artistic movement, but that that that's what Kazuo Koike does, you know.
Scott: Imagine if like, you know You're.
Scott: just imagine if the matrix instead of the scenes with the cool action fighting were scenes with like just crazy Necrophilia something I don't know.
Rym: now to quote Gerald the panel might have been too hardcore for Otakon.
Scott: I think the panel was too hardcore for pretty much Most anime conventions, but that's okay because we're hardcore.
Rym: Well, the thing is the only real issue with our panel and we realized it after the fact I didn't think it would have been as big of an issue is that We were busy and did not prepare our visual aids partly because we couldn't find our copies of sanctuary Because we're dumb shits.
Rym: Emily had moved them off.
Scott: I still can't find them.
Rym: They're right there.
Rym: They were moved up one shelf.
Scott: I just looked.
Scott: they weren't there.
Rym: They're.
Scott: they're gonna go look after the show regardless.
Rym: Emily moved them up one shelf and we were stupid and couldn't find him.
Rym: All right, so we didn't come with any visual aids, but Gerald had all of his visual aids.
Scott: So, of course while equal time was given to our educational miss and Gerald's crazy awesomeness in quotes the crazy awesomeness seemed to take over the mind share of the panel because it was visual whereas ours was just us talking.
Rym: granted it It didn't seem to matter because seriously the panel was a rousing success and the number of people who told us it was awesome or Demanded that we give them contact information so they could check out our show.
Rym: We got so many listeners from that panel good God and Katsucon was already like.
Scott: you were running that exact panel at Katsucon Aaron writer who is the guy who I think he's the head of programming at Katsucon.
Scott: now, right?
Scott: He was the head of gaming at Katsucon last whatever he is.
Rym: He's a big shot and he's also a really cool guy.
Scott: He's awesome.
Scott: I like him a lot.
Scott: He's way cool.
Scott: He helped us out at Katsucon last year awesomely and he was at our gecky got panel and he was awesome And he's still awesome.
Scott: Awesome guy.
Scott: Aaron writer Alright, so then we were done for the night.
Scott: Our panel was like midnight to 1 a.m.
Scott: We went back to our hotel room and then rims phone rang.
Scott: But he didn't pick it up because he's looked at the phone number.
Scott: He didn't know who it was and then my phone rang.
Scott: So I picked it up and it was the person from panels at Otakon and I. they're like Can you come back to the con?
Scott: and I was like, uh, I don't know Rym Can we go back to the con?
Scott: Obviously our panel was intense and we're gonna get in trouble.
Rym: I was like, alright, whatever We'll go back.
Scott: So we went back Badgeless, I didn't bring my badge in case they tried to take it away.
Scott: I wouldn't have it.
Rym: I didn't bring my badge because I didn't think I needed my badge.
Scott: Yeah We didn't need our badge because the staff person brought us right through.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So we go back and they bring us in and we're worried like alright did people complain about the panel?
Scott: Which I'm gonna get in trouble.
Scott: I mean it wasn't 18 plus panel.
Scott: What are we gonna get in trouble?
Rym: The thing is the two reasons why I didn't think we were in trouble is that one come few years ago?
Rym: Otakon showed without an 18 plus anything.
Rym: that is another thing Ola syndrome.
Scott: I gotta say Otakon they do this 18 plus panel business but they show things in the video rooms late at night Friday and Saturday with no 18 plus checking and I actually think they should Have 18 plus checking on some of that.
Rym: Yeah, because seriously if you're under 18, you should not have been able to watch Ebola syndrome.
Scott: You should not be watching each of the killer.
Scott: You probably shouldn't be watching killing machine, which I'll talk about soon enough.
Rym: Yeah well The worst thing was that Ebola syndrome pretty much headlined like one of the opening scenes was something worse than pretty much our All of Gerald's part of our panel combined.
Rym: Yes, so like one scene.
Scott: so there was no way.
Scott: I thought we were gonna actually get in serious trouble because I would have whipped out.
Scott: Well, you showed Ebola syndrome at this con, you know, what happens in Ebola syndrome.
Scott: You showed each of the killer at this con.
Scott: Nothing we did was worse than each of the killer.
Rym: and the other thing was that I remember from the panel.
Rym: Not only did no one walk out in disgust except one guy who walked out in the beginning before anything horrible.
Scott: Yeah, he made.
Scott: he walked out when he made our disclaimer and described what the panel was gonna be about.
Rym: We were basically like this is going to be a very offensive panel talking about some old very sexist Japanese literature.
Scott: I think Gerald actually started the panel with who likes rape?
Rym: Yeah, yeah, yeah, so people were fully warned as to what the panel may or may not be about.
Rym: yeah, but also no one else walked out and Every every single person who was in the room gave a standing ovation.
Scott: Yep So I think what had happened is Khan somehow heard that I guess From people walking around or I don't know how they heard or maybe someone did complain that stayed the whole time.
Scott: I don't know that our panel was like a rape Glorifying panel of some sort which if you walked in at the wrong time and stayed for the wrong amount of time It could be construed as such easily, but it was not in any way.
Rym: I think the main reason for that was that now I realize I think I'm gonna put my mr Tokai rape allegory section comparison at the end of the panel.
Rym: Yep, followed by the ode to cure.
Scott: Yeah, so if we just rearrange the panel we can avoid all possibilities of Misconstruing what the pen.
Rym: if anything I want to start with Gerald stuff and then move into the educational and say See as horrible as that is.
Rym: look what it turned into.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's a good move, too.
Rym: But regardless by the time we get there cuz it took us a while to walk back to the con.
Rym: the staffer the Otakon staffer who had been in the room for the entire panel who had kicked all the young kids out and who Would basically run everything for us had already been there defending us and telling the people who were concerned how awesome our panel was.
Scott: Yep, so mad props to that awesome guy.
Scott: He knew what the score was.
Scott: He knew our panel was awesome.
Rym: So I think it was as dang from the staff was there and actually the panels person Meredith the whole time It was like I'm sorry to bring you out here.
Rym: Don't worry about it.
Rym: Just just don't worry about it.
Rym: Come on in.
Rym: Yeah, so everyone everyone is super apologetic and we finally get there.
Rym: He's like so, uh, I heard some things What was your panel about?
Scott: and then we explained what our panel was about and he basically said oh I'm less angry now that I know what your panels about and this taff guy says you're not lying.
Scott: So you're okay Yep, and we're like, yes, we understand.
Rym: now I think we could do a whole show about how to get out of trouble or how to not get in trouble.
Rym: But it's very simple be us.
Scott: You won't get in trouble.
Rym: There's not be us.
Rym: It's more simple than it act like it frickin.
Rym: professional I mean.
Rym: we recorded the whole panel not for to put in the show or anything But just because that's what professionals do.
Rym: we keep archival footage.
Rym: We cover our butts.
Rym: We do everything by the book.
Rym: We're prepared for any eventuality.
Rym: if someone had been offended at the panel We were ready to deal with that and explain ourselves.
Scott: Yep, and it didn't take much to avoid any sort of trouble.
Scott: I think it also helped that the panel was super popular and also that we didn't do anything actually stupid like I don't know Live reenactments.
Rym: we did do live reenact.
Scott: I met live reenactment actually the other stuff.
Rym: Scott and I reenacted a scene from sanctuary and That Specific moment was cited by almost ten people as being the most awesome part of the panel.
Scott: It was a good part.
Scott: I think we should get in the panel.
Rym: a non from Apple geeks came over and class my shoulder and was and he wants to read Sanctuary and Eagle so hard he could cry now.
Scott: Yeah, I think we should do that reenactment again.
Scott: But if you actually show the manga on the screen while we do it, yeah, that'd be pretty cool.
Rym: Plus, I think you said the line wrong, but it didn't matter because you said these the same line in spirit.
Scott: Yep, I think I actually did say the same line.
Rym: No, cuz I think he said it hurts so much I could cry.
Rym: that's what I said.
Rym: You said it hurts like hell did I?
Scott: Yeah Doesn't matter.
Scott: I think cuz that just now when I said I'm pretty sure the line is it hurts so much I could cry at least as translated in the Viz publication.
Rym: Yeah, not like try gun where the bad translation was actually better than the real translation in that one scene.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah All right, regardless the gecky got panel.
Rym: Expect to see the final polished version at Katsucon and the New York and we're gonna do it at the New York Anime Festival I'm pretty sure.
Rym: Oh, man.
Rym: I gotta work out the details.
Rym: still is probably just gonna be you and me but The New York Anime Festival we met the guy Peter to terror who I've been working with.
Rym: I think the New York Anime Festival is gonna be hot the more I learn about it.
Rym: They're doing everything right.
Scott: at first I was Apprehensive because it's an anime convention in New York City in the Javits.
Scott: That's a recipe for disaster.
Scott: It's being run by read exhibitions the same people who run the New York Comic Con.
Scott: further recipe for disaster According to the book of Scott only because anime cons are not like comic con.
Scott: Yes, however Every all the signs.
Scott: now after learning about the New York Anime Festival and speaking to people who are closer involved with it They are outsourcing.
Scott: I don't know how much of it is official.
Scott: So don't believe everything.
Scott: I don't give any specifics, but but they're Outsourcing a core.
Scott: from what I have heard in the rumor mill a lot of the things at their convention to
Rym: People
Scott: who have done it before like I heard that they're letting Katsucon Which has excellent video gaming do their video gaming and they're letting someone else who does excellent video rooms do their video rooms.
Scott: Thus, they don't have to learn how to do anime con things from scratch.
Scott: They're letting people who have already done it for many many years do it at their con.
Scott: in addition Thus, basically, it's sort of like the best of the best like the anime northeast anime cons greatest hits in a way And I hope that's what it turns out to be.
Scott: I'm still not a hundred percent confident.
Scott: It'll be awesome.
Scott: But the more I learn the more confidence I get.
Rym: we're running some shows there So I think it's gonna be good.
Scott: It'll be good.
Scott: The parts that we do will be good even if the rest of the con fails because we will not let our parts go down.
Scott: Well, we won't let it happen, all right.
Rym: So the fact that we had all our panels on Friday was great because Saturday We pretty much just relaxed in our artist alley table took turns talking to people.
Rym: We met a lot of awesome people.
Rym: I'm not gonna even try to do shout outs.
Scott: People are awesome.
Scott: If you met us, there you go.
Rym: people didn't meet us not as awesome And of course by next year because like I promised we were very close to having all the swag done.
Rym: next year I think we're gonna have a double wide table and we'll be selling all sorts of GeekNights stuff as Supposed to giving you a piece of paper and doing surveys.
Scott: Yeah, the only things I could say about the artists alley is that the running of the artists alley awesome perfect in every way.
Scott: the guy Who ran it also awesome.
Scott: the art show run awesomely.
Scott: not as much art I was interested in as last year.
Rym: I don't know for me.
Rym: I thought it was better than last year.
Rym: Really?
Scott: Two years ago was the one I'm thinking.
Rym: Yeah, but the quality of the art not just in the art show But in the art Sally as a whole was like super high this year.
Scott: average I think the average quality was way super high.
Scott: like there was no bad art in the artists alley like.
Scott: so the average of the Quality of art was like way up there.
Scott: They're just.
Scott: personally there was not as many things that caught my eye and made me really excited.
Scott: There was like one person by these awesome stickers and I bought all their stickers.
Scott: They're awesome.
Scott: I wish I had the stickers to tell you their website.
Scott: But other than that it was like, oh, that's really cool.
Scott: That's really cool.
Scott: That's pretty awesome.
Scott: But nothing that was like, oh man's I need this his money I don't mean personally.
Rym: the things I really wanted were but I'd we bit Scott bit on it and it went for way.
Scott: I was in the art show.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, there was the curry beau shoe art.
Rym: That was awesome.
Scott: No, she was.
Rym: there was all those renditions of the Greek gods that were just.
Scott: those are also.
Rym: Oh my gosh I would have paid a lot of money for those but they went for even more than I wanted to pay.
Scott: I should have written down who did them to contact them if anyone remembers because Seriously that was some hot shit.
Scott: That was very hot.
Rym: Also, I'm we recorded something there, but I'm not gonna bother find it and play in it.
Rym: But in the 18 plus area of the art show there was something awesome in there.
Rym: There was something fantastic In there.
Rym: usually the 18 plus area of the Otakon art show is always really meager and filled with really bad art.
Scott: Not it's really like a naked furry To yaoi guys an anime character naked.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's nothing really horrendous like oh god discuss Always like poorly drawn and crappy.
Scott: It's nothing that's really good.
Scott: It's nothing really bad or scary.
Scott: It's just like some nudes and you're like, whatever what the hell is this for this year?
Scott: There was barely anything in there whatsoever.
Scott: There was like one tiny nude and Two things that were awesome in it.
Scott: Do I just say what they were?
Rym: no because I have the recording is of us when we went in there and I'll just save That for a special.
Rym: Okay, cool suffice to say that was one of the highlights of my con see.
Scott: in retrospect We should have bid it enough.
Scott: So it was forced to go into the odd ha ha that would have been so classic But we were not.
Scott: we didn't think of that until it was too late on Sunday when the art show was over.
Rym: Now the last big thing we did at Otakon on Saturday.
Rym: Well, we can talk about the dealers room in a minute But okay, basically our friend katsu because we always do a million panels of cons.
Rym: and this year, you know I told all our friends Hey, do you want to do a panel?
Rym: and katsu one of the few people we know who stepped up and said, you know What I'm awesome at kendo.
Rym: I'm a certified kendo instructor.
Rym: I'm a yonder.
Scott: I think we pushed him to do it.
Rym: We did is also but he decided to do a kendo panel and Basically he for an hour without a microphone in a standing room only busting at the seams room With just did a panel that we filmed.
Rym: James filmed.
Rym: It was Absolutely amazing.
Rym: I was on the panel, but all I did was MC it like straight up.
Rym: I did what every panelist should have from Otakon.
Rym: I introduced him I took questions in the audience and other than that I hid behind the speakers and didn't say a word.
Rym: Katsu had the audience on the edge of their seats.
Rym: It was an amazing panel.
Rym: He is going to be busting some shit up at katsu con.
Scott: Yeah, I heard the awesomeness of this panel But I did not go to this panel because I was happen in the artist alley.
Rym: Remember katsu was a kendo instructor.
Rym: He ran it like a professional College class on kendo and he basically just took questions in the audience and demonstrated and it was fantastic.
Rym: and when the panel ended no one wanted to leave and a crowd of people followed katsu out and Pestered him for another half hour.
Rym: Yep, and I felt bad for the panel that came in after because no one stayed.
Rym: But we've got a video.
Rym: we're probably gonna get it up on YouTube at some point because it's fantastic Yep, and the cool thing is Aaron writer the katsu gun guy came up to me after it and basically said wait a minute.
Rym: So it's not just you two.
Rym: Are you telling me that the whole front row crew can just do panels like that whenever they want?
Rym: pretty much and I was like You realize that the people in the front row crew combined could run all of the content at an entire anime con.
Rym: Probably I think we could between all of the help from the podcasting friends.
Scott: But that's about.
Rym: I think the extended front row crew alone has enough panel front row crew and associates.
Scott: Yes, definitely.
Rym: So, uh, once again expect some fucking busting out at Katsucon.
Rym: Alright, we want to try to make katsu the spokesperson of Katsucon Maybe?
Scott: alright, so dealer's room.
Rym: Alright, the dealer's room was gigantic.
Rym: It was great and had everything you want out of a dealer's room.
Scott: a lot less porn than usual Yep, there was a lot more swords than usual.
Scott: The layout was improved a lot less industry presence than in the past.
Rym: The industry good and bad that was there was back to its former glory with all the spectacle.
Scott: Well, mostly Bandai visual with their HD theater showing freedom, which yeah was nice But I have no desire for that.
Scott: and the full spectacle had not returned.
Scott: the full spectacle was the year that a TV had the Honda Civic full of merchandise and Hot booth babes making you take a survey about the anime network for a chance to win said car.
Scott: That was the spectacle.
Rym: Well, I think that's slowly returning.
Rym: I'm hoping.
Scott: I think it's actually declining.
Scott: as I see most of the people had the big booths in the spectacle in the past were the manga publishers like viz and Tokyo pop and I've noticed that recently they have been going to the comic cons for their business and they're sort of disrespecting the fan-run anime conventions, but yeah anyway Dealers room Pretty awesomely run.
Rym: There were super deals on DVDs.
Rym: I bought all of utenna.
Rym: I bought all of haibana.
Scott: There's one place that had these super deals.
Scott: on TV.
Rym: you could get all of slayers for like 75 bucks And when I say all of slayers, I mean all three seasons.
Scott: Yeah, if you wanted bad manga or old manga No one cared about.
Scott: it was easy to get in quantity for very cheap like five bucks or less per manga.
Scott: But the selection on that manga was pretty weak, you know.
Scott: So you had to get something you probably didn't like.
Rym: Connecticut had a much better manga deal selection.
Scott: Well, that was mostly because that one dealer that I forget kamikopia.
Scott: Yeah, they have excellent manga awesome deals.
Scott: But yeah, the thing is in terms of what was there.
Scott: there wasn't that much I wanted to buy.
Scott: I bought a Galaxy Express post.
Rym: Well, I'm really beyond buying all the little trinkets.
Rym: I mean, I've got boxes full of various.
Scott: I wanted to buy this one Pokemon PVC of Spiritomb and they didn't have it.
Scott: at WYSIWYG.
Scott: They had everything else in the set.
Scott: There was one guy who had sealed boxes of the set But I would have had to pay too much to get the set even though I thought about buying it and giving it to all My friends.
Scott: WYSIWYG was selling it for $2 each figure.
Scott: that would have come out to like $32 for the box Which I was willing to pay.
Scott: this other guy was selling it for $3.
Scott: So it would have been like Some a lot more money for the box and I wasn't willing to pay that even if it was for all my friends.
Scott: So and especially since I wanted one figure from the set the Spiritomb.
Rym: Yeah The thing is more and more.
Rym: I think Scott and I both.
Rym: I don't want to sound like oh, we're too.
Rym: But I feel like I want to buy the quote-unquote classy things in the dealers room.
Rym: exactly and by classy I mean the thing I want the most are like old Leiji Matsumoto posters from back in the day.
Scott: That's what I got.
Scott: I got a Leiji Matsumoto poster.
Rym: The thing is while they might have been free or cheap when they were you know out there And you can just get them.
Rym: They're kind of hard to find now.
Rym: So they're always like 20 to 40 dollars.
Scott: Yeah, I spent $19 on mine and it wasn't the best one they had either.
Scott: the other ones were a lot more money.
Rym: I'm also kind of feeling more and more like I don't want to collect cells.
Rym: I hate collecting I hate that old business, but I feel like I should own at least one cell.
Scott: Yeah owning a cell is pretty cool
Rym: and I Feel more and more like it might be worth it someday to spend the amount of money it would take to have like the one Cell with the background from the one anime that I love the most and just have it in a frame with a little like Plaque under describing what it is.
Rym: That's the kind of thing you put in the library when you have your manor house someday Yeah, you go for it.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: You know, I'll have that and I'll have my Nazi coin which I'm still proud of because I think that thing's really neat.
Scott: Yeah, and the few other small trinkets of history that I have Yeah, but if you're looking for a dealers room and not necessarily looking for deals, you know You're just looking to for availability of merchandise and you are not jaded and you actually want anime merchandise.
Scott: Otakon dealer's room super awesome.
Rym: I mean still Watching someone who has never been to an anime con before or never actually
Scott: never
Rym: Walking into that dealer's room for the first time and realizing that it's going to take them a couple hours just to walk the length of it That the look on their face is priceless And I remember how I felt when I first walked into it.
Scott: Oh, man, I spent a lot of time.
Scott: I first know to kind of the dealer's room.
Rym: I guess what I should say here is that Scott and I go to a lot of cons and we're kind of jaded.
Rym: We don't care about most of what's ad cons anymore.
Scott: So we're gonna give a bad review to pretty much any dealer's room Even if it's the best dealer's room ever more than that.
Scott: We don't care about it.
Rym: So as much as other people we tend to focus on the things we do and the things that go wrong Because that's all that stands out anymore.
Rym: You can assume that anything we don't talk about was probably 99% of Otakon was awesome.
Scott: I'm gonna say that right now.
Rym: Yeah, in fact, we've gone kind of long.
Rym: So I think I'll get to the con feedback session and then we'll have our final thoughts.
Scott: Is there any other things we just have to cover at the last second here?
Rym: I didn't go to the dance.
Scott: Oh the concert.
Rym: Oh right the Eminence concert.
Rym: We missed the triple-a concert.
Scott: Yes So we went to the Eminence concert.
Scott: Eminence just to sum it up there They're actually a full orchestra from Australia But they sent over a string quartet and a pianist to perform.
Scott: What they do is they perform video game and animation music in you know classical form and it's very awesome
Rym: and along with them because they Helped do a lot of the music for the Romeo and Juliet anime They had the composer for that music there with them and he's good friends with famous
Scott: anime composer.
Scott: It's like no boo then this guy.
Scott: the guy is no boo.
Scott: Yokokano, whatever.
Scott: Yeah He's like the top of the second line of awesome Composers.
Rym: the guy is a great composer.
Rym: He's awesome.
Rym: I feel bad that I don't remember his name Yeah, but the guy's awesome and he's really cool like he was up there talking and with them and I have respect for the guy.
Rym: and Actually the MC that came with Eminence was really funny and cool, too.
Scott: He was alright, even though he was a little nervous and he didn't know exactly what to say a lot He wasn't as cool as the guy who actually was like the first violin.
Scott: Yes The first violin guy should have been the MC and the MC guy should have just not been there cuz that got.
Rym: the guy was Hilarious and great.
Scott: Yes, the only problem I had with the Eminence concert because piano squall.
Scott: Yeah The performance they gave was great.
Scott: I was a little bit jaded because I felt that I don't know after seeing the the video game pianist.
Scott: I'm sort of jaded on video game and anime music performances, but suffice regardless of video game anime part of it.
Rym: They were a fucking fantastic quintet.
Scott: They were awesome.
Scott: The concert was awesome.
Scott: I wouldn't have missed it for anything.
Scott: I want to see it again and again again but I guess part of the reason they were there is because piano squall knew them and had contact with them and piano squall had Contact with Otakon.
Rym: That's cool at all.
Scott: He was the hookup guy like.
Rym: that's cool at all.
Rym: I'm glad he did it.
Rym: I respect him for that, but he was kind of a self-serving prick up on stage.
Scott: I knew piano squall from when he was at Otakon in the past.
Scott: I saw him perform at I think a cosplay intermission when I was in the simulcast room.
Scott: and The guy has piano skills.
Scott: I will not deny his piano skills might not be at the same level as Martin Long who I just mentioned the video game pianist But they are awesome piano skills.
Scott: He has better piano skills than most people.
Scott: also He has a good squall cosplay.
Scott: He looks like squall.
Scott: I cannot deny that He also has a pretty good shtick going and he has a lot of respect from a lot of fans and I can't deny that To him.
Rym: but in this particular instance when he was on stage He kind of came off as an asshole.
Scott: I also Didn't like him and I I don't like him as a person.
Scott: I think he's very unprofessional.
Scott: He's sort of fanboyish and he's sort of annoying and I don't.
Scott: and while I don't know him personally And I've only interacted with him as an audience member to when he has been on stage and that is it.
Scott: He doesn't seem like the kind of person.
Scott: I really want to talk to ever.
Rym: he talked way too much.
Scott: He said annoying things that made me want to groan that were unprofessional.
Rym: and the worst thing is at one point up I'm not arguing freedom of speech or anything because I went.
Rym: if I ever shied away from saying something offensive never The gecky got fat.
Scott: Oh, yes.
Rym: Yes But uh, he made a joke Somewhat disparaging of Baltimore.
Scott: and while I agree that Baltimore deserves to be disparaged It was only you do that.
Rym: Well, yeah, I mean you can do.
Scott: that isn't very poor taste.
Rym: You could do it if you did it well in the right circumstances but it was neither the time nor the place and it just.
Rym: it came off as really crass and tacky and I lost most of my respect for piano squall then.
Scott: Yeah I mean even if I if I'm a musical act and I go somewhere to perform even if it's someplace I hate like where's Someplace I hate.
Scott: well, it depends because some musical acts can get away with coming up on stage If you're fuck you Baltimore like Lewis black he can get up there and he'd be like, how do you people stand this shitty weather?
Rym: Oh, what?
Rym: He came to.
Rym: RIT is like fucking cold.
Scott: What the fuck.
Rym: you guys have tunnels cuz it's fucking cold.
Scott: Fuck you.
Scott: Yeah, exactly, but I'm only here because you made me he's a comedian.
Scott: if you're a piano like soloist and you're going to play piano You don't get up and say man.
Scott: Your city has a high crime rate.
Scott: Yes, please sucks.
Rym: But even then even that the way that piano squall did it and the just the circumstance and everything It was really lame in the first place.
Rym: And I think what spoke well of eminence is that they didn't react and the MC guy just kind of smiled and nodded and gave This look of what's wrong with you?
Scott: Yeah, they should have had if they needed to include piano squall in the thing at all.
Rym: Don't give him a microphone.
Scott: Just guy I I don't want to see this guy.
Scott: if I know the piano squall was involved with the thing That might have.
Scott: if I had known that beforehand I might have actually shied away from it which would have been bad on the great cause.
Rym: eminence is awesome.
Rym: I know also the guy on the far right who didn't talk much but at the Australian guy.
Rym: Well, they're all us.
Rym: Well, they're not all Australian, but it's an Australian group.
Rym: Yep Apparently Americans say they're ours like pirates.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That guy was a funny guy.
Scott: I liked him.
Scott: Basically they should have just let the musicians run the show themselves because they were ten times as awesome as the MC or piano squall.
Rym: But the MC was pretty good.
Rym: It was just.
Scott: it was okay.
Scott: piano squall piano squall It's really the only piano squall made him look good by relativism.
Rym: I think he did.
Scott: All right, that's enough of that concert.
Rym: All right, so we have a tradition every year of going.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Well, we'll link to them in the forum.
Rym: Good idea.
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: We're gonna link to a bunch of stuff in the forum cuz I gotta give shout outs to people and all that.
Rym: The forum thread will probably end up being long for this.
Rym: All right Suffice to say we have a tradition every year of going to the closing ceremonies and the con feedback session.
Scott: We missed the closing ceremony which is sad because if you miss the closing Sarah the closing ceremonies at Otakon are special because There are many anime music video showings at Otakon.
Scott: The problem with these showings is they're often crowded and annoying and loud and they're not pleasant at least for me and mostly since I don't care a lot about music videos and Most of the music videos are not so good and I only want to see the good one.
Rym: See I care a lot about anime music videos.
Rym: I really like them like they're a big part of cons for me.
Scott: But I have an idea that I came up with today that I'll let you know about.
Scott: anime probably already figured out my idea Anime con.
Rym: anime music video contest.
Rym: for a lot of reasons that we've talked about we've had in fact We had an anime music video expert on the show not too long ago.
Scott: Oh we did.
Scott: Yeah I actually I just thought about that earlier today.
Scott: Yeah, it was weird.
Rym: I thought about it at Otakon Huh?
Scott: Okay, then because
Rym: that was a good show
Scott: at Otakon at the closing ceremonies They show the winners of the AMV contest and only the winners and the honorable mentions and the judges choices and
Rym: all I remember is That every year it's just like six amazing music videos and to this day I still the one video that I saw the 25 25 video.
Rym: That's like the best anime music video ever other than that utenna one.
Scott: It's a really damn good anime music video.
Rym: It's one of those ones where it's good and it's serious Which is hard to do because if you try to do usually the best ones are comedic or like happening.
Rym: Yeah, if you try to be serious, you usually end up being lame or sappy.
Scott: That's one of those videos that gives you that feeling, you know that the same feeling that the awesome animes give Yes, which is what you're trying to do is give the same feeling awesome animes give with a song and some anime.
Rym: But we missed it.
Rym: It sucked.
Rym: I'm sad.
Rym: However, we went to the con feedback session and I'm not gonna go into a lot of detail.
Scott: One thing I could say about the con feedback session this year That was better than years past is they basically had all of the top staff there the whole row of them Which in years past they've only had like, you know a few staff guys.
Scott: They're taking notes And I think that was a good improvement because they were able to properly respond To more of the questions rather than just saying yeah, we'll pass that along all of the time.
Scott: They only had to say we'll pass that on a few times.
Rym: now this Otakon It broke the mold of con feedback sessions because the rule is 99% of any con feedback session is cosplayers complaining about cosplays masquerades This year.
Rym: No one complained about that.
Scott: At least I didn't hear any complaints about it.
Rym: There was one semi legitimate complaint about making the rules clear about what isn't is not allowed in the BCC.
Rym: but other than that almost all of the complaints were either Stupid fanboys complaining about bullshit that Otakon has no power over or Otakon shouldn't change now that I won't get into that or People complaining about autograph sessions and panels.
Rym: now with the autograph sessions The complaints were usually along the lines of I wanted the autograph and I didn't get it to which I say there are 22 to 25 thousand people there and there are like a thousand autographs going to be signed.
Rym: if you get one You're lucky if you don't.
Rym: better luck next year.
Rym: and the fat fanboy who tried to complain that because autograph sessions were set Simultaneous he was not able to get both autographs at the same time.
Rym: Fuck you Exactly.
Scott: That's I wanted to yell out like fuck you sit down and shut up.
Scott: And first the thing is Regardless of you know, yes, there's a limited supply and a demand is greater than supply.
Scott: if you get one, you're lucky There's also the.
Scott: it's a fucking autograph.
Scott: Someone just drags a pen across the paper.
Scott: Why I mean I want to wait in line to maybe talk to someone, you know Maybe like spend 10 seconds going hi, how you doing?
Scott: Maybe say thank you for the awesome art you make it I enjoy it a lot or something like that.
Scott: or maybe get something from them, you know.
Scott: But an autograph really doesn't mean anything to me and I don't really understand why it means a lot to other people.
Rym: Well, it could mean a lot to me if it was like someone I really respected.
Scott: but even then any the odd the physical artifact of the Autograph itself would be just a reminder of the time when I met the person which is what really has the meaning.
Scott: For a lot of these people it seems like the physical artifact of the autograph is the meaningful thing.
Rym: I have one case where the physical artifact is the meaningful thing.
Scott: What is that?
Rym: And while the Magic Johnson story is awesome Okay, if I ever get that signed that by Captain Lou and then the guy who played Luigi, but I know important thing I have the anime equivalent of a Catholic relic.
Scott: But the important thing there isn't the physical artifact of the autograph itself But the meta surrounding the combination of what the autograph.
Rym: yeah I don't want to yell at people who get autographs now.
Rym: I want to yell at people who like mindlessly collect every autograph they can get.
Rym: I view
Scott: anyone who collects like
Rym: our friend Lisa really Wanted to get the eska flown a guy's autograph
Scott: But she got pictures sketches from the eska flown a guy and she talked to the eska flown a guy Which is a much more meaningful and that's
Rym: I doubt this fanboy really really cared about all of the people who were giving autographs.
Scott: oh, he I imagine he did not.
Rym: he just wanted to fill out his autograph book and Frankly I wish Otakon see in the years past Otakon concert count is really good about this Was more forceful in shooting down stupid questions.
Rym: this year.
Rym: They were really kind of conciliatory and they very much.
Rym: if someone has a stupid question They basically said well forward that to the interested parties.
Scott: Here's an inch.
Scott: Here's an idea I just came up with you ready.
Scott: Tell me if you like this idea.
Rym: I'm listening.
Scott: when you get an autograph the autograph line system at Otakon It's just fine.
Scott: as far as I'm concerned.
Scott: the way they do it is you get a ticket and if you get a ticket you're Guaranteed an autograph and if you don't have a ticket you can wait in line, but you're not guaranteed an autograph.
Scott: That's that's a good system.
Scott: I think they should add one more thing to that system.
Scott: if you get an autograph They like punch a giant crazy hole in your badge and you're not allowed anymore.
Scott: you get one for the con period game over.
Rym: That's hot.
Scott: That's a good idea.
Scott: That would be fantastic.
Scott: You can only get one autograph at the con no matter what no matter who you are.
Scott: So if you're gonna get one you pick one.
Scott: if you wait in line and you don't get one We don't stamp your badge to permanently prevent you from getting any more autographs this year.
Scott: So you can still wait in another line and try again, but you get one.
Scott: That's it fanboy.
Rym: now as for the other complaints Which were almost all about panels half of them were the panels were totally fuck sword and no shows and scheduling problems And that was true.
Rym: The panels were completely fucked at Otakon.
Scott: I think the problem was is that before the con I got the schedule online.
Scott: The schedule online was more up-to-date than the printed pocket guide at the con.
Scott: Secondly there are if there was a problem with the pocket guide.
Scott: There was in the pocket guide a description for a panel about super flat.
Scott: No panel about super flat was scheduled on any schedule I've ever seen but there was a description for the panel in there.
Scott: So Problems with the checking of the printing beforehand already.
Rym: I'm very much of the mind that it would be worth the expense for Otakon.
Rym: I mean the pocket guides.
Rym: well and good and they could keep it in it.
Scott: Can they need some sort of pocket guide?
Scott: because carrying the program around like a kinetic con is no good.
Rym: But they should add to that and I mean I'd be willing to pay more even to go to Otakon.
Rym: Just a single piece of paper that has the most up-to-date schedule like the final day I think.
Rym: print it and still get it to the con and put it in the bag.
Rym: I actually not even in the bags.
Rym: Maybe they just pass it out when you get your badge.
Scott: I would really like it if they just had the schedule on some paper and not in the pocket guide and then maybe the pocket guy just had the descriptions of the events or Maybe the pocket guide had things just I don't know.
Rym: the pocket guide should just have maps and descriptions of things.
Rym: The sheet of paper the single sheet of paper should be the most up-to-date schedule.
Scott: They could have possibly printed Yeah I don't know it just or Print the pocket guide later so that the schedule is more up-to-date.
Scott: if the pocket guide does not have a useful and accurate schedule It's we might as well have nothing.
Scott: So Yeah, we need a pocket guide because we can't be carrying the program around the big giant thing All right now.
Rym: we've gone on long So I'm not going to get into what went wrong with panels.
Rym: Suffice to say we'll probably do a separate show about that.
Scott: as to I think the show Went wrong with panels at Otakon this year.
Scott: It was they had.
Scott: they could have prevented it if they had acted beforehand in a smart way But they didn't and it failed.
Scott: they did their best to recover from the disaster.
Rym: I got to say Meredith did a fantastic job of covering up and saving everything.
Scott: They did the best they could to recover from the disaster.
Scott: but in my opinion the disaster did not have to occur if they had acted smartly beforehand and There were some problems afterwards.
Scott: but some of those problems were due to people's stupidity.
Rym: I think we'll do a separate show.
Rym: That is going to be very simply Exactly how myself and Scott would run panels at Otakon if we were at any convention.
Scott: at any convention.
Rym: Yeah, but I think we'll go.
Rym: we'll go through the anime convention.
Rym: I think if we specifically do Otakon like I would do it exactly this way.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it doesn't have to be Otakon though.
Rym: But anyway that we've gone on We don't want to turn into anime world order here.
Scott: So is there anything else to say about Otakon this year besides how awesome it was?
Rym: the rest of the complaints about panels.
Rym: we're basically people complaining about the content of fan panels or the content of industry panels or The fact that a panelist like wasn't prepared or didn't show up or didn't use the microphone, right?
Rym: Yeah And to which I want to say Otakon needs to.
Rym: they should have come out straight away and just said fan panels are run by fans Not by us.
Scott: We have no con like the anime music videos.
Scott: if they suck that's not Otakon's fault.
Scott: They have no control if no one submits good music videos.
Scott: They can't make good music videos and put them in.
Rym: yeah, you know don't go to the con feedback and say the Hellsing panel or the the Inuyasha fan panel was crappy and Poorly run because they don't know.
Scott: they don't know what you what actually.
Scott: you should say that but not You shouldn't blame the con for the fact that the panel was poor but you should tell them hey I just want to let you know this panel was bad.
Scott: I don't suggest you allow those panelists back in the future and the con there is more demand to run panels.
Scott: Then there are panels to be run and the con really should be a lot Stricter and a lot more tough on who gets to run panels and who doesn't and which panels get to be run Because they can.
Scott: if they are harder on the panelists they can improve panel quality across the board.
Scott: But it's not the cons fault if a panel sucks.
Scott: It's the panel people's fault.
Rym: I mean.
Rym: basically we suggested to ConnectiCon things they could do to make their panels go better and they did everything we said And I think that ConnectiCon is gonna have better and better panels every year.
Rym: now I really think Otakon should do the same thing.
Rym: It wouldn't be that hard.
Rym: Nope All right, anything else and trying to other than that other than the panels.
Rym: catastrophe.
Rym: Otakon was run pretty much flawlessly and I didn't run into a single freaking problem at the con other than the Ten minutes we spent in that problem line at reg and the panel problems.
Scott: Everything else at the con was flawless.
Scott: I can't really think of ways to make it better other than things I could have done as opposed to.
Scott: there's nothing the con could Have done really to make it better for me other than what we already said.
Scott: I can't think of anything.
Scott: It was Otakon awesome every time.
Scott: there's a reason we go back every year.
Rym: Yes This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front road crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.