Rym: It's Tuesday, November 27th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott and this is geek nides tonight racing games And I really want to play virtual racing.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Today was a very good day for me.
Scott: I think how good was it?
Rym: Well, I got to say good Way, baby We always laughed about I we're never gonna buy virtual console games and Scott just bought 3,000 points or $30 to Spend on more virtual because I didn't realize if 0x was on the bridge.
Rym: zero X fuck that Simon's quest.
Scott: Simon's quest crappy shitty game.
Rym: Simon's quest in my opinion piece of shit is the third or fourth best Castlevania game ever.
Scott: Well, let's think about alright, so alright number one.
Rym: obviously, you know, you're wrong.
Scott: I can think of at least four better Castlevania games.
Scott: name them all of the other Castlevania games.
Rym: I submit a portrait of room.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: No, wait, there is only one.
Scott: Castlevania is game that is worse than Simon's quest That is Castlevania 64.
Rym: See I never actually played that.
Rym: I know Don't I'll admit sadly.
Rym: I know you'll hate me, but I didn't like the SNES one that much.
Scott: Well, yes any s1 is basically the same as the original one which is different maps and better controls and stuff like that and you can Swing the chain around.
Rym: Well, I mean the original was okay, but I didn't super like like.
Rym: I liked it.
Rym: I owned it and I played it and I thought yeah, it's a Nintendo game But Simon's quite.
Rym: it's kind of weird I'm.
Rym: maybe I'm just weird that way but Zelda 1 was an awesome game and I loved it.
Rym: but when Zelda 2 came out and Simon's Castlevania 2 those two games I just love and I can't well I guess I could articulate exactly why but it would take me about an hour because those games are so wonderful.
Scott: No, I think it's because you have bad taste and you like the fucked up games that no one else likes.
Rym: besides I didn't say it's the best Castlevania.
Rym: I think that is Possibly well symphony.
Rym: the night you haven't played I played bits of it.
Rym: I never played through the whole thing because I think I believe ever had a place to eat.
Scott: How could you play?
Rym: I believe that Al and a lot of people seem to back me up on this almost That the first DS one dawn of sorrow is pretty much that game in terms of quality.
Scott: No, the first yes one was pretty good.
Rym: I really really liked it.
Rym: I like I like.
Scott: I like the Super Nintendo one and the original first one Castlevania 3 for the NES.
Scott: I never actually played that way.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Yeah, it's actually kind of fun.
Rym: Yeah, maybe I think you'd like it probably and not in that penny arcade.
Rym: I think you're really gonna like it way.
Rym: But yeah, Simon's Quest was one of the few video games in my life that as a kid Actually scared me.
Rym: the game was just you weren't scared.
Scott: towards the end is all the one there I was it wasn't.
Rym: I was scared.
Rym: but in this more like Nervous something's gonna happen.
Rym: This is weird.
Rym: I'm worried that like gannons gonna appear suddenly and I'm gonna die.
Rym: This music is scaring me.
Rym: or when I was in the graveyard the first time and but no.
Rym: or like Zelda 2 scared me too.
Rym: when you get across to like the weird plague when you take the raft across and you're in That place with the enemies you can't kill and suddenly everything's dangerous and there aren't so many villages and everything's scary.
Rym: but yeah, Castlevania 2 was scary.
Rym: in this kind of Creepy a little bit fucked up weird things that were never explained to you by the rule book.
Rym: We just happen you'd run across these scrolls that said.
Rym: cryptic scary things then disappeared.
Rym: you didn't know why you could equip Dracula's heart or claw or eyeball and different things would happen but it was never quite clear exactly why they happened.
Rym: and That one time the game glitched and all those bodies started moving in the sky.
Rym: Ah Yeah, okay that game scared me as a kid.
Rym: also it kind of bothered me how everyone in the towns was just kind of fucked up and scary and Every time I walked into one of those places where those merchant men were Or even worse when I had to use holy water to break the bricks and go down into like the sub sub basement to find Him everyone's wearing gray robes with scary masks and they always kind of came at me.
Rym: It's not like they walked over.
Rym: Do you want to buy something?
Rym: They came at you.
Rym: the first time I walked into a store.
Rym: I ran away cuz I thought it was a bad guy that I couldn't kill.
Scott: Yeah That's basically the thing that I didn't like about cat Simon's quest is all the stupid store stuff.
Scott: It's like I should just be walking to the right whipping things.
Scott: That's Castlevania, I like to have walk into the right and whipping the old.
Scott: there's no figuring out.
Scott: It was.
Scott: it was worse than the average Nintendo logic.
Scott: It was just complete random.
Scott: No, not no Bullshit, it wasn't nonsense at all.
Scott: Like I in the first town The guy says wanna buy a crystal and I'm like, what the fuck do I need crystal for?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Well, there's someone else in the town who tells you what the crystal does.
Scott: Yeah, and I got it will show you the way in Berkeley Manor.
Rym: Do you know what you go to?
Rym: Berkeley Manor?
Scott: I didn't even know it was a Berkeley Manor or anything like.
Rym: that's the first man the mansion the first level And you know what?
Scott: I don't know where the first level was.
Scott: I walk out of town.
Scott: It's a horrible dangerous wilderness and I just get killed by wolf men in the night.
Rym: That's just because you suck.
Rym: it's a terrible night to have a curse but At least at least the dawn something.
Rym: I forget what it says game sucks.
Scott: He was vanquished.
Scott: the horrible night game sucks on two news games.
Rym: Awesome.
Rym: All right.
Scott: So in the news, there's a reason angry video game.
Scott: nerd agrees with me.
Rym: We'll have to do a show on this.
Rym: Anyway in the news, there's been a bunch of articles along these lines.
Rym: But I'll talk about this one the PSP slim which is the new better PSP and I kind of like it Has sold over a million in Japan.
Scott: All right.
Rym: now, you know people are arguing left and right like yeah, see the PSP isn't dead.
Rym: Hahaha, the PSP is gonna win.
Rym: and that's not what's happening because Nintendo expects to sell 28 million more DS's.
Scott: The only reason they can't sell more DS's because everyone already has one.
Scott: It's like who's left to sell a DS to?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: we can start advertising.
Scott: the people need to DS's.
Scott: Well, or they'll make a DS as soon as everyone in Japan has a DS light.
Scott: They're gonna make the DS light light so that well rebuys or they'll make the the next the successor to the DS.
Rym: Yeah, what about the third pillar?
Rym: I thought there was gonna be a game boy.
Scott: That was just the backup plan in case the DS didn't go over.
Rym: Well, man, you know people always rag on Sony for outright lying about rumble and all the all the crap They did with the ps3 and everything.
Rym: But people forget that Nintendo had this whole lie about yeah third pillar that they just kind of Swept under the rug and pretended they never say it would have been true if the DS didn't do so.
Scott: Well, if the DS didn't do so well, we would already in our hands have Game Boy Advance advances.
Rym: Remember we weren't sure remember when we bought the DS.
Rym: our rationale was either It's gonna be the best thing ever and we'll have that opening day or it's going to be the virtual boy.
Rym: And how cool will it be to own the virtual boy again ten years from now?
Scott: Yep, that was my rationale buying the DS on launch day.
Scott: And I guess I won.
Scott: my gamble was correct.
Scott: Was it not?
Rym: Yeah, but the PSP they expect to sell 10 million by the end of the fiscal year and Nintendo expects to sell 28 million DS's I think just in Japan.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I'm not even read the article but Way to go.
Rym: Well the point here one the reason the PSP slim is selling is that one Japan does have a lot of loyalty towards Sony and Nintendo, you know Japanese companies, but to Final Fantasy 5 7 crisis core, which I didn't even really realize came out Is on the PSP.
Scott: So, of course, yeah, there's that giant PSP that I see every day that's in the city.
Scott: It's like a billboard has a giant PSP on it.
Scott: I always see Japanese RPGs on it.
Scott: So and they definitely look square styling and you know square Enix style.
Rym: time a JRPG comes out I don't care what system it is It'll sell almost as many as the number of copies of that.
Scott: you could come out with a new console in Japan tomorrow and that All it does is play one Dragon Quest game that isn't available in any of their console and charge $500 for the console and $100 for the only game on the console and people.
Scott: you'll have people lining up to spend $600 to buy your console now
Rym: Despite the fact that there have been a lot of shall we say epic fails along the way at the PSP Including early games that had I don't know you had to sit there for 10 minutes while it loaded Or you could play UMD
Scott: movies.
Rym: UMDs.
Rym: Sony just kind of said yeah, never mind about that, which is probably good.
Scott: But they just say yeah, never mind with the blu-rays.
Rym: I still have no desire to get a PSP yet just because it's too much money and the only reason I don't get PSP.
Scott: I would get one just for the podcasting feature, but it's too big.
Rym: So no, well, maybe if they make the PSP slim slim It would also have to be ps3.
Scott: Not a gigantic screen.
Scott: Ah Which I don't think they couldn't do because that's sort of the selling point.
Rym: But my real news the point I want to make is that the PSP did not win.
Rym: The PSP has no chance of winning and never did.
Rym: but the PSP has pulled off something amazing.
Rym: It is as far as I can see not counting the WonderSwan and all that Japanese stuff in the rest of the world.
Rym: I think it is the only time we have ever had a Second-place in the portable gaming market.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you look at the history and it's been Gameboy.
Rym: It wasn't like the Gameboy and then like oh well in second place the game gear is doing okay.
Rym: It was the Gameboy and the superior game gear.
Rym: superior in the sense that it was better Technically much like the PSP is better technically.
Rym: I mean it was much better hardware if you discount the fact that the batteries lasted about six minutes.
Scott: Yeah, but in general it was Nintendo and then everyone else not just you know Tries and isn't as good as Nintendo.
Scott: It's everyone else fails.
Scott: the game gear died.
Scott: The Neo Geo pocket color died the Lynx the Lynx the Lynx still died.
Scott: It's sort of like the metal.
Scott: The Game Gear tried to kill the Gameboy, but it was smitten down to the ground.
Scott: You can't kill the Gameboy, which is now the DS and you still can.
Rym: nothing's Nintendo.
Rym: I mean people always never forget the fact never forget.
Rym: Nintendo has pretty much had a complete monopoly on portable gaming for as long as Nintendo has had an entry in the portable gaming market and the fact that the PSP did not get destroyed completely is Amazing.
Rym: so I give that system and even Sony some credit for that.
Scott: Yeah, but I have a feeling though that the DS is gonna be around for people are talking You know the Gameboy from the original Gameboy to the GBA, right?
Scott: Which you can really.
Scott: you can count that as one platform.
Scott: 15 years of dominance.
Scott: We're not talking dominance just portable.
Scott: We're talking dominance in terms of number one gaming console period not just portable.
Scott: So DS is three years old.
Scott: you can expect 12 more years of DS in some form.
Rym: cuz I mean think it was the Gameboy Which had a screen that consisted of two colors dark brown and light brown.
Scott: in fact The DS if you compare how the DS is doing three years in to how the Gameboy was doing three years in The DS is doing better than the Gameboy did.
Scott: so it might be 20 years of DSing for us The Gameboy with its brown and darker brown screen.
Scott: It was green and it wasn't green.
Rym: It was a yellowish kind of brown.
Rym: Yeah, it was dark Spinachy green brownish whatever green.
Rym: What's?
Rym: it was kind of yellowish?
Scott: Anyway, it depended on your contrast.
Rym: They never really improved.
Rym: I mean the Gameboy color was barely an improvement.
Rym: It was pretty much the same.
Scott: I could talk you do a whole show on the Gameboy color.
Rym: Well, let's do a whole show on the Gameboy like the evolution of the Gameboy.
Rym: All right, or portable gaming.
Rym: No anyway Yeah, that's it.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: What else am I gonna say?
Scott: So I got a story here and the headline on joystick is Nintendo dead.
Scott: last in Greenpeace guide to greener electronics, right?
Rym: Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Rym: Why are we talking about Greenpeace?
Scott: That's I don't want to talk about Greenpeace.
Rym: I mean Environmentalism aside Greenpeace is nothing but a bunch of wackos.
Scott: Well Greenpeace is a lot.
Scott: most of Greenpeace for the most part is well-meaning people But the organization is generally misguided and it does terrorist things and other ineffective.
Rym: That's why the founder said wow, you guys went nuts and quit.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: But anyway not talking about Greenpeace I'm mostly gonna talk about the video game journalism going on here, right?
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: You are.
Rym: what you're implying is that there is a such thing as video game journalism.
Scott: No, in fact, I'm going to Provide ample evidence that there is no such thing.
Scott: all right, so Greenpeace did us this little study thing.
Scott: I guess they do it every year or something like that.
Scott: And what they do is they pick the 10 the largest consumer electronics companies and then they give them a score based on criteria of how Environmentally friendly they are right.
Scott: and because Nintendo grew so much this year for the first time They're on the list as they're the 10th largest or one of the top 10 consumer electronics Companies in terms of size in the world.
Scott: So Greenpeace scored them for the first time ever.
Scott: Okay, and they scored zero points out of you know, whatever many points you could get which is the worst score you could get?
Scott: and Yeah, so all the games journalism websites, let me let me read from joystick here Oh, it ranks actually not top 10 top 18 manufacturers.
Scott: But anyway, according to the report Nintendo has no timeline for toxic blah blah blah.
Scott: The console is birthed from a foul process mired and substances like brominated flame retardants.
Scott: So they're right.
Scott: So joystick says that according to green speed Greenpeace the Wii is made with brominated flame retardants, right?
Scott: Let's actually read the PDF from Greenpeace.
Scott: What let me go.
Scott: Let me just scan around here.
Scott: Hold on.
Scott: Come on.
Scott: PDF.
Rym: I'm expecting a stellar piece of objective Rational well thought out and well researched journalism.
Scott: Okay, this really doesn't want to scroll properly.
Rym: Awesome Is this gonna be?
Rym: you know, legitimate journalism is this going to be?
Rym: Some somewhat objective.
Rym: Is this gonna be real?
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Well, it's basically all it is is a chart with some text in it.
Scott: It's not like a big essay written here, right?
Scott: So it says here at the top it says Let's see Timeline for BFR phaseout.
Scott: Nintendo got a score of zero, right?
Scott: That's brominated flame retardant, right?
Rym: Is that good or bad?
Scott: It's zero is bad.
Scott: Okay, then it says down here at the bottom timeline for BFR phaseout.
Scott: No policy on use of BFRs.
Scott: Nintendo scored zeros across the board.
Scott: not because they do anything Environmentally unfriendly because they provide no information about it whatsoever.
Scott: They Nintendo you gotta remember this is a company that makes video games and tries to make as much profit making video games as it Can.
Scott: it doesn't think about anything else?
Scott: They don't you know?
Scott: You see other companies like given to charities here and there and some of those things are good and some of those things are just For marketing but do good anyway, and some things are just for show and whatever.
Scott: Nintendo if you haven't noticed doesn't do any of that stuff.
Scott: Nintendo makes video games as only video games.
Scott: They don't waste their resources or well, well, I mean whether it's a waste is you know up to you.
Scott: But well, they don't sign their resources on other projects to look good, you know any more, right?
Scott: However, I have with my keen journalistic brain.
Scott: I have discovered something else.
Rym: Oh, have you?
Scott: oh, yes See at.
Scott: so first of all joystick has it wrong?
Scott: there be joystick says Greenpeace says that Nintendo is the most horrible evil polluting the environment company.
Scott: Reality Greenpeace only says that Nintendo provides no information.
Scott: That's why they get zeros.
Scott: because basically I guess according to Greens piece if you don't you know Have a whole website and a whole task force at your company devoted to environmentalism.
Scott: Then you got to be evil, right?
Scott: You're the worst.
Scott: There's a link in the Greenpeace PDF.
Scott: This is more information Takes you to the Nintendo US corporate fact and at the bottom of the Nintendo US corporate fact It says what does Nintendo do to help protect the environment?
Scott: It says we recycle paper in the office We don't use colored paper We buy recycled paper towels blah blah blah blah blah, and it doesn't say anything about brominated flame retardants or manufacturing or anything like that.
Scott: You know why it doesn't See, this is why I'm smarter than Greenpeace and joystick.
Scott: You know why it doesn't say that.
Rym: why doesn't it Scott?
Scott: Nintendo of America website Nintendo of America doesn't manufacture anything.
Scott: They're just an office.
Scott: If they had gone to the Japanese website, I don't read Japanese, but there may have been some information.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: maybe I'm not saying there is.
Scott: I'm saying I didn't go to Japanese Shocked that a journalist a video game journalist somebody gets paid to do this like me doing it for free wouldn't?
Rym: Okay, I mean Greenpeace.
Rym: those ain't my outrage.
Scott: any no surprise for Greenpeace, but the video game journalist the shock.
Scott: So basically Nintendo's getting this bad PR because they don't provide information that Greenpeace thinks that everyone should provide and Video game journalists didn't actually read the thing the Greenpeace wrote or research it in any way whatsoever.
Scott: I don't know what.
Scott: oh, that's one more thing.
Scott: I have to say about this Whether you can say about you know, what I don't even know.
Scott: Nintendo's manufacturing might be horribly poisonous with toxic chemicals.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: I don't know anything about it.
Scott: There's no information either way.
Scott: and that's why they got this bad score because there's no positive or negative information, right?
Scott: But apparently people are just believing the worst possible situation when there's no information either way.
Scott: We do know one thing about Nintendo and their environmental impact.
Scott: We know the Nintendo makes two consoles.
Scott: It's pretty much all they make is the DS and the Wii.
Scott: and we know that they're competitors the ps3 and the 360.
Scott: And we know that the 360 and the ps3 The amount electricity that either one of those things uses is about I don't know four times five times with the Wii uses.
Scott: So regardless of Nintendo's manufacturing process who knows about it.
Scott: It's complete mystery to us Nintendo's products using a lot less energy to provide more entertainment than the competitors.
Rym: So take that things of the day.
Rym: Alright, uh, so way back in the day before, you know The DS and before even the Game Boy Advance and before there were flash carts easily available and all that.
Rym: One thing I wanted in my life more than anything was the ability to play regular Nintendo and Super Nintendo games on the go.
Rym: like that was the dream of my childhood.
Scott: Well, you know you could starting with the Game Boy Color.
Scott: They released, you know, because the Game Boy couldn't really play a lot of you know It couldn't do an NES quality game even though some came close like Kirby's Dreamland or a Final Fantasy legend, too Right, but the Game Boy Color you could play Mario 1 on it.
Scott: In fact, that's the best implementation of Mario 1 there is before the virtual console and maybe equal and then the Game Boy Advance.
Scott: They just released straight-up NES games for it and even better than any escapes like Super Nintendo games on it better than Super Nintendo Sometimes.
Scott: so, you know, it happens mostly.
Rym: a lot of people used to try and make kind of cobble together solutions Like get a little screen make it.
Scott: Oh, yeah, there's that guy.
Scott: I think he works within gadget.
Scott: now He basically takes video game consoles and then he sort of rebuilds them in portable versions Like he has a PlayStation you can just hold in your hands.
Rym: Well now I think too little too late applies.
Rym: But there is now a Famicom adapter for the DS.
Rym: so you can plug this into your DS plug an original gigantic Famicom game into it a game that I will point out is pretty much bigger than your DS and Then play it on your DS.
Rym: Wow, you know you could just get the flash cart and That gets points for being retro and it gets points for being perfect and it gets points for being kind of awesomely used.
Scott: Yeah, it's very impressive.
Rym: The one thing it does give you is that at least it's legal.
Rym: There is no way you can be faulted for having the Famicom cartridge and playing it on your DS this way.
Scott: I Guess yeah, I guess that's legal.
Rym: I just wonder how much Battery it uses.
Scott: I hope it has its own batteries.
Scott: Yeah, baby.
Scott: I mean it's already impractical enough.
Scott: You might as well make it a little bit, you know, oh, it'll play American games too.
Scott: Oh, okay There's TV out.
Scott: So I know it has TV out.
Scott: That's pretty that's not bad.
Rym: So you could actually sort of replace your Famicom if it broke, you know Just reading that it might be worth it to get it because we have two non-functional Nintendos.
Scott: if you want to do that, you could just buy a functioning Nintendo like that any sex thing or I could buy this.
Scott: But this is stupider.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I kind of like the style and it kind of looks like an old Famicom.
Rym: It's all you it's all you know, red and white.
Scott: I think there's more practical solution.
Scott: It's got a speaker even if you're using the TV out.
Scott: there are more practical solutions many more.
Scott: Anyway, my thing of the day, right?
Scott: So, you know the old fist of the North Star.
Scott: Oh Yeah, they're making a DS game.
Scott: So the DS game is gonna be sort of like an interactive manga where you read a fist of the North Star manga And then yes, I guess you play Effectively elite beat agent.
Scott: Yeah, someone's just like it'll stop when there's a fight and you'll basically have to play the equivalent of elite beat Agents to sort that someone.
Rym: that's what I gathered for the from the screenshots of the game thus causing the person to Turn the shotgun on themselves because that's how that works.
Scott: That is how that works.
Rym: So the website or backwards off a cliff crying the whole time, right?
Scott: So if you go to the this website, which is the official Japanese website for Hokuto no Ken DS, right?
Scott: My thing of the day is not this game It's this website not anything in the website itself.
Scott: But if you load this website in your browser something very interesting will happen.
Scott: that is quite humorous.
Scott: Make sure you have your JavaScripts enabled.
Rym: Yes, sadly Scott sent this to me like oh my god, check this out and I watch it.
Rym: Oh It's that fist of the North Star game.
Rym: I already knew about.
Rym: I'm so paranoid about ads and I turn off so much stuff that nothing happened for me.
Rym: Yeah, and as a result, I totally missed it.
Scott: It happened for me and it's pretty awesome Right.
Rym: So tonight we're not talking about fist of the North Star.
Rym: We're talking about Racing games in general very broad very simple.
Rym: We're not gonna get into racing video games.
Scott: We're not talking about like formula day here.
Rym: We're also not talking about the power pad.
Rym: No, I want to talk about the power pad.
Scott: I'm at vehicle racing games mostly cars or car like things.
Rym: Yeah, cuz uh carts not Diddy Kong cuz they cover sass Did equal Diddy guy is not Ben.
Rym: It's a terrible game suck.
Rym: It's not fun.
Rym: You suck I'll get into why.
Scott: at least it's a racing game.
Rym: But yeah, we'll probably do shows in the future on specific racing games in a lot of detail.
Rym: I'm sure we could do a whole show just on the Ridge Racer series or just I'm.
Scott: we haven't played enough Ridge Racer.
Rym: I've played one to death to where I think I'm perfect at it.
Rym: I've played seven once on a broken machine or six or whichever one that was.
Rym: I think it was six.
Scott: I don't know Racer all right, so Yeah, what is a race?
Rym: I don't think we need to get it there.
Scott: I cuz I do.
Scott: I actually have a point that I want to make that some games you think are racing games are not racing Games.
Rym: Oh, I see what you're doing there.
Rym: All right, go ahead.
Rym: Well in my in my eyes a racing game is a video game Where there's a bunch of black cars on one side which are white cars on the other.
Scott: It's it's a game.
Scott: Oh man.
Scott: That was bad.
Rym: It was bad enough to where it kind of hits you after the fact.
Scott: It's basically a game that is testing your skill of you know maneuvering something along a path Right and it that is the skill it is.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: by that logic that carnival make the ring go across the magnetic snake without touching anything is a racing game.
Scott: Yeah in a way.
Rym: Ah Vehicle along a course Attempting to get there to the end.
Rym: Well that Esther than other people that's the typical metaphor that's used.
Scott: but I mean if I change the theme of the game to be like a snake on a Branch on a tree trying to get the end of the branch then
Rym: I'm yeah, the snake is now my vehicle I'm trying to get all
Scott: the ring is my vehicle and the the spirally thing at the carnival is some
Rym: sort of steering wheel or Stick.
Scott: All right Anyway, you get the idea.
Scott: the skills being tested are the ability to stay on course.
Scott: We're going as fast as possible, you know.
Rym: Well, I think a lot.
Rym: also the ability to know the limits of something and then to push those limits.
Scott: Yes, and You know many games fall into this category.
Scott: For example, Gran Turismo racing game Forza racing games stunts 4d.
Scott: Yeah, RC Pro M racing game F 0 racing game.
Rym: What about say?
Scott: Mario Kart, I'm gonna say that every Mario Kart game Except for Mario Kart for the Gameboy Mario Kart Super Circuit is Mario Kart Super Circuit for the Gameboy Advance is a racing game.
Scott: Every other Mario Kart game I have played the Super Nintendo one the n64 one, especially Double dash I haven't played enough of so I can't say I'd say the DS one is pretty much a racing game.
Rym: The only thing is the you basically pedal make the car go in a Flintstones way with your finger.
Scott: Yeah, kind of but especially the n64 at least.
Scott: in fact I'll just say the n64 one Mario Kart 64 is not a racing game.
Scott: It is not a racing game.
Scott: It may appear to be a racing game However, while there is a racing element to the game that is not the primary aspect of the game.
Scott: the primary aspect of Mario Kart 64 is luck with the items and cheating and How well you stay on course and how much you push.
Scott: the limit of your cart matters a lot less than what items you get or if the AI just decides to cheat and fuck you or if you use a Secret on the track as opposed to you know, just going faster, right?
Rym: So, uh, what's your favorite racing game of all time?
Rym: Oh, yeah Cuz I have three answers I got.
Rym: I got a few answers I can go based on Enjoyment testing of skill or nostalgia.
Rym: I have a different one for all three.
Scott: I have four answers ready.
Scott: No, do you?
Scott: okay for equals?
Scott: there are four equals.
Scott: for me personal right equal number one would be F 0 X which I just downloaded is F 0 X. I don't want to talk all about F 0 because I want to do a whole F 0 show.
Scott: It feels like every episode.
Scott: we talk about whole shows we're gonna do and then we never do them.
Rym: remind us.
Scott: Yeah, so the thing about F 0 is that it is more than any other game.
Scott: gives you this insane Sensation of speed and it's not just because the speedometer goes up to like 2,000 kilometers an hour.
Scott: It's because the game actually makes you feel like you're going 2,000 kilometers an hour and you're you're like racing on Cylinders and in pipes and upside down and flipping and it's just ludicrous But it's actually a racing game and you're actually like you're managing your boost energy and you're you know You're managing crashing into people or not crashing into people.
Scott: and there's actually a lot to F 0 and it's it's really Fast and really rapid fire and intense and it it's just about.
Scott: I can't really think of a way to make a better Racing game in terms of fun at least.
Rym: Well, it depends on what kind of fun.
Scott: because yeah, there are different kinds of fun.
Scott: But in terms of a racing game that concentrates only on the racing and you know as fun as it can be That's what it does is F 0 in fact F 0.
Scott: GX does the same thing where it takes the racing game the core of it and he just Polishes it to be as shiny as it can and doesn't add any fluff.
Rym: see Oh, I guess along those kinds of lines in terms of just sheer enjoyment.
Rym: I would have to go with the initial D arcade game.
Scott: Yeah, the initial D arcade game at least version 3 which is better than version 4 is So much better than three two and one combined.
Scott: I can my god I can believe that but I haven't played for so I can't say.
Scott: but I I can totally believe it because if two is better Than one and three was better than two and one it follows the four.
Rym: be but really helps is the widescreen flat panels.
Rym: That would help quite a bit.
Rym: And also, you know in like one two and three that steering wheel was a little like it felt kind of flimsy Like the force feedback wasn't great.
Scott: Yeah, the force feedback was not as firm as it is.
Scott: on say Oh, I just remember the best racing game ever.
Scott: so yes the best racing game ever by far Above every other racing game ever is virtue erasing.
Scott: In fact better than that is virtue erasing 2 by Sega Which is incredibly hard to play because it's only like one machine or two.
Rym: fucking good game.
Scott: Virtua racing was.
Scott: virtue erasing is the best steering wheel ever like I will just say it was also the first 3d racing game with you know used polygon old graphics and it was the first racing game That had where you could change the camera view with the three view changing buttons.
Rym: I remember when I was racing I would just sit there moving through all the views cuz that was just so cool to be out.
Scott: That was virtue erasing one.
Scott: virtue erasing two is infinitely better But is impossible to play.
Scott: because what system could you get it on?
Scott: almost nothing?
Scott: I think you could play it on maybe like the 32 X CD or the Saturn or something like that And I don't even know if that came out for real.
Scott: I think you can get like a bootleg of it.
Scott: But you could play in the arcade on a giant eight-seat machine.
Scott: or was it a ten-seat machine where each seat was actually a giant model, you know IndyCar and Frickin.
Scott: there was one at Disney World in Epcot Center and in like, you know the Innovation place and I had to pay like five bucks to play it waiting in line that I played it once.
Scott: So that's how hard it is to get that to play that game.
Scott: But that is the best racing.
Scott: and there is and the force feedback wheel for the first time.
Scott: That was amazing.
Scott: And in fact the best force feedback wheel ever.
Scott: it had frickin paddled in everything, right?
Rym: So initial d4 the steering wheel is a rock.
Rym: It is it's wonderful.
Rym: It's it's amazing Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's good in terms of initial D. just being fun though those games they pump you up with the music and that like.
Rym: it's just this feeling of I am fighting with someone in my car and The fact that it's set up where you duel.
Scott: other people say Definitely has the multiplayer racing because other games with the multiplayer racing is not so good.
Scott: Like you have the checkpoints and the.
Scott: there's other AI cars in the track.
Rym: much every one of those, you know gimmicky.
Rym: There's eight arcade machines lined up and eight people all race in an arcade.
Rym: They're all terrible games.
Rym: for the most part They're not Except for cruising world virtual racing - I was gonna say cruising world sucks.
Scott: I like Can't say it's really erasing.
Rym: I also like cruising.
Rym: It's not a good racing game, but it's not a very good game.
Rym: I consider it like at best a guilty, but I really like it.
Scott: I played it a lot.
Scott: I played it probably more than anything else.
Rym: I think the reason I played it so much is that most of the arcades I went to it was just the best racing game There.
Rym: yeah, it was good.
Rym: It was just they didn't have Ridge Racer.
Rym: yep, I would like to give a nod to Ridge Racer one because I Didn't appreciate that game when I was younger because I didn't know much about drifting and all that cool like oh my god He's drifting his car.
Scott: It's definitely ahead of its time.
Scott: It was like, you know The initial D class of racing game before that was really popular Anywhere cuz I'd play it and be like what the fuck my car spins out all the time.
Rym: I don't get it.
Rym: This sucks.
Rym: But now like I guess it was we used to go to University of Rochester Because RIT for being such a geeky school had like the shittiest on-campus arcade you've ever seen.
Rym: It was awful like they took teased us for two years.
Rym: Like we're gonna get a DDR machine.
Rym: It's coming.
Rym: we've got one any day now and Finally one day it arrived and we walk in.
Rym: and what do we see?
Rym: Not only is it a pump-it-up machine?
Rym: But it's a broken pump-it-up machine.
Rym: And in fact, it was the same broken pump-it-up machine that we had been playing at another arcade And then it had broken and then that arcade went out of business.
Scott: They're probably both renting from the same place.
Rym: I think yeah, but God anyway, so we go to the University of Rochester which had an awesome arcade a fifth makes DDR.
Rym: it had a fifth mix DDR and it had like That puzzle puzzle whatever game.
Scott: I was at a neogeo cabinet.
Rym: Yep, and it had Ridge Racer one.
Rym: Yep Also, it had girls unlike the RIT arcade.
Rym: but well mostly because we brought them.
Rym: but anyway, so I Couldn't play DDR all the time.
Rym: I had to stop every now and then you know playing eight nine ten sets in a row or sometimes there was a line.
Rym: so I'd always just go to this Ridge Racer one machine and I played it so much that I I set the ghost and then I kept beating the ghost and I just I love that game.
Scott: Yeah, Ridge Racer ones real good.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: What else is really good.
Rym: Uh, if we go for nostalgia I'm gonna have to go with stunts 4d racing.
Scott: Hey go RC Pro.
Scott: I'm on the new star RC program.
Scott: The second one actually is better.
Rym: it is but even the first one was Compared to other racing games out on that system at that time RC program was amazing.
Scott: I think the thing about RC Pro M is that you cite you sort of had BB.
Scott: It was the only game they got the car customizing, right?
Scott: It's like you collected stuff on the track and you won races in order to get money To buy more stuff for your car and get more, you know And you would upgrade the car to go faster.
Rym: There was that other game I forget was called my brother was really good at it where he drove the trucks or whatever and it was 4p With the four score and you upgraded the cars.
Rym: there was an arcade game too, but it wasn't that great No, but it was that just out off-road.
Rym: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: Yeah Now the RC problem definitely had the car customizing going on correctly and the game itself was really fun.
Scott: You just you drove around this track.
Scott: It's the only racing game that worked well with the overhead view because the controls are right A lot of those other overhead.
Scott: if you racing games just didn't have the controls that work Didn't get it.
Rym: a lot of people made overhead racing games with Absolute control so up is always up and down is always down instead of relative control.
Rym: and let me tell you that is not a Good decision.
Rym: No, no, that was evolution worked and that doesn't happen anymore Like off-road freaking.
Scott: use the steering wheel in the arcade to play a game where you could see the whole track at the same time.
Rym: Bad idea.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Good God.
Rym: Yeah, but that wasn't as bad as absolute control up up down down.
Scott: That's the worst.
Rym: actually, you know what a really good racing game was for the NES that bootleg micro machines game.
Scott: It was okay.
Rym: It was really fun and it was pretty good racing.
Rym: The only problem with it was that being bootleg it was kind of glitchy and I mean really glitchy But that was a pretty good game all things considered.
Scott: I don't know would you could Oh who can go without saying pole position?
Scott: I love me some pole position.
Rym: I don't actually like pulp.
Scott: I actually do like pole position.
Rym: I had it Was the first time I got when I got the Atari 7800.
Scott: I especially like oh, yeah The sit-down arcade machine of pole position one is is by far the best.
Scott: I mean, it's just.
Scott: it's straightforward It's simple.
Scott: It's step on the gas don't hit anything and Everything will be cool.
Rym: But if you want to play an old-school racing game, that's kind of fun.
Rym: Find a cracked copy.
Rym: I've never seen a legitimate copy of stunts 40 racing.
Rym: You'll pry.
Rym: find one cracked by kill fit because that's whoever was who cracked the one.
Rym: that Internet's right now it was installed on every single computer at my middle school and I brought it on a disc to my high school and installed it on every computer at my high school.
Rym: And I played the ever-living fuck out of that game.
Rym: I made a million maps for it.
Rym: That game was just amazing, especially considering it basically had crappy digital control and he was one of those.
Rym: You know, there's loops and jumps and it wasn't terribly realistic But it made up for that by being incredibly fun and incredibly skill based.
Scott: Yeah, that's something I think deserves talking about.
Scott: is that a lot of racing games there?
Scott: pretty much if it's a real racing game It's impossible to play with digital control.
Scott: Digital control means that you are that you all.
Scott: the only controls you have are you know?
Scott: accelerate not accelerate Brake not brake.
Scott: left not left right not right.
Scott: Those are the only controls you have to have a proper racing game.
Scott: You need to have analog controls which can be like Accelerate a little bit accelerate a little bit more accelerate a little bit more accelerate all the way.
Scott: Break a little bit.
Scott: break a little bit more.
Scott: break a little bit less.
Scott: turn left a little bit.
Scott: turn left a lot I get even more.
Rym: there were games that did with digital controls.
Rym: They achieved a lot stunts despite being digital.
Rym: There's a lot of skill involved and it was a great game.
Rym: And yeah, honestly, I'd love to see a modern racing game That's like that where it's completely Non-realistic but yet really self-consistent and as a result really really really really fun.
Scott: Yeah, there are a lot of it was but it's possible to make a racing game that is fun and playable with digital control But a proper racing game needs analog control.
Scott: It's just.
Rym: let's talk a bit about Realism because initial D is such a fun game, but it's not realistic worth a shit.
Scott: It's realistic if you consider initial D the anime to be the real world.
Rym: Well, it's realistic up to a point.
Rym: the cars will lose traction About as a real car would.
Rym: the problem is once you have lost traction and you're drifting The game doesn't make you counter steer which means in the real world If you tried to drift around a corner the way you did in initial D, you would die.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is initially once you're drifting the car basically magically goes around the corner properly like you drifted.
Rym: awesome.
Rym: No, I gotta say an initial d4.
Rym: I think it's more realistic because I tried my strategy of gas all the way.
Rym: suddenly I downshift and then you'll blah blah counter steer blue and I just fishtailed and crashed into the wall every time.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well the most realistic racing him I've ever played was NASCAR Silicon Alley motor speedway, which if you I don't know if you know about this But they set these up.
Scott: I don't know if there still are any setup But there was one set up in the Palisades Mall when it with the Palisades Mall was still crazy and malls still had animatronics and stuff, you know in the in the heyday of the 90s and Basically, it was eight full-size NASCAR cars.
Scott: They obviously have engines in them but they were Cards and you would get in the car put your seatbelt on and everything and the car was on a pneumatic lift and there was like a big projector screen in front of you and I forget if there was like a rearview mirror or if there was just a project there.
Scott: just Projected the rearview mirror onto the screen but the car would move.
Scott: you actually had real pedals and a stick and everything and You had this projector screen in front of you that was had the best graphics of the day and it was basically a simulator.
Scott: But it you know as a game and you paid like 15 bucks for one race against the seven other people who paid 15 bucks and it was incredibly realistic and Absolutely, not fun at all.
Rym: Honestly, I Really really enjoy like crazily realistic racing games and even though they're very difficult and I'll probably crash a lot No, cuz actually like.
Scott: of course I crashed a lot, you know at first But then I got the hang of it and once I got the hang of it, it was still not fun.
Rym: Well, I think it'd be more fun If it wasn't NASCAR.
Rym: Imagine f1 perfectly realistic because that the thing is.
Rym: I enjoy games like initial D because they're really really really fun and I get to drift and be all Takahashi Ryosuke.
Rym: and I also really like Completely unrealistic stupid racing games like stunts because I get to drive in a loop and fly off over the plastic cows.
Rym: but When it comes to an ultra realistic racing game with perfectly realistic controls.
Rym: I mean my ideal racing game would be Exactly a car and it's exactly like driving a car except if I crash I don't lose a bunch of money and or die Because getting good at a game like that Directly translates into being good at real driving.
Rym: It's like all that time turns me into a real good race car driver, and I really like go-karts and race car driving.
Scott: Yeah, okay There's actually this there's been.
Scott: there are a lot of PC, you know accurate racing simulators, you know They are car simulators.
Rym: They don't do it for me.
Scott: Well, it's sort of like that same culture of flight simulators, you know And I think one of the popular ones is called live for speed.
Scott: I'm not sure if it's free or not, but you can you can go get it and try.
Scott: I've never tried it.
Scott: So, I don't know if it's good or not but you know that's sort of like.
Scott: if you're one of those crazy people who like loves flight simulators like x-plane and you like Racing or you you can try to get live for speed.
Scott: See how it goes.
Rym: See, I think my problem is that like Gran Turismo games you'd think I like them all.
Rym: They're really real really realistic and they keep getting more realistic and better.
Rym: But most people I see play these games with a controller and to me the idea of taking a game and making it so Realistic and then controlling it in the most unrealistic way possible just removes all the fun from the game.
Rym: Yeah, I'd be willing to also though, you know, I like realism in terms of driving.
Rym: I don't care about the car I don't want to get money and buy the blah blah blah breaks instead of the blah blah blah breaks.
Rym: I couldn't I care about that so little Not at all.
Rym: It's like when you wanted to join the race car driving club at RIT You were like, can I just be really good at driving the car and drive the car?
Rym: and they were like no You also have to do the other stuff.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: well it was sort of like RIT had a formula SAE team where they make a little car and then you know They they race it and it's sort of like, you know, it's mostly an engineering thing, you know Can we make a better formula car than the other people in the competition?
Scott: It's sort of like educational level formula, whatever.
Scott: and I bet I went to those people because they think they were technically the largest club on campus.
Scott: and I found out who the Person was my freshman year and I said hey Well, technically the largest club on campus was the club club that consisted of anyone in a club.
Rym: But alright, right stupid IT.
Scott: Yeah, but I went to those people and I was just like, hey Are you the formula SAE?
Scott: whatever they're like, yeah, and I was like, what does it take to be able to drive that car?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: well, you got to join our club and you got a. you know spend years blah blah blah blah blah.
Scott: I'm really only interested in driving.
Scott: I know nothing about engineering and I don't care.
Scott: they're like, oh well Yeah, and I'm like, huh?
Scott: I guess if I was Michael Schumacher in disguise, you'd be SOL now wouldn't you.
Rym: but I'm gonna say it straight up playing in those games I just I don't see the appeal of playing a game like Gran Turismo with a controller.
Rym: It's analog.
Rym: Yeah, it's not a steering wheel with a gas pedal in a brake.
Scott: No Some people do go out and buy the steering wheel on the gas now break.
Rym: there's where I get into that because okay I've never seen a home steering wheel and brake other than custom things people have made or things that are stupidly expensive.
Rym: That is even close to realistic enough to justify Playing that game.
Rym: Yes If it's not if I can't translate my skills from a perfectly realistic or nearly realistic driving game Into the real world pretty directly.
Rym: I feel like I'm just wasting my time and I'd rather just go play initial D.
Scott: Yeah, I'd rather go play a fun racing game of some kind or f-zero or even excite truck.
Scott: I mean the thing with the people are thinking about using the Wiimote for steering wheels and that's it's not a bad idea.
Scott: I mean it kind of works.
Scott: Why does everyone do it wrong?
Rym: What everyone does it wrong?
Rym: It should be exactly like excite truck.
Scott: Yeah, well, it should be exactly like a side trick.
Scott: The problem is it's not with a steering wheel right the way.
Scott: the way the Wiimote works is relative You know, it gets the acceleration, right?
Scott: So it's like if I turn the Wiimote to the left it, you know, it knows that I accelerate it to the left.
Scott: So it turns the car to the left But then it assumes that I'm still at the left until it feels an acceleration to the right, you know.
Scott: And it's sort of like I really need that.
Scott: let go of the steering wheel and it recenters itself kind of stuff going on.
Scott: It's not it's.
Scott: it's better than a gamepad by a zillion, but it's still not a steering wheel.
Rym: also, there's this the issues of.
Rym: I need pedals and all that stuff and I need to be able to see out the sides and I need to bail.
Rym: just look into my rearview mirror and The thing that even if I get all that perfect I feel like the one of the most important parts of being a good driver when it comes to racing.
Rym: or you know, not the kind of driving you do on the freeway is Actually feeling the road and the car and the g-forces.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I think I'm better and I mean I don't.
Rym: it's not like I've ever taken my car racing but I think if I were I don't know trying to get away from the police which is not entirely out of the realm and in terms of where my life might end up I Feel like I would be better at trying to drive my real crappy car as in it's real my real physical car and it's crappy.
Rym: It's not real crappy.
Rym: I Feel like I could take that around a racetrack a lot better.
Rym: Then I could take a super fancy car around a racetrack in some realistic game.
Rym: Yes, I can feel.
Scott: yeah, like I feel when most of the time when I'm playing a game like Gran Turismo All right, what's the skill and grip?
Scott: What is the thing that you have to do to be good at Gran Turismo?
Scott: is to know?
Scott: It's the same thing as to be to know to be good at f1 in real life is how fast do you go?
Scott: Can you take the turn without killing yourself?
Rym: You know because you have a car how close can I get to that limit?
Rym: knowing any car to the limit the closer?
Rym: You are to die.
Scott: any car that goes and isn't broken can go straight, you know without worry about crashing.
Scott: You just hold the gas down and you hold the wheel straight and you're good to go unless the car itself fails, right?
Scott: But turning if you're going a hundred miles an hour around You know a 30-degree radius.
Scott: turn the car.
Scott: No car has the traction capable to do that, you know If you're holding down the gas pedal you have to slow down Right to a to a speed at which the tires will not lose traction while going around the turn.
Rym: now Not only that.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So let's say you slow down Exactly enough to make the turn.
Rym: like you have slowed down the minimum you're going at the maximum possible speed around the corner.
Rym: That's the maximum speed.
Scott: meaning if Anything changes if there's a pebble if your tire wears out a little bit because you you know This is the second lap and you'll immediately crash if the temperature goes up a little bit or temperature goes down Decreasing track because there's no margin.
Rym: so most of actual racing is just knowing the margin between crashing and not crashing and knowing your car and knowing what's gonna happen.
Rym: and It comes down to knowing where the limits are and choosing how much you are willing to risk on every corner.
Scott: yep, so knowing those things is step one.
Scott: step two is feeling those things right and Sort of like if you if I drive my car, right which is a normal street car you can feel the g-force is acting on your body if you go around a turn too quickly.
Scott: and If g-forces are acting on your body when you're taking my car around a turn It's not a race car.
Scott: if you're feeling force it g-forces when you're going around a turn The car is probably gonna lose traction, especially if the snow or rain or anything and that's not good.
Scott: So being able to feel that that g-force is what allows you, you know in addition to knowledge It's that that's the only thing that helps you take the car at its maximum speed is go as fast as I can and slow Down if I feel g-forces and I can take the car pretty close to its limit in an f1 car You're gonna feel g-forces because the car's capabilities are so insane.
Scott: It's but it's how much g-forces do you feel?
Rym: It's just like playing because I've played Gran Turismo with actual like not great controllers, but with you know pedal and brake and steering wheel yeah, and Driving around a corner the car will suddenly spin out even at you know, reasonable speeds just because I can't feel where the limit is.
Scott: Yep it's like I'll be going 50 miles an hour and I'll turn the wheel and From the sensation of speed I get from my eyeballs looking at the track on the screen.
Scott: It feels to me like I'm gonna make it around the turn But without the be the ability to feel that.
Scott: oh shit There's a lot of g-forces on my body.
Scott: the car spins out on the screen and I just go what the fuck.
Scott: and I'm frustrated Whereas if I was in that that car for real on that track for real I would have felt the traction being lost in my ass through the seat and I wouldn't have spun out in the first place.
Rym: Yep, I mean I because especially growing up just in Michigan and then in Rochester and always driving in snow and ice all the time My car, you know, I lose traction Pretty often and I think that's getting new tires.
Scott: I haven't.
Rym: it's probably the best example that I have many times in my life oversteered or under steered in the winter or in rain You know going fast on the freeway on purpose.
Rym: Yes, but that's beside the point but it's happened.
Rym: It happens cuz there's ice or whatever and in video games when that happens nine times out of ten I crash because I can't feel how to correct.
Rym: but in the real world Even if I'm going really really fast if I suddenly lose traction in the rear end and I'm you know over steering I can correct without even blinking because I feel it.
Rym: I just like you just feel and you correct and it works.
Rym: but in a video game where it should be easier It's a lot harder because I can't feel it.
Scott: Yep, and this is why I think that you know racing games in general like, you know virtual racing which lets you feel it through the steering wheel or Initial D, which you you don't feel it But it doesn't matter because you know The game is not real.
Rym: so really game kind of does a lot of correction for you and it's like zero knows the idea.
Scott: Let's make him get around the car and f0 which is you know, not even close to real-world cars.
Rym: I mean you have a hover car going 2,000 kilometers an hour or in stunts where I go through 100 foot tall loop in my f1 car and then hit a 45 degree ramp Yeah and jump over a windmill in all those games.
Scott: I think though that's why I find those racing games to be more enjoyable than the admittedly Technologically superior forces in Gran Turismo's because while realism is cool and all it's basically it's not fun If it they're missing the essential component of the realism, you know Even if the graphics were half as good and the cars physics were shittier if I could feel it Those games would be ten times better than they are.
Rym: I think this is why Scott and I really want to get into a pretty much now.
Rym: It's just a matter of time.
Rym: We don't as in we don't have time to do it at all and there aren't.
Rym: there isn't enough nearby.
Rym: We really want to get into go-kart racing.
Rym: Yeah I feel like even like the crappiest like the bottom rung of go-kart racing.
Rym: I'm not talking like you.
Rym: go to Jillian's and race the go-karts or the slick karts.
Scott: But one step up from that as in some guys have a club everyone makes a go-kart or buys a go-kart races it the lot.
Rym: I think the line is because I've been in real go-karts before in Canada in places where or The one time in Wildwood where they let us go in the rain.
Scott: That was good times.
Rym: if you get to the point where you cannot if you can hold the gas pedal down the whole way around The track it's not it's nothing.
Scott: Yeah, like if you if you go to the go-karts at the local amusement center You can hold the gas pedal down the whole time.
Scott: and if as long as you steer with the steering wheel Right and you pay attention You will not spin out because the car has been limited to go at such a speed that even at max speed of that Go-kart, you will make it around every single turn without losing control.
Rym: But I if you do go-karts if you find them if you haven't ever Do go-karts where you have to slow down or you'll crash or spin out It's better than any video game and I really and then you're actually racing.
Scott: I mean, you know, it won't cut it'll actually you know matter the how you control the vehicle.
Rym: I remember the first time I did it I was with my family in Canada and we saw this go-kart place.
Rym: My brother and I convinced my parents to pull over and they're thinking go-karts.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: Why do you want to simulate driving?
Rym: Drive rings boring and go-karts is stupid.
Rym: and then we get there and we discovered that the go-karts go 50 miles an hour.
Scott: Yep, and you're gonna wear a helmet and you gotta sign a waiver.
Rym: and Good God, did I suddenly become interested in car racing like you wouldn't believe?
Scott: Yeah, it's good stuff and it's only in Canada where there's not as much liability as the.
Rym: well There's a lot in the u.s.
Rym:  it's just we don't.
Rym: I don't have time.
Rym: That's really the only thing stopping me.
Rym: I've.
Rym: we've looked into it.
Rym: It's not that expensive to get into.
Rym: a lot of people are into it.
Scott: All I have to do all kinds of mechanics stuff even though it's simple like a lawnmower engine.
Rym: Not so much you can rent cars and you can join clubs where they provide cars or where everyone uses the same car.
Scott: Yeah, I know but the problem with that though is like I remember reading this story about a guy who went ski doing right with Like a bunch of people from work or something, right?
Scott: And basically he goes down there and all these guys had their own CDs.
Scott: or you know wave runners whatever you want to call him and he rented one and it was basically everyone else was like whoo and he was in the jalopy like.
Rym: Well, I have seen clubs where everyone like they'll have a mechanic who maintains them and everyone basically has the exact same car.
Rym: That way there is never ever any argument as to who is the better driver?
Rym: No, because it just comes down to you've all got the same car.
Scott: Yeah a lot of P pretty much a lot of the f1 drivers you see.
Scott: now like you I guess I don't think Scott Speed is still racing but Like I can't even think of a single name, but Kimi Raikkonen.
Scott: Well, he might have.
Scott: but a lot of those people they started out in their youth riding go-karts like, you know Scott Speed was like a like 10 year old 10 year old Go-karts.
Rym: f1 is a lot more like a go-kart than like any other kind of racing.
Scott: Oh, it's like a go-kart with a jet engine.
Rym: It's a really fast go-kart.
Rym: But I mean if you watch him in slow motion and watch like the way they move and the way they take corners Slow motion.
Rym: It's just like watching kids in a go-kart race.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much It's just little little turns little turn little turn big turn little turn.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I think we've gone on long enough.
Rym: We we like racing games, but we like real racing games are cool.
Scott: If you have virtual racing is the best one.
Scott: I forgot it though, which is sad But now I remember it which is awesome.
Rym: Ridge Racer one is the bomb.
Rym: if you can find it somewhere It's not bad.
Rym: all the ridge racers are.
Scott: not only you know Not only is virtual racing the best one But pretty much everything you have in racing games today came from virtual racing.
Scott: it pretty much invented Every fundamental, you know aspect of modern racing games and not much has changed since then.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website, which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.