Rym: It's Thursday, May 17th.
Rym: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight.
Rym: we make fun of those crackpots with their crazy conspiracy theories.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So uh somewhat unexpectedly I had a brush with death today at work.
Scott: a brush with death you say.
Scott: was it another Exploding power supply?
Rym: no it was an actual brush with death as opposed to a hilarious brush with death.
Scott: Well my day would have been quite interesting if you had died rather than just brushed it.
Rym: yes luckily I grabbed it with two fingers instead of my whole hand and thus.
Rym: I was spared death.
Scott: It was electricity then was so.
Rym: you see I was going down into the basement of this building and in the basement is a big gigantic metal rack cabinet with doors on it and inside of that is a rack and connotation.
Rym: the rack are a whole bunch of switches and routers networking equipment and no one is open this rack or Bothered with it for many many months because it works just fine and in fact I was only going down there to count how many PCs were plugged into it And how many things were patched down and that sort of thing for a future upgrade?
Rym: So I go down there and I open the door and I look in and I reach over and I grab the handle to this Cabinet to open it and suddenly I feel like the room is shaking.
Rym: and then I realized that no my hand is shaking.
Rym: And then I realized that no my hand is not shaking.
Rym: I am just being filled with 120 volts Awesome and with a bit of effort I pull myself away.
Scott: Yeah, I wonder what does that?
Scott: because like one time I was holding a light switch You know in the wall And it kind of the electricity went in one finger and out the other back into the wall.
Scott: It was sort of like a loop between my thumb and forefinger, and it's like hard to let go.
Scott: it's sort of like magnets.
Rym: Actually, that's the reason that generally when you're working with electricity 120 volts is a lot more dangerous than 220.
Rym: Because with 110 120 when when the voltage goes through you it Tends to cause your muscles to tense up and keep hold of whatever you're holding on to.
Scott: oh, that's how it works.
Rym: Yep, but 220.
Rym: It's so much power right away that more likely.
Rym: It's gonna spark and throw you away from it.
Rym: In fact my grandpa almost died when he was a kid.
Rym: He was.
Rym: he didn't realize there was a big rope hanging from a tree But it was actually a downed power line, and he went to go Tarzan on it And instead he just hung there dying of like well almost being electrocuted.
Rym: but eventually his dad like came out by eventually I mean Almost right away and hit him in the stomach with a log or a brick or something to knock him off of the thing.
Rym: I'm glad we're not using DC Well anyway, so uh, but I pull myself off of it, and I fall to the ground.
Rym: I'm sitting there going what the fuck God damn it son of a bitch, and someone comes in.
Rym: they're like Something going on, and I'm like fucking shit.
Rym: call facilities, and don't go into this room.
Rym: So I call the engineers and they come in and I'm like yes, there's a voltage leak somewhere.
Rym: this entire cabinet is electrified.
Rym: Meanwhile I point out that all the equipment inside of it's working just fine Awesome, so the guy looks at me and says yeah, you sure it isn't some static or something, and I'm like Touch it why don't you just touch it?
Scott: so he pulls out?
Rym: He's got one of those little testers And he touches it to it, and he's laughing.
Rym: and then the light goes bright red And he goes beep and he pulls it away and backs.
Rym: He'd like backs a step up and goes oh Don't let anyone go in there.
Scott: God people.
Rym: so then I take care of all this because I don't know what the procedure is for dealing with deadly voltage Filling and I know the procedure.
Scott: Oh, no.
Rym: I know my personal procedure.
Scott: What's your?
Scott: what's your personal procedure?
Scott: Let's see if yours is similar to mine.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Well first was don't fucking touch anything else.
Scott: Ah, that's that worth the similar ones.
Rym: number two back out of the room.
Rym: Yeah Call whatever electrical people.
Rym: yeah make sure no one goes in.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: And then I went back into the room and looked around to see if I could identify What was going on and see if I could just pull the plug outside of this thing?
Rym: That's plugging the whole thing into the wall and then back away Mm-hmm.
Rym: and I didn't because I didn't know what the procedure is for taking down an entire building's network infrastructure.
Rym: Yeah, it's out of the blue especially since it was technically all up and working.
Rym: Yeah Worse the voltage leak was coming from a faulty PDU stuck on the inside of it.
Rym: that PDU was connected to the UPS uh-oh and the whole thing wasn't grounded for some reason.
Rym: so I filled out the OSHA forms and I Did the whole deal.
Rym: they sent me to the doctor.
Rym: The doctor looked at me.
Scott: Well, you're in a hospital, right?
Rym: So yeah, so I just walked over to the actual hospital out of the office and I was like, yeah I just got shocked pretty bad.
Scott: So the doctor it goes.
Scott: All right, let's look at this You're living you're good.
Rym: Yeah, well they checked me out.
Rym: Actually, they did a bunch of tests to see if my hand had all the strength.
Scott: cuz I pointed out that the voltage just went Through my middle finger my ring finger that that puts me a little tangent here, but I realized why People going to the emergency room cost hospitals so much money.
Scott: Oh, uh, I can tell you in great detail It's like I didn't realize quite you know this that Hospitals lose all their money because if you show up to the emergency room whether you have insurance or not They'll do something for you.
Rym: Well, they have to do something.
Rym: You don't want to.
Scott: sometimes Yes and even if you go in with like a cold they have to do something because you went to the emergency.
Scott: and
Rym: I read a Study recently that I don't know which hospital it was for because I just read it briefly But one hospital did a study and determined that Fewer than 1/4 of any of the people who come into emergency room had anything even remotely close to an emergency.
Scott: Yeah, they really should be allowed to just say no you're not an emergency go away, but they can't.
Rym: no You know what?
Rym: They do usually if you ever go to an emergency room and you have to wait four hours to get treated That means that you're one of those assholes and it wasn't an emergency.
Rym: Yeah, because what they do is they make you wait hoping you'll just go away.
Scott: Yep But anyway, when you go to emergency room, they even no matter what it's for Even if you have a cold they will run basically all sorts of crazy tests to make sure because you came to the emergency room.
Scott: So they're assuming that if you came here, there's something seriously
Rym: wrong with you The term is triage and what that means is that they'll take you in and they'll determine if you're an imminent danger of death or Permanent disability or a serious turn for the worse or any anything that's dangerous to your eyes.
Rym: And actually that the basic tests are very simple and don't cost anything.
Scott: But then when they actually get around to taking care of you, even if you have to wait four hours They will run tests on you that are expensive and time-consuming.
Rym: Actually, not always the only read the only test they did ran on me was an EKG and the only reason they did that Was as a precaution.
Rym: they didn't do anything else other than you know blood pressure.
Scott: Yeah, but that's because you went in with electricity Cutioning.
Scott: Yeah, that's what they check you with now.
Rym: They didn't see something in my EEG where she looked at it for a while and then she said I'm gonna get a second opinion.
Rym: We'll call you back.
Rym: Uh-huh I don't know what that's all about But the interesting part of this story not that I had a brush with death because I don't care about that.
Rym: But I need to take a moment to preen in front of the crowds the audience of GeekNights Mm-hmm.
Rym: because so she's checking, you know My pulse and everything and my blood pressure.
Rym: and while she's checking my pulse the first time she stops shakes her head drives it again She has my other arm and then she pauses and says are you an athlete?
Rym: Yeah, and I said Not really.
Rym: She's like, well, do you run her a lot or anything?
Rym: I'm like, yeah, and she says your heart rate's super low.
Rym: That means you're either a professional athlete or you have a serious problem.
Rym: The second one actually no because all the rest of the test and at the end of the exam I was told by the doctor that I am perhaps the optimal picture of health for a 25 year old man.
Scott: Sure with your and your oh You mean my allergies?
Scott: Yeah, that's not the optimal picture of hell.
Rym: Well in terms of I guess cardio health or muscles or heart or anything like that.
Rym: I'm in perfect frickin hell.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure Alright, so news is outside of Rym getting electrocuted.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, no, I didn't get electrocuted.
Rym: Yeah, because electrocution means very specifically electricity applied on to death.
Rym: Uh-huh, you cannot say you were electrocute.
Rym: electrocuted because if you say that you're dead and you couldn't have said it I guess electroshocked.
Rym: No, because electroshock is part of electroconvulsive therapy.
Scott: Well, I didn't say like trust you received electroshock therapy.
Scott: I just said you were electroshocked.
Rym: I don't know if the term applies terribly.
Rym: Well, though I do realize now there is a loophole.
Rym: Uh-huh, if let's say you were shocked and your heart stopped and then someone revived you I'll bet you could say electrocuted because your heart was stopped by the electricity you were killed and then brought back.
Scott: Who knows I actually read that article recently about how even if your heart stops then we have to.
Scott: it's not quite dead anymore.
Rym: They can kind of save you and oh, yeah, there's been a lot of cases of that.
Scott: So we're to gotta like change what me what it means to be dead and stuff like that.
Rym: Generally, I'm of the mind that death would be.
Rym: I would go with something with the brain.
Rym: when brain activity ceases and the brain starts Deteriorate physically physically until one day we find out how to bring it back.
Scott: It's like up.
Scott: There's no activity going on here at all.
Scott: Click up.
Scott: Wait.
Rym: No, there is uh Yep, part of the problem there is if you have organ donation or anything.
Rym: You've got to determine if someone's dead before the organs are all useless.
Rym: That's why I don't you can't go thing But you realize that there's no danger of them taking organs out of you.
Rym: if there's any chance you're gonna survive.
Scott: just in case There's no just in case plus they can take them.
Scott: Anyway, even if I don't sign the thing not really And whatever.
Rym: no they can't.
Rym: so you're just being a dick.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: I'll be dead.
Scott: What do I care?
Rym: See, it's funny how you've pretty much come all the way around to nihilism in your philosophy over the last several years.
Scott: It changes every day.
Scott: What can I know?
Rym: It's been pretty consistently.
Rym: nihilism for at least the last year I don't know.
Scott: I think it changes all the time.
Scott: Yeah, but for the last year nihilism Oh, well, maybe next year will be the year of I don't know something else.
Scott: Dadaism.
Rym: Anyway, what do you got in the news?
Scott: so to get weird and Sort of non-GeekNights here.
Scott: I've got a news about sports, but wait, okay, and it's actually a sport.
Scott: I care nothing about basketball.
Rym: Ah Granted I kind of like women's college basketball.
Scott: This is the NBA here the worst of all basketball.
Scott: I'd rather watch kids in the street playing basketball than the NBA I agree, but something happened interesting here that I think we can bring back to the old game theory type stuff.
Scott: And it's pretty.
Scott: it's pretty interesting.
Scott: So NBA right now.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's like whoever wins the current series.
Scott: go to the finals.
Scott: I'm not telling too much.
Rym: I have no idea how the NBA works.
Scott: There's a playoffs and you do like, you know Three out of five series or four to seven series and then eventually there's a finals Which is a four to seven series never wins that wins.
Rym: All I know is the Pistons are doing really well like they always do.
Scott: Yep, so one of the current playoff series going on is these Spurs and the Suns, right?
Rym: I can't name either city San Antonio and Phoenix, huh?
Scott: All right, so I can't believe I know all the sports teams, even though I don't give a shit about Either.
Rym: I figured you're just looking in the article.
Rym: No, I know god I think it is.
Rym: I'm a really big fan of hockey and I still don't know a lot of hockey teams that I don't care about.
Scott: What's the hockey team in Chicago like?
Rym: if I know Blackhawks cuz I don't care about the Blackhawks.
Scott: I know one does.
Scott: Okay, I hope you don't Chicago listeners they suck.
Rym: Well, yeah the Blackhawks like I like Chicago.
Scott: Yeah, it's okay Chicago last never ever not once.
Rym: I've actually been in Chicago a whole bunch of times All right.
Scott: So let me get to this story.
Rym: No, I'm just gonna keep keep.
Rym: we're gonna stay off-topic all night in this series.
Scott: right the first game some guy got injured and he was on it and they couldn't heal him quick enough to get him back in The game and that cost him the game.
Scott: right in the most recent game There was some sort of altercation going on Right, uh-huh.
Scott: And the NBA rule says that if you get off the bench to go run to the altercation Then you're suspended.
Scott: That's what the rule says.
Scott: So these two guys who are pretty important players on one of the teams They went down the sideline Right and even though they didn't intend to join in the fight or anything like that They got off the bench and they were away from their bench when there was the fight going on Even if they weren't gonna get in the fight.
Scott: But the rule says that they would get suspended and they did so what if you were out taking a leak?
Scott: That's yeah.
Scott: People are basically up in arms because they consider these two teams to be the best teams this year And even and it's a shame because they're complaining like oh, why didn't they receive these?
Scott: This should be the finals not the semi-finals or whatever.
Scott: blah blah blah.
Rym: Everyone complains about that every year in every sport.
Scott: I know I know but the point is is that now because They they've decided to go by the letter of the law instead of using common sense in applying the rules They basically ruined the whole NBA playoffs this year by taking two and very important players off one of the best teams.
Rym: God, I would get a player to start some shit really close to the other benches and hope that they all stand up.
Scott: actually, oh There I listen to an interview because I listen to PTI every day Which is an ESPN radio whatever and they had the Commission of the NBA on talking about it, right?
Scott: Cuz it was such a big deal.
Scott: They interviewed him for like half the show and he was actually like yeah We had rules like this because You know one.
Scott: we assumed that at some point someone would get some chump players who were crap to start fights with star players and get them all suspended.
Scott: and they wouldn't care because it was some chump got suspended and some Star player got suspended.
Scott: That's why they have rules like this.
Scott: Meanwhile the rule made bad things happen and went against what they were trying to prevent.
Scott: it makes no sense.
Rym: Oh, well, I find it kind of hilarious.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty hilarious but you think about it when German board games part of the reason they're so great is because There's never an instance where following the letter of the rules of the game Goes against what's common sense
Rym: except in really bad game,
Scott: but that's a bad game.
Scott: But yeah, my point is
Rym: hell is hell is yes
Scott: But this is a way that you can tell a good game Apart from a bad game is that if you follow all the rules of the game to the letter There will never be an instance where you say that's bullshit and then you go.
Scott: No.
Scott: Well, there it is.
Scott: Yep It'll always be.
Scott: oh that makes perfect sense.
Scott: Like how many times do I say we sit around and we're playing a German board game?
Scott: when you argue like well This would make the most sense, you know It wouldn't make sense the other way and 99% of the time pretty much whenever it's a good game Whatever we say would make sense is what the rule ends up saying.
Rym: Granted we don't own a lot of crappy games and I'm sure there's some crappy games that have some nonsensical stuff.
Scott: Those are crappy games.
Scott: Yeah, so and be assessed my point is basketball is a crappy game.
Rym: So this morning just as I was leaving for work I hit the old f5 on slash dot and I saw a story about a judge ruling on a technology case or a case that involved technology.
Rym: It actually was a case about some quote-unquote terrorist inciting something something.
Rym: I don't even I didn't pay attention.
Rym: I barely read the article because it doesn't matter.
Rym: but apparently the judge didn't know and really had trouble understanding what a website was and I thought Crap, the Internet's gonna explode about this and I'm gonna have to talk about it tonight.
Rym: So here I am talking about it.
Scott: It's a British judge, by the way.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't even read the article.
Scott: albionic judge.
Rym: Yeah I don't know what this Britain is you talk about.
Rym: Yeah, I Mean last I heard it was a colony of Rome.
Rym: Oh But now I assume a lot of you out there, you know, oh, yeah Now Rym and Scott are gonna complain about how stupid this judge is and how fucked up the legal system is and about how every Judge should know all about the internet and all about how technology works and be up with the times.
Rym: And that's really not what I'm gonna say.
Scott: Okay, because we've all said that before.
Rym: Yeah Well, I say that about other things but when it comes to a judge Asking them to head now see I'm really divided on this issue and I think I'll get into why I'm divided.
Rym: on one hand asking a judge to only be able to rule or Consider cases where he is fully cognizant of all of the issues involved.
Scott: It's a little unrealistic because that means that like some like super surgeon has to be like the judge at some Practice suit and you really want him to be surgery.
Rym: Say there's a case where I don't know a whole bunch of pet food gets poisoned and the witnesses are all in describing What chemical got into the pet food and trying to make the case?
Rym: Well, the judge isn't a biologist.
Rym: He's not a chemist.
Rym: He doesn't understand exactly what all this is.
Rym: you show him the report of toxicology.
Rym: He won't really he won't know any more about it than this judge did about the website.
Rym: Yeah, and it'll have to be explained to him.
Rym: so Requiring or expecting judges to know everything about technology that they're going after and also about law.
Rym: Yes is Really going to.
Rym: there's no way we could rule on pretty much any case that would ever involve it science or technology.
Scott: It's pretty unrealistic because anyone who has the requisite knowledge to judge properly won't probably won't have the knowledge of the law.
Scott: Anyone with knowledge of the law probably won't have knowledge of every single specialized thing out there and We'd really either have a shortage of judges or we'd have a lot of people with valuable skills using them to judge instead of Use the skills themselves.
Scott: Like would you rather have a doctor doctoring or a doctor judging some doctors?
Scott: There's not enough doctors to do everything granted.
Rym: The other side of this is that in the modern world Basic computer literacy is pretty much tantamount to literacy in total.
Scott: at this point Yes, while at least in the industrialized world Yes, while I would not expect, you know a judge to have to be have a degree in computer science Although that would be nice to judge computer cases at least I should expect them to be able to.
Scott: you know Use a little Microsoft Word action and browse some websites send some emails send some IMs Know what my space is because it's probably a lot of cases involving that.
Scott: Understand, you know p2p and the basics what my mom understands.
Rym: see now the thing is Ideally, it shouldn't matter because the way I see it regardless of what the case is The judge is just judging on the facts and the law that sort of thing.
Rym: So whenever there's a case where something that the judge doesn't understand comes up I think it's just the duty of the lawyers and/or their expert witnesses to explain it in suitable enough detail for the judge.
Rym: because alright Let's say we get a judge who understands all these technology issues.
Rym: All right, hurrah now he can deal with the case Fully knowing what these expert witnesses are talking about.
Rym: I posit to you Scott What are the odds that even one of those jurors has one goddamn clue what they're talking about regardless of what the judge knows?
Scott: Not much because if someone like if you if you're a doctor who understands doctoring you're not gonna be a juror on a malpractice case They're not just not gonna let it happen.
Rym: well I mean you all remember from my jury Experiences where I was basically told that I am overqualified to be a juror and that I'll never serve on a jury.
Scott: Yes, but pretend it's not even a case with a jury.
Scott: It's just a civil case so it's just the judge.
Rym: even then the judge should be able to get from the expert witnesses and from the lawyers a Suitable explanation of what is going on?
Scott: So unless that both unless the judge is Unknowledgeable and all the expert witnesses are poor experts and the lawyers found poor expert witnesses because they're not too good at finding them Yeah,
Rym: or if the judge is stupid
Scott: Yeah
Rym: that I mean there is the problem where what if your expert witnesses explain everything in perfect detail and the judge is just too Dense to understand it
Scott: shouldn't be a judge.
Scott: Yeah, I just to be able to understand any expert witness What was the old quote?
Rym: I think it was from Monty Python might have been from somewhere else But it just comes to mind and I think a few people probably Posted it on slash shot and FARC and all the places that talk about this.
Rym: But you know, yeah, I wanted to be a judge but the entrance entrance exam was too tough So I decided to become a minor.
Rym: Unfortunately when you're too old and stupid to be a minor you can't be a minor anymore.
Rym: Well, the opposite is true for judging.
Rym: Now I do point out that there is one further possible issue Surrounding this whole thing and that is that the judge might not be as done dance as everyone seems to think.
Rym: I didn't read the article But I know that a lot of times when a concept is brought up in court Like say a website The judge might have said he doesn't know what a website is very clearly in order to force the people involved in the trial to Explain exactly what a website is for the purposes of this case because let me think the term website is kind of broad to me a website is Like a site and a web page is different.
Rym: and what's the boundary between one website and another website?
Rym: And is it the data in the database?
Rym: Is it the server?
Rym: Is it the content?
Rym: Yeah, things like that.
Rym: and also maybe in case the jury was I don't know Possibly not the brightest bunch of people the judge might have even been doing this solely for the benefit of the jury So they would force the people to explain this for the benefit of them.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: However You know, there weren't too many people paying attention to this case.
Scott: I imagine I mean, it's not like some high-profile on the TV You know case.
Scott: so the in order for someone to notice this and put it up on the internet to be like Oh my god Can you believe this?
Scott: it probably they probably would have had to been there and experience the dumbness or or?
Rym: They decided to write it up in the way that they did in order to get a bunch of digs or that someone made it Up.
Scott: Yeah, not true.
Rym: I wouldn't doubt it.
Scott: being made up quite frankly Regardless is just yet another tough excuse to talk about judges.
Scott: I choose you ditto.
Rym: Oh Anyway things of the day.
Rym: So in keeping with our main bit tonight, I linked to one of those random crazy Conspiracy nutjob videos.
Rym: and while this isn't one of them This is just a straight-up nutjob conspiracy about how Freemasons and Mormons and whatever could secretly control the world from Bavaria or whatever with aliens in the pyramids.
Rym: I don't know how people believe this shit But I discovered when I found this that there is an entire sub-genre on the internet of music videos set to Illuminati Imagery and they seem to all this anything like your famous Born to be alive.
Rym: I don't think so.
Rym: I'm pretty sure all of these people are trying to quote-unquote.
Rym: get the word out about the Illuminati Don't?
Scott: they know it's just a game made by Steve Jackson.
Rym: I don't think they do.
Scott: They not play the game.
Rym: I think they think the game is just a joke and the real Illuminati is waiting.
Scott: But but the game the game.
Rym: Well, I think the game may or may not have come after the term was calling of course But that's not the point.
Scott: The point is that the Illuminati was real.
Scott: the game wouldn't fly.
Rym: Maybe it would because you see if the Illuminati were real and they didn't let the game fly Then everyone who tried to make the game fly would have known because there would have been some sort of influence.
Rym: So instead cleverly the Illuminati acted like it didn't exist in order to let the game come out in order to convince everyone to think That the Illuminati doesn't really exist when in fact it does I'm sure but it doesn't all right.
Scott: We have an inside joke in the front row crew because at some point in time, you know I'm a fan of arts, I guess certain arts and I kind of like statues.
Scott: I like to go to museums and look at statues.
Rym: This wasn't an inside joke.
Rym: This was just proof that you're homosexual.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay, whatever.
Scott: so You know at one point in time people were talking about something.
Scott: I forget what the discussion was, but I was like, yeah I'd like to have some art in my house.
Scott: Maybe like one of those big statues of a naked Greek guy You know because they have statues of naked Greek guys and a lot of them are pretty cool.
Scott: And of course everyone took this to mean that Scott likes naked Greek guys gay.
Rym: Well, the thing is it was.
Rym: I want a statue in the house, you know, like one of those big naked Greek guys.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much.
Rym: and the room paused for a good ten seconds for we all just stared at Scott because that came out of Nowhere, it didn't really come out of nowhere.
Scott: I think it wasn't a non sequitur.
Rym: Big naked Greek guys came out of nowhere.
Rym: That is not what we were expecting.
Scott: Well recently because sculpture I think is a very unappreciated art form in modern times.
Scott: mostly I think because I'm mostly a fan if you couldn't tell of the Realistic kind of looks like people sculpture, you know, like when it's a statue but from far away It might be a person because it's so damn good.
Scott: That's the kind of sculptures I like.
Scott: but mostly nowadays the sculptures you see are things like the Sentinel at RIT Which is just some sort of abstract mess of shapes and materials.
Scott: and you know This.
Scott: I'm not saying that's wrong or bad, but I just not my preference.
Scott: I don't like that kind of sculpture as much as the you know Looks like a person made of one rock sculpture.
Rym: See I remember when they built the Sentinel and I wished at the time that instead they had built some sort of Equivalent of the Colossus of Rhodes some gigantic tiger over the entrance to RIT.
Scott: Yeah, we already had a little tiger Make that same thing only standing up on its rear legs maybe leaning on building one or something like that.
Rym: I think the scratching building one that would've been great.
Rym: I think the only reason they didn't was they calculated how many frat boys would die trying to paint the balls gold.
Scott: All right, so Recently on dig an awesome link appeared that I appreciate very much.
Scott: The link is five greatest sculptors of all time.
Scott: And well most of them four out of five of them are sculptures sculptors from very long ago that sculpted mostly Sculptures of people that are very realistic.
Rym: gonna hazard a guess is a Michelangelo in there.
Scott: He's number two.
Rym: How about Leonardo rafael donatello and splinter?
Scott: Donatello is number one, but no one.
Scott: none of the other Ninja Turtles have made a list.
Rym: I hate to say it but I get the impression that the only reason the majority of people in the world Even have heard of Michelangelo is because of the Ninja Turtles.
Scott: No, I think people would have heard of Michelangelo without the Ninja Turtles But Donatello Leonardo and Rafi all Leonardo people would have known also But they I bet a lot of people don't know that Leonardo turn into turtle is da Vinci.
Scott: They wouldn't like they wouldn't have mixed it up.
Scott: I remember when I was a little kid like I knew Leonardo da Vinci was and I knew the Ninja Turtles were named after like Ancient Renaissance artists, but I didn't match up Leonardo the turtle with Leonardo da Vinci.
Scott: I thought it was like some other Leonardo.
Scott: That was an artist.
Rym: Yeah, because Leonardo the turtle wouldn't have had trouble with that plum cherry.
Scott: That's for sure our plum tomato Yep, but yeah I would definitely wouldn't.
Scott: I personally would not have known who rafael or donatello were without the Ninja Turtles.
Rym: But it's so obvious.
Scott: Donatello was obviously that Renaissance guy with the post a yep Obviously, so number three is John Lorenzo Bernini, and I'm looking at his sculptures here, and they're pretty cool.
Scott: He's got this one.
Scott: It looks like Zeus or maybe it's?
Scott: Nope it see rape of Proserpina is the name of the sculpture, but it doesn't look like a rape of Proserpina to me.
Scott: Like Zeus or King Triton He's got like a little crown going on.
Scott: But the the sculpture.
Scott: that kind of freaked me out.
Scott: cuz I scrolled down quickly And I saw the leg on the sculpture And I thought it was a real leg like it even looks like it has hair on it, and then it's skin colored.
Scott: It's kind of scary.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: she thought it was real because it had a muscly leg with skin colored hair on it.
Scott: Well, no because like you look at it, and it looks like a real leg like damn.
Scott: Number four is Rodin.
Scott: who's the guy Rodin?
Scott: I don't know how to say it, but he's the.
Scott: He's the guy who made the thinker and the hell's gate and all that stuff.
Scott: and the fifth one is Constantine Broncussi who's a more recent sculptor.
Scott: he died in 57 and I look at it the two sculptures They display here as you know I guess examples of his work.
Scott: the second one is the endless column Which she looks just kind of weird, and I don't really like it that much.
Scott: But the first one is the kiss and it looks like it might be small.
Scott: I can't really tell the size of it from the picture, but it's not realistic, but I kind of like it anyway It's it's it's kind of cute.
Rym: So uh I heard that the Bavarian Illuminati controls the economy of the United States Really and that the WTO is working with the UN and the EU to create a new world order.
Rym: And they're going to use tech Mars to ship us all into tennis courts that are actually concentration camps.
Rym: Alright, yeah, and it turns out that the people who killed Kennedy are still alive But Kennedy is also still alive because there were two concurrent conspiracies And in fact Kennedy was shot so many times that the bullets hit each other inside and bounced out thus.
Rym: He was okay Uh-huh, so they replaced his brain with an alien brain, but that alien brain caused 9/11 because you see Wtc7 wouldn't have fallen except for the alright.
Rym: I can't go on anymore.
Scott: I couldn't even go on at all.
Scott: I'm surprised you could keep it going like as far as you did.
Scott: I Can't even come up with that shit.
Scott: It's so dumb.
Rym: see I could come up with realistic ones But I really took pains not to in this case.
Scott: yes Today we're gonna talk about Conspiracy theories because well They're just something that pisses us off and a lot of people believe in them, and we think those people are idiots.
Rym: Yep it basically comes down to the fact that a lot of people when something is somewhat unexplained or Not all the facts are known about a situation and for whatever reason they will latch on to this and fill in the unknown quantities with aliens and freemasons.
Rym: It's always aliens and freemasons.
Scott: Yeah, it's the same way that like when there's a hole in science people fill it in with God.
Scott: Well when there's a hole in history people always fill it in with aliens freemasons and shadow governments and illuminatis.
Rym: I mean granted like look at the Kennedy assassination in the US.
Rym: We don't know a hundred percent, and we probably never will unless like there's some magic footage We didn't know or some great confession somewhere that anyone was in a great confession is probably a lie.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I've been a couple of semi Unbelievable confessions in the past yep, but while we won't ever really know There's a big leap from saying there's still something fishy about that Or we don't know why that happened to saying it was a conspiracy.
Scott: Yep, I mean what's more believable a guy named Lee Harvey Oswald acted alone and had a gun and shot the president driving in a car while the president was driving down the road.
Scott: or Some crazy mafia some crazy shadow government.
Scott: Hi again this guy and a bunch in the CIA all got together and made a crazy plot that somehow no one knew about and there's no record of whatsoever and no evidence of anywhere in the world and They killed the president somehow and made it look like this guy did it.
Scott: Which one of those is more likely?
Rym: I believe Occam's razor comes to mind.
Rym: I think the worst one for me lately the one that bothers me.
Scott: well actually 9/11 ones bother me lately the most.
Scott: that one bothers me the most because it's on the internet a lot and a lot of People are believing it lately, which makes it even worse.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I think the worst thing is that loose change.
Rym: I've watched it and it was just stupid and a bunch of it got refuted or Straight-up contradicted by science pretty much right away and all the loose change people did was Alter the video to remove the parts where they got owned
Scott: and there's a great video I remember watching.
Scott: was it a thing of the day?
Scott: it might have been where they're.
Scott: basically there were two Scientists like engineers real scientists with relevant knowledge and the two loose change guys.
Scott: loose change guys said some bullshit And the engineers just like you're wrong.
Scott: science science, and then the loose change guys had like this laugh like No, you're not a conspiracy man.
Scott: You're totally conspiracy.
Scott: You're all in on it And I was like whoa.
Scott: see whoa.
Rym: if a conspiracy got to the point to where that many people Were in on it which basically for loose change includes the entire Scientific community
Scott: of the world except for the one guy
Rym: then it's not a conspiracy anymore If everyone
Scott: in the world
Rym: has to be in on it.
Rym: But you you best reconsider your idea of how the world works because you're probably wrong.
Scott: Yeah, man GeekNights, so we're not on television and not millionaires because the whole world is against us.
Scott: They got a plan.
Scott: they want to keep the nerds down.
Scott: They know we're too good for them didn't all the reason we have to settle for the shitty podcast?
Rym: Didn't all those shitty other webcomic artists in that documentary where penny arcade also kind of participated keep saying stuff like that?
Scott: Maybe they?
Scott: I think they were on the track a little bit But I don't think they came out and said there's a giant conspiracy against webcomics.
Scott: I think they what they generally did is like yeah regular comics looks down on us, and it's not cool.
Rym: I see I got the impression that they were saying more that the media doesn't want out like they try to take away all the Possibility of independent artists getting out there, and then penny.
Scott: okay I see it.
Scott: penny arcade is in newspapers and magazines.
Scott: PvP is all over the place or drew the stick is printing books.
Rym: mega Tokyo is still popular.
Scott: Yeah, mega Tokyo has a manga that's published in the bookstores and sells a lot.
Scott: I don't know why but it I don't see that happening.
Scott: Boasus just got put on comics.com.
Rym: Well, I think my favorite loose change bit recently was that not too long ago it was in the national news, but a tanker full of gas flipped over and set on fire on a bridge and Melted the steel support structure under the road.
Rym: huh now I believe that one of the chorus deepest most important assertions of these loose change crackpots Was that you can't melt steel with a gas fire?
Scott: You can ah huh even though the scientists have been saying that all along, but No, I wonder if these loose guys change guys ever went in their backyard with some gas and some steel and tried to set it on fire.
Rym: you know what.
Rym: my guess is that the people who made loose change don't believe it and Totally know exactly what they're doing and are doing this solely for the publicity cakes.
Rym: Maybe some money?
Rym: I'm sure they're gonna make money off.
Scott: It sounds like a crazy conspiracy thing to me.
Scott: I think they're just ignorant fools.
Scott: see I don't know much simpler explanation.
Rym: I think they're both equally simple because I think about the level of hoax that we could probably pull off.
Rym: We were so inclined and the only reason we don't is that we don't like hoaxes.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is.
Scott: I'm pretty sure they actually believe it because of the way they acted in that one video on that interview on TV.
Rym: yeah, there's a good chance.
Rym: They're just idiots.
Rym: Yeah But the one that bothers me a little more for some reason is the the u.s.
Rym: Didn't go to the moon.
Rym: that was all faked.
Rym: They filmed it in a studio somewhere.
Rym: In fact the last couple of episodes of Penn's radio show.
Rym: They really I didn't bother listening to all of them because he let there's this crazy crackpot that I guess he's friends with.
Rym: talk about the moon conspiracy and there was a semi-legitimate scientist trying to argue against him.
Rym: and I realized at that point that you can't argue with these people because if you put Forth a bad argument.
Rym: They'll shoot you down if you put forth a good argument.
Rym: They'll either deflect by saying oh Well, even if you're right about that you can't explain that.
Rym: And for every one thing you stamp out they've got ten more waiting and you know what it is.
Rym: It's like ground pound down with these people.
Scott: basically the people are irrational and they if they see that there is some sort of Possibility right they need in order for them to change their crazy ideas And believe something that's obvious as opposed to something crazy.
Scott: They need you to remove 100% of the doubt.
Scott: they need you to remove a hundred and ten percent of the doubt, which is impossible.
Scott: There needs to be no doubt whatsoever.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: There's always at least a philosophical doubt and I don't think that that level of doubting if that if the only doubt was Philosophical doubt these people would still believe their crazy conspiracy.
Scott: Yeah They basically believe what they want or some fantasy crazy world that they've imagined in their heads because it makes sense to them Despite because they've completely ignored all evidence in reality and they believe that and they won't change their mind No matter what.
Rym: and yet a lot of people fall for this bullshit.
Scott: Well, I can say that when I was a kid, I believed in stuff too.
Scott: I thought there was aliens and I thought that Sutton up with that Kennedy assassination.
Scott: So
Rym: I'll say I will say this I still think they're aliens in the sense that in
Scott: all Mexicans
Rym: In all of the existence that is out there and all the billions and billions and billions of stars We have observed the odds are that there is some form of what we might consider life Somewhere out there.
Scott: the odds are that there's probably about one maybe two As far as the stars that we can see now.
Rym: It doesn't matter because that's not the thing that these people aren't saying.
Rym: yeah, there's life out there.
Rym: They're saying yeah, the aliens buzz earth and the government knows and they abduct people.
Scott: Yeah, it's like that.
Scott: remember that video over the Phoenix sky that had like this blurry dot moving around.
Rym: How come it's always a blurry dot?
Scott: This is the thing I found a way to remove basically all doubt that all reasonable doubt that there are aliens.
Scott: Find every conspiracy nut Ufologists than what they call themselves, but I don't like using our just.
Rym: I prefer the term.
Scott: I don't like calling anyone an odd gist or an aji if it's not a real science.
Rym: I prefer the term crackpot.
Scott: crackpot is a good one.
Scott: go to Roswell find all those crackpots and you know what?
Scott: Give them.
Scott: just give them HD video cameras.
Scott: They make this all the best by now for less than a thousand dollars And you know what?
Scott: I think it's worth that price to give all these people HD video cameras and that way they'll go home watching their HD footage and They won't see any little fuzzy dots or fuzzy cigar shaped objects floating through the sky.
Scott: They'll see an airplane a bird something a reflective balloon.
Scott: They just some kid let go and fly away into the sky.
Scott: I don't know a false shooting star during the day.
Scott: They'll see what the fuck it is and they'll see that it's not a goddamn green green man and fucking UFOs abducting people with cows and shit.
Rym: now, I will say that when I was a kid, I also was leaning toward believing a lot of this.
Rym: and When I would say a kid I'm talking like first grade second grade, although it may be up to the third fourth Maybe fifth grade.
Rym: funny how I stopped believing in God long before I stopped believing in UFOs and Kennedy conspiracy theories, yes, they're a lot more plausible
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: but anyway I blame at least in terms of my childhood and a lot of the things I believed or at least Accounted for the possibility of.
Rym: I blame unsolved mysteries.
Scott: Yeah, I blame the sci-fi channel mostly and fate magazine because my grandma fate magazine you say my grandma never heard of such a thing.
Rym: Oh my god, you want to have some fun.
Rym: read fate magazine.
Scott: Does it still exist?
Scott: Probably let's search for it fate fate.
Rym: my grandma subscribed to it and it was nothing but Conspiracy theories UFOs and ghosts and say magazine true reports of the strange unknown It was.
Rym: it's so such a. it's so god-awful.
Rym: I can't even really talk about it.
Rym: but when you're like in first grade and you're sitting at your grandma's house while she's telling you ghost stories and you're watching Unsolved mysteries where they talk about the guy who had pictures of aliens but then the fucking government came and stole it and
Scott: One thing I remember seeing on TV that convinced me a lot was this guy had Like this piece of metal like covered in glass.
Scott: It was like a ring of metal with like a glass coating completely coating the whole thing and he's like This is a hundred percent aluminum covered in glass.
Scott: I found this at such crater somewhere on earth You can't make a hundred percent aluminum unless you're in space and I was like as a kid I was like that seals the deal.
Scott: There it is.
Scott: How can you deny it?
Scott: But reality I didn't think that.
Scott: Oh, he's just lying and it's a piece of metal covered in glass and it's not a hundred percent aluminum.
Scott: And he didn't find it in a crater.
Scott: Well, he's never done a proper metallurgical test on it and it's just a thing He made.
Rym: yeah What really bothers me is whenever the media or the press talk to these crackpots.
Rym: It's rare that they will ever directly and openly question them about the obvious.
Rym: They always do the opposite of begging the question.
Rym: They'll let the begged question hang and they'll ask like so how did you come to believe blah blah blah?
Rym: So what do you say to your detractors as opposed to asking the question?
Rym: I would have asked which is so uh, how do you know that that is 100% aluminum?
Rym: Yeah How did you come to this conclusion?
Rym: Did you test it somehow?
Scott: are you lying?
Rym: I guess you don't.
Rym: are you lying?
Scott: because are you lying?
Scott: It's in glass.
Scott: make this up.
Rym: the worst are the people who think that aliens abducted them because there might have been a time where I would have had sympathy for These people that maybe you know, they had some sort of sleep paralysis or something happened.
Rym: That's explainable.
Rym: and then they went online and they saw these other crackpots and someone brainwashed him.
Rym: They made a case.
Rym: but now I'm of the mind that if you think that aliens abducted you I really have no recourse other than to laugh in your face until you leave or cry.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty much it.
Rym: I don't even argue.
Rym: It's like if someone said that their child was an indigo child.
Rym: I wouldn't even try to argue I wouldn't even.
Scott: it's basically hopeless.
Rym: I wouldn't even bother.
Rym: I've lost hope for that person and I would just laugh in their face continuously.
Scott: Yeah, I guess that's what it comes down.
Scott: All right, so let's do a little summary here.
Scott: What is a conspiracy theory?
Rym: All right.
Rym: Well, it's basically the opposite of Occam's razor.
Rym: If if you haven't a belief, well, I guess we should just go through all the different.
Scott: I think what it is is that when there is a happening usually a historical happening and you don't know all the details and you come up with some explanation that While that explanation fits all the facts that you presently know it is not a simple explanation is in fact a crazy explanation that makes lots and lots of assumptions and Basically is completely crazy and unlikely and that I think that's what a conspiracy theory is.
Rym: Yeah you gotta go with Occam's razor here and remember Occam's razor doesn't say something so simple as The simplest solution is always the right one as a lot of people boil it down to.
Rym: it's more the idea that all other things being equal Generally if you have two competing Theories as to how something happened or how something works or how something is put together The idea that requires fewer assumptions is more likely to be correct.
Rym: Yep, and that is true.
Scott: It is absolutely true.
Scott: I mean, let's say like I give you three pieces of evidence, right?
Scott: Let's here.
Scott: I'm holding something ready.
Scott: The thing is so, you know what it can fit in my hand.
Scott: You know that it's red and you know that it's hot, right?
Scott: So, let's see here.
Scott: It could be that I've just got a coal in my hand and it's hot and I'm being burned.
Scott: that's pretty likely.
Scott: It could be that I've got I don't know One of those like hand warmer things and it's colored red, but no it makes sense.
Scott: But no, it's actually the Sun Miniaturized so small that it fits in my hand inside a red capsule.
Scott: that keeps it from incinerating me Generating power for all the whole world and I'm keeping it secret from everybody.
Rym: Yeah, I think that about sums it up.
Rym: yeah, and I've noticed a lot of common threads among these conspiracy theorists is that they all seem to be afraid of something that they call the New World Order.
Rym: or sometimes sometimes they'll tie in the WTO or World Bank.
Rym: a lot of times they advocate the gold standard or they they talk about some sort of Conspiracy involving money back in the day.
Scott: It's like anything.
Scott: that's secret.
Scott: Like if anyone keeps a secret like it's.
Scott: the governments of the world and groups in the world need to keep secrets.
Scott: Sometimes sometimes they don't and they do anyway, but I don't like it.
Scott: They do it anything.
Scott: That's secret.
Scott: Conspiracy theorists will assume that it's the worst craziest possible thing imaginable.
Scott: that's being kept secret.
Scott: Oh some general had a meeting and the whatever he talked about at that meeting was not released.
Scott: Well likely I would say he was probably just talking about some like Iraqi war strategy.
Scott: He doesn't want people to know.
Rym: but no obviously Aliens, obviously they were talking about the new alien craft.
Scott: He's talking to an alien about the alien craft that he was purchasing to use to fight the old ones in Antarctica.
Rym: Who keeps the metric system down?
Rym: we do we do All right.
Scott: So how do you detect a conspiracy theory?
Rym: Well, one of the things that they they seem to do a lot particularly the ones who were a little more adept at avoiding direct questioning Is they'll always kind of deflect whenever you question them directly.
Rym: They will always say things like how should I know?
Rym: I'm not a scientist but still it makes you wonder or yeah, but even if that's correct, you can't prove the blah I think the moon one was the worst on pen show when he was talking and the guys the guys saying all right Here's some proof that we went to the moon.
Rym: When they went to the moon They left the lunar rovers up there and they left a bunch of mirrors up there.
Rym: In fact you from your house can shine lasers at him and get reflections back.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You can have really good aim.
Rym: And his answer was like,
Scott: oh, well,
Rym: uh, we could have put those up there with an unmanned spacecraft And
Scott: no matter how you get a powerful enough telescope you can see footprints up there, you know, yeah
Rym: Oh, we could have sent a robot up there that made the footprints.
Scott: Where's the robot?
Scott: Yeah, it should be up there still then shouldn't it?
Scott: yeah, yeah, huh How come the things in this picture?
Scott: exactly the same as the things on the moon?
Scott: like he made this pattern of footprints in the video.
Scott: and well The pattern of footprints that we look at with the telescope on the moon is the same and they'll always make a lot of assertions.
Rym: bang bang bang like.
Rym: well This is just proven in this and this and this and this and this and they'll put forth all these things like the shotgun of Crazy ideas that all of which Allow for their conspiracy to be true and a lot of them are patently untrue.
Scott: In fact, well, obviously all of them usually I've noticed what is conspiracy theorists nowadays like the clever ones will be like this and this and this and this and this and this and like 75 to 80 percent of those will be true and it's just like.
Scott: but their whole Crazy nut job.
Scott: This relies on the 25% of untrue ones.
Scott: Like if you any of those is shown to be untrue which they are But they believe in those untrue things.
Scott: therefore their craziness holds up and they refuse to believe that the assumptions are untrue.
Scott: But they only argue above those assumptions because they've assumed them.
Scott: They don't even think about going against them.
Rym: There's definitely a shade better for the ones I see where they just throw a bunch of things out there Knowing that it takes a lot more time to debunk their craziness that it does for them to make up new craziness.
Rym: So every time once you've debunked them all they just make up more like.
Rym: and then if you debunk everything They'll just say that you're part of the conspiracy.
Rym: To which point?
Rym: if someone ever said that to me, I would lean in very close and say yes I am and if you speak a word of this to anyone I'm going to have you killed.
Scott: That's a good idea.
Rym: Yeah It's kind of like what I do whenever I argue with Christians because it always comes down to do that to the guys down at.
Rym: I wonder if those guys are still there.
Scott: Oh, I'm pretty sure they're still there every day next time.
Rym: I'm in Chinatown.
Rym: I'm gonna go might have to mess with them.
Scott: I hate those guys so much better.
Rym: Why don't we make a bunch of fake documents and give them to them all hurriedly?
Rym: Like we'll get this briefcase a beat-up briefcase, right?
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: and we'll lock it and we'll make a bunch of documents and We'll put them all on our website right away.
Rym: Like alright, this is what we're gonna see these idiots with.
Rym: We want you all to watch for them to hit the conspiracy sites.
Rym: You know what.
Scott: that's a great idea.
Rym: we might have to do this.
Scott: We got a print of a bunch of fake government documents and then like get the Manila Envelope going on and the sunglasses and just like pass it to one of those guys.
Rym: Yep, or even better I could dress up in a suit and put on some dark glasses and you like run by kind of like and like And you like drop it and be like you say something crazy and then you just run away.
Rym: So they're looking at it and then I walk by with you know with my hand in my ear like all the people do in the movies and looking around like They do cuz they're already pissed off for us making fun of them.
Rym: I doubt they listen.
Scott: I already.
Scott: I also doubt they listen but goddamn that would be a little.
Scott: we're gonna do that.
Rym: I think I think we are because it's so easy to do.
Scott: I think the thing is I don't have time to make up the fake government documents right now.
Scott: I do have time to deliver the fake government documents though.
Scott: so if someone can make up fake government documents that that like.
Scott: if You someone believed the documents were true that they would also believe that like Bush We made a plan with aliens to do 9/11 and they were actually no one on the planes.
Scott: and all those people are secretly Especially by aliens.
Rym: if the documents look like they're for someone else and they're kind of crumpled and old maybe typewriter stuff And especially they have to look like they were shredded it and taped together.
Rym: That's even better.
Rym: or if a bunch of stuff was redacted
Scott: You got to make it look real like it was actually a federal government document and Like if someone wanted to get rid of it and someone else rescued it somehow
Rym: you know what would be best if you took real government documents from the Freedom of Information Act and The head for Jack.
Scott: Yeah You just use no same font and just type different things in them.
Rym: take ones that are real and have redacted content and then Replace the redacted content with bullshit and then give it to them.
Scott: Oh That's pretty hot.
Rym: That's good.
Rym: Oh, that's great.
Rym: But yeah, it's a lot like what I was saying the argument I do with Christians where what?
Rym: eventually I'll just say, you know what?
Rym: All right I'll assume you're right because even if you're right, I would still side with Satan Dun-dun-dun because I've freaked some people out with that argument because there's nothing they can say to that.
Rym: Yeah, there's nothing they can say to me saying fine when your rapture comes I'll be on the other side.
Scott: I'd rather I'd rather serve in hell.
Rym: then Scott if you're going to say I'd rather serve in hell.
Rym: I think you got it wrong.
Scott: I think I do have a wrong.
Scott: what is it?
Rym: It's like I'd rather rule and I would rather rule in hell than serve in heaven I got.
Rym: what do you think that quote is actually from?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: I Think you'll find the answer kind of funny Simpson Seinfeld.
Rym: No way before that.
Scott: Uh, I don't know.
Rym: It's not what you think.
Rym: alright This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.