Rym: It's Tuesday October 9th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm hot and this is GeekNights.
Rym: No, you're not tonight.
Rym: We stopped talking about Team Fortress 2.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, I don't know when you guys are gonna hear this since our internet is coming and going in a bad way.
Scott: I Hate that's all I got to say.
Rym: You know, we were just talking a second ago about this, but it's almost like if your internet is Working it's great.
Rym: If it's not working at all.
Rym: It's fine.
Rym: Cuz alright, it's not working.
Rym: I'm not even gonna try.
Rym: but when it almost works when it kind of works when Every now and then I see a new thing on dig or a page loads It's almost like if you're calling on your car if it's broken and it breaks down.
Rym: crap I call a mechanic or I call a tow truck.
Rym: if the car breaks down, but it's still kind of going you almost feel like I'm almost there.
Rym: I'll make it.
Rym: I'll keep driving I'll keep driving and you're going five miles an hour down the freeway and your car's not gonna make it.
Scott: but let's sort of like Driving with a doughnut.
Scott: It's like you can drive but it sucks.
Scott: I drove almost worse than not driving because at least when you it's like well, it's like driving in traffic You're get you're driving everything works, but you're just not getting at where as fast as you could be.
Scott: But it's out of your control.
Rym: koma across the Long Island Expressway to Rochester in one go on a doughnut.
Rym: Yeah, it sucks, yep I kept also it's like don't take this thing more than 50 miles an hour and I'm going 50 and I'm going 50 and then I'm like 52 53 shake shake 50 Cruise control 49.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yeah, at least there was no danger getting a speeding ticket.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: Though actually I almost got a speeding ticket coming home today.
Scott: So did you.
Rym: I didn't though but I'm coming in to beacon.
Rym: You know, the speed limit goes from 55 to 30 in the span of like an inch.
Rym: Yeah It's also funny because the road goes from crappy to brand new and awesome right at the border of beacon right where the speed limit Drops.
Rym: Yep, and I'm going 35 Speed limits 30. there's a guy in front of me going 35 speed limits 30. a cop comes out of nowhere and pulls him over For going 35.
Rym: Oh The only reason he didn't pull me over because I kind of ran.
Rym: Well, he was pulling that guy over and I know he was gonna try and get me.
Rym: I just kind of turned off a side street and went And got off on another street and came home.
Rym: Nice job, which I've done often.
Rym: Yep I guess I should say that everything I just said was a lie.
Rym: I've never actually run away from a police officer.
Scott: He wasn't actively pulling you over you didn't run.
Scott: You just decided to go on a detour on your way home.
Rym: Hypothetically in the past it's possible that I might have done that when a cop Had his lights on and just couldn't catch me because there was an exit because it was poorly planned He didn't think his clever plan through and he had a speed trap at the top at the front of a hill.
Rym: But behind the hill was an exit.
Rym: But yeah, I may or may not have run away from the cops in that situation.
Scott: The thing is if they may or may not have hit a rest stop If they actually got close enough to you to where there was no, you know No way to say oh, he wasn't actually pulling me over and there was no uncertainty.
Rym: Hypothetically, let's say I was the only car on the road in any direction for as far as anyone can see And let's say hypothetically.
Rym: I was going maybe 90 and let's say Hypothetically.
Rym: were this actually to have happened that?
Rym: He was just sitting there and I watched his radar gun track me.
Rym: his lights turned on while it was pointed at me and then He floored it.
Rym: but let's just say I part may or may not have parked the car in the back of a rest stop and sat in the rest stop acting like I was shopping for 20 minutes while the cop may or may not have Driven
Scott: around
Rym: the rest stop and all the areas by that exit looking for a purple Sunfire.
Rym: But no that didn't happen at all Right, so no internet made it tough to find news, so I'm gonna do a geek bite.
Rym: Oh, man And I think it's a good geek bite particularly because I know a lot of you have probably never played this and while I have Played it in other forms a little bit not in any span or any reasonable amount to actually Really?
Rym: I couldn't have said I played it.
Rym: But uh Mario 2 the real Mario 2 the Mario 2 that Japan looked at and said Americans would not be able to play this Game was never released here except until it was released.
Scott: It was released for the Super Nintendo as part of Mario all-stars, which is sort of a re Skinning of Mario 1 2 3 law, you know mark 1 2 3 both twos And Mario world.
Scott: so that like if you bought a Super Nintendo early on you got Super Mario world You buy the Super Nintendo later on you got Mario all-stars, which is like every Mario game on one.
Rym: I never owned it just because other than you know Mario 2 the real one not doki-doki panic Mario 2 Which I think is actually a lot better game, and I'm really glad Japan did that.
Rym: but I?
Rym: Owned all those games, so I just it never seemed worth it to buy it for the lost levels And I just kind of forgot about him.
Scott: yep And then later on it was released a second time in the US because they came out with a cartridge for the Gameboy color.
Scott: It was a Gameboy color only cartridge.
Scott: you can also play on a GBA or GBA SP, but not on a Gameboy micro or a DS.
Scott: and This cartridge I have it is Super Mario Brothers deluxe And it has Mario 1 this real the real original Mario 2 from Japan and a whole bunch of other miscellaneous garbage that you can do also and The only time the only the third time it has been released the United States of America is just now.
Scott: you can get the original Unmodified real deal for the Virtual Console for it's like yeah, 600 points six dollars.
Rym: now I highly recommend you buy it and my only real reason for that is that While I don't want to buy a lot of Virtual Console games, and they are kind of really expensive There's something to be said for buying the absolute classics because that is the perfect way to play those games.
Rym: nowadays It works a hundred percent like the original.
Rym: There's the graphics are as the best they'll ever be.
Rym: that Mario 1 on the Wii is so crisp looking and just perfect.
Scott: it's the best Mario 1 and I got to say this.
Rym: this is the main gist of what I want to say Mario 2. a Lot of people when they found out that oh Japan didn't think that Americans can handle this game and decided not to release it.
Rym: Well, uh, there's probably more to the story than that because Mario 2 was basically a hacked together piece of shit in Japan.
Scott: It wasn't a piece of shit.
Rym: It was literally there.
Rym: You know people always say oh Nintendo.
Rym: They innovate.
Rym: They're the innovators they.
Rym: every sequel they make is always like leaps and bounds beyond.
Rym: Mario 2 is Identical to Mario 1 except the graphics are a little glitch here.
Scott: They're not glitch here.
Scott: They're the same.
Rym: they look Crappy.
Rym: they look because the way they set it up the way the levels don't look as polished that the Sprites they used and where they use them and the way they set the backgrounds up is not nearly as polished as Mario 1.
Scott: No, it's not it.
Scott: I don't know just something about it.
Rym: feel really hackish.
Rym: It feels like something a kid would have thrown together like what if I made it so I could jump over the flagpole?
Rym: What if I made us there was a blooper here?
Rym: What if I made it so there was a poison mushroom?
Scott: basically what they did is they added the poison mushroom and they came up with the craziest level design they possibly could.
Scott: and The thing is the level design is what isn't polished not the graphic.
Rym: yeah the level the level design.
Rym: I mean I guess I said graphics because they'll use a sprite or a Block in a certain place and it just looks like it was hacked there like it doesn't actually belong there.
Scott: But that's where it goes.
Rym: But if you've never played this game before cuz I had never played it at length until now I got watching me play on my on the Game Boy Color with Super Mario Brothers deluxe.
Scott: I was able to get to I think eight two or eight three.
Rym: I think yeah, two and that took some doing.
Scott: that's like a lot of doing.
Rym: well I started playing it when it came out.
Scott: I've played maybe two back in the high school days like 10th grade.
Rym: Yeah, that game is up.
Rym: I guess frustrating might be the word Difficult.
Rym: it brought back all those emotions.
Scott: not as hard as Silver Surfer.
Rym: No it's not.
Rym: but it feels as difficult for me now as Mario 1 felt when I was a little kid and I played it for the first couple of times.
Rym: I got to relive that whole experience of playing a game like that.
Rym: That's difficult and I can't get past things easily and I have to find secrets.
Scott: Remember that thing of the day where it's the incredibly hard Mario 1 levels and the guy just couldn't beat him.
Rym: This thing does stuff like that.
Scott: It does stuff a lot of times But at the same time it's not even close to that level of difficult.
Rym: But it's that same kind of thing where sometimes like you go to jump and there's just an invisible block Where you were jumping and it knocks you into a pit.
Scott: Yep Sometimes you'll be in the dark and you'll hit a block and a mushroom comes out.
Rym: You're like, is it poison?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I can't tell fuck.
Scott: I'm under cuz.
Scott: the above-ground Regular mushrooms are sort of yellow and red the usual colors and poison mushrooms like green and you could tell.
Scott: but underground Every mushroom is blue and green and you don't know which ones are poison which ones aren't.
Rym: the worst thing is I gotta say Because I never thought about it when I played Mario normally because the mushroom was always like this wonderful thing.
Rym: I loved it.
Rym: now that there's also a bad mushroom.
Rym: Watching that bad mushroom move around was a little bit scary just because it moves so Purposefully and so much faster than any bad guy in that game moves.
Rym: Yeah, bad games are all bad guys are all kind of like I do but it's like oh, it's a turtle walking real slow.
Rym: It's a beetle going real slow.
Rym: It's a pauberos.
Scott: They're fast, but they can only go in certain places, but the bad guys move in a in a pattern, you know Predictable way.
Rym: It's not that menacing?
Rym: No But those poison mushrooms are really menacing like.
Rym: Psychologically those things bother me because they come right at cuz it.
Scott: it's sort of weird in the game.
Scott: They positioned the regular mushrooms to sort of always go away from you to make them hard to get like you have to hit it And then hit a brick to make it bounce so that you know You'll actually go in the direction you want it to go so you can get it.
Scott: But meanwhile the poison mushrooms they come right at you like here I come and you ever think about avoiding a mushroom.
Scott: not easy I mean, it's really hard to avoid a mushroom, especially when you don't have a lot of room to move around in.
Scott: Yeah, and also it's like it's not like it's a goo like if a goomba right it's coming straight at you Right and there's bricks above your head.
Scott: Well, that's fine.
Scott: You'll just jump and step on the goomba.
Scott: Imagine if the bricks are very low above your head and you have to go over The goomba and it's moving faster because if you touch the top of the poison mushroom, it still hurts you.
Scott: That's the menacing part is that there's nothing you can do to fight against it.
Scott: You can't shoot it.
Scott: It's just so purposeful and so scary.
Scott: It's just you know, you can't touch it.
Rym: I think the worst thing about this game is that well worse not in a bad way But in a the most frustrating thing, but I like it.
Rym: I really like the fact that the game is this way because it gives me all sorts of ways to relive the Frustration of my childhood which I think played a big role in making me the man.
Rym: I am today.
Rym: No, I don't think you could understand out there.
Rym: if you didn't play these old Nintendo games You should probably watch some angry video game nerd.
Rym: It really felt like that to play a lot of those games.
Scott: sure did.
Rym: squeezing the controller so hard you almost break it and just.
Rym: But in Mario 1 if you found a secret it was always something awesome.
Scott: if you found a warp zone Imagine every Nintendo game in the United States.
Scott: if you found a secret of any kind it was awesome.
Scott: It's like a secret.
Scott: Yeah secret was synonymous with awesome.
Scott: There was no such thing as a bad.
Scott: so in this Mario telling and it wasn't even like half-life 2 or in half-life 2 you find a secret and it's like Med kits and a gun and some ammo.
Scott: Oh, but there's a zombie in here.
Rym: I'll just shoot the zombie So I'll tell the store I'm walking and you know, I figure alright.
Rym: in Mario 1 There's a warp zone on top of the first dungeon world and I can get on top in this game.
Rym: I know there's something back there.
Rym: Let's go back there and see.
Rym: and hey, there's just more level.
Rym: Hey There's a bunch of pipes to go to a pipe.
Rym: It takes me somewhere else.
Rym: weird what?
Rym: getting another pipe somewhere else?
Rym: even weirder What what?
Rym: and then I just died?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So then later I find I go to another pipe and I find this weird place and then I see a warp zone up ahead like hot diggity.
Rym: damn and I see only one pipe in there and I'm like oh man, it's gonna be one of those like straight to the end of the game warps.
Rym: and No, it was a warp back to world 1. the only thing that made it better.
Rym: and Emily was laughing because I'm standing there and I just I Mario just stops and I'm looking and I see a warp back to world 1. and you know They're really nice to you in this game.
Rym: They really want to make it a pleasant experience.
Rym: Right next to this war back to world 1 is a hole so that if I don't want to take my bad medicine I can just fucking kill myself.
Rym: and and that is what I did And I jumped over a flagpole and I was like, oh man, I jumped over a flagpole and I keep running.
Rym: Oh, man, there's a pipe back here suicide hole.
Rym: warp zone to world 1.
Rym: It got to the point where I'm playing and I'm afraid to go into any pipe because there might be something bad down there.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you don't ever find the real warp zones because you're so afraid that most of the warp zones are fake.
Scott: So, you know, you don't go for the secrets.
Rym: I was just waiting for a warp zone to lie to me.
Scott: That's what I ended up doing.
Scott: a lot of half-life 2. it's like if I play half-life 2 if I have ammo and I have health and I see like a house on the side of The road and I know that in that house are probably a lot of weapons But also a lot of bad guys and I have the option of just not going to that house.
Scott: I just don't go to that house.
Rym: I keep driving, you know hard it is for me to do that.
Rym: I have the FPS instant.
Scott: first time I played half-life 2 I stopped it.
Scott: There's a house and I went to every single room.
Scott: and now when I play half-life 2 because I just beat it the other day.
Scott: Cuz I'm preparing for episode 2 which comes out tomorrow.
Rym: Don't don't do that.
Rym: I haven't even played Bioshock and I own it.
Rym: I haven't even beaten half-life 2.
Scott: Well, I beat half-life 2 again and I be.
Scott: I'm halfway through beating episode 1.
Rym: I spent my whole weekend playing Team Fortress and I became the transcendent spy, right?
Scott: But you know now what I do is I just burn through the game as fast as I can only doing the necessary bits.
Scott: Because why should I waste my time walking around all these rooms to kill zombies when I know there's nothing actually for Bioshock?
Rym: I was playing that way.
Rym: I didn't go after secrets.
Rym: I just kind of played it, you know kind of just straight in a game like that though.
Scott: I would stop for everything.
Rym: Well, I'd stop for anything cool or interesting, but I'm not like worried about finding everything.
Scott: I'm worried about just enjoying the house cuz I was playing System Shock 2.
Scott: I still didn't beat it.
Scott: I barely played it actually but like the little part I did play I had to investigate everything.
Rym: See, I don't know.
Rym: I feel like if I don't have this desire to get like the hundred percent.
Rym: Oh I don't have a desire to get the hundred percent.
Scott: but like the fun of the game is that there's all these bits to poke All over the place and I got a poke off.
Rym: I feel like it's more fun if I just play through the game doing whatever strikes my fancy And strikes my fancy is poking all the pokey bits.
Rym: It depends.
Rym: You didn't poke all those houses.
Scott: I did the first time I played.
Rym: ah, see I'm playing the game the first time and I'm still not poking all the houses.
Scott: Oh Crazy.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Oh, I guess I have to do a news, right?
Scott: I guess you do so, you know We used to go on to this podcast and talk about how PC gaming was dead and it kind of was it kind of still.
Rym: Mostly it's getting better a lot.
Rym: I think a lot of people are.
Scott: basically there's one game for the PC that's sort of bringing it back the orange box and that's it.
Scott: and the orange box is on Xbox 360 and It's gonna be on ps3 later on.
Scott: but tomorrow it's gonna be available for PC and 360.
Scott: In fact on your PC, you could download it right now and you'll probably let you play it at midnight.
Rym: I'm guessing you might remember that feeling from when tribes 2 got not tribes 2.
Rym: I wish tribes 2 came out again Team Fortress 2 and You know, we're sitting there and Scott's like, you know, it's on our computers right now It's just missing a little a couple of bits.
Rym: if we knew those bits we could play right now.
Scott: Basically, they give you.
Scott: they give you all the data files, but they don't give you the exe files.
Rym: Sure I read somewhere else that they just give you an encrypted game and then they decrypt it.
Scott: that it's it's some combination of the two Things.
Scott: that's that's what I've heard.
Scott: But mostly it's the data files.
Scott: that way there's less stress on their servers.
Scott: the day of is what the idea is.
Scott: Yeah, of course totally helpful for you because as soon as the game comes out you can play immediately.
Rym: It's totally mitigated by the fact that even though people have it pre-loaded they sit there refreshing steam Constantly, even though that doesn't do anything for like four hours not helped by the fact that our Internet's not working.
Scott: So I know yeah, but just to prove, you know yet another reason why PC gaming is not doing so well Right the I guess the hit PC game that's coming that some people are excited for that I don't really give a shit about.
Scott: Honestly, is this crisis game and it looks to be another sort of generic far cry kind of FPS, you know in the jungle Military it's a little bit of sci-fi action.
Rym: I'm waiting for portal.
Rym: I couldn't care less about crisis.
Scott: Yeah, but well portals coming out tomorrow cry now coming out November 13, you know hard This is.
Rym: I have this bonanza of gaming and I'm not even touching my GBA anymore.
Scott: I'm not even yeah, but this and this news I gotta tell you.
Scott: Today they released the system requirements and Recommendations for crisis and this is like the hit PC game that people are excited about.
Scott: and I just want to read these system requirements and I cannot say anything else after that other than This is my one more piece of evidence on the pile that despite the orange box PC gaming is still not too well in the United States at least.
Scott: because well if the orange box is all you got that's great.
Scott: But that's one thing and it's not even a PC exclusive.
Scott: All right, this is this is the next best thing on the PC.
Rym: So hit us with it.
Scott: Okay, Windows XP or Vista.
Scott: All right, this is the minimums minimums.
Scott: Okay, I'll do the recommended after I do the minimum processor 2.8 gigahertz or faster for Windows XP 3.2 gigahertz or faster for Vista.
Scott: Whoa.
Rym: Wait a minute like core 2 gigahertz.
Rym: It's all it says.
Scott: Then it says memory one gig or one and a half gigs if you have Vista video card.
Scott: a 256 meg video card would be nice, but it has to be at least a g4 6800 GT or better.
Rym: Wow That's actually pretty high Relatively.
Scott: Yeah Oh supported.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Oh, here's the explanation of the processors an Intel Pentium for 2.8 gigahertz.
Scott: Yeah, that's the minimum.
Scott: see it's weird.
Scott: all the PC Vista.
Scott: you need a Pentium for 3.2.
Rym: all the PC games seem to give speeds relative to the Pentium for and I find that strange because you know because in the Recommendants they give it a core - really?
Rym: Yes, huh?
Scott: So then I'll see video car hard drive 12 gig 12 gigs of space.
Rym: God, I remember when a game that took up 200 megs was like crazy and under requirements.
Scott: It says sound card DirectX non compatible, but you can't play without a sound card.
Scott: again.
Scott: I Recommended Intel core to duo at 2.2 gigahertz.
Rym: All right, I beat that two gigs of RAM.
Scott: I got more than that a geforce 8800 GTS Slash 640 or similar.
Rym: That's not worth it.
Scott: And basically that everyone on the internet is saying well you want to play this game You're gonna have to shell out to buy a new computer.
Rym: I think the problem is Bioshock didn't even run so well on my computer and my computer is pretty badass.
Scott: Yep, and if you really I mean think about these same games if you put them on the 360 It's not because you put the same game on the 360 it runs nicer.
Scott: It's because when you program a game for the 360 you're building it to one unchanging hardware target.
Scott: Right if you make crisis crisis has to work on pretty much all sorts of PCs with all sorts of different setups.
Scott: So you have to.
Scott: you can't really optimize it very much when you compile it.
Rym: And there used to be a lot of problems with games work.
Rym: Like if you had a certain motherboard processor combination, usually an Athlon something something some games would crash.
Scott: Yeah, but for 360. the 360 is a lot less powerful than this kind of machine but all 360s have the same hardware.
Scott: so you can optimize the software for the 360 or for a Wii or for a PA or for any console because all the consoles have the same exact hardware.
Scott: So when you build the software when you compile it you can really optimize it for that Specific machine and a much less powerful machine can do a lot more stuff.
Scott: so that's the reason that one thing that's really hurting PC gaming in the US is because You need a much more powerful machine because they can't optimize the software very much.
Scott: Thus it's more expensive wouldn't?
Scott: and they're putting out the same games for the 360.
Rym: You wouldn't need a much more powerful machine.
Rym: I mean look Team Fortress 2 looks amazing.
Rym: Bioshock isn't?
Rym: I mean it works pretty well, even if you turn the graphics down It still looks really great.
Rym: Half-Life 2 looked amazing and those games require almost nothing of your cuz.
Scott: these people are graphics nuts.
Scott: That's the other thing.
Rym: Yeah, that is the problem.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, yeah I think the real indicator of how well PC gaming is doing is just that you'd think alright A good idea.
Rym: Team Fortress 2 has been this anticipated game forever and you can get into the pre-order.
Rym: So you imagine like all the hardcore PC gamers bought the orange box and are gonna play the Team Fortress 2 beta.
Rym: There aren't that many Team Fortress 2 servers and there aren't that many people playing the game.
Rym: It's kind of scary.
Scott: Yeah, it's only like they're only thousands of players and that's it thousands.
Rym: Yeah, anyway sells more than that.
Scott: Yeah, I mean back in the day Counter-thousands of players at a time, but I mean count and then counter-strike.
Scott: God Counter-strike, we're talking tens of thousands or hundreds of thousands.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: We'll see what happens after tomorrow, you know and tomorrow and tomorrow Creeps in this petty pace from day to day.
Rym: Yep orange box.
Scott: As you're listening to this the orange box is probably available.
Scott: Why don't you have it?
Scott: buy it online?
Scott: Don't buy the box in the store and those you have dial-up then buy the box in the store.
Rym: if you have dial-up I don't know what to tell you.
Rym: Yeah Things of the day.
Rym: I gotta talk about it.
Rym: You haven't seen it.
Rym: Go watch it.
Rym: Meet the demo.
Rym: man is out.
Rym: It's are really funny.
Scott: I'm against Rym doing this thing of the day because it's something everyone's probably already seen.
Rym: who cares You know, I don't think everyone has and - there's nothing else on the internet funny.
Scott: Well, I think the problem is you have internet connection to find out.
Rym: yeah, that is also the problem because I was gonna look for something else but YouTube not going so well and wall Scott showed me Ignis solace and That's the first machinima for you know, Team Fortress 2 and it started out really cool.
Rym: It went nowhere and was really disappointing.
Rym: Nah, I was sad.
Rym: Okay, it was.
Rym: it could have been so great.
Scott: There's no father Frank's best.
Rym: Uh you know Dave and Joel talked about Bubblegum crisis and how they realized suddenly that while they thought they liked it in an ironic sense No, they like it in a real sense.
Rym: when it comes to father Frank's best I do not like it in a non-ironic sense.
Rym: It is not funny And only noteworthy because it was like the first machinima ever.
Scott: The father Frank's best trailer is on YouTube.
Rym: Really wonder if it's the original deal.
Scott: I'm trying to find the real thing, you know, I've got it.
Rym: I've got a hard drive with my original quake to install.
Rym: that's been passed from peace here.
Scott: Find a website that has it.
Scott: Oh good Zara Thustra Studios.
Rym: Yes, that's it.
Rym: All right, I'll warn you all.
Rym: Maybe I should just make father Frank's best my thing.
Scott: That's what I was saying.
Scott: You should do.
Rym: I think I've already done that though.
Scott: Well, let me find out the Internet's kind of working all right.
Rym: Regardless if you can find a video of it or just get a hold of quake - and know how to install a mod for quake - which I'll warn you is not so trivial.
Rym: then you can watch father Frank's best which is among the first machinima and you know what?
Scott: It's That's the first FPS machinima.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I Still can't think of any before that that I knew of.
Scott: No, me either.
Rym: granted some people made some scary things in Sierra's the realm But I don't know if that was machinima or just cyber sex.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what counts.
Scott: Okay, check this out.
Scott: We always rag on halo, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: I think the analogy for halo is very simply that the Renaissance This is pretty cool.
Scott: when he came up with this the other day The Renaissance in Italy was a great thing.
Rym: it was like the world had gone through this dark age and people had forgotten a lot of things.
Rym: and then People started rediscovering this joy this wealth of knowledge and information and art and it was like it was Rome and Greece and all this Amazingness.
Scott: and there's a dark age.
Scott: and then people remembered what the good stuff They used to have before the Dark Age and they brought it back this revival.
Rym: So Renaissance first-person shooters like halo are effectively the Renaissance of first-person shooters Except that it's like if the Renaissance happened like say in Britain But Rome was still there and they just like forgot it about it.
Rym: We had this gold like FPS is made these leaps and bounds and were amazing and then they just kind of fell off the radar for a long time.
Rym: and there were these experiences that us old FPS errs had.
Rym: and then you see that new gamers who have never played these old FPS's and don't realize the wealth of the Roman Empire that collapsed around them, even though it didn't really collapse It just kind of disappeared.
Scott: It's still there.
Scott: We still have all the tablets We're still in Rome and we're watching your Renaissance build itself up and we're still drinking until we vomit then drinking again.
Rym: Oh, how quaint.
Rym: they've discovered two-dimensional art yet again.
Rym: Perhaps soon they will find music.
Rym: Yep but Games like halo while the I mean They're kind of like a rebirth of these old games and they didn't really do anything new and I don't think they're really better Than a lot of much older FPS's.
Rym: but at the same time all these kids play these games like halo and While they don't know the culture of the old FPS's they never went through all the things we run through and kind of had the collective society of FPS thing that we had.
Rym: I Notice in Scott's video that he's gonna talk about in a second prove
Scott: that
Rym: Some of these things much like arts in the Renaissance versus art in the ancient Greco-Roman world are Universal and even if they're destroyed humans tend to recreate the same great things over and over again and the cycle repeats and this video is just.
Rym: It is the Renaissance of everything.
Rym: that is great about FPS's and the fact that these kids are experiencing these things Without knowing just completely on their own in a vacuum Validates my childhood.
Scott: Yeah, I think is back in the day.
Scott: You'd play yourself a counter-strike, right?
Scott: It'll be.
Scott: some amazing thing would happen.
Rym: No one would believe you either but there'd be legends about it.
Scott: Like someone would throw a grenade and it would bounce some guy into a roof But he wouldn't die to have like a health left.
Scott: and then he'd like he take out his deagle Like turn around real quick and shoot randomly and get a headshot and the team would win.
Rym: Like the one time when you're playing action quake 2 and it's 8 on 8 and your whole team dies and it's you versus the Whole enemy team and then something happens and somehow you suddenly you're breathing heavily.
Rym: They're all dead You've won and everyone is typing WTF.
Scott: Yep You know a lot of when you play an FPS crazy shit likes to happen.
Scott: That's just because the way the games work stuff goes on and people go.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: And Team fortress you could tell the people who designed it were trying Purposefully to capture that essence of FPSing where crazy stuff happens by making a game Where the game is the crazy stuff happening, but in halo like every other FPS Crazy stuff still happens.
Scott: and this is a video of something particularly crazy happening in halo involving a guy a grenade and some jet of air.
Scott: and They are really a really good video of it.
Rym: I must say it it is it's perfect.
Scott: It's kind of mean like never having played this game, but having played other FPS is I watch it and I go ah Just like that video where they were shooting vehicles into the sky.
Scott: Yeah, there was that other.
Scott: No, I think it was a thing that a long time ago I think
Rym: it was
Scott: say they would you they had these shields in halo and I they basically they put a vehicle on the shield disable the shield then enable the shield and it would make the vehicle fly into the sky and was all crazy.
Rym: and That is the same thing kind of that we used to do back in Counter-strike.
Rym: that is that APC math.
Scott: that is the same essence that is being captured in this video and that team fortress 2 tries to Recreate intentionally and that is why FPS is are awesome.
Scott: Especially multiplayer FPS is yes.
Rym: So for a lot of you say Oh Rym and Scott you're so down on modern FPS is it's more that We're living in Rome.
Rym: So we have no desire to go to you know, piss-filled Renaissance to bring back Rome where we've.
Scott: we're there.
Rym: We've been there for a long time We're not going anywhere and we really want a lot of you to come join us.
Scott: because yeah Why are you hanging out trying to recreate what we already have at our offering?
Rym: But at the same time I can't.
Rym: I don't feel bad about games like halo because there are so many kids who never played these Old games and a lot of F computer FPS is are kind of hard to play and they're very inaccessible.
Scott: Halo is very accessible.
Scott: these kids get a hundred million dollars excess.
Rym: These kids get those same experiences of like a LAN party But instead of having to go to a LAN party which back in the day was quite a feat They just bring their Xbox to a friend's house and plug them in with a special cable.
Scott: and it's okay because all the people in Like Europe and other places in Korea where they don't have consoles so much or the you know Consoles are looked down upon or the release.
Scott: I feel like my my crap.
Rym: my video game soul when I die is going to leave my body independent of the rest of me and go to South Korea and just possess some kid.
Scott: Yeah Cuz it.
Scott: the mostly Northern Europe where they still have like the giant many thousand computer LAN parties or all they play is like modern FPS man, we should talk about LAN parties cuz they don't happen like they used to nope.
Scott: Anyway, yeah.
Rym: so today against my Argument I think there's a lot to say and thus we can be done with it.
Rym: We can close this chapter in our lives.
Scott: Rym wants to talk yet again about Team Fortress 2.
Rym: well, we've been able to play it a bunch now and Things are starting to solidify.
Scott: I'm starting to see exact and the final version comes out tomorrow.
Scott: So I can't assume that the version we're playing is much different from the final version.
Rym: Yeah, nothing's gonna change.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, maybe we did an episode about Team Fortress like through the years Talked about Team Fortress 2.
Rym: a few times yeah, but always like as an aside or a tangent.
Rym: and uh, I'm kind of worried about the longevity of the game.
Rym: still and I think my main reason for that is that Anytime skilled players play against skilled players.
Rym: The game is always a stalemate.
Rym: always Anytime two teams are equal are competent in any like any level of competence the game just evolves to a perfect stalemate.
Scott: I've noticed that pretty much if the other team does something smart Unless a whole bunch of people on my team are smart more, you know unless I have more smart people on my team than they have on their team, there's no way that I can get through their defense or Stop their offense.
Scott: it is at the same time if I people on my team are doing smart stuff and the other team is doing Stuff that's not so smart.
Scott: I can't help but just capture the intelligence or capture the points or just dominate them.
Rym: now that used to happen in old FPS.
Rym: I mean, I can't say that like if if there were five planners like me and four friends from a clan We're on a team in a pub server somewhere in weapons factory that we wouldn't just dominate the ever-living Crap out of the other team because that that kind of thing happens.
Rym: but in This game and Team Fortress 2 because the FPS skill cap is so low and I'm gonna say that again because while we said Oh, I feel like it's low.
Rym: I There's no way to argue against it at this point It takes very little FPS skill to play anything but the sniper in Team Fortress 2 but surprisingly So few people have the skill.
Scott: It's like it's pretty much a Boolean.
Scott: It's either.
Scott: it's not like quake where you could be like bad decent better awesome amazing super amazing.
Scott: God fatality.
Rym: if you're an engineer you either are a Optimal or near-optimal engineer or you are a useless engineer pretty much.
Scott: It's like there's a way to engineer Perfectly, it's like if you know the map and you know how to use the engineer you and your team doesn't have like an excess of engineers.
Rym: you're usually your team's just smart at all.
Rym: like 2-4 is an example.
Rym: if say if you're playing like a six on six the absolute perfect defense There are two different places to put the century in the flag room and you kind of alternate so they can't predict every now And then you might move it and you have a pyro running around down there and between the engineer and the pyro Unless the entire enemy team attacks at once and no one comes to defend you which they would.
Rym: if your team's smart You have a perfect defense.
Rym: It's optimal.
Rym: There's nothing better.
Scott: Yeah, it's like the most skilled scout in the universe could not get through.
Scott: What's he gonna do?
Scott: the most skilled soldier in the universe could not get through.
Scott: he's gonna get set on fire.
Scott: This is just the way the map is and as long as you're smart It doesn't think they really need to come in with something big and In full force to get through.
Scott: and if in order to get through with something that big the rest of your team would have to Be completely incompetent?
Scott: at the same time if you make with an awesome offense like let's say you come in with like You know you got two medics you got a heavy you got smart soldiers You got some scouts that know how to move.
Scott: you know you got some snipers backing you up from far away.
Scott: You can get across and into the enemy intelligence room You know plus like one or two spies that know what's going on.
Scott: You'll get through every time.
Scott: I mean as a scout alone Nine times out of ten I can get to the enemy intelligence room.
Scott: granted
Rym: The reason we were able to do that is because no one in this fucking game playing it except the planners from other old FPS is like this Understands probably one of the most important tactical I guess innovations in the history of warfare and that is called defense in depth.
Rym: You don't put four centuries in the goddamn flag room.
Rym: you have a defensive perimeter and then an internal perimeter.
Rym: Someone shouldn't be able to just get right to the flag room.
Rym: There is a fight their way to the flag room.
Rym: that way by the time they get to the flag room They're already weak, and you finish them off.
Scott: Yeah There is a spot in the map because there's only two ways to get.
Scott: there's only two entrances and exits to the basement.
Scott: One of them is in the is in the the open-air area with the stairs and the wooden barn and the other place is Through like the main lobby of where you know all the guys usually typically spawn right right up at the front of the.
Scott: you know Right behind the battlements right.
Scott: and is that there's the spiral ramp.
Scott: You can position a turret so that it can shoot at people going down the spiral ramp and going to the barn.
Scott: so if you put that there and you have one in the intelligence room and then you have Some people in the waterworks, maybe downstairs.
Rym: No one can get through.
Scott: what is it?
Scott: There's nothing they can do.
Rym: and what it basically breaks down to is that if everyone plays their classes well And Wells not I guess optimally because games like this all games break down when players all play optimally.
Rym: That's why we always complain about a lot of German board games like.
Rym: they're really fun.
Rym: But once you know how to play optimally and everyone else playing knows how to play optimally the game's not fun because like settlers Of Catan, you don't know how the game works.
Scott: You just learned it.
Scott: You're new to games like this.
Scott: You know you start playing.
Scott: it's crazy fun.
Scott: You're trading you're wheeling and dealing you're building your so it rolls seven and then everyone bribes.
Rym: I'm like, please don't put it on me I'll give you sheep.
Scott: Yep, then Once you realize how to play you learn everything.
Scott: you're playing with three other people who know as much as you do.
Scott: They're masters of the game.
Scott: There's no decisions.
Scott: It's not fun.
Scott: It comes down to who rolls the dice now in.
Rym: what the dice say in more complex FPS is now again I'm not gonna say that those old complex team fortress solid games were better because that is not a road I want to go down.
Rym: I'm not even gonna pretend those games were better in any objective sense Yeah, but what they were?
Scott: in many ways they were far worse.
Rym: Yes, God, but what they were is There was a much larger skill component of players and tactics mattered a lot but Individual skill mattered.
Rym: you could not play the engineer Optimally in those games.
Scott: you could not play the optimal recon like there was a theoretical Like you knew the theoretical limits of what could be done with say the engineer you do what he was capable of humans I actually execute that with your mouse and keyboard was so incredibly difficult.
Rym: like the number of people who played near optimally in games like that were few and far between and those people were the Fatalities of their day.
Rym: Those people were gods among FPS men.
Scott: It's like reflexes and aiming and Button pushing and twitching and and you know aim all that sort of stuff mattered a lot.
Scott: so even if you pick the right class you picked medic and you knew exactly how to use a medic for the best way possible and You try to do that with all your might.
Scott: you said we need a medic.
Scott: our team needs a medic.
Scott: I'm gonna be that medic.
Scott: the medic needs to heal that guy and needs to do this and needs to do that.
Scott: You know everything that needs to be done But it's incredibly difficult to actually execute that and if you don't do it just right the other team is.
Scott: there's gonna be a weakness and you're gonna get hit in team fortress 2. if You have any level of skill at all, you know, you can aim in the general direction of the bad guys.
Scott: You know how to detect a spy.
Scott: you have basic skills.
Scott: you read the little hints.
Scott: the game tells you You don't need such a high level of skill.
Scott: You just pick the medic.
Scott: you know what to do with the medic.
Scott: you go you do it and that's the best that could be done.
Scott: and there isn't really gonna be a weakness and Someone else being slightly better than you isn't gonna make a difference unless they figure out what needs to be done.
Rym: You know, there are pros and cons to this.
Rym: I mean it does make the game more team based and more tactics strategy based and a lot less.
Rym: you can't lone wolf it.
Rym: Well, you can because most people aren't good at this game yet.
Scott: But yeah, if I'm on a server full of dumb people I can just take the scout and win take the soldier and win.
Rym: Yeah, I'm really.
Rym: Mostly if one of us joins the server Unless like there's other good people playing which this is about a 50/50 shot.
Rym: if there aren't other good people on the server I'll literally just pick a team and just look at him like just decide All right I'm gonna win the game right now and I'll just go over and capture three times or I'll just go get the point.
Scott: Pretty much when I join a game the game is either in a situation.
Scott: I join a random team pretty much every time.
Scott: I always be in a situation Where I could just like capture capture capture on my own and just destroy the other team single-handedly or with a little bit of help Or it'll be in a situation where my team is so dumb that no matter what I do is completely hopeless And there's nothing I can.
Scott: I once
Rym: got into a base that was like almost Optimally defended and they're actually pretty good about spies but I got in and I bit by bit kept getting in and inching the intelligence out and Finally, I got the intelligence to the top of the battlements and they were sitting there and I was yelling into the microphone And typing everyone go scout.
Rym: We only need one cap to win.
Rym: It's sitting in the battlement.
Rym: if you all just run we win Automatically, there's nothing they can do to stop us.
Rym: if we're all scouts just go and no one did it and the intelligence went back To their base.
Rym: Yep, and it's just that.
Rym: see that's the thing A lot of people don't see the the final fatal flaw of Team Fortress and I don't want I'm trying not to sound like oh we're so good because we're not.
Rym: the thing is a lot of people are Just not.
Rym: they're not experienced with games like this So they're not super good at it yet.
Rym: But I think as time goes on a lot of players are going to play their classes optimally because it's not hard to do.
Rym: I think the sniper requires the most FPS skill of any.
Scott: Yeah, the sniper you actually have to aim and you can miss.
Rym: and sadly I have met one Optimal sniper in the course of my play.
Rym: I met a couple.
Scott: I didn't actually meet them But basically I was trying to scout which is the smallest and fastest guy So supposedly also the hardest to hit and I maneuvered all over the place as much as I could Attempting to cross the field and I knew there was a sniper there.
Scott: I knew he was there and I was trying to avoid him to the best of my ability and he shot me dead every time.
Rym: Now I'd always avoided playing sniper in this partly because in all the other games like this It was really hard to be the sniper like really hard and I was never good at it.
Scott: I've been also sort of boring because I like to move around the map.
Scott: I like to make stuff happen.
Scott: I like to see what's going on.
Scott: See I like it a sniper.
Scott: you tend to stay in one spot and you tend to do a lot of waiting for people to Come by see.
Rym: my role was always in the in.
Rym: the play was in any out.
Rym: like previous games I was always kind of the defensive coordinator guy like I'd be defensive and I would constantly just be reporting to the team on what the defensive situation is and what's going on and be like enemy nurse spotted at the spiral staircase enemy spy disguised as demo man spotted at the blah and just you know on top of Defense and all that.
Rym: and I like being the defensive dude.
Rym: Mm-hmm I also like, you know when you're about to cap suddenly all the defense goes offense to make sure you finish the cap And then you all go back to defense and all that stuff.
Rym: But in this game, it's really kind of boring.
Rym: I've so many games.
Rym: I'll set up my century and No one can cap and even though my team's not defending at all because my team's full of idiots People just keep coming down and dying on that century and spies keep coming down and I guess they get surprised when I shoot them.
Rym: and oh actually Probably the best moment in Team Fortress 2 happened to me not too long ago.
Rym: I was playing on a server full of super nubs and it was like four on four.
Rym: So it's just like it's a fun easygoing game.
Rym: I figure I'll just go defense and kind of practice and figure out where the optimal century spots are and I'll just let the teams Do whatever they want.
Rym: I don't care if we win But I'm not gonna let anyone cap and I set up my century and then I get bored with that.
Rym: So I go pyro and I'm sitting in the flag room and someone decides to go engineer and he builds a century in a stupid spot and I'm like Build it where I'm standing instead pointed direction.
Rym: I'm facing he's like why and I explained he's like, oh, okay He obviously was a nub, but he was respectful of his elder.
Rym: So he sets it up and we're sitting there and I run away to do something and I change classes and I come back and I Change classes and I come back again as a pyro and he doesn't shoot at me when I walk in the room.
Rym: So I just kind of walk over to the century gun and stand in front of it and he just kind of looks at me.
Rym: So I walk over to him and I say you dumbass you should have shot me.
Rym: and he's like what?
Rym: why?
Rym: and I was like I might have been a spy.
Rym: and he's like I Didn't think about that.
Rym: and I'm like you should always shoot Anyone who ever walks into this room?
Rym: Even if I've been a pyro for an hour and I've walked into this room every five minutes You should shoot every pyro that walks into the room no matter what.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You should if you're an engineer Even if some guy what spawns at the same time you spawn and he walks out of the the Spawning room the supply room the same time as you walk out of the supply room and he doesn't leave your sight at all.
Scott: You see your cat your eye on him the whole time.
Scott: if you build a sentry and then he walks near it shoot him.
Scott: Ammo is free.
Scott: spies killing your turrets are not free.
Rym: But uh, and while I'm saying this he says to me cuz in the typing team chat, that's crap you're just being paranoid.
Rym: That's a really stupid way to.
Rym: and while he's typing that at me He's typed a couple lines.
Scott: a medic
Rym: walks up behind him A medic on our team and I'm a pyro so I just flamethrower yep, and the guy catches on fire and starts to run away and he turns around and sees the spy fall over on fire and Then he says, okay, I'll shoot anyone who walks in.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: And it was just.
Rym: it was so perfect.
Rym: I couldn't have paid someone enough money to be a spy and walk in at that moment.
Scott: Nope, but they did.
Rym: but I gotta say something.
Rym: I'm a really good spy.
Rym: like spying is really fun and I like doing it.
Scott: Yeah, I was an okay spy.
Scott: like other spy like I can't be fooled by a spy.
Scott: I've never been fooled by a spy.
Scott: everyone's spies have killed me like I'm walking down a hallway.
Scott: They come up behind me cloaked and then they stabbed me.
Scott: They didn't fool me.
Scott: They just got me.
Scott: There's a difference between fooling and getting.
Scott: you know fooling would be.
Scott: I'm standing there A soldier on my team is standing there.
Scott: then he destroys my turret and sabs me.
Scott: that's fooling me, right?
Scott: Also, you know if I sometimes they don't fool me I see them I start shooting them, but then they kill me first.
Scott: That's not fooling me.
Rym: That's getting me usually because you have low health already from a previous encounter something like that, but they've never fooled me.
Scott: I've never said.
Scott: Oh, that's not a spy.
Scott: and then it is.
Rym: I once spent an entire game Basically guarding the enemy intelligence quote-unquote as an enemy pyro and I just sat in their flag room and people would walk in and look and be like Oh someone's defending it and walk away.
Rym: and I had an engineer there with a century and I never destroyed a century.
Rym: I just sat there and sat there and every time the team was like it's time to cap I would just kind of do something to make sure they capped and then I'd come back as no one ever suspected me.
Scott: Yeah, what seems like when I play a spy like I was having a little bit trouble at first Cuz what I was doing us.
Scott: I was cloaking going across to their base then Disguising.
Scott: then Rym said, you know, you can disguise then cloak and I was like, oh, yeah.
Rym: Oh, that's big.
Scott: Yeah, that helped me out a lot.
Rym: The only the inside I had it took till over the scene wasn't any amount of skill.
Scott: It was knowledge that helped me out.
Scott: Yeah, I was doing everything right.
Scott: I can manipulate the spy to do everything He can do.
Scott: it was just the knowing once I know I'm perfect.
Rym: The only thing I did and I knew this but it took me a while to force myself to do it was when I'm spying Once I have revealed myself or been caught like once they're like people like realize and start shooting at me.
Rym: I always tended to stand my ground and try to kill a couple more people and then die.
Rym: That's what I do - what I realized is if I just cloak and run away They won't find me.
Rym: and now I'm still in their base.
Scott: Yeah, that's the thing is like I use the cloak as a device to get across the open battlefield.
Scott: You know cuz on the open battlefield, right even if I'm disguised as the enemy team They see someone running out of our base and into there.
Rym: Well, no more importantly they should be shooting everyone.
Rym: they see always spies Cannot work in this game unless people don't know how to play Yep.
Scott: So the only thing I can do to get from my battlefield to from my base to their base where it disguised as effective in Their base at least effective against stupid people is by cloaking.
Scott: So I'd use the cloak to cross from one base to the other but from then on I would rely on the disguise and I Wouldn't cloak again.
Scott: And what I realized I got to do is I gotta like be disguised stab someone in the back and cloak.
Scott: That's what I got to do.
Scott: Yep, and I just know I just gotta remember to do it.
Scott: It's not that I can't do it.
Scott: It's it's the it's the knowing the knowledge.
Rym: I Guess it's just.
Rym: I really like the game and everything's great about it But more and more like the skill is capping out.
Scott: I think I imagine if it was like 10 on 10 and 10 amazing players for his 10 amazing players They were all coordinated.
Scott: I think it'd be a stalemate forever.
Scott: And you know happens if there's a stalemate even the uncoordinated games are stalemate.
Rym: All right, I gotta say this too.
Rym: when we first started playing this I the sudden death.
Rym: I thought it was a cool idea.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the problem with a lot of these games in the past was that they would go on forever.
Scott: It's like you'd play and play and play for hours and hours and hours.
Scott: No, we capture the flag Or no one would get a lead and nobody read.
Scott: thing is wetting wouldn't go anywhere.
Rym: So a lot of the games would set it where there'd be like a one or two hour Usually a one hour time limit on a mat and it would be if no one won by the end Whoever had the most points won.
Rym: and usually you got like I think weapons factory It was.
Rym: you got ten points per player per flag cap.
Rym: So if you had ten players a flag cover with a hundred points and each player got an additional point every time they killed an Enemy so theoretically killing
Scott: games or it's like you get like a hundred points for capturing the flag and like one point for touching The flag.
Rym: Yeah, just anything to break up little ties and just whoever has the most point of the end wins.
Rym: But sudden death could have been cool except one sudden death has a time limit.
Rym: Yeah, I don't like and to sudden death is just game theory ruined sudden death And I tried in three separate games to try to explain this concept of people But no one got it.
Scott: in any sudden death situation and there's a sudden death is where okay Whoever gets the next point wins and no one can respawn.
Scott: There's no respawning.
Scott: So if you die, you're dead like counter-strike now.
Rym: in that case Game theory wise you have no option but to camp and defend and never go on the offensive.
Scott: yeah, get it.
Scott: hopefully you switch to engineers and medics and heavies and those sorts of things and Snipers possibly maybe even spies and you just sit there and wait for the enemy to come to you and die on your ultimate Defense
Rym: because
Scott: soon as enough of them die You can all go over on the offense and beat the one or two guys left in easily.
Rym: because in this game defense is king generally and a 100% defense cannot be broken by 100% offense no matter what is even with moderately skilled players.
Scott: So think of this unless your defense is all scouts.
Rym: It's kind of like a Team Fortress equivalent of Pascal's Wager.
Rym: Forget the fact that Pascal's Wager was completely fallacious is completely fallacious.
Rym: Yes, well is and was it's complete garbage and it's been disproven like a thousand different ways.
Rym: But anyway, so the matrix of What happens.
Rym: let's say I camp my team camps and the enemy team camps stalemate Alright stalemate.
Rym: everyone loses.
Rym: the game tries to make a point like yes You're all losers, but you know what?
Rym: I tied the other team even though I lost.
Scott: I'd rather everyone be losers than my team be losers and the other team be winners.
Rym: Yes Because the net gain or the net law the net loss is less the net gain is more.
Rym: You're better off being the same as your enemy.
Scott: if that was like a tournament at the CPL for a cash prize or something That wouldn't be too bad.
Scott: If we were all losers I'd rather have it that way than the other guys get the prize and I don't.
Rym: now.
Rym: it's very Best-case scenario you win.
Rym: worst-case scenario you tie.
Scott: now Let's why why would you ever go on office?
Rym: because office now you have a much less chance of winning Especially if they camp.
Rym: it's the prisoners dilemma there.
Rym: if you now your matrix is best-case scenario We win.
Rym: worst-case scenario.
Rym: It's not we tie it's we lose.
Scott: So why would you do that?
Scott: You've increased the chance even if you're all gods of Team Fortress 2.
Scott: The only way that full-on offense is gonna work is if at least part of the other team is stupid and significant part of the other team.
Rym: as a result if you have intelligent players leading teams The prisoners dilemma tragedy the comments all those fun things.
Rym: All they really mean is smart players will never attack another thing.
Scott: if you're doing capture the flag, right and Someone else like your team has one flag capture, right?
Scott: Let's say I capture the intelligence now, it's one nothing.
Scott: Why should we defend anymore?
Scott: There's no reason to defend.
Rym: Yes I can't explain this to people either.
Rym: so many games go by where you have to get three caps to win and We've got two caps and the enemy team has none.
Rym: or even if you're up by one If your team just goes a hundred percent offense, the odds are the enemy team is not also going to go a hundred percent defense.
Rym: Even if they start capping you're gonna cap faster As long as you're using scouts to capture the Intel.
Rym: or or You leave one engineer behind or at most one engineer in one pyro because the one engineer staying behind Prevents the empty net goal, but at the same time who cares if they cap as long as you can't you?
Scott: It's like it's like when you're playing ice hockey, you know, and you take the goalie out because you need one more goal.
Scott: So you take the goalie out and you have six guys on the ice trying to score and you.
Scott: so it mostly works.
Scott: It's the reason they do that you take down your defense.
Scott: because why if you need three caps to win, right?
Scott: And it takes let's say a minute to capture the flag right at going with a scout.
Scott: You have one cap and they have zero.
Scott: Okay, fuck our defense full offense.
Scott: We can even if we let them capture the flag.
Scott: We'd let them just get it.
Scott: No defense whatsoever.
Rym: Plus they're not just gonna get it because yet you have the one.
Rym: they have to get back into their base Where your guys are fucking them up anyway.
Scott: Yep, so They get two caps in the same time.
Scott: It takes you to get two caps and you win three to two.
Scott: you in.
Rym: now see In in FPS.
Rym: is that require a lot more pure FPS skill Which again not good or bad because they definitely tried to limit the amount of raw Kind of silly FPS skill this game required.
Rym: you end up with situations like that Instead of situations of the people who are better at the game tend to do better.
Scott: you do end up see but that's his thing.
Scott: Let's say play the same scenario out, but only skill matters, right?
Scott: Okay, we're up by one.
Scott: Let's go on full offense.
Scott: Okay Well, we would have gotten two caps and they would have gotten two caps meaning a final score of three to two.
Scott: but Joe on our team wasn't as good at you know, Shooting his rocket and aiming it as Mike on their team and Joe died Even though Joe had the better knowledge and strategy and he was doing everything right.
Scott: He just he was just slower.
Rym: or Baldwin on the enemy team was a Preter naturally amazing optimal scout and he just kept a bunch of times.
Rym: cuz he's so awesome.
Scott: Yeah He learned to like amazing tricks had like cap so quickly and destroy engineers on his own with his skill Which things that normally couldn't be done.
Scott: He achieved feats of amazingness.
Scott: Yep, and that's the thing is there's no feats of amazingness in Team Fortress 2.
Scott: It's your class has a limit.
Scott: That's the best it can do.
Scott: Cannot take it any higher.
Scott: The only time you will accomplish something amazing is when the other team is incompetent or if your team Works together in such an amazing way, but even then that will only work if the other team is a cop.
Rym: I mean one time I was playing a weapons factory and I saw like.
Rym: I went in on a suicide mission to take out a bunch of sentries and I somehow got the flag and I kept and The whole server was like what the fuck.
Rym: and it wasn't skill.
Rym: It was mostly like this crazy fluke where I just happened to get out.
Rym: I can't pretend that I was that good.
Rym: it was just like this crazy fluke of a thing and Like everyone's like wow.
Rym: Damn one in a million.
Rym: and in Team Fortress 2 things like that don't happen Nope ever.
Rym: It's not like one in a million.
Rym: It's like one in.
Scott: they designed the game so well that it's too Perfect.
Scott: There's no Like.
Scott: there's no loopholes.
Scott: There's no there's no nothing.
Scott: It's exactly as they wanted it.
Rym: They've been making little game fixes like they made the pyro stronger.
Scott: Yeah, the pyro is kind of useless because like you'd set people on fire But then they'd live long enough that so where they kill still kill the pyro.
Scott: so they made his flamethrower more powerful.
Scott: So now I think it disintegrates.
Rym: be I think in a recent update They made the Rockets from the marine a little bit more damaging.
Rym: I'm not sure exactly if they did or not, but I think that yeah, that was always the one thing I think they need to.
Scott: that sort of annoying in the game is The pushback from getting hit by the turrets.
Scott: like but I'm a scout.
Scott: Sometimes someone will put their turret in a narrow hallway, right?
Scott: And all I want to do is run through the hallway perpendicular to the turret real fast.
Scott: But what happens is I I'm willing to take the damage.
Rym: No Scott.
Rym: The thing is I can I can answer the Pushes me back.
Rym: It pushes you.
Rym: they did that on purpose.
Scott: I know it's it's no.
Rym: very specifically I agree with them.
Rym: once I saw the rationale they decided, you know It's really hard to figure out how strong to make something like a century in a game like this.
Rym: Because with AI like I used to mod stuff for doom, right?
Rym: I could make an enemy that always hit you no matter what and I could make a century that always hit you no matter what And it invented damage or whatever.
Rym: Mm-hmm What they did is they decided that they would make the centuries boolean in that if a century You come into a century's line of fire If you do not immediately take cover.
Rym: no matter what class you are you will die.
Rym: It is a Boolean.
Rym: you either will die or won't and you dying is dependent solely upon whether or not you take cover.
Rym: Now if you are able to take cover and there is no one attending the century like an engineer or a pyro Then you will always Boolean be able to destroy that century.
Rym: because you are able to take cover You will be able to trick it somehow and like around the corner rocket around the corner rocket.
Scott: Yeah I've killed centuries with the scout and a pistol by going and shoot.
Rym: She how many centuries I've sniped.
Rym: because people just don't realize that the sniper can take out a century in one eight.
Scott: Yeah I was the scout.
Scott: someone built a century at the top of their battlements and I was on the other battlements and I was a Scout.
Scott: so I took out the pistol and I shot across the entire fort a whole bunch of times and it blew it up With the pistol.
Scott: Hey, what'd I do?
Scott: It's alright doesn't shoot that far.
Rym: I think we've ran it enough.
Rym: The only other thing I wanted to say this just because I learned about it recently But the arts style.
Rym: in Team Fortress 2 we commented a lot about how awesome it is Because it is really awesome.
Rym: Like it fits this game So perfectly well and all the characters just look so great and so stylized and blah blah blah blah.
Rym: The art for the game is actually based on the art of a turn-of-the-century Artist named JC Lane Decker.
Scott: How do you spell that?
Rym: L-e-y-e-n-d-e-c-k-e-r.
Rym: Say that slower Lane Decker.
Scott: I'll just try to figure it out.
Rym: Len Decker I'll link to it or something.
Rym: You know what also.
Rym: I want to say this because I don't think many people noticed it in the main screen routine fortress, too.
Rym: There's a. there's a bunch of options there.
Rym: And one of them is a developer commentary.
Rym: I Recommend you click on that and do what it says.
Rym: You'll probably learn a lot about the game.
Scott: Yeah, I got.
Scott: I never actually watched those commentary things, but it's cool.
Rym: You walk around and there's like stuff like there's a room where there's two Spies stand in there red one in a blue one and there's dialog boxes all over the place.
Rym: And if you shoot a dialog box that dialog box starts talking and player models near you Will act out the relevant things to show you what the developers are talking about.
Scott: It's really really hot and you'll learn a lot about the game Commentary for like half-life 2 and I think half-life 2 episode 1 I just never watched him or listened to him and then maybe I should.
Rym: Right and on that note Partly the reason I wanted to do this episode is to get all this team fortress to talk out of my system.
Rym: So we stopped bringing it up all the time randomly.
Scott: I. well I didn't want to do the do it because we I think we talked about enough already.
Scott: But well Rym might talk about more time.
Scott: So we did.
Scott: it's all Rym.
Scott: Yeah, what were your complaints Rym at?
Rym: for the thing is Scott was like we already covered everything.
Scott: Oh god damn.
Scott: So next week We're doing ask Rym and Scott.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: We've talked about it all last week.
Rym: If you were not gonna explain the whole thing again.
Rym: If you have a question for us related to video games or gaming in any capacity Go into our forums and post it or if you must email it to us.
Rym: if it's a good question and it's not stupid We'll probably answer it next week on the show.
Scott: Yes ask we need questions for Tuesday.
Rym: Whatever you want It could be like what's your favorite video game?
Rym: It could be how do I beat Mario 3?
Rym: It could be how come Mario was a plumber.
Rym: It could be how do you feel about dating guy?
Scott: Mario is a plumber because you can find that out on Google.
Rym: Yeah, but it questions like if you ask a bad question We just won't answer.
Scott: Yeah, just ask questions.
Scott: more questions the better.
Rym: and if you have a non gaming topic question Just ask it anyway because we're doing this all week for all nights next week And as you might know Thursdays don't really have a topic.
Scott: So if a question doesn't have to do with Monday Tuesday or Wednesday ask it Thursday.
Scott: Yeah, it's everything else.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row.
Scott: crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.