Scott: It's Monday July 2nd.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: tonight We discussed democracy on tech news sites like dig and slash dot.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So rims got this fancy new computer.
Scott: I do it's finally working enough.
Rym: I guess I've been playing a half-life 2 quite a bit though.
Rym: Now I want to hold out playing half-life 2 fully and all the way until I have the widescreen monitor to go with it.
Scott: That's a good call.
Scott: Yeah call cuz it gets pretty intense.
Rym: But at least now you recognize the amazing this that is half-life - oh, I recognized all along I've wanted to play half-life - since it came out.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: you used to always diss these single-player FPS's if they were not worth your time.
Rym: Well, you know what other than half-life and half-life - and the possible possible exception of doom - though Only due to nostalgia and the fact that it's one of the only games like that.
Rym: They aren't they're terrible.
Scott: I think that System shock the game.
Scott: that's like the great game.
Scott: We haven't played.
Scott: I have hopes for that.
Scott: You know cuz it.
Scott: people won't shut up about it.
Rym: We'll see cuz.
Rym: we've had a lot of times in the past where people wouldn't shut up about a game And we finally just say alright.
Rym: We'll play it and a lot of times They're not as great as they were universally acclaimed.
Scott: for me to dismiss it like that.
Rym: No yeah You know what World of Warcraft is pretty universally Yeah, no, and it's not universally acclaimed.
Scott: I haven't seen any.
Scott: so you know there's just as many people saying wow sucks as people saying wow is awesome.
Scott: in fact a lot of you who play Wow say wow sucks.
Scott: yeah, but System Shock 2 is Universally revered.
Scott: I've never seen anyone say it suck.
Rym: anyway, so I imagine you brought up my computer for a reason.
Scott: yes So my computer not so awesome.
Scott: I mean it's not bad.
Scott: It's not bad.
Scott: I only bought it two or three years.
Rym: It's still good.
Scott: It's still good.
Scott: It is still good.
Scott: I mean it's got a XP 2500 plus processor which is so fast But it's one point eight gigahertz.
Scott: It's fast enough.
Scott: It's got you know enough hard drives.
Scott: I just filled up one of them, so I could just buy another one, and I'll be all set big deal.
Scott: It's got a geforce fx 5900 which well not exactly you know the fastest car in the universe.
Scott: They're only on the 7900 or eight thousand something now.
Scott: I'm not too far behind.
Scott: I can still play half-life 2 just fine.
Scott: That's not a problem, but I only got 512 megs of RAM.
Rym: Wow even even on my old computer.
Scott: I had a gig and even when I'm using Linux and Just browsing the web or listening to music it kind of fills up.
Scott: And it's not enough.
Rym: now think about that.
Rym: used to be just fine with 16 Yeah, oh yeah, and now makes a ram.
Scott: I could play mech warrior 2 now two gigs for me.
Rym: I use it all.
Scott: Yeah, so I had to decide because my computer takes DDR 400 RAM Which is sort of old and busted and it only takes two sticks of DDR 400. if I want to use three sticks I have to use DDR 333 which is significantly slower.
Scott: So I already have two sticks that are 256 megabytes each.
Scott: so if I want to replace the RAM I've got to buy two new sticks and get rid of the two old sticks.
Scott: Which there's nothing wrong with the two old sticks.
Scott: They work fine.
Scott: They're actually pretty high quality.
Scott: So I had to decide am I gonna buy two new sticks Or am I gonna buy a new computer?
Rym: when you know half-life 2 episode 2 and portal and all those things come out now you Buying a new computer would have completely cocked up the system because Scott and I have a tradition For as long as we've known each other of at any given point.
Rym: one of us has a computer That's very old and one of us has recently bought a brand new super fast computer.
Rym: Yeah, so I got to RIT with like the machine of the gods and Scott had his old Pentium 3.
Rym: Then when my computer was still the machine of the gods But much weaker gods, maybe not the best gods anymore Scott bought a new computer that was like eight times faster than mine and then Rym bought this.
Scott: Yep, but I have a laptop but that laptop isn't really so fast either.
Rym: But if you buy a computer, it'll be the same speed as mine.
Rym: because you know about technology.
Rym: you'd buy the same processor.
Rym: Maybe maybe you'd buy the one the 50 instead of the.
Rym: oh, oh, but I made.
Rym: I probably would actually yeah But that's the only difference.
Rym: we buy the same basic computer.
Scott: The point is I Decided it was a tough decision whether to upgrade and get more RAM and another hard drive or to just wait it out.
Scott: And I said, you know what?
Scott: I'm gonna buy the RAM and I bought it today.
Scott: I bought the cheapest possible two gigs of RAM a new egg that would go in my computer and I hope they saw up.
Rym: What shady brand did you end up picking?
Scott: That's a good question.
Scott: Let me look at my G. You don't even remember it was the shadiest brand available for the type of and size of RAM I needed.
Rym: yeah, it's tough because some of the things that look shady are actually fairly legit nowadays.
Rym: It is very difficult to tell and the people that used to be legit Went into the monster cable direction instead of into the quality direction.
Scott: Yeah, I hate that stuff.
Scott: It's pretty sucky.
Rym: I've already lost interest.
Scott: I know I know I just got like four new egg emails and get figure out which whatever.
Rym: You probably don't want to give them any publicity.
Scott: Anyway, it's g-skill Ram.
Scott: Oh, they're not so bad Yeah, but it wasn't like the ones with the fancy heat spreaders.
Scott: it was just two bare sticks.
Scott: Wow Yeah, we'll see how it works.
Scott: If it doesn't work.
Scott: I'll just return it and give up and keep the hard drive.
Rym: So last year around this time we did a show where we had two friends of ours who are also podcasters Do our show.
Rym: they were guest hosts on our show while we were out of town.
Rym: It was Richard and Allison from simply syndicated calm movies.
Rym: You should see you should check them out.
Rym: They're one of my favorite podcasts and they're awesome.
Rym: Yeah, two of them specifically Yeah, but basically we go away.
Rym: you all suck.
Scott: every year after Otakon We are we go to a undisclosed vacation spot.
Scott: Yes entire week.
Rym: It's kind of like the South Park writers really undisclosed.
Scott: We've said it many times before I'm just being silly.
Rym: It's the front row crew.
Rym: writers retreat.
Scott: Yes, so While we're away on this vacation far away hiding we can't really make shows and we don't really feel like making a bunch of shows In advance.
Scott: so last year we said alright anyone who wants to make an episode of GeekNights We don't want you to make an episode of your show.
Scott: We want you to make an episode of GeekNights for one of the days of the week And then we'll put it up instead of the GeekNights by us.
Scott: and last year We got one taker on our offer.
Rym: However, the one taker happened to be awesome.
Scott: It was one high quality taker and then we decide we had to fill in the other three days.
Scott: So you made shit.
Scott: two-minute episodes.
Rym: I remember our Thursday was 45 seconds long.
Scott: I think that was a day before.
Rym: that wasn't the Thursday during It's still part of the week.
Scott: It is part of it.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, so this year we want more than one taker.
Scott: We've already got one taker.
Scott: I think yes.
Rym: so far the people we've got lined up to do the anime night are pretty hardcore And I think you're gonna like him.
Rym: I think their Style really jives well with the GeekNights format.
Scott: yeah, so if you want to make a Monday show a Tuesday show or a Thursday show of GeekNights and You just want to do that then email us or something.
Rym: However, I'll point out that just because you email us don't feel bad if we say no because there are some mean you're free To make a show.
Scott: Yeah, we're just not gonna put it on our site in our feed if we don't like it.
Rym: There are some undisclosed requirements many of them having to do with intelligence and audio quality and technical aptitude.
Scott: Yes, so if you fail to meet the requirements I mean anyone is free to just make GeekNights episodes and remixes all you want.
Scott: go nuts That'll only make us more popular.
Scott: Yeah, as if you make a really good funny remix and it's on the YouTube or something, but For us to select it as to be in an actual real episode of GeekNights.
Scott: It's got to be something special.
Scott: But don't don't let that scare you into not asking.
Scott: ask because only one person did it last year.
Scott: So maybe no one will do it and you'll be the only one and we'll let you do it.
Scott: Anyway, you suck.
Rym: Ah, we'll see.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: it depends a lot on who you are and how we're feeling.
Scott: Yes, but don't hesitate to ask.
Rym: I also enjoy just making the 32nd episode and putting it up.
Scott: Yeah, those are fun, too.
Rym: But anyway in the news, I thought this was kind of interesting.
Rym: I think it bodes somewhat poorly for Universal.
Rym: They've decided not to renew.
Rym: According to slash dot their contract with Apple for their content on I have they actually like.
Scott: I saw a rumor that was like universal Might not renew or universal threatening to not renew.
Scott: Did they actually?
Scott: Officially not renew?
Rym: the last I saw was to quote slash shot.
Rym: It appears for the moment that Universal will not renew.
Scott: Oh, well, that's that's the end of their music pretty much.
Rym: Uh, I don't know what they're thinking.
Rym: CD sales are down.
Rym: iTunes is much of the music market nowadays and How else they can second after Walmart, so they're probably still gonna rock Walmart.
Scott: So they'll make their money there, but they're not down.
Scott: It's got going down constant.
Rym: It's not gonna last.
Scott: Yeah, basically what this amounts to is imagine if there was the Pony Express and then they invented the truck.
Scott: So there are three male companies and one of them all of them upgrade to trucks Right, and then one of them says fuck these trucks.
Scott: I'm going back to ponies.
Scott: That's what this is.
Scott: It's kind of obvious what's gonna happen.
Scott: All the ponies are gonna get run over by the trucks.
Rym: Well what they might be thinking is they're trying to exert pressure on Apple.
Rym: because you see the real point of contention Other than DRM is the fact that Apple will not let people charge more for their music.
Rym: They have fun at all.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's a dollar Perry.
Rym: You can charge less, but you can't charge.
Scott: Well, I think you get a discount if you buy the whole album.
Rym: No, no I mean you can say your music cost less than a dollar.
Rym: Okay, and you I don't know But you can't say it costs more than a dollar.
Scott: Well, actually I think the non DRM music cost slightly more than a doll.
Rym: Yeah, but that's still so.
Rym: even then it's a flat price.
Rym: they can't change it.
Rym: Yep, and They don't like this because they want to charge you a lot more money.
Rym: They feel that a song is worth more than 99 cents.
Scott: They also feel that you know because a song is brand new from like Britney Spears It should be more money than an old cruddy song.
Scott: No one likes I.
Rym: just I really wonder what they're thinking because Apple I know Couldn't care less.
Rym: They have the music industry by the balls.
Scott: I'm beginning to feel that Cuz cuz we saw that record company guy at RIT.
Rym: remember him Oh the guy who wouldn't answer my question because I happen to be wearing a skull and bones.
Scott: Yeah that guy You know that guy he wasn't totally aware of you know, everything that we know, but he wasn't completely stupid either You know and I got to assume that the other record executives are at least as smart as he is.
Scott: Maybe a little dumber maybe a little smarter right?
Scott: I'm beginning to think that at this point the record executives Realize that there is absolutely no way to save their sinking ship and they're just trying to get as many Nice paintings and statues and jewels and fineries off of that ship before it sinks seat.
Rym: now I do want to point out that I don't think that the idea of selling music is the sinking ship.
Rym: I think the sinking ship is the current model of the music industry Which is get a band make them super super popular and sell a million of their CDs as opposed to the future Which is probably the long tail of many many many bands each doing a little bit of music and making a little bit of money.
Scott: Yes I think the days of because I think the one problem is that you had with music sit.
Scott: ever since Elvis the music industry worked in such a way that someone had to become a star a rock star who had a lot of money and Glamour and fame and huge arena concerts and all that jazz.
Scott: and I think for now on Yeah, still some of those people will emerge, you know, if someone gets stupidly popular all across the internets or whatever.
Scott: But for the most part, you know There are gonna be musicians who are popular enough and they're gonna make the same amount of money that you and I make.
Scott: they're gonna Make a decent living just doing normal business.
Rym: Well, the only reason the music industry ended up being the way it was was simply that before the internet You couldn't get played on the radio.
Rym: You couldn't get gigs You couldn't do anything more than play for like the county fair and in Peoria.
Rym: Yeah, unless you went to the music industry and said I'm gonna sign away all my rights make me famous.
Rym: Nowadays, we have YouTube.
Rym: if a band's good enough and they put themselves on the internet.
Rym: They'll become popular.
Scott: So what we had before Actually was a system in which you were either super rich and famous or you weren't cutting it as a musician alone.
Scott: You had to do something else on the side, you know, maybe a radio DJ or maybe working a McDonald's a radio DJ.
Rym: Those still exist.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well in the I'm talking about back in the day and then Nowadays, we're moving towards a system in which pretty much most of the musicians will there.
Scott: You know, if you're a good music, of course, if you suck, you're not gonna make anything.
Scott: That's still gonna be the case.
Scott: But if you're okay, and you have talent, you're probably and you you're not stupid.
Scott: You're probably gonna make enough money to live from your music and no one very few people much fewer than you know back in the 70s or 80s will get stupidly rich just from being a musician.
Scott: and it's kind of funny because it's basically a combination of capitalism and technology That make the playing field even as whereas normally you would think that communism or socialism would do something like that.
Rym: Now you see what we have here with Universal.
Rym: I'm going on a different tack with this.
Rym: now all right is basically a real-world example of the prisoners dilemma because Universal has said all right We're defecting from Apple.
Rym: if every other or at least if a few of the other labels decided, you know, what we're with you We're defecting - then they all win collectively and Apple loses.
Rym: However There's a choice now.
Rym: if all the other labels say, you know what we're gonna let universal love twist in the wind a little bit.
Rym: Then basically they defect against universal and they all stand to gain because they look better for the tech crowd.
Rym: They now have more presence in the market because they're still on iTunes.
Rym: They're still on Apple's good side.
Rym: They can even run the PR machine to sell the fact that they're not evil like universal and they're not backwards like universal.
Scott: Well, it all started with the original prisoners dilemma of there's a bunch of record companies who's gonna sign with Apple?
Scott: Yeah, and one person signed and then they all went and now one person leaves.
Scott: Will they all leave?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I think I'm gonna say no.
Rym: Yeah It is my opinion that the rest of the music industry is at least smart enough to realize that without Apple They're gonna have a lot of trouble.
Scott: Yeah, and I think Any record company that's planning to stay with Apple is more than happy to let the others leave.
Rym: Yeah, because that means they would like more market share more promotion.
Scott: They would like nothing more than to be the only record label on Apple.
Scott: All right, speaking of selling musics.
Scott: You may or may not know of a website.
Scott: It's pretty popular That everyone who's on the Internet's probably knows about it called all of mp3.
Rym: It was one of the great old, uh, I don't know I want to call it Soviet, but it's not really.
Rym: it's just one of those shady Russian or pocknerian Deals that was going around back in the day.
Scott: Well, it was going around for a long time It wasn't.
Scott: you know, it wasn't too old.
Scott: It's only a few years old but
Rym: that's back in the day as first the internet
Scott: of this site was that in Russia The laws about copyright and royalties for music and stuff like that are different from the US and due to a legal loophole They were able to make a website where you could download pretty much any music you wanted.
Scott: that was you know Popular record company music because they didn't have rare indie musics there so much and you could pay a price like 25 cents for a song and you could get any format at any bit rate you wanted and of course height they would charge like by how much?
Scott: so if you got like a flack of like a Half hour song that would cost a lot more than a shitty mp3 of a two-minute song.
Rym: course a lot more.
Rym: It was still nothing.
Scott: It was still like less than a dollar for most songs.
Scott: like albums were less than five hours and The problem with all of mp3 of course is that all the other countries, you know, Russia didn't like it so much but there's nothing they could do about it really and You know in order.
Scott: Russia wanted to join the World Trade Organization but they couldn't because this site was still there and like you can't join the World Trade or trade organization if You know part if your country is doing things that are piracy related.
Rym: granted It wasn't just all of mp3 that was keeping Russia out of the no But it was a factor.
Scott: it was something that the politicians involved in that sort of thing knew about and brought up.
Rym: It was just the fact that things like this Existed and Russia wasn't doing anything about it because there were a lot of shady outfits very similar to this in Russia.
Scott: Oh, yeah all over the place, but this is one that was of note.
Scott: It was probably the biggest one actually.
Scott: Well today Russia finally shut down all of mp3 Permanently.
Scott: forever it's gone the end.
Rym: didn't that happen before?
Scott: well It's been shut down temporarily at times and but it's always crawled back from the dead And now it is finally all the way gone.
Rym: Maybe it will reappear in Ukraine.
Scott: Well.
Scott: No it will not reappear in Ukraine.
Scott: however We don't know how.
Scott: you know.
Scott: well We don't know.
Scott: I guess it could just reappear.
Scott: that might happen But it seems it at least it seems to me that they've.
Scott: they've sealed the legal loophole that locks MP3 all of mp3 away.
Scott: however the same people who made all of mp3 Have made another site called mp3 sparks.
Scott: It's launched by the same people.
Scott: It's not illegal under Russian law because they use a different licensing model and a different loophole And you can still get albums for like $3 outstanding.
Scott: so Everyone change your bookmarks from all of mp3 calm to mp3 sparks.
Rym: And I had read the news, so I didn't realize that part.
Scott: yeah Yeah, actually there's another.
Scott: there's a. there's an old story like in in the article I'm reading about all of mp3 being shut down.
Scott: There's actually a story that is kind of old But I didn't know about it until just now.
Scott: Apparently there's a Danish internet service provider called perspective and a while ago They decided to block all of mp3 for their users.
Scott: So no one using perspective as their ISP could get to all of mp3.
Rym: calm wow I wonder why they would do that.
Rym: I can see almost no incentive unless our government was leaning on you right.
Rym: well the Pirate Bay Working together with pirates Byron did they give people access to it through the Pirate Bay?
Scott: no No, that would have been one thing.
Scott: I would have thought is that they would proxy.
Scott: You know the all of mp3?
Scott: Yeah, instead they blocked all of perspectives customers from getting to the Pirate Bay.
Scott: Hahaha, so basically the Pirate Bay if you went to perspective it wouldn't let you in.
Scott: not long after that perspective Opened up all of mp3 again.
Rym: I wonder why.
Scott: yeah think about that.
Scott: Pirate Bay Is that powerful with their bit torrents of illegalness that they can force?
Rym: In a what are you talking about the Pirate Bay does not violate any laws.
Scott: It doesn't which is awesome.
Scott: And There's think about it was like an act of piracy.
Scott: they sailed up with their pirate boat and they menaced That's this Danish internet service provider and rather than be boarded and skewered and be have all their loots Taken they gave in to the pirates.
Rym: I gotta say regardless of whether or not you agree or disagree with the Motivation and and the modus operandi of the Pirates Bay you have to respect the testicular fortitude They have shown to us.
Scott: They're my kind of people.
Rym: This is Sparta.
Scott: That's not good There's so.
Rym: we were talking about this a little while ago But it surprises us the sheer number of Sparta remixes of things on the internet.
Scott: What is it about that 300 movie that makes it so remixable?
Scott: I mean usually I'll be like, oh that is so remixable, right but Like take for example snakes on a plane.
Scott: the idea of snakes on a plane was super remixable But the actual movie not so much.
Scott: for some reason 300.
Scott: I Don't know why.
Scott: what what about it?
Scott: I think why is it out of control?
Rym: Here's my hypothesis.
Rym: I believe that the reason Sparta is so remixable aside from the homo eroticism and the fighting and the violence and These silly lines yelled at each other and all that business.
Rym: The guy's face is one of those Lord of the Rings on the go faces and It has been used in the Lord of the Rings on the go face humor way for great effect.
Scott: I suppose so.
Scott: but I definitely did not see this Fad coming of remixing the Sparta.
Rym: I think it just comes down to people yelled in Sparta a lot.
Rym: well in 300, I guess they yelled in Sparta a lot too, but There's a lot of yelling and it seems like whenever someone yells in a thing and you want to remix it What better thing to have them yell then something from Sparta?
Scott: So what's it?
Scott: so what you think of it is I imagine it's some sort of art or remix.
Rym: We came upon this somewhat by accident.
Rym: We were watching dramatic.
Rym: Look for some reason.
Rym: I think you all know what you're mad at.
Rym: And Then we saw dramatic look remix, which was a short remix.
Rym: That was basically that plus a lightsaber.
Scott: it was high quality.
Rym: and then we noticed in the related a Sparta remix that was actually quite long.
Rym: and while this is probably only going to be funny once I recommend that you watch it all the way through and There's a point at which it becomes Lord of the Rings on the go and I could not help but laugh out loud Uncontrollably when that happened.
Scott: Yeah, this is a pretty good one And then we tried to find more of these and the other ones kind of sucked.
Scott: So this is the best one you're gonna get on YouTube for now.
Scott: someone might up top it soon.
Rym: I wouldn't be that hard to top it.
Rym: We could top it if we were doing a show.
Scott: We don't have video editing action or skills.
Rym: The real issue here is I noticed that I found two not one but two other videos on YouTube That were actually the same video as this With a different song and like.
Rym: they cut off the end or the front and I don't get that.
Rym: It's like they remixed the remix.
Scott: Well by remixing a remix isn't so bad But they did.
Rym: problem is in such as I barely barely changed it.
Scott: It's like some guy edited all this video together and some guy just changed the song and put it back up.
Rym: Plus even this I got to admit.
Rym: Well, I don't get why for several seconds.
Rym: We just see Phoenix Wright standing there.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I don't understand that either and then I really don't get Why they showed the clip of Batman running away from phantos completely unedited and in its entirety.
Scott: Yeah, I don't understand that.
Rym: either now if you were to replace the phantos head with a Sparta head That would have been great.
Rym: or if you'd been carrying the Sparta head running away from a Sparta head or if Batman had had a Sparta head I would have just had the The.
Scott: what's the groundhog thing the prairie dog?
Scott: Yeah, I would have had it do the.
Scott: you know The look with some sort of Batman added to it Uh-huh, like, you know, I don't know.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I just would have taken that gif and added Sparta to it.
Rym: I don't know why they didn't.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I don't get there's a the middle bit of this.
Rym: There's no way you won't laugh at it with a little go-kart thing.
Rym: and then the panda jack-in-the-box.
Rym: Yeah They replaced the sneezing panda with a jack-in-the-box or the or the football players at the end.
Rym: I think that's when I really lost it.
Scott: Yeah, they're alright, too Alright, so that's a funny video right there.
Scott: But I think I've realized something.
Scott: You know how we often use Japanese television as things today, you know We often use YouTube and dig videos as things of the day.
Rym: Well Japanese television is awesome and YouTube is the closest thing we have in America to that.
Scott: That's what I just realized recently.
Scott: is that Japanese television apparently I guess forever.
Scott: I don't know when it started.
Scott: It's basically the same stuff that's on YouTube.
Scott: It's just like a bunch of thrown together hilarity.
Rym: Yeah, the worst part is it's usually it shows that like game shows that are set up to create those situations.
Rym: It's like they do it on purpose.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if youtubers had enough money and they could make a living for just making funny videos.
Scott: They basically just recreate Japanese television.
Rym: I think so.
Scott: So here's something funny from Japanese television that I thought was kind of cool.
Scott: There's a guy in a zoo and there's a gorilla in the cage and the guy's got a hose and I think it's his job To clean the gorilla cage.
Scott: slash the gorilla.
Scott: So he sprays the water at the gorilla and the cage and the gorillas in a cage.
Scott: It's not gonna hurt him.
Scott: It's not a mean gorilla either.
Scott: So there's no blood and gore in this one and The gorilla realizes that the floor is getting all slippery from the water.
Scott: so the gorilla starts to do some funny stuff with a slippery floor and Just watch the video.
Scott: It is the entertaining a couple times.
Rym: Yes, is that I Liked videos like this when it chose a monkey or an ape or gorilla or any sort of animal Exhibiting that sort of?
Rym: I don't know intelligence and love of fun.
Rym: Did it bump up?
Rym: bump?
Rym: Yeah, because that's still relevant Right, so instead of talking about how computers work because we've been doing that a lot lately We realized something that I mean a lot of people talk about this but I've been thinking about it more lately partly because I go to both sites about equally and Both of them are starting to annoy me for this for the same amount, but in different directions.
Rym: I really think we just have to talk about dig and slash dot and internet democracy versus Push content and all that sort of business.
Scott: Well to introduce.
Scott: basically you have websites on the internet that take those websites on the internet.
Scott: yes, their websites on the Internet and They have news on them.
Scott: some sites make news like CNN.
Scott: Well, I guess that no you see that I UPI and Associated Press make news.
Scott: local newspapers Also sometimes make shitty local news, but there are places that make news also like sometimes.
Scott: You know Engadget makes news like not so much as here is a fact we researched.
Scott: but here is an editorial type news.
Scott: You know something.
Scott: we you know reviewing a product that is new, you know something.
Scott: they wrote original content.
Scott: And then there are sites which take the content around the internet and sort of list it.
Scott: So that way you don't have to go to a hundred different sites to get all these newses.
Scott: One site collects all the best newses for you custom You know just similar to your interests and you can just go to one place one-stop shop.
Scott: And he used to be back in the day.
Scott: one of the first places that did this in a good way was slash dot and slash dot would go around and I think the Slogan of slash that still is news for nerd stuff.
Scott: that matters right and they would go around finding news that nerds cared about the geeks cared about that.
Scott: Nerds and geeks think matters.
Rym: There wasn't a third kind.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: You're about.
Rym: you're trying to say the third kind but there wasn't one.
Scott: there wasn't one and People would submit the stories to slash dot.
Scott: so you would suggest hey slash dot why don't you put this on your site?
Scott: and then pretty much every article in the entire known universe was always submitted and Then people at slash dot keep.
Scott: employees of slash dot would decide this news story will go on slash dot.
Scott: This one will not.
Scott: and you couldn't see which stories were approved or not approved.
Scott: all you saw was which stories made it and which stories you submitted.
Scott: that's all you knew and It worked pretty well.
Scott: slash that was the biggest things in sliced bread for years and years and years back.
Rym: Then it always had the news long before anyone else did.
Rym: you didn't have to go digging for it It was just there.
Rym: Usually the commentary was somewhat insightful and the crowds the mobs the people posting and commenting on slash dot.
Rym: We're by and large pretty intelligent.
Rym: there's a lot of good humor there a lot of sense of community and The moderation system will get to that.
Scott: Yeah But people on slash dot they always said hey We don't like how these people at slash dot decide which goes on the site and which doesn't.
Scott: we want to decide?
Scott: Which news goes on the site and which doesn't.
Rym: yeah There's always the troubles with like.
Scott: they'd complain about Roland peak Paley or because like every day There would be another story from Roland peak Paley's blog and you'd be like why the fuck is that guy's blog always on slash?
Scott: Dot?
Rym: this is bullshit or people complain about dupes.
Scott: They'd complain about yeah, they'd be like hey, why is that story there?
Scott: That was already there.
Scott: It shouldn't be there again.
Scott: These editors fucked up.
Scott: We're smart enough.
Scott: We know that's a dupe.
Scott: Why are you putting it up?
Rym: or editors over editorial izing?
Rym: Yeah, all sorts of stuff like that.
Scott: so for years and years and years people always had the idea that there should be some sort of slash dot with a voting system of What stories go to the front page and for some reason no one was ever actually smart enough to make it including me.
Scott: I could have done it.
Scott: I just didn't.
Scott: I was too dumb.
Scott: I didn't do it.
Scott: It could have been me.
Scott: Yeah, you know what to be Scott Reuben and I Kevin Rose.
Rym: I think part of the reason I never thought about it at all was I didn't really care since I had FARC which wall.
Rym: It's definitely dictatorship like slash shot.
Rym: at the same time Everything funny was always there.
Scott: so I didn't care but I mean it was.
Scott: it was so obvious.
Scott: Everyone wanted it.
Scott: No one did until dig and I'm sure dig wasn't the first one, you know, well there was corrosion.
Scott: You know corrosion was about fiction though and not so and about articles written by people and not about news Sure.
Rym: It was a lot about nonfiction and commentary though.
Scott: Yeah editorials and things.
Scott: you would write a story basically or an essay and put it on corrosion.
Scott: then people would vote it to the Top.
Scott: Yeah, you couldn't link to some news like hey vote this news article over there to the top.
Scott: that didn't work.
Scott: That wasn't what the site was about.
Rym: Yeah, thought no more personal note.
Rym: I can say that I have interacted with the corrosion community a few times in the last few months Mostly to get free copy editing on things.
Rym: I write I just make an account and submit something and get.
Rym: those are some Generally intense and scary people.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Anyway, so eventually, you know some sites came out that were semi-democratic You know and different from slash.
Scott: that I mean delicious was a site where you would bookmark, you know all you used it was to supplement your you know, normal bookmarks and They had a page.
Scott: that was the popular page and it would show.
Rym: I don't think we need to talk about any more history.
Rym: Yeah dig is the opposite of slash shot.
Rym: It's democratic.
Rym: instead of a select few choosing what the masses see based on submissions from the masses You have the masses choosing how popular something is by each giving it a little nudge up or a nudge down and that's it.
Rym: And as a result now that we've had some time and these two sites are both firmly established still Slash shot is moving more and more toward news and commentary and editorial izing and that sort of thing.
Rym: and Dig is moving more and more not toward news but toward being like a snapshot of the zeitgeist that is the internet.
Rym: you go to dig on any given day and look at what's at the Top and you pretty much know what the internet is talking about at that time.
Rym: What's popular?
Rym: What ideas are popular?
Rym: What ideas are unpopular?
Rym: What politicians are popular?
Rym: among the kinds of people who read diggin slash dot?
Rym: you never got that on slash dot.
Rym: All you got was here's the news and as a result people only talked about the news.
Scott: Yep, I mean slash dot, you know used to be the place to go to find out things.
Scott: now if it's on slash dot I know it already pretty much a hundred percent of the time.
Scott: I've already heard that news somewhere else.
Scott: slash that is no news to offer.
Scott: Dig on the other hand, you know it tell you by looking at all the headlines and you can figure out what people who will use dig on the in the general geek internet community are thinking and what they agree with And what they disagree with and what they think is important what they don't think is important.
Scott: But you might also get a link to the news itself But these you're not gonna get anything else besides that the comments are basically just bleh Gosh dot.
Scott: the comments are still somewhat usable You know what?
Rym: I'll say openly that the comments on FARC are more usable than dig.
Rym: Whoa Insult.
Rym: Yeah, I got insult because I got to get this on slash dot for a long time.
Rym: I was an uber moderator Which I didn't know that existed until we asked them at penguin con because I had had mod points continuously for like four months.
Rym: Yeah non-stop.
Rym: So we met the slash dot guys and I was like, uh Thing broken, how come I have infinite mod points?
Rym: They're like, oh well you're one of the blah and they explained it.
Rym: so I had the power to moderate slash dot as Much as I could and I realized that the amount of moderation you can do on slash dot Even if you have effectively infinite power is very minor because you can't do anything with the story.
Rym: You can only edit what people have commented on.
Rym: you can't change a story so you can't pick what's popular.
Rym: on slash dot.
Rym: You can only decide what people were writing better in the comments.
Rym: but even then you can only nudge things up a little tiny bit or nudging down a little tiny bit and It just didn't feel like it had any effect and I felt like it just wasn't worth it to bother the time It took to moderate.
Rym: I could have just gone somewhere else and done something better or more important.
Rym: dig Everyone can moderate everyone.
Rym: Finitely everyone on dig already has more power than I had on slash dot ever.
Rym: We can still only nudge anything up or down a little bit But you could nudge every single thing up if you want it or every single thing down.
Rym: As a result you start to see what ideas are popular and what ideas are not popular.
Rym: in a way that could never happen on Slash dot.
Rym: on slash dot you only saw what ideas had piqued the interest of a moderator because not everyone could moderate.
Rym: So in fact, we used to play a game Scott and I where it was who can have the longest uninterrupted streak of +5 comments The max you can get on slash dot and we realized that there was a specific Formula where you could say this is going to be a +5 post if I post it within the next two minutes.
Scott: Yep, you just had to post it early enough.
Scott: So if the story goes up you have to post your comment right away because that's when people are gonna see it.
Scott: You gotta post something that you know.
Scott: either Agrees with that everyone is thinking and brings up, you know, the major points or you got to say something.
Scott: That's you know, like a new talking point that wasn't mentioned yet in the comments or something like that.
Scott: And pretty much every time I go all the way to +5.
Rym: Yeah, I filled my entire history once As a result good time.
Rym: Yeah, but then slash shot.
Rym: while the comments that filter to the top are always very good They weren't really representative of what people thought.
Rym: they were just representative of the I guess Generally most learned commenting on the story at hand, which is useful.
Rym: But dig you can see very clear like for example Atheism is big on dig religion not so much our conspiracy theory.
Rym: Yes It's definitely not.
Rym: You're starting to see that the internet the types of things that are popular and the types of people that are on the internet while very diverse have certain leanings and we never could really see this as Clearly as we can now with dig.
Scott: Yeah, I think dig is very useful for that.
Scott: But on the other hand Sometimes you just get fed up with it because I want a site I want to be able to have you know, just a list of all the news as I care about with no news Is I don't care about.
Scott: you know and slash used to provide some of the news I cared about.
Scott: almost no news I didn't care about.
Scott: as soon as I filtered out John Katz and They there was news I cared about they weren't putting up there mostly the non tech news.
Scott: Dig has a lot of the news I care about in fact almost all of it.
Scott: But it also has a bunch of bullshit news that I want to get rid of very badly and it's very difficult to get rid Of it.
Rym: Like for example, I care a lot about political news in the United States.
Rym: I pay attention to that quite a bit.
Rym: On dig.
Rym: the only political news that ever gets dug up is I'm not like.
Rym: it's not like it leans a little to the left to the right.
Rym: It's pretty much nothing.
Rym: But oh my god this super obscure Underdog candidate is too awesome because of my blog post says.
Rym: it says so That that they just be like links to crap blog posts and some bad grammar.
Rym: Ron Paul is awesome.
Rym: dig this and a bunch of people would dig it.
Scott: Yeah, or there's people who made a website that was a link to the dig API.
Scott: So it check to see how many digs it has and based on how many digs it has it would show more dots in a picture And so if enough people dug the story you could see the whole picture.
Scott: Yeah, that's really useful news.
Scott: I need that link in my RSS reader.
Scott: See I would have died without that one.
Rym: I don't mind seeing news that I don't actively care about.
Rym: I like to get just a picture of the world.
Rym: That's why I generally just read Google News for my world news.
Scott: Yeah, that's the thing though Is that there is news I care about.
Scott: that is not world news.
Scott: So it's not in Google News, you know Like news about.
Scott: you know computers and video games and all these sorts.
Rym: Yeah, you know what I go to multiple sites I do.
Scott: I RSS many many sites Seattle and RSS.
Scott: But the thing is is that when you RSS something like say in gadget right and gadget reports on gadgets You know, but and they they're pretty good.
Scott: They're all really smart.
Scott: Everything they say is pretty respectful and intelligent and complete pretty much.
Scott: But there are a lot of things they don't cover.
Scott: and if I you know, I don't care about everything on engage.
Scott: I only care about some of the things on a gadget.
Scott: and in order to get all the gadget news I cared about I would need like 15 gadget blogs and then a filter on each one to only get the bit of news on each blog that I want and That is why I don't use RSS.
Rym: It's useless if I want to get all my news because all the sites I go to Have some unique news and then they dupe everything else.
Rym: yep, but much more dear to me is simply the idea the comments because Usually a tech article is either crap or long or boring or doesn't have all the information or is biased or whatever And that's the reason I prefer to get all my tech news still from slash dot.
Rym: if I go to slash dot I'm guaranteed that if I read the article and then I go to the comments if There was something wrong in the article or someone miss cited some comment will say this is wrong Every time.
Rym: the comments in slash dot will give me the whole story almost every single time and I don't need to do the research because it's there.
Rym: and I found over the years that I can generally Trust most of the research I find on slash dot.
Scott: We should have some sort of system where instead of commenting right we people will actually write the Text that should go up there as the description and then people moderate to see which description should be the one that replaces.
Scott: That way you'll get the whole story without having to read a second thing.
Scott: That would be cool.
Rym: now dig.
Rym: on the other hand The I learned that the only way to read dig comments is to immediately block Basically ban from you ever seeing again Anyone who is stupid immediately.
Rym: and I used to think that dig was this chaotic sea of jibbering idiots.
Rym: And one day I decided that anytime I see someone who writes with poor grammar and spelling Writes a crap post like just like lol FTW OMG or something crap like that or just writes in Unpunctuated no capital letters garbage sentence or write something stupid.
Rym: or Anyone who believed in the autism vaccine link or anyone who was religious and espoused it on dig.
Rym: now I say and there they had to do both or I didn't care or in general just said anything stupid.
Rym: now Not something I disagreed with just something stupid.
Rym: if someone says something interesting about religion or posted something interesting Arguing for or against autism vaccines, whatever cool.
Rym: But if what they said was stupid regardless of whether or not I agreed with them in principle I blocked them.
Rym: My block list is hundreds and hundreds and hundreds hundreds of people.
Rym: I blocked five or six people every single time I go to dig and I realized when I first did this I went into an article about autism and vaccines and I blocked everyone who was stupid.
Rym: and I noticed that I started seeing a good percentage fewer posts when I went to any other discussion and I realized that the majority of the crap on dig is caused by a Very small minority of the people on it.
Scott: Yeah, there are just a few people.
Scott: We've got nothing better to do and they're dumb and they write a bunch of shitty comments all over dig like crazy.
Scott: And if you just block those people all the comment sections start to clear up pretty nicely And it's not perfect.
Scott: But it's pretty it's not bad.
Rym: It appears that if enough people block a person The person will end up being banned or something in some sort of algorithm that seems to be semi hidden But people have referenced it before.
Rym: I implore all of you if someone is stupid on dig block them together.
Rym: We can end this Yep, not the general.
Scott: the way I see it is that you know slashdot isn't perfect and dig isn't perfect.
Scott: They're really still even after getting what we wanted after all those years of slashdot.
Scott: We want to dig.
Scott: we asked for it We got it.
Scott: We still don't have exactly what we want.
Scott: Nobody's really a hundred percent happy.
Rym: even better people complain just as much Slashdot.
Rym: they always complain that the editors pick everything and they still complain to a degree.
Scott: and now they complain the editors are The people.
Scott: the masses on dig are too stupid posted a bunch of crap.
Rym: Yep I mean if you go to dig so many people are just so fed up and they complain like how come everything on dig is pro Atheist how come everything on dig is left-leaning and how come everything on dig is sensationalist?
Rym: Yeah, and the answer is because that's what the people on dig believe.
Scott: I think while slashdot should stick around because we need something that does that.
Rym: Oh slashdot is still the best site All of them as far as I dig.
Scott: we need dig to stick around and it's in its pure democracy Forms so that we can see what people on the internet are feeling.
Scott: we can get the vibe of the mass, right?
Scott: I propose we need a third thing a third way.
Rym: a third way Not the straightaways not the corners, but the third place.
Scott: the third place.
Rym: You see the tires slash out of this whole thing.
Scott: There is one part that has no problems and that is the slashdot comment system.
Scott: The reason the slashdot comment system works is because it is democratic in a way Not purely democratic but democratic.
Scott: there is voting by the people using it as to what should go up and what you go down.
Scott: But not everyone gets to vote only the representatives get to vote Huh?
Scott: That's a really good idea of filtering out stupidity by having a representative democracy.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: has anyone ever thought of that crazy idea before?
Scott: I don't think so.
Scott: Maybe some people that might have started a country that's been around for like 200 years and now isn't going away anytime soon.
Rym: There's nothing like that.
Rym: No, no, no.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Well since there's nothing like that.
Scott: No one can sue us for patent infringement That Uses a representative form of democracy to determine what should go up and what should go down.
Scott: I guess people would only be able to vote on other people and then people who have a lot of votes from other people Would then actually get to vote on stories and comments and those sorts of things.
Rym: However, I mean, it'd be very difficult to pull that off Like diggin slash dot.
Rym: I have to deal with the problems of people gaming the system to get more influence and things like that.
Scott: Yep There are quite many more questions to answer before something like that is feasible possible and not broken.
Scott: But I think that is the the way to go in the long run is some sort of maybe you know I mean Netscape tried it where they just paid people to be the.
Scott: you know, the influencers.
Scott: that doesn't work.
Scott: You can't pay people.
Scott: it has to be people doing it because they want to because those the only people who are gonna do it You know because if you're paid to do it, you don't really care how it turns out.
Scott: only people using it care How it turns out.
Rym: Yep, so like Wikipedia my worry though I mean slash dot does have that in the not really it's representative.
Rym: It's not a democracy in that moderators are chosen and then those moderators have power for a time.
Scott: Yes, but those moderators are chosen by an algorithm not by a human.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but the point is that people who moderate slash dot get sick of it and then don't bother anymore.
Rym: And any time you rely on people to do something like that Where they have to make an effort as opposed to dig where it takes zero effort People eventually get sick of it and just stop doing it.
Rym: You have to always keep bringing in the flesh the fresh blood.
Scott: Well, you know this all comes into exactly.
Scott: How are you going to implement this?
Scott: For example, I could implement a system that looks just like dig where everyone puts in the small effort of digging stories, right?
Scott: But what it does is instead of every dig is one vote.
Scott: What it could do is it could say all right who submitted that story and it got a lot of digs.
Scott: That must be a person that people like and then the people who submit stories that people like Their digs will actually matter in terms of putting things on the front page.
Scott: Whereas other people won't matter.
Rym: really Well, the problem with that is that most people I think who post things on day or things that get dug up.
Rym: Basically do nothing all day but sit there and try to find the stories that'll get them dug up.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: But as a result they cater toward the sensationalist crap audience instead of I don't know me they do.
Scott: But I think having some sort of you know system like this or something I you know, I'm not gonna come up with the perfect answer here on the show.
Scott: Forget about.
Rym: well, you'd better Otherwise your crap your ideas crap.
Rym: You're a bad person.
Scott: Yeah, my idea is crap.
Scott: It's only kept us going for how long.
Scott: and yeah It's only the.
Scott: you know, the form of government used in most of the civilized world.
Rym: Scott we pay our representatives.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: Yes We only pay them.
Rym: in fact decide that we're who we're going to pay Except that we don't really decide because the incumbency rate is in the 90% surround here I know but no one.
Rym: most people don't decide.
Rym: No one cares on paper.
Rym: besides do you want?
Rym: I mean you see how the American government works?
Rym: Do you want a site to end up as corrupt as that?
Scott: Yeah, there I think there are ways we could do about it like maybe keep who the representatives are secret stuff like that.
Rym: The way you go about it is you have dig but behind the scenes you just completely rig the system secretly.
Scott: That'd be alright, but I still I think but if you just rig the system you basically just made slash that.
Scott: that looks like dig.
Rym: Yes, but then people don't complain as much.
Rym: yeah because they think they have control but they don't know.
Scott: I want to have you know, a representative system where you have people voting democratically to choose what goes there.
Scott: So that way you get a large quantity of content filtered down to just have the meat and potatoes But at the same time you're filtering out all the stupidity.
Scott: So even if something is incredibly popular, but it's stupid as all hell It doesn't get up there.
Rym: You know what dig needs.
Rym: very simply right now I can block a person and not see their comments.
Rym: if I block someone I shouldn't see their submitted digs No matter how dug up they get either.
Scott: Maybe it works that way.
Rym: No, I don't think it does.
Rym: Well, it should if it does because I see the same Doug stories as everyone else.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, I mean you can filter out categories Which is huge because I don't want to see that stupid medicine and health category.
Rym: I know it's full of bullshit because all the time I bury everything and then I go in and block everyone who boasts Yeah, but that's not I don't.
Scott: I can't click that many times.
Scott: I basically does not look at the bullshit.
Rym: I stomp around dig with a sword just cleaving people left and right.
Scott: I don't have time.
Scott: I just want the fucking news.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew com or you can send audio feedback.
Scott: Audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.