Scott: It's Monday September 24th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: Malware what it is how not to get it and how to get rid of it.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well on Friday we went to a metal concert though We means everyone but Scott who stayed home and went to bed other people did not go besides me.
Scott: How many other person how many people were there total in the whole group in the whole place?
Rym: Oh in the whole place?
Rym: I don't know a hundred.
Scott: So you're telling me that Everyone meaning seven billion went now.
Scott: It was seven billion minus.
Rym: I thought that was really lame.
Rym: out of the front row crew who was coming to our house for the weekend Only two people did not attend this concert.
Rym: And in fact two other people who did not stay for D&D attended this concert.
Scott: Oh, I didn't know that.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, we went to a fin troll concert, which is I'm just gonna call it heavy metal because I don't really care much about all the different Is it hardcore metal?
Rym: Is it folk orchestral?
Rym: Gruntle sub architect metal.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I I kind of ignore sub genres in music but anyway, it was a pretty badass concert.
Rym: went on real laters at the chance in Poughkeepsie, but Something interesting happened well beyond the fact that we got to see fin troll live.
Rym: So, you know any concert like this a whole bunch of bands will play and as we learned from the tool concert We went to back and we were at RIT.
Rym: Sometimes those bands suck Particularly phantomas.
Scott: Yeah, do we tell that story?
Rym: I don't know if we did enough and I'm just gonna skip it.
Rym: All right, if we didn't tell the story, maybe someone will tell us we didn't tell it.
Rym: But uh, we're at this concert and a band comes out and they're okay.
Rym: I mean they weren't great, but they weren't terrible.
Rym: So I'm chilling and then the announcer comes out of the MC.
Rym: Who's?
Rym: this gigantic awesome black guy is the same guy who was there the last time I went to the chance.
Rym: I think he's the owner or something or at least he's like the permanent MC.
Scott: He's he's the guy.
Rym: He's big and jolly and he's a really cool guy.
Rym: He always comes out and he has funny things to say and he gets the crowd together and he's real jovial and it's cool.
Rym: And he comes out and he introduces the next band and he says now I want to warn all of you that this band is not exactly metal But I think you might like him seriously.
Rym: give these guys a chance I this might be up your alley and he basically just kept saying, you know, check this band out.
Rym: Give it a chance.
Rym: This is gonna be pretty cool.
Rym: You're gonna like it and then the band comes out and They're kind of mediocre, all right They say Jesus a lot and we're debating with each other.
Rym: Are they a Christian metal band or are they just being ironic about it?
Rym: Cuz I don't understand bands.
Scott: Why would they come there?
Scott: Why would don't they usually stick together?
Scott: Well, no, it wouldn't matter.
Scott: This isn't fintral like pagan.
Rym: Well, that's the thing.
Rym: We're not sure if it's a Christian band.
Rym: We're leaning toward.
Rym: no because fintral The the thing about fintral is they're basically a pagan band.
Rym: when fintral came out on the stage after their first song They basically said how do you feel about?
Rym: Christians and the crowd is like He was like.
Rym: tonight we will have a song about how to enjoy Christians by cooking them.
Rym: They're like super anti-christian is kind of funny.
Rym: But so we're debating.
Rym: is this fan Christian?
Rym: and they kept saying Jesus, but whatever I think you could have been saying something bad about him.
Rym: We couldn't tell it was metal.
Rym: It was blah blah blah blah blah Jesus blah blah Jesus blah.
Rym: Then he made a pose the main singer of someone being crucified and he was not being ironic About the fourth or fifth time.
Rym: He did that we started to suspect.
Rym: and then the last song they played was entitled yay God Uh-huh.
Rym: So yeah, there were Christian metal which independent of that They were pretty crappy.
Rym: all their songs sounded the same and the worst thing is the guy was dancing on stage.
Rym: It was as though he had read a book on how to dance on stage, but he did it technically very well.
Rym: But it just ended up looking really really stupid enforced and the crowd was basically just standing there ignoring him and he came over.
Rym: He's trying to like clap and get the crowd to clap and the people in the front are just kind of staring at him with This look of what the fuck you trying to get me to do.
Rym: At one point he starts singing right in the face of this girl Who's just looking at him like you've got to be kidding me.
Rym: and then he like puts his hand in her face like blah And she moves to bite him and he backs off like shit.
Scott: Yeah, it was a metal concert.
Rym: Yep, so, uh the band gets off the stage and another band plays Lazarus, which was fucking awesome.
Rym: And then another band plays.
Rym: they're kind of mediocre and before a fintroll I comes out.
Rym: the cool MC comes out and he has a few words to say.
Rym: I'm gonna paraphrase, but he basically says to us now apparently black star incorporated which is the crappy Christian metal band that played.
Rym: I Thought that I somehow Disrespected them by saying that they were in a metal band and the crowd starts to yell, but he says well I'll get into that I'll get to that.
Rym: So I have a message and I'd like to say a few words about black star Incorporated and how I may or may not have introduced them in a level of respect involved.
Rym: Fuck you black star Inc.
Rym: Fuck you goddamn pussies your music sucked.
Rym: You're one of the worst bands that has ever played at the chance and the fact that you I didn't disrespect you.
Rym: You're not a metal band and I warned the audience that the audience doesn't hate you because I told him you weren't metal.
Rym: the audience Hated you because you sucked ass.
Rym: I hope you're still here so you can leave in shame.
Rym: Fuck your parents.
Rym: Fuck your uncles and anyone who was here to see you.
Rym: So without further ado fintro It was Quite hilarious.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know a guy who runs a small place like that, you know He doesn't have anything to lose.
Rym: He doesn't answer to anyone.
Scott: He doesn't mean to lose by insulting some crap band that probably didn't bring.
Scott: no one came there to see black star incorporated.
Rym: I am NOT saying oh they sucked because they were Christian metal and all that does.
Rym: granted I never heard Christian rock.
Rym: that was good.
Rym: But if anyone can find me some I'll give it a go.
Rym: the band independently of being Christian metal was just really crappy.
Scott: Yeah, but think about it.
Scott: He knows the customers here.
Scott: That's the kind of thing to make the customers like him and come back.
Rym: I'll go back course.
Rym: I like the chance.
Rym: the two concerts.
Rym: I've been to there have been about what I expected kind of awesome.
Scott: It's how small places like that are.
Scott: they're all kind of cool.
Scott: if they're not kind of cool.
Scott: They're not around anymore.
Rym: Sadly, I forgot to bring jeans with me to work.
Rym: So when I took the train up to the concert, I ended up going to this metal concert wearing white pressed dress pants And black dress shoes.
Scott: Yeah That's one problem.
Scott: I always have at concerts is I want to be in the concert with nothing but jeans and a t-shirt, right?
Rym: But remember a tool.
Rym: they even took away your carabiner.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like that's all I want to have on me.
Scott: The problem is I got to have my keys to get back to my car possibly my wallet Maybe a ticket or something.
Scott: It's like I have to have this stuff because it's but there's nowhere to put it.
Scott: But I don't want to have it.
Scott: I just want to wear jeans and t-shirt nothing else.
Scott: It's very difficult.
Rym: Luckily Alex drove there drove to work as you know, we didn't want to take the train home late at night.
Rym: In fact, I think the last train would have been after the concert ended.
Rym: So I just left all my crap in his car.
Rym: I went in there with my wallet so that I could buy booze.
Scott: Yeah, and in my defense for not going I mean first of all, I was tired.
Rym: I mean, I had a whole day of shoe shopping and he was just exhausted.
Scott: It was a few people Frickin.
Scott: I got home.
Scott: I would have had to like leave immediately for the concert with no time at home and I had stuff to do.
Scott: and I was tired and I Heard seen fintral on YouTube and I was not so impressed.
Rym: So I was impressed.
Rym: I really liked fintral.
Rym: granted I'll admit I liked Lazarus more because they were very.
Rym: Lazarus was very much the kind of standard 80s early 90s metal that I really really liked.
Scott: Yeah But give it a choice between like driving like 20 minutes to Poughkeepsie staying there for hours and hours and hours driving 20 minutes back and going to bed at like 2 a.m.
Rym: Or Well to speak in Scott's defense - I was at a heavy metal concert and the band that played before fintral.
Rym: I fell asleep during it because I was so tired.
Rym: There you go Emily and I both just kind of fell asleep.
Rym: And then I realized the irony of that the next day.
Scott: I hope that the band as I awoke and everyone in the house is sleeping.
Rym: I just hope that the band that was playing didn't see me cuz that That would really have to be a kick in the balls if you're playing at a metal concert and you're on stage and there's some Dude, and a girl next to him asleep.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean seriously though I woke up like three hours before everyone else on Saturday and did a whole bunch of stuff.
Rym: Yeah, I was exhausted.
Rym: I do also want to say that I Have and so does Scott and most of us in the crew have semi expensive super awesome musicians earplugs that They reduce their not expensive like $14 compared to normal earplugs, which are like 50 cents.
Scott: Are they really?
Rym: Yeah, you can buy a sack of normal earplugs at Home Depot for like nothing.
Scott: Let's see how much they actually cost.
Scott: hold on who.
Scott: they have new versions for small ear canals.
Rym: Ah, well, you know we talked about isolation earbuds.
Rym: These are kind of the same thing But they're specifically made for playing in or being at concerts and that they reduce the volume overall like 10 20.
Rym: But how many deficit decibels you want?
Rym: but they do it evenly.
Rym: So if you wear it like normal foam orange earplugs, the music sounds kind of crappy.
Rym: but if you don't wear earplugs you do fantastic amounts of damage to your hearing in short order and by the time the band you actually went to see plays because they always play last your ears are fatigued and usually feel like Shit, unless you're already half deaf from going to concerts
Scott: They're $12.
Scott: and yeah going to just one concert without earplugs will do permanent damage to your hearing Period.
Rym: end of story and I've been to like three.
Scott: well, I guess if you want to like some classical music Maybe not, but it depends on the real close and there's a full orchestra or some fucking earplugs.
Scott: Yeah, in fact,
Rym: I'll even say I played in bands in high school not just hot like in the high school But I played trumpet and especially
Scott: they have hornet instruments
Rym: playing in a band Will fuck your hearing up pretty quickly and I do have a minor amount of hearing loss right about in the range where my trumpet was
Scott: it happens.
Rym: but The fact that several of our friends were at this concert without earplugs was quite disturbing to me to be honest Because I was wearing the super fancy head.
Scott: I wear earplugs in like dealers rooms at conventions.
Rym: Yes I start I wear earplugs on the train.
Rym: I wear earplugs on the subway a lot of times.
Rym: if I'm driving I'll wear them.
Scott: Yeah, well driving not so safe.
Rym: Well, it's okay because remember these aren't no sound at all.
Rym: These are all.
Rym: sound is attenuated by I think 15 decibels.
Scott: I think it's 20.
Scott: I forget you can get 30 decibel ones if you want, but the ones we have are 20.
Rym: You can also get like 5 decibel ones.
Scott: Yeah, those would be okay for driving.
Scott: You can pick the amount of attenuation you want Yeah, but the ones they sell the ones that I'm talking about are $12 in their 20s.
Rym: Yeah, they're totally worth it.
Rym: If you go to more than one concert in your life buy a pair of these.
Scott: Yeah, they come in a little thingy so you can carry them around with you.
Rym: The music will sound better because your ears won't get fatigued and you won't get a headache.
Rym: It's kind
Scott: of funny like if you go to a concert and they just start up like a metal concert especially where they start it up and if you let you try to listen is Right and you put the earplugs in and suddenly it sounds like their album is playing and you're like, oh man
Rym: It's so
Scott: awesome.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right, right news.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you got some news for us.
Scott: being Monday night I do as far as I'm concerned, right?
Scott: There are two types of personal computers for normal people in their houses home users.
Rym: not ten types.
Scott: No two types and two.
Scott: yes, the the two types are number one the completely normal computer for like your mom who wants to browse the web and do normal email and I am and normal stuff and then does the serious machine for someone who wants to Play games and Photoshop and edit videos.
Rym: I are serious cat and my computer are serious business.
Scott: Yes, there are two types of computers for home users at any one per moment in time.
Scott: There is a best Computer for the normal person and a best computer for the crazy person.
Scott: in terms of price.
Scott: I mean in terms of performance $10,000 is always the winner.
Scott: Yeah, but but in terms of price performance ratio there is always one sweet spot for each machine.
Scott: and until now the crat the normal computer for normal people in terms of a PC that you build has been an AMD machine because of and if you buy you can you can go out to Newegg and buy an Nvidia.
Scott: well, not the motherboard won't be made by Nvidia but a motherboard with Nvidia chips all over it.
Scott: that for like $100 contains a video card a sound card a network card Everything except pretty much the RAM the CPU and a hard drive.
Rym: now think about that.
Rym: If you have a computer that's just surfing the web and whatever that's everything you need except the actual processor and RAM.
Scott: Yeah, they have Nvidia because they make the n-force chips and all this other stuff.
Scott: The n-force chips is like a whole computer almost on two chips except for the CPU and RAM.
Rym: Yeah, and I mean a lot of people especially people our age who kind of grew up during the.
Rym: the only way to build a Usable computer is to build it yourself because there was a time when to make a powerful computer There's really the only way to make something that was reasonably priced.
Rym: yeah, if you the the common wisdom was onboard components are shit usually because of the Previous issues with that with the wind modems.
Scott: Yeah, and that's most.
Scott: wind modems like ISA modems.
Rym: Yeah, but like does that sort of thing?
Rym: like?
Rym: embedded components were crap embedded sound cards just were shitty and embedded video cards were slow.
Rym: but nowadays unless you're Podcasting or something an onboard sound card no matter who made it is more than enough and totally perfect.
Rym: You will not be able to hear this.
Scott: most.
Scott: 99% of people just need to hear stereo sound and an onboard sound card Will do that with no hit to your performance.
Rym: Yep sound card technology in terms of making the audio sound good For consumers has not other than fancy stuff like surround sound or whatever.
Rym: in terms of playing stereo audio Has not significantly improved in like eight years All right.
Scott: So, you know every other component is the same way.
Scott: most people just want to look at 2d imagery an onboard video card.
Scott: Does that now?
Scott: most people just want to get a network connection an onboard Nick.
Scott: does that now?
Scott: So what do you care if it's on board or not?
Scott: So the cheapest way to get a computer for like your mom to just browse the web was to get an nVidia n-force IGP which is see.
Scott: most n-forces don't have IGP which means you still need to go out and get a video card Separately and put it in your AGP or PCI Express x16 slot.
Scott: But if you get an IGP, there's a video card built in to your Northbridge, which is like well I don't have to buy a video card that saves you so much money.
Scott: I'm buying the computer.
Scott: You can't say no if you don't need 3d.
Scott: In fact, it does 3d, you know weak 3d pretty well.
Scott: You could probably play like half-life 1 with one of those things.
Rym: Oh, you could easily play.
Rym: the half-life 1 requires you get all.
Scott: you could definitely play quake 1 & 2 with.
Scott: you know You won't get like 60 FPS constantly, but you could play reasonably with one, right?
Scott: So the problem here for Intel has been that if you want to get an Intel Chip instead of an AMD chip and you don't want to spend a lot in the computer.
Scott: That's gonna be troublesome because you're gonna have to get some sort of Intel motherboard with an Intel video card on board and it.
Scott: You know, it's it's more expensive.
Scott: But Nvidia the news is this that Nvidia has said they're going to make an n-force chip with the IGP for Intel.
Scott: So now the cheapest and best computer for your mom might not be AMD.
Rym: when Nvidia gets this stuff rolling man Intel has just been wrecking AMD left and right.
Scott: I don't know because AMD is actually hitting back those.
Scott: there's like the new quad-core octoron.
Scott: things are supposedly like the shit.
Rym: Well, yeah But at the same time the next iteration of the core 2 and all those is supposedly going to be the same Super-efficient architecture but ramped up another gigahertz.
Rym: it could be.
Scott: but at the moment I think if I remember what people were saying you could get one of these like quad-core Octorons for like a few hundred dollars, which is like a ludicrous price for like the best chip out there.
Rym: Well the problem it's hard to say because Intel and AMD compete with each other but they compete with each other in two completely separate arenas the home user PC and the enterprise server Server PC.
Scott: There's also the laptop arena, which oh, yeah the third arena which Intel has been completely dominating.
Scott: Well in terms of consumers and PC's they also compete in other areas that you don't notice because you're just as far as you care About.
Rym: it's those three.
Rym: and well Intel almost always had the advantage on power consumption Which is why they always win the laptop or I mean Especially back in the day like in the AMD k7 era an AMD laptop was perhaps the most laughable idea in the world.
Scott: Yeah, pretty not so good granted.
Rym: They were cheap, but the battery lasted like five minutes.
Rym: Yep Alright, right.
Rym: So I find this very interesting and I guess it was kind of expected but according to this article on slashdot Linux is going to be installed at every single school in Russia by 2009 that they're generally trying to just give up on Windows and Outfit all their schools with PCs and servers and all the IT stuff they need running Linux.
Scott: Someone must actually be thinking about something there.
Rym: There's a lot of speculation both by me and people onto internet as to why this is the case and I think I'm just I'm not Gonna bother with the article I'm just gonna break it down as to why I think
Scott: someone in a position of power to make a decision was convinced by someone Intelligent.
Rym: Oh, yeah but I mean like actual direct reasons as in the cause and effects think of this.
Rym: that used to be that a lot of developing countries or even developed or mostly developed countries they used Windows because they just pirated it and Microsoft couldn't really do anything about it.
Rym: I mean Microsoft couldn't really tell Russia to stop Russians from pirating because they had no leverage.
Rym: the same thing with China and India and all these Countries, but as these countries become more and more quote-unquote Legitimate in the world marketplace and start competing like actually for serious, you know for real in the marketplace there are international agencies and regulations and law enforcement bodies and organizations that can Do bad things and trade sanctions and all that sort of thing to a country like Russia.
Rym: if they continue to allow software Piracy to happen and the more legitimate the economies of these countries get in terms of a modern international market the more pressure is on them to not allow piracy.
Rym: and Russia being somewhat smart must have realized that hey We were only using Windows because it was free.
Rym: now that we have to pay for it Why don't we just use Linux because it's free.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, that's obviously a logical thing But you know, who knows what actual?
Scott: well, there's more chronic process ended in this decision.
Rym: In Russia unlike in say the United States the government or whatever bodies control different arms of the government Have a lot more power to just say this is the way you're doing it.
Rym: Fuck you Yeah, so if someone higher up says alright Why don't we standardize the country on X?
Rym: because it'll be cheaper overall and we can standardize on support and blah blah blah blah.
Rym: They can just force people to.
Rym: but in America It's really hard to force companies or public institutions to do anything.
Scott: It sure is.
Rym: And in the end, I think this is gonna be a good thing because oh, there's no doubt about that.
Rym: what are the primary reasons that Windows has a large user base among nor like people who are into technology is just that It's the OS they used first.
Rym: because if you use any UI or any OS first That's gonna be the one you're comfortable with and a lot of people really don't understand their computer enough to be able to Understand that doing this in this operating system is analogous.
Rym: understand all the hackers come from Russia But if you start on Linux, you'll be more likely to use Linux.
Scott: Yes in general because I can't say that's why in the early days Apple pushed their Apple twos and their Macs into the school So heavily.
Scott: but you know and it was until later that you know Windows Dominated the business world that schools switched not because the the apples and the Macs were no good But because they realized that with the kids Using the apples and the Macs weren't being prepared to for the business world where Windows was the winner.
Scott: So that's you know, it eventually came down from the top, you know into the colleges and the high schools in the middle schools.
Scott: None of the elementary schools pushing out the apples yep, but originally it was the apples because Steve Jobs and they pushed it in there really hard knowing that was gonna help them.
Scott: and It kind of did.
Scott: I mean you have people who were in.
Scott: they were kids played the Oregon Trail on their apples and Nowadays, they're buying iPods and using their Mac books.
Rym: now I'm not gonna make the argument that Using Linux instead of Windows will make these kids better at using computers because it's really not the case.
Rym: What is gonna happen is they're just gonna be used to using Linux and most people no matter how educated they are Just are never going to understand exactly how their computers work.
Rym: They're going to understand how to make the computer they use do what they want to do.
Scott: though I do think that in Russia more a greater percentage of people understand because Russia seems to have a lot of a Larger or at least from my perspective, you know with my just my feel for my Hackers and those types in.
Rym: I would argue that the only reason that is true is because the laws are a lot more lax in Russia.
Rym: it could be easier to get away with that stuff.
Scott: It could be but you know Russia has all sorts of things coming out of it like the all of mp3s and such.
Rym: Well, that's again.
Rym: That's just because the copyright laws are different there.
Rym: How many people who are quote-unquote Russian hackers are actually u.s People just working with Russian people because they don't want to get caught.
Rym: It's hard to say it could be Of course granted.
Rym: maybe this kind of gray market black market culture has facilitated people.
Scott: You know when the kids are all wares in there they're learning to.
Scott: you know They go from script kitty to a kid.
Scott: you actually knows.
Rym: I guess you could have a point because I think back to when the US was still the wild wild west and Much of what I learned about computers.
Rym: I learned from being in that wares scene and trying to hack and crack and dollars.
Rym: Yep things of the day.
Rym: now last week.
Rym: I talked about Captain don't tase me bro, and how he totally deserved to be don't tase me bro.
Scott: Don't tase me bro.
Rym: Don't tase me, bro.
Rym: Well of course the internet responded and like the internet does there were a whole bunch of mashups.
Rym: I think there's one on dig that was just MC hammer dancing.
Rym: But every time you would have said can't touch this it cut to the guy saying don't tase me And things like that.
Scott: don't tase me.
Rym: of all of those there's one that stood out and I awarded the Lateral thinking mashup award of the week alrighty.
Rym: I don't think this will be a regular thing.
Rym: It is basically.
Rym: I mean you could just watch the video, but in case you don't want to it's just that scene from Star Wars Where the Emperor shocks the ever-living shit out of Luke and all it does is dub over Luke's dialogue with don't tase me, bro.
Rym: Don't tase me, bro.
Scott: Seriously Only now at the end.
Rym: do you want us to understand?
Rym: It's just it's too perfect.
Rym: I mean in general it seems like there's sort of this.
Rym: like people talk about lateral thinking and lateral thinking puzzles We're like how do you get out of the room if the doors are all locked and blah blah blah blah blah?
Rym: and the answer Is something weird kind of like a Buddhist riddle or a cone.
Scott: or how do you make a mashup at it?
Scott: Don't tase me, bro.
Scott: That'll make all the nerds laugh up Star Wars.
Scott: There's the one.
Rym: well It seems like internet people particularly Farkers and 4-channers.
Rym: There's all those different cultures on the internet.
Rym: There are connections between events that happen and various things in popular culture.
Rym: that and it's perfectly obvious To the internet person who thinks of it.
Rym: they see a video of a guy being tasered and the first thing they think is That's just like when the Emperor tasered Luke Make that mashup while normal people they don't think sideways like that that the thought wouldn't even cross their mind.
Scott: But if they see it they go oh shit.
Rym: I feel like YouTube and Fark and 4chan something awful in all these places internet culture.
Rym: They're kind of Fostering this environment where the lateral thinking is rewarded And I'm really curious to see how that is going to affect art and literature over the next decade.
Rym: I think it's actually going to be a significant movement Possibly in a bad direction.
Scott: Yeah, I think the problem though with lateral thinking is that forward thinking suffers.
Rym: That was that was very aptly put.
Rym: you get a golf clap.
Scott: all right all right.
Scott: So you know a rice paddy.
Scott: you ever seen a rice paddy?
Rym: You mean a place where rice is grown.
Scott: Yeah, you know.
Scott: you know how it's arranged like the rice is all in rows.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: Have you ever seen the actual rice plant?
Rym: I've seen pictures of them on like Wikipedia.
Scott: Yeah, what's it look like?
Rym: looks like a plant in water.
Scott: Yeah, so you know there's different kinds of rice, right?
Rym: Yeah, there's like jasmine rice and brown rice and various other rices.
Scott: Well.
Scott: Did you know that?
Rym: Honda civic yep?
Scott: Well, you know the red rice.
Scott: You know the leaves of the red rice plant.
Scott: they're sort of dark and the leaves of the normal rice plant.
Scott: They're sort of green.
Scott: So what if you are planting rice in these rows and you strategically place red rice and normal?
Scott: Green rice in such a way that From above your rice paddy looks like something because you have multiple colors to work with.
Rym: I think if someone did that That'd be pretty damn cool.
Rym: I wonder if anyone's uh done anything like that.
Scott: gee I wonder what all these pictures of people have done that are.
Scott: huh how interesting are these pictures from like?
Scott: Helicopters of rice patties with pictures on them.
Scott: They're actually like you think.
Scott: okay someone You know wrote something in the rice paddy or made a picture.
Scott: You know it'll be about the quality of say like a crop circle.
Scott: This is way better quality than you think it is.
Scott: rice is a small plant high resolution Imagery and lots and lots of like.
Scott: you know Bored Japanese people who got a lot of time on their hands to get it just right and they do it every year.
Scott: They've had practice, and they've got all season to wait for it to grow.
Scott: So they're not gonna screw it up when they plant it.
Rym: wow so uh a crappy somewhat poorly done crop circle.
Rym: Obviously no human technology could create that and it had to have been done by an advanced alien race.
Rym: yet Yet this high-resolution rice images piece of cake.
Scott: yes There's this high-resolution picture of like a geisha for that appears from the sky in a rice paddy, huh?
Scott: Yeah, yeah that made by aliens.
Scott: They came down with their laser guns and drew it in the rice In Japan by changing the colors of the leaves.
Rym: I just saw this one As a kid where there was like there was a crop circle and the crop circle expert was like see how these are bent.
Rym: There's no way you could do that without.
Scott: and then a guy took a stick in a rope and made the no not even then I saw the one with the stick in the rose like that.
Rym: But it was the guy as an expert and he just took our stock and he Bent it like bit right in front of the guy, and it looked exactly the same Yep, and the guy was like well different.
Scott: No the one I saw was like God.
Scott: they were like look see how though it's.
Scott: it's in a spiral right.
Scott: so the guy's like That is kind of strange.
Scott: It's in a spiral.
Scott: if something landed on it from above it would just been flattened straight down instead of in a spiral.
Scott: So it had to be some sort of spinning alien ship right.
Scott: so some other guy goes Uh-huh, and he takes a stick and a rope and he sort of holds on to the rope puts the stick under his foot And he walks.
Scott: he starts somewhere in the crop, and he just starts walking in a circle Crushing the corn with the stick on his foot, and it makes a spiral circle of crushed.
Rym: I think the moral is.
Scott: anyone who thinks crop circles are made by aliens is stupid Yep, yep, and anyone who thinks high-resolution rice paddy images are made by Now people in America Was only Japanese people could do.
Rym: I think the only logical conclusion of this is to make a rice paddy representation of a Honda Civic Thus blowing up the earth.
Scott: Sure, I think we need to make a rice paddy image of the Emperor shocking some guy The don't see our death star.
Scott: Go see go see rice paddy.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: No, we had to get.
Scott: no we just need a picture of a plain rice paddy, and then we need to Photoshop it.
Rym: Oh that could be but I'd rather have the permanence.
Rym: well not permanent I guess because the rice isn't gonna be there forever.
Rym: Yep, right.
Rym: so tonight I realize this is a topic a lot of people ask us about.
Rym: you know that they get some spyware on their machine or Something's wrong with their computer, and they ask us ribbon Scott.
Rym: How could I get rid of this virus now?
Rym: Can I not get viruses in the future?
Rym: and no one seems to understand?
Rym: What viruses and Trojans and all those things actually are?
Rym: and even worse people don't seem to like the answers we give?
Scott: no They don't seem to like the answers.
Scott: you want to talk about what they are first or it's like what.
Rym: yeah well, I think the purpose of this episode very specifically is to Prevent more people from emailing us the same questions over and over again.
Scott: all right cool all right.
Scott: so first question What is well?
Scott: I think the biggest see the problem is the definitions of words like virus and Trojan and malware and spyware.
Scott: Is that there's.
Scott: some of them are subsets of others.
Scott: some of them are not the same as others and there's quite a bit of.
Scott: It's not like big disagreements like everyone sort of generally agrees what they are, but there's not like this.
Scott: firm.
Scott: This means this.
Scott: this means that yeah, we're gonna give a broad Yeah, I'm gonna mostly give you what I think slightly combined with what Wikipedia thinks at the current moment in time.
Scott: So the first one I think the largest category it personally is malware.
Rym: Yes I mean people say oh spyware whatever where I think it all is classified as malware.
Scott: Yeah I mean malware.
Scott: mal is bad Latin root where software.
Scott: if you have some sort of software that is bad Be it spyware a virus a Trojan a worm.
Scott: It's all malware.
Scott: It's all bad Where simple is that okay?
Rym: I just couldn't help thinking like malware wolf Malware wolf Plus.
Scott: some lateral thinking you got going on.
Rym: believe that the word where originally was a root that meant man.
Rym: So theoretically malware could you?
Rym: you are very malware.
Rym: it could be like and Very bad, man, bro.
Scott: I'm trying to combine like and throw up and virus.
Scott: It's not working anyway.
Rym: So the next thing well that we should define malware very how I would define malware?
Rym: Just straight up.
Rym: I mean you obviously probably think oh, I know what malware is is any Code that is on a PC that does things that the owner of the PC would not Intend it or know about it doing.
Scott: yeah Anything that's bad anything you don't want yeah any.
Rym: I mean I consider DRM to be malware.
Scott: Oh, yeah, definitely Anything.
Scott: yep all right.
Scott: so a virus a virus.
Scott: I sort of say that like you know every Viruses is pretty much everything, but like spyware It's sort of like it's on it.
Scott: first thing about a virus that makes it different from say spyware Is that you didn't put it there.
Scott: it got put there on.
Scott: it doesn't announce its presence.
Scott: It's not like you see it.
Rym: Yeah viruses are the oldest form of this sort of thing.
Scott: yeah, a virus will be like you got an infected file and You you know it attached itself somewhere, and it's running and doing things without you knowing perhaps replicating itself.
Scott: in fact some people say it must replicate itself for it to be a virus and it spreads to other files and it infects.
Rym: I Wrote a few very weak viruses when I was in high school.
Rym: Yeah, mostly to steal documents from my friends.
Rym: Examples of viruses would be like that Michelangelo virus yep or form or the ogre oh the Monster.
Rym: that was a real virus Jabberwocky yep.
Rym: And a lot of them are really kind of benign and funny and a lot of them are really really bad like the ogre Which just encrypted your hard drive?
Scott: Yeah But it's basically a program.
Scott: That's probably doing something evil.
Scott: it spreads around from file to file generally and You didn't put it there.
Scott: it sort of crept in somehow usually maybe on a floppy disk or on a CD.
Scott: or you Downloaded something and it was infected or someone gave it to you who knows.
Scott: So a worm a worm is a little is kind of similar to a virus.
Scott: It's a little hidden thing.
Scott: You didn't even know it's there, and it's doing bad stuff, but worms specifically Replicate over the network, and you don't have to do anything.
Scott: if your computer Just plugged into a network a worm can just walk right in.
Scott: like what was that one that happened when you're on IT?
Scott: That was huge like the Natchez or the?
Rym: I don't even remember.
Rym: you know cuz.
Rym: it's not a concern to be anymore to be honest but it basically what.
Scott: the how the how that worm spread is.
Scott: Windows has security vulnerability in it and you could Send some packets to a Windows machine that was not patched.
Scott: And if you sent those packets to the Windows machine properly the Windows machine would open itself up Copy move some bits around on its hard drive and thus cause it to do some bad things as well as begin spreading this virus to other windows.
Rym: the worm to other windows machines is a big deal because Standard viruses and Trojans and things they can't really spread themselves.
Rym: an idiot has to spread them.
Rym: But a worm can get you without you doing anything.
Rym: you
Scott: could just have a computer brand new from Dell say right Windows installed Windows patched all the way and if there is a Vulnerability to some sort of worm on that you know in Windows at the current time And you just plug it into a network and another computer on that network is spreading the fire at the worm.
Scott: You got it.
Scott: It's on there, and now you're spreading the worm.
Scott: I mean a worm.
Scott: the thing is with a worm even if it doesn't do anything bad to your computer It takes up network bandwidth.
Scott: It's it's automatically bad No matter what.
Rym: well, and it's it'll probably eventually especially now with the current culture of hackers out there or crackers.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, is that you'll be spamming people with Viagra?
Scott: probably?
Scott: But yeah most worms just infect your computer And then they most worms and viruses and everything.
Scott: these days The vast majority of them try to turn your computer into a spam sending machine.
Scott: So all right I guess the other one we could talk about is a Trojan.
Scott: a Trojan a Trojan.
Scott: It's a lot like.
Scott: I don't know why I was saying Trojan Is a lot like well a Trojan horse from the Greek story of old where you know a wooden bunny is driven up.
Rym: You know you get an email From your mom's and sister's uncle's friends nephews cousin, and it says hey check out this funny flash video file Exe.
Rym: so you double click on it, and you see a funny flash video.
Rym: well that funny flash video executable was you know?
Rym: 400k of flash followed by four megabytes of malware.
Scott: Yeah, it's you know.
Scott: you go and someone gives you something or someone appears to be giving you something that Disguises itself as a picture or a video or a video game or something and you click on it, and you say yes Yes, yes, yes, yes, and you've just opened a horse and a whole bunch of Greeks jumped out and stabbed you
Rym: right.
Rym: But that's enough of that because we've talked about some of these things before.
Scott: I think that about covers.
Scott: El spyware is the only one left.
Scott: do we have to say something about?
Scott: yeah spyware is sort of.
Scott: you went there was it's this piece of software usually free and You went and you got it.
Scott: You knew what you were getting like.
Scott: hey.
Scott: I need a video player.
Scott: There's a video player.
Scott: I will download this video player and install it and sure enough it plays video.
Scott: Maybe not well, but it's a program that does what you thought like Bonsai buddy.
Scott: right it gives you a little funny bonsai buddy on your desktop, but in the meantime It's also looking at information on your computer and sending it to someone else far away So that they can make money off of you.
Rym: I mean Gator did whatever it claimed to do.
Scott: I don't even know I think it like helps you remember passwords.
Rym: Yeah, that's awesome.
Rym: The deal with these is that if you actually read all like what it tells you when you install it They don't pretend at all.
Rym: I mean It's like we are going to take your data and do this and this and this.
Scott: we're also probably gonna use your CPU cycles to Conduct evil business maybe and while it's shady you agreed to it.
Rym: you put it on there.
Scott: Yeah, some things don't say they're spyware like you know it's.
Rym: it's not obvious that it's by where you almost in that case You wouldn't call it spyware.
Rym: You just call it a virus straight up.
Scott: It's sort of difficult to always like to really accurately label like large groups of malware because you know There's there's two components to any malware, and that is the vector and what it is.
Scott: you know like you could have.
Scott: You know the worm has the network as the vector, but once it's installed It's kind of like a virus.
Scott: or you know spyware is like using a trojan vector But once it's installed you just installed software that had a trojan style vector of infection.
Rym: before we get to the next part Which I think is the part you all want to hear about I would like to say one thing and this is kind of important.
Rym: the plural of the word virus is viruses.
Scott: Really straight up.
Scott: There's fire.
Rym: I know it's not fire.
Scott: I I gotta look this up now.
Rym: I I am a hundred percent I'll bet you without.
Rym: well actually it's more complicated than that because the word virus Really doesn't have a plural and it never did because the original word.
Rym: I think it meant like Venom.
Scott: all right according to the Wikipedia in the English language the standard plural of virus is Viruses the most frequently occurring form of the plural and refers to both the biological virus and a computer virus.
Scott: well the less frequent Variations viri and viri are wrong because the word viri means like man or vitality are virtually unknown in edited prose and no major dictionary recognizes them as Alternative form.
Rym: the reason is if you I mean Latin had many more sort.
Rym: I'm not gonna get into this because it's complicated if you don't know about language at all.
Rym: But basically Latin had a lot more ways of writing words or declining words or Conjugating words things like that.
Rym: so you had a lot of different ways.
Rym: you could write the same word depending on the context It was being used and there were different rules depending on the root word as to how you pluralize things or past tense things like I made the phrase past tense.
Scott: Yeah, I like how alumnus becomes alumni.
Scott: so virus you think you would become Viri but no virus isn't the same route.
Scott: nope, but you know what sheep become sheep eye.
Rym: Yeah, basically the the plural is virus and this was drilled into my head.
Rym: This is a computer.
Rym: yeah viruses of virus.
Rym: This was drilled into my head by more than one professor at RIT Continuously, and it's kind of a pet peeve of mine.
Rym: and while you can argue about a lot of other words There is really no academic source in the world and no credible source in the world that pluralizes Viruses virus as viri.
Scott: Yeah, it's viruses.
Rym: So the.
Rym: the important thing about this episode is what we're gonna talk about next though.
Rym: Cuz this is what you want to hear and this is what people ask us the most.
Rym: It.
Rym: the second part of this is how do I get rid of them?
Scott: We're mostly gonna be repeating like one sentence over and over.
Rym: Yeah, first and foremost.
Rym: How do you protect yourself from viruses?
Rym: We're not gonna talk about the history.
Rym: We're not gonna talk about the past.
Rym: We're gonna talk about right now today.
Rym: How do you avoid viruses.
Scott: step one step one?
Scott: You need either a software firewall of some sort on your machine or Some sort of network level protection a NAT router Just a normal router that you buy at the store a linksys router.
Scott: if you plug it in and use it and it you get A connection by default it is protecting you.
Scott: You cannot get a worm if you are using a router Unless someone else in your house is spreading the worm.
Rym: Well, there is an exception to that.
Rym: if you use if you have that Plug-and-play whatever that automatically do not enable universal plug-in play.
Scott: Do not enable UP NP.
Scott: Do not turn that on.
Rym: Yes That is theoretically useful but what it actually does is let your computer if it gets compromised at all or if your router gets Compromised a virus or a worm could just open up your router and let stuff.
Scott: Yes See the purpose of UP NP, you know We always talk about port forwarding and how you have to kind of like figure out what ports to enable.
Scott: and kind of tricky UP NP does that automatically.
Scott: UP NP basically makes it so that let's say iTunes wants to open up a port so we can do Something.
Scott: it lets it be smart enough to do it on its own bit torrent actually uses UP NP.
Scott: And you said you don't have to do your MIT You don't have to figure out the port forwarding to be ready for most things.
Rym: You don't need to forward ports at all because the way NAT works Almost anything a normal person is going to do on a PC does not require port forwarding then that just works.
Scott: So don't enable UP NP unless you really know what you do and don't enable port forwarding unless you know what you're doing And why.
Scott: and then if you don't if you do those things and you have a router or software firewall like the zone alarm or something No one can get you with a worm unless they bring the worm into your house on like a laptop or something, right?
Rym: So you might say well Rym and Scott, that's well and good But how do I avoid getting spyware and malware and viruses and all everything else?
Rym: and the answer is and I can't stress this enough Don't use Internet Explorer which will say shield you already from like 80% of what's out there.
Rym: Yeah, and to don't click on shit if you don't know what it is.
Scott: Don't trust Anything.
Rym: if your mom if you don't file don't open it.
Scott: Yep, unless it's a picture if you are looking for like say an image editing program or something.
Scott: Maybe that's not.
Scott: that's a bad example.
Scott: Let's say you're looking for an mp3 playing program.
Scott: You just want to try a new one, right?
Scott: So you're going on to the internet and you find a new one.
Scott: unless you can confirm Without any doubts that it is not spyware Do not download it.
Scott: assume everything is spyware.
Scott: assume if you go on Pirate Bay and there's a pirated version of a game Assume that it's full of viruses.
Rym: until proven otherwise You know what?
Rym: The answer is it almost always is full of ours.
Scott: if you're going to download a movie on BitTorrent assume it's full of viruses.
Rym: Well, here's the thing that the real answer is do not execute Any file executable or not that you get from the internet from an untrusted source?
Rym: Some files don't need to be executed and because software is robust It's very difficult for looking at a JPEG file or looking at it.
Scott: But it's happened.
Scott: there were.
Rym: there were bugs with like Wmf files and there is stuff like that, but things like that are pretty rare and you can avoid 98% of viruses if you just don't run exe files or bin files or .scr files or .bat or .com files.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Luckily .bat you can just open it and look at what it's doing.
Scott: I know I know but most people won't understand it.
Scott: They'll open it up into the same gibberish They'll get if they open up an exe file.
Rym: Yeah, but - I mean if you go to a website and you are you're using ie.
Rym: There are a lot of exploits especially for pre 7 versions of ie Where you don't have to click on anything and you'll just be infected because you went to the website.
Scott: Yep Even so if you whenever you're browsing the web even with Firefox even with ie 7 even with opera Right and you go to a website and it says would you like to do something?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: No unless you are 1020% sure that you're at the absolute correct website and that you want to do what it is asking you to do And you know what it's about to do.
Scott: say no always Never say yes Unless you are a million percent sure.
Scott: because if you say yes And it's good as you start doing something evil and then you're done game over.
Rym: Yep, and that's it.
Rym: It's just don't use ie Have a net firewall don't go to shady sites and download things and then run them.
Scott: Yeah, don't go to shady websites period.
Scott: I mean someone said safe Google safe leak Dudes where's calm not safe.
Scott: Don't go there.
Rym: Don't do anything there Don't trust anything and if you're gonna go there at least use Firefox or something.
Rym: Hopefully don't don't.
Rym: not being on Windows is a huge help But even if you're on Windows You'll be reasonably safe if you use Firefox or the equivalent and you're generally canny about what you click and don't click on.
Scott: Yeah, if you are smart and you don't trust if you are Untrust giving enough and you are so good like me that you never install anything stupid You do not need an antivirus program.
Scott: they're just going to waste your system resources.
Scott: an Antivirus program can only help you if you're stupid and you try to install viruses And they will tell you yours.
Rym: they're useful if you gave this computer to your mom now.
Scott: That's also useful Yes, but if you are smart And you do not let shit get on your computer like I'm right I'm using Windows a lot lately to play Team Fortress 2 so I'm browsing the web on it And I'm.
Scott: I am and on it and stuff like that.
Scott: right no problems.
Scott: No Antivirus I'm behind in that router so worm can't get in and I don't.
Scott: I keep the computer up to date.
Scott: I always do all the windows updates on Black Tuesday, and I don't click on stupid shit.
Scott: And so far the computers like new.
Rym: as far as Windows is concerned Three viruses or malwares in my entire life.
Rym: The first one was the form virus that I got from a diskette that I borrowed from someone in Starbase when I was in middle School.
Rym: Wow and you know what.
Rym: and once I realized I had it I didn't get rid of it because it didn't do anything bad And I started collecting viruses as a result and somewhere.
Rym: I still have a bunch of floppy disks with old like DOS viruses.
Rym: Yeah, the second one.
Rym: I got was I don't remember, but I remember I got a virus at some point It was like in the early days of spyware.
Rym: and the third one.
Rym: I got was when I rebuilt this new computer I installed windows and downloaded a bunch of wares as a test.
Rym: I determined that every single piece of pirated software I downloaded contained viruses, and then I reformatted and reinstalled windows.
Scott: The only time I ever got a virus and knew about it was back in the in the days like I guess like 2002 3 ish when like the crazy worms are going around the internet fucking everything up.
Scott: Oh, yeah, not she and everything right?
Scott: Coincidentally at that time without even me thinking about it right we were at RIT.
Scott: obviously I rebuilt my computer because it was just that time.
Scott: you know I knew I was doing it.
Scott: so I reinstalled windows I connected to the network and I started doing windows updates pretty much immediately.
Rym: But the crazy worm was spreading around the network so fast between when Scott rebooted after installing windows and when he clicked windows update to get the patch.
Rym: he was already infected.
Scott: and then Like the next day RIT kicked me off the network as I was spreading the worm, and I was because RIT is smart.
Rym: It'll go too long for that.
Scott: I didn't even realize I had it.
Scott: It was so fast.
Scott: Yeah, there was no way I could have gotten it that fast.
Scott: No I got it that fast.
Rym: It's too much for this show, but in a future show some months from now We'll probably do one on like corporate security and corporate virus dealing because it's a total different ballgame in that world.
Rym: But yeah RIT is one of the few entities that is smart about it.
Scott: So if you're not dumb you're not thinking happen to your computer.
Scott: And if you are dumb you need an anti-virus to back you up when you're dumb But even then it's not gonna help you a hundred percent.
Scott: They're not perfect so and they're gonna make your computer slower and crappier.
Rym: the final question that we get all the time is Rym and Scott I was dumb and I got a virus or whatever.
Rym: How do I get rid of it and forget the past in the present the current state of the world?
Rym: The real answer is you cannot because due to root kits and the way modern viruses work Once a computer has ever been compromised you can never ever Trust that that computer is wholly free of compromises again for the rest of its life unless you reformat and reinstall.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you can trust it.
Scott: You know to do some things.
Scott: they can trust it to go to dig and to load dig properly But you can never a hundred percent trust that software on that machine ever again.
Scott: You can always.
Scott: you know it might be sending all your personal information out.
Scott: It might be key logging.
Scott: you have no idea.
Scott: There's no way to know.
Scott: I mean your spy bots and your you know ad-awares work Very poorly compared to the way they use your clam av.
Scott: you can clean the computer up to a certain degree Using tools, and if you're really lucky.
Scott: You know maybe you only got one little virus, and you happen to have a tool That's really good at getting rid of that virus, and it may it might make you perfectly clean But there's no way to know you're perfectly clean.
Scott: No way to know.
Rym: you can monitor your traffic for months and months and run all these things and if you see anything you Can prove.
Rym: yep?
Rym: I was still infected But you can never be sure about that computer again, so if you care about your data at all if you've ever been infected Back your shit up.
Rym: and when I say back your shit up.
Scott: I mean back up non executable files Yeah, back up your mp3s and your JPEGs and whatever and that's it back.
Scott: It looks like DVDs or something.
Rym: any Program on your computer is suspect for the rest of that computer's life.
Scott: until you reinstall and then even when you you know back Up all those files make sure that after you reinstall You know before touching any of those files you mount you sort of get them in on a read-only Basis and you scan them with every fucking scan thing.
Scott: you have to make sure that there's nothing attached to them.
Rym: because I see the answer Is reinstall.
Rym: that's the only way to know and I'm sad.
Rym: and that's it.
Rym: and in a corporate environment That's the only solution.
Scott: imaging yeah, if you're infected fuck you your computer's gone Yep, so if you actually something I recommend to to make it You know like I'm at the point where I do a lot of my stuff on the web I use Google for as much as possible.
Scott: You know it really.
Scott: it used to really matter like being at school on the school computer Sucked because all my stuff was on my computer at home on my hard drive.
Rym: You know I carried a zip disk around and I had my next Samba shares.
Rym: that worked most of the time.
Rym: It wasn't good enough nowadays.
Scott: do as much as you can on the web.
Scott: use a thumb drive.
Scott: You know have a laptop.
Scott: that helps, but you know and that way it doesn't really matter What computer you're at or what operating system?
Scott: It's running.
Scott: as long as you have a web browser and a connection to the internet.
Scott: It's like I'm at home almost no matter where I am.
Scott: I mean at home.
Scott: I'm still slightly more at home.
Rym: I mean theoretically if I go to any computer.
Rym: I've got steam.
Rym: I could just get all my steam games anywhere and play them.
Scott: Yeah, I mean like if I used to be like when I had to reformat was like God I have to reinstall all those applications.
Scott: now I I'm like using a clean install of Windows with Firefox And it's as good as me being in my Linux.
Rym: whatever my windows has all the windows updates the drivers for my shit Firefox the acrobat reader and steam and those are the only pieces of.
Rym: so I have audacity for backup emergency, but I've never used it.
Scott: Yeah, so if you sort of arrange yourself into a position where you are not reliant on Sort of desktop applications you can like.
Scott: I could like reformat the windows today, and it's so little effort because it It's no different.
Scott: It doesn't matter to me.
Scott: So if there's a virus and it's not gonna be a hassle for me to reformat because that's the kind of computing environment I use is one where it's not dependent on the operating system or very many local applications.
Scott: Reformatting is no problem.
Scott: so viruses who cares?
Scott: reformat end of story.
Scott: who cares also of course if you use Linux Or even Mac or anything that's not windows.
Scott: Yes, whatever.
Scott: You know people argue.
Scott: Oh less people use it.
Scott: That's why there's less viruses for it.
Scott: We're not even gonna touch on that are not even gonna make all those arguments.
Scott: those arguments could go on for two episodes.
Scott: The reality is if you use the other operating systems besides windows You can be stupider and also be much safer.
Rym: It is pretty much almost impossible to get some sort of spyware or virus short of downloading questionable code Which there isn't that much of and running it on your Linux box with root permission.
Rym: There is almost no way to compromise.
Rym: you could try to compromise your Linux box.
Rym: you'd have a little bit of trouble.
Rym: I mean you'd have to know what you were doing.
Scott: yeah, and even Vista.
Scott: You know it is a lot better than Windows XP.
Scott: It's pretty hard to get Vista to have bad stuff on it without saying yes.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yes Yes, when a bunch when the evil thing tries to do its bidding yep.
Rym: So if you're really worried about security and viruses and all that and you're not gonna switch to Linux or a Mac get Vista.
Rym: There's no reason not to and you'll thank yourself and just don't Anything.
Scott: don't trust anything.
Scott: every program that you aren't a hundred percent sure about is evil File.
Rym: don't open it until you have verified that it's me and even then think do I really trust that Rym character a hundred percent?
Rym: Would I trust him with the ability to see every single thing on my hard drive and find out that I'm into?
Rym: Furry scat porn yeah, or whatever you're into.
Scott: or would you trust him not to?
Scott: Download a bunch of furry scat porn onto your computer to frame you and not even do what?
Rym: would I trust him to fuck me?
Rym: You also have to think what I trust the person who is sending me this file To know enough about computers to not have been infected themselves and then be passing it on to me through stupidity.
Scott: trust Absolutely nobody and you will be safe, and you won't need to waste your stupid computers resources on Antiviruses.
Scott: you won't need to reformat so often.
Scott: you won't need to worry if you just don't trust shit.
Scott: Everyone is out to put evil things on your computer Everyone.
Rym: so all that aside we have announcement to make about the show and that Sometime in the next month or two we're not entirely sure when.
Scott: but oh good I totally forgot.
Rym: we're going to do something that we did a long time ago.
Rym: That was super awesome.
Rym: a lot of people liked it.
Rym: where we did a question show.
Rym: you all sent us your questions about us And we answered them honestly for about an hour and change and we're gonna do that again, but a little bit differently.
Rym: It's going to be per episode.
Rym: so if you have any questions about science technology Computers Linux anything at all related to technology and science Send it to us either by email or more importantly.
Rym: I'd rather you join the forum and post it there sometime tonight I'm gonna make a thread about it and sometime in the future.
Rym: We're once.
Rym: we have enough good questions We're going to do a Monday show.
Rym: that is nothing, but us answering your questions now.
Scott: Here are some guidelines.
Scott: cuz I'm gonna be honest with you I am NOT going to answer crappy questions.
Scott: a crappy question is basically as good as no question.
Scott: So here are some guidelines if you want your question to actually be answered on the show.
Scott: number one Make your question clear and concise.
Scott: I got to know what you're asking.
Scott: be able to give an answer.
Scott: Don't be like ramble ramble ramble ramble ramble, and then I don't know what you're asking.
Scott: Don't be I'm not even.
Scott: I'm not even gonna like.
Scott: try to figure it out.
Scott: I'm just not gonna answer.
Rym: don't be the don't tase me bro guy.
Scott: Yes Number two keep it kind of short.
Scott: if you write like an essay or the question at the end No, we don't want to hear what you have to say.
Scott: It's you want to hear what we have to say.
Rym: don't try to impress us with your four paragraphs of Linux knowledge.
Rym: before you ask Your question just ask the question.
Scott: keep it short because I have to read your question on the air And if your question is two sentences I'm a lot more likely to just read your question number.
Rym: the next if your question can be answered Trivially through Google and does not require Clarification beyond the first few links on Google don't ask we're not gonna answer.
Rym: You could have answered it well before we do this.
Scott: show yes, don't ask us something you can answer Yourselves or a question that is just a piece of information.
Scott: ask us something that requires You know.
Scott: like like a try to make them more like discussion topics then like don't ask What's the best thing?
Scott: Well, that's I guess a good discussion time.
Rym: Don't ask us.
Rym: How do I set up a lamp server?
Rym: Ask us I'm new to Linux.
Rym: Oh, how would I go about learning how to set up a lamp server?
Rym: There's a big difference.
Scott: Yeah, don't say what's the command to show me?
Scott: What files are in our directory?
Scott: ask?
Rym: What's the file?
Scott: Yeah, ask you know, what are some really clever commands, you know, cuz that's a discussion now.
Rym: These can also be personal questions related to science and technology or Monday night Pretty much.
Rym: the board is open and if you ask a smart question You're gonna get a smart answer or at least a sarcastic answer.
Scott: Yeah, and if you ask a bad question, we will ignore you.
Rym: Yes, it's not like.
Rym: oh if you ask a really dumb question We're gonna make fun of you.
Scott: We might make fun of you if it's if it's that kind of question.
Scott: So try to avoid that.
Rym: if you don't want All right Let me go to this way if your question smart will answer it.
Rym: if it's dumb will answer it snarkily.
Rym: if your question is lame We're not gonna answer it.
Scott: Yeah, so think about the questions you're sending in carefully and Send them in because we want quantity but quality isn't gonna.
Scott: you know quality quality is gonna get through the sieve.
Rym: I recommend that you go into the forums and read the thread where these questions are posted and don't duplicate questions.
Rym: And also if you if you post them publicly like that You're gonna get a lot more Discussion and maybe follow on questions before we get around to answering them and you might get a lot more interesting Discussion as a result.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right, just so people, you know Don't like try to avoid doing this.
Scott: if you know the forum goes and answers your question You know because you post a question in the forum like tomorrow and then people start answering it in like another thread or something.
Scott: If it's still a good question, we'll still answer it on the show Feeling we're gonna need all the good questions we can get to fill out an hour.
Rym: Yes, plus as rockin as our forums are you're a very small minority of the listenership.
Rym: Yep by the same token This is a good chance as you haven't joined our forums to join them because I got to admit I hang out in my own Forum something.
Rym: I never thought I would do in my whole life.
Scott: Yeah, I thought I might do that one day.
Rym: Well, but our forms are actually cool.
Rym: Even if I wasn't doing the show I would hang out there.
Rym: and I'm not just saying that This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.