Scott: It's Tuesday, May 1st.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we review an awesome board game called Vinci.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So since I was in Rochester for the weekend I did get a chance to go to millennium games the pretty much undisputedly best gaming store in the United States.
Scott: There might be a better gaming store somewhere.
Scott: I mean like I went to the complete strategist in New York City and Sure, they have more games total.
Scott: I guess.
Scott: and the games they have?
Scott: they have more copies of them than millennium does.
Scott: But really millennium is a better store overall.
Scott: They have a wider variety of types of games And they have a gaming
Rym: store that is full of people from when it opens early in the morning until when it closes late at Night every single day no matter what and it
Scott: only sells games not like the local dragon's den, which is okay But it's also a comic book store and a video game store and an airsoft store And an everything geeky store whereas millennium is just a gaming store and nothing else.
Rym: well I was there and of course every time I go to Rochester I buy board games because while I can buy them online buying them at millennium is always the best deal.
Rym: There's no shipping.
Rym: It's just perfect.
Rym: plus the people there know a lot about games.
Rym: if I walk up and say hey How's such-and-such they know everything about it?
Scott: Yep also buying board games in person is Especially if you've never played the game before.
Scott: it's sort of a must.
Scott: you don't buy a game You've never played or looked at before on the internet.
Scott: Just looking at pictures on board game geek That's not enough to decide.
Scott: you either have to play it and then buy it online or read the rules And then buy it on or something.
Scott: But if you're in person with the game in a box You can tell from the box and from board game geek with you know you can tell if that's something you're worth buying right now.
Rym: Well I did pick up.
Rym: it costs a lot.
Rym: it was 60 bucks.
Rym: I hope it's worth it, but I figure I would pay a lot of money for a good two-player game.
Rym: Yeah, you might have heard about our troubles of finding two-player games that don't suck after off.
Scott: hellis hell It's the worst game.
Rym: It wasn't the worst game.
Rym: I played.
Scott: what worst game.
Scott: if you play I can think of a few.
Rym: Candyland's pretty bad Monopoly's pretty bad.
Scott: Oh that the unspeakable game for the Gamecube.
Rym: Oh that one.
Rym: yeah that one, but yeah I got Twilight struggle which is a really different kind of game from the kind of games We normally play and I'm not gonna get in any detail.
Rym: We're gonna review it once we've played it which might be a while because it's a complicated game.
Rym: Yeah, it's basically an abstracted historical pseudo-simulation of the entirety of the Cold War.
Scott: yep.
Scott: however whereas other games You know lean more towards the simulation of history this game goes that way, but it leans back never.
Scott: It never abandons its gameness, and it's also a card war game as opposed to a miniatures war game.
Rym: So it's basically an asymmetric card based war game for two players.
Scott: Yep, and there are apparently a lot of games like this, but according to everyone who likes these kind of games This is the one.
Rym: yes partly Because it doesn't take eight hours to play like some of the other ones do.
Scott: yep if this one is good I'll buy Shifting Sands, which is a similar game in the way It works.
Rym: also I got to say the cover art sold me on it even if I didn't know anything about this game.
Rym: the cover art just so Perfectly says everything this game is about.
Scott: I think the only if this game lives up to my expectation.
Scott: I think the only disappointment will be that it's only a two-player game Because it's the kind of game like yes.
Scott: We have a two-player game.
Scott: No.
Scott: It's only two-player, and it's so great.
Scott: Why can't we enjoy it with more than two?
Scott: the one cool thing?
Rym: I want to point out though is that it's a game that involves the Cold War.
Rym: you know the possibility of nuclear war.
Rym: Anytime there's a game that involves nuclear war there's always the point at which all the nukes get launched, and it's awesome like civilization.
Scott: Yeah, I got the nukes nuke nuke nuke nuke nuke nuke nuke nuke.
Rym: yep, or I've got the nukes.
Rym: There's a bug in the game.
Rym: I now have a thousand fortified nukes sitting off the coast of Europe Just waiting for Russia to start.
Scott: shit yep.
Rym: But in this game There's DEFCON levels and all that.
Scott: if you reach DEFCON 1 and nuclear war breaks out pretty much Which is guaranteed at you have found one.
Rym: the game ends and whoever started the nuclear war loses regardless.
Scott: It's not whoever started.
Scott: no new whoever causes the nuclear.
Rym: well.
Scott: That's not what the rule is.
Scott: I read the rest.
Scott: It is actually if it's your turn and the nuclear war starts, so let's say I yes however the way events work.
Rym: If it's your events then it's now effectively your turn.
Scott: while it happens however let's say I do something and You have a decision whether to you know nuclear war should start or not because it rests some based on some other factor whether the DEFCON level will decrease.
Scott: then you might force it to decrease because you know it's my turn and Then nuclear war breaks.
Rym: from what I read any case where you can force it to decrease would almost every time if not every single Time be when you were phasing and then you would lose.
Scott: well I don't know.
Scott: we're gonna have to play this game a few times to get all the but think it's not like other games where Nuclear war is the end like you're waiting for it.
Rym: you expect it.
Rym: It's the fun part of the game.
Rym: It's nuclear war and to be avoided is the end of the game.
Scott: cuz you failed you lost the cold And that's only one of the ends of the game.
Scott: all the other ends of the game are much more preferable.
Rym: However, I'm thinking what we should do is every time we play this game if there's a nuclear war we should just play DEFCON And then declare we gotta wait for new PCs to play DEFCON any day any day, I think tonight's the night.
Rym: I think I've hammered out all of my long-standing issues with buying a new computer.
Scott: Well, we'll see.
Rym: but in actual news Nintendo's been doing pretty well with this whole Wii thing.
Scott: Yeah, that's kind of weird.
Scott: They've been doing so well, but they haven't been selling any games have they?
Scott: well I mean they sold five hundred thousand pokemons, but other than that not too many games.
Rym: Nintendo hasn't been making very many games And I think the reason is they haven't needed to.
Rym: because in the previous year the fiscal year Nintendo's profits Profits operating profit not revenue not but straight-up profit jumped a hundred and fifty percent and they made almost one Trillion yen, that's like eight billion US dollars.
Scott: It's still not Bill Gates level of money, but that's pretty big money.
Rym: Remember that's profits.
Rym: their revenues are insane.
Scott: Yeah, it's kind of sad.
Scott: It's like, you know the company Above and be all other things is trying to make profit, right?
Scott: But they're also a company that makes entertainment for people and the people like the entertainment the company produces.
Scott: But if the company is profiting they will see less and less reason to take risks and make more interesting Entertainment for the people.
Scott: so in a way Them profiting is good for us because they will still be around to make more entertainment.
Scott: Oh, but it's bad because they're not making enough.
Rym: I have to make a little Clarification because I'm actually looking at a different article from what I read before and the other article was a little confused.
Rym: They made a trillion or a trillion yen in revenue and they made 226 billion yen in profit.
Rym: Uh-huh, which is still a lot.
Scott: That's still a lot of fucking money Yeah, and they've sold to date.
Rym: Well in the last year alone 23 million DS units and 123 million software units.
Scott: Yeah, see I can only think that like if they weren't profiting they'd be gone.
Scott: There wouldn't be any Nintendo action, right?
Scott: But if they were profiting just a little bit, all right or just enough but not crazily like they are profiting then They'd be putting out all kinds of awesome games to try to make more money.
Scott: But now because the profits are crazy, we're gonna see a game trout for about a year.
Rym: But they sold just shy of six million wheeze and they expect to sell Another 14 million next year.
Scott: They've sold at least a million pokemons.
Scott: I mean they pre-ordered half a million pokemons.
Scott: Yeah, like a quarter million pokemons in the US alone not counting the Japanese pokemons and that's just one game one game Good God, well for the current fiscal year the company has forecast sales of 22 million more DS's and 130 million more.
Scott: they think it's all 22 million more DS's than have already been sold in this fiscal year alone.
Scott: Oh my god All right.
Scott: If anyone is still has their doubts about the DS being the king and the we just being kind of air for the year to come You're wrong.
Rym: So despite the fact that Nintendo has made these record profits and these record revenues in these record sales They're predicting a better fiscal year next year.
Rym: They're predicting sales to increase Increasingly, you know why?
Scott: because they'll actually have some goddamn games next year to freakin sell.
Rym: Well, the thing is the Wii is still selling pretty much on the virtue of we bowling.
Scott: Yep That's pretty much all.
Scott: it sell it All right now.
Scott: and Zelda and Zelda and Zelda.
Rym: But I think now anyone who wanted like was buying a Wii for Zelda has a Wii and I think most of the people who?
Rym: Are buying wheeze are those you know non gamers who?
Rym: Wii Sports is amazing and they want to get it and it's cheap and it's cool.
Rym: And now they're suddenly into gaming and they'll be satisfied for a long time.
Scott: Yes, it seems like a lot of people are like really happy with their virtual console action.
Scott: I'm like virtual who's a lot of people are dumb enough to buy all those things mean virtual console money reportedly has gone down But there's still.
Scott: it's still crazy high.
Scott: how many people are buying those games?
Rym: Well because the it's almost a hundred percent profit.
Rym: you already own the property.
Scott: It doesn't take much to pour higher to college-aged cheapo Programmers to make sure the game works in the emulator on the Wii and then you put it up on the website And you know what.
Rym: considering that they know exactly how the Nintendo worked I don't think it was hard for them to make a Nintendo emulator.
Rym: That was perfect.
Scott: I'm pretty sure they already had some lying around because most you know when you play like a GameCube game like for example sonic mega collection.
Scott: right sonic mega collection for the GameCube is Basically a bunch of Sonic the Hedgehog games one two three spin ball Sonic and Knuckles etc.
Scott: and it's on a GameCube disc.
Scott: You know what's on that disc?
Scott: Basically the ROMs of those Sonic games and a Genesis emulator.
Scott: That's what's on that disc.
Scott: like Midway arcade classics to the head rampart was basically maim on the disc with a rampart ROM.
Scott: That's all those things are.
Scott: so it's not too hard to put the emulator in this console and then Download the ROMs.
Rym: all right, there's a lot of numbers here, and it doesn't even matter.
Rym: so don't even worry about the numbers.
Rym: I said because the point is Nintendo is doing so stupidly well that they could just cancel the Wii.
Rym: right now They could just say all right.
Rym: We's done.
Rym: No more games, and they still made out like bandits.
Scott: Yep all right, so Speaking of consoles the Xbox 360. you know that elite thing that they came out with.
Scott: it's the basically the best Xbox elite.
Scott: it has a bigger hard drive it has a HDMI hole right and it's black.
Scott: Apparently, it's not so hot.
Scott: it costs more than the premium.
Scott: It does have a bigger hard drive, and it is black.
Scott: the HDMI According to reports of people just you know subjective You know just people saying what they're all opinion.
Scott: Well, you should actually say some guy on the internet says some guy on the internet says the HDMI doesn't look any better than the Not HDMI on the premium.
Scott: this thing Is not the greatest buy because it doesn't really offer you anything above the premium Xbox 360 other than increased cost Black plastic and a bigger hard drive, but the black plastic yeah.
Scott: I know well if the bigger hard drive is enough for you.
Scott: if the smaller hard drive of the premium was keeping you down And you've got money to burn you really play your Xbox a lot.
Scott: you buy the elite and you use the HDMI Which doesn't offer anything.
Scott: you buy this thing.
Scott: well now you got to take all your data from your old Xbox hard drive and move It to the new Xbox hard drive.
Scott: You can't just take the old Xbox hard drive out and put it in the new Xbox.
Rym: that would kind of defeat the point of Having the bigger hard drive.
Scott: well not only that but you know it does your old hard drive.
Scott: It's not encased in the black plastic.
Scott: It's white, so it's not gonna look too good.
Scott: ah Not only that but all this stuff on your Xbox hard drive is DRM to hell.
Scott: They can't just let you just copy it from one drive to another.
Rym: Drm everybody's friend.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it would be easy enough.
Scott: I mean it's a USB hard drive.
Scott: I'm pretty sure you could just plug it into your computer and copy all the data from one drive to another.
Scott: But this DRM.
Scott: so that wouldn't work because you can't copy data.
Scott: if you copy it then the DRM locks in and now nothing works.
Scott: So if you buy an Xbox 360 elite if you want to transfer your data from your old hard drive to your new hard drive You have to get the Xbox 360 data migration kit.
Rym: I like how they say if you want like there are people who don't want to yep
Scott: to get the kit you have to print out a PDF Fill it out with all sorts of numbers from like you know I guess your serial number of your Xbox 360s and stuff like that.
Scott: mail it to Indiana.
Scott: They will decide if you should receive a kit or not.
Scott: I assume they probably will most of the time and then they will mail you your kit for free.
Scott: at least It's free.
Rym: decide if I need a kid or not.
Scott: yeah, huh?
Scott: So Just to let you know if you're thinking about replacing your premium with an elite Which is a stupid waste of money which it wouldn't be a waste of money if the elite at least had Wi-Fi or something But it doesn't even have that it has nothing.
Scott: basically.
Scott: Then you're gonna need to fill out this form and mail it because it says on the form.
Scott: That's a limited time offer.
Scott: It's subject to product availability and subject to change without notice.
Scott: So this offer might not last very long.
Scott: if you wait too long to buy your elite You might be SOL.
Scott: you might have to pay some money to get the kit or they might not have make kits anymore And you'll have to buy one on eBay from someone for any ludicrous price or who knows.
Scott: Just to let you know you people there with your DRM's and your 360 things of the day.
Rym: For the last several weeks I've been really trying to have things today that aren't just on dig and I've realized now that That is basically becoming impossible because one either Everything good is already on day I mean anything that is on dig and gets near the top is probably a candidate for being thing of the day Especially if it's a video because that's already like the top 1% of the internet.
Rym: But to
Scott: any
Rym: time I put forth all the effort to find something out there that didn't make it to dig yet It makes it to dig
Scott: Long
Rym: before I get a chance to use it as a thing of the day Thus defeating the point of finding it ahead of time.
Scott: Yeah I mean a lot of the stuff I find something in the morning to use as a thing of the day that night It's gonna be on dig sometime during the day.
Scott: There's there's no way around it.
Scott: And if I find something right before the show by the time you listen to the show You'll see it on dig the next day.
Scott: So unless I make the show I find a thing of the day.
Scott: unless the thing of the day Appears on the internet at like 9 p.m.
Scott: I put it in the show and then you listen at midnight.
Scott: even then 5050 shot it's gonna be on dig.
Scott: So what can we do about it?
Rym: Thus?
Rym: I'm not even gonna try anymore.
Rym: I just I'm gonna use whatever I saw like the original theme of you know things of the day The coolest thing I saw in the last 24 hours.
Scott: Yeah, whatever it happens to be.
Scott: We don't care where it comes from.
Scott: if it ends up being shit on dig that everyone's seen It's too bad.
Scott: That's what we're doing.
Rym: Yeah because you know what.
Rym: now think of it this way the three of you who complained that all of our news and things of the Day are just farks slash dot dig one.
Rym: We don't provide news.
Rym: We provide commentary on news so you can die in a fire.
Rym: See even though you might have already seen the video of the guy getting hit in the nuts or the other guy getting hit in The nuts or the guy falling and then getting hit in the nuts We provide commentary on the video of the guy getting hit in the nuts.
Scott: Oh, man I totally didn't see that that guy was gonna get hit in the nuts.
Scott: That was probably the worst hit in the nuts I've ever seen.
Scott: I mean you think the testicle like went right back up to where?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Oh, but look at the video it links to at the related videos that guy gets hit in the nuts twice.
Rym: Oh Now that aside my thing of the day I had something else like I often do and then I saw this and I thought I was gonna click on it.
Rym: Decide wow, that guy's crazy.
Rym: not even bother talking about it and move on.
Rym: It's a long video - it's about eight minutes.
Rym: But I'd recommend you watch the whole thing and it's kind of complicated how I feel about this video.
Scott: Basically.
Rym: It's a crazy guy.
Scott: It's definitely a crazy guy there is no doubt about it.
Scott: this guy that crazy like remember the pedophile in Australia Oh god, no, no, not that crazy, but he's definitely a crazy middle-of-the-woods guy.
Rym: He's lucid in the very least and he is intelligent.
Rym: He reminds me a lot of the people who form the Michigan militia and live in the wilds of Michigan Just waiting for the day when they can rise up and restore patriotism and the Constitution.
Scott: Reminds me just like the crazy old man who lives down the road.
Scott: He yells at kids to get off his lawn.
Scott: That's pretty much what he is.
Rym: Well, I knew a lot of people like that in Michigan.
Rym: We're just like this guy, you know get off my property get off my property Constitution.
Rym: But the guy definitely rants in that little bit out of it.
Rym: probably really was trying to hide something kind of person.
Scott: Yeah, I'm I'm betting 90%.
Scott: he's hiding something.
Rym: I wouldn't be surprised.
Rym: if the follow-up to this is yeah They got a court order and bodies as far as the eye can see brass murder.
Scott: It could be it very well could be but that's not the point.
Rym: but the situation.
Rym: Then the reason I find it so interesting is that there are three actors in this situation actor number one the main character the Unseen voice behind the camera the crazy guy basically a crazy middle-of-the-woods guy who they was on my property.
Rym: I has my rights.
Rym: that kind of person Yep, the kind of person who knows and has memorized every law that will ever help them get away with something shady.
Rym: Actor number two the stupid police officer who's not entirely stupid, but he spends most of the video mouth-breathing Obviously not fully understanding what's going on and obviously not wanting to be involved.
Rym: Yep, and then actor number three the angry frustrated and yet somewhat not understanding possibly of the law Federal or state bureaucrat whatever.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: She's some health inspector lady of some sort.
Scott: She's trying to inspect this guy's property.
Scott: She tried to inspect the property before and he didn't let her on the property because doesn't have to.
Rym: Now the situation is basically that she'd come and tried to inspect his property and she said I'm from the government You have to let me on.
Rym: and the guy who obviously knows his rights said, where's your warrants?
Rym: Yep Where's your court order?
Rym: Where's some sort of document?
Scott: while he's a crazy guy probably hiding something.
Scott: He's right Crazy guys aren't always wrong.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the woman didn't have a court order or anything.
Rym: So unless there's some crazy law in this state that allows this or something We don't know about and if there is such a law, it's probably an unconstitutional law.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: We don't really know.
Rym: No, but the point is that this woman didn't seem to have any sort of backing on her side.
Scott: I mean the guy is like could have been like imagine if some state health inspector Right has the state health inspector badge like our friend Pete, right?
Scott: What if they just show up at your house?
Scott: Like how do they know she's even on the job?
Scott: This is even assignment.
Scott: She could just be someone who has the job of inspector with a badge using it to sneak onto your property.
Rym: Well, actually when I worked for the feds back in hot like right after high school my first job I had it wasn't a metal badge but I had a badge that said that I was a federal employee and blah blah blah and I Totally could have scammed people into letting me do so.
Rym: all sorts of things with that.
Rym: Yeah, I was a jackass.
Scott: Yeah, so without a warrant or something I don't think that he should have to let her on his property no matter how crazy or nutty he is.
Rym: I wouldn't have let her on my property.
Rym: I also would not have little thing is if she had come back with an argument along the lines of like Here's the law that says I have the right to come on your property.
Rym: It is a section blah, whatever.
Scott: Oh, here's a court order signed by a judge.
Scott: Here's a warrant for searching.
Rym: then I would have let him on and this.
Rym: This guy probably would have to yeah, or he would have gone nuts with the shotgun, but we're not sure I don't know because he didn't go nuts of the shotgun in the video.
Scott: So I don't think he was ever gonna go nuts of the shotgun.
Scott: He was going nuts of the video camera, which is pretty good because that means he's not that crazy.
Scott: But the.
Rym: basically the woman is saying I'm allowed to be here I'm allowed to trespass and look at your shit and the guys saying according to this specific law that I've memorized and this part of the Indiana State Constitution that I also have memorized
Scott: and the federal Constitution of the United States of America, you do
Rym: not have this right.
Scott: you do not.
Rym: and the police officer is trying to convince the guy.
Rym: the police officer seems to know that He doesn't have the right because one the cop is smart and dumb at the same time.
Rym: I point out that the cop very pointedly does not step on the guy's property.
Scott: Yes You might not realize but in most states The there is like a certain number of feet varying by town or state.
Scott: wherever you live in from the street That is not your property.
Scott: For example, for example, my parents house, right?
Scott: Their house borders Street.
Scott: their driveway touches the street.
Scott: the grass that is within 10 feet of that Street belongs to the town.
Scott: so at one point in time there was a tree on that part of the Property that was dead and gonna fall over.
Scott: the town had to cut it down for free because it was on the town's property.
Scott: However, if the town decides to make the street wider not much my parents can do about it.
Scott: Also, my parents are responsible for mowing that grass.
Scott: You can't just not mow it or else the town comes and yells at you for not maintaining the property.
Rym: Yep I knew a lot of people who had property where they basically have a gigantic yard But half of the yard was in a federal or a state easement and the deal was basically they get to use the property do Whatever they want with it and a lot of cases they could even fence it in.
Rym: They just weren't allowed to build anything on it.
Rym: And if they did that's fine that your mailbox can go there But the state could tear it down if they ever wanted to.
Rym: yep, and my grandparents had a. it was a military thing.
Rym: Cuz there's a military base nearby Where the government could at any time if they wanted to it was already in all the deeds and all the land Build a road that went between all these houses where they lived.
Scott: Yeah, so this cop despite saying a lot of stupid things.
Rym: He doesn't leave the easement and he is very smart Yes, and the woman seems to be like well you gonna help me and the cops like you're on your own lady.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I'm not like.
Rym: I'm not gonna stop you, but I'm not gonna.
Rym: But the thing is the cop keeps trying to convince the guy with the argument of if you got nothing to hide Just let her in.
Rym: cuz you got nothing to hide.
Rym: and while the guy's crazy.
Rym: He responds to that aptly.
Rym: Yeah, and we don't need to talk about this anymore.
Rym: Just watch the video.
Rym: It's kind of fascinating because the interaction of the stupid cop the woman who didn't have all her papers in order and the crazy yet Lucid freedom guy is really this intricate dance that probably is going to end in some sort of fun follow-up on FARC.
Scott: Yeah It's just so weird to watch something with a crazy guy and I'm usually would be against the crazy guy and this health inspector lady.
Scott: I imagine she is inspecting something and it's probably a violation and I would want that violation.
Scott: Yeah, cuz the guys like guys obviously up to no good.
Rym: I'm just moving dirt around.
Rym: I'm just moving dirt around and I keep thinking yep mass graves.
Scott: Yeah, this guy's doing something bad on his property and this lady's gonna find out and get him and that's what she should do.
Scott: but at the same time You can't go on the dude's property without a warrant.
Rym: plus this hell.
Rym: how smart is this guy?
Rym: He makes a point of getting them to present their badges and names and he refers to the officer by name.
Scott: Yeah pointedly so it's all recorded and he's got the comes out with a video camera.
Scott: He's he's he's not like.
Scott: it's not even like one of those low-res and he's pointing the camera in the wrong place.
Scott: videos It's like he's got everything that you need to see covered.
Rym: You mean like all those videos of.
Rym: oh, I captured a video of a UFO.
Scott: Yeah, I imagine that his video is gonna hold up in court and all those pictures that the health inspector lady took are not going To be allowed to be submitted as evidence.
Scott: So that's just my guess as a non lawyer.
Rym: Well, we have a lot of lawyer listeners.
Scott: So if any of you lawyer listeners are also residents of Indiana If you can shed some light on this or you know Look it up in your law database what the law is in Indiana for health inspectors coming on your property.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I kind of side with the crazy guy just because I Mean the cops.
Rym: I was like just be polite and the guy makes a point of I don't have to be polite.
Scott: Yeah, I mean he starts out a little bit polite, but then you know, he's he's sort of crazy.
Scott: So he's as polite as a crazy guy can be I imagine.
Rym: Yeah, he's less crazy than a lot of people I've seen in the Bronx every day.
Scott: Yep All right, so my thing of the day.
Scott: I have for you a video game.
Scott: Would you believe that a whole video game?
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: In fact, it's a free video game.
Scott: You could download and play.
Rym: Oh, where's that?
Scott: No, I tried to play it in wine.
Scott: It didn't work.
Scott: So if you got windows you can play this.
Scott: I Rebooted to play it and I'm glad I rebooted to play it.
Scott: I actually rebooted to play it like a couple weeks ago and I forgot about it.
Scott: The game is called acid bomb to Rearm.
Rym: Was there an acid bomb?
Rym: one?
Scott: there probably was I think there was.
Rym: I mean It's like when I was a kid and we always saw Street Fighter 2.
Rym: No one really had ever seen Street Fighter 1.
Rym: So as far as we were concerned there never was one.
Rym: It just started with two.
Scott: Well, there was.
Scott: you've seen it.
Rym: I know I've seen it now.
Rym: In fact, we you ran a tournament.
Scott: I did anyway as there was an acid bomb one that I never played and I know nothing about acid bomb 2 is It's an independent kind of fun unique sort of video game and that it combines pycross and minesweeper.
Scott: Basically, you have this grid right and some of the squares on the grid might have bombs and the rest are just blank.
Scott: You don't care about them, right?
Scott: So there's some weird shape and you have a crosshair and the crosshair is a vertical bar that's completely across the whole top straight from top to bottom of the whole map and Left and right from all the way to the left all the way to the right and you can aim it at any square You want.
Scott: let's say you aim it at the top left square, right?
Scott: Now that's going to obviously cover the up and down row that is on the left and the horizontal row that is on the top.
Scott: the game will tell you a number the number of bombs that are covered by the widths and lengths of this crosshair and You move the crosshair around watching that number change as you move it and you have to figure out where the bombs are.
Scott: Aha, it was actually really fun and they threw in a lot of curveballs and a lot of different sort of levels.
Scott: Like there were biological levels and there were.
Scott: there were levels.
Scott: like you you you know a minesweeper.
Scott: You can put a flag to say this is not a bomb.
Scott: This is safe.
Scott: There are levels so they don't let you do that.
Scott: There are levels where like more bombs will appear if you wait too long.
Scott: There are all kinds of cool things and the game started out easy and fun.
Scott: It quickly got more challenging and I got like 80% of the way to the end and then I stopped.
Scott: But if you have windows and you have a free half hour You should download this and play it cuz it's better than mine.
Scott: sweeper and pie cross combined.
Rym: What about World of Warcraft?
Rym: How does it compare to World of Warcraft?
Scott: It's not even the same genre But it's definitely more worth your time to spend a half hour playing this than to spend a half hour in Azeroth.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: Just wanted to make sure.
Scott: yeah, that's definitely So.
Rym: talking about board games like as we've been back into board gaming a lot and we've been playing a lot of our board games Entirely to death to the point that they're not fun anymore.
Scott: Yeah, it's at the point in which you have to buy expensive board games Which we're not sure if they're good or not in order to just take a chance cuz we need a game real bad.
Rym: What we really need to do is just get more people to move in with us because we've played out all the two-player games and all the three-player games and Once we get another person we can play out all the four-player games.
Rym: However, the game we're about to talk about Vinci is a three to six player game.
Scott: Yeah, we actually talked about this game once before in an episode of GeekNights But it was an episode where he talked about a whole lot of crap.
Scott: So we're gonna concentrate now on the whole game of Vinci and go into the details that we probably missed in that other episode.
Scott: Of course, I didn't re-listen to that other episode.
Scott: So I have no idea how much we talked about Vinci, but I don't care either.
Rym: That's fine because Vinci is still one of my favorite games.
Scott: Vinci is a damn good game.
Rym: It's in my top 10 or 15 easily.
Scott: Yeah, I say top 15 definitely 10 maybe.
Rym: well partly because a lot of my games that would be in there I've decided or discovered that they are flawed or I've otherwise solved them and once the game is solved It's really not fun anymore.
Rym: like settlers is a great game But I can't put it in my top 10 because it's not a great game anymore.
Scott: So Vinci is a civilization game.
Scott: You've got Europe and the surrounding bits mostly Europe.
Scott: Yep, and overtime civilizations rise and fall and they rise and they fall and Some are big and some are small and some last a long time and some last not so long.
Scott: and some are really good at Mounting and some are really good at fighting and some are really good at farming and whatever.
Scott: and over the course of this game each player Build civilizations and then lets them go in order to build newer civilizations.
Rym: now I think this is a really cool mechanic where you build a civilization and it has powers whatever and you move around the board in a Deterministic taking things from other players or from barbarians way and then Whenever you think your empire has either been totally butt-fucked by someone which happens fairly often
Scott: pretty often in Everyone's good at playing or
Rym: it's peaked or whatever reason you choose not to just get rid of it and start a new one But to decline it.
Rym: it falls into decline much like the Roman or Byzantine empires, right?
Scott: So let's say I don't have any special things right.
Scott: I build an empire that is ten countries large ten Areas on the map large.
Scott: I'm getting ten points a turn from that without anything special, right?
Scott: So I decide you know what?
Scott: There's not really any way that I can expand this empire, you know.
Scott: It's because nothing increases in military might over time except medicine except medicine.
Scott: If unless you have medicine You're pretty much your strength of your civilization does not increase it can only you just use the power that it has to Expand over the course of a few turns and then you just can't expand anymore.
Scott: You can move around but you can't get any bigger unless you have medicine.
Scott: So the sieve has reached this max.
Scott: I got ten spaces.
Scott: It can't get bigger.
Scott: I say alright, I'm declining I put little Crumbling pillars and all those ten spaces and that's place still gets me ten points because it's still ten spaces that belong to me.
Rym: Yep, but now you can't do anything with it.
Scott: I can't do anything with it.
Scott: It's just a. it's just a bunch of stuff on the board that gets me points.
Scott: It doesn't do anything much like the later Byzantine Empire.
Rym: It exists slow solely to be slowly picked apart by all the other players.
Scott: Yep, everyone else will pick it apart But you hope they pick it apart less quickly because you're still getting points from it.
Scott: Just not that many.
Scott: Meanwhile after I decline that Empire I make a new civilization that hopefully will get me many many points.
Scott: Hopefully it will get me many many points while the old one still exists so that I can get a whole lot of points For both at once.
Rym: so the game goes around where each player will get an empire build it interact with all the other players and then everyone chooses in a cycle when to decline and start new empires and Sometimes a bunch of people all decline at once.
Rym: Sometimes one guy just gets screwed and has to decline early.
Rym: Sometimes one guy just does really well in declines of his own volition.
Rym: Actually, it's really funny.
Rym: several times We basically you really get into this game with a theme because you know, you see oh Those are obviously the fins or ah, that's the Romans.
Rym: just the way the board sets up for the powers they ever way.
Scott: I mean if some guy starts his civilization coming in on England and then he takes over France it's like ha ha ha ha ha ha as
Rym: opposed to ha
Scott: ha ha ha ha yes,
Rym: but Many times we end up having a dark age where suddenly it'll go around and everyone will decline and the entire board just falls into darkness and decay.
Scott: It's fun quite fun.
Rym: Yeah granted We really get into our board games But I think that anyone who enjoys board games really and truly enjoys them gets into games like that.
Rym: You have to have your little sticks your little playing around and that's what German board gaming is about.
Scott: a guy wrote an article recently Saying y'all got a brick.
Scott: Yeah, he's like what's the difference between abstract games and euro games?
Scott: He's like pretty pictures painted on the on the board, you know.
Scott: And the thing is while I'm usually the kind of person who says it's all about the gameplay.
Scott: The theme is whatever when you play a German board game.
Scott: It's not so much the theme itself that makes the game better It's it's the fact that the way the players interact with the theme to add another layer of entertainment above the gameplay itself.
Rym: and Every gaming group seems to have its own little bits and its own little inside things or ways they get into games.
Scott: Yeah I mean range from just Calling the pieces of the game pieces from other games like a different name than what it's supposed to be called.
Scott: Like imagine if you're playing I don't know.
Scott: Let's think of an American.
Rym: Well, it's like you're playing Monopoly and you don't call it boardwalk.
Rym: You call it.
Rym: I don't know something else.
Scott: Yeah, or you don't call it, you know free parking.
Scott: you call it the car crash.
Rym: We tend to go around in a cycle like in Puerto Rico.
Rym: There's a governor and an ammon ray.
Rym: There's the Pharaoh but we tend to call the governor the Pharaoh and the Pharaoh the governor.
Scott: Yeah, we just are like in in El El Grande.
Scott: There's a guy who's the king but you just call him the penis cuz it looks like a giant penis.
Rym: Well, it looks like a very small penis.
Scott: Yes, but it's like, you know, and we're not allowed to touch the king in El Grande.
Scott: So you say don't touch the penis and I love such a penis under any circumstance.
Rym: The thing is people don't get that rule no matter how many time.
Rym: whenever we're playing with someone always tries to do something with the penis And it's always like.
Rym: it was the only rule you had to remember.
Rym: Yeah, it was the first one.
Scott: So in Vinci there's quite a bit of that.
Scott: because when you get a new civilization basically there's a bag and the bag has little chits in it and on each chit is a civilization trait such as livestock breeding or field general or fortification agriculture something like that.
Scott: and you draw these out of the bag in sets of two and each set of two is a civilization.
Scott: and when you get a new civilization You pick one of the available sets of two.
Scott: if it's been sitting out there for a while You can just take it without any worries.
Scott: If it's a new one You kind of have to pay victory points to get it.
Scott: this gives you sort of a bit early in the game.
Scott: It adds a little randomness but later in the game it evens out because now Civilizations that nobody wanted are now very enticing because you might even get points just for taking them.
Rym: It's very much a well-constructed built-in balance system because the powers that Civilizations can get are definitely not all equal and civilization combinations can be stupidly powerful or Stupidly useless, but you can.
Rym: the game will always increase the incentive Continuously to take a bad civilization and in the end it's not that bad.
Rym: because alright So I've got.
Scott: you'll have a choice between taking a badass civilization but having to pay 10 victory points to get it before someone else does or Taking a shitty civilization that's been sitting there since the beginning of the game.
Scott: But if you take it you get 10 points, that's a tough call right there.
Rym: It also adds a lot of strategy where you might want to decline But you don't want any of the civilizations out or what I do often is there's a civilization you want But it's too far out on the track and too expensive.
Rym: You only got to wait for other people to decline before you can get it.
Rym: But you got to hope that no one just pays the price.
Rym: But then again if they do pay the price then you get some victory points.
Rym: You don't care anymore.
Scott: Yep, it's really a tough balancing act.
Scott: But anyway, each civilization has these traits and these traits, you know Put slight modifiers and how that particular civilization is going to work.
Scott: It determines how much the military might of the civilization how far it can expand how quickly it can expand and In what ways it can expand.
Scott: for example astronomy.
Scott: if your civilization has astronomy You can just expand all over the place because you can take the water for free because you can navigate whereas people without astronomy Can't really go over the water that much
Rym: at all
Scott: and they have to basically keep conquering adjacent land Civilization countries not civilization.
Scott: Yeah so these traits add a lot of fun to the game because you get let's say you get barbarians and Mountaineering and you start in much prefer barbarians Barbarians, yes, and you start in Norway you go.
Scott: Hahaha.
Scott: We are to Viking.
Scott: Hahaha, we get you we crush you from the north and it is quite fun.
Rym: I think the best description of all the powers is the barbarian one because it gives you a lot of guys.
Rym: and the description is Barbarians have no special powers.
Rym: There are just a lot of them.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I The board is a lot like risk, in fact, it's almost exactly like without dice though.
Rym: Yeah, I'm the board not think I'm saying the board very specifically.
Rym: I said the board.
Rym: All right, wait a minute.
Rym: Listen.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, so the board is a lot like risk and you have your little tokens that you put on the territories.
Rym: How many guys you have there, but when you want to conquer a place it is straight-up deterministic.
Rym: It costs you X guys and by cost I mean you have to put X guys down on that place in order to take it and you can expand to your heart Content until you run out of guys for that round.
Rym: then you pick all your guys up and reconsolidate however you want.
Rym: So no because it's really simple.
Rym: basically it costs.
Rym: in order to take a place you have to have two guys there minimum plus one for every guy the opponent has there plus any Modifiers like if it's a mountain or a forest which are harder to take or it has a fortress there minus any other modifiers Like if you have weapons or you're attacking from the mountain and all sorts of things like that.
Rym: And if you put the number of guys down, that's it and you took it and the other person has to take their guys up.
Scott: Yeah If they had one guy there that guy dies.
Scott: if they had two guys there one guy dies and the other guy they get to Put in one of their other places.
Scott: Yeah, if there are three guys there one guy dies pretty much always.
Scott: one guy dies.
Rym: Anytime you take an opponent's place.
Rym: One of the pit guys that they have left there is lost from their army or their civilization Forever until they decline and pick a new one.
Rym: now think you'll start with maybe I don't know 12 14 guys total.
Rym: Unless you have medicine you'll never have more than that.
Rym: every time you lose a territory your civilization has been irrevocably weakened Yep, and it's never gonna get stronger.
Scott: medicine is the only exception.
Scott: if your civilization has medicine It increases by one guy every turn just one.
Scott: that might seem pretty good.
Scott: You have a civilization that grows in a game where civilizations can only shrink and it can help But if your civilization doesn't last very long, it's not gonna help that much.
Rym: the problem I see most people having with medicine is that they tend to use it and Despite having medicine which is good and you want to hold on to that civilization for a long time They hold on to a civilization longer than they should have just because they feel like they should because they have medicine
Scott: Yep,
Rym: well a big part of this game is knowing when to just cut and run just figuring out Alright, this civilization is not doing anything for me.
Rym: I gotta dump it now cuz the I.
Scott: the key way to win the game is you want to you gonna get many.
Rym: He went away to win.
Rym: the game is to be Alex.
Scott: That's true But you want it.
Scott: the way the game works is it's not whoever has the most points after so many turns wins.
Scott: it's the first person to get X points wins.
Scott: and Let's say the guy who goes first You know the first player Crosses the line.
Scott: then everyone else still gets to take their turn to see if they can jump ahead.
Scott: that way ever gets an equal Number of turns, but it's a race.
Scott: So you want to get points is not just a lot of them But quickly.
Scott: so a plan that gets a few points early on and then a bunch later is not so good.
Scott: you want to get points constantly all the time non-stop and The way to do that is you want to get one civilization on the board because you start the game blank and then you decline it and you get another civilization on the board and that lets you get points from the declining civilization and your current civilization Simultaneously.
Scott: then when the old civilization is starting to get smaller You decline the one you've got and you're bringing a new one and you try to balance it.
Scott: So you're always getting points from a declining and a current civilization at all times if you can keep that up.
Scott: Usually it's unrealistic to keep that up at full steam the whole game But get as close to that as you can and that's the way to get as many points as possible and Cross the line before the other players do.
Rym: now one really fun thing about this game because it's really rare in most German or euro Style board games is that unlike most other games there is direct straight-up man-to-man Fucking of players by other players and not the sexual kind.
Rym: you will have options that it.
Rym: I mean some games.
Rym: you can hurt another Player but it always hurts you too or isn't optimal.
Rym: in this game not only is it okay to just straight-up attack other players all the time or to Purposefully knock someone out of the game for a round, but it is often the best way to win.
Rym: Yeah, in fact when we first started playing this game because we were used to playing Puerto Rico Sometimes the game even just forces you to hurt other people.
Rym: Yeah, you have no choice, but all these other games we were playing We really were very Congenial to each other and we very much like people wouldn't step on each other's toes.
Rym: We'd all get like I'll build over here and you build over here and there wasn't a lot of fighting because he always felt like In any other game whenever you directly attack another player Usually you just weaken yourself and them and then some other player wins.
Scott: Yeah It's generally.
Scott: other games seem to have a lot stronger prisoners dilemma mechanic where if everyone just cooperates and no one fucks anyone We can all get a lot of points and this will become a game of who gets the most points.
Scott: And if anyone decides to just you know screw everyone.
Scott: It's gonna really does not turn out well for them and the one guy who stays out of it It's like let's say me Rym and Alex are playing a game right and I attack Rym.
Scott: Well that hurts Rym and it hurts me and Alex wins and Vinci.
Scott: that is not the case.
Scott: The prisoners dilemma is not an accurate model at all.
Rym: Yep in fact in Vinci pretty much you have to always screw other players particularly whoever's doing better than you as Hard as you can as much as you can while simultaneously getting points for yourself.
Rym: it is a game that I will say right now.
Rym: if you cannot distance yourself from a game emotionally or if you were the kind of person who Takes it personally if another player like straight up just says I am going to ruin you and then ruins you in a game You can't play Vinci.
Rym: You will not like it.
Scott: You will not like that.
Scott: I mean there was one game I remember where I declined a civilization and I came off the board.
Scott: I selected a new civilization that had quite as large military power.
Scott: Alex came on to the board and again the board goes around and then it was my turn.
Scott: again.
Scott: There was really no option for me to come on to the board in a way that would get me a lot of points because like You can't go near your declining civilization I'm not gonna get into the rules of it.
Scott: But needless to say the best option for me was to come into the board in the exact same spot.
Scott: Alex had just come into the board and I came into the board so strongly I Completely eliminated his entire brand new civilization that existed for only one time.
Rym: I remember when it happened and we're all sitting there looking at.
Rym: he just says well shit Yeah, it was just I declined.
Scott: I took all of his guys off the board.
Scott: he could either try to come on the board again with his remaining pieces at which like five of them were dead or Declined.
Scott: I basically made him lose an entire turn which is huge Absolutely huge and for me it didn't bother me at all because I put my guys on the board.
Scott: I was gonna put him on the board somewhere.
Scott: I got him all on the board So you got as many points as they could have gotten now.
Rym: That's another really fun thing about this game.
Rym: the board is set up to where different areas of the board are laid out kind of differently and have different strengths and weaknesses and Depending on the civilizations that come out some areas become more or less desirable or more or less Defensible or more or less point worthy depending on what's out there.
Rym: So say there's three civilizations that all need agriculture.
Rym: now all the places where there's agriculture nearby Become hotly contested and dangerous to be in.
Scott: yeah, but you can also look at the available civilizations and say wow There's three agriculture civilizations.
Rym: I'm not playing that game.
Scott: I'm gonna take the.
Scott: Even though it might not be as good as civilization I'm going to take the livestock civilization So I don't have to deal with that shit and it might actually get you more points even though Judging from a you know a general standpoint.
Scott: It's not as good as civilization.
Scott: It doesn't have as much military might.
Scott: it doesn't have as much point bonus potential but for the situation that the game is currently in it might actually be Superior in terms of how well you can defend with it how long it will last and how many points it will net you in.
Rym: Now like I said before one of the really strong points of this game is also that it has three to six players Which is great because most games are four player or there's the few five player ones.
Scott: But having game player and games that are like most games will be three four or five players and some of them like only work Well with like four and like the three and the five are kind of hackneyed.
Rym: Yeah, like Tigers New Freighties is three to four or two to four depending on what version you have even though they're the same.
Rym: Yeah, it doesn't work at all.
Rym: two player and it works really crappily.
Rym: three player, but four player.
Rym: It's one of the best games ever.
Scott: It's kind of weird because the German version of Tigris and Euphrates is two to four and the English version says three to four.
Scott: But really it's a four player only game if you ask me.
Rym: But then Vinci much like Puerto Rico every number of players is the same basic game.
Rym: But in terms of strategy and the way the game plays out, it's like an entirely different game.
Rym: So you basically bought a three four five and six player game each one of which is different slightly different I mean the four and the five aren't so different.
Rym: but the different like the three-player game is a separate game with completely separate strategies.
Rym: Civilization.
Rym: Oh, yeah, like a civilization that is stupidly awesome in the three-player game is kind of useless in the six-player game.
Rym: Well a civilization that would win in the six-player game is not so great in the three-player game.
Scott: I think what it is is when you're playing like this six the five the larger player games You the main difference in the rules is that every civilization is going to be weaker militarily.
Scott: And the reason that is is because obviously that way all the civilizations can fit on the same board at once.
Scott: if everyone had a super strong Civilization then you just conquer the whole board and someone else to conquer the whole board.
Scott: and in a three-player game where you really only Had to divide the board into three, you know parts.
Scott: You can have a pretty strong civilization That's large enough to conquer a third of the board.
Scott: in a six-player game You really can only have a civilization strong enough to conquer a sixth of the board or else the game gets screwed up big time.
Scott: so in a six-player game you tend to make civilizations that are smaller yet have to get more points with less might and Deal with being adjacent to more players and being on the board for a shorter period of time.
Rym: now There is some randomness in play just in terms of the fact that a lot can happen between your turns as other players act.
Rym: But it's not randomness that just in the game.
Rym: It's randomness of what other players will do which are things that you can fairly readily anticipate.
Scott: Yeah The only real randomness is what civilizations there are at the beginning of the game because it's possible that at the beginning of the game The best civilization ever is the first one.
Scott: whoever gets to go first picks it and hooray for them.
Scott: They just got lucky.
Rym: However, the game lasts long enough and is constructed in such a way that one good civilization will in most cases not win You the game.
Scott: Yeah, so I Think I've been paying attention and people who go first and pick that awesome Civilization right away that tends not to be so healthy.
Scott: They don't tend to win all the time or anything.
Rym: Well, it used to be that Alex won this game a disproportionate amount of the time.
Rym: Yeah But now just recently the last several playings pretty much every game and extremely close and one of us just pulls ahead by the end.
Rym: Yeah, I won.
Scott: Yeah, I want to Everyone's winning this game.
Scott: everyone's winning.
Rym: I think we've solved the three-player game at least in so far as nobody makes any boneheaded moves Yeah and everyone plays pretty optimally and it comes down to very minor tactical decisions in terms of who wins like Like literally if I lose the game or Scott loses a game, it'll be like in the middle of the game.
Rym: I waited one round too long to decline that one civilization.
Scott: Yeah, and that's that was a gin.
Rym: but the fact is it wasn't random.
Rym: it's oh I made X mistake damn it yep.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what I do sometimes feel not often but occasionally You know one game every once in a while Like there aren't any good civilizations coming up like every civilization that goes up is crap.
Rym: Luckily.
Rym: Everyone has to deal with that.
Scott: Yeah But the problem is if there was say good civilization early on and someone got it and then everyone else gets crap Someone gets a slight lead and if all the civilizations continue to be crap They don't have a hard time maintaining that lead and then they win.
Rym: Yep, but again because the game is long enough.
Rym: It really seems to mitigate that.
Scott: it doesn't happen often But it can.
Rym: and if you find randomness being a factor just by your style of play There's nothing wrong with just adding another 50 victory points to the victory condition and then playing a longer game.
Rym: Yeah, the longer the game goes the more the luck will leave it out.
Scott: Yeah, and also if you really wanted to you could develop some sort of civilization drafting mechanism.
Scott: Of course, the game does have a civilization drafting back a very good one I might add but you could add to it to remove the drawing them out of the bag and somehow doing something else.
Scott: I don't really know if you want to bother with that.
Rym: I don't think it's necessary But it is a possibility if you're really crazy now also we talked a lot about German style games But this is actually a French game.
Rym: Oh It is a game for France!
Rym: Filipe K-Arts.
Scott: K-E-Y-A-E-R-T-S.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: It was put out by Descartes Editieux Editieux This is the best.
Rym: it didn't win any spiel this yards or anything.
Rym: obviously It's not a German game or anything, but it won the 1999 Concours Internationale de Cratures de Jour de Socit.
Scott: What is that?
Rym: The International Creators of Game Society conference Uh-huh or something to that effect.
Scott: That's not bad.
Rym: Now the guy who designed this game He looks like he also made as far as I can see a game called EVO Which we've also played which was kind of meh, but then again, we played it with some kind of men people.
Scott: So That game was meh.
Rym: Oh, no, wait, we played it with men people and we played it with cool people.
Rym: I played it twice.
Scott: Oh, wait, I don't think did I play this game?
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: We played it at those other board gaming nights.
Rym: We used to go to not our way, but the other one.
Scott: Oh, I did play this game.
Scott: Yes, I did.
Rym: Yeah, and I think we also played it with Luke on a separate occasion.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yeah, this game was meh.
Rym: Yeah, it was okay.
Rym: It wasn't a great game.
Rym: I played a game again a game again.
Rym: Now that I'm a little older and wiser in the ways of German games cuz back then I still thought El Grande was the hot Shit.
Rym: Yeah, I still like El Grande, but it's not the hot shit.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: Okay now here's something else.
Scott: You gotta know about Vinci that there's nothing to do with the game itself.
Scott: There are two printings of Vinci.
Scott: There's an old busted printing with a lot of typos and all sorts of problems the one we have.
Scott: Yep Well, we Alex got it super cheap on the discount rack.
Rym: So alright Alex owns that game not us.
Rym: Yep, and I always forget cuz it's in our house.
Scott: Yeah, and there is the new hotness printing that is doesn't have these problems.
Scott: And if you buy this game I suggest you buy the new hotness printing unless you can get the old busted printing for the cheapness.
Scott: See if you can get the old printing for cheap You can go and figure out what the corrections are on board game geek and you'll save a lot of money.
Rym: They're actually pretty minor.
Scott: Yeah Generally, you just want to avoid paying full price for the old busted version and it is worth it to pay full price for the New hotness version.
Scott: That's all I'm gonna say All right.
Scott: one less thing about Vinci.
Scott: if you want to play this game without Buying it at the store in a box or if you can't find it or something You can play it online at a website called ludagora www.ludagora.net.
Scott: It's a French website So it's kind of hard to read.
Rym: French is not that hard to read?
Scott: Well, it's.
Scott: it's kind of.
Scott: it's a little bit hard to figure out what to click on to be able to play the game.
Scott: All right, but once you play in the game at least yeah, the interface is kind of bad But you can play the game there and they work.
Rym: Hey, it's not nearly as bad as that online Tigers and Euphrates.
Rym: that didn't even work.
Scott: Nah Spiel by web is still the best online board game turn-based playing site, you know.
Scott: But ludagora exists and they have Vinci.
Scott: So if you want to play Vinci you can head over there and have some Vinci fun.
Rym: I highly recommend Vinci because it is in the very least unlike many games we own.
Rym: It is stood up to the test of repeated continuous play.
Rym: Yeah I mean there aren't many games that we could play three times in the same day and not be sick of it.
Rym: and this game Is one of those few?
Scott: Yeah, and a lot of games get played out.
Scott: We're like up.
Scott: I know the answer to this game.
Scott: There's no point in playing it anymore.
Scott: It's just a you know an exercise in exercising our fingers moving pieces around.
Scott: but Vinci it's still an okay game and I'm not always in the mood to play it, but I'm never gonna say probably never gonna say that up.
Scott: There's nothing else to be had with Vinci.
Scott: No reason to play that anymore is?
Scott: it's not a solved game by any means.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.