Rym: Well, if you couldn't tell from the lack of music, it's not a normal episode of GeekNights Which means it's that time again.
Scott: You're not even putting the music in the specials anymore.
Rym: I've never put music in the special I don't know.
Scott: I don't listen to the specials because they're not so specials have never had music in them.
Rym: They're just we start talking.
Scott: No, okay, then take that Specials take that internet fair.
Rym: But yeah, I'm out of town.
Rym: So this Episode was actually recorded last night and there probably won't be a show tomorrow night.
Rym: Let's Scott and Emily decide to figure out how to use my computer to record something.
Scott: if I did I would just.
Scott: it would just be low audio quality and I would just push record and then Stop and then make an mp3 with no editing.
Scott: So that that's what it would be.
Rym: But yeah, I know we have a lot of new listeners coming in periodically.
Rym: But if you've never listened to GeekNights before you might want to check out any other episode before you listen to this one.
Rym: This is what we call a special.
Rym: Special is code on GeekNights for we were too lazy to make a real show.
Scott: So we made a show that takes a quarter the effort in half the time unlike specials on television Which means they put in more effort more time and more money to try to get new listeners.
Scott: This is laziness to keep existing listeners.
Rym: I mean we could have a very special GeekNights But that would mean like Scott locked himself in a refrigerator in a dump yard and almost died and then we all learned something.
Rym: All right, like that episode of punky Brewster.
Scott: I never watched punky Brewster ever.
Scott: I've heard of it and I know it's some show but that's all I know.
Rym: You don't know about the tonight on a very special name of show.
Scott: I do know about that.
Rym: Yes, cuz punky Brewster I believe started that.
Scott: Oh punky Brewster's live-action show.
Scott: Yeah, I never.
Scott: I didn't know anything about.
Rym: it was a live-action show.
Scott: I never knew anything about it at all other than there was a show called punky Brewster that I never watched.
Rym: I used to watch it as a kid.
Scott: Well, it was on for 1984 to 86 and then again in 87 and 88 with some syndication.
Rym: I watched a lot of reruns on channel 9.
Rym: I was watching elf I think during those times You know as a kid, I'd say that I watched some good stuff and some bad stuff.
Rym: I mean I watched he-man.
Rym: but now I know that he-man was terrible.
Scott: Yeah Not I'm glad I watched it when I was a kid because when I was a kid was awesome.
Rym: Yeah, but I think the worst show I watched as a kid was small wonder.
Scott: I don't know what that is.
Rym: It's not good.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Anyway, I'll take your word for it.
Rym: So instead of doing you know, it's a special if we can do whatever we want But it is anime manga comic night and it just so happens that over the last weekend We got an email from a listener that Scott wanted to talk about it right away But we decided to wait until the night where it was topical.
Rym: and now that we're doing a special it seems like the perfect day To broach this topic.
Rym: Well,
Scott: not only is this pretty like the specifics of this email very topical But I have a rant that has been building up inside of me and I've been letting loose little by little
Rym: Mostly because unlike me Scott hangs out on the comic geek speak forums and they're cool people and he hangs out there But I think he disagrees with 75% of the opinions posited there.
Rym: perhaps but like I Wager that he is that guy in those forums.
Rym: I mean, you know probably yeah I'm definitely that you all know that there's that guy in our forums.
Rym: I think you know exactly who that guy is.
Rym: Well, uh Anyway, everyone's thinking am I that guy?
Scott: But anyway, this is rant that's been building and this doesn't target that rant directly But it is encompassed by my rant and therefore is an excuse for me to let loose.
Rym: I'm going to read this email in its entirety before we come in.
Scott: I mean, it's a special and we're only doing one geek back.
Scott: So why not?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Now the email is from Kate.
Rym: You know in radio, it's like Kate from Iowa, but I have no idea where Kate's.
Scott: from the internet Kate what don't manage you from Kate?
Rym: It doesn't say at something at us dot something.
Rym: I imagine it's in America.
Rym: Anyway While I applaud the idea of not buying bootlegs and not pirating after something is licensed The real thing hurting anime DVD sales is people not buying DVDs.
Rym: The quote/unquote rule of fan subs is if you enjoyed watching the show You should buy it not if you loved it not if it changed your life But if you just liked it and were entertained.
Rym: no matter what the u.s Anime industry is not like the Japanese industry.
Rym: the u.s Doesn't get to rely on advertisers for their revenue for the most part.
Rym: They have to rely on us the fans.
Rym: So while renting anime is all well and good to see if you like the show shouldn't the same rules apply?
Rym: Because otherwise while it might not make people feel bad.
Rym: It is just as hurtful to the industry.
Rym: I feel like I just wish into a what's-it-pepper box voice, then I just keep going is it?
Rym: And Since most DVDs are well-priced even cheap.
Rym: It's not too hard.
Rym: I also hear complaints.
Rym: You spelled here wrong.
Rym: Kate I'm sorry about the price of US anime DVDs, but if you really think about it $30 is a good price for four or five episodes.
Rym: Yeah, I remember paying $30 for just two episodes of cowboy bebop on VHS.
Rym: I also remember those times.
Rym: those were dark days.
Rym: Now I'm not saying that is right, but anime is the niche market.
Rym: So it seems ludicrous to expect the same price on a DVD of the latest spider-man movie on DVD.
Rym: Anyway, what I'm getting at is that we all need to buy more anime period Kate.
Scott: Alright Kate I got like I could have stopped it like ten different places in your email and said how dumb you are.
Rym: Not so much dumb.
Scott: No, no, yeah, but how you are wrong.
Rym: I'm gonna get my words in edgewise cuz I think once Scott gets going he's not gonna stop.
Scott: maybe Let me try to dig up this email.
Scott: I shut my laptop so I can go back into it.
Rym: Yeah Well, I do find it funny.
Rym: I mean I got to make fun of any email I read.
Rym: but the real thing hurting anime DVD sales is people not buying DVDs.
Rym: That is a beautiful example of the kind of marketing speak that I used to hear at IBM at like business meetings.
Scott: The real problem is like people have made frames.
Rym: They would say a long sentence that basically said sales are down because people aren't buying our products.
Rym: Wow, yeah, that would that was.
Rym: that was beautiful and transcendent, but let's ignore fan subs.
Rym: We're not gonna talk about fan subs at all.
Rym: Let's just talk about either you're pirating something illegally or you were watching it legally.
Rym: So anime is available in the US on DVD and I can purchase it.
Rym: It is perfectly legal for me to rent it and that has been upheld in courts time and time and time again.
Rym: The rental industry is perfectly legal.
Rym: Mm-hmm And also the copies I am renting were purchased by the company that is renting them out And they have the full legal right to do that.
Rym: It was paid for and it is done.
Rym: Mm-hmm If it is available legally at that whatever price or whatever means then I don't think anyone can be morally impinged upon by Purchasing it or consuming it in that way.
Rym: I mean just straight up.
Rym: I can't make the argument more directly than that.
Rym: Watching it in Netflix or watching it on Blockbuster is identical to purchasing it as far as I'm concerned.
Scott: Yeah, why not make sense to me?
Rym: Yeah, and The real issue I mean aside from that just one renting it still generates revenue because if something's rented a lot Netflix in those places have to buy more copies of it.
Rym: and I know for a fact that anime fans ruin DVDs.
Scott: I can't tell you how many times we got scratch DVDs from Netflix and we send them back.
Scott: and I must assume that if the Demand for that DVD remains the same because anime fans keep renting it and scratching it that Netflix is buying more copies.
Rym: So but it's only people.
Scott: you're hurting the anime industry because you're not scratching.
Scott: your Netflix is enough.
Scott: That's your Netflix is more to help the anime industry.
Rym: But I mean that issue aside if someone has the choice of getting something illegal or getting it legally.
Rym: getting it legally wins.
Rym: if Someone has two means of getting something legally say buying it at full Manufacturers suggested retail price from the company directly or Buying it super cheap used from deep discount DVD.
Scott: There's no difference between those two options or getting it in like a box for ten bucks at a convention years Later or renting it from Netflix or borrowing it from a friend.
Rym: or I watch cowboy bebop.
Rym: I'm done with it here.
Rym: Take my DVDs I don't need them and then you watch it and then you give them to someone else to watch them and we just pass them.
Rym: Now notice not copying not ripping but just giving.
Rym: yeah trading or selling used.
Scott: what's wrong with that?
Scott: this part This Kate seems to think that if you watch something and you like it you are somehow Obligated to spend money on it.
Scott: Even if you wouldn't have spent let's like here.
Scott: Let's pretend there's an anime a right anime a comes out and I watch the fan subs, but it wasn't that great.
Scott: But I watched him anyway.
Scott: cuz I was bored Kate seems to think I should go and buy the DVDs, even if I'm never gonna watch the show again now.
Scott: Let's pretend that that same show came out and for whatever reason I wasn't bored.
Scott: So I never watched the fan subs.
Scott: I still wouldn't have bought the DVDs ever.
Scott: There is no situation Where I would have bought the DVDs not like the fan subs prevented me from buying the DVDs.
Scott: if I was gonna buy it I was gonna buy it and the fan subs aren't gonna change whether I was gonna buy it or not.
Scott: So just cuz I like something I'm not under any obligation to spend money on it.
Scott: If I'm gonna spend money on it I'm gonna and if I'm not I'm not.
Scott: and you're not gonna say oh you're guilty cuz you didn't spend money You're not guilty.
Rym: yeah, I mean before we get into the deeper issues here it is there's.
Rym: I just think of it this way Practically from a purely practical rational standpoint ignore morals or anything else Even though I think the moral argument is clear in this case as well because you are purchasing it legally or watching it legally
Scott: Well from a law and morals and I say but
Rym: even then from a purely rational perspective Say I wanted to watch a show So I rent it all and I watch it all.
Rym: if the show wasn't that good and I door I just don't feel like I'm ever gonna watch it again.
Rym: What purpose does purchasing a physical meet a good that had to be manufactured and then letting it take up space in my house serve?
Rym: What if I do buy all the anime that I liked just to support people but then I just sell that anime on eBay or I just give it away or I throw it away a Waste plastic and paper and your money.
Rym: Yeah, it wastes energy.
Rym: There's no point to buying something I've already seen unless I want to show it to someone else or watch it again.
Rym: And honestly a lot of anime.
Rym: if I want to watch it again.
Rym: I'll just Netflix it again.
Rym: Yeah, that's sadly enough.
Scott: Now the deeper issue a deeper issue is this It seems to think it seems to me that what Kate is asking people to do is Basically treat the anime company like a charity.
Scott: Well, the anime company is in need that you.
Scott: they do something we like and therefore out of the good of our hearts Even if we don't want the product they're selling we should give them our money just because we like them so much.
Rym: Now it's not just anime.
Rym: I mean I want to touch on the really deeper issue here.
Rym: Yep in particularly anime manga Science-fiction fandom this seems comics
Scott: any niche geeky market Mostly the niche geeky markets where there is a professional industry of some sort, you know, like indie comic books or Small toy companies that make cool statues
Rym: there seems to be in the in this whole market a culture of You should support
Scott: even like indie music.
Rym: Yep You should support the scene and support the industry even if you don't actually like the individual things in the industry.
Rym: You know, hey palladium is going out of business.
Rym: Everyone who cares about gaming should purchase palladium books to keep them from going out of business.
Rym: Hey indie comic artist X isn't doing so.
Rym: well Buy his comics even if you don't like him just to support him.
Scott: or hey Indie comic artist has a new comic.
Scott: you like you should buy the monthly issues that are full of ads instead of the trade that You actually want or else the trade might never come about.
Rym: I think that's the worst thing.
Rym: That's the worst one that bothers me more than anything in the world is when some comic fan tells me that by not purchasing these gigantic poorly printed annoying hard to store Expensive monthlies or weeklies or whatever.
Rym: that is a pain in the ass.
Rym: I just want to throw them away when I'm done with them and waiting for the you know Rational format the book the bound book that has the entire story in it with no ads.
Scott: That by waiting less money for more pages.
Rym: I am somehow the reason that the comic industry is not doing well.
Rym: maybe The fact that the reason the way they're making money is by having to sell the product that no one wants and people the people Who buy that product buy it out of charity as opposed to out of actual desire is the actual problem.
Scott: Yes, the main point here is that you should never under any circumstance blame the Consumer for the failure of the business.
Scott: if a business is not making money It is not the consumers fault.
Scott: in a capitalist society 110% of the time it is the business's fault.
Scott: if a TV needs money because no one's buying DVDs It's a TV's fault for selling DVDs shittily.
Scott: if some indie comic artist doesn't make money because I don't buy the money Monthly's that's his fault for being stupid and printing monthly's.
Scott: that he lost money on it.
Scott: if some guy Makes like some fan film and that he doesn't make his money back.
Scott: if palladium books is going out of business It's because they're making a product no one wants or selling it improperly or failing to market it properly.
Scott: Well, it's not my fault for not buying it.
Scott: This is not a fucking charity.
Scott: Businesses are not charity.
Scott: if I'm gonna give to charity.
Scott: I'm gonna give to poor starving kids in Africa.
Scott: palladium books or ATV films Marvel Comics are not charities.
Scott: They are businesses.
Scott: if they don't have money.
Scott: It's their fault.
Scott: if they go out of business I don't give a shit.
Scott: It's not my problem.
Rym: Damn, I knew you had your aunt and I saw it coming But I actually had to turn you down because the compressor didn't know what to do.
Scott: Ah, man Don't tell me that we should support someone.
Scott: if someone can't support themselves That's their fault.
Scott: if they want my money They should make something I want.
Scott: I mean I am a person who pays money for things I want.
Rym: I mean just the anime right?
Rym: All right.
Rym: So I want a Netflix stuff.
Rym: the reason I Netflix most anime is because most anime is not that great.
Rym: and you know Hey, that was cool.
Rym: I like I didn't mind seeing that but I wasn't willing to pay more than practically nothing to see it like.
Rym: There's a lot of anime that i'll buy.
Rym: if the price is right pretty much once it gets to five dollars the dvd or less I'll buy almost anything.
Scott: Yeah, I mean we bought freaking what?
Rym: Grappler bocce god, well that was special.
Rym: those ended up being pretty much free.
Scott: I know I know but i'm saying like we bought like ko beast at a convention for cheap.
Scott: I wouldn't have paid full price for ko beast but it's worth it to me to pay 10 bucks for it.
Scott: Yeah, but that's what i'm gonna pay plus.
Rym: Yeah, I mean you make the point that Thirty dollars for four or five episodes of something is a good price.
Rym: The thing is that was a good price eight years ago.
Rym: Nowadays, I mean look at in america how dvds are sold.
Rym: you buy the whole season of like csi or whatever for like 20 or 30 Bucks.
Scott: Yeah, I could buy a season of futurama for less than 30 bucks.
Scott: Why would I buy four episodes of an anime for 30 bucks?
Rym: And the thing the other thing is, you know, why would I even buy the individuals?
Scott: I should buy the box set the thin pack even which takes up less space in my house Precious space in my house because you know what rent costs a lot more than dvds plus.
Rym: It's a fine line.
Rym: I mean Where.
Rym: what's the point at which it's not?
Rym: Okay, I mean like I said before all right buying the the dvds as they come out every month for full price?
Rym: What if I buy those dvds on sale?
Rym: What if I buy those dvds used?
Rym: what if I buy those dvds from a reseller?
Rym: What's the point at which it's not if my friends lend them to me?
Rym: Yeah, is lending.
Rym: Okay legally it is Any anything legal shows it to me?
Rym: What if an anime club runs a marathon?
Rym: should anime clubs not run marathons of whole shows?
Rym: Because that prevents people from buying the show?
Scott: Oh, no, even though the anime company gave them permission to have the marathon.
Rym: Yeah I mean I I don't think I have much to say.
Rym: we've been repeating ourselves because I think the argument is pretty straightforward.
Scott: Yes, basically all I want to do is all these people, you know, you you you're a geek You enjoy some niche product like an indie comic book, right?
Scott: And it's.
Scott: it would be sad for you to see that go because you know you like it And you will only get it as long as the person who makes it is making money.
Rym: like example firefly.
Rym: A lot of firefly fans, but that's a good example.
Scott: I didn't think of because I don't like it.
Rym: I loved firefly.
Rym: I did not like it was just like amazing and to this day.
Rym: I look back on it with such nostalgia and i've seen the whole thing like five times and i've watched the commentaries twice.
Rym: Yep, it's great.
Rym: I loved it but We have a friend.
Rym: Let's say his name is uh Jot, sonson, ha ha so good thing.
Rym: There are many people who share his name But people like him bought things About firefly that were not good like the firefly prequel to the movie comic which was absolute shit.
Rym: And a lot of these people bought multiple copies of it and they bought multiple box sets of the dvds not for any practical reason but to somehow try to boost sales and like Support it and support firefly.
Scott: coming back like some of them would buy two one to keep and one to lend to friends.
Scott: That makes sense.
Rym: No, there were people who bought three.
Rym: There were one to keep one to lend to friends and one to support joss weeden.
Scott: There are people who went to see the movie in the theaters multiple times or would buy extra tickets and only use one of them.
Rym: You know sadly while I like the movie it wasn't I mean it was a good movie.
Rym: It was a solid movie, but it wasn't super great.
Rym: It wasn't as good as the show It tried to do too much with it, but there are people.
Scott: these people are buying products That they don't actually want the product or they're buying products They want but they're buying extras of it that they don't need or want or have room for simply because they want more of it and they they feel it.
Scott: they're basically giving to charity and It's okay to give to charity.
Scott: There is nothing wrong with giving to charity if you feel That your dollars are best spent, you know.
Scott: If you let's say you're a mill you're bill gates and you love firefly and you you know If he spent all his money, he could have kept firefly afloat very easily.
Scott: He's bill gates.
Scott: if he did that That would have been an act of charity.
Scott: Yeah, don't get me wrong.
Rym: We're not saying you people out there can't support an industry.
Rym: We're saying don't ever Ever get mad at anyone else for not doing the same thing.
Scott: You're exactly what i'm saying.
Scott: if bill gates decides to save firefly or support an indie comic artist That's fine And actually you could commend him for doing that.
Scott: if you think that's you know A good way to spend his money would of course actually bill gates spends his money in a much better way.
Scott: You know curing malaria, but uh who needs to give charity to curing malaria?
Scott: when
Rym: you know a starving
Scott: indie comic writer in new york, I would
Rym: put forth a Relatively substantial amount of money if I could see more firefly Like like if it was a fact that if say ten thousand firefly fans each gave a thousand dollars There'd be another season I might.
Rym: it might be worth a thousand dollars to me.
Scott: Yeah, you can if you want give to charity.
Scott: It is charity.
Scott: Don't fool yourself and there's nothing wrong with that.
Scott: It's perfectly fine if you love something that much.
Scott: But the problem I have is when people go around and tell other people that they're bad or they're wrong or they Have an obligation because they like something to also give to charity.
Scott: No one is ever obligated to give to charity nobody.
Scott: I mean, it's nice to do so but you can't tell someone they're bad for not doing it.
Scott: I guess you could tell someone they're bad if they stole from charity.
Scott: Yeah, that would be bad If you went into like the united way and just walked out with 20 bucks.
Rym: But then I mean like what's the if you?
Rym: if someone is saying that what's the line?
Rym: you didn't donate five thousand dollars to whatever?
Rym: You didn't give your kidney to some random person you're breathing air.
Rym: Someone else could be using that that that xbox you bought that those plastic I mean, what's the line?
Scott: and it's even worse when they're talking about charity to For-profit companies usually, you know companies that are trying to make money.
Scott: You know if an anime is failing because it doesn't have good enough marketing That doesn't mean we should buy more dvs.
Scott: It means maybe adv should get better marketing.
Scott: It means maybe funimation should learn how to sell their dvds.
Scott: Maybe bandai visuals should lower their prices.
Scott: It's not my fault that they're not making money.
Scott: It's their fault.
Scott: and don't try to blame me because then i'll yell at you for on a special episode of GeekNights.
Rym: Now one last thing before we end this and aside from everything else.
Rym: We've said there's one more reason why the argument really doesn't work.
Rym: The anime industry in the us as far as anyone can determine Makes jack and shit off of dvd sales.
Rym: the primary market is in merchandise Like plushy tachikomas or plushy cactuars, which I spent 40 on.
Rym: Yeah for one.
Scott: Well, someone might be making the argument that they would make money off dvds if you guys just buy them dude.
Rym: But no the the all the money is in marketing.
Rym: That's why a lot of shows that are really good Don't make a lot of money because a lot of those shows aren't very marketable.
Rym: I mean how much gankotsuo merchandise could is there out there?
Rym: Not so much But how much bleach merchandise is there?
Rym: how much full metal alchemist merchandise was there?
Rym: Some shows are more marketable in that arena than others and those shows are the ones that tend to make piles and piles of money.
Scott: Yeah, if you want to talk about where vis's money is coming from or funimation's money is coming from It's from naruto merchandise.
Scott: It ain't from naruto dvds.
Scott: Well naruto manga makes money.
Rym: Well, plus I mean a show like naruto.
Rym: That's a show that's pretty much designed to be watched on tv.
Rym: You're.
Rym: no I don't think anyone is reasonably expected to purchase The dvds of a show that goes on that long because you're never going to watch it again.
Rym: It's something like it like says I saw it even though that's not out in here.
Rym: Imagine a show that goes on for years and years and years or like the simpsons You know 13 14 20 40 seasons as it just keeps going Other than buying like the seasons that you care about because you want to show them again.
Rym: I don't think anyone is reasonably expected to purchase the entirety of the simpsons.
Rym: You saw it on tv.
Rym: You got your enjoyment out of it.
Rym: I think you've got better things to do with your life than watch all those episodes again or track down The one episode from season 13 that you missed and buy it.
Scott: though I would like to own all the simpsons dvds I would like to own because then I could watch any simpsons episode at any time.
Rym: I wanted to but I don't really have A need to.
Rym: you know much of a pain in the ass That would be.
Rym: i'd rather have but I would pay a lot of money to have a thing on my computer Where I can search through simpsons episodes scripts by words and find the exact episodes I want and then watch them.
Scott: Give it five years.
Rym: I would pay a lot of money for that.
Scott: You just sell hard drives at the store.
Rym: that if every episode of the simpsons on them and you can search through all the episodes And they're all you know how much I look forward to the day when all this drm bullshit is behind us Where I can buy movies on usb sticks.
Scott: Yeah, uh, you just I would just buy movies download.
Scott: It'd be kind of like steam where there's a list of every movie i've ever bought and they just click and they play.
Scott: Oh, i'd be willing to pay but I can also download them in a non-drm format.
Rym: I'm not gonna pay a dollar a song which is the reason I don't use itunes a dollar a song forget it.
Rym: But even with I mean if there were no drm and it was like five to ten cents a song I would spend thousands of dollars on music.
Rym: There was.
Scott: there was a study that said that the sweet spot for music prices online is five cents.
Scott: if it was five cents I would just go online and like type in the name of like The doors and click buy everything they've ever done.
Scott: beatles buy everything they've ever done.
Scott: Let's have them.
Scott: buy everything.
Scott: even though I own some cds same with anime.
Rym: Like if I see a box set of a show that I kind of liked for 40 bucks or less I'll probably just buy it because it's so cheap and if nothing else i'll give it away as a prize on GeekNights.
Scott: So this is just but.
Rym: but if I give a show away as a prize that i've already seen Aren't I hurting the industry because that person didn't buy those dvds?
Scott: I think this just proves that if your only customers are Rym and Scott that yet again You can't blame us for not buying it's their fault for not making the price the correct price determined by capitalism.
Scott: I watch so much lower now that netflix is make more money from people like us And that's it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I think we're done.
Rym: Yep So once again, this was not a normal episode of GeekNights.
Rym: This was in fact a GeekNights special.
Rym: if you're a new listener, and I know there are a lot of you Listen to any episode that does not have the special tag or in is in the special category.
Rym: You'll get a much more sense of what our show is about.
Scott: It's not just scott ranting and me laughing while he rants and if you don't support GeekNights with charitable donations You're a bad person.
Rym: Yeah, send us five bucks.
Rym: So we're not doing the show anymore.
Scott: Yeah, just kidding.