Rym: It's Wednesday, February 28th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We reviewed the New York comic-con at the Jacob Javits Center in New York City.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So for the first time in a long time, I'm actually a little excited about an anime coming out Really?
Rym: Well Scott downloaded.
Rym: we finally watched this preview trailer interview special for this new anime called Moonlight Mile that's debuting in Japan in a few days.
Scott: Yeah, usually, you know previews what you download for anime, you know Tend to be really short and they don't tell you much about the show But I like to download them because it takes like five minutes to get one of these things.
Scott: when they do fan sub them And it just it saves me the trouble of downloading episode 1 And wasting, you know more time in my life trying to figure out if the show was worth watching or not.
Rym: Well, the thing is this looks really cool and it looks like kind of this gritty Serious take on exploration and politics and space and I guess it has the potential to be like gassaraki Which is something I really dig.
Scott: Well, I think at this point pretty much any anime that isn't high school drama wacky high school crap a fighting show or any of the you know, typical Anime genres that are super popular is the show that we're gonna latch on to?
Scott: yeah like ergo proxy It's like if you make a show that's like a serious plot that takes place in sort of the real world like a sci-fi anime or a real horror anime or a Real historical anime and not just samurai fighting Kenshin style.
Scott: It doesn't.
Scott: you don't have to do that great a job to get us to latch on to it Just because we're desperate at this point.
Scott: So Moonlight Mile seems to be a serious show about Explorers and politics in space and Energy and all sorts of stuff.
Scott: So I hope it's good.
Scott: And even if it's only kind of good Still kind of reaching here for it.
Rym: The thing was I had never heard of the guy who directed it at Iku Suzuki as I looked it up and Apparently he hasn't done much.
Rym: but he is known for dear s which he worked on not a good show.
Rym: Maze which he worked on average as direct average to not good show and it looks like he directed the fake Oav.
Scott: not a good show.
Rym: also not that bad of a show.
Scott: I never watched it.
Scott: I've never seen it either.
Scott: But isn't that a boy a man love show?
Rym: It's rated highly.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: A lot of people like it.
Rym: Alrighty I can't speak on it.
Rym: Maybe we'll review it if you guys out there really want us to.
Scott: I just heard that fake was a sort of a boy love show.
Scott: So I kind of wrote it off.
Rym: So in the news, I suppose we should talk about that it's over it's done.
Rym: the American Anime Awards have finished their scam and With the final tragic, you know, they're gonna do it again next year.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see about that.
Rym: I'm telling you you me and Daryl Surratt have to make our own anime awards.
Scott: I think we should an independent Non Industry body should decide the American Anime Awards for stuff that happened this year only.
Scott: Yeah, and if you're gonna do stuff that's if you're gonna give a lifetime achievement award You don't go giving it to who do they give freaking awards to whatever.
Rym: I mean our lizard pretty much be Satoshi khan Miyazaki.
Scott: Yeah, they're basically before guys.
Scott: Well, maybe five guys winning all the awards and everyone else would get dick.
Scott: because well Maybe six guys and if you're not as good as them then you suck.
Rym: Yeah, so who did win awards?
Rym: I mean we talked about this.
Scott: Well, let's see.
Scott: Wait.
Scott: I haven't seen the results.
Scott: actually I'm not kidding.
Rym: I'm looking at him right now.
Scott: All right, so it was fan voting Which is why it sucked the primary reason why it sucked.
Scott: So with fan I did see the nominees.
Scott: So with fan voting I would say that Naruto had to win at least one award.
Rym: Naruto didn't win dick.
Scott: Wow Okay.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Let me try again.
Rym: Well, remember I have.
Rym: the categories were really weird.
Rym: I mean, they have such things as best male actor in a comedy.
Scott: Is it that Vic guy that is everyone's super popular these days?
Rym: No, no Vic won an award for something else.
Scott: Oh, well, at least I'm getting the right track.
Rym: Yeah, no Vic won best actor but not best male actor in a comedy which goes to Dave Wittenberg for Zatch Bell.
Scott: I never even heard of Dave Wittenberg.
Rym: Zatch Bell had best actress in a comedy - Full Metal Alchemist won pretty much every normal award.
Scott: Oh, I could.
Scott: that was my next guess.
Rym: Best actress went to Mary Elizabeth from Ghost in the Shell Standalone complex second gate.
Scott: Oh my god an award that makes sense.
Scott: an anime that came out in the US this year With a great actress.
Scott: Holy crap.
Scott: There's one award.
Scott: They got one.
Rym: Wait, wait, wait, wait, though.
Rym: That was for the dub.
Scott: Yeah, she was good.
Rym: I haven't seen the dub.
Scott: Oh, yeah, she's all right.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right That's the only award on there that has any validity at all.
Rym: Oh, yeah and remember according to the internet population who voted on the American anime Awards the best manga ever in the History of manga since anything that had been published in the US is up for grabs was fruits basket apparently.
Rym: so I guess I gotta throw away all that sanctuary and and Buddha we got laying around.
Scott: I guess Osamu Tezuka Katsuhiro Otomo and Masamune Shiro have nothing on I don't know just the popular shoujo of the day.
Rym: Yeah, don't forget going a guy.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, yeah, I could have guessed that though cuz fruits basket is sort of the number one most popular manga in the US.
Scott: So that does make sense.
Rym: But oh, well, I just I can't reiterate enough.
Rym: these American anime Awards are such a bullshit scam.
Rym: I'm really surprised we haven't been sued or at least threatened for libel or slander, but that's the way it is.
Scott: I Think it's just that they wanted to make awards for I don't know because they felt like there weren't any and there had to be And they didn't actually bother to make the awards any good or have any meaning or respect?
Rym: Well, they didn't need to remember the way these things work.
Rym: is it's kind of this industry circle jerk?
Rym: I mean look at the Academy Wars the real Oscars.
Rym: I didn't even realize they happened until recently.
Scott: I didn't realize that happened until the day after they happened when everyone started talking about what happened at them and I saw YouTube videos From it, but I never actually saw a list of winners.
Scott: I don't even know what won best picture or anything.
Rym: Yeah, me either.
Rym: Yeah, I pretty much never cared about in my life and I still don't care about him.
Rym: But yeah from all the people who talk about going Candidly as opposed to the actors who try to pretend like they mean something they always say that it's boring as hell.
Rym: I mean, I think Penn Jillette and teller said something to the effect of every award ceremony ever is just like the high school.
Scott: Whatever Awards, it's so true.
Scott: God so true.
Rym: But yeah, thankfully we won't have to talk about this again.
Rym: Hopefully next year, hopefully by next year either We'll be having our own anime Awards or these people will all be dead in a gutter.
Scott: I think what we should just do is the anime podcasters should get together every year Get a list of all the manga and all the anime that came out in the u.s That year and then we should pick and it'll just be the American anime podcaster awards.
Scott: We'll decide among ourselves.
Rym: I think among ourselves by ourselves meaning us and our podcast friends.
Rym: We have to decide who counts as an anime podcast Because I looked on dig the other day after I noticed that dig podcast searching was broken as I was trying to find a new podcast to listen to.
Rym: Oh And there's a lot of anime podcasts out there now like they're growing exponentially and they all really Suck.
Scott: Well, no, it would just be the anime podcasters.
Rym: We know yeah, it would just be us and Fast karate Darryl Surratt and Gerald and Clarissa on anime world order.
Rym: Yeah, we just be Ninja Consultants.
Scott: Yeah, that's who.
Scott: it would be all those people some weekly anime review.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: They could be in there, too We wouldn't we?
Scott: basically we would make a little coalition amongst ourselves.
Scott: You wouldn't just let any anime podcaster vote.
Scott: It would be us.
Rym: we would all sit down together on Skype or something and discuss the winners amongst ourselves and of course the thing you can do to always at lend Legitimacy to anything like that.
Rym: we'd send invitations to all the great directors of anime that are still alive Asking them for their votes on our nominations.
Scott: No, we don't need them to vote.
Rym: No, no, we just asked him.
Scott: No, no.
Scott: What you do is after you pick the winners you send letters to the people who won and if they want they could call in And we'll record like their acceptance speech.
Scott: Thank you, whatever.
Rym: No, but before that you see you're missing the point here.
Rym: If you even if no one responds to your letter at all Even if your letter gets lost in the mail You can then legally say that among the voting members of your board include blah blah.
Scott: I know that is necessary.
Rym: Why not?
Scott: if I think it's I think it's much better to for us We should just do the penny arcade style, but we were right.
Rym: awards, you know, they stopped doing that.
Scott: Well, that's just yeah, they missed it years and years ago.
Scott: Yeah We should.
Scott: I think we need to pick it up.
Rym: Someone needs to even if not us because the American Anime Awards are a blight upon this earth.
Scott: Alright now I was gonna.
Scott: let's move on to my news Which is nothing because I was gonna talk about I guess something that was announced.
Scott: I mean the New York Comic Con happens.
Scott: We're talking about this show and there were a lot of panels there and you had to imagine among all those panels and now They were all industry panels.
Scott: There had to be some news worth talking about but no none of it's really worth talking about.
Scott: I mean such-and-such manga was licensed such-and-such comics are gonna come out such-and-such movies are now available Such-and-such people are working on such-and-such thing.
Scott: So and so signed a contract with so-and-so.
Scott: It's all just information.
Scott: None of it is particularly interesting or new or exciting.
Scott: You can go read it on newsarama and anime news network.
Scott: I'm not gonna bother reiterating it.
Scott: It's not worth it my time or the time in the podcast Of course.
Rym: one final thing just so.
Rym: you're all aware and you'll be ready for it.
Rym: But later in the episode when I get to a certain thing that happened at the CPM booth I am now announcing that I a contest we're going to run for a Somewhat interesting prize that is currently sitting in front of me on my desk.
Rym: Uh-oh, but we'll get to that when the time comes.
Scott: I was just trying to get rid of crap.
Rym: I don't want to spoil.
Scott: we should do is all the crap at our house that we don't want anymore.
Scott: We should just get rid of in contest.
Scott: I feel like yeah, I eat this banana.
Scott: I don't need this banana peel anymore.
Scott: All right, nice contest for Scott's banana peel.
Rym: next Monday We'll have a contest for who can get the 12 inch CRT.
Rym: that is sitting under my desk unused.
Scott: Oh then after that don't tell him though that the week later There'll be a contest for the 710 inch CRT.
Scott: I'm trying to get rid of.
Rym: Oh, don't forget the 40 gig hard drive.
Rym: That doesn't work.
Scott: Whoo.
Scott: Good prize.
Rym: So that was kind of awesome.
Rym: normally I say things the day right about then but instead for about 10 minutes I was saying such things as motherfucker shit shit shit.
Scott: God, damn it crap ass shit motherfucker.
Rym: You see between doing the front half of the show in the back half of the show I thought hey, let's get that cool Scott's thing of the day so I can put the audio in the show.
Rym: So I started fiddling with my awesome mixer to record it and that Causes my awesome mixer to crap itself partly because my computer is physically a nightmare mess.
Scott: And you're holding out replacing it until the summer.
Scott: God knows why you should have replaced it last summer.
Rym: Oh, no, sorry I lied three summers ago every day that I don't upgrade my computer the computer I'm going to get with the same amount of money is like 1% faster I know.
Scott: but if by that logic you'll be sitting here in 2030 not buying a new computer.
Scott: No, it's gonna push me over the line 31 the computer will be 10 bajillion terahertz instead of 90 bajillion terahertz.
Rym: Yeah, you see we're still on this cusp here and to Write about when I'm gonna get a computer is right about when Team Fortress 2 is gonna come out and I'm gonna start playing FPS's again.
Rym: But that's all beside the point.
Rym: After rummaging around and hitting my computer on the side a bunch of times USB started working again.
Rym: So we're back on the road.
Rym: Oh by the road.
Rym: I mean the road to podcast Ville.
Scott: I Think we're already living in podcast Ville.
Scott: so things of the day Right all this week are things of the day have been openers to various television shows from that are sung in other languages besides English.
Scott: Not and I can say foreign languages because this might be your home country that we're talking about here on Monday.
Scott: What do we do?
Scott: like you did Chinese Sailor Moon?
Rym: Yeah, and I did.
Scott: I don't remember doesn't matter.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Rym: I don't think we need to do a recap.
Rym: suffice to say check out the things of the day all week.
Rym: Because of all these things out there we have been kind of picking the best.
Scott: or I did Hebrew macron one.
Scott: Yesterday you did Sonic Underground in French Mario Brothers Super Show in German.
Rym: now today we're going to prove probably something that we've been thinking about it now.
Rym: There's no way around it.
Rym: It seems that the German people for whatever their good points and bad points are the masters of taking American or Japanese shows and either faithfully recreating the openers in their native language or in Creating entirely new openers that are in many ways better than the originals.
Scott: Yes I present to you the original opener to Sailor Moon again.
Scott: Why is Sailor Moon showing up twice this week?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't even like Sailor Moon Moon.
Scott: the germ.
Scott: the original opener to Sailor Moon in German is so badass.
Scott: It might be one of the best openers ever.
Rym: I mean the music is really good.
Rym: It's so good in the kind of techno that we like.
Rym: It's good song.
Rym: aside from that the opener itself like all the Sailor Moon openers is very well animated and very Stylistic and if the show were anything like that opener Sailor Moon would be a great freaking show man If Sailor Moon was like that opener, that would be holy crap.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: I would watch every episode of that show.
Rym: See the thing is the reason I watched all of Sailor Moon was that while the show is mostly monster of the day and you Know Sailor Moon style antics.
Rym: There are a lot of scenes in the show Just not enough of them that are just like that opener.
Scott: Yeah, how many scenes like that?
Rym: like one every 20 episodes about one every eight or nine?
Scott: It's not that bad It's still pretty bad.
Scott: It should be the whole show and the whole show should only be 26 episodes long.
Rym: Yeah, yeah as opposed to 200, but yeah suffice to say I watched it all and it's not that bad of a show.
Rym: There are worse.
Scott: I guess if you have nothing better to do with your time Then you can watch 200 episodes of Sailor Moon.
Scott: But anyway things I want to point out about this opener.
Scott: number one Of course, we said already the music in this opener is so badass Holy shit, and two there's like towards the middle of the opener There's a quick like.
Scott: it's like less than a ten less than two seconds of animation.
Rym: It's like three beats worth of stuff.
Scott: Yeah of the masks.
Scott: like turning around multiplying and then like the mask guys Sort of coming up and taking up the whole screen.
Scott: like every time I see that imagery It just gives me this feeling of whoa.
Rym: Yeah It's just like a new tenor in the Black Rose saga.
Rym: whenever it cuts to the basement where all those kids died long ago And they all just in one motion look back toward you.
Scott: Yeah, it's kind of.
Scott: it's really cool.
Scott: And if there was an anime they gave me that same feeling that I get when I see those masks turn around Throughout the whole anime.
Scott: that'd be the best anime ever.
Rym: now see this.
Rym: this has happened before to us.
Rym: You know this thing.
Rym: the style and the mood and the vibe of this opener is So much darker and better than what Sailor Moon actually is.
Rym: the same thing happened with you ten a movie.
Rym: if you watch the AMVs To the you ten a movie they make that movie look amazing.
Rym: You'll watch them and think holy shit this movie is gonna be the best thing ever.
Scott: no It's not snake cars.
Rym: Yeah, naked cars, but you wouldn't know that from those music video.
Rym: No, cuz naked cars aren't in the music videos, so I was gonna do the one-piece opener in Italian.
Scott: Oh my god is the one-piece opener in Italian awesome?
Rym: It is so much better than the Japanese and the American openers I agree, but the right.
Rym: instead I want to do the opener to gargoyles the American cartoon in Germany now while in unlike the Sailor Moon thing which is totally different and better it is pretty much a straight-up Perfect rendition just had happens to be in German.
Rym: in fact It sounds a little bit cooler because the German language at least to my American ears sounds a little bit more dark and medieval.
Scott: Maybe because that's where the medieval stuff happened.
Scott: You know in Germany.
Rym: Yeah, yeah But it just.
Rym: I like gargoyles, and I like this German opener And I think this proves that the Germans are absolute badasses when it comes to Remastering or remaking the openings of shows.
Scott: maybe they try really hard at it I have no idea, but yeah the German opener to the gargoyles TV.
Scott: Show is tat awesome.
Rym: so enough awesome.
Rym: Let's review the New York comic-con.
Scott: Alright, so New York comic-con for those of you who do not know is a comic primarily comic convention But it also includes anime and gaming in the Jacob Javits Center in New York City.
Scott: This is the the second annual one happened this past weekend.
Rym: That was an awkward sentence.
Rym: Yes, you see you might remember.
Rym: We've talked about it a bit, and we did a show on it last year.
Rym: But last year they tried to do a New York comic-con for the first time ever and it was perhaps the most poorly managed debacle of a disaster to ever have graced New York City at least in terms of anime manga comic conventions.
Scott: Yes, well basically to sum it up They decided to have a convention in New York City because there wasn't one and it felt like there should be which is correct.
Rym: They did it eating.
Rym: There's a reason why there aren't any.
Scott: there's a reason why there aren't any conventions in New York City At least not nerdy ones because there aren't any convention centers in New York City that are Good for having nerdy conventions in.
Rym: yeah, we're not going to talk about what happened last time.
Rym: We've talked about it enough yet.
Rym: I want to hear about.
Scott: just to sum it up They had a lot more people than they could handle.
Scott: they had to turn people away.
Scott: It was unhappy.
Scott: It was crowded.
Scott: It was black.
Rym: so this year They got more space and they tried to rectify these problems and instead we got to see the actual con Which had a very different set of problems?
Scott: Well, yeah basically, I think the number one problem with the convention this year is the timing of things and The like basic simple logistics of what went on.
Scott: It's like you could buy a ticket and you could get in and they stopped selling tickets for Friday.
Scott: So everyone who paid got in and no one showed up.
Scott: if you showed up and didn't get a ticket and get in That was your own damn fault for not visiting the website or not reading any information, you know.
Scott: So that problem was averted.
Scott: They solved that one.
Scott: Here's the problem.
Scott: They did have.
Scott: let's use our personal experience as the example.
Scott: We show up.
Scott: All right on Saturday Friday We have Friday only badges and on Friday The con is open to normal people from 4 p.m.
Scott: To 9 p.m.
Rym: Now now think about 4 to 9 p.m.
Rym: And it costs us what 30 bucks.
Rym: Yep, see I'm trying not to be hard on this con, but 30 bucks for 4 p.m.
Rym: To 9 p.m Where for very little much more than that I can get a whole weekend at Katsu con or Otakon.
Scott: Yeah, the prices the badges don't really make too much sense Unless you buy the weekend pass which is sort of annoying because there's no reason as I will get to.
Scott: there's no reason to Buy a weekend pass to the newer comic sadly.
Rym: That was the saving grace.
Rym: Sure It was only open 4 to 9 but by 6 45 I had done everything I wanted to do with the con and I grabbed my stuff and left.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I left soon after I think like seven something.
Scott: Ish I left.
Scott: I don't really remember.
Rym: you could literally do everything at this con in two hours.
Scott: Yeah, I mean not coming unless you if you're someone who cares about buying comics first of all This isn't the con for you because there isn't much in the way of buying comics.
Scott: and to Even if you did want to buy comics and you came there to buy them now, you know that would basically take you a half a day to look through all the comics there.
Scott: and If you wanted to go to panels and events, which I don't really you know I'm not interested in the panels and events that they were offering then maybe it would be worth it to go all three days.
Rym: but yeah, except all the panels that are worthwhile cost extra money and sell out and are hard to get to or Happen before anyone can actually get into the car.
Scott: Yes That's what I was trying to allude to before.
Scott: the number one problem with this convention.
Scott: We show up We have.
Scott: they were smart in that we could get our badges any time during the day.
Rym: Yeah, we showed up at like two o'clock.
Rym: We went in.
Rym: there was no line.
Rym: No crowd.
Rym: We got our badges and alright Let's go get some food.
Rym: So we left.
Scott: Yeah, I mean we looked and there were people who were waiting to get in the doors at 4 p.m Cuz until 4 p.m.
Scott: It was like, you know exhibitors and industry only time which I think they should have moved to Thursday and had Friday been every one Day, but whatever.
Scott: and there are people waiting in line to get in the door at 4 p.m.
Scott: Maybe like a hundred people 200 at the most I counted.
Rym: there were about 180 people because I had that stupid axe clicker since we got a box of a billion of them from Katsu Kan.
Scott: yeah, and There was no point in us waiting for two hours in that line so that we could be among the first to get into a room.
Rym: So of course because there's no food anywhere near the Javits we walked aways.
Scott: We walked aways to like 8th Avenue.
Scott: We got some food.
Scott: We came back at around 3. ish.
Scott: So we got an hour until the doors open.
Scott: when we get back at 3 There was a line going from where the line was before out into the street and we had already checked our coat.
Scott: So there was no way we were going outside again now, so we're smart.
Rym: now all these other people.
Rym: we watch people Trying to like game their way into the line or cut ahead of people or you know Just kind of walk in the door.
Rym: and there's this one awesome security dude standing there.
Rym: He was probably the best part of the whole con as far as I was concerned.
Rym: Maybe he's standing there and he's just yelling with high energy keeping these nerds in line.
Rym: Keep walking.
Rym: Let's talk in yelling at him Very much ridiculing anyone who actually tried to jive him and get into the line where they shouldn't.
Rym: and he was sending everyone outside and telling them they Were stupid for trying to get into the line at the middle.
Rym: Mm-hmm He was the only reason this didn't descend into chaos.
Rym: that single man saved the con.
Scott: Yeah I mean because he pretty much beyond him was the roped off area where you don't need so many people to manage because this roped Off area.
Scott: but you know, he was managing everyone who is not in the roped off area keeping them from being stupid.
Rym: now I gotta say the sheer number of people at this con who tried to sneak in or cut in line or get past This guy was astounding to me.
Rym: it averaged about two or three a minute.
Scott: Yeah it was kind of crazy like how many people were trying to like sneak around.
Rym: the guy was getting more and more angry as time went on as people kept coming up with sob stories or excuses or trying to like distract him and get around behind him just to cut in line, he
Scott: was cool though because obviously this line was for people who had badges already and wanted to get in you know to the actual con and Anytime someone showed up to him without a badge yet.
Scott: He would say go up there get your badge and when you come back I'll let you in here.
Scott: At least he was cool.
Scott: You know, he wasn't like mean or anything.
Scott: Anyway as a result of this crazy line and there being only one entrance to the convention The convention that supposedly started at 4 p.m.
Scott: We couldn't get into it until past 5 p.m.
Rym: In fact, it was about 5 30 little after 5 30 that we finally got through the doors.
Rym: And the thing is there wasn't really wasn't any reason for it to take that long it.
Rym: the line could have been easily processed faster.
Rym: I don't know what they were doing.
Rym: Maybe they only had one guy at the front checking badges.
Scott: It was like a single file line of everyone who wanted to get into the con right away at 4 p.m.
Scott: Now here's why it had to be a single file line.
Scott: It could have been like a five file line.
Scott: It could have been three or four or five file lines.
Scott: There are multiple entrances to this place.
Rym: Well, here's what really bothered me.
Rym: after we got into the con and I got bored.
Rym: So I went to leave and I noticed after I went out and got my coat That there was no line to get in and there was almost no security or anything.
Rym: So on a whim I just walked back up without my badge visible and had no trouble getting anywhere.
Rym: I wanted to go just about.
Scott: yeah, it's kind of silly.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, so we finally get in after standing in the first.
Scott: There's a problem with this.
Scott: the fact that the con opens at 4 right and people can't Realistically get into the convention until about 5, you know what the problem is Well, wasn't there an event that you wanted to go to it for?
Scott: there are a lot of things scheduled for 4g.
Scott: That's great.
Scott: You scheduled something for 4 when even though the con is open.
Scott: No one can get in.
Scott: I mean even conventions like, you know Otakon are not so run by fans.
Scott: This is a convention New York Comic Con run by the industry.
Scott: It is paid for.
Scott: there's a Company that runs the thing.
Scott: It's a company.
Scott: read exhibitions.
Scott: All they do is run conventions.
Scott: That is their job.
Scott: They run trade shows.
Scott: you think they would know better than to have events at the same time as you start letting people in Like someone's gonna come into the door at the exact moment the con starts and run to an event immediately.
Scott: Otakon is that smart enough not to do that?
Scott: In fact every anime con I've ever been to even the really terrible ones like Ohio con 2.0.
Scott: I don't know how con is now But you have a con.
Scott: you don't start your programming your scheduled programming until a little bit after.
Scott: You know you give people time to get into the convention.
Scott: you have your main You know room open so people have something to do as soon as they get in.
Scott: But you don't start scheduled events until people have time to get into the convention center, that's just stupid.
Rym: So we finally get in and there's a big open area We can see.
Rym: it's pretty much to your left is a gigantic dealer's room and that's it a dealer slash exhibition room.
Rym: It's just a dealer's room.
Scott: Did you actually know if you actually look at who's in that room only about?
Scott: 25% of it is Dealing and selling shit.
Scott: the rest of it is all people just exhibiting shit and showing stuff off, but it wasn't anything special.
Rym: I mean there was no.
Rym: there were mediocre games that were being demoed and effectively was just marketing.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty That's what exhibition is.
Rym: yeah, and to your right was a little escalator that went up to the artist alley area Except there was a line to go up the escalator And they couldn't let anyone up until people came down already.
Rym: mind you the kind of just started.
Rym: We just gotten in the door and pretty much It was almost impossible to get up there at any time, and they weren't managing this line very well.
Rym: There was one guy and every time one person came down the escalator you let one person up and the line pretty much went Straight across the entrance to the con preventing anyone trying to get in from getting anywhere else without shoving through them.
Rym: Yeah, yeah They should have just turned the and no one even said no one even said what the line was.
Rym: so there was just this crowd of people and then this other crowd of people standing around this crowd of people trying to figure Out what this first crowd of people is for and he after the guard he pretty much just said I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, basically when I went up to the escalator when I was done in the X main exhibition hall I wanted to go upstairs to the artist alley the guy.
Scott: you would just stop everyone from going up the escalator Unless you had us.
Scott: unless you were a special person then he would just let you up then.
Scott: You know people are basically constantly coming down the escalators.
Scott: many people has wanted to come down.
Scott: They didn't care and then every like minute.
Scott: He would let like 10 people up the escalator, then he would stop everyone.
Scott: Yeah, I would let 10 people.
Rym: I went over here earlier than Scott while he was still looking around the dealer area And when I finally got up there, I couldn't actually go into the artist alley.
Rym: It was so full of people I literally would have had to push people out of my way or stand there and shuffle at a rate slower than an old person Buying fruit at a convenience store.
Scott: Yeah, the artists alley was Ludicrously crowded and the out the aisles in the artists alley were very narrow Narrower than they should have been and the actual booths at the artists alley were kind of small and close together.
Scott: So like if there was a popular guy at a booth next to you and like three people were waiting to talk to him they would basically cover the front of your booth and then make it harder for people to walk in the aisle and Etc etc.
Scott: etc.
Scott: if they have it.
Scott: I think the problem was and this is actually one good thing about the New York comic convention Usually when you go to a comic convention, right the the semi famous people or the famous people are guests of the convention.
Scott: You know, they have panels, you know, they wheel them out for autographs and stuff like that.
Scott: But they don't usually have artists alley tables.
Scott: artists alley tables are for you know The small-time people who they're not guests of the convention.
Scott: they pay to get in there and whatever.
Scott: at the New York comic convention There were
Rym: lots of
Scott: famous creators who would have been guests of honor at most mid to small sized comic conventions and Since the New York Comic Con was so big and so up there these people were just in artists alley Which was awesome except for the fact that artists alley was tiny.
Scott: Thus it created a bigger problem when you have a famous guy just sitting there going hi How you doing?
Scott: And now people are lining up and crowding around in a cramped artists alley.
Rym: granted I'll admit since I don't really read many comics I didn't know who any of those people were so I had really no reason to be up there and I I wanted to just But I couldn't really know.
Scott: browsing is pretty much impossible.
Rym: The only thing I could have done there was look for names of people, but I don't recognize any of these people.
Rym: So I just gave up after about 10 minutes of trying to squeeze in.
Scott: Yeah I basically walked up and down the artists alley looking at the people's names above the booths and then looking down to see if they Were actually there.
Scott: if I recognize the name, let's see What else is going on.
Scott: at the end of the artists alley was the podcast arena?
Scott: I think which is where all the comic podcasts were hanging out and You know, they had a lot of room over there.
Scott: they were having a good old time and whoo-hoo awesome for them.
Scott: I went over there.
Scott: I talked to a bunch of people and it was awesome fun going down that away.
Scott: if you're interested in Podcasts if you didn't know those people if you didn't you weren't interested in podcast.
Scott: You're privately just like.
Scott: what the fuck is this shit Charles?
Scott: Who are these people?
Scott: Why are they in between?
Scott: You know the gaming room and the artists alley, huh?
Scott: You know, whatever it was cool to have a podcast arena that was sort of like.
Scott: noted It shows that the con is respecting podcasts in some way, but I don't know.
Scott: It didn't really seem to do anything except provide the podcasters with a fun place to hang out for them And a place for their listeners to meet up and hang out.
Rym: I imagine the only reason they have podcasting there at all is Simply because they expect these people to cover the con and those provide more press.
Scott: perhaps perhaps I mean, it really does seem like the New York Comic Con is incredibly podcast friendly.
Scott: I mean they have their own podcast.
Scott: They're podcasting all their panels over time.
Scott: the guy who runs the con goes on podcasts and talks to people You know, so I guess they're really trying to harness the power of podcasting in some way.
Scott: great Yeah, and beyond there was the gaming room, which I didn't go in But it was basically a bunch of CCG is being played and stuff like that And that was also where the autographs were being done.
Scott: But I didn't even know that because there was no way to know that.
Scott: I actually heard stories from other people that they wanted to go to someone's autograph session, you know Cuz I don't really care about autographs and they couldn't find it because it was hidden in the side of the game room and there Wasn't much signage to tell you that it was going on.
Rym: So pretty much the only other thing we did was wander around the giant dealers room and not even all of it.
Rym: I mean half of it was just people selling comics.
Scott: yeah, the back like left-hand corner was just people selling comics.
Scott: and You know, I guess if you want to buy comics Good for you.
Scott: But if you're in New York City, why don't you to go to a convention for that?
Scott: There's like four Tremendous awesome comic book stores that you can go to though at least a better deal in this area.
Rym: konami had a big setup and they were pushing you all the new DDR mixes and They gave us a bunch of free CDs of the music from all their new mixes Which of course we actually kind of threw him for a loop.
Rym: when you know They give them to us and we said something like oh, yeah We had these Akatsukan.
Rym: we were giving them away and they were taken aback by this like what how'd you get him?
Rym: And then we just left.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, so I Guess one of them.
Scott: it was an EBE giveaway, I guess right?
Scott: Yeah, we only had one of them.
Scott: They gave us three or four that we didn't have already.
Scott: Oh, well, what else was in that main dealers room?
Scott: That was good to look at.
Rym: Well CPM was selling stuff, you know CPM the company that's pretty much going out of business.
Rym: Yep, if they're not well, they're effectively out of business.
Rym: They're just selling off their stock.
Rym: So we talked to them for a while.
Rym: They were cool.
Rym: They had.
Rym: it wasn't just you know, like the usual five dollar DVDs or whatever's deal I bought a pile of really bad anime for almost no money including a silent service and Grappler Baki, we're not watching that shit.
Rym: No, however, the guys were really cool.
Rym: We talked to him for a while and When they you know rang up my order and they gave me my little baggie with my DVDs in it He grabbed a fistful of other Stuff and shoved it in the bag and said here you go now.
Rym: little did I know at the time?
Rym: But he was actually trying to kill me.
Rym: You see when I got on the train to go home I looked in the bag and among the things that he had shoved in there without my asking or paying for Was the soundtrack the OST to the second worst anime ever MD Geist?
Rym: OMG, so thus I'm going to have a little contest.
Rym: I want you out there to write or Say or in any somehow expressed to us not only what was the worst anime you've ever seen.
Rym: I mean, we know MD Geist is the second worst anime ever.
Rym: What is the worst anime you have ever seen?
Rym: But it's not just that easy.
Rym: You got to tell me why it's bad.
Rym: I want examples.
Rym: I want details.
Scott: Yeah, and I guess over has the best one will get the MD guys sounds the original soundtrack to MD guys.
Scott: I have a feeling that people are not going to enter this contest because they do not want the prize Including such songs as prologue gang of craziness.
Scott: and wait, what's the best one brain palace?
Scott: Brain palace.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: final program quotation mark.
Rym: D quotation mark is pretty cool.
Scott: You mean what's that called?
Scott: Death force death force.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: And of course the the snazzy football uniform.
Scott: Oh All right, let's see.
Scott: what else did we see?
Scott: that was cool in the dealers room?
Scott: Oh, there was a. there was like a sci-fi DVD purse selling person, but they had a lot of cheap anime DVDs.
Scott: We got all of ko beast for $25.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I'm very pleased with that.
Rym: We're gonna be reviewing ko century bees probably next Wednesday, maybe What else is cool in there?
Scott: There were.
Scott: basically there was a different, you know, every major comic publisher had some sort of booth or display there.
Scott: You know, I stopped off at all the ones that I know and I chatted him up.
Scott: ATV was there selling their Chevalier DVDs.
Scott: There are quite a few people selling the same manga that I saw Katsucon at the same prices.
Scott: I saw at Katsucon.
Rym: Granted the anime industry seems to be slowly recouping from the bad years They've had recently since they were here at least the ones that were here.
Rym: We're here in full force.
Scott: Yeah, they basically I mean Viz had like I think right up front like they had a little like a little house and Like they gave they were giving away their canvas bags and their free sneak peek Mangas.
Scott: Viz was out like.
Scott: that's the biggest convention setup Viz has and Viz didn't even go to Otakon this year.
Scott: So that was pretty cool to see them there.
Scott: Who else was cool?
Scott: the DC booth was basically just like this rotation of comic creators doing signings and whatnot and it was actually kind of funny because it was really small and cramped and You had to like kind of look around to see who was sitting where.
Scott: they had like four separate desks of different heights and positions And if you were the last person in line to talk to a creator They would give you the sign to hold.
Scott: that said I am the last person in this line.
Scott: Haha Wow, I saw some nerd holding the sign and I laughed at him.
Rym: Yeah, we did see while we were waiting to try to get into the con Stan Lee walked by with his entourage and if he Hadn't been as far away as he was I would have totally run up before the guard shot me and asked him why the hell He bolded all those random words.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah I mean we probably could have run up and like been like, excuse me We can get an entourage of like 30 people or I was in like 30.
Rym: It was at least 18 people.
Rym: There were a lot of people.
Scott: it was like five feet.
Rym: Oh, it was far more than that.
Scott: That's not what I saw.
Rym: That's what I saw.
Scott: I think you're there were.
Rym: no there were in all seriousness At least 15 people following him and like this teardrop shaped trail, that's not what I saw anyway.
Scott: Yeah, Oh one cool thing about this actually was down the right side of the exhibition hall.
Scott: it was actually sort of poorly laid out.
Scott: these people all had their backs to the wall and there was like a pillar in the Way and there wasn't a lot of room in front of them.
Scott: But down the right side of the exhibition hall in the last aisle were tiny booths for all like the ridiculously independent small-time publishers like vertical was over there and Like all the people usually see an artist alley at mid-sized conventions and that I saw a lot of cool stuff down that way.
Scott: I just didn't want to buy any of it, but it was pretty cool.
Scott: talking to a lot of those people like hey What do you make here?
Scott: Whoa, I never heard of that.
Scott: Ooh, that looks pretty cool.
Rym: Yeah, other than that.
Rym: I mean we ran into the guy who does dr.
Rym: McGninja who is totally awesome.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Dr.
Scott: McGninja guys Awesome.
Rym: Scott ran into Jim Vowles the former con chair of Otakon.
Rym: I had already given up on the con and was getting my coat at that point.
Scott: But yeah, basically, I think the final word in the New York Comic Con is that is a big room.
Scott: It's full of some awesome stuff and some not-so-awesome stuff.
Scott: If you know comics the artist alley is really awesome.
Scott: if you can get around the crowdedness of it.
Rym: Well, if you know comics and you care about the semi-famous people who do them.
Scott: Yep I don't know.
Scott: if you want to get autographs and sketches There's pretty much no better place because whoever you want to get them from is almost guaranteed to be there.
Rym: But other than that, I mean don't because there I saw a lot of anime fans.
Rym: I walked around just kind of asking people about the con since I really didn't have much to do at it And there were a lot of anime fans or people who like were at katsu kana went to anime cons at this con and without Exception.
Rym: they were all very much disappointed and bored and said they'd never come back.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much Even though this is like the biggest baddest comic-con in the East Coast I mean pretty much only San Diego comic-con beats out this one.
Scott: It's not run any differently from any other comic cons except that it's bigger really big too big for its own shoes.
Rym: I mean really if you like the stuff they've got you can do all that stuff.
Rym: But even beyond that there's really no way to hang out.
Rym: There's no where you can just sit and hang out with other comic fans easily.
Rym: it's just crowded and hard to get around and expensive and difficult to get to and I was thoroughly unimpressed.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you like comics I'd say it's worth it to go for one day if you're a comic fan like Friday or Sunday not Saturday It's not.
Scott: it's not worth it to go to this thing on Saturday ever unless There's some crazy event that you must go to.
Scott: but none of the events really interested me.
Scott: you can go to the website and look and see what the events were.
Scott: all of the cool events like see Stephen Colbert or see Stephen King or Watch the new sci-fi TV episodes before they're on TV.
Scott: you need separate tickets for all that shit and They don't really tell you where to get those separate tickets or how much they cost.
Rym: Actually when I was going around asking people about the con They they must have assumed I was press or something.
Rym: cuz you know, I'm asking him stuff.
Rym: So they're always at the end like hey So, you know where I can get tickets to whatever and I had no way to tell him.
Rym: I didn't know.
Scott: yeah I mean That's one thing that I really like about.
Scott: pretty much every anime convention is a badge to the con.
Scott: is a badge to the con.
Scott: You have a badge.
Scott: you can do anything as long as your badge is for the right day.
Scott: You know if you buy a Friday badge You can do anything.
Scott: that happens on Friday at this con and I think a lot of other comic cons.
Scott: Alright a Friday badge gets you in the door on Friday.
Scott: Oh you want to do that ten bucks.
Scott: Oh you want to do that ten bucks and a lot of the stuff happens at the same time.
Scott: or You don't know where to get the tickets or only special people can get the tickets and alright You know while that's not nice and I don't like it I guess it's fair.
Scott: But what I don't think is fair is that when they promote this con to you they say hey come to the New York Comic Con Stephen King will be here.
Scott: or hey come to the New York Comic Con Wes Craven and Stan Lee will be here and you that's.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: that's a selling point to come to the con.
Scott: But coming to the con doesn't actually get you.
Scott: that it's like if I said hey buy this game It has this awesome car in this racing game, but then you buy the get racing game and the car isn't in there.
Scott: Oh you actually have to buy this other thing to have that car.
Scott: You know it's sort of like a disingenuous sell when they do that And I don't like it.
Rym: plus It's just more that the greater problem with cons like this is that Con you no matter how great a con is the content will only take you.
Rym: so far You're not.
Rym: not many people who go to these geek cons really seem to want to go to Nothing, but panels and events.
Rym: they want to spend some time hanging out with other geeks.
Rym: But you really can't do anything like this.
Rym: Yeah, there was then again at a comic-con.
Rym: I mean you all remember when I covered Philly Wizard World last year It was very difficult to strike up a conversation with anyone.
Rym: people tended to shy away if I said hello That was without a microphone.
Rym: I might add not II I didn't even have any of my stuff out.
Rym: I was just some guy saying hi trying to talk about spider-man.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I mean the primary reason I Decided to go as opposed to not go is because there were a lot of people at this convention that I knew Either from the Internet's or from real life or from whatever that I wanted to go and say hi to Hell, there were people there that I knew that I need even know we're gonna be there like the ninja consultants were there.
Scott: I'd even run into them, but they were there and I didn't know until afterwards and they did a show on it.
Scott: You know if I had saw if I had seen them there I would have stopped to chat and say hi You know and that's I think that's the number one thing that he were.
Scott: comic-con is going for.
Scott: is that a bunch of people?
Scott: I know were there.
Scott: But even when I ran into people I knew and started to talk to them like Jim Vowles or whatever we had to stand in the aisle and talk blocking the way and We couldn't talk for that long because you know, it wasn't really like a hangout.
Scott: It was just stopping and saying hi in the middle of a hallway in a busy busy convention room.
Scott: It's not like in an anime con where there's even an anime con if all you do is events and stuff.
Scott: there are lots and lots of events where you can go to the event and talk to people and And this like it's sort of like a social event or play events where you can, you know Even at a panel at an anime con there's a lot more interaction with the panelists themselves.
Scott: It's it's less of a top-down sort of thing when you go to a panel at a comic-con It's super famous guy up on the day as you sit there and be quiet and listen to what they say.
Scott: Maybe you can ask a question at the end.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: It's it's I don't know I just I really can't jive with cons like this.
Rym: I'm a social creature.
Rym: if I go to a con is mostly because I want to meet and hang out with people and Even if I wanted to do events there was really no event at this con.
Rym: Maybe just cuz I'm not much of a comic fan that interested me at all and I must say Part of the reason I went was that way back.
Rym: I used to complain like yeah comic cons.
Rym: I definitely don't like them.
Rym: They're kind of a they're not my bag and a lot of people out there are listeners and Scott said hey You can't knock it till you tried it.
Rym: Well, I went to Philly Wizard World and I went to the New York Comic Con.
Rym: I hated both of them and regretted going to them and I probably will never go to a comic-con again.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if I go back to the New York Comic Con It'll it'll have to be because like I don't know in order to get me to go back There would have to be some like awesome shit going down for me to buy the one day.
Rym: It would have to go beyond.
Rym: I mean we could get a table in the podcaster alley.
Rym: That wouldn't be difficult to do at all.
Scott: Yeah, if I got it if we had a title in the podcast alley I might sit.
Rym: see you know, what I'm saying is even if we were given one totally free unsolicited I still wouldn't go really because that means I have to for three days in a row.
Rym: Friday Saturday Sunday Take the train down to the city Walk my ass over to the Javits and sit there in a loud room not playing music not DJing not doing fun stuff just sitting there talking to people.
Scott: Oh, I don't know.
Scott: I might go if he had a podcast alley table, but that's all you.
Rym: you can run it.
Rym: Other than that you're gonna take the train every day.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: I'm thinking about it's not just a train It's a tough car.
Scott: It's the train and then walking over to is I can get the table right and I could go on Friday and If I'm not having a good time hanging out with people in the podcast arena on Friday, I could just stop coming.
Scott: I just won't show up Saturday.
Rym: You can't really do that.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: if you're gave I mean a kind like that.
Rym: if you've got one of those precious table spots It's really not cool to just not be there.
Scott: I can give it to someone else.
Rym: Oh, how are you gonna give it to some?
Scott: Artists I know or something.
Rym: Yeah, so now there's an artist sitting next to me who already has a table.
Scott: Yeah Oh even so that it it's I cannot.
Rym: yeah, I cannot think of a situation.
Rym: Well, then again, it's not just that.
Rym: I can't think of a situation where I would ever go To a fan convention in the Javits Center in New York City ever again, let alone a comic convention.
Scott: Yeah, I mean they're gonna have that anime festival in the Javits Center like what later this year.
Rym: next year I predict that's not going to go.
Scott: Well, I also predict it's not gonna go.
Scott: Well, but I somehow feel like I have to go to it to see what's gonna go.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: You said that last year about the New York Comic Con and I wisely stayed home and did whatever I did and I'm a better Man for it.
Scott: Yeah I guess now that I'm gonna be working in the city again It'll be I guess less painful because I won't have to pay for the ticket because I've already paid to go to the city Every day of the month, so it's all you.
Rym: I can't think of anything that would drag me back to a comic-con.
Scott: Yeah, it's a tough call because you're basically paying for anyone who buys a weekend pass.
Scott: you better be one hell of a comic fan who's gonna go around to every artist and spend time looking at everything in every booth and go to all the autograph sessions and Figure out how to get the secret tickets to the secret special event.
Rym: Yes, you'd better know the names all the people who draw your comics.
Rym: You're not gonna.
Scott: if you're not someone who like is fans of comic creators Like.
Scott: if you're not that nerdy there is really nothing at this con for you because you're basically gonna.
Scott: He.
Scott: there's gonna be a bunch of people who are somewhat famous, but you don't know their names You don't know who they are and that's like 90% of the cons Entertainment value right there.
Rym: So once again more important than all that Tell me about the worst anime you've ever seen.
Rym: whoever tells me about it the best gets the original soundtrack to the hit anime video.
Scott: MD guys and the New York Comic Con is a comic-con only big.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.