Rym: It's Thursday September 20th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: how to not suck at going to college part 1.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well today was awesome.
Rym: I go to get on the train and it turns out my train was canceled due to mechanical difficulties.
Scott: My train was also canceled for mechanical difficulties was Emily's.
Scott: it was the same train the same train.
Scott: So I just went home played like a round of tf2 then went back and took the next train.
Scott: I also.
Scott: that was good for me because I forgot my iPod and I was able to go and retrieve it which is a big Help because I listened to a lot of stuff today.
Rym: My iPod is actually kind of useless on the way to work unless I Drive because I have the DVD player.
Rym: I'm just watching master Keaton, and I don't really need a podcast to listen to plus.
Rym: I listen to all my podcast.
Rym: I'm all caught up, and I can't find any new ones.
Scott: I like oh Okay, all right here.
Scott: We go you ready.
Scott: Here's an awesome podcast.
Scott: I just found uh-huh it's called Old-time radio sci-fi.
Rym: no you've told me about that.
Scott: Yeah basically the deal with this podcast is they have old sci-fi radio shows from back in the day and they just put them in a Podcast for you to get.
Scott: it's not perfect.
Scott: first of all it's done by those pod show people, and I don't like them.
Scott: They're no good, and I think what they're really just doing is taking all this old Material either from an archive or from the public domain I'm not sure if it's public domain or not and they're just sticking it up in a feed And they're not doing it very well because like for example one of the things I found in this feed that I really liked was like a radio drama of Jules Verne's Journey to the Center of the Earth and Up there.
Scott: first they put up part one there's eight parts then they put up part two Then they put a part six and then they put a part seven interspersed.
Scott: as I'm not willing to put up with crap like that I listened to one and two and they were awesome, so I'm just holding off Until the rest is coming out.
Scott: actually I listened to seven by accident first because it was at the top of the feed And I just kind of got it, and it wasn't labeled properly.
Scott: But the stuff is actually really good And I like it a lot like I like it a lot more than I thought I was gonna like it.
Rym: Well, I used to listen to a lot of old radio dramas.
Rym: There's a radio station that actually had him on my drive home from work when I lived in the mountains from IBM And I listened to some radio dramas, but you know what.
Rym: they were Contiguous and every episode was directly followed by the next episode.
Scott: Yeah, that would be nice, but yeah these are.
Scott: I thought you know I wasn't sure I would enjoy these and It's sort of like gives me the same feeling as like watching the Twilight Zone.
Scott: It's really cool.
Rym: Honestly I wish there would be.
Rym: I mean there are fiction podcasts, and there are you know radio drama podcasts?
Rym: But there aren't that many and there aren't that many that are very good.
Scott: No, there aren't many that are very good.
Rym: I mean if anyone can recommend one.
Rym: I'd be welcome to it.
Rym: I already know about escape pod and pseudopod and plus those just read stories.
Rym: It's not a radio drama It's just a reading of a story.
Scott: Yeah, that's why I say I don't it's.
Scott: there's a big difference actually between like an audio book and a radio drama.
Scott: It's totally different you know and if it's if it's an audio book I kind of don't like them that much because it's like there's a book and someone's reading it.
Scott: But if it's a radio drama the people are you know acting there?
Scott: It's it's like a play only you can't see anything.
Scott: It's a totally different thing and I like it a lot more.
Rym: though the thing is I've noticed in all the old radio dramas I've ever listened to the style of acting.
Rym: Maybe it's just because that was the style of acting back then because you hear it a lot in movies, too.
Rym: But the way people talk when they're expressing one emotion versus another is just like it's almost painfully Stereotypical yeah, like it really stands out.
Rym: It doesn't bother me It just it.
Rym: it really stands out, and I can't not notice it.
Scott: another thing for me these Old-time radio sci-fi also, I tried to listen to old-time radio comedy, but it wasn't funny, but I did.
Scott: from both of these I managed to actually learn a lot about radio.
Scott: Just listening to it.
Scott: It's like ah such as What'd you learn nothing that is like you know like textbook knowledge?
Scott: But like just you know things I can hear like oh, I hear that that was clever, but like for example in the The Listens like a Jack Benny radio show right on the comedy one and the sponsor was Jell-o right and Jell-o had an announcement at the beginning of the show and they had an announcement after the show was over like you know by Jell-o, it's great for your family.
Scott: It tastes good blah blah blah right, but during the show the show was uninterrupted at all.
Scott: But they joked about Jell-o, and they made fun of the announcer and how y'all hit.
Scott: they're like ah that announcer always shut not talking about Jell-o.
Scott: He needs to shut up.
Scott: and It was really kind of clever advertising.
Scott: And I think you know like if they just took the ads off the beginning in the end and just you know did it that Way it's like you wouldn't even known there was an ad.
Scott: you just think that guy talks about Jell-o a lot And I don't think anyone would be fooled.
Scott: I don't know because they did it in a very Non fooling way.
Rym: no just the way our society especially people in our generation We're just so tuned to avoiding advertising that Anything that's in any way an ad just kind of stands out.
Scott: It wasn't intended to be but it was funny how back in the olden days of radio They tried to make the ad in obtrusive to the show and like the show was the focus And they were trying to think of this.
Rym: you went to advertising school.
Rym: They'd probably talk about how yeah, that was the old way before we discovered modern advertising techniques.
Scott: probably probably But you know it made me happier Right?
Rym: so this is all over the internet and people are expressing various levels of outrage, but apparently the Harvard bookstore
Scott: Supposedly like the one that like students go to to buy books
Rym: yeah Yeah,
Scott: okay,
Rym: supposedly kicked someone out or some people out because they were writing down the prices of the books.
Rym: Uh-huh now the thing is they're perfectly within their rights to do that.
Rym: you can kick someone out of your store for any reason as Long as it's not a protected class such as Religion race.
Scott: well as long as you don't do it because they're a protected class.
Scott: for example if there is a you know a Black person an Asian person and a white person in my Hispanic person in my store I can't be like I'm kicking out the Asian you all Asians out.
Scott: You can't do that.
Scott: But if say a black person is you know being nice and a white person is harassing them because they're like a KKK guy I could be like all right I'm kicking you out of my store because you're making a scene I can't be like.
Scott: I'm kicking you out of my store because you're.
Rym: But people are saying oh the store can't do that.
Rym: It's an outrage.
Rym: those stores are all ripoffs blah blah blah.
Rym: They are all ripoffs.
Rym: no It's not because the stores themselves aren't necessarily a ripoff because the margins on textbooks are really really razor-thin.
Scott: well It's not.
Scott: it's a. it's a combination of the store being a ripoff as well as the textbook.
Rym: Well the storage does the whatever it can because otherwise it wouldn't make any money at all.
Rym: It couldn't even exist.
Rym: and you're paying the.
Rym: when you pay the high prices at a textbook store Especially for the used books you're paying for the convenience You're not paying for anything else.
Rym: the actual ripoff is the fact that the eighth edition of a textbook is usually identical to the seventh edition.
Rym: But yet, it's a hundred and eighty dollars while the used seventh edition is five dollars.
Rym: But they'll always change a couple of the questions so that you can't actually do your homework from the seventh edition.
Scott: This is why I think that they should not put Assignments in textbooks, but they they do it because they make money.
Scott: But if I was a professor and I had the power to choose textbooks if I Liked a textbook because if you know the text in it, and I would never and I happen to have assignments I would never actually assign those assignments.
Scott: I would never make.
Rym: They don't even think that much.
Rym: It's not even that issue because I went to our a college.
Rym: You know we I went to a university and with one exception Never was I forced to buy a textbook that was actually useful to the class.
Rym: Anytime.
Rym: a professor always has the list like you gotta buy this book in this book in this book and they do like One chapter from the book and you didn't even need to read it because he just gave all the information to you in the lecture.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, it wasn't in the lecture wasn't tested or anything and he'd say oh read these chapters of the book And then read these chapters and then read these chapters, and it never came up in class at all.
Rym: It was totally told.
Rym: I told me to buy that book for no reason.
Scott: that is absolutely true.
Scott: Many oftentimes I would buy a textbook and never use it.
Scott: the only times I used a textbook were when I had say a math or physics class and I was assigned graded homework.
Rym: Oh see you forget that I had my no homework policy.
Rym: so even if that were the case I still did graded homework.
Scott: I didn't do non graded homework.
Rym: I didn't do graded homework.
Scott: some teachers would say read you know read these chapters.
Scott: I never read those chapters unless it was a literature class in which case I would get the book read it and keep it.
Rym: I Still didn't.
Rym: but that's because I had to read tree of red stars.
Rym: No, no, I never owned that.
Rym: I never read that book.
Scott: I took other literature classes like real ones.
Scott: later with real books.
Rym: I didn't and honestly what I usually did because most classes the professor would assign the book or whatever.
Rym: But it didn't matter except in my PTC classes.
Rym: But it was just that they'd say we have to use the book and they'd refer to the book and that sort of thing.
Rym: But they'd always say you gotta buy this edition.
Rym: if I bought a textbook at all I always just bought the previous edition and dealt with it.
Rym: and if there were assignments I Paid someone in the class who was dumb enough to buy the book a dollar or two to let me copy the questions from his book.
Rym: Yeah or my favorite thing to do was to Buy the book and then return it for a refund within seven days after having Xeroxed all the assignments out of it.
Scott: That's a good move too.
Rym: or even better I'd go to the bookstore open it do the homework really quick in the bookstore and then close it and leave.
Scott: that also works.
Scott: Basically College textbooks are a ripoff all around.
Scott: they make you buy ones You don't need.
Scott: the bookstore has a huge markup.
Scott: the publisher charges way too much for them and keeps changing them.
Scott: It's it's just not good at all and you should do your best to do everything within your power to avoid spending and every save as much possible money on textbooks as you can.
Scott: if you absolutely need to have a book then Buy it like used at the biggest discount you can.
Scott: if you don't need the current edition get the old edition.
Scott: if you don't need The book don't buy the book.
Rym: Well, the most important thing is pay attention because if you ever have a professor who says yeah buy the previous edition of this book.
Rym: They're almost guaranteed to be a good professor.
Rym: and also watch out for professors who?
Rym: Tell you to buy specific books and don't do much with them.
Rym: a lot of times either They wrote that book or one of their friend professors wrote that book and they're making money off of it.
Rym: And that might sound evil and shady.
Rym: and you know what that happened a lot at RIT.
Scott: yeah, I think I took like two or three classes where a professor told me to buy their book.
Scott: and You know the thing is I usually didn't but a couple times they'd be like yeah I know I'm telling you to buy my book So I'm just gonna give you all copies of it cuz I can.
Scott: cuz my book and I think one time They're just like yeah, I'm gonna make my book optional.
Scott: Just you know cuz whatever I guess Whenever you have to take a class and oh one time one of the dudes books was a pamphlet.
Scott: so I bought it.
Rym: Just look at the what books are assigned and don't buy them right away.
Rym: Wait and try to figure out if you actually need the book or not because in all seriousness At least half the time you don't need that book.
Scott: Yeah, this is mostly for freshmen who always go in with their parents like and before school even starts.
Scott: You know when they're moving into the dorms they go to the bookstore and they buy every single book.
Scott: It says two on the list.
Rym: in fact I'm gonna give you all a little hint cuz I know your parents don't listen to GeekNights.
Rym: If you're going to college and your parents are going to buy your books for your first quarter or semester or whatever say yes Let them buy every single book even the optional book all the books you need.
Rym: take the list of books that your professor said you Need
Scott: and get every one of them and
Rym: then as soon as they leave return all the books except the ones you need
Scott: Exactly
Rym: now also the bookstore at any college is always gonna try to Take your books back like you bought a book for a hundred bucks And then at the end they say hey, we'll buy your used textbooks back and resell them.
Rym: They're gonna resell that book for like $90.
Scott: It's the same thing with selling blood is selling video games to GameStop.
Scott: All right used to give it to GameStop for ten bucks.
Scott: They sell it for ten bucks.
Rym: You realize most colleges are gonna give you like four dollars for your hundred dollar textbook.
Scott: This is why you go on Amazon or eBay and you sell it and you're not gonna be able to sell it.
Rym: you go Find out when the next class of that is scheduled the next semester.
Rym: show up on the first day Outside the room and say here's the textbook 50 bucks that worked.
Rym: It's so wonderfully and I the school will try to stop you sometimes do it.
Rym: Anyway, it's totally worth it.
Scott: that works.
Rym: if you're too lazy to eBay or Amazon Because you'll get better prices you'll get instant cash.
Rym: and if you're really clever What you do is stand by at the end of a semester the used bookstore thing because usually one.
Rym: they'll have a bin Where you can throw the books that they're not gonna buy.
Rym: the scam there is.
Rym: they'll just take that bin and then sell those books.
Rym: Anyway, yep What you do is listen and as soon as they offer someone money for a book immediately say I'll give you 20 bucks for it Or I'll give you five bucks more or ten bucks more and just buy all the books and then resell them.
Scott: That's tough.
Rym: It's not tough at all.
Rym: the only problem is the bookstore is eventually gonna call campus safety and all you have to do is Leave and then come back as soon as campus safety is gone.
Rym: or get a friend to do it for you or sell them Just outside his site like around the corner Like as someone's walking up to sell the books.
Rym: just say I'll give you five bucks more than whatever they offer for every single book You try to sell.
Rym: just come back to me.
Scott: You're gonna be like this illegal book dealer I know but it's it's sort of it's you know, you're gonna be like a guy with like a trench coat.
Rym: I got textbooks But the thing is it's perfectly legal and actually a lot of bookstores are gonna try to lie to you and say that you can't resell the books.
Rym: a lot of Bookstores gonna lie to you and say that you can't use the old edition.
Rym: The professor's won't allow it.
Rym: if you ask a professor like if I did this once we had to get the eighth edition of some Bullshit public speaking book and we actually needed it because there were assignments in it.
Rym: So I asked the professor if I could get away with using the seventh edition and she thought for a minute and said you know What?
Rym: yeah, probably I don't think anything changed.
Rym: and then the next week She tells the class.
Rym: Yes, so Rym over there cuz I my professors knew I was named Rym usually Said that the seventh edition is the same as the eighth edition and it's only ten bucks.
Rym: So go buy that one and if you bought the other book, I'm sorry return.
Scott: All right, let's done.
Scott: We're done with the textbooks now.
Rym: Well, it's kind of relevant to what we're doing tonight.
Scott: So are we gonna do that tonight?
Scott: I thought we didn't decide yet.
Rym: Well, I decided right now cuz it's kind of a anyway.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Yeah, we're lazy We're tired.
Rym: I want to eat and we weren't sure what we were gonna do the show on.
Scott: I do actual news now.
Rym: You got news.
Scott: I do have a news.
Rym: What's it about?
Scott: Well, basically, this is lady who's in some Evil homeowners association and you know how much we hate homeowners associations because they are the living embodiment of evil And they just evil very specifically the kind of evil that like Alright, so the u.s.
Rym: Isn't faded foreign nations and there's genocide going on.
Scott: That's more evil than homeowners associations.
Rym: But what I was about to say is whatever I mean not from a real, you know human perspective or my personal perspective But from a has a chance to affect my life directly right now.
Scott: yeah, a homeowner's Association basically is a group of people that say we care more about money and Feeling good about ourselves and feeling powerful then we care about freedom and civil liberties and right and wrong.
Rym: Oh the way a homeowner's association works in the United States because a lot of people might not be familiar with this really simply is That they're usually attached to the deed of land that you buy and you can't opt out of it.
Scott: Or you can you can live somewhere else.
Scott: That's your choice.
Rym: Yeah, your choices live somewhere else, but a lot of land in the?
Rym: u.s.
Rym: now if you want to buy a house on it, you have to agree to this homeowners association and everyone who lives in a certain area is bound by it and you have little elections to decide who in the community is going to run it.
Rym: and you have a little board of directors and you all have to pay dues and basically Anything the board votes.
Rym: You have to do if the vote board just decided to vote that all houses have to be painted pink If you don't paint your house pink you get fucking evicted.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you buy it.
Scott: This isn't like I'm renting a place and as a landlord this is I own the land I have a mortgage.
Scott: I own the house.
Scott: It belongs to me, but in order.
Rym: well, it belongs to the bank, right?
Scott: Well, okay.
Scott: I paid off my mortgage.
Scott: I own.
Scott: Let's say you do.
Scott: let's let's say you paid off the mortgage.
Scott: it doesn't matter I own the land in the house.
Scott: They belong to me.
Scott: I have the deed everything It's all mine, but when I bought the land, I was forced to sign a contract.
Scott: otherwise, they would refuse to sell the land to me.
Scott: and when I signed that contract I agreed that I would do whatever the homeowner Association said.
Scott: and If they say paint my house pink and I don't they can kick me out of the house that I own Owning it belongs.
Scott: That's like if I came to you and I said, oh, that's a nice Computer you got there that you bought.
Scott: Yeah, too Even though you own that computer belongs to you.
Scott: when you bought it you sign this contract that says I can pee on it.
Scott: You have to let me pee on it.
Scott: You have to let me.
Scott: and basically The story here is that there's some lady who lives this.
Scott: actually stories like this happen every day.
Rym: But if you want to see him read far, yeah stories like this happen every single day.
Scott: but this particular one is in the Wall Street Journal and I think it's Pretty good because it's actually people standing up for themselves rather than just homeowners associations peeing on everybody.
Rym: granted There was a recent story where a homeowners association got sued by all the members of it and all All the members.
Rym: Well, not all the members less than the majority.
Scott: Oh good But basically what happens is this lady set up a clothesline which is apparently banned in the vast majority of homeowners Because clothes lines make your area look very low income, you know.
Rym: How does someone not have a washer and dryer?
Rym: or you know, we have a washer and there's a dryer right there But I use a clothesline anyway, because I like to write.
Scott: so she set up a clothesline and the person next door was person.
Scott: the person next door thought it was just temporary that you know because maybe the dryer broke or something.
Scott: and then The person kept putting it up.
Scott: and then they complained to the homeowners association.
Scott: and now the ladies having to fight.
Scott: but she's apparently got a few friends in the homeowners Association because Person across the street is thinking about setting one up too.
Rym: Well, remember here's the modus operandi of a homeowners Association.
Rym: This is why it's so hard to fight them because you think all right They can't do anything too stupid because the majority of people in your little community have to vote and the majority of people living In a suburb can't be stupid.
Scott: Can they done done done one?
Rym: yeah, they're run by you and you get to vote but who has time to deal with that if they also have a job?
Scott: the Vast majority of people who are active in homeowners associations or even though they exist are old biddies and crotchety old men and People who care about their property value more than they care about anything else because there's just people who sit around taking care of their property.
Scott: I mean people who people are people who like the kind of person who would live in a house That's in the homeowners Association.
Scott: because I mean you go look at these houses and it's in a place where all the houses look the Same and they all have really well-tended lawns and they're all clean and they're all right Because that's what the homeowners Association makes you do.
Scott: so the person who likes who really cares about the fact that all the houses on the street look the same and look nice is The kind of person who's gonna move into this kind of place.
Scott: and thus if you aren't that kind of person and you move in You're surrounded by all these people who care about what your property looks like and they'll be upset If the other person's things don't match their things and that sort of thing and now to
Rym: mope because you know people who have lives don't bother with this because they don't care.
Rym: unless there's an egregious thing like When your neighbor scraps the 19th car in his front lawn I don't see a problem with the homeowners Association intervening at that point.
Scott: No, but if I have you know, if I decide that I'm gonna be you know, I'm a mechanic I like to work on cars and I have an old Camaro and I want to work on it in my driveway.
Scott: That's not.
Scott: you're not allowed to do that in most homeowners Association.
Scott: No, I'm not even allowed to own a car that's older than like this were over six years.
Rym: Even if this were actually a legitimate democracy It wouldn't be that bad because people should generally have the right to self-govern.
Rym: I think the issue is that you know, like I was saying most of the people are old biddies and crotchety But there's no minority rights in a homeowners Association.
Rym: Well, I was gonna get to that.
Scott: if you are just captain interrupting tonight because you're taking so long here We got to get to the main bit.
Rym: You're the one who brought this news up, you know, and we've talked about this before.
Rym: I just won't say anything then.
Scott: All right, fine.
Rym: So the other inch I thought you were gonna stop if you're gonna go.
Scott: I gotta say the last interesting thing that you've been preventing me from saying what's interesting because so far this is like every other homeowners story because Apparently there are laws in some states that set that put that Restrict certain things that homeowners associations are not allowed to ban.
Scott: For example in some states homeowners associations are not allowed to band like solar heating and solar electricity Generating equipment and things like that.
Scott: and this clothesline lady is claiming at some you know It's an environmental thing to use the clothesline because you're not using like dryers I think are like the third most electricity using things in houses and stuff like that.
Rym: Yeah, I mean even if you have a gas dryer they cost a lot of money to run Oh and a lot of power and energy.
Scott: So in some states, I think two states Clotheslines you're specifically not allowed to ban them because they are solar energy like equipment.
Rym: So is this lady in one of those states?
Scott: No But she oh.
Scott: she's in one of those states where it's questionable and it's not Explicitly written that clotheslines are not allowed or you know not allowed to be banned But solar stuff is not allowed to be banned.
Scott: So she's got.
Scott: she might have to fight in court to say so.
Rym: the clothesline is a solar equipment something You know, the moral is pretty simple, even though a lot of places you might want to move have homeowners associations.
Rym: Don't move where there's one.
Rym: don't ever move.
Rym: while they can be used for good The majority of them are used for evil the evil of old bitty cat.
Scott: ladies unless you really you know Care more about what your neighbor's lawn looks like then you care about your freedom to do whatever.
Rym: Because it's not that if you have a job or something You're not gonna be able to participate in this stupid homeowners Association.
Rym: because these people tend to set it up so that the meetings are always at like two o'clock on a Wednesday because they know All the real people can't show up because they have jobs or stuff to do.
Scott: Yep Well, that's the other thing is they don't want those kind of people living there.
Scott: They want like, you know a nice typical American family.
Scott: Well, one person goes to work and one person stays home to go the homeowners.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and you know 1.5 kids and two cars They don't want like two 20 year old guys who were a Commuting in Tekken and setting up all sorts of cables and wires and dishes and antennas and air hockey's in the basement.
Scott: They don't want that.
Rym: Oh, man Yeah Okay Anyway things of the day.
Rym: I'll be real brief about this because I don't think much need to be said.
Rym: The view is probably the most facile garbage talk show in the english-speaking world.
Rym: I don't think anyone does.
Scott: I've only heard of it because people keep like saying stuff about it on dig.
Rym: It's just it's.
Rym: No, it's for idiots.
Scott: All I know is that it's like a show with a bunch of ladies on in the morning talking about stupid shit.
Rym: but here's the thing this one.
Rym: there's a woman on here who was a creationist and whatever and whoopi Goldberg is on and She is very delicately trying to put forth that maybe this woman hasn't quite thought her clever plan all the way through and aside from the fact this woman just keeps interrupting and Really just doesn't say anything worthwhile nor does anyone else sitting around this table except whoopi Goldberg.
Rym: But the woman in all seriousness did not know if the earth was flat or round.
Rym: Honestly didn't.
Scott: I saw him dig something today where like they were trying to cover up for her or something.
Scott: But it's obvious when you watch this video.
Scott: She does not know if the world is round or flat.
Rym: She starts acting like yeah, it's something I'd look up in a textbook.
Rym: and then everyone else starts getting these looks of And they start trying to dig into her.
Rym: and She starts trying like she starts to realize that something's wrong something she just said is wrong.
Rym: and she gets this flustered look on her face and she just starts spouting more and more drivel.
Rym: and This woman seriously did not know if the earth was round or flat.
Rym: and if her kid asked her that question I she said I best be getting to the library.
Scott: Yeah, you hear kid probably come home from school and tell you what's what but this is you know This is just further a I guess supporting something that the view is terrible.
Scott: Besides that is it something I've learned in recent years.
Scott: Is that you know, we always say Oh, most people are stupid.
Scott: blah, you know And you see like funny things were like some guy on a game show doesn't know if the world is.
Scott: you know that the earth?
Scott: Revolves around the Sun.
Scott: he says the Sun revolves around the earth or something like that, right and you say all these stupid people Famous people are just as stupid.
Scott: just you know, I don't know.
Rym: if she was famous She might have just been on and she's on a TV show.
Scott: She's I guess famous enough.
Scott: She might not be super famous like, you know, I guess Steven Spielberg famous.
Rym: It's kind of like how a lot of actors get really into social activism even if they don't understand the issues They hand.
Scott: but famous people are just as stupid as the rest of us don't Say.
Scott: I
Rym: would like to point out that despite the fact that the view is just a terrible show and nothing worthwhile has ever come out of it When this woman went beyond the like beyond the black of stupidity like beyond the edge of the stupidity universe Into the unknown void where they're there aren't be dragons because dragons are smarter than that.
Scott: Yeah, there's There's.
Rym: it's where the front fell off.
Rym: Yeah But everyone else on that table Obviously had this moment of while that woman's stupid even though they couldn't say it outright.
Scott: see that's the other problem.
Scott: Is that just in with television in general?
Scott: I guess also on a show that's watched by you know, stupid people stupid people and is like.
Scott: You know that that kind of show like a morning talk show is not the kind of show where people want like yelling and like Wow, you're dumb on it.
Scott: You know, that's they save.
Scott: that I do But they do.
Scott: those shows are mostly saved for like the late-night Comedy Central types.
Scott: They're not the early morning network television types.
Scott: And I think that's a problem with television and a reason why there's a lot more is a lot less skeptical and Don't think about it this way.
Rym: You're you're a business and you want to put something on TV that's gonna get people who are up at whatever time to watch your Thing.
Rym: so what will make people be more inclined to go?
Rym: Ah and keep watching and feel good about themselves.
Rym: some woo-woo psychic lady saying yeah And you know just talking about how she's a psychic and she found the kidnapped kid with her fave psychic powers.
Rym: or James Randi saying That's not true.
Rym: and here's proof.
Rym: One's a lot more interesting even though it's completely made up.
Scott: Well, I think the difference is would you rather watch some people going chatty chatty chatty chatty chatty?
Scott: Like they're in a coffee shop, or do you rather someone going?
Scott: Wow, you are stupid and you should be going back to elementary school because you don't know if the earth is.
Rym: Whoopi Goldberg was making a very Diplomatic point and she was doing it in a very conciliatory manner and not just let loose and said wow You're a dumbass.
Rym: well even that she didn't do that.
Rym: the fact that the the stupid indignant woman just kept interrupting her and wouldn't Even let her finish her very conciliatory Remark was quite.
Scott: I think we just need some sort of thing where we can just say well You have to go back to elementary school.
Scott: You're not allowed to work.
Rym: I am of the mind that anyone who wants further education of sir I mean obviously not everyone should get.
Rym: you know medical training.
Rym: now I'm done.
Rym: I think any adult in this country should be eligible to get Basic schooling if I think they should be forced to get it if they need it.
Scott: All right, anyway.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: so you played the Oregon trails?
Rym: It's one of the my favorite games ever.
Scott: you got dysentery.
Rym: See it was always like the.
Rym: you know your thing sank in the river.
Rym: you lost four Bullets and a hundred pounds of food.
Scott: and Billy right well that game You know you can set up emulators and play the Apple to version and there are ways to play that game still.
Scott: But it's not the easiest thing to get a hold of and get running on your system Especially not perfectly.
Scott: and some guy made a remake of Oregon Trail in flash, but to bring it up to the modern times He he re-themed it, and he called it thule trail.
Scott: I guess the company is the thule company.
Rym: Oh, I know that company.
Scott: Yeah, whatever they make software I guess but it's bit It's a road trip.
Scott: You know a modern road trip and like you to just to give you an idea the theme of the game is real quick.
Scott: Instead of going to the store to buy wagon wheels at the beginning of the game and you know oxen You go to Clem's mini-mart in Chicago And you buy magazines and games food and drinks music pellets and car parts And you choose instead of choosing like the type of wagon you choose like between the SUV the speed wagon or the sports car.
Scott: It seems you know it's.
Scott: it's got the same gameplay as the old Oregon Trail for the Apple - But it's got the re theming of modern times And I think it's pretty fun for anyone who looking for an Oregon Trail in flash.
Scott: when huh?
Rym: So I was looking to see if I was sure cuz I didn't remember if it was thule or another company I was thinking of but according to Wikipedia here thule is also a title of an ancient possibly not having existed island Thule.
Scott: yes, Sweden Sweden it says thule and then in like the L and the E sort of combined and it says Sweden in there I think it's a Swedish software developer.
Scott: ah Yeah, all right, it's thule trail calm all right, whatever.
Rym: It's not Cthulhu, so yeah, it's all Cthulhu based, Oregon Trail You're trying to get to really yeah, ooh.
Scott: You're trying to get out Really really a trail.
Scott: It's got to be made.
Rym: It would be perfect if the map was just made up as you go and didn't actually go anyway.
Scott: Hey, the cult is five dollars to get across the burning sea.
Rym: oh, but they hate you anyway.
Rym: Billy has dysentery.
Rym: Billy has died of insanity.
Rym: So Luckily I guess my news sparked a conversation along these lines, but tonight We're gonna begin another one of those long-running series that won't be updated.
Scott: so I feel like we've done an episode or two of this before Especially in the early days of the show.
Rym: I think we've done this specific thing and we haven't.
Rym: I kind of want to break it up more into actual specific advice.
Scott: Yeah, it is often asked.
Scott: It's like one of the most common questions we get in emails and forums and things and a lot of people really suck at it.
Rym: So the question tonight is what is semprene?
Scott: Well you see In 1957 or 58 right?
Rym: The topic tonight is how to not suck at going to college part one.
Scott: well mostly today We're gonna concentrate on the stuff before college from the time when you're just a kid in high school To the time where you say this is what I'm gonna do.
Scott: That's the stuff.
Rym: Yep part of it's because a lot of people Particularly people from colleges are going to throw you a line and feed you one at the same time.
Rym: They're going to lie in any way they can to get you to go to their school Basically everything your high school tells you about going to college.
Scott: now They do have your your best interests at heart usually like your guidance counselors and stuff.
Scott: But they don't know as much as they you know, it seems like they know.
Scott: they just know a lot more than you.
Scott: So it seems like they know everything.
Scott: it is their job.
Scott: They must know they don't know shit.
Rym: I mean here's an example.
Rym: I went to my guidance counselor who I'd never met when I was a junior in high school And I said high school guidance counselor.
Rym: I think I want to go into computers or music.
Rym: What should I do?
Rym: and he said well if you want to go into computers?
Rym: You should go into a major called computer science so and go to like MIT or Caltech.
Rym: I was like okay, and what about music?
Rym: He's like you don't want to go into music.
Rym: Not only that but that was the extent of his knowledge of everything I wanted.
Scott: that was it.
Scott: my guidance counselor was pretty similar.
Scott: I mean he didn't know about like smaller schools or any.
Scott: you know they don't really know.
Rym: you have to do No, no he also of course.
Rym: He said well.
Rym: We'll go to U of M too because everyone went to U of M.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean like.
Scott: they didn't know about schools like say Rose-Hulman or even CMU or not.
Rym: even then He didn't know that there were majors other than computer science.
Rym: think about this, and this is a problem.
Rym: this is a huge problem in the computer industry because Computer science is not the major it used to be.
Rym: but I don't think anyone at the high school level knows that.
Rym: I mean I didn't know it when I was in high school and no one none of my teachers knew it.
Scott: No one you think your guidance counselor knows the difference between IT Software engineering computer science electrical engineering computer engineering or micro electronic engineering applied networking.
Scott: now They're all super different.
Scott: they all super matter.
Scott: But if you don't know that when you're in high school because your guidance counselor doesn't freaking know What do you got to do your own research, and you can't be relying on those guidance counseling yep?
Rym: I mean think about it.
Rym: I went to RIT for an orientation thing and I was like yeah I want to be a computer science major, and they were like oh really coding coding coding coding.
Rym: I was like what about Networking and engineering?
Rym: like oh, that's a different major that you've never heard of.
Scott: yeah So the first thing you have to do in high school before even thinking about college is what do you want to do?
Scott: I mean, maybe you want to be a mechanic or something like that you got.
Scott: maybe you want to be a fireman Maybe you want to be you know an astronaut me because you're still in kindergarten.
Scott: now.
Rym: more importantly when you think about what you want To do try not to think along the standard lines because there are a million awesome careers out there That no one's ever going to tell you about and you're gonna find out about him long after it's too late.
Scott: I know like since I've started working.
Scott: I see all these jobs about and I start to realize wow that's someone's job like Underwater welding or like dude you make so much money underwater.
Scott: well super dangerous But you make so much money.
Scott: if I own if only I'd known you know you could even like within Careers that are obvious.
Scott: like you think about teaching.
Scott: Oh, I don't want to be a teacher But then no one tells you oh you didn't even realize you could be a shop teacher.
Scott: Oh, I would totally be a shop teacher.
Scott: There's a zillion careers out there in the world and most of them You just won't even think about because they're sort of obvious, but non obvious They're hiding in plain sight.
Rym: a good example was printing like printing science and color science and all those things.
Rym: because I Didn't even think about that and I heard after I got to RIT Yeah, RIT has like a good program in that.
Rym: now RIT has a world-famous program in that and you can make a zillion dollars Doing it.
Scott: so what no one does.
Rym: one of our friends one of my friends from high school actually went to RIT and went Into that major and I thought oh whatever printing something His job is awesome.
Rym: I would love to have his job.
Rym: if I'd known that major was what I didn't know it was I would have gone into it and forget IT packaging science.
Scott: racecar driver.
Scott: Damn, racecar driver didn't think of that job.
Rym: Yeah, you realize that that's an option.
Rym: seriously It's not like.
Rym: oh you like you might think about world-famous racecar driver.
Scott: It may be a little difficult, but Professional racecar driver making money definitely an option.
Scott: yeah.
Rym: So if you think you want to do something even if it's out land It's just do some research and find out what it takes.
Scott: work in the air hockey Manufacturing factory, I don't think that's the greatest job.
Scott: No, but it could be a job.
Scott: There are jobs out there.
Rym: there are there are two and there are exceptions to this and I've known some of them.
Rym: So this is not 100% like Perfect law, but generally if you don't know what you want to do, and you don't have a clear plan forward You probably either shouldn't go to college right away It's.
Rym: or if you go to college don't go to a major university Don't go to any don't do anything expensive.
Scott: like.
Scott: if you don't know what you want to do either Go to your community college and just take classes that you think are fun and try to figure out what you want to do while you bide your time.
Scott: or Maybe you know I mean a lot of people just went right into jobs without going to college.
Scott: You know like Steve Jobs Yeah, Steve Wozniak or Bill Gates dropped out of college.
Rym: You know if you're gonna go to an expensive college like RIT or Caltech or Yale or something you better know what the fuck you're Doing before you go there.
Rym: because and RIT this was so prevalent where someone RIT Someone would come to RIT and they'd go undeclared me or they'd go into a major and then realize they didn't like it.
Rym: Yeah, but usually because that's okay because you think you won't like it and that's at least a start.
Rym: But a lot of people came to RIT Undeclared and RIT even acted like this is an option and they act.
Scott: they did act like it was an option.
Rym: It's not an option.
Rym: It's not so you show up, and you start taking class.
Rym: It was
Scott: an option if you want to lose a lot of money
Rym: and the thing is at any like major University particularly in tech and science fields if you don't know exactly what you're doing And you don't plan out all the classes you're gonna take pretty much forever from the start The prerequisites and all the things that are gonna get in your way are gonna totally fuck you And you'll be there a lot longer than you expect.
Scott: yeah I mean if you go to RIT And you know exactly what you want to do and you stick with it the whole time and you were right that was what you Wanted to do five years, and you'll be okay.
Scott: If you don't know what you want to do you might be there six years minimum probably seven years.
Rym: That'll basically cost you hundreds of thousands of dollars because a lot of those you know general non matriculated Whatever class is don't actually count for anything in a lot of majors nope.
Scott: So you got to figure out what you want to do in life And then before let's say you figure out what you want to do you decide I'm gonna be this I'm gonna be that.
Scott: Well if you decide you want to be a doctor you have to go to medical school you have to get super good grades You're gonna spend like the next ten years of your life Being in hospitals and doctor schools and all sorts of stuff and you have to get ready and do that because that's the way to Be a doctor.
Scott: if you're gonna be a mechanic.
Scott: go to the vocational school in your town learn to be a mechanic Get a job at like a firestone or something and be a mechanic.
Scott: You don't need to go to college.
Scott: why spend money Going to college getting drunk for five years when you didn't have to do that?
Scott: you could have gone right to work.
Rym: Well the reason for that and I think this is probably the crux of the issue.
Rym: I've been saying that a lot lately in all our shows like this is the crux.
Rym: This is the base.
Rym: This is the the important part.
Rym: yep anyway the crux of the issue is the college particularly University.
Rym: I Think the primary thing that I got out of college was not my IT knowledge or my computer knowledge or my PTC knowledge or anything I learned from the classes.
Rym: nope it was the college experience.
Rym: yep And if you go to a college and you fit like you're in a major and as long as you don't absolutely hate the major It's making your life miserable, but say you get two years into I don't know computer engineering you decide You don't really want to do it as a career.
Rym: It's generally not in your best interest to switch majors because then you basically have to start over.
Rym: However if you finish the major finish the degree at least you're gonna be able to get a job and more importantly you still get The full college experience, which is the important thing of going to college.
Rym: You'll learn a lot more about life and living and friendship and all that you know stuff.
Rym: Then you're gonna learn in your classes.
Rym: Yeah, and a lot of you learn stuff in my classes.
Scott: I mean some most of the class well some of the class yeah, but now that was worth it.
Rym: You know and if I didn't learn that it would have been sort of a waste to go and spend all that money like I'll Say this the things I did in the RIT anime club have affected my life a lot more than any class I took at RIT.
Scott: That's for sure.
Scott: So so you have to you know before you go to college.
Scott: you have to.
Scott: you know.
Scott: It seems like a lot of people just go to college by default like they don't even think about it like after high school.
Scott: you Go to college.
Scott: It's like grade 13.
Rym: Yeah, it's kind of the same thing that costs a lot of people like all right.
Rym: I'm out of college get a job All right, I got a job time to get married.
Rym: all right.
Rym: I'm married.
Rym: gotta have kids all right.
Scott: Got to send the kids to college got a diner to retirement home after you graduate high school And you're 18 at least in the United States.
Scott: You are now free to do as you please.
Scott: I mean if you want certain things you're going to have to do certain things to get those.
Scott: like if you want to have a House you're going to need a job and money.
Scott: Which means you if you want to you know a certain kind of house in a certain place you might need a higher paying job And thus you might need college.
Scott: But you have to figure out what you want and then figure out how to get it.
Scott: and don't go Doing a college thing Unless you decide that's what you really want to do with your life for four years.
Rym: Or if it's something you need to do yeah think about it this way If you're gonna go to college, and you know you're gonna pick a college, and I'll just think to yourself What do I actually want to get out of this and list everything?
Rym: I mean it might be degree and the experience of college, and that's fine Because maybe it's spend five years in a fret.
Rym: That's fine as long as you realize exactly what you were going to give up And what the opportunity cost is to get what you have decided you want.
Scott: Yep, now if you there's also a lot of other options you can consider.
Scott: Let's say you decide you really want to go to college and study Literature.
Scott: right because you want to be like I don't know an English teacher or an author or like a book publisher or something like that A librator.
Scott: Right well you go to library science for that which is needs a master's degree, but You decide you want to do that.
Scott: That's what you really want to do.
Scott: You know you worked in a library in high school.
Scott: You're all about the books.
Scott: so you go But you don't have a lot of money.
Scott: But you really want to get a degree from this really fancy school because that will let you get the job of the fancy library You really want to work at.
Scott: you can save a lot of money by going to community college for like two years then Transferring to the real college.
Scott: I know a lot of people who did that and they ended up.
Scott: You know they actually went to a community college.
Scott: They learned a lot there because they found a good one.
Scott: They didn't spend much money there because it's super cheap they and in the end they basically got the degree from the better school, but only having to go for the bet to the better school for two or three years or two and a half years and They paid like half price.
Scott: It's like discount degree.
Rym: another way to go about this is now there's something else in some other places But in most of the United States, there's something called Advanced placement classes in high school.
Rym: hmm it is in your best interest to take these classes and then take the AP tests even though They cost money because The vast majority of colleges in the United States will accept these as college credit for a lot of classes And you can basically get the same effect as going to community college in high school.
Rym: I mean I went into RIT with 41 credits taken care of from the Tests that I took in high school and another eight from community college.
Scott: Yep, that's one of the only two things that actually matters in high school.
Scott: don't listen to anyone who tells you otherwise Yeah, your grades don't matter.
Rym: well on getting like as long as you have a decent G.
Scott: Well the grades matter.
Scott: it depends what you want to do again If you want to go to Harvard you need that like 4.0 GPA or something.
Scott: But if you decide that Harvard isn't for you that you not really need to go there You don't want to be like a Harvard lawyer.
Rym: if you want to go to RIT at 1.8 It's fine.
Scott: if you just want to go to your state school You can get some C's and stuff in high school.
Rym: It depends like in Michigan actually University of Michigan.
Rym: It was super fucking hard to get in.
Scott: couldn't you go to Michigan State though?
Rym: You could.
Rym: Michigan State just is awesome.
Rym: My brother actually went there.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I'm just saying it was you know What actually I would say.
Rym: Michigan State was a much more fun campus though U of M was a much more serious business campus.
Rym: No, I don't know.
Rym: I prefer the latter.
Rym: Anyway, well, you know, let's skip all it cuz that's actually a really important thing Even if you know you think all right I want to be a whatever.
Rym: so I've got to go to Yale because Yale is the best school for that It does.
Rym: if a school is good if good enough for something Then you don't need to worry about it because if you want to go to like the best school in the field.
Rym: That's a whole different ballgame but Much more important than going to the good school in your major is going to a school that you're going to be able to live At and joy and prosper in for four or five years.
Scott: Yeah If you end up like a lot of people Transfer from schools because they can't hack it like people who transfer out of RIT not because they want to leave but because they can't Deal with it or they get there and they don't like it.
Scott: That is not good.
Scott: going from community college to real college because that was your plan is good.
Scott: Transferring between colleges because you got there and you didn't like it is bad.
Scott: That was poor planning.
Scott: It cost you a lot of money and it cost you a lot of time.
Rym: now We've got a case in point.
Rym: a lot of people, you know They want to be an IT major because they find out oh, yeah IT there's a lot of money in that and they don't have to code so much which is kind of a lie, but Alright, so I want to go to IT.
Rym: Oh, well the best IT school in the country nay the world is probably the Rochester Institute of Technology.
Rym: I should obviously go there.
Rym: That is when you want to stop and think about it because okay It's a great IT school, but there are other IT schools and every college campus is totally different.
Rym: Even if you want to be an IT major RIT might not be the one of play the place you want to live.
Rym: You might not enjoy RIT.
Rym: A lot of people don't like living at RIT and freak out and have to leave.
Scott: there are a lot of things that are different at a lot of schools that you know aren't obvious.
Scott: and Remember when you go to a school and the people there, you know, even the students, right?
Scott: They're trying to sell you the school.
Scott: don't think that you're going to look to buy a school and they're just you know.
Scott: Being all honest.
Scott: They have a school.
Scott: you're going to pay them a zillion dollars if you go there.
Scott: They are salesmen.
Scott: They are going to only tell you the good things and they're not going to tell you the bad things.
Rym: Yeah, if you show up at RIT for those parents weekends, like check it out.
Rym: Your kids should come here.
Rym: Check it out kids You should come here.
Rym: RIT Redoes the landscaping right before the parents come like they put in landscaping.
Rym: the campus looks beautiful for like two weeks.
Rym: And then after the parents leave and you've committed and you've paid money and you're now at the school That landscaping all disappears and then the snows come and the snows don't stop and you're trapped.
Scott: This isn't just RIT there.
Scott: We're not picking on RIT.
Scott: every example Every school has hidden secrets like that.
Scott: things that you know, they might you know, tell you about them But they'll make them seem like good things.
Scott: like they'll say RIT has this great quarter system But if you can't hack dealing with an entire class in ten weeks, you know and doing three freaking quarters a year They're calm quarters because the summer quarter.
Scott: But if you can't deal with three ten week periods of taking classes a year and a lot less Vacation than other schools that have semester systems.
Scott: You're going to bomb at RIT.
Scott: It'll be very unpleasant for you.
Rym: And also this campus does not look the way it normally does when you visited for some sort of orientation or pre weekend or whatever.
Rym: So whenever you're thinking about a college very simply go to whatever event they you know.
Rym: Say like oh come and see the college on this day because they get a lot of information.
Rym: Go back to the college sometime in the middle of a quarter or semester like go midterms and go unannounced.
Scott: Don't be like going to the admissions office being all like, you know, yeah I want to come for a tour and then they'll have someone guide you around.
Scott: No Just go to the school and just show up and we'll look around while people are taking.
Scott: Hang out in the quads go to the library go to the gym go to the coffee shop walk through Go anywhere that non students, you know can get around to without being suspicious.
Rym: So in the end, I mean we could go on about this forever and we're probably gonna do a lot more shows about.
Rym: You know things like how to actually show up at college because you know a lot of people show up with like a UPS you Gigantic truck just full of crap that won't fit in the room.
Scott: and some people show up and then over the years they get rid Of all the crap they realize.
Rym: but then some people show up like without bedsheets.
Rym: Well, we can.
Rym: that'll be an episode in of itself.
Rym: But the moral of this one is pretty simple.
Rym: Don't trust what anyone tells.
Scott: you do your own research and do a lot of research into everything the school the major What you want to do with your life, etc.
Scott: Don't don't like don't leave any stone Unturned don't do what Donny don't does.
Scott: and also it's good to know what you want to do.
Scott: And you know, if you're having a hard time knowing what you want to do Well think about what you do all day if you just click on dig all day.
Scott: Maybe you want to be like an internet sort of advertising bloggy person.
Scott: Yeah, you can try to do that.
Rym: I cried her it.
Rym: you don't have to go to college right away.
Rym: It's totally okay to go to college a year later.
Scott: So Leo gay to college and you're like 30.
Rym: It's totally okay to just work in game.
Rym: stop the rest of your life so you can play your video game.
Scott: You can eventually be like a Gamestop regional manager pretty easily stuck with it.
Rym: I mean if you do what you want or do what thou wilt and know how to do it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front road crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.