Scott: It's Thursday, January 18th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: And I'm Rym.
Scott: And this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we discuss snooze.
Scott: Snow.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well, as I was reminded last night, because I actually forgot, as I've forgotten in the past, tonight's actually my birthday.
Scott: Congratulations.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: An arbitrary time has passed.
Rym: I have survived for another year in an arbitrary time scale that involves planets.
Scott: Yes, the sphere upon which we live has traveled its entire orbit a round number of times about, well, I mean, it'll, for like a nanosecond, you know, the smallest unit, if there is a smallest unit of time, that was true.
Scott: Now it has passed.
Rym: Well, the thing is, I don't remember, well, obviously I don't remember, but I don't know when I was born during the day, so it could be any time.
Scott: I think I was born like two in the morning.
Scott: I don't really remember.
Rym: See, I think that too, but I might just be totally making that up.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I'm really, I don't know.
Scott: But yeah.
Scott: You could still be 24, possibly.
Rym: But at least this year, I didn't totally forget.
Rym: It was like, it came up what day it was, then I was like, "Oh, yeah, my birthday's in an
Rym: hour.".
Scott: Huh.
Rym: I think it was two years ago, might have been three years ago.
Rym: I completely forgot it was my birthday.
Rym: I absolutely had no idea, and then eventually I forget who it was, but someone wished me a happy birthday.
Rym: And I was like, "It's not my
Rym: birthday.".
Rym: And then someone else convinced me it was my birthday, and I thought about it.
Rym: "Wait, Jenny?
Rym: Yeah, hot
Rym: dad.".
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yeah, we just don't really pay attention to birthdays around here.
Rym: Birthdays are- No, we used to.
Rym: Remember at RIT?
Scott: Other people really paid attention to them for us.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It was like we were getting pushed into it by others.
Rym: See, we have two general traditions around birthdays that pretty much died as we left RIT, just because we're not around each other every waking moment of every single day.
Scott: Birthday punches.
Rym: Yeah, but that wasn't all.
Rym: That was mostly just Kate coming and punching us, regardless of whether or not it was our birthday.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But no, we had one tradition among a small number of us.
Rym: I think it was Peter who started it, where on your birthday, you had to buy a steak dinner for everyone else.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think that was a tradition.
Scott: I think that was just people did it because, like I remember on my birthday, I took everyone to the Outback because it was my birthday.
Scott: My mom decided to pay for everyone to go to the Outback, so I took as many people as I could.
Rym: It wasn't like a- Oh, yeah, it wasn't the whole crew.
Rym: It was pretty much just a few of us who did that, and we did it semi-regularly, if we remembered birthdays, for about two and a half years.
Scott: I guess that's about right.
Rym: It was almost your tradition, and then we moved away.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That, and we always tended to get cakes, which ended in the archangel, dark angel debacle that I won't get into.
Rym: Oh, God.
Rym: I still, to this day, do not know how that happened.
Scott: I remember that now.
Scott: That's a good one.
Scott: I can't believe I forgot it.
Rym: I was thinking about it the other day, in fact, because I was talking on the phone when Emily reminded me it was my birthday, so I started telling- Ear?
Rym: Yeah, ear.
Rym: I started telling birthday stories, which, of course, the ultimate birthday story is the story of the ear on the cake.
Scott: I totally forgot about that, but now it all came back to me in like a rush.
Rym: How that ear appeared on that cake, man will never know.
Scott: No.
Rym: There's no way to track down the person who put it there and ask them why they did that.
Scott: It's a great mystery of the universe.
Rym: Maybe we'll actually tell the story someday.
Scott: Maybe we will.
Rym: I don't know if it's as good as the blow-dryer story.
Scott: I haven't heard the blow-dryer story because I haven't listened to Penn in God knows how long.
Rym: Yeah, but there is more important news, aside from it being my birthday and me being exactly, give or take, up to 12 or so hours, a quarter century old.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: A third of my life is gone.
Rym: Maybe a quarter if technology stays up and I'm as healthy as I think I am.
Rym: But, uh, it snowed today for the first time.
Rym: Ever?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: How did we have a word for it?
Rym: I made the word up just now.
Rym: Now, it snowed.
Scott: All right, so everybody, that white stuff that you see falling from the sky, we're gonna call it- Snew.
Scott: I can't bel- What's snew with you?
Rym: Do you even know the origin of snew?
Scott: It's a joke from Kermit the Frog on that commercial with Fozzie.
Rym: No, it came from way before then.
Rym: Oh, really?
Scott: Yeah, cuz that was the best.
Scott: It was like he had those barrels and Kermit was like, "What's
Scott: snew?".
Scott: He's like, "Snew?
Scott: What's
Scott: snew?"
Scott: and Fozzie goes, "What's snew with you?
Scott: Oh,
Scott: zing!".
Rym: Now there's a much older snew.
Rym: In fact, if any of our listeners can bring up that older reference to snew, which specifically refers to- The show knows what snew is.
Scott: I'm just curious.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: And uh- I don't need to remember his Fozzie bear.
Rym: You won't win anything.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: They're like, "He'll win fuck
Rym: all!".
Scott: Ooh, that's a good prize.
Rym: But yeah, it hadn't snowed yet this year.
Rym: In fact, it had barely frosted yet this year.
Rym: I have been wearing t-shirts outside up until about two days ago.
Scott: Yeah, well, yeah, two days ago it got cold and I was like, "Ooh, it's cold now.
Scott: I have to wear like a coat and I wish I had a
Scott: hat.".
Rym: Yeah, but it wasn't bitterly cold.
Rym: It was hovering around freezing.
Scott: It wasn't really below freezing.
Scott: Yeah, I wasn't shivering outside in my coat, but walking out to the car I was just thinking, "Woman, it is
Scott: cold.".
Scott: And, you know, there was frost on the car.
Scott: I had to defrost it a little bit, warm it up.
Scott: You could see the exhaust coming out of cars.
Scott: It was cold, but it wasn't like Rochester cold.
Rym: God.
Rym: See, maybe it's just because I grew up in Michigan that- I mean, cold is cold.
Rym: And if it's below freezing, it's cold.
Rym: But it's not that special kind of cold unless it's below zero Fahrenheit.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: That's the moment where I go outside and go,
Rym: "Fuck!"
Rym: And you turn around and go back inside.
Rym: No, you end up doing that Rochester shuffle where you're walking as fast as you can, but you're holding your body perfectly rigid hoping that no amount of air will in any way enter your clothing.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I pull that string at the bottom of my coat in to keep the air from going up into my business.
Rym: But no, my news is that it snowed and I live in a state where it snows.
Rym: It snows pretty much, barring catastrophe, every year in New York State, both upstate and downstate.
Rym: It snows here every year.
Rym: You'd think after the previous thousands and thousands of years of it snowing.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I'll even go closer.
Rym: Since the invention of the automobile, except for that first winter, people knew it was coming.
Rym: You knew it was gonna snow.
Rym: You knew that your car might spin out or somehow lose traction in snow.
Rym: You know exactly what snow is going to do when it's on a road.
Rym: You'd think after that first winter we would have this down.
Rym: It wouldn't be an issue anymore.
Rym: But no, it snows today.
Rym: And not only did I pass five or six major, major freaking accidents with dead people laying in the street, but one of the accidents that I passed, there were about no exaggerations.
Rym: I'll tend to exaggerate stories.
Rym: There were exactly 16 police cars that I could see and more than six ambulances.
Rym: There were at least 20 cars involved in this accident.
Rym: There was debris everywhere, and I'm pretty sure I saw body bags.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Now, I would have understood this if there had actually been any significant amount of snow on the ground, but the roads were just fine.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I, driving home, I drive half the way home on a freeway and half, well, an interstate, and half the way home on this country road.
Scott: that kind of sucks.
Scott: And on the country road, there was one part that was slippery going down an incredibly steep hill, and my anti-lock brakes made it nothing.
Scott: So, and they didn't even engage the rest of the way home.
Scott: I just kind of coasted home.
Rym: I probably would have just, as I crested the hill, downshifted.
Scott: Yeah, either way, I'm just saying, I had no problems going home at all.
Rym: It seems to me that people, when it comes to snow, when they're driving, can't take a rational, middle-of-the-ground approach.
Rym: It seems like everyone out there either goes faster for some reason, just as fast as they can possibly go, tailgating me, or they go five miles an hour.
Scott: It's like people are either driving, you know, they're like, "Oh, it's safe to drive," and they drive fast.
Scott: Or they go, "Oh, it's dangerous," and they drive too slow.
Rym: It's like, what the fuck?
Rym: I mean, first, I pass all these horrible accidents, and now I'm just on the taconic.
Rym: I'm going about 50.
Rym: The only reason I'm not speeding, the road is fine.
Rym: Absolutely fine.
Rym: It's just snowing a little bit.
Rym: The only reason I'm not speeding is because there's cops everywhere.
Scott: The road was worse when it was raining a week ago when there was fog.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, eventually, traffic slows down in the traffic wave pattern.
Rym: So I get in the right lane, because everyone ahead of me seems to be getting in the right lane, and everyone seems to be slowing down a lot.
Rym: So I figure, all right, there's trouble ahead.
Rym: I'm just gonna, you know, do the smart thing.
Rym: So five minutes later, I just kind of zoned out listening to movies.
Rym: you should see.
Rym: I'm catching up on the archives.
Rym: I actually finally listened to the episode where we reviewed Attack the Gas Station on their show.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: See, I listened to the ones where we were on their show a long time ago.
Scott: Their episodes were not on the show that I had.
Rym: I gotta say, that was a long time ago.
Rym: We didn't do a very good review.
Scott: No, we didn't.
Rym: We just kind of gushed.
Scott: Yeah, that's about it.
Scott: We did the same thing for our City of God review also.
Rym: If they ever ask us to do it again, let's give them a real review.
Scott: We'll have to prepare.
Scott: That sucks.
Rym: No, I think we just have to avoid saying things like, "This is without a doubt the greatest achievement in the history of
Rym: cinema."
Rym: Which we said more than once about Attack the Gas Station.
Scott: Well, we didn't lie at least.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, so after about five minutes of this, I hit pause, and I think, "All right.
Rym: I've been going 30 miles an hour for five minutes in a line of cars in the right lane.
Rym: The left lane is empty.
Rym: I'm going to go for
Rym: it.".
Rym: So I pull into the left lane, and I accelerate back.
Scott: That's a big risk.
Scott: What if the left lane is closed ahead?
Scott: Now you're going to look like an ass.
Rym: Yeah, so I drive a lot.
Rym: I've driven this road a lot.
Rym: I drive hundreds and hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of miles every single week.
Rym: So I think I've made a calculated risk here, and I start going.
Rym: I accelerate to 50.
Rym: I accelerate to 60.
Rym: I accelerate to 70.
Rym: I pass hundreds of cars.
Rym: Eventually, I get to the front, and there's no traffic anywhere.
Rym: These people are just so paranoid about this zero inches of snow and this light dusting that is slowly falling from the sky and quickly melting on the salt that they're driving 30 in the right lane of the Taconic during rush hour.
Scott: Don't they usually drive 90 in the left lane?
Rym: Yeah, I actually got home faster because of the snow because everyone got the hell out of my way and went to 30 miles an hour.
Rym: Awesome.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I couldn't fathom it.
Rym: I just kind of drove.
Scott: Maybe there was an accident, but you just waited so long while listening to movies.
Scott: You should see that when you got up there, the accident was cleared out.
Scott: You got there just at the perfect time.
Scott: The last police car was pulling away as you got there.
Rym: The thing is, I drove for a long time, and no one was in the left lane anywhere in that entire time, including all the way behind me, and no one thought to follow me.
Scott: My guess is that a lot of the people who were in the left lane assumed that there was an accident up ahead.
Rym: Well, no.
Rym: What I think it was, because there's a bunch of somewhat sharp corners around there, while there was no snow on the ground and traction was just fine.
Rym: In fact, I tested my traction by braking carefully around corners to see if I would start to lose control, and I didn't.
Rym: It was fine.
Rym: But because of the wind, it looked like there was a slick surface.
Rym: It looked like there was a lot of snow on the ground, but it wasn't.
Rym: It was just kind of swirling in the corners.
Rym: I think people were just afraid of having an accident, especially after having passed three fatal accidents just before that.
Scott: Yeah, I think it was a combination.
Rym: Of course, the best part is there was one accident blocking my area of traffic, not from the accident.
Rym: The accident was in the southbound lanes, but the car, which had crashed all by itself due to stupidity, had crashed into the guardrail.
Rym: Various bits of large debris had continued through the guardrail and blocked my side of the road.
Rym: There was a hood laying there and a fender.
Scott: Going pretty fast, wasn't he?
Scott: His hood flew off.
Rym: I don't know what he was doing.
Scott: I didn't even see an accident on the way home, but as soon as I got on the interstate, there was a short, about a half mile of slow traffic in both lanes.
Scott: An ambulance got on the highway.
Scott: It merged right into where I was sitting, so I just kind of stopped in the middle of the highway until the ambulance went away, down the highway in front of me.
Scott: I assumed, oh, there's an accident up ahead.
Scott: That ambulance is going to it, right?
Scott: Then eventually, I'm going down about a half mile, then traffic picks up again, and I'm on my way home.
Scott: Then eventually, I get to one of those cross-the-highway bits, and the ambulance is going to the other side of the road.
Scott: It was somewhere way behind me.
Scott: I wasn't even close to it.
Rym: Actually, one, you have to give right away, obviously, and you should give right away, but you don't have to stop for an ambulance on the freeway.
Scott: I was at this merge, and there was no way it was getting on unless I let it.
Scott: If I wanted to, I could have held the ambulance there and not let it go anywhere.
Rym: A few months ago, I was driving up the Bronx River Parkway, and there was an accident somewhere up ahead.
Rym: I'm in three lanes of traffic, completely balled up, stopped for like 10 minutes.
Rym: Eventually, I see a commotion way back, so I just get out of my car and look.
Rym: There's an ambulance trying to get to the scene of the accident, furiously.
Rym: The ambulance driver is obviously very pissed off and fervently trying to get through this crowd of cars, and all the cars in front of it are just sitting there like, "Where do you want me to go?
Rym: There's nowhere to move my car.
Rym: There is no way we can let you through.
Rym: What were you thinking?
Rym: Whoever you're coming to save is already
Rym: dead.".
Scott: The road is too narrow and full of cars.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: If you're an ambulance guy, you should grab your little medical first aid kit and run.
Scott: That's what you should do.
Scott: I got a news here.
Scott: It said the headline is MySpace to Offer Spyware for Parents.
Scott: Now, you read that headline and you think, "All right, what is MySpace going to do?
Scott: They're going to give a program that even the stupidest parents can install that will let them see everything their kid is doing on MySpace, even the private stuff and everything, to make sure their kids aren't doing any nasties, right?
Rym: The first thing I thought was, "How can I gain the system in installing this for one of my
Rym: friends?".
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: However, that's not what they're doing.
Rym: What are they doing?
Scott: Parents who install the monitoring software on their home computers will be able to find out name, age, and location their children are using to represent themselves on MySpace.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: Can't you just look at their MySpace?
Scott: Oh, shit.
Rym: Does this cost money?
Scott: I have no idea.
Rym: I hope it costs money.
Rym: I hope this costs money, because that is a direct...
Scott: It's like, in order for this to work, you'd have to know your kid's MySpace username anyway, to type it in, to know what... The software has to figure out who to look for.
Scott: Maybe it could root through your cookies or something, but I doubt that highly.
Scott: This makes no sense.
Scott: It's basically, MySpace is doing nothing at all, and stupid parents see this nothing as if it's a move to help them out and make MySpace safer when it's actually nothing.
Rym: I'll bet I know what this is.
Scott: These stupid experts, all these expert people, they're like, "Ah, now the kids are gonna run away from MySpace because the parents can watch them on it.
Scott: They're gonna start using something else because kids are all fickle.
Scott: They'll just go to a different social network as soon as one starts to
Scott: suck.".
Scott: I'm like, "Dude, MySpace already sucks the most.
Scott: It doesn't get much worse than MySpace.
Scott: Anyone who hasn't pleaded already isn't
Scott: gonna.".
Rym: I think I know exactly what MySpace is doing.
Rym: By doing this, they can now say that, "We have implemented measures to protect children from predators.
Rym: It is now the parents' responsibility to make use of this tool that we have provided.
Rym: You have no excuse.
Rym: You can't sue us.
Rym: Nah nah nah nah nah nah.
Rym: Nah nah nah nah nah.
Rym: Goodbye.".
Scott: Well, kind of what it says here is a group of 33 state attorneys led by Connecticut's attorney, Blumenthal.
Scott: That guy's not so great.
Scott: I know him.
Rym: Who are the other 33?
Scott: Other state attorneys general.
Rym: Yeah, I know.
Rym: Which states?
Rym: Does it say?
Scott: No.
Rym: Because I want to know so we can tell people not to ever vote for them again.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They're thinking about taking legal action against MySpace if it doesn't raise the age limit to join the site to 16 from the current 14.
Rym: But the law says 14.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Not to use such low language, but this is a phrase that I think applies perfectly and should be the response of MySpace.
Rym: Eat a dick.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It also says that they want MySpace to verify members' ages against public databases.
Scott: What?
Rym: Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Rym: I don't think anything needs to be said about that.
Scott: The answer is lawyers do not understand technology, and MySpace has done a double whammy.
Scott: These lawyers who don't understand technology causing MySpace some trouble because they don't understand technology.
Scott: So what does MySpace do?
Scott: They go, "Hey, wait.
Scott: These guys are giving us trouble because they don't understand technology.
Scott: Let's take advantage of the fact that they don't understand technology, and let's do
Scott: nothing.".
Scott: And because they don't understand technology, they'll think we did something, and they'll leave us alone.
Scott: It's brilliant.
Scott: It's, "Hey, look.
Scott: These dumbasses are causing us trouble because they're
Scott: dumbasses.".
Scott: Well, since they're dumbasses, it's not easy.
Scott: It's not too hard to fool them into going the fuck away.
Scott: And it looks like what's going to happen to me.
Rym: I think so.
Scott: So, yeah.
Scott: Anyone who saw this headline and didn't actually read the story, MySpace is doing nothing.
Scott: See, now- They're not giving your parents spyware to check your emails or anything.
Rym: This is actually one of the main reasons why I'm more and more seriously considering going to law school.
Rym: I'd probably be maybe one of, I don't know, 10 lawyers in the world who knows something about technology.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I mean, I have a BS.
Rym: I have a bachelor's of science in information technology.
Rym: I'm an expert.
Rym: I've worked in the industry.
Rym: If I was also a lawyer, I think I could do some good.
Rym: I think I could actually change something.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: Also, I do find it interesting that GeekNights has a lot of strange or somewhat counterintuitive target demographics.
Rym: I mean, we're popular among Australians.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Much more so than you'd think.
Scott: We have a not insignificant number- Well, I think podcasting in general is pretty big in Australia more so than you would think.
Scott: I don't know why, though.
Rym: I'll bet it has to do with- Because I don't know enough about Australia.
Rym: I'll bet some of it might have to do with access to other media.
Scott: Perhaps.
Rym: Because, you know, Australia always gets dicked when it comes to video games and DVDs.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: They do get stuff, but they do have Wii's there.
Scott: They got Wii games.
Rym: They don't get dicked as much as Europe does.
Scott: I think their proximity to Japan helps them a little bit, but I don't think they have the greatest selection of German board games in Australia.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: They might.
Scott: They might, but I'm just guessing that they don't.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: GeekNights is also very popular among atheists.
Rym: And GeekNights apparently is more popular than you might randomly assume among lawyers.
Rym: A not insignificant number of the people active in our forums are lawyers.
Scott: Which must mean that at least one person not active in our forums is also a lawyer.
Rym: Yeah, so if you're a lawyer and you're listening to this- Oh, he says it's a safe assumption.
Rym: Join the forums and there's other lawyers there.
Scott: Gasp.
Scott: Law-ing.
Rym: Well, the mayor mays, the lawyer lois.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Things of the Day.
Scott: Oh, I found this I think last night maybe.
Scott: It's pretty good.
Rym: Yeah, Scott had another thing of the day and we're just about to start recording the show.
Rym: And I say, "Well, it's my
Rym: birthday.".
Rym: And then Scott says, "Oh, shits!
Rym: I gotta use this other thing of the day.
Rym: Start
Rym: over.".
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Even though that had nothing to do with- That's right.
Scott: As any real geek knows, if you were to watch Star Wars Episode VI, Return of the Jedi, if you were to watch the special edition, at the end, there's this big celebration where they show you all these cities around the galaxy and- And they play some jive music.
Scott: And there's this jive song going on, right?
Scott: Well, if you watch the original Star Wars Episode VI, Return of the Jedi, at the end, they don't show you cities around the galaxy.
Scott: All they show you is the Ewoks celebrating.
Scott: Everyone else who's celebrating, you don't see them.
Scott: And during that, they don't play no jive music.
Scott: They play the Ewok song.
Scott: Yub nub.
Rym: Okay, it's a pretty catchy song.
Scott: And I like it.
Scott: Even though a lot of people hate it, I like it.
Rym: The only reason I didn't play that song just now is that I don't want to get sued by George Lucas.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, that is the song.
Scott: Now, how could I turn that song into a thing of the day?
Scott: I mean, it's just a song in a movie, you know, it's hard to-.
Rym: Well, maybe if someone made a music video to that song.
Scott: Ooh, that would be pretty good, but I don't know.
Rym: Maybe someone took the new Star Wars and put that music over it.
Scott: Yeah, that wouldn't be so good.
Rym: That would just- Maybe if someone else performed that song, a cover, if you will.
Scott: Well, it just so happens that this song has been performed by a mediocre barbershop quartet.
Rym: Now, when he says barbershop quartet, he means it.
Rym: When he says mediocre, he fucking means it.
Scott: Yeah, there's a video on YouTube of these four guys.
Scott: That's what a quartet is, four guys.
Scott: And they're a barbershop quartet.
Scott: They're not a very good one, but they're better than no barbershop quartet at all, I guess.
Rym: I think they get an A for effort and an A for concept, but a D for execution.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you look at them and you say, "Well, okay, that guy with that beard, he's such a nerd, oh
Scott: god.".
Scott: Those other guys, yeah, they're pretty nerdy too.
Scott: And they sing Yub Nub, the Ewok celebration song.
Scott: And they have some subtitles so you can see what they mean, what the Ewok words mean.
Scott: What the fuck does Yub Nub mean?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: The thing is, I don't know how they came up with these subtitles.
Scott: They must have gotten it from some Star Wars fan site because Ewok is not a language that you can speak.
Scott: You can speak Klingon because nerds have figured out the whole language, but- Did George Lucas put out some official lyrics?
Scott: I don't know, but you cannot speak Ewok.
Scott: And a lot of times, I think they say like one word and then they say another word and both of those words translate to mean celebration.
Scott: So, I don't know what fucks up with that.
Rym: Well, obviously, they're different inflected tenses of the verb.
Scott: It could be.
Scott: I mean- It could be just a bad subtitle.
Scott: It could be just a Hong Kong subtitling.
Scott: I mean- We need to go get the legitimate region one DVD.
Rym: Because we can speak hut just fire, beach of a wookiee Chewbacca.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: And I can speak Boba Fett real well too.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Or even Jawa.
Scott: I'm fluent, Boba Fett.
Scott: Oh dee dee.
Scott: But yeah, you cannot speak Ewok.
Scott: That is not a fully fleshed out language.
Rym: So, my thing of the day is very much related to the topic at hand and to my news.
Rym: You see, all three of my things are in fact the same thing.
Scott: Snow.
Scott: Oh my god, is there a word for that when all three things match?
Rym: Well, you see- A trifecta?
Rym: The word used on Fark is trifecta, which apparently is a term from horse racing when a very specific thing happens.
Rym: But on Fark, a trifecta is when three stories that are far too related to be normally statistically probable, like
Scott: say
Rym: there are two stories of fat people exploding, then people start posting in the end of the second one, "Man, if there's a trifecta of this, I'm buying a lottery
Rym: ticket.".
Scott: I would too.
Rym: So I guess this is the first GeekNights trifecta.
Rym: Well, other than, I don't know, I guess every show is a geek trifecta.
Scott: I guess so.
Rym: Two of them in fact.
Scott: All right, but yeah.
Rym: I would never have used this as a thing of the day, and I'm using it only as a public service announcement and an educational bit to all of our listeners who do not live north of the Messier Line in the United States, because I don't think anyone else in the world does this.
Rym: At least not to the extent that Americans do, to the point that we have a word for it, a commonly understood and known word.
Rym: You see, a long time ago, I was hanging out with a friend of mine from down south.
Scott: Not even that far down south.
Scott: North Carolina.
Scott: Not that far at all.
Scott: Not that far south.
Rym: And for somehow, the conversation of donuts came up, and this person was entirely utterly confused as to what I meant.
Scott: They thought we were talking about Krispy Kremes and Dunkins.
Rym: And they wondered how Krispy Kremes and Dunkin' Donuts had anything to do with snow and cars.
Rym: What, do you get a warm donut and sit in the car while it's cold?
Rym: Is it a euphemism for something?
Rym: And I was flabbergasted.
Rym: I think I realized at that point that there are a lot of people out there, especially people who don't live in pretty much New York State, Michigan, Ohio, Wisconsin.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it reminds me, one time I was at my grandparents' house in Florida, and I needed a haircut pretty badly.
Scott: So I went to just whatever the closest place was that could give a haircut, and I got a cheap, shitty haircut.
Scott: But the person who cut my hair was like 40-something years old at the time, and this must have been years ago.
Scott: So they must be 50-something now, right?
Scott: And they said that they had never left Florida in their entire lives.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I can't fathom that.
Scott: No, I can't either.
Rym: I mean...
Scott: That have never left the state of Florida.
Rym: My wanderlust is enough to get that.
Rym: I would just die.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Scott: But it's probably never seen snow, ever.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: Except in TV.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So.
Rym: All right.
Scott: There's no... I can't expect that person to know what I mean when I say, "Do a
Scott: donut.".
Rym: So, a donut, which is... I mean, there are probably terms for this in other places that it's done, but to all of you in foreign countries, I don't think you quite understand, even Canada, the extent and the fervor which is put forth when it comes to donuts up here.
Scott: I mean, there are a lot of places in the world where donuts are done, but specifically in the Northeast US, I don't know about other places, but we're really intense about doing donuts.
Scott: College students and high school students in the Northeast United States love doing donuts, and they will do as many as they can.
Rym: Like in high school, right?
Rym: If I was in 10th grade, I got my car, 11th grade, whatever, anytime all through high school, I've got my car.
Rym: If it snowed and I had nothing else going on, I would probably just get in my car and drive over to the high school, which had a gigantic donut-shaped parking lot of all things.
Rym: And in this parking lot, I would proceed to make donuts.
Rym: Now, not only would I be doing this, but I could count, I could just expect at least 10 or 15 other cars to be in this parking lot doing the exact same thing.
Rym: There'd probably be one guy in the church parking lot across the street because he's afraid of getting hit by someone.
Rym: There'd probably be some kid doing it at the park in the grass on the ice.
Scott: It's kind of like, you know, if it snows, you go down to the golf course with your sled and what do you see?
Scott: A bunch of other kids with sleds.
Rym: Yeah, or you go down to the local pond and you all start ice skating.
Rym: Y'all go down to the local thing and start doing donuts.
Scott: Yep, that's what donuts are.
Rym: And pretty much it was either that or play hockey.
Rym: That's what we did.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So a donut, very specifically, is when you get into your car and there's a slick ice covered or snow covered surface somewhere.
Scott: I guess you could do a donut when there is no ice, but you would have to be going very fast and it would be rather dangerous.
Rym: I wouldn't call it a donut.
Rym: So you get out of the parking lot.
Rym: Now, part of the reason that I think they're so pervasive in the U.S.
Rym: is to other places is that in the
Rym: U.S.,
Rym: especially in a lot of the places we've grown up or lived, everyone has a car.
Rym: Also, everyone has a parking lot.
Scott: And when it snows, those parking lots are empty and icy.
Rym: And they don't bother plowing the parking lot because people can just deal with it.
Rym: They usually plow it like on Monday for work.
Scott: But actually one that was like plowed recently, but then it's still snowing.
Scott: That's usually the best.
Scott: Yes, because if they plow it because it's got like a foot of snow and it's still snowing, you can go there when there's like half an inch.
Scott: That's perfect.
Rym: However, I think the best possible donut is when there's about two to three inches of snow and it can just be powder.
Rym: It has to be a little bit wet, but it can't be too wet.
Scott: But you got to be slippery.
Scott: It's the kind of snow where you get out of your car and fall on your ass if you weren't careful.
Rym: Yeah, but not the so cold that it's a solid sheet.
Scott: Yeah, solid sheet of ice.
Scott: You just kill yourself because you don't have enough friction to stop or get going.
Rym: You want snow that when you step on it, compact snow that would make good snowballs makes good donut snow.
Rym: So then what you do is you get into a large open area, which are very common in the United States in the Northeast in your car, and you proceed to start driving until you reach whatever speed you are comfortable with performing this maneuver.
Rym: Now, at this point, it depends on your exact car, your level of ambition and adventure and your skill.
Scott: And if your car is front or rear wheel drive.
Scott: Yes, all sorts of front or rear or mid engine.
Rym: But considering that most Americans have a two wheel drive, front wheel drive, automatic car in one of those cars, the front engine.
Rym: Yes, for the front engine.
Scott: I mean, you could have a rear engine front wheel drive.
Rym: I don't think anyone's ever made anything like that.
Scott: I think there does exist, but I don't know.
Rym: Maybe someone made one to say they made one.
Rym: That seems like a bad idea all around.
Scott: But that's not the point.
Rym: And what you do is you go in at a good clip, so say 30, 35, 40 miles an hour.
Rym: Then you turn your real a little bit to the right or a little bit to the left, depending on which direction has less stuff, just enough to start the car turning.
Rym: Now, obviously, at this point in a car like this, you're going to understeer, meaning your front tires are going to lose traction and your car will start to angle to the right or to the left.
Rym: But it will continue going mostly straight and the front tires are not grabbing at all.
Scott: It will go in the direction you were originally going and not in the direction you were trying to turn into.
Rym: At this point, you flip your car into neutral so you don't stall out and you simultaneously pull your parking brake.
Rym: Now, you don't hold the parking brake the whole time.
Scott: You just pull it a little bit because pulling the parking brake, what it does is it takes your rear brakes and locks them.
Rym: Now, also, you do not want to do this if you have a Boolean parking brake, the one that's just on, off.
Rym: You only do this if you have a normal parking brake.
Rym: Usually you want the hand one.
Scott: Yeah, if your parking brake or your emergency brake or whatever you want to call it, it's a parking brake, is the kind where you pull a lever with your right with your hand, your hand brake, that's good.
Scott: If it's the kind where you push down this locking pedal, like on the left, like to the left of where the clutch would be, that's no good.
Rym: Now, you can do it without using the brake, but the brake will give you the most dramatic results with the least required skill or effort.
Scott: That is correct.
Rym: Your car will then proceed to spin any number of times while flying across the parking lot at high speed, eventually coming to a stop.
Scott: Yeah, because what's happened here is the initial turning, your front wheels have lost traction because they are trying to go in a direction, but the momentum is carrying you in a different direction.
Scott: Secondly, your rear wheels, which still have the traction, have now locked and those wheels will not spin.
Scott: Thus, your car will spin around in a circle with a little 360 creating a donut on the ice.
Rym: That's the basic, basic, basic donut.
Rym: If you want to be more advanced, obviously you can do really cool things.
Rym: It's kind of like Initial D, you can drift all around, you're not going to ruin your tires, you're not going to hit anything unless you're a complete consummate jackass.
Scott: Or dumbass.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, God.
Rym: There was a friend of ours once, because in addition to donuts, I would often use my parking brake in snow.
Rym: It's something that, because I grew up in Michigan, if you live in a place where it snows a lot and you just have to drive in snow all the time, it snows and that can't stop you, you just have to go.
Rym: The parking brake is often useful to swing your car around a corner that you might not otherwise make due to your current speed.
Rym: So whenever I was dropping people off at the dorms on my way back to our apartment, I'd usually do that coming up to the area where I could let people out, because otherwise I'd have to go real freaking slow to get around that corner.
Rym: So I'd just go faster, pop it, come around, come to a stop, let them out.
Rym: One of our friends, while they were driving someone else home, because one time I drove them home and they saw me do this and they were a little bit impressed, probably more impressed than they should have been.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Because a lot of people who go to RIT are not natives to cold places, so they can't understand what all these donut snow people are doing.
Scott: It's like, "What are you
Scott: doing?".
Scott: This is still the thing of the day.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Rym: That's fine, because it's relevant.
Rym: It's pertinent.
Rym: So then he decides to do it one day with someone else in the car, and he comes around, he pops the parking brake, car slides and bump just right into the side of the building, just and stops.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But really, if you want to get advanced, instead of popping your car into neutral, you use the accelerator and use the wheel right to try to get a perfect slide or some counter steering, try to land on a target.
Scott: I think my goal, usually when doing donuts, the goal is to go as fast as you can safely and then do as many 360s as possible in place.
Scott: That's the goal.
Scott: My goal is almost always to do the- Because that provides the most thrills in the car.
Scott: Anyone else who's in the car with you, it's like an amusement park ride.
Rym: God, there were like four times at RIT where I took someone out who had never been on a donut run before, and I just took him out into a parking lot, and I did a donut.
Scott: Like a shitty donut too.
Rym: Just like a little like, because Scott was in with a couple times, and we'd just be like a little, like I'd maybe go like one 360, like a little, "Shit, it wasn't going more than 30 or 35 miles an
Rym: hour.".
Rym: And they'd totally freak out like I was going to kill him somehow.
Scott: I think what it is, is people feel those g-forces not too often, and when they do feel them, it's in an environment where they know they're safe, like a roller coaster or something.
Scott: So when you feel them in a car, which is a place where you never want to feel those kinds of g-forces, you freak out.
Scott: Now unless you're from the place where these are common- Unless you fee- Well, you know, if you do it twice, then you're used to it.
Rym: I mean, the first time I ever did one, when I was in 10th grade, I didn't even have my driver's license yet, I had my learner's permit, I was so afraid I was going to hit something, and then I did one, and I didn't hit anything, and I did one again, and I realized that you can't hit anything unless you're a consummate jackass.
Scott: See, now I want to encourage people to do donuts, that way they'll be better to able handle their cars, like if they get into some serious snow traction situations in the snow, not on purpose.
Scott: However, is it illegal to do donuts or not?
Rym: You see, it depends.
Rym: If you're doing it on private property, it's not illegal unless you're trespassing.
Rym: They could get you for reckless driving if you did that on a public road, but you shouldn't be doing that on a public road anyway.
Scott: No, I think just don't do it where you know you're going to get in trouble for doing it.
Rym: RIT turned a straight up blind eye to it.
Rym: Well, I'm sure if Campus Safety was right there- Campus Safety was right there watching me one day.
Rym: I was just sitting there in his car, and I was doing donuts.
Rym: I didn't notice him at first because it was still snowing, so finally, in the middle of one of my runs, I look and I see this car, this Campus Safety guy sitting right there looking at me, and I just stop, and I sit there like, "Great, he's going to come do something to me,".
Rym: and he doesn't do anything.
Rym: So eventually, I build up a little bit of courage, I do another donut, and then eventually his lights come on and I think, "All right, now he's coming after me,".
Rym: and he drives off into this other parking lot, does a donut, and then drives away.
Rym: It was one of the most beautiful moments in my life, second only to when this jackass ran a- I keep saying jackass today.
Scott: Ran a stop sign- I had to say ass hat instead.
Rym: The guy passed me from behind over a double yellow and ran a stop sign.
Rym: He was then immediately pulled over, and I drove past him.
Rym: I was laughing so hard with the window down, and the cop looked up to me, and he gave kind of this smirk like,
Rym: "Yeah?".
Scott: "Lol.".
Rym: Yeah, I mean, we rely on cops a lot, but we don't dislike cops.
Rym: We just dislike some of the uses of cops.
Scott: Yeah, and some cops.
Scott: All right, so.
Rym: So, my thing of the day- Oh, shit.
Rym: Is a video of someone at RIT in the donut parking lot.
Scott: Doing it in a Saturn.
Rym: I mean, D-Lot is well and good.
Rym: If you've never been to U-Lot.
Rym: And he does a pretty damn good donut.
Scott: Anyone but us got that reference.
Rym: Now, I will note that while the donut- the normal donut he does is really impressive.
Rym: The end of the video is doubly impressive.
Rym: I would give it a 20% chance that he faked the second half of the video with a clever cut and then having a guy laugh.
Scott: It could be.
Rym: However, I have known people.
Rym: I am not- I cannot do this.
Rym: I don't think Scott can do it.
Rym: I don't think anyone we know can do it.
Scott: I could do it if I practiced a bit.
Rym: Yeah, but I knew people in Michigan who could do donuts.
Rym: you wouldn't freaking believe.
Rym: They would have two cars and they'd go at each other like you're playing a game of chicken.
Rym: And then one would veer to the right and one would veer to the left and they'd like initial D past each other.
Rym: And that was like the common game and I never ever had the balls to try that.
Scott: I would never have the balls to try it either.
Scott: Unless it was a shit car and like a demolition derby of ICE.
Scott: Then I would do it.
Rym: Yeah, and yeah, I guess in that case.
Scott: Yeah, if it was like a demolition derby car with like the roll bar and a helmet and everything, I'd be up for it.
Scott: But not in my car.
Rym: Right, so the topic today is snow because it snowed today.
Scott: What is there to say about snow?
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: It's cold, it's wet, it falls from the sky.
Rym: It's made out of mostly water, but sometimes there's some acid in it.
Scott: A lot of people in the world don't deal with it.
Rym: A lot of people get a lot of it.
Scott: Sometimes it's good and sometimes it sucks.
Scott: It's pretty much like all weather.
Scott: It's like you want it and sometimes you gotta deal with it when it comes.
Rym: Yeah, and I think every part of the world, people just growing up have very different snow experiences.
Rym: We both grew up in somewhat similar climates.
Scott: Yeah, where I live it's got summer, spring, winter, and fall.
Scott: It's just like the climate is here right now.
Rym: Yeah, and contrary to popular belief, while it's really cold in the winter and it snows a lot in Michigan, it's really hot in the summer too.
Rym: So yeah, but I remember it seems like the older I got, like my joy from snow is inversely proportional to my age.
Rym: Because when I was young, no matter what, if it snowed it was a good day.
Scott: Snow was the best thing in the world as a kid for many reasons.
Scott: In my cancel school.
Scott: In my cancel school, in my delay school.
Rym: I went to a private Catholic school.
Rym: They would cancel school at the drop of a goddamn head.
Scott: In my younger years, they wouldn't cancel school so easily, but later as liability fears rose, they would cancel school over anything and that made everyone happy.
Scott: Except for the parents, well some parents.
Rym: See my high school never canceled school, and actually as I got older, especially when I lived in the suburbs, no one ever canceled school when it snowed unless there was freezing rain and they just expected you to drive in it.
Scott: Yeah, they always canceled school because buses and shit.
Rym: Yeah, well I think it's just a different, I mean I grew up in a place where if it snowed a foot, you weren't expected to alter your habits in any way and no one did.
Scott: See the other reason snow was awesome as a kid is because it was sort of like this toy that you didn't know if you were going to get to play with it and just some days it would appear outside your house.
Scott: Like imagine if outside your house there was a swing set and most of the time you looked out the window and the swing set wasn't there.
Scott: It was just the summer, you look out the window, no swing set.
Scott: Then in the winter, on just a few random days for one part of the year, the swing set would appear.
Rym: Not just in your yard, but in all your friends' yards too.
Scott: Yeah, and in the streets and everywhere.
Scott: And that was the best times, building snow forts.
Rym: Snow igloos which always collapsed on me.
Scott: Yep, throwing snowballs, snow angels, snowmen.
Rym: Whitewashing as I got older.
Scott: Snow everything.
Rym: Every Bill Cosby stand up about snow.
Scott: Yeah, there was just so much shit to do with snow if you were a little kid.
Rym: God, I mean, I love sledding.
Rym: I still love sledding.
Rym: Sledding is one of my favorite things in the world.
Scott: Sledding is pretty damn good.
Rym: I haven't done it recently.
Rym: I wanted to.
Rym: In fact, I had decided to this year.
Rym: I had a sled picked out to buy and everything and it just hadn't come to be.
Rym: Rosebud.
Rym: But when it would snow, like my brother and I were serious about it.
Rym: When it snowed, we'd get together kind of like Calvin and Hobbs style.
Rym: And alright, this is what we're going to build out there in terms of sledding hills.
Rym: We'd always make sledding hills in our front and backyards.
Rym: We'd always make different, like in the front yard because the plows would pile up all that extra snow from the street into the front half of the front yard.
Rym: We'd take all that in addition to the driveway snow and the yard snow and make one really, really tall hill to sled off of.
Scott: Oh, see our backyard had a hill so we mostly sledded on that.
Scott: But if you wanted to get some serious dangerous, possibly dangerous sledding, you could go to this one golf course where one of the holes just was like a big, big hill.
Scott: And you would just go right down this hill on your sled.
Scott: The thing is, if you went too fast and you didn't slow down or stop properly, there was a little hill.
Scott: There's like a bump at the end, sort of like a slip and slide.
Rym: No, wait.
Scott: The thing was that you were going straight for the road.
Scott: And I don't know if this is true, but I heard a story once that someone went down that hill full speed, hit the bump, went out into the road and got hit.
Scott: I don't know if that's true, but I guess it'd be, it would be pretty difficult if you've seen the area.
Scott: Like they would have to be going really fast.
Scott: But if someone did have a really fast sled and they were big enough and they got a running start, it could be possible.
Rym: If you had one of those cigarette style bullet sleds.
Scott: Yeah, it could be possible.
Scott: But just a story that they make about that hill to scare you from going to the fun hill.
Rym: It's kind of like going over the bar.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: Even though a kid did go over the bar at my school and did break his neck.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: But he didn't go over the bar all the way so much as he went so high up that he just kind of fell right down out onto his neck.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, it sucks.
Rym: Then he got beat up after he came back to school.
Rym: He was fine.
Rym: Just other than a broken neck, but he had to wear this huge horrible brace and some kids beat him up.
Scott: What the hell?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: See, I grew up in... Getting hit by a car.
Rym: I grew up in Michigan.
Rym: There weren't hills anywhere.
Scott: Ah, true.
Rym: We didn't see anything ever.
Rym: So we had to make our own.
Rym: Now, as a result, we got really good at it and we learned that while the tall hill seemed like the best idea to a young kid, make a tall hill and go off the top of it.
Rym: You didn't go so fast.
Rym: What we realized, the ultimate way to sled in a flat front yard.
Rym: We made a bump about, I don't know, a little over knee high and we'd make it really, really compact and we'd pour some water over it and more snow overs.
Rym: It was this compact solid ice thing.
Rym: What you would do is you would run at it at full speed.
Scott: You'd hit the bump and get some air.
Rym: No, you'd run at it full speed just before you got to it.
Rym: You jump into the air, stick your sled under your knees and land on it.
Rym: You would go flying down three or four yards.
Scott: Oh.
Rym: And usually we'd put jumps or angles or beams or ice or something.
Rym: A lot of times we'd pull out a hose and make ice lanes.
Scott: Yeah, that's always a good plan.
Scott: You know, you can make like a little, what's it called?
Scott: The thing in Cool Runnings.
Scott: The toboggan run.
Scott: A bobsled action.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You pile up snow on two sides and then you compact the snow in between and then you just run for it and go right down the middle with your sled.
Scott: And if you put a turn or two in there, you can bank off the turns to pick up more speed.
Scott: That could be some good stuff.
Rym: See, we'd always make those kind of, they would just happen because we're sledding in the same place.
Rym: It kind of made a dip in the snow over time.
Scott: Yep, yep.
Scott: You didn't actually do it by hand.
Scott: That takes too long.
Rym: But oh, when I was a kid, I was a Cub Scout and right before I, you know, left the Cub Scouts and decided not to join the Boy Scouts because no offense, but it seemed really kind of nerdy and I didn't like any of those people.
Scott: Yeah, I also did the same thing.
Scott: I got like two Cub Scout things and no- I got all the way to Weebillows.
Scott: I didn't go to Weebillows.
Rym: I also got a pile of medals and pins and whatever.
Scott: I gave them the finger way before Weebillows.
Rym: I didn't get the religion pin.
Rym: Because that was before they kicked atheists out of the Cub Scouts.
Scott: I actually got that one for Jew.
Rym: Really?
Scott: I don't remember actually.
Scott: I had to go look at my little- I remember one of the-.
Scott: The thing was my mom was so like lazy about sewing those things on to the stupid shirt that like I had a whole mess of them that never got attached to anything.
Rym: That's so sad.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, my Pine Box Derby cars always sucked ass.
Scott: Yeah, I had one and it sucked ass, and I only did the Pine Box Derby once.
Scott: But in that one Pine Box Derby, I saw the kid who won and I realized the answer to winning.
Scott: And if I would have had another year, I would have won because I would have done it Formula One style.
Rym: I think we could do a show on Pine Box Derbies.
Scott: That's not a good idea.
Rym: If we also include CO2 cars.
Scott: Ah, CO2 cars.
Rym: I think the two combined will be a good show.
Rym: But anyway- So we went to this huge Boy Scout camp in the middle of nowhere.
Rym: And it actually was somewhat hilly there.
Rym: But it wasn't hilly like, you know, rolling hills.
Rym: It was hilly like dangerous hills in the woods.
Rym: So at our cabin, right next to it was not really a cliff, but a very sharp grade.
Rym: It looks like it was a drainage ditch and it was snow and ice.
Rym: And it formed what appeared to us as young, not so bright kids to be a perfect toboggan run.
Rym: However, at the bottom was a little bank of snow.
Rym: And the toboggan run kind of went to the right or to the left.
Rym: And there was a raised section in the middle.
Rym: And directly behind this raised section was a gigantic oak tree.
Rym: So we're all debating, will the bank push you out of the way before you hit it or not?
Rym: So finally, one kid gets in a little saucer and he goes- A saucer?
Scott: Oh shit, I wouldn't do it in a saucer.
Rym: Why, saucers are the crappiest of sleds.
Scott: No, you're not using the saucer properly then.
Rym: How do you use the saucer properly?
Scott: You got to make sure that you don't let yourself rotate in the saucer.
Rym: Oh, I'm well aware.
Rym: Saucers can't go nearly as fast as certain other kinds of sleds.
Scott: No, saucers can go fast.
Scott: What you have to do is you have to bend the sides up, right?
Scott: That way it does less-.
Rym: Oh, I'm well aware.
Rym: You can also steer by pulling one side up or the other side.
Scott: Or you can do the national lampoon style where you get the metal saucer and you polish it.
Rym: That doesn't actually work.
Scott: I know, but it's hilarious.
Rym: I was thinking, I was trying to come up with a way to reference that.
Scott: I just came out and said it because I knew.
Rym: I was going to reference it somehow and be all clever.
Rym: So he's going down and he's going straight for the tree.
Rym: And at the last second, because there's- He just jumps off.
Rym: No, because the snow goes up, it goes right toward it, and then it just kind of falls to the side and keeps going down the trail.
Rym: Oh, sweet.
Rym: So the next kid's like,
Rym: "Badasses!".
Rym: He just jumps down without even thinking.
Rym: Same thing, but he goes to the left.
Rym: And so we're saucering for a while and people are like, they figure out how to pick left or right and it's going okay.
Rym: Then a kid pulls out the toboggan and we're like, "All right, who's with
Rym: me?".
Rym: Not me.
Rym: So I got on, but I was at the back.
Rym: There were six people in front of me.
Scott: It's a big one.
Rym: Yeah, it was a big straight up wooden one with metal railings on it.
Scott: Oh, shits.
Scott: No, it was either plastic dish or it was plastic sled.
Scott: We didn't have no wooden ones.
Rym: The most dangerous sled are the ones that are about six feet long, about a foot wide.
Rym: They're made out of plastic.
Rym: Basically just a shallow piece of plastic and they have basically rifling along the bottom.
Scott: Yeah, that's dangerous.
Scott: Those things got- Remember when we went sledding with dinner trays?
Rym: That didn't end well.
Scott: No, it didn't.
Rym: No, that was awesome.
Scott: It was hilarious.
Rym: I watched a guy try to snowboard with a piece of cardboard.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: He met down a steep hill.
Rym: He made it about two feet and then he fell on his face.
Scott: At least did he attach it to his feet with strings?
Rym: You'd think that.
Rym: It basically just stopped and then he just fell.
Rym: This toboggan, I'm at the back of it.
Rym: I'm the seventh person and the lucky hobbit at the back.
Rym: I know this is not going to end well.
Rym: I've decided to be at the back because that way I have six airbags in front of me.
Rym: It's going down and they're like, "Yeah, we're going to make it.
Rym: We're going to make it,".
Rym: because they're all big tough boy scouts.
Rym: Now I'm a little young cub scout.
Scott: This thing is not going to turn.
Scott: It's how long?
Rym: This thing's going straight for the tree.
Rym: I bail about halfway down.
Scott: Bailing is something that you do in snow often, not just when it's in sledding.
Rym: Yeah, I bailed and rolled.
Rym: I saw that one other person bailed and at the last second I hear, "Oh shit," and it just goes right into the tree.
Rym: Just, "Fuck," and the back of the toboggan goes up and then back down and I just hear,
Rym: "Oh."
Rym: Right in the mean bean machine.
Rym: They were all hurt.
Scott: As they deserved.
Rym: They totally deserved it.
Rym: Yeah, I think though in the front row crew, I'm really the only one who skis.
Scott: Yeah, I'm just sort of anti-skiing.
Scott: Like, I actually kind of like watching downhill skiing in the Olympics.
Scott: It's kind of cool and I like playing Ski Free for Windows 3.1.
Rym: I remember that.
Rym: The Yeti would get you again.
Scott: The Abominable Snowman.
Scott: Yeah, that was a good one.
Scott: I love that game.
Scott: But actually skiing, I've never done it and I don't plan to because I can get a lot more fun with a lot less danger.
Rym: Skiing is not that dangerous.
Scott: I'm not saying it is that dangerous, but it is dangerous.
Scott: See, the thing is- And there is the danger to fun ratio is not good enough.
Rym: I don't think you quite understand how fun it is.
Scott: I think I know how fun it would be for me.
Scott: Not so much.
Rym: Well, that's just because you have no leg strength.
Scott: I have plenty of leg strength.
Rym: We'll see.
Scott: But even if I, you know, it's like the amount of time to take that... If I tried to ski right now, I'd kind of suck at it and it wouldn't be fun.
Rym: Not because, honestly, the basics of skiing.
Rym: I mean, you saw that South Park.
Rym: French fries, pizza.
Rym: French, that's it.
Scott: But even so, you know, it would take me a while before I could actually ski anywhere fun.
Rym: It would take a lot of time.
Rym: That's not true at all.
Scott: And a lot of money and I might get hurt.
Rym: The first time I ever went skiing, it cost me 20 bucks for a lift ticket and 20 bucks to rent skis.
Rym: I went over to the bunny hill.
Rym: Someone explained to me how to use the tow rope.
Rym: That's all I needed.
Rym: And they explained to me, I took a little 20-minute lesson where they taught me how to go faster, how to go slower, how to turn, and how to not impale myself.
Rym: Impaling yourself, you see, never hold a ski pole out in front of you.
Rym: Because if it, like, anywhere in front of your body, because if it catches, you have basically just planted a spear against the charge.
Rym: And you know that that does triple damage.
Scott: Oh man, I never thought about that one.
Rym: Neither did I. And the ski instructor was like, don't do this, don't do this, don't do this, don't cross your skis, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: Crossing your skis totally sucks.
Scott: See, this thing, there's just too many things.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I can go to a roller coaster.
Scott: It's faster, it's more fun, it's cheaper.
Scott: And I can ride it a bunch of times.
Scott: I don't need to learn anything.
Scott: I don't need to sit on some lift.
Scott: It's not cheap.
Scott: I don't need to wait in line.
Rym: To buy a ticket, to get on the dope-ass Disney train.
Scott: It's much cheaper and it's much less effort.
Rym: Meanwhile, at Roller Coaster Land, press A. Actually, I'm kind of considering the two of us should go.
Rym: Maybe we'll get anyone in on it.
Rym: Should just fly out to Ohio, go to Cedar Point, get all of our rollercoastering out of our system and be done with it forever.
Scott: Maybe that's a good idea.
Scott: Then we'll have to go to the Slitterbot and get all the water parking out.
Scott: The thing is, I kind of want to go to the water park more.
Rym: Well, I do too because I haven't been to a water park nearly so recently as I've ridden And I like water parks a lot more than I like roller coasters.
Rym: Yeah, well that's because you won't go on half the good roller coasters.
Scott: I just don't like the upside downy.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know why.
Rym: I think the upside downy is great as long as it's done well.
Rym: As long as it's all the special kinds of loops and not just a circle.
Scott: Uh, not a fan.
Rym: Yeah, but I like roller coasters, but I like skiing more.
Rym: The problem is I skied in school and I went to RIT and I didn't have any money anymore and no one I knew skied.
Rym: So I basically just gave up skiing.
Rym: And this year, now that I'm finally, I've settled somewhere.
Rym: generally, I have money.
Rym: I thought I'm going to ski.
Rym: I'm going to buy a bunch of equipment.
Rym: I'm going to go skiing.
Rym: And it hasn't fucking snowed until today.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I guess they have places where they make snow.
Scott: Yeah, but there's some mountains that are high enough around here where there's snow, even though there isn't any on our front lawn.
Rym: Oh no.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: There were places I could have gone to ski, but all the places that were really close and really cheap.
Rym: No, not so much.
Scott: There's a reason places are cheap.
Scott: You know, it's when the skiing sucks, they make the prices low because that way you can ski even though it sucks.
Scott: And then, you know, the prices are high.
Scott: That means there's good skiing going on.
Rym: Though a friend of mine from IBM, the one who was over the other day did point out to me that because the skiing season has been generally abysmal, I can pick up ski equipment real cheap.
Scott: Well, it's not real cheap.
Scott: It's relatively cheap.
Rym: No, that's real cheap.
Scott: No, I mean, it's relatively cheap for ski equipment.
Scott: On an absolute scale, ski equipment is still expensive.
Rym: Yeah, but I could outfit myself with everything I would need and high quality relative to my skill for about 500 bucks.
Scott: Yeah, that's about right.
Rym: That's not bad at all.
Scott: Well, you know, it's still 500 bucks is a lot of money.
Scott: You could get a PS3, the low end one.
Scott: Couldn't get a real PS3 or get an Xbox 360 in a game.
Rym: You could buy for good ski equipment and go skiing for less than the cost of an iPhone.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Yeah, but now that I'm older, I love snow still because I want to go skiing.
Rym: I have snowball fights and everything, but most of the time all snow means is my commute is going to take longer because people don't know how to drive.
Scott: Once you get out of high school and the snow, it generally just sucks because you've made enough snowmen in your life.
Scott: Sleds are too small for your body most of the time, even though not always.
Scott: Well, the other thing is skiing takes time and it's expensive.
Scott: You can only do it on the weekend.
Rym: When I went sledding again at RIT, I realized something important.
Rym: When I was a little kid and I sledded, my body was resilient.
Rym: I would just bounce off of things.
Rym: Now, a lot of the things that I did as a kid would kill me, including many of these stunts I've tried to pull when sledding.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You know, when you're a kid, you could just fall down in the snow, jump around.
Scott: It was okay because you just bounced around as an adult.
Scott: You fall down once you're done.
Scott: Oh, my hip.
Scott: Oh, my ribs.
Rym: Yeah, I'm 25 now.
Rym: I'm a quarter of a century old.
Rym: That's the end.
Scott: It's very much the end.
Scott: So, uh, yeah, as an adult, it's like, oh, great, it snowed.
Scott: Now I have to clean off my car.
Scott: Great.
Scott: Now I can't go anywhere.
Scott: It's way for my car to warm up.
Rym: I will never complain about cleaning my car off again.
Scott: Oh, I have to shuffle, you know, shovel the walkway.
Rym: We don't have to shovel the rockway.
Rym: We pay people to do that.
Scott: I know, but you still have to do it indirectly.
Rym: See, the thing is.
Scott: It would be worse if we did have to shovel like most people do.
Rym: I always used to like shoveling snow.
Rym: And if we didn't have a service already, I would just shovel the snow because I like doing it.
Rym: It's good exercise.
Rym: I like being outside like that.
Rym: And usually if I'm out there anyway in snow pants shoveling, I've got no excuse not to build a snowman or something since I'm already snowy.
Scott: The thing is like with shoveling snow is a lot like mowing the lawn, you know, it's like before I mowed the lawn, I really wanted to mow the lawn.
Scott: You know, like I thought mowing the lawn would be so fun.
Scott: And then once you mow the lawn once, you know, it's fun to use the lawnmower.
Scott: But after that, there's no fun in it anymore.
Scott: It's like, oh, great.
Scott: This sucks.
Scott: I walk around for an hour pushing this thing with a tractor.
Scott: It's a little more fun.
Rym: No, no.
Rym: See, I actually even right up until I left, I always like mowing the lawn.
Rym: The only reason I wouldn't want to mow the lawn is that to mow the back lawn, I'd first have to pick up the dog crap.
Rym: And I never wanted to do that.
Scott: See, I just I liked mowing the lawn maybe twice and then it was not fun anymore.
Scott: The same thing with shoveling snow.
Scott: See, I like mowing it.
Scott: You know, if you had a new shovel, it would reinvigorate the joy of snow shoveling for a few minutes.
Rym: Well, we have a new shovel.
Scott: I know.
Scott: So you'd shovel for a few minutes.
Scott: You'd be like, whee, a new shovel.
Scott: And then you'd be like, oh, yeah, shoveling snow sucks.
Scott: Unless, well, I guess if it's a light snow, it's not so bad.
Rym: No, heavier the better.
Rym: I love just battling the elements like that.
Scott: No, just it's like, yeah, it's great to battle the elements for the first battle.
Scott: And then as soon as you win one battle and then you realize you have to fight that same exact battle 100 more times, it's just like, fuck this.
Scott: I'm going inside.
Rym: But remember, we lived in Rochester.
Rym: We can never complain about cleaning off our cars again because here we have to clean our cars off maybe once every couple of weeks, even when a normal winter happens.
Scott: And it's real easy to do it.
Scott: I don't have to chip off a half an inch thick shield of ice from my front windshield.
Rym: In Rochester, it would snow just enough to where you would have to scrape your car off every single night.
Scott: Every snow, not every night.
Scott: Every time you got in your car, you would drop, you would wake up, you'd get in your car, you'd go, you'd wake up, you clean off your car, you'd go to class, you would come back to your car in the parking lot, clean it off, drive home, go inside for 10 minutes, come outside, clean off the car.
Rym: Double awesome.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: My strategy whenever there was a perfect sheet of ice just covering the windows, which there often was, I would turn the car on, have the heat going full blast and all the defrosters and everything on all the time.
Scott: And what eventually would happen is the ice, the part of the sheet of ice that was closest to the windows, the parts that were actually touching the windows of the car would melt.
Scott: And then I would just push the sheet of ice off the car.
Scott: Just whoop.
Scott: That was the great strategy of Scott.
Scott: No chipping, no hacking, no scraping.
Scott: That was the key.
Scott: It still sucked because it took so long to wait for that shit to defrost.
Scott: But it was fun when I pushed that device right onto the ground.
Rym: I always used to love sheets of ice whenever I could get a hold of them.
Rym: I always felt like I was breaking a giant plate glass window.
Scott: Remember that dude with the recycle bin?
Rym: Actually, one time, we'll end on this just because we've already gone way too long for an episode of this caliber.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: My mom had to wash her Jeep to get the salt off of it and the sand off of it so it wouldn't cause problems.
Rym: And it was in the winter, but car washes are open in Michigan in the winter.
Rym: So we go to the self-serve car wash and there is a sheet of ice about three to four inches thick covering both walls.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: So we wash the car and then we pull the car out.
Rym: I go back in and I start doing something that's rather non-intelligent.
Rym: I start poking at this wall.
Scott: That's not a good idea.
Scott: That sheet of ice is going to fall down on you.
Rym: So I realized this right away.
Rym: So I back away from it.
Rym: I take the power washer.
Rym: I put some quarters in because I figured this is going to be worth it.
Rym: Uh-oh.
Rym: I set it to the strongest setting.
Scott: This is not, it's gotta be on YouTube.
Scott: Why didn't you have a camera with you?
Rym: Because I was in high school.
Scott: Dumbass.
Rym: You wanted me to go find my, uh...
Scott: You should have had the foresight to know that 10 years later, YouTube would be around.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Back then the idea of a video on the internet was crazy.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So I set it to the wide spray.
Rym: So I've got...
Scott: Well, I guess real player might've been out.
Rym: So I've got this basically hot sword of water and I proceed to cut the bottom of this ice sheet and eventually I hear creak, creak, creak, creak, creak, creak.
Rym: And then the thing just goes, it starts to fall like the whole thing in one sheet.
Rym: And then the top breaks off and it makes a tremendous mess.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: And then we drove away.
Rym: That pilot was there for another three or four weeks.
Scott: Sweet.
Scott: You should have done the other wall.
Rym: I'd already lost interest.
Scott: Oh, that's too awesome.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.