Scott: It's Thursday, January 25th.
Rym: I'm Scott, and I'm Rym, and this is Geek Next.
Scott: Tonight we discuss Odoru Daiso Sase, a.k.a.
Scott: Bayside Shake Dad, a.k.a.
Scott: Rhythm and Police.
Scott: Let's do this!
Rym: So I had a bit of an adventure going into work today.
Rym: I talk about my car a lot lately, but my car, now that I spend 10 hours a week in it, has a great influence on my life.
Scott: Yeah, I just don't have problems with my car ever since I got a new one.
Scott: You know, I used to be like, "Uh, car's old and shitty, huh?
Scott: Car's old and
Scott: shitty.".
Scott: You used to drive- Then for like a week, it was like, "Uh, I got a new
Scott: car.".
Scott: Then it's, "It's a
Rym: You used to drive the second worst car I had ever sat in.
Scott: The worst car- That was it?
Scott: That was the second worst car you ever sat in?
Scott: You're pretty good off.
Rym: Well, the worst car I ever sat in was the identical car that James owned.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, my car- my old car was bad, but it wasn't that bad.
Scott: I've seen a lot worse cars.
Scott: Like, cars with holes in the floor.
Rym: Oh, I've seen them, but I've never been in them.
Scott: Ahh.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But no, I get up, you know, I'm going to work like you do, and I get in my car, and I start it, and it's like any other day.
Rym: My car drives flawlessly.
Rym: It's an old car, but despite the over 100,000 miles on it, it works like a perfect car.
Rym: Nothing's wrong with it.
Scott: It goes.
Scott: It doesn't have air conditioning, but it goes.
Rym: Yep, and actually, it goes pretty fast, and it's a fairly- considering what I paid for it, and considering it's only 120 horsepower, it performs pretty well.
Rym: I can get up to about 95 before it starts shaking or anything.
Rym: But anyway, so I'm driving to work, and I'm just about to get on the Taconic, when suddenly, the battery light comes on.
Rym: Uh-oh.
Rym: Now, I'm thinking to myself, you know, and then, while I'm thinking to myself, I flash back to a couple years ago, where I was getting my car inspected for New York State, and I'm looking at it, and while they're doing everything, I tell the guy, "Could you please replace my battery?
Rym: That's the original battery from this car.
Rym: It's never been changed.
Rym: It's never been serviced.
Rym: I should probably just get a new
Rym: one.".
Rym: And he took one look at it, tested it, and said, "Not only is this battery fine, it's like new.
Rym: I'll buy you a new battery and pay for your towing if that battery fails you within the next 100,000
Rym: miles.".
Rym: And I was like, "You know what?
Rym: Whatever.".
Rym: And I kept the same battery in, and now-- Did he get that in writing?
Rym: I trust this guy.
Rym: I work with him all the time.
Rym: He's been my mechanic for a long, long time.
Rym: So I'm thinking back to this driving now, and my battery light come on, and I'm thinking, "Son of a fuck.
Rym: That was a bad
Rym: idea.".
Rym: Because either my battery has done something catastrophic, which is somewhat possible because the battery is weird, or my alternator's died, which is the more likely thing in general-- Or somehow, in a freak accident, the wiring somewhere in there got messed up.
Rym: Which isn't out of the realm.
Scott: It's not out of the realm, but it's not common.
Rym: Yeah, old cars tend to have wiring problems.
Scott: If the battery light goes on, 99% of the time, its alternator or battery is broken.
Rym: Most likely, if it comes on while you're driving, it's alternator.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So now I have to debate, because I've just gotten on the Taconic.
Rym: There's basically no civilization between that part of the Taconic where I just got on and my work.
Rym: So I'm debating, "Can I make it to
Rym: work?".
Rym: Because at my job, in the industrial pla-- Well, it was an industrial plaza, now it's more commercial.
Rym: There's actually a mechanic right there.
Scott: Well, if you turn off your radio and your lights-- No.
Rym: See, it depends.
Rym: I'm thinking-- I mean, I'm going all these calculations.
Rym: Is my alternator dead, or is it just not charging the battery so well?
Rym: Does that light mean the alternator's not charging it, or does it mean the battery is close to being drained?
Scott: Yeah, it's the same problem I have with Macs, is that they give you an error message like, "Printer not
Scott: working."
Scott: And I'm like, "Well, why don't you give me some more information so I can actually figure out what the fuck I'm supposed to
Scott: do?".
Scott: Instead of just, "Eh, battery
Scott: problem."
Scott: It's like, "Can I have more details,
Scott: please?".
Rym: Yeah, my car has basically four lights.
Rym: It has check engine, which means anything that isn't described by the other three.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It has a battery light, which I'd never seen before.
Rym: It has a fluid light that refers to any and all measurable fluids in the car.
Rym: If any fluid is low, including my gas, that light will come on.
Scott: Oh, wow, I have a separate gas light.
Rym: And then I have the analog brake and all that.
Rym: But, so now I'm thinking, "Ah, shit, what do I do?
Rym: I know where a mechanic is, but I have to go
Rym: north.".
Rym: And at the last second, I decide, "All right, I'm getting off because I'm at this exit.
Rym: I'm not going to risk it breaking down on this
Rym: conic.".
Rym: So I turn around, I go back up north, and I pull into this mechanic.
Rym: Now, while I'm driving back up north, my headlights, my daytime running lights dim a little bit.
Scott: Uh-oh.
Rym: Then my analog brake light comes on, meaning that there is now no longer enough power for analog brakes.
Scott: Then- At least you still have normal brakes.
Rym: My power steering ceases to function.
Scott: Oh, now it's going to be real hard to drive.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So I obviously had made the right decision, and I kind of hobble into this mechanic, but I've seen this mechanic.
Rym: I've driven past it.
Rym: I've never so much as stopped anywhere near this guy.
Scott: And you say, "Hey, man, you got a battery in
Scott: there?".
Rym: No, so I pull in, and I leave the car running, because once I turn it off- It's over.
Scott: Well, if you're at the mechanic, I would feel safe turning it off.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, so I don't want them to have to drag the car into their little bit.
Scott: Oh, that's true.
Rym: So I walk in, and I'm like, my battery came on, and he's like, "I ever had a problem with your
Rym: alternator?".
Rym: And I said, "I've never had a problem with this
Rym: car.".
Scott: Well, you have.
Rym: No, I had one problem a long time ago that was resolved handily for almost no money.
Rym: In fact, the problem was so simple, I could have fixed it myself if I'd known.
Rym: But this car has had no major repairs ever.
Scott: Well, except for the time you crushed it.
Rym: Well, yeah, when I was involved in a seven-car pileup on 490 outside of Rochester.
Rym: But even then, that was purely cosmetic damage.
Rym: The car itself has had no repairs.
Rym: And, you know, why would the alternator suddenly fail?
Rym: It's been fine forever, but, you know, he tested.
Scott: Because moving parts don't last forever.
Rym: Yeah, but it failed completely.
Scott: Entropy is the win.
Rym: It failed completely and suddenly.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So the guy replaces my alternator, and while he's doing this, I tell him, "Replace my drive train belt thingy," because that thing is also original.
Rym: And he's like, "Yeah, it's kind of
Rym: old-looking.".
Rym: And it's cheap to do, since he's taking the alternator off anyway.
Rym: But more importantly, I tell him, "And while you're at it, replace that battery.
Rym: It's the original freaking
Rym: battery.".
Rym: He's like, "Really?
Rym: Really?".
Rym: And I'm like, "Yeah, it's almost 10 years
Rym: old.".
Rym: He's like, "You've never done anything to
Rym: it?".
Rym: He's like, "I've never even looked at
Rym: it.".
Rym: And he's like, "All right, I'll replace
Rym: "Yeah, goddamn, shouldn't have left that in
Rym: there.".
Rym: So then he's replacing the alternator.
Rym: He comes out and he says, "Come
Rym: here.".
Rym: So I come out and he says, "You're sure this is the original
Rym: battery?".
Rym: I'm like, "Yes, this is the battery that came with the car when it was
Rym: new.".
Rym: And he says, "This battery is acting like a brand new battery.
Rym: There's no reason to replace
Rym: it.".
Scott: - What the hell?
Rym: - This battery is like the battery of the gods.
Scott: - I think that there must be something wrong with the battery that fools the detection machines that test the battery.
Rym: - Because the battery is just fine.
Rym: Not only is the battery fine, but despite the fact that it wasn't being charged for some amount of time, it managed to get me like eight miles back to a mechanic.
Scott: - I think I'll have to submit the battery to some battery test lab and then they can make more batteries like it for other applications like laptops.
Rym: - Well, see, because my family has a history of appliances and cars lasting far longer than they should.
Scott: - Wait, you're suggesting somehow your genealogy is responsible for a magical physics-defying battery?
Rym: - Well, you know, that is obviously the only logical solution because random chance, there's no way.
Rym: I mean, what?
Rym: Ah, ah, call Randy.
Rym: But I mean, no, seriously, my grandparents have a fridge that they've had since the '50s, and it's without service, been working perfectly to this day, and they still use it.
Scott: - Hey, what you gonna do?
Rym: - Keep using it.
Scott: - Yep.
Rym: - Yeah, so I've still got that battery.
Rym: That battery has seen 130,000 miles and almost 10 years of driving.
Scott: - Cool.
Rym: - And that's the end of my story.
Rym: I got to work two hours late, no one batted an eye.
Scott: - Yeah, so I'm at work today and not doing any work, of course.
Scott: And I realize, hey, 'cause I set up this website at work where people can apply to work at our company.
Scott: So I checked it to see if there were any new applications, and there were.
Scott: So I emailed my boss, "Hey, here's some
Scott: applications.".
Scott: And he said, "Cool," like a second later.
Scott: So then I'm like, "Oh yeah, I keep forgetting I'm taking off Katsu-kan,".
Scott: and he says,
Scott: "Okay.".
Scott: And I'm like,
Scott: "Huh.".
Scott: Then I'm like, "Since you're responding so quickly, can we discuss this issue that, you know, you keep avoiding and never
Scott: discussing?".
Rym: - The thing you're supposed to be working on, but no one ever gets back with you?
Scott: - Well, it's more like a recent problem that's come up.
Scott: that's under my responsibility, and I need someone else to do something.
Scott: I can't just do it all on my own.
Scott: I need some discussion, some decision-making.
Rym: - Welcome to my goddamn world.
Rym: I could do all the work I'm given at any job I've ever had in like one day a week if it weren't for the fact that I have to rely on other people.
Scott: - Yeah, so he doesn't respond immediately.
Scott: (laughing).
Scott: - The other things.
Scott: I emailed him, he responded within a second with one word.
Scott: This one, no immediate response.
Scott: A few hours later, doo-doo, there's an Outlook email, and it says, "Yeah, can we talk about that on Monday?
Scott: I'm on vacation in the Dominican
Scott: Republic.".
Rym: - What?
Scott: Why was he checking in?
Scott: See, I don't get this.
Scott: - Well, with the Blackberry action.
Rym: - No, that's not cool, 'cause everyone I work with, if they have any meat, they'll check their work email every day when they're on vacation, and they check it over the weekends, and they check it at night, and as far as I'm concerned, unless I'm on call for something specific, like make sure this doesn't break overnight on this day, I turn my pager off, and I don't even think about work until eight in the morning the next
Scott: day.
Scott: - The thing is, when you have a smartphone, you've got all your emails going to this one device.
Rym: - Oh, I'd set up a filter that would queue up and not show me work email on weekends.
Rym: - You can't do that.
Rym: - Yeah, I could.
Scott: It'd be difficult.
Rym: - Plus, I wouldn't even send my real email to a smartphone.
Rym: Email is, to me, exists solely to talk to people who aren't on aim, I can't call, and I want a record of my conversation in case I need to cover my own ass later.
Scott: - Well, that's what people do, and--.
Rym: - God, most email I send at work these days is simply proving that I put due diligence forth on something.
Scott: - Yeah, so it made me realize, not only does my work not know or care what I do most of the time, but apparently I don't know what they do.
Scott: I mean, think about this, Rym, if your boss went on vacation to the Dominican Republic next week, all week, would you know?
Rym: - God, well, it depends.
Rym: I mean, at IBM, there'd be a lot of times where we'd be sitting around, and something would be going down, and we'd be like, all right, we need to talk to the boss, and then someone would ask the ever-present question, where is the boss?
Rym: Is she in today?
Rym: I thought I saw her this morning, but I wasn't sure.
Rym: Is she in her office?
Rym: Well, she's not on same time, huh.
Rym: But then again, in my work now, I get a month's notice if anyone's gonna be gone for five minutes.
Scott: - Yeah, so I want everyone out there to think about this.
Scott: Maybe start a thread in the forum.
Scott: If your boss went on vacation, would you know about it?
Scott: I mean, my boss apparently is in the Dominican Republic all week, and I had no clue until I tried to talk to him, which I don't do so often.
Rym: - Huh, of course, see, I'm a weird case, 'cause I rarely have a boss straight up.
Scott: - Well, I mean, I don't know if there's technically, there isn't sort of this boss kind of thing, but I mean, I'm the programmer, and he's a CTO, so he's above me.
Rym: - Yeah, I mean, there's a person who clearly, this is the person who will be giving you assignments, and without their input, you won't do anything new.
Scott: - Uh-huh.
Rym: - That's what I would call a boss, at least in the technology world.
Scott: - I don't know, it's sorta, it's weird.
Scott: - 'Cause really, in technology-- - The point is, my job is fucked up, and I'm trying to find a new one.
Rym: - Yeah, I would be trying to find a new one, except my company pays me quite a bit, considering how, I guess, non-technical the job requirements actually are.
Rym: But yes, it's not Monday, it's Thursday, so we're allowed to go on rants, but we're not gonna go too long.
Scott: - Let's move on some news.
Rym: - All right, so on Digg, you might've seen that there was this thing about how, hey, if you microwave a wet sponge for 30 seconds or so, you can de-germify it, clean it up, and whatever, and now it'll be like a brand new sponge, and it won't smell bad.
Scott: - It makes sense, unless you have the problem I have, which is where the sponges get shredded by knives, 'cause we don't have a dishwasher.
Scott: So you have to clean all the knives with the sponge, and thus the sponges get cut up, and then I needed to change the sponge out, even if the sponge is perfectly clean.
Rym: - Also the forks and some of the spatulas, they just do a number on our sponges.
Scott: As soon as you get a dishwasher, we'll be able to use a lot fewer sponges.
Rym: - But yeah, this is old news, but for some reason it was all over Digg, and even some mainstream media picked up on it a little bit.
Rym: The news here is that there
Scott: has been a
Rym: follow-up set of stories on every major news outlet today, talking about the numerous fires, injuries, and accidents that have come about as a result of people who probably don't know much about physics and have no business owning a microwave trying to emulate this trick.
Scott: - Oh my God.
Rym: - Apparently a lot of people heard about this through various means and thought, "Hey, that's a great
Rym: idea.".
Rym: So they went to their microwave, they dutifully put their dry, not soaked in water sponge in the microwave, which is the same as putting nothing in the microwave.
Rym: They then turned the microwave on for like five minutes and walked away, assuming it would sterilize the sponge.
Scott: - Five minutes?
Rym: - Well in many cases, they just didn't put a wet sponge in.
Rym: I mean, running an empty microwave is not the best idea.
Scott: - All right, now go ahead.
Scott: Did anyone put some steel wool or a Brillo pad in there?
Scott: - Yes.
Scott: - Oh, oh God.
Rym: - So now, there are stories on CNN and MSNBC about such things as, "Yes, you can do this.
Rym: "Make sure you wet the sponge.
Rym: "Make sure your sponge does not contain metal.
Rym: "Make sure you keep an eye on it.
Rym: "Make sure you only do it for a short amount of time.
Rym: "Be warned, the sponge will be hot.
Rym: "when you try to remove
Rym: it.".
Scott: - Yeah, this actually kind of fooled me for a second.
Scott: Like when I saw the story on Digg, I saw the headline only, I didn't read it.
Scott: I said, "That makes a lot of sense,
Scott: yeah.".
Scott: And I'm like, "Someone should just make a dishwasher.
Scott: "that uses microwaves to clean all the
Scott: dishes.".
Scott: And then I said, "Wait a minute, "you couldn't put silverware in
Scott: there.".
Rym: - Not at all.
Scott: - But other than that, it's an okay idea when you think about it.
Scott: If something is microwave safe, there's no reason you couldn't clean it with microwaves.
Rym: - Well, except that microwaves wouldn't remove physical gunk, all it would do is disinfect.
Scott: - Eventually they would.
Rym: - Nah, 'cause depending on the gunk, it might not even burn or anything.
Rym: Most of the microwaves died because if you run microwaves, especially older ones without anything in 'em, they'll just burn themselves out.
Scott: - Mm, I guess maybe.
Scott: a dishwasher with some sort of microwave action might, it might be okay.
Rym: - Most modern dishwashers basically steam clean--.
Scott: - Yeah, well they have the steam clean super heat burning everything to death function.
Rym: - Yeah, which we'd probably use.
Scott: - They use it once in a while to super clean the dishes.
Rym: - Once a month to clean all the silverware.
Scott: - Yeah, it makes all the dishes real hot though, like hotter than the microwave.
Scott: - That's fine.
Rym: We have enough dishes to entertain like 40 people.
Scott: I don't think-- - I don't think we, oh.
Rym: - Well, silverware.
Scott: - Yeah, oh, okay.
Rym: - We have enough silverware to entertain 40 people.
Scott: - Hey, if you count the plastic silverware, yes.
Rym: - Oh God, if you count the plastic silverware.
Scott: - All right, so remember Diebold?
Rym: - I'm well aware of the company called Diebold.
Rym: - Yeah, well, apparently-- - They make voting machines for those of you who are unawares.
Scott: - Incredibly insecure and faulty voting, electronic voting machines.
Rym: - Lots of shady business going around left and right.
Scott: - Yes, the government trusts this, the US government trusts this company to make sure that electronic voting works and is not hacked or frauded or anything.
Rym: - Well, these machines have already been compromised in almost every single way possible.
Rym: Are you telling me that the last possible way has been compromised?
Scott: - Well, apparently, the company Diebold on their website, oh, okay, these voting machines all have a key that you can use to physically open them, all right?
Scott: And that's pretty secure, a key.
Scott: I mean, this key's not the most secure thing in the world, but you gotta copy a key, it's not--.
Rym: - Yeah, well, I mean, think about it, even if-- - You need to call a locksmith to sit there.
Rym: - Well, no, even if it's a pickable lock, 'cause almost all locks are easily pickable, it takes a non-trivially amount of time, like, it takes a couple minutes, and you can't just sit there using a bump key inside of the voting booth, they'll notice.
Scott: - Yeah, and nobody's gonna have these keys except election workers and Diebold themselves.
Rym: - Granted, there were corrupt election workers at the most recent election where I voted, but I digress.
Scott: - Yes, anyway, remember how Princeton was doing a study on these voting machines and showed how they were all insecure and everything?
Scott: Well, they noticed on the Diebold website, because if you're studying Diebold machines, you're gonna go to Diebold's website, that there was a picture of the key.
Rym: - Um, was this the high resolution picture, per chance?
Scott: - It wasn't, I don't know how high the resolution was.
Rym: - What, they've got like an HDTV screenshot fully zoomed in of the keys on it?
Rym: -
Scott: I don't know, but they took the picture of the key, they went to Ace Hardware, they got some similar looking keys, and they sculpted the keys, you know, into look like the one in the picture, and two out of the three keys opened the test voting machine that they had for their lab.
Rym: - Outstanding.
Scott: - So Diebold realized this mistake, and changed the picture on the website to a picture of a digital key card, instead of the physical key to open the voting machines.
Rym: - Yeah, way to close that barn door, I'm sure those horses will.
Scott: - That's what it says right here.
Scott: It says, "Shutting the barn door after horse has
Scott: left.".
Rym: - See, you gotta be in that, like in WarioWare, smooth moves when those customers are trying to get out of your store, you just gotta pull that thing down.
Scott: - That's right, that's right.
Rym: - Of course, maybe if you just never opened it in the first place.
Scott: - Yeah, this is just a lesson in security, and for everyone out there who, you know, is not security minded, don't put a picture of your frickin' key anywhere.
Rym: - Things of the day.
Rym: So cats don't like to get wet, that is well known.
Rym: I have watched people attempt to watch cats who did not want to be washed, and serious injuries have resulted.
Scott: - I've always seen people who use like, spray bottles of water to like, tame their cats.
Rym: - That doesn't wash them, however.
Scott: - No, it doesn't wash them.
Rym: - All that does is piss them off and cause them to further plot your demise.
Scott: - All right.
Rym: - So basically, I've seen people wash cats.
Rym: that tends to involve wearing leather gloves, holding the cat at arm's length, into a spray of water, and holding it there.
Scott: - You'll get to scratch up your arms pretty bad.
Rym: - That's why you tend to wear protective equipment.
Scott: - Can't you just take your cat to like a grooming place that'll wash your cat for you?
Rym: - Well you can, and thanks to the power of the internet, we now know what goes on in many of these places.
Rym: Apparently there's a product that is basically a torture chamber for cats.
Rym: - What?
Rym: - It's this box, and it's called like a pet spa.
Scott: - Wait, wait, wait, if you took it to a grooming place, wouldn't like, one person just hold the cat, and then another person wash it for you?
Rym: - That's not, I mean, cats are pretty strong, and you're gonna have to pretty much hold the cat's arms and legs so it doesn't scratch everybody.
Rym: I imagine they use this on cats that are particularly, I don't know, evil.
Rym: But, all right, so this video is kinda, I mean it's funny, but at the same time, that poor cat, but at the same time, the cat probably smelled a little bit better when this was all over.
Scott: - Okay.
Rym: - So they take this cat, and they put it in this box with a big window door.
Rym: It looks like a washing machine.
Rym: So they close the door, and the cat's just kinda sittin' there like, the fuck is this shit, childs?
Rym: What's goin' on?
Rym: The cat's lookin' around like, ugh.
Rym: Then the guy walks up, and he punches in some settings, like air temperature and water temperature and whatever.
Rym: And the cat suddenly jumps and looks around with his look of, oh no, you didn't.
Rym: And it's at this moment that water starts to bubble up a little bit in the bottom.
Rym: And the cat looks at the water and looks out the window, and that cat is ready to kill anyone.
Rym: (laughing).
Rym: Now this bubble of water turns into multi-directional spray, and at this point, the cat loses it.
Rym: And there's no way out, and the cat doesn't, the cat is basically like a guy screamin', fallin' off of a building, where eventually you just run out of breath and stop screamin', and just kinda take it.
Rym: The cats go freakin' out and freakin' out, press A, press A, water's in the room, it's gettin' you wet.
Rym: And then finally, the cat just gets so tired that it just kinda half-assedly is poking at the door like, bastards, all of you.
Rym: And when they finally take the cat out, it has this look of just, I can't describe how angry and tired this cat looks.
Rym: I feel bad for it, but at the same time, how else are you gonna wash a cat?
Scott: - The hose.
Scott: Hoses work.
Rym: - It's pretty hilarious.
Rym: And don't think it cruel of me that I laugh, because I guarantee that you will laugh at least a little bit at this.
Scott: - How can you not?
Rym: - Oh my God.
Scott: - So apparently there's a trivia game show in Britain, and I don't know the name of it, but someone else probably does, and they're gonna yell at me.
Scott: So I'm not even gonna say the name, because I might be wrong.
Scott: But anyway, it appears from watching this video on YouTube that the way the show works is you choose a topic for yourself.
Scott: Like, I could go on and say, ask me about Linux.
Scott: Yeah, that's right, ask me about Linux.
Scott: Oh look, I know everything.
Scott: Pund.
Scott: And then at the second part of the show, they ask you general stuff, which is usually stuff you have no idea.
Rym: - Like pop star blah, football team blah.
Scott: - Yeah, and you go, ah shit.
Scott: But, you know, and then I guess whoever, when you get questions right, you get points.
Scott: It seems pretty good, it's kinda fun.
Scott: Anyway, this chick went on the show, and she says, yeah, ask me about H.P.
Scott: Lovecraft, that's all right.
Scott: - Ooh.
Scott: - That's right.
Scott: And she's like, yeah, I know that shit.
Scott: What you gonna do about it?
Scott: And it's pretty cool.
Rym: - I gotta say-- - You're the chicks in Britain.
Rym: - I'm a huge fan of H.P.
Rym: Lovecraft, but I couldn't answer three quarters of those questions.
Scott: - Yeah, and for anyone who, you know, is still kinda new to the whole H.P.
Scott: Lovecraft thing, you might learn something watching this.
Scott: 'Cause like in the middle part, the host guy kinda questions her out about H.P.
Scott: Lovecraft a little bit, and she gives you some information.
Scott: Of course, you'll probably learn more going to Wikipedia, but hey.
Rym: - Or just reading the Colorado of Space.
Scott: - Yeah, or any of those other--.
Rym: - Or the thing on the doorstep.
Scott: - Or the Call of Cthulhu.
Rym: - Tales of Horror and the Macabre.
Rym: - Yeah, whatever.
Rym: - Tales of Terror and Death.
Scott: - Yeah, so, it's pretty cool, you should watch it.
Scott: I don't know, this actually looks like a pretty cool quiz show.
Scott: You know, it's definitely a lot better than that millionaire where I just get frustrated and go, goddamn, you're stupid, goddamn.
Rym: (laughing) What orbits around God?
Rym: Without further ado, we've been doing a lot of hard-hitting episodes lately.
Scott: Just in terms of-- - At least we think we have.
Rym: - Not in terms of particularly our content or the way we handle the show, but in terms of things that we particularly like.
Rym: I mean, Dave and Joel talk a lot about things they don't like.
Rym: We talk a lot about things we like, and this is something we like perhaps more than almost anything.
Scott: - I don't know about that.
Scott: - We like it a lot, though, a whole lot.
Scott: - Well, consider-- - We like it as much as you like Initial D.
Rym: - I think I like it more than Initial D. I think I like it twice as much as I like Initial D.
Scott: - Oh, that's a whole lot of liking going on.
Scott: - It is, goddamn.
Scott: - I like it as much as I like Initial D, which is a lot.
Rym: - Odoru Daisousasen.
Scott: - Hey, hey, everyone listen to that carefully.
Scott: Odoru Dais-- - So-- - I had it right, and now when I actually try to do it on the show, Daisousasen.
Rym: - Yes, now the reason we say it and bring that up is that when we first heard of this and we found out, there's a whole story as to how we came up to this.
Rym: There were many near misses where we almost found out about this but didn't, due to our own stupidity.
Scott: - We'd be like, oh, doo doo, D.C.
Scott: Sousen.
Rym: - Well, we didn't even know what it was.
Rym: - Yeah, yeah.
Rym: - An event for a longest time, I was like, Odoru Daisousasen, and finally our friend Katsu was like, RM, it's not how you say it.
Scott: - Yep, Daisousasen, Sousasen.
Scott: - O-A-E.
Rym: - Before we go into the details of what exactly this is, other than the fact that it's awesome, I think we should give you a little bit of backstory as to how we discovered it, 'cause it's a convoluted and interesting tale.
Scott: - Mm-hmm.
Rym: - You see, now remember, there's a pre-story before any of this when I was a freshman at RIT and our friend Katsu was a freshman, and he would talk fairly often about this cop drama from Japan that he was a big fan of, and we all just kinda totally brushed it off 'cause we had no way to see it, we
Scott: didn't--.
Scott: - I remember him talking about it freshman year.
Rym: - I remember it partly because he had a scheme to try to fan sub it.
Scott: - See, I remember that coming later, but it doesn't really matter.
Rym: - And he tried, he wanted my help, and I didn't know a lot about that sort of thing, I didn't have a genlock, and I didn't have all the good software to do it well nowadays, so we tried a little bit, I watched an episode raw, and I didn't know what it was, and I didn't understand it, so I didn't think it was that funny, and after a little while, we just kinda ignored it, and I forgot about it.
Rym: - Fast forward, playing DDR, we're playing the song that is perhaps my second favorite song in DDR, and Katsu says to us, "Hey, that's the theme song "to my cop
Rym: show.".
Scott: - See, I don't even remember that particular incident, I just remember somehow, we had this song in DDR.
Scott: that was a cool song that we liked to do, and somehow, it came into my brain from someone else that there's a TV show about police that goes with this song here.
Rym: - See, I think it might have been for me, because when I played with Katsu, and then Katsu was like, "This is from that cop show,".
Rym: and I was like, "Oh,
Rym: really?".
Rym: Rhythm and police.
Scott: - But yeah, all I knew for the longest time was rhythm and police, it's a song in DDR, it's a cop show of some sort, and the theme song is really cool, and it's in DDR, and I like to dance it, and I wish I could find the show in English.
Rym: So then, we talked about it for a few days off and on, and it came up, and the gist was, Katsu had a bunch of it, untranslated, and that was basically the end of that, we weren't gonna--.
Scott: - Yeah, I'm not even, yeah.
Rym: - I tried to watch an episode or two with him kinda translating, but I didn't have the magic.
Rym: So whatever, forget about it.
Rym: Fast forward to the future.
Scott: - Well, every once in a while, we would play the song, and we would always think, "Ah, all right, there's a
Scott: show.".
Rym: - It's just like the tapestry with your family.
Rym: It would just come up, and like, "Yeah, we should do something, eh,
Rym: whatever.".
Rym: So then, fast forward further.
Rym: We have the Video Barn, which is the most awesome--.
Scott: - Well, in Rochester, in, well, Henrietta, Rochester, New York, near RIT, there is a video rental place, much like a Blockbuster, however not Blockbuster, it is Video Barn.
Rym: - Yeah, here's the caliber of this place.
Rym: We walked in, and we saw some movie that had just gibberish on it, moon language, but written over it in marker was very good sword fighting.
Scott: - I think it said, "Sword fighting very
Scott: good.".
Rym: - Something like that, so we decided--.
Scott: - What was that, Princess Blade?
Rym: - Princess Blade, which was a crap movie, but-- - Sword fighting very good.
Rym: - Sword fighting very good indeed.
Rym: And you know, we went there once, we're like, "Hey, you ever heard of this movie called "Attack the Gas
Rym: Station?".
Scott: - The guy reaches behind him, pulls the DVD out, and it's like, "Here you
Scott: go.".
Rym: - Here you go, and then we bring it back, he's like, "They liked it, didn't
Rym: ya?".
Scott: - These guys are pretty awesome.
Scott: It's like the best damn video store in the world.
Scott: I mean, not only did they have all sorts of awesome Asian films, not only did they have basically every anime ever released in the United States on VHS or DVD.
Rym: - Including a lot of Japanese stuff.
Scott: - Yeah, not only did they have a huge selection of porn that I never looked at.
Scott: - Well, we walked in once.
Scott: - We walked in once, and let me tell you, the porn section of the video store looks a lot like really colorful manga from far away.
Scott: - Yeah, until you get up close and-- - It looks like a bunch of teen magazines from far away.
Scott: With all these bright magenta and yellow colors all over the place, and so that's what I remember from going back there for like five seconds.
Scott: - So Scott and I would often just-- - Oh yeah, they also had basically every movie ever.
Rym: - Yeah, especially obscure stuff, and art house stuff.
Rym: So Scott and I used to go a lot and just spend a half hour looking, pick a movie based on the cover.
Rym: Usually we'd look for more than one Yakuza, perhaps some lightning in the background, anything like that, anything-- - We always had trouble remembering to return stuff, the video bar.
Rym: - Yeah, but they never cared.
Scott: - No, they didn't.
Rym: - 'Cause they knew us, and they seemed to be really cool and kinda with it.
Scott: - Yeah, anyone who was renting awesome movies, they liked.
Scott: Anyone who was renting normal stuff, they were like, whatever.
Rym: - And they never steered us wrong.
Rym: If they recommended something, it was solid gold.
Scott: - Yep.
Rym: - So one day, Scott and I are there, and we don't have katsu around or anything, and we see this movie called Bayside Shakedown, and I'm like, hey.
Scott: - I kinda wanted to get this ninja movie or something.
Rym: - But I'm like, hey, wait a minute.
Rym: That guy kinda looks like the guy from that cop show that katsu always talks about.
Scott: - I'm like, what?
Scott: Are you saying that that's the rhythm and police whatnot?
Rym: - And I'm like, I don't know.
Rym: So we're reading the back of it, and we're trying to figure it out.
Rym: I tried to call katsu a bunch of times, but I couldn't get ahold of him.
Scott: - Yeah, and I'm like, I don't know if this is it, man.
Scott: It looks like just some random police movie.
Rym: - So we decide after a while, it's either the ninja movie or this, and we decide we can't pass this up.
Rym: There's a chance.
Rym: Worst case, it sucks.
Rym: We deal with it, my bad.
Rym: So we take it home, and we watch it.
Rym: And we're not sure if it's the thing until the music starts.
Rym: And at that point, we knew that we had struck gold.
Rym: This was it.
Rym: We didn't know.
Rym: TV show, movie, multiple movies, whatever.
Rym: All we knew was that this was a movie about the exact same thing that that cop show was.
Scott: - It was a movie that was the thing the DDR song came from.
Rym: - Now, not only is this movie so amazing, not only should we tell movies you should see to review it, why'd we tell them to do Attack the Gas Station?
Scott: - No, Attack the Gas Station, I think, is more important.
Rym: - Yeah, but they should do this.
Scott: - I like this as much as I like Attack the Gas Station.
Rym: - Yeah, me too.
Rym: We then immediately showed it to a bunch of other people, like the whole crew.
Scott: - It was like, oh shit, we found an awesome movie.
Scott: We must show everyone.
Rym: - And then we showed it to more people.
Rym: We rented it multiple times.
Scott: - I think they did a fireside Friday with it.
Scott: - Yep.
Scott: - Oh no, I remember.
Scott: - Yeah.
Rym: - Yeah.
Rym: - So then, I was on the board of this anime club, this huge anime club for three years.
Rym: And I was president, I was riding high, I was at the peak of my popularity at RIT, I had my adoring fans, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: But the tradition at RIT is that when a president resigns at the end of his term, before he graduates--.
Scott: - But when an anime club president resigns.
Rym: - Well, yeah, because-- - You're like, the tradition at RIT, when the president resigns, like what the president of RIT is-- At RIT, there was the anime club and the gaming club and the other gaming club, and pretty much every other club was just bupkis.
Rym: I mean, the anime club had more members than like 80% of the rest of the clubs combined, and the gaming club was almost up there.
Rym: Like, the geek clubs outnumbered everyone else.
Scott: - Yep.
Rym: - But the tradition was, when you're retiring, when you're done, when you're passing the reins on to another president, you get a showing that's all yours, you can show whatever anime you want.
Rym: And not only did I show Bayside Shakedown, which is not an anime, it's live action, but I built it up for months.
Rym: I mean, I'd leave hints like it's got an opening song that is also in a DDR game.
Scott: - And when you, I remember when you put it in, some guy in the back was like, wait a minute, is this Rhythm and Police?
Rym: - And at that moment, the song comes up and the crowd's like, woo, woo!
Rym: And I'm like, yeah, by the way, it's live action.
Rym: The crowd's like, what?
Scott: - And then they said, oh shit, it doesn't matter.
Rym: - Yeah, 'cause I pretty much told them, 'cause it was one of the highest, like there were so many people there.
Rym: It was one of the biggest showings ever.
Rym: Not the biggest, no, but one of the biggest.
Rym: And not only, like I warned everyone, this isn't an anime, and they're like, what?
Rym: I was like, I will stake all of my honor and I guarantee that you will all like this, I promise.
Rym: I put everything on the line.
Scott: - And you did not lie.
Rym: - Oh my God, there's a scene at the end of this movie where the crowd is silent, absolutely silent.
Rym: You could hear a pin drop in that room and everyone's like (gasps).
Scott: - That's my favorite part, where they're on top of the building.
Rym: - Yeah, that and the car ride afterward.
Rym: When they're driving away and that sad music's playing.
Scott: - Yeah, it's all right.
Rym: - And then when the two big events happened, it was one of the few times in the history of the Anime Club where not only did the crowd cheer and scream, but they jumped up and gave a standing cheer scream applause in the middle of a movie.
Rym: Not at the end, in the middle, because one thing happened.
Rym: That's how awesome this is.
Rym: It was so fantastic, that showing.
Scott: - Anyway, I learned, to give you a perspective on how great this movie is, I'll give you a fact I learned today from Wikipedia, you ready?
Scott: Oh, two facts from Wikipedia.
Scott: Number one fact, this is the fifth best performing film in Japanese box office history.
Scott: Remember, this is Japan we're talking about.
Scott: This is competing with Miyazakis and Akira's and all those other live action Japanese movies.
Scott: - Yeah, number-- - This is number five.
Scott: There are only four better Japanese movies than this according to Japanese people.
Rym: - Nevermind the fact that the show itself was crazy popular.
Rym: - Yep.
Rym: - And is still crazy popular.
Scott: - And after the TV series was off the air, applications to the police force in Japan skyrocketed.
Scott: Yeah, so let's give a rundown on the whole thing 'cause it's not just a movie.
Rym: - No, it's in 1997 and '98, there was, I think, whatever.
Scott: - There was a TV series, it was a TV drama.
Rym: - Odoru Daiso Sase.
Scott: - That's what started the whole thing.
Rym: - Now it's about a guy, Aoshima, who quits his job to join the police force because he's idealistic, he wants to make Japan a better place.
Rym: So he is working in this made up precinct somewhere, I think it's around Tokyo or in Tokyo.
Scott: - Yeah, they make up the fictional Wangen precinct.
Scott: Wangen, whatever, it doesn't matter.
Rym: - And he's idealistic, he's young, he's energetic, he wants to change the world.
Rym: Problem is, the actual police force is no better than his corporate job.
Rym: There's full of red tape and bureaucracy, civil servants that don't give a crap, his bosses are more concerned with keeping their jobs and saving face and looking good for the national police than they are actually fighting crime, and his hands are tied behind his back at every turn, a lot of people are incompetent, and it's just, it's a comedy.
Scott: - Yeah, there's a lot of character drama going on, like there's the old detective who's smart and awesome, and there's the girl who's a girl.
Rym: - Yep, and there's Moroi.
Scott: - It was Moroi who's the best character, even though he's not the main character.
Rym: - To put it in a perspective that would make sense to Americans, imagine if Aoshima, the main character, is like a beat cop on the street, and the old detective is like an old, retired, amazing detective in the US, and Moroi is like an FBI guy who comes in when big things happen, and he can't concern himself with the little stuff.
Scott: - Yeah, I think he used to be, I think the story of Moroi is that he was a little guy, but he was so good that he got pushed up into the ranks, and therefore is more awesome.
Rym: - Yeah, see, we haven't actually seen the show, so we can't talk a lot about the backstory.
Scott: - Yeah, we've only seen the two big movies, which is what we're gonna talk mostly about.
Rym: - Bayside Shakedown, and then Bayside Shakedown II, Save the Rainbow Bridge, which was basically the exact same movie.
Scott: - Yeah, anyway, after the show ended, there were a few special TV episodes, then the two big movies, and then in 2005, there were two spin-off movies, and that's it, that's all there is.
Scott: - Yep, for now at least, I mean, it's been, I mean, the last movie-- - It's been two years since they did anything, those spin-off movies, but they might do more.
Rym: - It was two years between the second movie and the spin-off movies.
Scott: - That is true, that is true.
Rym: - And apparently the show still sells really, really well on DVD over there.
Scott: - Yeah, there was a DVD box set of the whole show I just saw on the internets on CD Japan, it was a lot of money, and it didn't have subtitles, it was region two box set, but it was really nice, and they said the DVD set came out in 2005, so, you know, hey, not bad.
Rym: - But anyway, the pertinent information here is simply that you don't need to have seen any of the show or anything to appreciate the movie, because the movie is standalone, and while all of the character drama is there, and in fact, a lot of character drama from the show comes to a head, but yet they do it well enough to where you know exactly where everyone stands, and you don't know the exact backstory, but you know enough about who likes who, and who's with who, and what's going on, to enjoy it fully.
Scott: - Yeah, so there are some inside jokes that you won't get.
Scott: if you watch the movie without seeing the show, such as there's the mascot of the police station, you won't know what the hell it is, but there was a whole episode about it, you just see it there in the movie, but it doesn't actually hurt your enjoyment of the movie, but it can enhance the enjoyment of the movie if you do know.
Rym: - But you can't really get ahold of the show.
Scott: - No, not in English, not easily in English.
Rym: - Yes, the movie, however, you can just get.
Rym: It's in English, on DVD.
Rym: - Yep.
Rym: - Get it at any anime con, they always have it.
Scott: - You can get it on the internet, it's pure Amazon and eBay, and just make sure you get a DVD with subtitles, we had one, it was at Video Barn, you can get one too, they exist.
Rym: - Yes, they're also torrents periodically, because this movie is super popular.
Scott: - Yeah, fifth biggest movie in Japan ever is gonna be a torrent somewhere.
Rym: - Now, I think what makes these movies, well this movie in particular, so amazing, before we get into a lot of the details, is simply that there's drama, and there's serious drama, and there are very, very poignant, amazing action moments, and it's a straight up action-packed thriller, but at the same time, it's a straight up laid back, goofy, pun-riddled, low comedy.
Scott: - Yeah, I mean, dramedy is usually a bad word, but this isn't like all the dramedies that, the typical, stereotypical dramedies in the United States, you know, it's more like, it's not like a combination of drama and comedy, it's the two side by side, with not interfering with each other so much.
Rym: - Yes, and while the plot, if you actually analyze it from way back, is not the most complex thing in the world, and there are a couple of, effectively, deus ex machinos coming around, the thing is, it's executed to the point that it'll take you along for the ride.
Rym: We kind of mentioned that in Brave Story.
Rym: It's so good, you'll just go along for the ride, accept everything at face value, and it's just awesome.
Scott: - Yeah, a lot of it is kind of silly, like the detectiving, you're not getting the best detectiving action here.
Rym: - It's Phoenix Wright level of detectiving.
Scott: - It's a little better than Phoenix Wright level, but not much better.
Rym: - Yeah, but the movie itself, this one specifically, is about, actually, I don't want to ruin anything about this movie, it's really hard to talk about it.
Scott: There's a crime.
Rym: - Yes, well, here's the thing.
Rym: The opening scene, I don't want to ruin this, but when we showed the movie, the opening scene happens, and the whole crowd in the anime club was like, wow, I didn't expect a movie to be like this, and the opening scene, the way it gets resolved, is so hilarious.
Scott: - With the golf?
Rym: - And so amazing.
Scott: - Is that the golf one in the car?
Rym: - Yeah.
Scott: - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Scott: - Yeah.
Scott: - The second movie, actually, the second movie, the second movie is not as good as the first movie, but it's still good, but the opening bit of the second movie with the hostage situation on the boat with the guns is so awesome, oh my god, I think that was like the best scene in both movies combined.
Scott: The beginning of the second movie is the best scene in the whole thing.
Rym: - I don't know, I think the die in the air scene and the (snores) scene.
Scott: - Those are good ones, but I think the boat was way cool, 'cause it totally fools you right away.
Rym: - It does, 'cause I was thinking, what the fuck?
Rym: What the fuck?
Rym: And I didn't learn my lesson from the first movie.
Rym: - Nope, not at all.
Scott: - At all.
Scott: - I didn't learn it either.
Scott: I'm watching the second movie going, what the fuck's going on here?
Scott: And then all of a sudden it's like, mother, oh, woo!
Rym: - It takes a movie, a fucking movie, to fool you twice.
Scott: - Fool me three times.
Rym: - Can't fool me again.
Scott: - Yeah.
Rym: - But long story short, a big name, a big shot, an important person gets kidnapped.
Rym: And Aoshima is a beat cop, and they wanna solve the crime.
Rym: But at the same time, because it's a big crime, the high up Moroi and all the real cops, like the national awesome cops come in.
Scott: - And a lot of the drama of the movie is the big people at the top of the National Police Department of Japan, all the big time people running the investigation, they are all doing grumbly stuff that's not so good.
Scott: And the guys who work on their feet, the actual cops, they know how to get this job done, and there's all sort of conflict between them.
Scott: At the same time, they're trying to find the guy who did the crime.
Scott: And aren't there some side crimes also?
Rym: - Yeah, it seems to be.
Rym: both movies were like this.
Rym: There's the main plot crime.
Rym: But there are two, or actually I think there are three, pretty much unrelated threads of crime that are going on that they have to deal with independently of the main crime.
Scott: - Yeah, usually all of the detective people will be looking to solve the big crime, but each one of them will have some sort of side crime they have to deal with.
Rym: Like what was the one, the-- - Well, there's the crazy woman with the suicide thing.
Scott: - Yeah, there was like a purse snatcher or something?
Scott: What was it?
Scott: - Well, there's the-- - That's right, someone was stealing things from the desks of people in the police department.
Rym: - However, that one has a twist ending.
Scott: - That one has a great twist ending.
Scott: It's hilarious.
Scott: I'm not gonna give that away at all.
Rym: - Oh, we can't give anything away.
Rym: This movie is, ugh.
Scott: - That's a big part of this movie is total surprises.
Scott: It's like, huh, there's a mystery.
Scott: And you can kinda get some clues a little bit, but not so much, 'cause it's not a mystery show.
Scott: It's a comedy drama.
Scott: So mystery doesn't enter into it so much.
Scott: And then when it kindly resolves, surprise!
Scott: And you go, oh, shits!
Scott: And it's either "Lul" or "Oh My God" or both.
Rym: - Yes, this movie really is a kind of a rollercoaster of build you up and then hit you over the head with an awesome scene.
Rym: And then build you up and hit you over the head with a more awesome scene.
Rym: You'll yell at the screen multiple times.
Scott: And I insist-- with people around.
Scott: 'Cause watching it alone, you don't get the same effect.
Scott: - The more people you have in the room with me-- - Oh, and you gotta turn the music up loud.
Scott: - Yes.
Scott: - I think we've just demonstrated that enough.
Rym: - I think we have.
Rym: Now we were talking about the big, national, fancy police versus the low beat police.
Rym: And this seems to be a theme or a thread that is present in a lot of Japanese fiction.
Rym: Where there's the person on the front lines, the person, like the grunt down there.
Rym: And he knows how to get the job done.
Rym: And he has to trust the people above him to make the right decisions.
Rym: And then there's the people at the top.
Rym: Who have to, they have to make the right decisions because the things they do directly affect the people on the line.
Rym: And they rely on the people on the front lines to do things for them.
Rym: But at the same time, they can't just walk all over those people or nothing will get done.
Rym: And it's this whole kind of, the bond between the low level salary man and the high level CEO.
Rym: And how both of them are required.
Rym: And how you have to have a balance between the two.
Rym: And all these sorts of things that are really cool and poignant, but you don't need to worry about them if you don't care because there's also awesome, crazy, funny scenes.
Scott: - It also has a little bit of sanctuary in it.
Scott: You know, a sanctuary is all about, I'm in the mafia and you're in the government and we'll work together, you know, me on one side and you on the other side to, you know, set things right.
Scott: There's also-- - In Bayside Shankdown, they have the whole thing of, you know, we're friends, you go up the ladder and I'll stay here on the streets and we'll work together to set things right.
Rym: - And there's this really cool plot of like, the friendship between Oshima and Moroi is really strained by this.
Rym: Because Moroi has to make decisions based on information that Oshima can't see.
Rym: And Moroi often has to make decisions that are painful or outright suck for reasons that he has no control over.
Rym: But those things still fuck Oshima.
Rym: And he has, he trusts Moroi and he has to trust Moroi even when he thinks that Moroi is doing the wrong thing.
Rym: Because his role is the grunt, doing what they say.
Scott: - Yep.
Rym: - Of course, he's also a troublemaker who never gets any sleep and can never go to the bathroom.
Scott: - Oh yeah, there's all kinds of stuff like that.
Rym: - Actually, one of my favorite scenes now that I'm thinking about that thread is remember the scene where-- - The vending machine in the-- - I was about to say the vending machines where-- - I always remember that one.
Scott: I don't know if I like it so much.
Scott: It's a good scene, but it's not like my favorite.
Scott: But I always remember it.
Rym: - Well, the fact that the old detective was eavesdropping.
Scott: - Yeah, the old detective, I think, is my favorite character in the whole thing.
Rym: - Yeah, I mean, I like Oshima in the same way that I would like Ranma.
Rym: It's just, like, he's the awesome, funny, oh my god.
Rym: guy.
Rym: But all the supporting cast are really good.
Scott: - Yeah, the girl actually reminds me, like, Scully from X-Files, only less serious, and Japanese.
Rym: - Yeah, we've really avoided talking about the movie in any specific detail, because ruining this movie is a crime.
Rym: I mean, that's like ruining cowboy bebop for someone.
Rym: It's just, you can't do it.
Rym: That's horrid.
Scott: - The thing is, this is just not very well known outside of Japan, and it's awesome.
Rym: - Yes, I can't stress enough.
Rym: I know we say this a lot about things, but that's just because we tend to review things we really like.
Rym: I guarantee you will like this movie.
Scott: - If you are a human being.
Rym: - If you do not like this movie, and you give us a valid reason, an actual valid reason, I mean, we'll probably play your critique on the show.
Rym: If you actually give us a good reason why you didn't like this movie, but you'd better be honest, because we'll know if you actually liked it, and you're just lying to get on the show.
Scott: - Yeah, you could be just lying.
Rym: - We'll know, because I've never met a human being who did not absolutely love this movie after they saw it.
Scott: - Yeah, I think one of the key things about this movie that makes it so great is, here in the United States, right, we have police shows, and the range of police shows seems to be on one end, we've got NYPD, Blue, and CSI, and all these serious, you know,
Rym: police,
Scott: we gotta figure out who did this horrible thing, we found 'em.
Rym: - We found 'em decapitated.
Scott: - It's all dark and gritty, and police procedural.
Scott: And on the other end, we have police academy.
Scott: - God.
Scott: - Or naked gun, and crap like that.
Scott: We don't have the in-between in the United States.
Scott: Can you think of one?
Rym: - Not really, I can't think of any movie that's at all like this.
Scott: - Every police, or detective, or even lawyer, there isn't so much loi-ing in Bayside Shakedown, or Doru Daisousasen, but it seems to either be really serious, or really wacky.
Scott: And this is way in between, it's got serious and silly, but not wacky silly, just normal silly.
Scott: And it's awesome, super awesome.
Rym: - Get this movie, watch it.
Scott: - Any way you can, if we find a link to somewhere, we should find a link to somewhere you can buy it, and put it in our little thingy.
Rym: - We probably will do that, maybe not right away tonight, but at some point.
Scott: - Yeah, so go to frontrowcrew.com, either in the forum, you know what, yeah, in the forums, there will be probably a thread about the episode, and if we find a link to where you can buy it, we'll put all the different links up in there.
Rym: - Yep.
Scott: - So go to the forums.
Rym: - And in fact, go to the forums anyway, 'cause the forums have recently exploded more so than ever.
Scott: - Yeah, there's a lot of people talking about a lot of stuff in there.
Scott: now, it's like there's way more action going on than before.
Rym: - Yeah, the forums are to the point where I can't even keep up with them anymore, and I admin them.
Scott: - Yeah, so frontrowcrew.com, people.
Rym: - This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: - Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com, where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: - We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week, covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: - You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontrowcrew.com, or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an Odeo on the right side of our website.
Rym: - If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Scott: - GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.