Rym: It's Tuesday January 9th.
Scott: I'm Rym and I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we preview Castlevania portrait of ruin for the DS and excite truck for the Nintendo Wii.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: And yet again our semi-annual holiday Steve jobs of us is behind us.
Rym: I don't know what it is with these Mac people.
Rym: I mean, I understand that Apple makes cool things and I understand I mean we camped out for like four hours for a chance of touching Miyamoto once But we didn't camp out overnight and at least we were gonna get something.
Rym: The people camping out overnight to see Steve Jobs didn't get anything.
Scott: They got the same thing you could get by going to a website for free and now there's so many websites Mirroring this thing that it is no like delay or lag or 404s or anything.
Rym: God, not only were people aiming me all of the updates in real time But someone was posting him in our forums.
Rym: I was on a website and Scott and I were talking about this.
Scott: Yeah, I was like, dude, why are you posting this in the forums?
Scott: Everyone can read and gadget just like you can.
Scott: do We really need to mirror this thing anymore?
Rym: Yes, because obviously people Google for it.
Rym: They'll get us.
Scott: Hi guys But we'll talk more in detail about the iPhone and the ITV Next week after the dust has settled.
Scott: Yeah, you know on Monday Tech day, but just let it be known that we are not the biggest fans of these Incredibly hyped up events and keynotes and things see part of it.
Rym: I would blame on the fact that we're kind of up.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: What's the word cynical?
Rym: Maybe a little bit world-weary a little bit pessimistic sometimes Accurately, so yeah something like that.
Rym: Yeah, I mean we had the chance and actually we failed We've talked about this before to get signed things from Miyamoto when he was at the Nintendo Store because we being rational logical adults concluded that Rather than camping out on the streets of New York City in Rockefeller Center all night No one would be that fanatical.
Rym: and if we just took an early train into the city we could easily get one of the 200 spots.
Rym: and Well taking that early train proved that there are a lot of people far more dedicated to far more trivial things than us in the world.
Scott: Then people be crazy.
Rym: Yeah, I don't get it.
Rym: I don't get it at all, but I remember even last year at IBM I was sitting there watching some IRC channel where the updates were coming through and simultaneously my cube mate cool Korean guy is Sitting there with his back to me and every time a chat came in on my thing He'd go like whoa whoa, and then I look and he's looking at the exact same IRC channel.
Scott: Yeah Why are people just so excited if you CES is going on right now.
Scott: at CES There are more new and amazing products.
Scott: I mean did know did you hear about the Windows Home Server?
Rym: Actually, I did because I redid it's pretty cool.
Scott: I River came out with a whole bunch of stuff.
Scott: Samsung came out The whole bunch of stuff I heard.
Scott: there was a hundred and something inch LCD screen.
Scott: That's what I heard and there probably is.
Scott: it's only a prototype though, but why does you know that?
Scott: iPhone pretty cool?
Scott: ITV not as cool But people makes like a big deal out of two things as they make out of the entire rest of the consumer electronics industry.
Rym: well remember Normal people don't even know any of this happened.
Scott: Nope normal people They don't even realize that there are new electronics products being entered into the world as we speak I mean Walt.
Rym: while the the internet was going crazy most people were just going about their business.
Scott: All right, so it's game day.
Scott: forget is forget those technologies.
Scott: Yeah, we'll talk about them another day No a week from yesterday.
Scott: give or take Give or take a few hours.
Rym: Yeah, I definitely give or take a few hours.
Rym: We've been kind of erratic and putting up the show lately.
Scott: All right, so my news.
Scott: I'll do my news first.
Rym: I can do yours first.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So second life.
Scott: We know I've never played it.
Scott: You played it.
Rym: You see I already have what's called a first life.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah Well, I haven't played it and I didn't news on it before.
Scott: remember about the giant penis attack?
Scott: Yeah, that was quite.
Rym: I did that for humorous reasons But now there's an actual you kidding that was one of the greatest moments in the history of the Internet.
Scott: perhaps it could be in the top 50 but this news about second life is actually pretty serious and pretty awesome.
Scott: as You know second life is an MMO, but not really so much the RPG just the MMO part.
Scott: It's massive multiplayer online Walking around doing stuff.
Rym: It's more like a. I guess a moo is what I would call a second life.
Scott: who knows whatever Acronym you want to use to describe a second life.
Scott: I could care less, but they're all very specific.
Rym: I mean, you know mush muck mud moo All the other ones that don't actually mean anything and it's object oriented to a degree.
Rym: so I would call it a moo.
Scott: perhaps anyway Second life has decided to open source itself now.
Scott: at first that seems crazy Because well they make money with second life.
Scott: if people could just get the code to second life They can run their own servers run their own clients and never pay any money to Linden Labs.
Rym: Yep, they won't need to buy any Linden dollars.
Scott: I guess that's true that oh well Some people are gonna play second life on some other servers and not pay Linden Labs any money and I guess that's just fine.
Scott: However, I don't think that's going to hurt them in the long run because well How many people are you gonna get to play on your pirated?
Scott: Well, not pirated but completely legal Second life server probably not as many as on the second life server.
Scott: So people who want to play in an environment with other people They're probably gonna need to spend some money to get some Linden dollars to do stuff and I don't think their revenues will be affected.
Scott: In fact, I think their revenues are going to be affected positively Because of the second thing it says in this press release now.
Scott: Most games you play even online games like counter-strike.
Scott: They don't charge you a monthly fee.
Scott: You buy the game and you're done and they make their money from selling you the game MMOs like World of Warcraft.
Scott: they sell you the game and then they make you pay a monthly fee.
Scott: The reason they make you pay the monthly fee is because in order for this game to work They have to have a giant server farm somewhere and that giant server farm is expensive as all hell.
Rym: Well, also they make more money that way because their business model is not give you a great game that when you're done with you Quit but give you a game that will string you along enough to where you'll play for the rest of your life.
Scott: Yes, and of course, you know Even if they just charged like a hundred dollars for the game and then they stop charging you They would still fail to profit because the server farm cost so much.
Scott: now.
Scott: It has often been thought by many smart people including myself that hey if you could somehow have the MMO But not need to manage this giant server farm You could save a lot of money and actually becoming like ludicrously profitable.
Scott: That's like a jillion dollar idea if you can make it work.
Scott: Well, the idea itself is not a jillion dollars.
Scott: Anyone could come up with.
Scott: the idea is how do you make it work?
Scott: Is what's worth a jillion?
Rym: Yeah, and if you don't I mean the idea isn't just oh.
Rym: now the hostings for free.
Rym: We get more money.
Rym: consider that also say you still spent the same amount of money you were normally spending on your hosting and your bandwidth on content.
Rym: You'd have the baddest as MMO ever and I can guarantee both of us would play it and there wouldn't be any more GeekNights And you could also get more people to join because you had so much new content, etc, etc, etc.
Scott: so having an MMO without needing a server farm or needing less of a server farm is Insanely profitable if someone were capable of doing it.
Scott: Well open sourcing second life is a step on the road to achieving this goal.
Scott: Apparently they're developing something called the second life grid, which is a vision.
Scott: they have a vision.
Scott: their vision is that people because they have the code to second life will run their own servers and All these servers will somehow connect to form the bigger world that is second life, you know.
Scott: So I might run my little area and even if my server is a little different than someone else's server You know.
Scott: if it works with the second life client people can get to it.
Scott: and you know, the rules might be different.
Scott: There might be flying people or something, you know, cuz I changed the code but still works.
Scott: It's still second life.
Scott: I mean, what's the worst someone could do with the second life code?
Scott: I guess if they really want to do they could go and make a different MMO and charge people to play it.
Scott: But you can't really do anything to hurt Linden Labs the makers of second life with the second life source code unless you find some security holes and
Rym: yeah some sort of way to I don't know launder Linden dollars or make things for free and then sell them to people.
Scott: Because of the GPL 2.0 If you found such things you would be legally obligated to release your source code and how you did it so they could fix it.
Rym: Well, no If you didn't if you chose not to distribute or allow access to your server to other people you wouldn't be obligated to share.
Scott: But let's say you modified your client to get free Linden dollars on the official servers.
Scott: You know you you just you modified the code of your client And if they caught you doing that not only could they get you for cheating you get rid of your account and such and such But if they really wanted to they could take you to court for breaking the GPL which doesn't happen too often.
Rym: But there might be ways around that there might be.
Rym: but I'm just especially since you're not just if you don't try to distribute it Or so yes, I'm just saying on paper.
Scott: They could.
Scott: Anyway, this is way cool because it's totally messes with your mind that hey someone's got a product.
Scott: They release the product.
Scott: you know it's.
Scott: it's free to play second life unless you want to do something.
Scott: that requires Linden dollars.
Scott: But they made it even more free and as a result They're gonna make more money because now they have all these people helping them to build this second life grid and also fix security Holes and second line it.
Rym: We'll see what actually happens.
Scott: We will see what actually happens.
Scott: But I imagine that second life will become more awesome because there has been some criticism of second life recently in their Reporting of the number of citizens.
Scott: You know it's like they're like.
Rym: oh because no other MMO totally blatantly lies about How many people are in their game?
Scott: I know, but people are ragging on second life about it recently and not ragging other MMOs about it.
Rym: Well the thing is it's funny how the way MMOs go since I'd say maybe not the majority But a very substantial number of people who play MMOs are not otherwise gamers or at least they don't play a lot of other games And they tend to look at things like how popular their MMO is and if the MMO isn't so popular They might not want to play it anymore.
Rym: They want to be on whatever's hot right now.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Scott: I think it's just.
Scott: I think what it's more like is people are already playing MMOs.
Scott: They like the MMO that they're playing that they're used to.
Scott: you know when whenever people change MMOs they tend to not like it and they tend to want that new MMO to change to be what their old MMO.
Rym: Well I remember in the early days you know back when there was a bunch of competing MMOs that were all doing kinda Well relative to each other.
Rym: it wasn't like today where there's the powerhouse world of warcraft And then effectively nothing else.
Rym: they would either guard their numbers to the bitter end kind of like the anime industry Or they release the numbers only when they were good or the numbers would suddenly start disappearing if they started falling.
Scott: I think the way where the numbers matter is not to existing MMO players But to new MMO players.
Scott: because you're coming into MMOs you're right like huh, which MMO should I play?
Scott: the one that has a Thousand people you know do I want to go?
Scott: and you know play in a world with a thousand other people or play in a World with a million other people?
Scott: You know and the million other people tends to get the win.
Scott: Does that?
Scott: because that's what MMOs are about.
Scott: is people wanting to go and hang out with lots of other people?
Scott: and I think also You know open sourcing Second Life will just bring a lot of people who want to play with the code.
Scott: I mean a lot of people probably had no interest in Second Life.
Scott: now that it's open source They'll probably go ooh.
Scott: Let me look at that source and see what's going on in there.
Rym: I mean I'll even admit Second Life is probably the closest thing to the world in Snow Crash that we've yet seen perhaps and That's really cool to me.
Rym: What wasn't cool to me was paying money for it.
Scott: Yeah, you don't have to pay money for it unless you want to buy anything that requires Linden dollars.
Rym: Yeah, you could just walk around without paying money, which wasn't exactly what I was interested in.
Scott: No, if you don't pay money, it's just a big chat room.
Scott: you walk around and talk to people kind of like most MMOs.
Scott: exactly IRC is free people.
Scott: No need to use Second Life.
Rym: Well, no no no you got to perfectly emulate the MMO experience.
Rym: you have IRC open But you also have to have a bot that's constantly making up names and asking for Gil and shit.
Rym: Ah, and then on top of that you need spam sex whisper bots constantly harassing you And of course last and certainly not least you got to get a copy of progress Progress Quest and keep it open in the background at all times.
Scott: I already do that.
Scott: Let's see what level I am in progress.
Rym: Are you really still running that?
Scott: I'm really still running progress crest.
Scott: I am currently level 76.
Scott: I am a level 76 enchanted motorcycle or paladin.
Scott: Can you guess what my highest stat is?
Rym: I don't know charisma or strength.
Scott: No, my con is 16,457. not bad not bad at all.
Scott: I am an act XL VI.
Scott: Yeah, I think I'm not gonna read off any more of this because it's just stupid.
Rym: No, there's an awesome raid coming up.
Scott: Yeah, well don't make me cast level LV curse family on you.
Rym: what number do you think LV is Scott?
Scott: Oh Let's see.
Rym: You don't know do you X?
Scott: I think L's.
Scott: L's a thousand, right?
Rym: What's M then?
Scott: all right M's a thousand.
Scott: so L 500. no no 100.
Scott: I thought C was a hundred.
Rym: Uh, yeah C is a hundred.
Scott: What could L be 50?
Scott: Yeah, L is 50 All right, so I got a little 55 curse family.
Scott: Why is it?
Scott: I hate freaking roman numerals when they go on the 50s.
Scott: That's always annoying.
Rym: Anyway, well, they go on the fives, too.
Scott: Yeah Right.
Rym: So my news is kind of a. it seems like on a semi-regular basis websites for various reasons.
Rym: We'll decide that they need some publicity.
Rym: in order to get some publicity They'll do some sort of top 10 list.
Scott: Here's
Rym: our list of the top 10 games ever
Scott: and
Rym: they almost always will have a generic list that tends to list very popular current things or things that are in the consciousness of the Internet
Rym: Almost always the number one or the number two thing will be something controversial even outright wrong Because even though the list may be crap It talks about things that people are interested in so people all link to it and dig it up and have a grand old time.
Scott: It's funny cuz on dig I see like three different kinds of stories.
Scott: like about about 15% of the stories I see on dig fall into three categories.
Scott: There's here's my lit top 10 list of something how to something right or something tutorial and How to make a how-to list or tutorial that will get on dig.
Rym: Well, a lot of people seem to be following that advice Because right here is a fairly piss-poor list from computer and video games com About the worst game endings ever.
Rym: now when I heard this the first games I thought of were I don't know Simon's Quest pretty bad one.
Scott: every Atari game ever Mmm-hmm half of the Nintendo games ever karate kid pretty much any game where the ending was either Nothing, just you know, I mean freaking Dig Dug is the worst ending game over.
Scott: Well, that's not the end That's the end.
Rym: No, that's just when you lose if you beat the game.
Rym: Well, I guess you can't beat the game because an infinite number infinite replay.
Scott: Yeah I mean, what's the ending of pac-man?
Scott: the game crashes.
Scott: the end?
Scott: Yeah, it's like that's the worst.
Scott: every the game just crashes.
Rym: I know kaboom at a pretty good end.
Rym: if you get to a high enough score The bomber makes a face at you and the game continues.
Scott: that is better the ending than pac-man.
Scott: That's because the bomber makes a visit.
Rym: So this follows pretty much these straight-up formula.
Rym: I'm not gonna read the whole this but like number 10 fable, which I never even played A perfect dark perfect dark.
Scott: the ending wasn't good, but the game had an ending which is more than pac-man Which it just crashes.
Rym: Yeah, I mean they're talking about the worst endings ever.
Rym: All right Metal Gear Solid 2.
Scott: I'll give them that Metal Gear Solid 2 was fucked up and bad But you know what?
Scott: It's still not as bad as all those Atari games that had no ending at all.
Rym: Also Metal Gear Solid 2 is ending.
Rym: while it might have been bad from a semi-objective, you know observer standpoint.
Rym: Yeah, the plot just crazy screwed in terms of watching it or the internet humor about it.
Rym: It's a great ending any ending.
Scott: No game has the worst ending.
Scott: what World of Warcraft?
Rym: What is the ending of World of Warcraft?
Rym: because I thought of like four jokes and I couldn't think of a good way to make All of them.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'll just leave it at that.
Scott: No, you know what other game is a really bad ending daikumud.
Scott: Daikumud is a really bad ending ever.
Scott: quest also It's got.
Rym: the bad ending of daikumud is a divorce and a bitter lonely life.
Scott: Oh You know a game also second life as the worst ending ever.
Scott: also now because you can make money off a second I would say that the ending to pac-man is a lot worse than the ending to World of Warcraft.
Scott: I mean being better because at least in pac-man it's like aha.
Scott: Look at that.
Scott: I crashed the machine.
Scott: only three other people have done that ever.
Rym: but World of Warcraft has crashed on people before.
Scott: Yeah, but not because you were awesome Or maybe you were so awesome.
Scott: pac-man only crashes when you're awesome and you roll the score over All right.
Rym: So the end of World of Warcraft I imagine looks exactly like the end of the South Park episode about World of Warcraft.
Scott: It is a bad ending All right, but yeah, I mean those.
Rym: these endings aren't bad bad.
Rym: They're just.
Rym: they're funny bad.
Rym: or they're Controversy bad or they're bad.
Rym: to make this article popular.
Rym: But the issue I take is that the number one game the game that they say has the worst ending of any game ever is Super Mario Brothers.
Rym: They you know, thank you Mario.
Rym: Your quest is over.
Rym: We present you a new quest push button B to select a world.
Scott: That is not bad because number one you get to see the princess who you haven't seen yet ever ever - you feel really good.
Rym: Yeah, I mean back then it's I mean today.
Rym: people complain about the end of a game if it isn't basically a four-hour perfect movie File that comes right after an insanely difficult but not impossible awesome square boss fight.
Rym: Yeah back then beating a game was enough.
Rym: if you beat a game it was.
Rym: I mean now It's.
Rym: there's not the foregone conclusion.
Rym: If if I buy a game, I'm gonna beat it.
Rym: It was I beat it.
Rym: Holy shit No one I knew beat it.
Rym: I'm the only one.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, think about this Zelda one right ending.
Scott: You walk into a room and then you stab some fire, right?
Scott: so wait first see the whole thing about beating a game in those days was that it was so hard to do and So crazy and so rarely done.
Scott: at least, you know in the minds of the kids playing who were the only people playing?
Scott: Well, not the only but most of the people playing were kids that you saw at the end of a game There would be like two rooms with stuff that wasn't seen anywhere else.
Scott: It was completely new.
Scott: So it was like holy shit.
Scott: Look at that Ganon dude.
Scott: It's frickin green pig and he disappeared.
Rym: Holy shit What do I do?
Scott: What do I do?
Scott: and then you kill him and you're like what the fuck is that red triangle?
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: There's a red triangle.
Scott: It's the Triforce And then you a door would open and you'd go in and you would see Zelda.
Scott: you had never seen Never.
Scott: you didn't know what she looked like and there she was and there was fire there in a room You had never seen before and you could stab the fire and it would go away.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: Also, Zelda was wearing a dress the same color as whatever you were wearing.
Scott: if you had the green suit her dress is green But if you had the blue ring her dress is white.
Scott: if you're the red ring cuz you're awesome.
Scott: her dress is red.
Rym: Well, no have beating the game with a red wing red ring Makes you the opposite of awesome because you weren't manly enough to just skip all that and beat the game taking four damage from basic monsters.
Scott: no because Because I was a little kid and I said I have to get every goddamn item in this game.
Scott: I am NOT leaving until I get that red ring that I know is in this dungeon somewhere.
Scott: Anyway, and then you stand next to Zelda and you both hold up Triforces and then text goes by that says stuff that you never read before Final
Rym: Fantasy one I remember when I finally beat that game and that was after years and fucking years and starting over and getting lost.
Rym: and oh my God, all the ending is.
Rym: is you know, there's blue text boxes that pop up whenever you talk to people Like four of those full of text.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: That's the game.
Rym: That's the end and I was amazed by that.
Scott: Yeah Beating games was all.
Scott: it was like Unlocking the final chapter of a book.
Scott: imagine if you were reading a book or watching a movie and the very end of it was locked away and you couldn't access it and After a long and difficult trial, you know that tested your skills and abilities and efforts it unlocked.
Rym: Yeah, and not even that.
Rym: imagine if it was like that, but most people never even unlocked it.
Scott: Yeah, it didn't matter What was in there as long as it wasn't nothing.
Scott: it was awesome because you got it.
Scott: There it is.
Scott: It's like opening a treasure chest and you found some amount of treasure.
Scott: You're happy wasn't.
Rym: until the Super Nintendo days were like Final Fantasy 4 and those games started having these long endings and then people would think of the ending of a game.
Rym: the longer it was the better and I remember people on the internet going Nuts about the fact that Final Fantasy 6 aka Final Fantasy 3 had like a half-hour sequence at the end.
Scott: It's like people want like this such a great reward for their meager effort of beating the game.
Scott: The game itself is the reward.
Scott: Hello, if the game itself isn't the reward all you want is the ending.
Scott: just go watch the ending on YouTube.
Scott: remember though That wasn't an option when we were I know but I'm just saying if all I want is the ending go watch it on YouTube.
Scott: The point is the game itself.
Rym: Yeah, but this list is crap.
Rym: and Mario Super Mario Brothers not only for the day But I'd say of all video games ever.
Rym: if you average the ending of every video game ever Especially if you wait that graph based on the difficulty of getting said ending Super Mario Brothers has one of the best endings ever.
Scott: Yeah, especially since that after you beat it you start the game again, but there are beetles instead of goombas.
Scott: Yeah Oh shit, I mean, you know Playing it now you go up beetles instead of goombas, but as a kid, oh my god The game is beetles instead of goombas.
Scott: Whoa Crazy.
Rym: I better pause it and invite all my friends over God, I remember how many times would I when I'm about to kill the final boss I'd pause the game and call my friends Billy.
Rym: I'm gonna be Zelda two bitches.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: I Couldn't even beat Zelda one without like the support of friends in the room.
Rym: God you would all every.
Scott: I was like the third try on Gannon and there were some people over my house or a barbecue And like my brother and some friends are sitting there and I finally beat it and we were all like
Rym: oh My god, I remember is always the eternal race between me and my brother who would beat a game first and I Call my brother
Scott: when I beat Mega Man 2 on that like early Saturday morning And I had to beat it before the cartoons came on.
Rym: Yeah, I know that it was like I tried.
Scott: it's like my third or fourth try and I finally got to dr Wylie and I'm like all shits.
Rym: when I was in fourth grade I used to go home for lunch because just because I went to a Catholic school and for various reasons I lived right next to I could just go home for lunch.
Rym: Remember one day I went home from lunch and I was playing Final Fantasy 4 Which I thinking about how long ago that was.
Rym: that makes me feel really freaking old.
Rym: But I had to beat that antlion and get to a safe spot before my dad drove me back to school With an an argument ensued where my dad's like you got to go back to school and I'm saying no But then I'll have to do this all over again.
Rym: That's a fate worse than death and my dad turns the SNES off and drives me back to school.
Rym: That's right I was.
Rym: that was one of the worst things that ever happened to me.
Scott: You live a bad sad life Dad.
Scott: I could tell which thing today you're doing.
Rym: Ah, yes, you can.
Scott: indeed then what's the name of that song?
Rym: That'll be puckle bells cannon indeed.
Rym: You might recognize it from such hits as every goddamn song in the world.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Everyone's heard this song.
Rym: Everyone knows this.
Scott: I think you might not know that you've heard this song, but you have heard this song.
Rym: So, uh, there's this comedian, you know, he's one of those guitar comedians kind of like how Dana Carvey used to do that.
Scott: It's like some hip college guy or something.
Rym: Yeah so he gets up there and he's doing you know stand-up comedy with the guitar.
Rym: and This is a clip of probably the end of his long bit because this is definitely kind of a.
Scott: it's most definitely the finale because he Says as much yeah, but I mean this is the home run here.
Rym: This is his best bit and basically, he just bitches about Pachelbel and Pachelbel's cannon.
Rym: indeed and I don't want to ruin anything, but I'll see you in hell Pachelbel.
Rym: What more can I say?
Rym: the song is Ubiquitous and the stand-up humor is hilarious.
Scott: Yeah, the feeling I get from the guy is that he's probably not my favorite comedian in the world But this bit is a funny bit, especially if you understand music a little bit.
Scott: Yeah Somebody's going All right.
Scott: I don't want to talk anymore about the iPhone today But in the course of my looking at websites about the iPhone which lasted about 30 minutes today I discovered a new website that someone was using to compare the size of the iPhone To the size of other things such as the iPod the Zune the Nano cell phones decks of cards
Rym: Scott's penis
Scott: my penis.
Scott: The site is called size easy S I ZE ASY.
Scott: they took out one of the ease.
Scott: so it's not size easy.
Scott: It's just size easy.
Rym: I see what you did then I do.
Scott: I see what they did there.
Scott: it's a very nicely designed web 2.0 ish site and it lets you enter in the dimensions of a three-dimensional rectangular Object, you know something a rectangle with a depth and then it allows you to compare that rectangle with the depth to other rectangles with depths that you specify and Standard everyday Objects such as decks of cards boxes of matches credit cards wine bottles CD cases monitors Doors paper etc.
Scott: Now.
Scott: Why is this useful?
Scott: Well, because we do a lot of online shopping these days and when you're online shopping Something you'll often see and like sites like Newegg or Amazon and such is you know what are the dimensions of this object?
Scott: and it'll say 10 inches by 12 by 2 and It is not always perfectly easy.
Scott: unless you have a ruler and some paper near you, you know to picture in your mind Exactly how big that is, you know, is it gonna fit on my shelf?
Scott: You got to get out a ruler, you know, is it gonna fit in my pocket nicely?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Unless you have it in your hand You don't really grasp the size of it and pictures are always deceiving.
Scott: You know you look at a picture of the Motorola Q online and then you see it in the store and you go Holy shit, that's thin online.
Scott: It didn't look so thin.
Scott: Holy crap.
Scott: So, you know, I was bit by this once I bought the Logitech Z 5500 5.1 surround sound system for my computer, which I highly recommend.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It's a very good speaker system Scott However, the best sound system in the house, but the subwoofer.
Scott: the subwoofer is ginormous.
Rym: It's bigger than two of our friends.
Scott: It is bigger than two of our friends.
Scott: This thing can double as an ottoman or footrest of an ottoman is a footrest.
Rym: You know for a second maybe just because I was reading of course more Byzantine history and Ottomans, I pictured an ottoman just kind of bent over.
Scott: if you took the speaker out of it, you could perhaps use it as a Christmas tree stand, but it is very large.
Scott: and You know, I didn't understand how large it was because I bought it online and I was just looking at a picture You know engaging with my mind the size of it.
Scott: if I had actually had access to size easy.com when I bought this thing I probably would have realized the subwoofer was too large and bought perhaps the next system down Smaller subwoofer because as it is I have turned the base way down and if I turn it up I can make the old lady downstairs believe there is an earthquake.
Rym: All right, it's easily four times the size of my subwoofer.
Scott: easily It's.
Scott: it's four times the size of my previous subwoofer, which is the correct size.
Rym: So to hit back on the I guess classic format of our gaming days.
Rym: We're just gonna talk about two games.
Rym: We've been playing.
Scott: Yeah, because we got a new board game.
Scott: We're gonna talk about next week.
Rym: Yeah, we picked up a copy of battle.
Scott: Oh, don't say oh, well, well, you know, I wanted to be surprised.
Rym: Oh, well, they don't want to surprise people.
Rym: We want people to go who they're gonna talk about that game.
Rym: All right All right battle or is a great game.
Scott: Yeah next week We're gonna talk all about battle or which we just got and we have played one time.
Scott: But we're gonna play it right after we're done with this show.
Scott: Yes for the second time.
Rym: Let's hurry the fuck along then All right.
Rym: So today I'm going to talk about excite truck and I'm going to still talk about Castlevania portrait of ruin for the DS.
Scott: who wants to go first into rock-paper-scissors?
Rym: All right, rock, huh?
Scott: Hey, we got both scissors.
Rym: Huh?
Scott: I win.
Scott: Okay, that means you go first.
Scott: what?
Rym: Alright fine.
Rym: So I I reviewed a long time ago Castlevania dawn of sorrow for the DS which I contend is probably the best of the Metroidvania games.
Rym: I might get some flack from the people who like Symphony of the Night, but I'm sorry This is just a fantastic freaking game and the fact that it's portable and that I can just stop playing and save at any moment Was just perfect.
Rym: Portrait of ruin is not as good as Castlevania DS right now.
Rym: It is not that good Compared to that game.
Rym: However, it's right there under it.
Rym: It's still a great game on you.
Scott: You didn't really play the GBA once did you?
Rym: I have played them But I've never owned them or played them for more than a few minutes.
Scott: The thing is they've got this Cartridge that has the first two GBA ones on it and they didn't include the third one.
Scott: So it's like if you can get all three of them on two cartridges, but not on one.
Scott: It's sort of annoying.
Rym: Well if you like I mean I'd recommend everyone who has a DS to get.
Scott: if you like the Symphony of the Night GBA style Castlevania games you should pretty much just buy them all because none of them are that much worse or better than any of the others.
Rym: though if you haven't played many of these games or if your idea of Castlevania is a game that has a Belmont in it Then I'd suggest you get Castlevania DS and try it if you like it.
Rym: get portrait of ruin.
Rym: If you like both of them and you want more Go get all the GBA ones and Symphony of the Night and all that because they're still all really really good games.
Rym: I'm not knocking them don't even consider the possibility.
Scott: You know, it's like.
Scott: it's just more of the same though.
Scott: Don't expect, you know, something revolutionary and new and better.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like if you like Final Fantasy 4 play Final Fantasy 6. it's more the same mostly.
Rym: so portrait of ruin is Like all these games.
Rym: it has kind of a gimmick and unlike Castlevania DS where the gimmick was you draw these seals on the screen to seal in the bosses.
Scott: Oh good, because I hated drawing those seals.
Scott: That was annoying.
Rym: I kind of liked it.
Rym: Actually.
Scott: I thought it kind of like I was trying to whip the boss and then all of a sudden I had to pull the stylus out.
Scott: draw on the screen.
Rym: Well one I didn't pull the stylus off I just used my finger.
Scott: I eventually use my finger But I don't.
Scott: I don't like using the finger.
Rym: see to me.
Rym: To me.
Rym: it added this element of like I'm fighting I'm fighting and suddenly this thing comes up and now it's panic mode Because I've already wasted two seconds going.
Rym: What's this all right, and then I try to draw it before the boss comes back and fighting some of the later bosses.
Rym: I'd have to redraw that thing like seven times.
Scott: I never had to do it that much you suck.
Rym: Anyway portrait of ruin the gimmick.
Rym: They don't use the stylus really at all.
Rym: They removed all that from the game Which is probably good because a lot of the DS uses of the stylus were kind of gimmicky.
Rym: It still uses the two screens the same way, but the new gimmick is that you control not one person, but two people.
Scott: Oh, I hate that because then one person always ends up doing something You don't want to do see.
Rym: now you might think that because every game I've ever played where you control two people was either Move one guy switch to the other one move that one switch back and it becomes annoying.
Rym: hellish game like that Vikings game for The SNES.
Scott: well there are some games that do it.
Scott: Okay, like double dash where you know they draw two characters on the screen But really you're controlling one like using the ice climbers and smash brothers.
Rym: not so annoying Yeah, but games like that Viking puzzle game for the SNES yes, or the caveman puzzle game for the turbo graphics Yeah, yeah.
Rym: But the way this game does it is number.
Rym: in Castlevania DS You could hit X to switch between your two loadouts, which was great.
Scott: That was really good.
Rym: Yeah, like that's.
Rym: that's what made that game for me Honestly mm-hmm because I love tweaking inventories and that let me double tweak my inventory and the inventories are easy to tweak and not Complicated or annoying.
Rym: this game doesn't throw away any of that stuff plenty of weapons in fact.
Rym: It uses the inventory even better in that.
Rym: now It's not like that the other game where you just use the biggest heaviest weapon all the time.
Rym: Skeletons say are weak against crushing weapons But they're strong against swords and trees are weak against axes but strong against maces and you got to keep switching off weapons depending on what you're fighting and Unlike the other you know DS where it didn't really matter.
Rym: just use the strongest weapon you can reasonably deal with.
Rym: You got to change weapons and really think about what situation you're in and what weapon would best deal with.
Scott: Was it easy to change them?
Scott: or do you have to go to the menu come out?
Rym: well to change weapons?
Rym: You've got to go to the menu and come out But you don't really have to change weapons much.
Rym: within a screen or within one fight.
Rym: all right like for an area You'll figure out all right.
Rym: I should really be using a halberd for this part, okay, okay?
Rym: But in stating X instead of switching an inventory switches between the two characters.
Rym: Forget the names.
Rym: whatever the plots of Castlevania games are pretty much.
Rym: Just stupid at this point.
Scott: beat Dracula, please.
Rym: no It's never even Dracula.
Rym: It's always beat this other guy And Dracula's around.
Rym: so if there's some funny bits in this game where?
Rym: Death who apparently in the Castlevania universe now is good friends with Dracula.
Rym: You're in Dracula's castle to fight this Bronner guy who's taking it over and death appears, and you're like crap.
Rym: We got to kill death and death is like hey What are you doing here, and you tell him then he's like wait what I better go.
Rym: look into this.
Rym: I don't like anyone other than Dracula being in my castle.
Rym: Yeah But hitting X which is between the two characters and the one character is the same Effective guy from DS.
Rym: run around pick weapons.
Rym: look cool.
Rym: the other characters this girl It was a magician and her set of weapons is totally different.
Rym: you get books And the first book you get is an encyclopedia and you hit people with it straight up.
Rym: Okay, but the later books like now I got Don Quixote and when you open it a knight charges out at a windmill it does fire damage.
Rym: That's okay, and all the books are just kind of cool and neat.
Rym: and in addition She instead of stealing soul whatever's from enemies and casting them She collects spells or you can just buy spells and she straight-up cast spells.
Scott: You can add the spells useful.
Scott: Yes, okay?
Rym: You can also hit a to bring your ally down.
Rym: now They're both on the screen.
Rym: your ally will follow you in a very rational Realistic non annoying way.
Rym: if it gets stuck it just teleports to where you are immediately.
Rym: So there's no dealing with that, and it just generally fights.
Rym: if it takes damage You don't take hit point damage you take magic point damage.
Rym: So even if the game fucks you and it gets stuck on a monster for a minute It's not just gonna kill you just lose your magic.
Scott: How do you get magic back?
Rym: same as every Castlevania game tonics waiting or hearts all right waiting okay?
Scott: You just kill all the bad guys and stand there for a while.
Rym: Now there's also a lot of stuff like.
Rym: the puzzles will often involve using both people and you can go stand somewhere summon your ally But hold down an a at the same time.
Rym: They'll stay there, and then you can go off and do business and then switch back to them.
Rym: Or if they're both on the screen at the same time and you want to switch You just trade places with them.
Rym: you just suddenly you're controlling the other guy who might have been halfway across the screen.
Rym: Not gonna go into too much detail about it But suffice to say the mechanism of doing that works about as well as you could expect which is far better than I had hoped hmm.
Rym: and also the other.
Rym: I mean they removed a lot of the Killing monsters farming them to get their souls up.
Scott: Thank God That was.
Scott: the only bad part of that Castlevania DS is you had to get all these souls and like you'd want a particular soul from a monster But you didn't get a soul every time he killed it.
Scott: So you'd end up like leaving a screen coming back killing the monster.
Scott: I remember there's this one monster had a really good soul that let me throw Axes and I just kept leaving the screen coming back killing it leaving the screen coming back killing it for like 30 minutes until I Had full maximum level on that soul.
Rym: see there is still some of that.
Rym: I mean you can level them up But it's not as annoying.
Rym: and also you really care because the main thing is you don't have to do that to upgrade weapons.
Rym: Instead you just get better weapons.
Scott: Where do you get them?
Rym: You can find them you can buy them or there's an interesting thing they added where you can talk to the guy who's the voice from Soul Calibur 2.
Scott: and Wait, which voice from Soul Calibur 2?
Rym: The narrator.
Rym: Oh, okay, and he'll give you quests which range from collect these three items to do a Hadoken for me Right now to almost die and he'll give you things you can get special weapons from him special items from him.
Rym: You can also learn a lot of techniques from him to where during the game You have all the normal Castlevania crap.
Rym: You can also do Street Fighter 2 style Combo attacks, which really seems to add a lot to the game.
Rym: I'm running through an area fighting guys with swords.
Rym: suddenly There's one skeleton instead of you know going into the menu switch into a mace.
Rym: I just do kind of a double Street Fighter 2 super move and my guy kind of jumps at him and kicks him.
Scott: Hmm, it's really fun.
Scott: I'm still trying to think of something the guy from Soul Calibur 2 said.
Scott: oh He always said things in level started like yeah, like a sacred quest a master key.
Scott: Yeah, random words random words before your battle fight.
Rym: Yeah, well, he says stuff too and he might be a Belmont or something.
Rym: I haven't even read the text.
Rym: I don't even care anymore at this point.
Rym: I run into plot.
Scott: I just want to play to hear the guy's voice.
Scott: now cuz I'm gonna go look and see who that is.
Rym: Yeah, we should.
Rym: we should try to interview him.
Scott: I guess yeah He's a voice actor.
Scott: We know right watch.
Scott: He's like our best friend.
Rym: He probably makes at least a million space dollars a year probably.
Rym: So, I mean the game is pretty much just a standard metroidvania With a bunch of little gimmicks that make it interesting enough to where even if you're tired of all the same old There's just enough new stuff to make this interesting.
Rym: Hmm I haven't beaten it though.
Rym: I must say that it has so far the best boss in any Castlevania game ever.
Scott: Oh really other than better than a completely average vampire bat from Castlevania 1.
Rym: why in fact one of the bosses is a giant and by giant I mean, you can't see it all on the screen at one time.
Rym: ball of Naked dead human bodies.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you showed me that now Not only do they fall out of it and wander around trying to attack you by the hundreds But if you hit it with a mace you shake just hundreds and hundreds of them off of it.
Rym: Yeah, and it's dripping blood and screaming the whole time.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Rym: It's quite fantastic.
Scott: All right, let me tell you about site trick now.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right, so One of the launch games to the Wii was excite truck and people are like, all right.
Scott: All right They're obviously just stealing the name from excite bike and it has nothing to do with excite bike because it's trucks.
Rym: Well surprisingly, I don't think many people made that connection.
Scott: Yeah, that's kind of scary also kind of like the Beatles.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Anyway excite bike does have an connection to excite truck, which I will explain.
Scott: Anyway, you know and they looked at this game and it look, you know before I got it I looked at it and I said, all right, that's obviously just a launch game.
Scott: It's not the greatest game.
Scott: You drive a truck.
Scott: It might be fun, but there's not gonna be too much to it.
Scott: I'll buy it anyway.
Scott: And I did and I must say it's actually one of the better Wii games that I have and I've got like six Wii games Actually, you know what next to Zelda and Wii Sports.
Scott: I think it's you know, one two.
Scott: This is the third best Wii game there is right now.
Scott: Yeah, let me that I have and I have six Wii games.
Rym: It's better than monkey ball.
Scott: Well, anything's better than monkey ball.
Scott: monkey balls ass Alright, it's not perfect though.
Scott: Anyway in excite truck you drive a truck you push two Which is a if you hold it like an NES controller, right and two is go and B. You know a is go B is break, even though it's two and one You tilt the controller left and right to steer and that actually works really well.
Scott: I mean at first you're gonna notice yourself doing it and you're gonna have a little trouble.
Scott: But I mean at this point in the game when I play it, I don't even realize I'm doing it Like yeah, Scott says at first we're talking like 30 seconds and then you forget.
Scott: Yeah It's like I completely forget that when I'm playing this game I'm not steering left and right with my thumb or with a wheel, but I'm actually just tilting this thing back and forth.
Scott: I don't notice it when I play but I do it because I'm really good at excite truck.
Scott: suddenly, you know It's it's really crazy.
Scott: So, you know while a lot of the fun of the Wii is moving the controller, you know in Wii Sports You're very conscious of the fact that you're swinging the wiimote around and excite buck.
Scott: You are tilting the wiimote and using it full-on for all your excite buck excite buck.
Rym: I think you did whatever.
Scott: You're not conscious that you're doing it once you have learned the skill which that I mean one that's definitely the failing of monkey ball.
Rym: You never are not acutely aware of the fact that you're manipulating the strange and foreign controller.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's because monkey ball handles it very poorly.
Rym: But to me because Scott's played excite truck a lot more.
Rym: but I from what I've played the one observation I can make about the game It's really the only thing I can say about it is that the game seems like a typical whatever racing game Until you go airborne.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: See now you can tilt the controller left and right to steer left and right But when you hit a jump you pull back on it to get some more air or you pull forward you push it down forward to.
Scott: you know go down for the ground and A lot of the game is flying.
Scott: a whole lot of the game is flying.
Scott: I mean you saw that excite truck speed excite bike speed run that we put on the other day where the guy just hits the Jumps and flies.
Scott: that's an excite bike was all about was hitting those jumps and jumping over.
Scott: shit.
Scott: Yep, landing at the right angle bouncing properly Yeah was leaning forward and backward hitting the ramps at the right speed and getting huge distance off of them.
Rym: excite truck Same thing but it does it so well.
Scott: Oh, man Like the execution of the jumping in this game is so perfect.
Scott: when you get big air Like the music will fade out because this game has some pretty average, you know But not painful rock music going on and engine noises.
Scott: when you get big air like the music volume will go down and the game will kind of slow down and Your car will be way up in the air and the camera is always in just the right position.
Scott: It's like they didn't try to do too much with this game But what they did?
Scott: they perfected absolutely.
Scott: the camera is perfect the controls are dead on.
Scott: the music isn't annoying the tracks while there's only like Six or seven different environments, you know, all the tracks are very interesting and some of them are you know?
Scott: difficult and fun to do.
Scott: The thing is that's bad with this.
Scott: game is well for oh, I forgot something boosting.
Scott: Remember if you ever played excite bike.
Scott: you push a to go But no you push B to go and to normally and a to boost right to go better.
Rym: What was it the other way around?
Scott: I don't remember either an excite bike.
Scott: the original one button was just go.
Scott: the other button was go faster But when you went faster you started to.
Scott: you know your bike started to heat up and if it reached a certain point you would pull over to the side of the road because you were overheated and You would have to push a a whole bunch of times in order to get back on your bike Or you'd have to wait for it to cool off and then you could go again, you know.
Scott: So you didn't want.
Scott: you wanted to boost but you couldn't do it too much.
Scott: you overheat same thing and excite truck.
Scott: You have a boost meter you push the arrows which you're not using them for steering so you push them to boost which you're pretty much gonna boost as much as you want and This water that you can drive into to instantly cool off.
Scott: So if you're on a track with a lot of water, you're gonna be boosting a hell of a lot.
Scott: You can also boost at the like eight just like the beginning of jumps with perfect timing to get these turbo jumps.
Scott: And that's how you're gonna go fast and get big air, you know.
Scott: And if you land nicely you get like it'll say nice landing and you get a free boost that doesn't heat you up And
Rym: you'll be amazed when you start jumping around just the feeling you get from being airborne
Scott: Especially when you unlock some of the cars that have a law a very high air statistic.
Scott: I mean the cars have four stats and They don't matter so much except for the feel of the car.
Scott: None of them are really unbalanced until you get really good at the game.
Scott: Then you unlock the second set of cars that are the better cars, but all those are equal as well.
Scott: But the cars that have big air have big air.
Scott: I you can fly like over large portions of the track if you hit jumps in the right way.
Scott: So yeah, it has the same boosting mechanic as excite bike.
Scott: it has the same jumping mechanic.
Scott: It has the same cool off when you hit certain things mechanic.
Scott: It's got.
Scott: You know if you crash an excite truck You have to push one button really rapidly and if you do it rapidly enough Then you'll be back on the track and going really fast.
Scott: You'll get a free boost which is just like excite bike.
Scott: where you fall off your bike You have to push the button really quick in order to get that.
Scott: make the guy run faster to get on his bike again.
Scott: So while you might not speak the connection with excite bike and excite truck might not be obvious to the casual observer.
Scott: It is very much in the same vein and everything.
Scott: the problem with excite truck Is that perhaps its most promising aspect.
Scott: the multiplayer is kind of bad?
Rym: You see Scott was playing the game a lot more than me and I finally sat down and you know first time ever played.
Rym: I'll play some multiplayer with Scott and I beat him Every time we played and even I had to admit that I was not racing nearly as well as he was.
Rym: so why was I?
Rym: Winning?
Scott: well the way excite truck works.
Scott: that is different from excite bike.
Scott: excite bike was all about coming in first place.
Scott: Go as fast as you can.
Scott: Excite truck is also about going as fast as you can but it is also about collecting stars.
Scott: You collect stars by doing various things such as Stars.
Scott: right if you drive near trees But do not touch them you get stars.
Scott: if you do it for like a significant amount of time you get more stars.
Scott: the most Stars you can get it once is five.
Scott: So let's say I drive near a tree and then I'm back on the road.
Scott: I'll get like one star.
Scott: It'll say tree run one star.
Scott: if I drive through a forest and I don't touch any trees It'll be like super tree run and I get five stars.
Scott: If I keep driving through the woods and I keep not touching any trees It'll be like super tree run super tree run super and I'll get five ten fifteen stars.
Scott: And that's how you get a lot of stars, and it's not just driving through trees getting big jumps that gets you stars.
Scott: Sometimes rings will appear and you can jump through them.
Scott: That'll get you stars crashing into other trucks.
Scott: You crash into them hard enough.
Scott: You can get a super car smash five stars Etc.
Scott: etc.
Scott: There are many ways to get stars, you know And there are many ways to modify the track.
Scott: when you there are exclamation points on the track.
Scott: if you hit them track changes Usually giving opportunities to get more stars.
Scott: in the one player excite truck coming in first gives you 50 stars.
Scott: So while it is advantageous to drive through trees and jump high etc.
Scott: It is much more important to come in first.
Scott: because well 50 stars and in the one player mode You're trying to unlock the next track and there is often a requirement You know get a hundred and ten stars on this track in two laps and then you can have the next track.
Scott: So that 50 stars is pretty big in the multiplayer.
Scott: It is also a game of collect the most stars.
Scott: whoever gets the most stars wins But coming in first gets you a measly 15 stars.
Rym: So Scott would win by a lot.
Rym: then I'd be like, I don't know 15 seconds behind him yet Because I was reckless and crashing into things and flying over trees and flying through trees and drifting all over the place because I wasn't There and so well, I'd have like 80 more stars than him.
Scott: Yeah And I mean sure once you beat the track Their start used to get a star for like every second that the other guy doesn't finish.
Scott: So if I beat Rym by 20 seconds I get 20 more stars and that makes up a little bit for the fact that I'm not getting 50.
Scott: But it didn't matter because I was driving very fast on the road and getting big air.
Scott: Rym was driving very slowly through a lot of trees which got him a lot more stars.
Rym: So even though he drove either that or I was driving fast and constantly crashing into things.
Scott: Yeah crashing actually gets you a star or two if you get a nice crash and it also Crashing lets you get back on the track with a nice boost.
Scott: I mean very often crashing can be a way to come.
Scott: in first place, you know, if you do it add Strategic moments in strategic places, you know, I mean, I can't tell you how many times I've crashed while in second place Smash that button and then it puts me back on the track in first place.
Scott: So the multiplayer is sort of not fun because it doesn't reward you for driving.
Scott: Well, it just kind of Rewards you for driving poorly.
Rym: Yeah, I wish they at least had had.
Rym: I mean I can see why a lot of people like it's the excite truck multiplayer in that Where people who aren't very good at the game it makes it very fun.
Rym: Oh it sure does I mean, it's still fun to play even though winning or losing doesn't mean anything.
Rym: It's still fun to race against someone.
Scott: the other problem with the multiplayer is Number one, it's sort of a combination problem.
Scott: The screen is split in half Obviously a necessity but the controls are not the same, you know I talked about how in the one player it's so perfect the way you handle the car and where the camera is at all times Not so much in the multiplayer.
Scott: I mean I would drive in the single-player on a track with this car and do it amazingly The same handling on the same track in the same car and multiplayer no dice.
Scott: You know you you're freaking flying all over the place.
Scott: The car is much looser much more difficult to drive.
Scott: Also, it's much more prone to crashing.
Scott: I mean, I'll play one player and I'll hit a big jump and land on a rock and keep going.
Scott: in Versus mode if you touch something a little bit your car explodes and crashes.
Scott: It is no give at all.
Scott: or first play.
Scott: in single-player You can hit the car pretty hard against some stuff without completely killing yourself.
Scott: So it gets really annoying for anyone who's really good at the single-player mode to play the multiplayer mode.
Scott: You just get upset at yourself and you get upset at the game and it's not as fun.
Scott: However, that's okay because the single-player mode actually has a lot to offer.
Scott: there's a lot of tracks as a lot of cars to unlock.
Scott: the difficulty increases easily and gradually from a very You know any from a very low level to a very difficult level and the game is constantly Rewarding you with new tracks and new things to experience.
Scott: So as long as that single-player remains fun You're probably gonna have something more to do, you know I thought the game was gonna run out once.
Scott: I beat super excite mode and it didn't because I still have another mode to unlock And a lot more cars to unlock.
Rym: Yep I imagine we'll review at least portrait of ruin more thoroughly in the future.
Rym: after you know We beat them and we both played them and such.
Scott: Yep Anyway, I think that pretty much covers the site track.
Scott: You have a Wii and you're looking for a game and you like racing at all You know.
Scott: and if you're not interested if the multi the lack of multiplayer isn't gonna upset you too much Excite truck is worth whatever they're charging for it.
Rym: Yeah, it is definitely one of the top games to be out on the Wii right now.
Scott: And even if you know what I think was if it's still 50 bucks and you're not too excited about Driving a truck and hitting big air, which is a whole lot of fun Yeah, if you wait till it's 20 or 30 bucks, then you should definitely buy it.
Scott: Oh hands down There's.
Scott: no there's no reason not to.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has Everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.