Rym:
Rym: It's Tuesday, June 19th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: what's wrong with Dungeons and Dragons?
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: if you recall last week, we told that we went to the amazing millennium game store and Purchased a whole mess a new board game.
Rym: for the first time in our entire lives.
Rym: we went to the board gaming shop and usually we'd either not buy anything or One of us would buy a game usually saying I'm not buying the next one.
Rym: It's all you this time.
Rym: We didn't hold back and we bought everything that took our fancy at all.
Scott: No, no, there are plenty of things that took my fancy that I did not buy.
Rym: I bought every game that I have wanted that they had every game I physically saw that I had desired in the past.
Rym: I bought.
Scott: We bought let's see a total of I guess four and a half games and Alex bought a fifth game.
Scott: So we bought a lot of games and this weekend we played all those games.
Rym: it felt really good.
Scott: What felt even better was against all odds every single one of those games was good.
Scott: They were not bad games at all.
Rym: Yeah I mean the worst of the games and I'm still not sure which one that is But I got a few candidates is still better than a lot of games out there by far and is still playable.
Scott: Yeah There are a lot of games that we own from way back that we just don't play anymore and I said learn I see these Being played for a very long time and also Providing much to talk about on the show.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: I actually can't wait to talk about Gloria Mundi and the Interesting experiment we ended up going through because I didn't pay attention when I went through the rules.
Scott: Good job.
Scott: But yeah, we've talked about Gloria Mundi before though because we did play it.
Rym: Well, yeah, but I'd like to do a whole show on it someday in the future.
Scott: We will.
Rym: we will suffice to say it was a good weekend.
Scott: Yeah, also we have talked for perhaps for I don't know how many years maybe six years Setting up some sort of computerized database system to record who wins and loses in the board games We play.
Rym: usually whenever someone would propose this idea It was always whoever had just won a bunch of board games recently and they'd usually say something like I don't want you people to Forget that I'm the one in charge here.
Rym: I'm the business.
Scott: You mean me?
Scott: I'm always the.
Rym: I mean me.
Scott: Yeah anyway We have proposed And we had never implemented this system.
Scott: Well board game geek actually implemented the system and you can go and report board game sessions there.
Scott: But we never actually bothered to do that either.
Rym: We kept saying we would.
Rym: at one point on the inside of one of my computer cases I used to mark every time I won a game of air hockey against Scott and that was the closest we ever got.
Scott: so finally Alex got off his horse and Said aha and he made a real.
Scott: he didn't make you know The perfect ultimate finished product got off.
Rym: his court wouldn't be.
Rym: got on his horse and went and did something.
Rym: You don't get off your horse to be High horse.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: It was not a high horse.
Rym: Maybe you saw horse.
Scott: Maybe maybe.
Scott: anyway, I couldn't think of a better Turn a phrase or idiom.
Scott: So he got off his ass and he made one.
Scott: He didn't make it perfect.
Rym: Wait a minute That works perfectly.
Rym: got off his ass but an ass like a mule kind of like a horse.
Scott: That's why getting off the horse works.
Rym: So it does I concede the point.
Rym: So I'm not gonna let you finish.
Rym: It's hot out if you haven't been if you listen to Dave and Joel lately They like to talk about how hot it is.
Rym: luckily.
Scott: I'm today warm yesterday even warmer today.
Rym: Luckily, I have the solution to the heat in my hands my favorite summertime drink lemonade and southern comfort melonade.
Scott: Anyway anyway We made it and it works.
Scott: We're not putting on board game geek.
Scott: I guess maybe that could be in the future and it doesn't have all the features we would like yet but we've been keeping track of who wins and Rims not doing too.
Rym: Well, I did.
Rym: Okay Okay Plus I do point out that I did win the last game.
Rym: we played in a very closely run affair where Alex almost won.
Scott: That was because you both had prior experience with the game and I played it just fine.
Rym: Wait a minute Wait a minute.
Rym: You were claiming my prior experience in a game where I denied having played it because I didn't think that I had Until the last minute when I recognized one graphic on one of the cards on the board and said maybe I did play this game.
Scott: Yeah, you said you definitely played it anyway, and you did.
Scott: Oh I did but I didn't realize it regardless Because I was inexperienced and I was forced to go first.
Rym: plus I also won the broken game of Gloria Mundi.
Scott: Yes, I was forced to go first and I made an incredibly horrible opening play and My plays after that were just fine.
Scott: But my opening play was so poor that it ruined my entire game and that will not happen in the future.
Rym: Of course the system we put in place fails to take into account my 80 to 85 percent victory.
Rym: rated Carcassonne As well.
Scott: it should all right.
Scott: Let's make some news happen.
Scott: news a yep.
Scott: So Rym you like it to guitar heroes.
Rym: I While I've only played probably an hour's worth of guitar heroes I played more than an hour's worth of not so much more.
Rym: a few hours I mean if you count the time where I stand around with other people playing guitar heroes waiting to play guitar heroes.
Scott: But I'm saying you know playing one song takes almost like more than five minutes.
Rym: sometimes I played less than 20 songs.
Rym: I don't think so.
Rym: I didn't play it as much as you guys did every time we were over at someone's house.
Rym: I woke up late real late, and you guys were always playing anyway.
Rym: I went to a con.
Rym: I end up not playing anyway.
Scott: Everyone's talking about this rock band that they're making.
Rym: I don't know how I feel about it But I'm excited.
Scott: everyone has you know you get a bunch of different instruments going on and today they're released.
Scott: were pictures of the rock band guitar.
Scott: now if you I'm not you know some guitar Fanboy or something you know or a guitar geek.
Scott: But I must say that I am aware that there is a company that produces Guitars that is known as fender and there is a company that produces guitars known as Gibson And I know that the guitars and guitar hero are Gibson guitars, and I must say that I prefer the way the fender guitars look.
Rym: just looking at him I think looks are the only thing we have to go on.
Scott: yes You know the and fender makes like you know the Stratocaster and the Telecaster and Gibson makes the Les Paul.
Rym: And you know the difference between a Telecaster and a Stratocaster.
Scott: They look slightly different They sound slightly different, but they're electric.
Scott: so I guess I would assume that if you plug it into some amp Then you could make them both sound the same with the electronics.
Rym: I hadn't heard both of those terms until I started listening to meatloaf.
Scott: Yes, I was barely 17 and I once killed the boy with a fender guitar.
Scott: I Don't remember if it was a Telecaster or a Stratocaster But I do remember that it had a heart of chrome and a voice like a horny angel.
Scott: I Don't remember if it was a Telecaster or a Stratocaster, but I do remember that it wasn't at all easy.
Scott: It required the perfect combination of the right power cords and the precise angle from which to strike.
Scott: Anyway In Guitar Hero the guitars in the game as well as the plastic guitar are all Gibson's in Rock band.
Scott: the guitar you are going to use is a fender Stratocaster made of plastic Too shabby, and I gotta tell you this picture of it.
Scott: It looks pretty cool, but that's not the only difference.
Scott: They have changed other things about this guitar.
Scott: first of all instead of putting the colors of the buttons on The surface of the guitar you know on the surface of the buttons they put them on the side of the buttons.
Scott: So looking at the side of the guitar you can see what color you're pushing.
Scott: So you don't have to hold the guitar like face up to see the colors Which is pretty good.
Scott: the second thing they have done is they have added a second set of five buttons Way down at the bottom of the neck The meadley meadley meadley's as well as the Squeed Lee's?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I feel about that.
Scott: I want to know is that how is that gonna come into play in the game?
Scott: I mean is it just gonna be for you know your personal feelings like here comes a Squeed Lee part of the song I'm gonna go way down and play down there, or maybe here's here's what I would do.
Scott: I would just have it say in the game There would be some sort of visual cue that says switch to the other half Back to the other hand.
Rym: you might do something like that.
Rym: But I'd say they both work and they play the same notes.
Rym: Just if you're playing on the Squeed Lee's it makes Squeed Lee's and if you're playing on the meadley's it makes meadley's and you Could just kind of screw around That.
Scott: see actually I think maybe the ultimate solution is to have different play modes.
Scott: You know like the normal play mode you know you're only gonna use like three buttons And you could use either.
Scott: set it doesn't matter you know.
Scott: and yes It would sound different if you used one of the other.
Scott: But I think there should be an advanced play mode that says use these now use these now use these and also if you use I guess in the normal play mode.
Scott: if you were to use the Squeed Lee's at the right time even though you weren't required to That you would somehow get bonus points.
Scott: I think that would be a good play mode, but I do kind of feel that It really shouldn't matter which ones you use.
Scott: for another reason.
Scott: that reason would be if you already own guitar hero guitars You don't have to replace them all.
Rym: are you sure you might not have to anyway.
Scott: That's what I'm wondering.
Rym: I imagine you will see.
Scott: I'm really hoping that these guitars are backwards compatible and old guitars are forwards compatible.
Rym: Otherwise the last thing I need is a collection of fake instruments to go to all of the other things.
Scott: I know it's like people already have enough.
Scott: You know plastic you know instruments, and if they're doing this rock band We're going to assume they're gonna need drums of some sort yeah, and then They're gonna make ska van.
Rym: we're gonna have these remote trumpets coming out.
Scott: Yeah, we want to minimize the Plastic musical equipment in the house so make everything as compatible as possible.
Scott: And if I'm looking at the picture here, and it is five buttons green red yellow blue orange So that's guitar here right there, so it should be alright But I definitely want to use that thing more than I want to use any of the existing guitar hero guitars Just because that's my personal flavor.
Rym: so in much more depressing news the Barbarians living over on the great old island of Albion have decided that they don't like free speech.
Scott: Well, they don't like a lot of freedom.
Scott: I mean they got those freaking security cameras all over the place.
Rym: Oh, yeah, like we don't in New York City.
Scott: And you know it took them a lot longer to get rid of their kings than we did.
Rym: their kings have been impotent for a Long time.
Rym: we kicked their ass 1776. we can kick him in 19.
Rym: I guess we already did in 1996.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: There's a reason we did that.
Rym: yeah But I know it looks like Britain for the first time in a decade according to this article here on BBC.
Rym: I guess that's where the news comes from an Albion.
Rym: I don't know what the B stands for.
Rym: You know I realized we've gotten a lot of new listeners.
Rym: I'm just gonna let you all know that we call Britain or Great Britain or United Kingdom or England or any of those places?
Rym: Albion because that's the only word we could come up with.
Rym: that Encompasses all that we mean without meaning things.
Rym: We don't expect.
Scott: yeah It's like if we just sit like when we're talking about a subset of Albion like if we're talking about just Scotland or just Wales.
Scott: We can do that because we know what those are.
Rym: yeah But what's the difference between the United Kingdom and Great Britain and Britain?
Scott: and yeah if we try to just you know say like UK And it was actually only England or something like that.
Scott: I don't know I could be wrong right now already getting yelled at.
Scott: I Just get yelled at.
Scott: so we say Albion to avoid being yelled at and always will never be wrong if we just say Albion every Time.
Rym: yeah, you know what someday the Romans are coming back, and this business will be sorted out.
Rym: Yeah, my homies know who done it all right, so sorry I love the barbarians and Albion did what.
Rym: so uh my parents say what man I'm - is a somewhat violent video game And they decided that this video game is so abhorrent that it is banned from the island Period.
Scott: huh, that's uh anti freedom to quote.
Scott: is it fascist over there?
Rym: David cook director of the BBFC I guess that should be the Albionic equivalent of the FCC.
Rym: man on two is distinguishable from recent high-end video games by its unremitting bleakness and Callousness of tone.
Rym: there is sustained and cumulative casual say - I like that alliteration.
Rym: Cumulative casual sadism in the way in which these killings are committed and encouraged in the game.
Rym: the game is morally irresponsible.
Scott: It's it's a horror game now.
Scott: It's supposed to be like that.
Rym: How is this worse?
Rym: Then I don't know reading a book about Jack the Ripper murdering people or I don't know reading a book about anything the Bible.
Scott: I don't think we need to make an argument.
Scott: Violent video games don't hurt people because it's made a thousand times and we're right and they're wrong.
Scott: and that's the end of that.
Rym: I just it bothers me that.
Rym: well it bothers me on one level that people treat video games differently.
Rym: But then again, they used to treat music differently rock and roll.
Rym: now that they blame hip-hop It seems like people always want to have an excuse to blame For whenever their kids stray when bad things happen.
Rym: and currently video games.
Rym: is that scapegoat?
Rym: I mean, I look at Hillary Clinton.
Rym: She's running for president of the United States and one of her platforms is yeah I got to stop those evil video games ruining our kids and I know she's an intelligent woman and she doesn't believe that.
Rym: but Well, I hope.
Scott: I don't know she might.
Scott: I get the feeling that but
Rym: a lot of politicians are on this boat because it's really Easy to say that video games caused the problems and that by getting rid of them You'll solve the problems because we all know that when they stopped letting people play rock and roll.
Rym: There was no more crime.
Rym: No Now the reason this really bothers me isn't so much that they banned it because whatever the people on the island of Albion can do Whatever they want.
Scott: I think what it's time to do is get a whole bunch of copies and start shipping them over there in disguise.
Rym: Here's the part that bothers me the second half of the article.
Rym: quote.
Rym: the original Mad Hunt game caused huge controversy and Was blamed for the murder of Stefan Pachira.
Scott: Did did the game just jump out and stab him?
Rym: Apparently the kid was walking through the albionic equivalent of Walmart.
Rym: So all Mart are ye olde Mart and The cartridges jumped out and stabbed him in the eye.
Scott: It's a cartridge game.
Rym: No, what actually happened was he was randomly stabbed and beaten to death by a mugger and in some albionic town in 2004 and His parents believed that he was the killer was inspired by the game.
Rym: I don't think there was any evidence of that whatsoever.
Rym: But a lot of people jumped on this bandwagon and apparently the parents have been campaigning against violent video games since.
Scott: but at least like At least some of the other people who blame violent video games like the people who blame violent video games on Columbine At least those guys played doom little yeah, but obviously, you know They probably were still crazy fuckers and they probably would have killed him even if they hadn't had doom.
Scott: They would have killed him if it was the year 1832 and we had schools like that.
Scott: and you know, those kids were the same kids they were.
Scott: it was there.
Scott: You know, they're nuts, but at least there were video games there here.
Scott: Is there was there any evidence at all?
Rym: I mean, I don't know.
Rym: This is just in the article.
Rym: It seems to be.
Rym: the BBC likes to a lot always have two related story like they always have the first half of the story and then the second half of the story is related but only kind of and There's not enough info and I didn't feel like looking it up.
Scott: Here's the other thing is that this game apparently got an adults only rating in the u.s right and The people at who made the game were like.
Scott: so upset they were like, oh we thought we were making it a mature game.
Scott: Hey man, hunt one was an M game and we made it in line with man hunt one and we're very sad.
Scott: We got adults only and I'm like, what wait, wait, wait.
Scott: What?
Scott: why are you sad you freaking?
Scott: it's an adults only game.
Scott: now It's like who.
Scott: everyone wants it.
Rym: Well the last game that they did like how South Park had the MA and everyone wanted to watch it.
Rym: the last game that they did this to was Carmageddon in 1997 a decade ago and apparently that was.
Scott: I played the demo of Carmageddon.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: It's not really adults only all you do is drive a car around it.
Scott: There's a little pixelated people go squish.
Rym: Well, they apparently overturned that on appeal and the Albion's got to play this game.
Scott: Uh-huh so we'll see what happens if this gets appealed or whatever, but I think the problem here is that the games industry itself seems to be like They're not.
Scott: they don't have the.
Scott: they have some balls.
Scott: They're definitely on the right side.
Scott: They're on our side saying, you know, video games don't hurt people etc.
Scott: Etc.
Scott: They don't cause violence.
Scott: You're all just a bunch of crazies But they also don't have the balls to say yeah, we believe this so much that we're you know, yeah Okay, rate the game adults only.
Scott: we're still gonna sell it in the goddamn stores.
Scott: What are you gonna do about it?
Scott: Yeah, what are you gonna do?
Rym: Well, apparently the Albion's will just ban the game entirely.
Scott: They can do that but in the US if GameStop and EB and Amazon had balls they could still sell this game.
Scott: Adults only doesn't mean illegal to sell Yeah, but ban does.
Scott: yeah, it does.
Rym: I don't know the exact detail.
Rym: I don't know what kind of time you'll do if you illegally import this horribly seditious material into Albion.
Scott: I wonder should we do some smuggling action?
Rym: That would be awesome.
Scott: and solo bringing a whole bunch of like burn DVDs into Albion.
Rym: We got our friends over movies.
Rym: You should see.
Rym: we should just mail them a crate of the game and a note that says do what you will.
Scott: Well, we'd have to somehow like disguise the game Like we take the DVD cases and disguise them as like some other sort of like region to DVD.
Rym: Oh, well, you know the perfect disguise.
Rym: What we do is we mail to everyone in Britain one of those guy Fox masks and inside of it is this game?
Rym: Oh, obviously Things of the day now.
Rym: originally Scott had a thing of the day and I had a thing of the day and they were kind.
Rym: It was like a theme day not quite a theme week, but a theme day and Scott then discovered something so cool that we there's no way we could pass up.
Scott: I discovered it this morning, but I remembered it as I browse the internet.
Rym: Yeah, but suffice to say we couldn't push it off another week because it was a chance we'd forget.
Rym: So we'll let Scott go last.
Rym: but the original things of the day.
Rym: We really like a band you might have heard of.
Rym: they're called Daft Punk.
Scott: They're two French guys who remain anonymous, but I think you can see pictures their faces on the internet.
Scott: But they usually wear like robot masks and they make awesome musics.
Rym: Their music is some of my favorite kind of music and one of their songs is fairly iconic to us partly because at RIT Someone I'm not sure who I think it was Scott Johnson, but I don't actually remember offhand showed us this flash video Made to this music and the flash video is the River City Ransom guy the narc guy Yeah, Ryan the narc guy the blue one Barbie and Boy from a boy and his blob not the blob just boy.
Scott: Yeah the blob does not appear now.
Rym: this video was one of those things much like the leak spin that ended up consuming all of us for about a week and To this day.
Rym: I really like this video.
Rym: I think this is the kind of clever shit that I like to see on the internet.
Scott: Yeah, this is definitely a classic thing of the day.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's not been a thing of the day before even if it hasn't.
Rym: I figure you got to see this.
Rym: This is part of front row crew culture.
Rym: This is from that old era before YouTube when people would go to flash websites and watch animations that were usually pretty piss-poor.
Rym: Something like this was amazing back then.
Scott: Yeah, it was good stuff.
Scott: Well, uh, you need to see
Rym: we only thought to do this because we were reminded by my actual thing of the day which is on dig right now and I saw it and I clicked on it only because I thought it was gonna be one of those horribly lame things and if anything I was gonna make fun of it on the show.
Rym: It's the song and there's someone's hands.
Rym: It looks like a girl's hands and it's called like the Daft Punk hand job whatever and the hands just kind of stand there if the cameras just zoomed in on them and She kind of dances with her hands to the song and it's kind of cute, but it's also kind of lame.
Rym: You wonder what's going on?
Rym: All I want to say and I'm not going to say more is Keep watching until you realize why it's awesome.
Scott: just keep playing and if you Know how the song goes and you will if you watch the first flash video first before you watch this YouTube You will be able to figure out where it's going.
Scott: and it goes.
Rym: it goes all the way.
Rym: Scott when we were watching it when I showed it to Scott He pretty much said is she gonna do the?
Rym: and then she did.
Rym: it was perfect.
Rym: Yep, and I get a lot of respect for this because it's quite a bit more than I expected.
Scott: Alright, this thing today is so cool.
Scott: I didn't even like my brain can comprehend it because it's sort of like a bunch of pieces that were put together and I could have eventually figured out Hey, this could be possible, but I didn't think that it was done and apparently it was done many times.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the real thing is that I know about the two components that make up Scott's thing of the day.
Rym: I knew about the one thing I knew about the other thing But the idea that someone had combined them and done something this awesome is still a little bit staggering to me.
Scott: Yeah, and the fact that it was done so long ago yet not discovered on by the Internet's until just now By at least discovered widely on the Internet's until just now is is also amazing.
Rym: God We need internet archaeologists to find things of the day for us.
Scott: Yeah, we do alright, so whether you know it or not back in the day before we had magnetic media like floppy disks or we had Optical media like CD roms or anything like that Computers used a lot of them at least personal computers.
Scott: Well, I mean think about the really big computers that you know, the big old mainframes They use like two reels of tape.
Scott: right they would go from reel to reel and then eventually They when you bought a personal computer instead of having a big reel of tape you had a little cassette tape to the same kind you would put in your stereo.
Scott: and If you ever used a dial-up modem here those noises it makes.
Scott: well if you took a tape with digital data on it and Put it in a cassette player.
Scott: It would sound like a modem or a fax machine or whatever because that's what those things do.
Scott: is they send Digital data over an analog phone line and that an analog phone line?
Scott: that it's noise and you can hear it.
Scott: So early pcs used cassette tapes to store data regardless of that.
Scott: But my dad has a lot of vinyl records cuz he lived in a time when vinyl records with a shit and he had a Turntable and he liked music.
Scott: and he's got a lot of vinyl records.
Scott: and as a kid I listen to many of those vinyl records on my big bird turntable now, which was later replaced with a non-sesame street turntable.
Scott: and what are the vinyl records I enjoyed listening to?
Scott: and perhaps my Early preteen teenage years.
Scott: I was a Monty Python album Which contained the audio of many my Monty Python sketches without the video Which you which doesn't make sense now that you can buy all of it on DVD But it made sense in the 70s when VHS did not exist.
Scott: so On one of these Monty Python albums the vinyl record There was a secret track.
Scott: The way it worked if you know how record works is you have this vinyl disc with grooves and the needle goes in the grooves And the groove is a big spiral.
Scott: so when you spin the record around the needle goes around the entire groove getting closer and closer to the middle of the record until Eventually, the entire record is played and in the groove are bumps which bump the needle around it.
Scott: when the needle is moved around It makes noise you.
Scott: that's why when you put your finger on like a needle on a record player You can hear you know scratch it and it makes noise.
Scott: That's why when you move a record back and forth it goes wicker wicker wicker, right?
Scott: So someone had the genius idea on this Monty Python album of making a groove in the grooves.
Scott: If you were really careful on you had a really pointy record need.
Rym: it was practically impossible.
Scott: I was never able to do it.
Scott: You put this needle between the tracks so there's a groove going around the record and then there's a second smaller groove that is in between the Existing the main the normal groove.
Scott: and if you balance the needle on this second smaller hidden groove There would be more data it on the record that normally there would be.
Scott: there's hidden hidden audio, right?
Scott: apparently back in the day on certain albums people put a Hidden groove on a record and in that hidden groove they put digital data.
Scott: and if you put your needle on that hidden groove and played it and had a tape player a tape recorder and Recorded that hidden digital data on the vinyl record to a cassette tape and then if you put that cassette tape in Your Sinclair Spectrum personal computer you would get a video game
Rym: That is so
Scott: hot.
Scott: it's unbelievably hot and on this website here They've got screenshots and I think you can even play one of the games online and like a little st Claire emulating thing and one of them's like a text adventure with low-resolution girls on the beach and another one is like Flying trains and all sorts of weird stuff.
Scott: There's one.
Rym: I don't care if it's clusters revenge.
Rym: The concept is just so cool.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't matter what the hell game this is.
Scott: Holy crap There were video games that people made.
Scott: look this one says like hail Satan lick his cloven hoof.
Scott: Oh And there's the basic code and it's all kinds of crazy stuff going on here.
Rym: Check this business out.
Rym: They let their homies know who done it.
Scott: This is crazy-ass business and It's kind of sad that since our technology now is just completely digital in every way.
Scott: that fun stuff like this doesn't happen anymore We don't you know?
Scott: We're not forced to do crazy hacks like this and the hacks we do do are most of them are far less interesting.
Rym: Well, we're seeing that in video games anyway.
Rym: I mean even back then when they were digital video games are still a mystery like you see
Scott: like you go to the minus world In mario
Rym: 1 and it was amazing and you couldn't understand why it was there and you'd explore the game Looking like you like in Castlevania.
Rym: I once got on top of One of the castles where you shouldn't be and there's all this water and it was scary up there and I remember this feeling of As a kid when I got into areas, I shouldn't have gone.
Rym: It was this land of mystery.
Scott: and now like Metroid with all its crazy wall Are you here?
Rym: like I heard there's a. if you walk back and forth in front of the Tower of whatever a Thousand times and then fight a dinosaur General Leo will join your party.
Rym: now I can just dump the ROM and see clearly that there's no code for that.
Scott: Yes, and You know why everything happens?
Scott: It's total demystification, you know, and now not only is the minus world not a mystery in mario 1 But also we can just make mods for games.
Scott: And yeah, it's the end.
Scott: but how we can make our own games Yeah, but this this is pretty awesome right here.
Scott: Check it out.
Rym: So we haven't talked about role-playing games in a while.
Rym: We figured it was about time to bring it back up and I was also reminded even before when our friend Ken was arguing with us about World of Warcraft and we haven't actually gotten a Chance to respond in detail to that yet.
Rym: But one of the points he made was that how dare we basically said that we shouldn't impinge upon the awesomeness that is Dungeons & Dragons?
Rym: And we're huge fans of role-playing.
Rym: We played D&D a lot in our lives and we continue to play.
Rym: We have a campaign with much of the front row crew that runs once a month.
Rym: That's the only time we have but I mean we played all through college.
Scott: I played all through high school in middle school and played it a lot in summer camp and such.
Rym: and despite all that I'm gonna come straight out and say it Dungeons & Dragons Is all things considered a pretty piss-poor system of role-playing and I rather dislike it
Scott: For a game of role-playing tabletop role-playing where your goal is to play roles Dungeons & Dragons is not so great.
Scott: It has its benefits and its upsides, but for the most part you can do a lot better very easily.
Scott: So, I mean, I'm not even talking like go all out and do burning wheel There.
Scott: there are a lot of there many many other systems that are better than Dungeons & Dragons that no one plays now.
Rym: We're not.
Rym: I don't really want to get into all the other systems.
Rym: We're trying or the systems that are out there any of that.
Rym: We talked about them before.
Rym: if you're interested in alternative systems check out an old show We did where we interviewed Luke Crane the creator of burning wheel.
Rym: That man is a role-playing genius and I respect his opinion very highly.
Scott: Anyway, the reasons why Dungeons & Dragons is not so hot as a role-playing system go all the way back to when it was created By Gary Gygax in the 70s.
Rym: Yeah, there were other people involved.
Rym: We're not gonna talk about the history in terms of you know, this man did this and this man did this because it's incredibly boring Yes, but basically there's a man named Gary Gygax and he is credited with creating dungeon dragon.
Rym: He's kind of scary, too.
Rym: Yeah, he's a scary gamer, but at the same time I got some respect for him.
Scott: He's a famous geek person.
Scott: You should know who he is.
Rym: You should you did.
Rym: He's pretty recognizable.
Scott: His name is Gygax.
Scott: Think about that.
Scott: What coincidence.
Scott: a guy named Gygax You know Ended up making dungeon dragons.
Scott: anyway, he He basically, you know was a fan of the miniature war games like chainmail and other such games, you know games like Warhammer.
Scott: You have miniatures and you move them around a map and they fight right and from that he spawned the first edition dungeon dragons, which While you know, it had the role-playing capacity that you know where you can pretend to be whoever you are For the most part.
Scott: It was a game of walk around the dungeon hit the monster collect the treasure, you know.
Scott: Oh, you know Search for traps, you know, you basically play it a lot.
Scott: the way you play hero quest only more complicated.
Rym: Yeah, the game was basically just a set of rules for combat and dungeon exploration And if you role-played beyond that it was entirely your prerogative.
Scott: yeah, I mean the original Dungeons and Dragons was so tied into the Concept of dungeon crawling that there wasn't experience points.
Scott: It was when you get to the next level of the dungeon you get a level.
Scott: That's how it was.
Scott: It was that crazy like net hack where it has levels of the dungeon and you go down one level.
Scott: Oh stairs Let's go down the stairs real quick.
Rym: Yeah, I always wanted to go down never wanted to go up.
Scott: Yeah, because as soon as you went down you got more powerful and the monsters got more powerful and you got closer to the end.
Rym: So fast forward.
Scott: fast forward to second edition and third edition.
Scott: Dungeon dragons change quite a bit between first edition and now I guess three and a half edition and a potential upcoming.
Rym: Yeah, because I'm buying fourth edition not but dude I didn't buy three and a half edition until I had to because my players handbook fell apart.
Scott: Yes but they did change dungeon dragons quite a bit from its first edition roots as a simple dungeon crawler and they added all sorts of Rules to do this and rules to do that and they expanded it quite a bit.
Scott: and There's a lot more to help you do role-playing and there's a lot more to help you do all sorts of things and role-playing is Definitely more feasible and a lot more scenarios besides just crawling down a dungeon and killing all the monsters are possible and encouraged.
Scott: however, many remnants of the original tabletop Miniatures war game remain and actually a lot of them have been brought back somewhat especially in the more recent version.
Rym: So thus what's wrong with D&D today?
Rym: because I will say that and I used to talk about this quite a bit Especially back at RIT when you know third edition came out just about before we went to college.
Rym: So well, like I played it a little bit we converted characters in it and all that.
Rym: but I remember griping a lot about things I didn't like in third edition and how I thought third second edition was a Superior role-playing system.
Rym: and that was really partly due to the fact that I didn't know much about all the alternatives out there.
Rym: So I'd always complain Yeah, second had handled this better second had handled this better and I guess now that I'm older and wiser and more well informed I realized that second edition didn't really handle things better.
Rym: It was just that second edition had a lot of gaps in the rules where the Dungeon Master and the players were forced to just kind of Go with it and make something up or handle it somehow.
Rym: a lot of it was very subjective and As a result it encouraged a lot of creative play and a lot of role-playing.
Rym: third edition.
Rym: They fixed that because they got rid of a lot of the complicated stupid rules like that co.
Rym: Not that I still can't calculate a fat co like that and not that I can't that co.
Rym: well You didn't play a lot of second head.
Rym: Did you?
Scott: I played it maybe ten times?
Rym: Yeah, I play.
Rym: I've still played more second head than I have third head.
Rym: Oh, no, it's kind of scary.
Rym: It's very when I really think about it.
Rym: and I used before that I played Dungeons and dragons.
Scott: Yeah, you don't want to play have that but you don't play.
Rym: Yeah, I had the rules Cyclopedia that I spilled Dr.
Rym: Pepper on once.
Scott: they almost cried about the three boxes at the Goodwill the red the blue and the whatever.
Rym: Oh, I had.
Rym: well after that.
Rym: I just dungeons and dragons the rules Cyclopedia Yeah, and then I bought advanced Dungeons and Dragons because advanced I'm older now I can take it.
Rym: But yeah, so it seems like everything that I liked about second edition Really just had to do with the fact that second edition was so convoluted and hacked together and full of gaps That within those gaps I had done all the things that superior role-playing systems do as part of the rules.
Scott: Yes, I mean it wasn't really.
Scott: it's not really an aspect of second edition to have good role-playing.
Scott: I'm pretty sure the vast majority of second edition play is not with the high quality role-playing action.
Scott: It's up to the players to fill it in.
Scott: So if you're playing with role players and you play second edition, you're gonna fill in the gaps with good role-playing.
Scott: But if you play second edition with normal guys, you know, just people who played first edition They're gonna do the dungeon crawl just as always.
Scott: It's now system doesn't help you out.
Rym: third edition.
Rym: they fix that by fixing all the rules and making everything very calculated and precise and accounted for and Balanced and as a result you lost all those gaps wherein.
Rym: look a combat example in the second edition.
Rym: Maybe you're in combat is your turn to fight.
Rym: You might say something instead of just I attack the ogre to the left.
Rym: I try to jump up and Blah blah blah do something crazy.
Rym: and the DM.
Rym: there's no rule for that.
Rym: the DM would usually say Make two decks checks and if you passed in both you'd say all right Roll for damage.
Rym: it worked or now you fell on your ass or something fun like that.
Rym: in third ed.
Rym: There's usually rules for what you tried to do and it's really difficult to just say I Try to do X because that doesn't fit into the system of you know partial action for move action full action all the things you can do on a turn in combat.
Scott: if they've basically got a rule covered for basic for almost anything you would want to do and Even though you could potentially, you know play it fast and loose and deviate from those rules It is usually to your detriment to deviate from the rules.
Scott: Yeah following the rules in the book and doing what they say and Selecting your options from among the words in the players handbook is the way to get the best You know results I guess the most desirable results for your character in terms of beating up bad guys.
Rym: And the other thing is that despite all that all the things they added to make the game more good if you look at what it takes to make a character in D&D or what you put into it or There's no role-playing at all inherent if you make a character 80% of what you do is setting up the characters combat ability 10% is figuring out all the numbers and then maybe you write a little bit of backstory or
Scott: This thing is any sort of backstory or anything else you do is completely outside of the role-playing system.
Rym: Yep, there's no color in the game.
Rym: any skill you take is a appraisal.
Rym: I get to appraise the Rings that we find or diplomacy.
Rym: I get to smooth talk the dragon or bluff.
Rym: I get to lie to people.
Rym: there's no.
Scott: just I Will make the the argument that hey I don't want any of the role-playing in the system.
Scott: the system doesn't need to have any role-playing in it.
Scott: I can just role play on my own and I just need this system to figure out.
Scott: you know when things happen and what people Are able to do and what they're not able to do etc.
Scott: etc.
Scott: as sort of you know We always talk about you need the restriction on your creativity because yeah sitting around the table Just saying whatever you want and being allowed to do whatever you want doesn't work.
Rym: Now I think the problem that I see with that is that when you play D&D Because none of the role-playing is part of the system at all It is very easy to get off track with the role-playing which can have very profound if subtle effects on gameplay For example.
Rym: indeed because all this stuff is outside of the rules.
Rym: It doesn't matter and it's very easy to forget or lose track of things that you set up in your character.
Rym: You might have written a little backstory thing But you might just forget about things your character believes in or you might forget that your character has a flaw or whatever because there's No reason to remember it.
Rym: There's no rule to remember it and also because it's outside of it It's.
Rym: there's no force other than everyone's Willingness and ability to keep the role-playing interesting and on track and it's really easy for a game to get bogged down in a bunch of characters talking and talking and arguing or Deciding what to do in combat or doing things that feel like role-playing, but are actually just procedural.
Scott: Yes The only the thing is is when you take the role-playing out of the game system itself Then you sort of run out of ways to encourage the role-playing and to make the role-playing matter.
Scott: It becomes.
Scott: it's out of the system, which I guess doesn't really matter.
Scott: You still have the ability to role-play But now you don't have the mechanism to integrate the role-playing with the things that happen.
Scott: Yes, and thus can't you all you can really do.
Scott: I mean the best you can do in Dungeons and Dragons is if the DM gives XP to people who role-play or Recognize who role-plays and then you know completely separately from that, you know gives them more treasure.
Scott: But if you do stuff like that You don't make that connection with my role-playing got me that you need the direct connection.
Scott: I like you know that you do.
Scott: you act something and then directly that what the thing you did Results in the good stuff as opposed to you know separate non-associative rewards.
Rym: so as a result it's very difficult to keep everyone on track.
Rym: role-playing in character and as and to play D&D with good role-playing takes a lot of discipline among everyone involved both the DM and the players and That amount of discipline can often be stifling or difficult to maintain over many hours.
Scott: And while it is possible for I'm sure plenty of people role-play awesomely with the d20 system all over the world It could be you could and I have seen systems burning wheel where you can get people who are not Experienced role-players to role-play awesomely because the system is designed in such a better way.
Rym: I mean when we played these burning wheel games with Luke Crane at uber con and I we played in several he people.
Rym: there are people who have never role-played before who will sit down at this and not know what to expect and They'll within a half hour be role-playing better than a lot of people who have played D&D for much of their lives And they'll be fully into it and they'll just they'll grasp everything and they'll be playing their character.
Rym: and in D&D You don't see that because a lot of well not often I mean we brought some people who haven't played a lot of D&D into our current game and Luckily, well, it's not really a good example because we've been using a lot of burning wheel mechanics in our D&D game.
Rym: Yeah, we've slowly been turning D&D into burning wheel But in normal cases someone who hasn't played D&D before gets so bogged down in the rules and the procedure of play that it's very easy to lose track Of actually role-playing because you're too busy trying to figure out whether you have a plus 15 or a plus 16 in your diplomacy check.
Scott: Now, let's let's actually talk about some of the specific mechanics in D&D that I think really hinder it.
Rym: All right I got a big one.
Rym: I'm gonna save till the end.
Scott: Yeah, the first are you gonna talk about?
Scott: combat takes forever?
Rym: Oh, no, no the one at the end.
Rym: I want to talk about Reward and failure.
Scott: I want to talk about that too.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Well that will we'll talk about All right.
Scott: So the first thing that's obviously wrong with D&D is that if you look in that in the rule book The vast majority of the rules deal with one thing and one thing alone and that is fighting.
Scott: Combat between characters between you and monsters mostly but fighting in general.
Rym: now I liked combat a lot more in second ed than I do in third ed Despite the fact that the system of combat in third ed is very well put together and is a wonderful combat system.
Rym: It takes care of everything.
Scott: you can have fairly large battles that are very Interesting and somewhat tactical in third ed D&D and there are a lot of interesting options open to you Even if you don't have magics, but however, you have magics is even more interesting.
Rym: However in second ed because the system was so limited in scope and kind of broken You ended up being very creative in combat and combat tended not to take as long and it was much more abstract.
Scott: Regardless in both D&D systems combat does take too long.
Rym: I think it takes twice as long in third ed as it did in second ed.
Scott: It's still.
Scott: that means it takes a half hour in second ed in an hour in third.
Rym: Well part of it is that second ed was the combat.
Rym: in second edition D&D was designed so that you can play with miniatures But it is not necessary.
Rym: it can be abstracted very easily to where you just you choose who you are attacking with just a general sense of who's where in the room or what's going on and who you can target with spells and as a result you can Kind of imagine and just roleplay with it and roll with it a lot easier.
Rym: in third ed You have to worry about all right If I walk 15 feet to the right and then I cast magic missile.
Scott: Even so the emphasis on combat in all Dungeons & Dragons is and in fact most other role-playing games like the GURPSES and all the White wolves and things is way too much.
Scott: I mean think about it.
Scott: You're role-playing okay, so there's some sort of world And you're a character with some sort of goals and unless you're a boxer or perhaps in an army Oh, you mean like a fighter?
Scott: Yes, or unless you're in an army that is at war even if you're an army at war in a fantasy setting How often are there actually battles, but when you play D&D it's just constant battles all over the place.
Rym: Yeah, you gotta have a fight in every game where people get restless because and I hate that and luckily we've shied away from that But even our really good games we played in college Every session there was at least one fight because otherwise at the end of the session while you might have a good role-playing session You'd feel like you wasted having this character because almost everything on your character sheet is for combat and combat alone.
Scott: Yeah, it's like even if you try to make the least combat character in D&D you end up making an Ineffective character like let's say you're role-playing right you're?
Scott: you have some sort of role-playing goal That is outside of beating people up or winning a war or fighting monsters or getting treasure, right?
Scott: So you make a D&D character with many non-combat skills and abilities and stuff like that.
Scott: You know of what there are available.
Scott: if you do that you're going to make a largely ineffective character who is not going to be able to physically achieve their goals according to the rules because Someone else who made a character for combat will work be much more powerful within the system and they will stop you.
Rym: I mean I tried it once.
Rym: I tried to make a pacifist scholar and I put all my points into knowledge skills and all these Things.
Rym: and thus whenever the party got into combat everyone took part except me.
Rym: You just kind of fell asleep and didn't bother because there's nothing I could do.
Rym: and outside of combat while I could role-play Most of my interaction with the game in terms of my character was the party.
Rym: Oh, well, what do we know about X?
Rym: Rym rolls a d20 based on his knowledge skill?
Rym: Oh Rym knows X the DM reads what rims knows.
Rym: play continues It.
Rym: it made it unfun to play the character and just wasn't worth it.
Rym: If you've character can't engage in combat in standard D&D your character is often very difficult to play effectively At least within that system.
Rym: Yeah now this because we've already gone a little long.
Rym: This is the thing that really rankles me about D&D in most systems.
Rym: Oh and it really plays into what Scott just brought up about the combat and the combat taking forever and the combat being the focus.
Rym: Yeah, D&D Rewards success and punishes failure and that is it.
Scott: Well, it doesn't really punish failure.
Rym: Well, you die I guess.
Scott: yes, but the thing or you don't get XP the thing in D&D is look look even not the d20 system Previous systems, right you're rolling this 20-sided dice, right and some numbers are failure and some are success.
Scott: but in general you always have a 5% chance of guaranteed success and a 5% chance of failure.
Scott: and Usually success means you got what you wanted and what you expected.
Scott: the monster died you were able to jump over the cliff You were able to climb up the wall, whatever.
Rym: Failure in D&D basically means either you died or At most you don't progress the plot You don't progress the role-playing or the story or anything.
Scott: the game just stops until you can find another method way to succeed by rolling a different number or somewhere else.
Scott: or You have to go and do something else in a large tree blocks your path.
Rym: Yep, like oh, we're at a door.
Rym: We got to get into this room pick the lock.
Rym: I fail Crap what do we do now?
Rym: We have to figure out how to pick this lock.
Scott: Well, we bash the door down we fail.
Scott: All right, what do we do now?
Rym: that and that's really the the crux of the matter Is that in D&D if your characters fail at something that sucks always and if your character succeed That's awesome always but in it in a better role-playing system because in the real world or in a fantasy world or anything Sometimes people fail and I think that a good role-playing system or a good role-playing session is one Whereby you play your character as that person.
Rym: if they succeed or fail You still have the same amount of enjoyment.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: See you got to remember that in D&D, right?
Scott: It seems like you're the character that you are playing is separate from you, right?
Scott: And a lot of people are like all to have the really good role-playing you have to make them one in the same To be your character and you do in some ways.
Scott: But at the same time you're playing a game.
Scott: if you're any game you're playing board game video game Whatever, you should be having fun the whole time and no matter what happens.
Scott: All right, if you'd be playing a video game and you just can't beat it It's not good if it's not enjoyable the whole time and a D&D when your character succeeds it's enjoyable and when your character fails, it is not enjoyable for you the human being playing Dungeons and Dragons an Ideal role-playing system
Rym: how Bernie will burn?
Scott: you should be fun.
Scott: whether your character succeeds or fails.
Scott: It should be fun if you die.
Scott: if your character dies, it should be fun if your character falls off a cliff.
Scott: It should be fun if your character gets stabbed.
Scott: It should be fun if your character gets into a fight and gets beat up.
Scott: It should be fun if your character gets Captured by the evil wizard no matter what happens.
Scott: It should be fun for the human being pretending to be that character.
Rym: now to clarify that a little bit I mean it should be fun but what that really means is that let's take an example from burning wheel versus D&D.
Rym: if You in D&D you get to the door and you attempt to get through the door by the means you have available and you fail now the game bogs down into a procedural how to get past the door or do we avoid the door or whatever?
Rym: and Anytime you see it's like you're climbing a ladder and any toward the plot goals or your characters goals and anytime you roll Well, you go up a rung and anytime you roll poorly You're stuck on that rung until you roll well or do something to make yourself get past it.
Rym: in burning wheel There's no ladder.
Rym: There's just a sea of possibilities and if you fail at something you failed at it.
Rym: You don't procedurally.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Well, what if I do this?
Rym: What if I do?
Scott: the rule is let it ride.
Scott: if you roll it opening the door and you fail to open the door You fail to open the door.
Rym: period myself Scott and Pete played a very good short demo of burning wheel with Luke once where it was three characters who all have goals and we all want this one McGuffin in this place and we're Arguing over and whatever.
Rym: Scott grabs the McGuffin and fucking runs away.
Rym: So Pete and I say alright, we're in this together Let's get that little prick.
Rym: So Scott tries to escape and we try to get away.
Rym: now when D&D this would go on forever Scott tries runs away.
Rym: we chase him run chase him.
Rym: There's rules for chasing.
Rym: if we catch him Alright now maybe I can get away this other way.
Rym: maybe I can get away this other way in burning wheel.
Rym: The way we resolve that was we did the thing.
Rym: We've rolled the dice.
Rym: will Scott be able to get away or not?
Rym: There is no procedural bullshit.
Rym: It's just will the plot go in direction Scott escapes or direction Scott does not?
Rym: Scott rolled and it ended up that he was not able to escape.
Rym: what that meant was that that plot point was done.
Rym: It was settled.
Rym: Scott did not escape from us.
Rym: We are going to catch him now.
Rym: We can skip the procedural bullshit and get on to the role-playing of the real situation.
Rym: That's interesting.
Scott: Yeah, so now we move directly to.
Scott: Scott is caught.
Scott: they have caught up to Scott.
Scott: now What do you do?
Rym: and it's this idea of by skipping the procedural crap?
Rym: It's so much easier to get into character because you don't have to worry about the meta You don't have to worry about.
Rym: but what if my character dies?
Rym: you just look at your character.
Rym: This is what my character wants and this is what he is willing to risk.
Rym: I am also willing to risk that.
Rym: let's go.
Scott: And as you play the game the game never stalls no matter what you do.
Scott: The game is always moving forward.
Scott: who knows where it's moving forward.
Scott: I don't know It could be going left right up down.
Rym: who knows you skip the boring parts and get to the dramatic.
Scott: Yes The game always moves forward towards wherever it's going and in D&D the game a lot of times stops.
Scott: I mean it stops when you have a combat that might in-game take five minutes of time.
Scott: You spent like two hours moving miniatures around and rolling a billion dice.
Rym: Yeah and playing all this meta game because combat in D&D is so meta.
Rym: it's a tactical miniatures game and you can't think in terms of what your character is thinking because you have to think in terms of Five footsteps and attacks of opportunity in burning wheel and a lot of other good systems like burning wheel particularly combat.
Rym: While it can be very complex It is still from the perspective of the character as opposed to from the perspective of the player.
Rym: You're not manipulating the five footsteps and doing the rules and figuring out if my fireball will be able to engulf all the goblins But not engulf Scott.
Rym: you say alright, I try to stab him because he's in front of me I try to hold back.
Rym: I try to faint.
Rym: it's all from the perspective of the character.
Rym: It's like a first-person view instead of a third-person view.
Rym: It's really hard to explain what I mean by that, but I hope you get the point.
Scott: You just buy the book and find out.
Rym: yeah, you can get into the characters head in combat and in role-playing.
Rym: in D&D It's very hard to stay in the character's head and still do the combat Especially since the combat takes an hour to resolve what takes a minute of game.
Scott: It's in the end.
Scott: D&D is a role-playing a tabletop role-playing system and it is possible to have excellent role-playing while using yes Don't come to us and say but we play D&D.
Scott: Well, it is possible But yes, but D&D is not conducive to role-playing.
Scott: It is not a catalyst of awesome role-playing.
Scott: don't in fact the opposite of a catalyst don't pretend of a catalyst than anti-catalysts hindrance.
Rym: D&D does not assist your role-playing in any real Tangible way.
Rym: D&D can be played well and with good role-playing But it takes so much discipline and you can't pretend that it's easy to maintain Good role-playing throughout an entire game or campaign of D&D.
Scott: It's not I can't do it.
Scott: But yeah, if you're looking for you know D&D doesn't also have the advantage that it's available everywhere and easily accessible Where it's.
Scott: pretty much every other RPG is much harder to find requiring a game store or worse or the Internet's or something or to get the books even.
Scott: but regardless D&D as a system for tabletop role-playing like you're trying to play roles and act and such is not so great and other things like burning wheel and even inspectors and It's a primetime adventures and all those other all those other games.
Rym: Listen to the Luke crane interview.
Rym: He talks about every game you should play.
Scott: They are much better at it.
Scott: They are conducive to role-playing and are not like D&D.
Rym: So why do we play D&D?
Rym: Personally, the only reason is that it is the lowest common denominator.
Rym: everyone knows how to play D&D or at least enough to where you've got the critical mass to just go with it and not Worry about teaching someone a new system.
Rym: but we're working very hard to eventually drop D&D entirely and just use burning wheel or a similar system.
Scott: and also if You're we are starting with people who have already been playing D&D for years.
Scott: We're already D&D geeks and we already own the books.
Scott: So it's actually it's very cheap for everyone to play it if you wanted to play something else.
Scott: Basically, it's not.
Scott: it would be easy if we had one person who already knew something else and could teach it to us.
Scott: But we're all sort of learning it together and it's quite difficult especially on a once a month basis to learn a new system because learning any role-playing system even a tiny one is Not as simple as like learning a board game.
Scott: We just learn the rules and then you follow the instructions.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Scott: it's a whole big learning experience and It's a lot of work and it takes time.
Scott: But if you haven't learned any systems already.
Rym: Go right to the burning wheel.
Rym: it it seems complicated.
Rym: just go with it.
Rym: I See the question in this show that we're just concluding right now was what's wrong with D&D?
Rym: And I think the answer Scott and I just came to was it's not burning wheel.
Scott: Yeah I'd wanted to.
Scott: I started out the episode not wanting to mention burning wheel so much and just keep mentioning what's wrong with D&D.
Scott: and but it's kind of hard once you've Seen the burning wheel and experienced it to get away from it.
Rym: Yeah, and it's not just burning wheel It's just that burning wheel was the first system We ran into.
Rym: that solved all the problems that we hadn't even realized were problems in D&D for the most part.
Rym: I mean all the problems I thought were with third ed.
Rym: that second ed did.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I was just stupid.
Scott: I'm sure there are plenty of other awesome systems out there that are akin to burning wheel and you know if I Experience them I would say oh, this is just as amazing.
Rym: I think part of it was the sheer force of Luke cranes Personality.
Scott: yes that and the fact that I do think that burning wheel is the biggest of these role-playing systems.
Scott: You know, it's sort of like, you know D&D gurps and all those big ones and then on the top of the indie pile is like burning wheels.
Scott: It's like the king of the indie RPGs and there's a reason it's the king of the indie RPGs.
Rym: So in this case, we don't say anything like this often.
Rym: But there's gonna be a forum thread about this show like there always is.
Rym: but I want to hear what you guys have to say About D&D and whether or not you agree with us.
Rym: I want to hear about your experiences.
Scott: We want that for every episode.
Rym: Yeah, but I want this particularly for this one because I'd like anyone to just tell us what you think about D&D.
Scott: Oh that reminds me anyone who joined the forum.
Scott: All right Yes, if you join the forum, you know the way our forum works.
Scott: You don't just join and then immediately you're in.
Scott: I have to click approve and usually I click approve within like 10 minutes of you Registering.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: We have not like the next morning.
Rym: If maybe you apply while I'm asleep We have only once ever denied someone entrance to the forum, right?
Scott: So the thing is is views hotmail.
Scott: when I approve you You're not gonna get the email that says you were approved because hotmail sucks and you should probably switch to Gmail.
Scott: But if you registered for the forums and you did not get an email that said Congratulations, you have been approved.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: Congratulations, you have been approved.
Scott: come back to the forums and sign in with whatever username and password you picked.
Scott: and also if you can't Remember username and password or if you're not sure you can just email GeekNights at front recruit.
Scott: I calm and I'll take care of you.
Rym: and also just a fair warning because a lot of people have been joining the forums lately.
Rym: we do have moderators and moderator.
Rym: well, we're getting more moderators because he's a little bit overtaxed now with all you newbies, but at least relatively adequate spelling and grammar are enforced.
Rym: You'll see when you go to our forums or forums are not like the rest of the internet and we take pride in that.
Scott: Yes, so and you start, you know spelling things wrong and not using their their their correctly.
Scott: And and you know, if you don't have commas you go here and and capitals, that's not good.
Scott: You need those things.
Rym: Yeah, I mean you can go over to the penny arcade forums or 4chan if you want to talk like that.
Rym: We're trying to make an ivory tower and we're trying to be elitist assholes here so go with it or get out.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit.
Scott: don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.