Rym: It's Thursday February 1st.
Rym: I'm Rym, and I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We talk about my experiences with jury duty.
Rym: Let's do this Now.
Rym: being a geek there is something that you'd assume.
Rym: you just assume that I would own A Leatherman.
Rym: well I do own one, but actually I own a Gerber not a Leatherman.
Scott: I need to get a Leatherman.
Scott: the thing is it too much money.
Rym: Yeah, they're not really so much money.
Scott: Well, I mean the thing is it's like yeah, you really need one, but then you look at it.
Scott: It's like $70 and you go man Okay one for 40 bucks.
Scott: Yeah, I don't like those ones.
Scott: the 70 I've looked and the minimum one is 70 bucks anyway.
Rym: But also more important than that even is the simple subtle Maglite.
Scott: you see a maglite is a very interesting device in that not only is it probably the best flashlight You can well the best non LED flashlight that you can easily obtain just about anywhere It is also perhaps the most practical bludgeon available in stores.
Rym: I mean granted it's nothing compared to that special flashlight in kryptonomic.
Rym: on now that I'm finally reading it good God know I want a galvanic Lucifer more than anything.
Scott: yeah Well the thing is you know you got the the 4d version there.
Rym: Yep, I got the 4d mag light.
Scott: the 8d mag light is far superior.
Rym: Well the thing is I don't need the 8d mag light.
Scott: Oh, no you do the same way.
Scott: you need no you know or gigahertz processor.
Scott: There's the different gigs of RAM.
Rym: I could have gotten the 2d But the 2d doesn't last as long and it's not as effective a bludgeon.
Rym: the 4d is an excellent bludgeon.
Rym: Lasts for freaking ever with the 4d batteries in it, and it's super bright.
Rym: Yeah Here's the difference between the 4d and the bigger ones The 4d and less if I'm just carrying it around with me.
Rym: It doesn't terribly arouse suspicion on its own and I can conceal it easily.
Rym: Merely carrying this 4d mag light does not in and of itself give a police officer probable cause to look for the rest of my burglars tools.
Rym: Now if I'm carrying the 8d mag light I'm definitely up to no good.
Scott: burglars did not use the 8d mag light.
Scott: burglars use what I have.
Scott: well not exactly what I have.
Scott: I have the single triple-a mag light.
Scott: It is so small.
Scott: Oh, man, someone could totally make innuendos about mag light size and yeah, but yeah well I'm holding my mag light right now, but the thing is my triple-a.
Scott: my single triple-a mag light is Bright silver and only a crook would get the black one.
Rym: ah yes Well, I got the black one because it's all RadioShack head, and I realized suddenly that one I have money.
Rym: Yeah, and I don't own a mag light three.
Rym: I need him.
Scott: I have two or three flashlights, but they're all shitty and They're shitty.
Scott: That's all I got to say.
Rym: well also considering that at ToraCon I'm kind of planning on skipping out on the con and Taking a bunch of people who missed it the first time through the Rochester subway again.
Scott: Yeah, you go do that.
Rym: Yeah, well I need a flashlight and a bludgeon for this and I've just killed two birds with one stone you have indeed.
Scott: Oh, when is ToraCon?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: spring right March something like coming up.
Scott: February's Katsucon at the end of February is newer comic-con if I go to it.
Rym: March ToraCon yeah, so I got to figure it out.
Rym: the uber cons cancelled right yep.
Rym: We're good after that.
Scott: There's no conventions until.
Rym: Well, I'm going summer.
Rym: Well.
Rym: There's a bunch of little ones.
Scott: I think oh, when's an amazement?
Rym: I don't know Otakon.
Scott: May sometime.
Scott: What else?
Rym: Otakon, Katsucon?
Scott: All of a sudden it feels like a bunch of cons disappeared.
Rym: Well no because we go to all those cons we forget about in the summer like Kinetic Con Anime.
Scott: next are you gonna go to Kinetic Con?
Rym: Yeah, well theoretically they said we could be staff, but they haven't gotten back with us, okay?
Scott: Anyway, so today.
Scott: I didn't go to work, but my work doesn't know that.
Scott: uh-huh instead I went to interview for another job.
Rym: How'd that go?
Scott: it went pretty well really yep, and I don't know I might take the job.
Scott: I might not.
Scott: who knows we'll see.
Rym: well Scott doing this cuz I my job's doing okay I mean the money isn't as much as I'd like and the jobs really kind of easy and not Particularly challenging.
Rym: I mean someone without my degree could do this job.
Rym: And I was thinking you know I should just get more money and work somewhere else.
Rym: And it looks like Scott just with zero effort was offered a lot more money.
Rym: Yep, I could probably also get offered a lot more money with zero.
Rym: We basically we could probably One point five X our income with almost no effort.
Scott: Yeah, well I will have to work more hours.
Scott: Oh you mean you'll actually have to work Yeah, and I'll still lose time on the train.
Scott: But I won't really lose time on the train.
Scott: cuz I'll get work done on the train like I did before.
Scott: Yeah, I do wasn't living a bad life when I was commuting before.
Scott: it'll be the same now.
Scott: So it's yeah.
Rym: well I mean riding the train as opposed to the car one.
Rym: if you're tired you can sleep.
Rym: Yep - you can do things other than listen to podcasts.
Scott: Yep I usually listen to podcasts while doing something else on the train depends on what I'm doing.
Scott: Yeah, it does.
Rym: You know what if I had a commute on a train I'd probably have a laptop, and I'd probably get a lot more GeekNights work done.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I might definitely make a promo CD like every week.
Scott: I'd need like a web server on the laptop there and stuff who knows I?
Scott: Definitely use the Bluetooth dial-up networking of my phone now anyway.
Scott: Yep of course.
Scott: I still have Some other job Prospects and as soon as I tie them all up.
Scott: I'll make a decision.
Rym: Yeah, I'm kind of waiting.
Scott: It's almost certain that there's gonna be some sort of a change at the bare minimum getting paid more money to do what I'm doing Already, I'm just kind of waiting for the one year anniversary of me being hired at my current job.
Rym: Cuz I assume there'll be some sort of performance approach even though in all the jobs I've had I've only ever once had any sort of formal or even informal performance appraiser.
Scott: You know what when I was a summer camp counselor that was when I had the most formal performance appraisals ever.
Scott: I actually had like graded you on different things like enthusiasm and and Attentiveness and all sorts of shit.
Rym: see they did that at RIT.
Scott: meanwhile at the job I'm working at now that I might not be working at too much longer It basically when I was one year into it.
Scott: They were just like yeah You're doing a great job.
Scott: Here's more money.
Rym: Well, they did that to me at RIT once and they gave me all these grades on how good I was and how smartly Dressed I was and whatever and then they bought me a lunch and then I quit that day.
Rym: I have a lot more experience quitting jobs than getting jobs.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Scott: I've never quit a job Really?
Rym: Well, yeah, you've really only worked for this one company since you got out of.
Scott: so I work.
Scott: I've worked for a lot of things.
Scott: I was kind of fired once From why Remember when I worked at that?
Scott: Well, I work freshman year of RIT.
Scott: I worked at Crossroads, right?
Scott: Yeah, and then sophomore year right away.
Scott: I got a job working in Like the student services office of the art school.
Rym: Yeah, you had that job for a while kind of like how I had that IT job, right?
Scott: I worked in that office and it was cool.
Scott: then as soon as the summer came around I kept that job But instead I used.
Scott: I was working like two different student services offices for the two halves of the art school but then in the summer I just got stuck in one half and not the other and then Someone who had had that job previously decided to come back in the summer.
Scott: So they're just like, yeah All right, we'll let that person work instead of you.
Scott: We like them better.
Scott: so Wow, but then base it wasn't really sort of a like a firing because it was like There's someone else downstairs in another office and you could work for them and I worked for them the rest of the time I was at RIT except for when I was like co-op.
Rym: Well, I mean I worked at the Ritz and then I quit.
Rym: Yeah, I was just not working.
Scott: you worked at the Bellas and then you quit.
Rym: Yeah, I worked at that factory.
Rym: one day.
Scott: This is gonna be the first time I've ever gone and been like I'm.
Scott: you know, I mean I've left jobs But it's never been like I'm leaving prematurely.
Rym: Anyway, so we don't go too long tonight since we keep seem to be going long fairly often on the show lately.
Scott: Yeah, Oh lips and thing has never filled up.
Scott: even though we seem to go long every time.
Rym: We've got about a hundred megabyte buffer at any given moment.
Scott: now that sounds good because I was alright because I remember doing Calculations and it always came out to where we were gonna be way in the hole or living on the edge.
Scott: But if we're not that's cool.
Rym: What calculations were you doing?
Rym: when?
Scott: megabytes per episode.
Rym: We're using to calculate megabytes per episode.
Rym: how many megabytes you think?
Rym: the average episode of GeekNights is now 40 50 60 45 50 at the absolute most.
Scott: All right, it's not that big.
Scott: So what is the?
Rym: anyway, whatever it doesn't matter.
Rym: in the news a Roman treasure has been discovered and I am all a twitter about this.
Scott: a Roman treasure.
Scott: you say yeah, they found pirate universe.
Rym: Um, not at all.
Rym: Anyway Apparently they've discovered a bunch of the various artifacts from Maxentius who you may remember from the Battle of the Milvian Bridge, which is where Christianity and paganism had their essential final stand.
Scott: Wait, but they won.
Rym: There's no Maxentius lost.
Scott: No, I'm saying Christianity still here.
Rym: Yeah, cuz constant it was this last stand between the two.
Rym: one of them was going to fall.
Rym: It's more complicated than that But essentially Maxentius was the Emperor and Constantine wanted to be the Emperor.
Rym: and Constantine wasn't a Christian But he liked Christianity for various reasons.
Rym: so he eventually won the battle due to Maxentius foolishly putting his troops in front of a bridge and then trying to retreat over the bridge and then just basically being Slaughtered while he was trying to retreat over the bridge.
Scott: Those bridges there.
Scott: whenever there's a war game or some sort of tactical game bridges are so important.
Scott: Advance Wars bridge is so important.
Scott: You know, it's just.
Scott: how could you be so dumb?
Rym: Yeah, but anyway They found a bunch of cool Roman bits and I think this is really neat and I really don't have anything more to say about It.
Rym: I see if you want to learn more about Rome You should listen to the best podcast ever made 12 Byzantine emperors.
Scott: You mean not GeekNights?
Rym: No, we're number two.
Scott: Okay so this is old news very old news, but it seems a lot of people don't know it because Well, it was on the guard.
Scott: it was in the Guardian Unlimited on January 16.
Scott: Oh 2003 okay, so it is very old news, but it was just on dig recently because apparently people never heard.
Rym: Well, never mind the fact that we've talked about this at least three times on GeekNights.
Scott: Have we really?
Rym: Yes I don't remember that we never used a main bit for it, but we have talked about this more than once.
Scott: Okay, okay, cuz I don't remember us ever talking about it.
Scott: I want to talk about bananas.
Scott: Bananas are gonna be extinct probably.
Rym: Well, the thing is they've been saying that for a long time and they haven't become.
Scott: let's see this was in 2003 and they said in ten years time and it's been four years and Bananas in the store ain't what they used to be.
Rym: So, I don't know.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: They're the same Cavendish banana.
Scott: They are but you know, like the stores aren't restocking as much.
Scott: Yeah, they are I don't know.
Rym: I don't know where you're getting this.
Rym: the bananas at the store near us have been the same as they always are.
Rym: Anyway, they're a little more green lately, but that's probably just because it's winter.
Rym: They're always a little more green in the winter.
Scott: No, I guess I never realized stuff like that.
Rym: Yeah, but bananas are the same.
Rym: There's no difference in the banana supply as far as we're concerned here.
Scott: downstate, New York Yes, but well, I guess now this is new 2003.
Scott: The only thing.
Scott: well, okay Let me sum up the banana story just for anyone did it hasn't heard it before?
Scott: on GeekNights Cuz Rym seems to think we said this before.
Rym: we talk about this a lot both on GeekNights and in our daily lives.
Scott: Yeah, anyway back in the day the type of banana that was most common was the gross me hell banana Which I really want to try.
Rym: I've never had one.
Scott: I never had one either But the commercial banana plantations were devastated in the 50s because there was a Panama disease And the Panama disease killed the gross me hell.
Scott: There is still some out there probably but not many.
Rym: Well, the reason it was such a bad plague was mostly due to the fact that the gross me Cal was effectively a monoculture.
Rym: So if there was something that would kill one it would kill all of them and spread easily.
Scott: Yes, because bananas, you know, they didn't grow them from seeds.
Scott: the way normal plants grow the the banana trees You know, they would just split off other banana trees and they're basically all clones with the same exact genetics.
Rym: Yeah, they basically originally bred them because people don't like having seeds in their bananas.
Rym: They wanted them to have as few seeds and the smallest seeds as possible and eventually Bananas just basically didn't have any seeds at all in them.
Scott: Yep Anyway, so the gross me hell died out mostly but the Cavendish Happened to not get killed by this Panama disease the cat.
Rym: the Cavendish is also a monoculture and it became the dominant Banana at least in America.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The Cavendish banana is the banana you eat today But only the only reason we still have them is because we spray fungicide on them 40 times a year.
Rym: Not just that but there are crazy rules about banana plantations.
Scott: There are crazy rules and it's apparently the number one threat is this Sigatoka fungus that will eat all the bananas in if we don't eat them first.
Scott: Now what's the solution?
Scott: Well, we can try to get bananas to evolve again.
Rym: Basically, the only solution up until now when someone did some trickery that Scott's gonna talk about Was to try to genetically engineer seeds back into the Cavendish or to genetically engineer Cavendish's that are immune to this disease Which a lot of people are against any genetically modified food and there's a lot of trouble with that as a result.
Rym: So that really wasn't an option people.
Scott: But anyway, this is a story from 2003.
Scott: But some Honduran scientists peeled and sieved 400 tons of bananas and they found 15 seeds for breeding.
Rym: Yeah, I mean think about it It's not perfect that they bred the seeds out so odds are every now and then a seed might just accidentally get formed Mm-hmm.
Scott: But yeah, this is why Cloning is bad and Darwin was right.
Rym: Well, the cloning isn't necessarily not necessarily bad.
Scott: But if your species consists entirely of clones and there is no Darwinian evolution and DNA You know mutation going on anywhere.
Scott: That's not good.
Rym: Well, if you're a monoculture then whatever one of you is weak against you're all a week again.
Scott: Imagine if every person on earth had the same DNA because we were all clones of this one banana plant somewhere.
Scott: Well, if some bacteria finds a sort of plus-five against human Rude the fact that we have all these different DNA, you know.
Scott: Sure, a bunch of people over there have one horrible condition and other people over there have a horrible condition.
Scott: But as a whole we're gonna keep going.
Rym: Yeah, I mean even the bubonic plague.
Rym: it killed a lot of people but there were also people who survived it.
Rym: Yep, all right, of course that might have had more to do with hygiene.
Scott: and But hygiene I think you could link it back to DNAs, you know only the smart people.
Scott: because because the DNA made us have bigger brains and then we were smart We were able to think of hygiene Etc.
Rym: I'm not gonna touch that statement because I don't think the people who had better hygiene during the Middle Ages were particularly more evolved Physiologically than the people who didn't.
Scott: huh, perhaps but they are.
Scott: But they were more evolved than the people from before the Middle Ages who did not have high.
Rym: Oh, you mean the Romans who had excellent hygiene?
Scott: Yeah with their vomitoriums.
Rym: Yes, the vomitoriums.
Rym: you actually know what the vomitoriums were used for prevalent They were or what their purpose actually.
Scott: even if there was only one of them and it wasn't like I think it was there was Still vomit everywhere.
Rym: Well, what's wrong with the vomit?
Scott: You can't tell me.
Scott: the Colosseum was had the good hygiene.
Scott: they didn't Wob the swab those gladiators with the antiseptic before they got bit by lions.
Rym: However, you know what the Romans had that a lot of people in the midget Middle Ages didn't.
Rym: aqueducts running water sewers.
Rym: Yeah bads.
Rym: Taking bads is probably the most important part of civilization.
Rym: as far as I'm concerned.
Scott: The Vikings did not take that.
Rym: I go to anime cons and I will tell you now if you do not bathe You're not evolved.
Rym: Oh burn things of the day.
Rym: So one of the biggest problems I have in my life and I don't have many anymore.
Scott: Is that what you got problems?
Rym: You just don't know when I do my laundry, right?
Rym: I gotta you know Keep track of what time I put it in and I gotta go take my laundry out at the right time And I have to plan around when I'm doing laundry, especially if I have to go to a laundromat.
Scott: Yeah, I think a biggest problem we have is that we have a washer but not a dryer.
Scott: So it's a wash a whole bunch of clothes.
Scott: carry them to a laundromat dry them all then bring them back.
Rym: Absolutely fine because I really don't want to put my clothes in those industrial washers me either.
Scott: But I do wish I could just put them in my own dryer in my own house.
Rym: Well, we could have a dryer but you don't seem to think we can fit one in there.
Scott: I don't think we can fit what we can.
Rym: it'll be a tight fit, but it'll fit.
Scott: I don't think we can fit one.
Rym: Anyway, well the thing is There's some interesting good news and some interesting really kind of stupid news all rolled into one here.
Rym: What?
Rym: Apparently there's a school not gonna go in any details because no one cares where this happened or what school or what companies or anything.
Rym: But for the school at this university, they set up a system where when your laundry is dry You can set it up so that the dryer will email you telling you that your laundry is ready.
Scott: Oh, that is awesome.
Rym: That's really awesome.
Rym: Plus one.
Rym: I want that in every washer or dryer ever.
Rym: Here's the problem.
Scott: I'm gonna quote from the IMU though or text message because email you might not be checking it.
Rym: No, because you could have it email a computer.
Scott: that does something you could you could but you see my point.
Scott: I want or at least you should have the option to also do IMs text messages, etc.
Rym: I just want any sort of Electronic notification, but here's the problem.
Rym: quotes the school paid for the $13,000 annual software fee dot-dot-dot By raising the load of laundry about 50 cents.
Rym: the cost.
Rym: see apparently there's this company called laundry view monitoring service and They provide this to colleges and it's a total scam.
Rym: They set up a system where the laundry machine will email you.
Scott: which god That's such a trivial system.
Scott: If you paid me you could pay me almost nothing.
Scott: I could set that up.
Scott: Yeah, and you know what make it happen.
Rym: even here's the better part.
Rym: This doesn't require any ongoing maintenance.
Rym: You set it up.
Rym: It's done forever yet.
Rym: They charge $13,000 a year and Stupid stupid stupid universities like you know what I will call about the University of Iowa will pay this.
Scott: Oh Iowa there They're all dumb over there.
Rym: They'll pay this.
Rym: Hello, Iowa for a service That is effectively something I could write with a bash script and a serial port and a breadboard in about a day.
Scott: Yeah, I could make this and set the whole thing up and you would only have to pay me once.
Scott: I would use all open-source software.
Scott: It'd be amazing and perfect.
Scott: I would need one server.
Scott: That would be like $300.
Rym: there seems to be more and more.
Rym: this problem of colleges will purchase Absolutely stupid services for their students.
Scott: Well, no, it seems to be a problem all around of all sorts of businesses whether they be Academic service providers or otherwise, you know buying things that are ludicrously expensive Or overpriced because they don't know any better, you know I mean you could do pretty powerful things with technology nowadays, you know, very simple technology.
Scott: I could take something really cheap and really simple and do something amazing with it.
Scott: And if I sell you just that one feature You'll be amazed.
Scott: so amazed you're willing to pay a pile of money for it Even though you don't realize it's not that amazing a feat, you know, and there's a lot of scamming going on.
Rym: Well, I've universities in particular.
Rym: one have a captive audience and they have money to burn That's.
Rym: or when they don't they don't have money to burn per se but they have money That's always available to.
Rym: you know, help out the students and they usually these systems will set up something where?
Rym: You take a cut and we'll take a cut kind of like speed trap cameras.
Rym: Yep, I remember RIT fell into that.
Rym: with one of those students can download music for free services.
Rym: We just have to raise tuition a little bit.
Scott: Yeah I'm sure that every time students go to Iowa to see if they want to become student enroll there that the school is gonna be Like hey, you know, we're so cool.
Scott: are washing machines email you when they're done?
Rym: Yeah, and then you know when the students ask oh, how do they do that?
Rym: And the answer is we pay thirteen thousand dollars a year for what's probably a Windows 95 box and some cereal parts.
Rym: Yeah Yeah Yeah, so that's all I got.
Scott: So for anyone who did not know the car from the first Ghostbusters movie the Ecto one That car is a 1959 Cadillac.
Scott: I did not know that me either but now I do.
Scott: well Did you know that that car was also used in the movie?
Scott: The heat of the night.
Rym: I've never even seen that movie.
Scott: There's a movie called in the heat of the night starring Sidney Pottier and Rod Steiger and This car was in it before.
Scott: it was in Ghostbusters.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: It wasn't in its Ghostbusters form.
Scott: It was heavily modified for Ghostbusters.
Scott: Oh, so whatever Yes, it's a very famous car.
Scott: apparently when they were moving the Ecto one from one place to another One time they did it on You know an open truck as opposed to a closed truck and it screwed up traffic because everyone stopped to look at it.
Rym: I can see that I would stop to look at it.
Rym: Yep I'd stop and take a picture and then of course steal it.
Scott: It seems to be in in perfect working order and it draws lots of crowds whenever it's available at auto shows And that makes perfect sense.
Rym: I should buy it.
Scott: you can.
Scott: you can purchase the Original and only Ecto one the one used in the first Ghostbusters movie the Cadillac 1959 Cadillac for a hundred and forty nine thousand nine hundred ninety eight For a lot less money than that.
Rym: I could make a car that looked almost like it.
Scott: Well, it'd be tough to get the 59 Cadillac.
Scott: But I imagine the 59 Cadillac that isn't Ecto one would be less than a hundred and fifty thousand.
Scott: the modifications I don't know.
Scott: It might be you.
Scott: it'd be tough to figure out exactly what they modified to get it exactly to nerd specification.
Rym: Most people you could probably make a car that looked half like the Ghostbusters thing And they think it was amazing.
Scott: People are really easily fooled about things like that partly because only the nerds would say hey your car does not have the Ecto Tank.
Scott: blabbe blabbe blah on it, obviously, you know, but there aren't many Ghostbusters nerds.
Scott: No, they're alright.
Scott: Well the thing the only thing you really need to get right on the Ghostbusters car is get the logo on the side.
Scott: You gotta have the thing on the roof and you got to make it so that when you open up the back the the hatch In the back that all the power packs slide out that you can put them on Three things you need for the Ghostbusters.
Rym: You don't need that.
Rym: You just don't stop.
Rym: you just drive around town cruising.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know that I would notice that and I don't know all the Specifications that was missing.
Rym: How would you notice?
Scott: because that's the.
Scott: those are the three cool features of the Ecto one.
Rym: so if the real Ecto one's there and they just don't decide to open up the back and show you I can look In the rear window and see that the power packs are not in there.
Rym: What if I have the power packs in there, but they just don't slide out?
Scott: Huh, yeah, you might fool me.
Scott: I'd ask though and I'd say yes They slide out and then I believe you because it's your Ecto one and you paid $150,000 you have the right to lie, even though I probably actually paid half that and have a fake everything.
Scott: Yeah Those are the three key features of the Ecto one.
Rym: Yeah, I always liked the Ecto one.
Rym: It's a little kid.
Rym: I had a model of it and I loved it and one day I threw it down the stairs and it broke.
Scott: I didn't have one.
Rym: I threw it down the stairs as hard as I could.
Scott: someone else.
Scott: I knew had a big one I think I was simulating.
Scott: you could be action figures in.
Scott: it was so big.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I was pretty big and I put action figures in it and I threw it down the stairs.
Rym: I was simulating some sort of horrible car accident.
Rym: Good job, and I believe everyone died.
Rym: Okay, so this week I had the wonderful experience of going to jury duty And I thought I'd talk about that a bit.
Rym: since we've talked about juries jury nullification Drug laws all those sorts of things fairly often on GeekNights And now that I've actually gone through the civil process I am a little bit scared that I will ever be put in front of a jury.
Scott: Well, I've never had jury duty, but I know about as much about it as the average person.
Rym: Well now that I have gone to jury duty.
Rym: I've learned a number of truths.
Rym: But first I'll just tell the story of exactly what happened.
Rym: So I call Sunday night and they say you don't have to show up on Monday.
Rym: Whatever I go to work I called Monday night and they say hello you have to come in on Tuesday.
Rym: So I show up at 930 which meant I could wake up at like eight forty five eight fifty Which was great.
Rym: Normally I have to wake up at six to get to work.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: So I take the day off work.
Rym: I take a leisurely train up to Poughkeepsie.
Rym: now I'm kind of miffed that I have to pay for parking.
Rym: I have to pay for transportation.
Rym: I drive to the train station.
Rym: I'm looking for a parking space and I see a guy pulling out of a really close one.
Rym: So as I'm driving up he rolls down his window, so I'm expecting him to be along the lines of hey I'm gonna be right back.
Rym: Don't take my spot or something instead.
Rym: He says hey, man I'm out of here that space is paid for.
Rym: have a nice day and I was like you're the man.
Rym: I park I buy my little two-trip train ticket and I get my way for the train.
Rym: get on the train.
Rym: No one ever takes the train north from Beacon to Poughkeepsie out a week morning.
Scott: Well, there are a few people but no not many now.
Scott: I've seen people do it.
Rym: I was the only one as far as I can tell and they didn't.
Rym: I didn't even see a conductor I didn't even need my ticket.
Rym: No, you didn't so I got your.
Scott: I think it's only two dollars anyway, right?
Rym: It was five fifty four.
Scott: Oh, I thought it was much cheaper than that.
Rym: No, no Anyway, so I didn't have to pay.
Rym: so I had this train ticket that was unused Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I get there and I go in and I'm confronted one by the fact that I'm the only one who showed up on time Really?
Scott: Eventually about I think if you're gonna show up to jury duty you'd show up on time.
Rym: Oh a few people showed up on time, but a lot of people showed up after 930.
Scott: Wow Like we're talking 945.
Scott: We're talking 1030 here.
Rym: They're like five to ten minutes.
Rym: I showed up early a little bit because I was afraid that something bad would happen if I was late.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Well five to ten minutes isn't really a big deal Yeah.
Rym: So I think they planned on starting everything at ten and the Commissioner of Jurors for the county or whatever comes out and introduces How do you get that job?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Maybe it's elected maybe now.
Rym: They also went to great pains to explain that normally they would pay for your parking.
Rym: In fact, they'd love to give us free parking but apparently the County of Dutchess and the state of New York have a very Adversarial relationship with the city of Poughkeepsie and the city refuses to accommodate the courts in any way.
Scott: the town of Poughkeepsie school But the city sucks.
Rym: the town of Poughkeepsie is very upscale and very nice.
Rym: We couldn't afford to live in many places in it.
Rym: Even now.
Rym: All right, the city of Poughkeepsie is essentially a hellhole.
Rym: I think God we.
Rym: we went up to a heavy metal show in Poughkeepsie one time and They were like woo Poughkeepsie and no one really cheered.
Rym: and then they're like, where are y'all from?
Rym: and everyone is from out of town.
Scott: Yeah, they're like who's from Poughkeepsie like three people like whoo.
Rym: Yeah, and it was in Poughkeepsie and the band was like what like.
Scott: imagine if you went to a show in say Chicago And you're like, yeah, Chicago.
Scott: Whoo rock and roll people be like, yeah It'd be like who here's from Chicago and most people would be like me You know, you'd ask who's not from Chicago and three guys would go.
Scott: Whoo It was totally backwards in Poughkeepsie.
Rym: Yeah, plus there's all those sculptures on Main Street.
Rym: Yeah Poughkeepsie's not the most happening city at all.
Scott: It's definitely it used to be happening half a century ago and now not so much.
Rym: But I go in and I have to fill out this little form that basically says I assert that I'm not a felon That blah blah blah felons can't be on juries.
Rym: No that I'm a US unless you have a a God the thing that waives your civil disability You know.
Scott: if the consequences of being a felon weren't so much I might be inclined to commit felony to avoid jury duty.
Rym: Uh, not really because I learned something really important.
Rym: I'll say that in a minute I'll go through the whole story because the thing I learned really frightens me, but alright, so we sit down.
Rym: There's all 500 people and this woman walks up and she's like the assistant.
Rym: She's the deputy commissioner of jurors and she explains what's going on.
Rym: She thanks us all for coming.
Rym: She makes a nice joke about how you know, even though you didn't really have a choice.
Scott: Wait a second.
Scott: There's a deputy commissioner of jurors.
Rym: I will say this the two people are running the show of the the deputy and the real guy.
Rym: They look like they have to run all this on a shoestring budget and despite that they were very cheery and very cool.
Scott: Well, I mean, yeah, but you're their job every day is to deal with a whole bunch of jury people.
Rym: There's a lot of crime.
Scott: Okay, I was like this two people to do that job.
Scott: How do I get the deputy job?
Rym: Yeah, so then they explain that there's judge Hayes is gonna have a trial and judge Hayes.
Rym: this trial could last two weeks If not more.
Rym: it's gonna be a big deal.
Scott: What happened to the right to a speedy trial?
Rym: So well see the right to a speedy trial is often interpreted from what I've heard as a right to Begin your trial within a reasonable span of time.
Rym: Anyway, so and then she basically says this trial could last up to two weeks maybe more probably last about two weeks.
Rym: Is there anyone who doesn't think they could commit to a two-week trial?
Rym: and Almost everyone raises their hand.
Rym: Of course, and I actually didn't raise my hand cuz I thought it'd be kind of cool.
Rym: I don't really care.
Rym: I'm interested in the process Alright, but then we break up into groups and I you know, I look at my calendar and I realized that Even though my work could not technically penalize me for going to jury duty.
Rym: I am at least going to fill out the form Stating all the possible problems that might be caused by me going to jury duty.
Rym: That way I could at least say that I put forth my due diligence Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I signed this little form that says is there any conceivable reason you couldn't serve on a jury this long?
Rym: And I basically just said here's what my job is.
Rym: I just said my job description and that's it and I didn't.
Rym: I expected them to say that's not an excuse.
Rym: get back in there and She looks at me and she says alright your job is obviously important.
Rym: You can go home and I said what?
Rym: She said yeah There's no reason we'd have you serve on a jury Because my job is important enough to where it's not worth taking me away from it.
Scott: for a jury I Rym if you didn't go to work for say a month, right, but they kept.
Scott: you kept your job.
Scott: Let's say you took a month's vacation, right?
Scott: What would anything bad happen?
Rym: I Bad things would happen.
Rym: I mean projects wouldn't fail.
Rym: the company would go on as it did before.
Rym: I think a lot of projects would happen a lot slower and there'd be a lot of problems.
Rym: just cuz I I Mean on a larger scale in the grand scheme of the world me not going to work like people wouldn't die.
Rym: No, because I'm not support for all that hospital stuff.
Scott: Yeah all right So but no.
Rym: and basically what I got out of this and from looking at the other excuses people were giving was that if you?
Rym: Have a job of any note whatsoever if your job is Anything at all they'll excuse you like that.
Rym: Wow, and it seems like the only people who they would even allow to serve on a jury are the people who want to be There.
Rym: and the only people who really really want to be there are the people who don't have anything better to be doing.
Scott: Who wants to be there?
Scott: I mean, I guess if you have no job or
Rym: Well, actually all the people who work
Scott: at McDonald's
Rym: all the people who were in the room with me doing me fill out the form That says why you might not be able to commit to this trial They were all basically mumbling or saying to themselves or saying to each other the same thing I want to do it I want to be here.
Rym: This is important, but I just have too much to do in my role in my life.
Rym: I don't have time for this.
Rym: hmm, and it seems like the if your excuses.
Rym: I have a job.
Rym: That's enough.
Scott: Yeah, actually I kind of feel the same way.
Scott: It's like surfing on a jury might be interesting and entertaining and fun And they're you know, it'd be pretty cool.
Scott: go see some court, you know decide someone's fate.
Scott: Oh, you know good stuff.
Rym: Yeah, in fact the trials I was up for.
Scott: if it takes two weeks I don't have time for that.
Rym: that that like mess up my whole business especially since by law Jury duty is totally a sucker's bet.
Rym: if you'd aside from being a juror and all the goodness of that They'll pay you 40 bucks a day only if your employer doesn't pay you that 40 bucks.
Rym: And your employer while they can't fire you for going to jury duty is not obligated to accommodate you in any way pay you or Anything other than the first $40 of your salary if you make less.
Scott: So if I was at a two-week jury Assuming I didn't get paid for those two weeks.
Scott: I'd basically lose half of my month's salary.
Scott: I only get paid twice a month So I'd lose one.
Rym: I'd lose a whole paycheck and you'd get 40 bucks a day from the state.
Scott: And you know what I'd be disastrous.
Rym: after the first three days your employer doesn't even have to pay you that 40 bucks anymore.
Rym: Even worse when I got the summons.
Rym: now, this is what something that really pisses me off one.
Rym: the summons Obviously wanted to be a Netflix kind of envelope, but they didn't want to violate any copyright or patents.
Rym: So they made this ghetto thing.
Rym: that didn't work at all - they don't give you free return postage.
Rym: You have to buy a stamp and stick it on.
Rym: the summons.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: Wait a second.
Scott: that makes me think of something.
Scott: it really shouldn't be illegal for The government to infringe on Intellectual properties.
Scott: and you know, it's like the government wants to make a Netflix envelope.
Scott: Why shouldn't they?
Rym: well actually Scott The basis of modern American industry comes from the fact that our government pointedly ignored copyright law in order to steal Anything of note from the Industrial Revolution from Europe?
Scott: Yeah, yeah, we.
Rym: our country has a fine history of pirating for the greater good of ourselves.
Scott: It's like, you know if some guy, you know invents Let's say a pharmaceutical company invents an amazing drug, right?
Scott: They have a right to sell it and keep other companies from making it and all that.
Scott: But if there's some sort of need for it because usually you don't want the government involving itself in business, you know.
Scott: But if there's like a sudden outbreak the government should be allowed to mass-produce that shit all at once.
Rym: But anyway, yeah Here's the even worse part.
Rym: The only notice that I am going to be on a jury is the summons that comes about a week and a half Before I'm supposed to show up.
Rym: Now it comes just normal mail.
Rym: I have often gone out of town for two weeks or more.
Rym: If I had happened to have been out of town when this arrived like say this arrived the Wednesday before Otakon, right?
Rym: I would have come back from Otakon in the shore to find that I had violated the law by not showing up to a jury Duty summons.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: So if you go on vacation jury, I'm sure that if you were on vacation that we know when they came to get you You would say I didn't get the man.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: They don't come to get you they just basically Do bad things to you and that basically they warn you.
Rym: if you don't show up your credit rating could suffer You.
Scott: there'll be a warrant possibly sure that when you get back you say I got this.
Scott: I just got it in the mail today.
Scott: I was on vacation.
Scott: His proof.
Scott: I was on vacation the whole time.
Rym: I mean, you're not obligated to get your mail every day.
Rym: What if you just don't get your mail for a while?
Rym: What if you just you don't have any proof that you were on vacation?
Rym: What if you're just at your mom's house and she wasn't there?
Rym: you were just bumming there for a month?
Scott: I have no idea.
Rym: It's just it's kind of annoying that they they don't really think these things through now.
Rym: But the one nice thing Even though I had to call this number every night to find out if I had to show up the next day They had the call-in message on the website.
Rym: So I just go to the website every night.
Scott: Oh, that's cool.
Rym: Yeah, that was kind of cool.
Scott: That was the government actually taking advantage.
Scott: technology amazing.
Rym: now I noticed two interesting things when I showed up.
Rym: The first thing was that most people seem to be at least minimally smart.
Rym: They were smart enough to understand the instructions of jury duty and to show up.
Rym: About 10% of the people there just totally fucked it up.
Rym: They just had no idea what was going on and they couldn't follow the simple instructions.
Rym: There are people who showed up and the Pearson was like didn't you call the call-in number?
Rym: We said specifically you don't have to show up and their excuse wasn't.
Rym: Oh, I didn't call the number or oh Whatever their excuse was.
Rym: basically I didn't understand the call-in message So I figured I should come in.
Rym: The call-in message was effectively if your number is between 1 and 500 come in tomorrow at 930.
Rym: Wow, yeah, the other thing I noticed was that the average a what do you think the average age of the people there was?
Scott: It's probably mostly older people.
Rym: I think the average age was over 50.
Rym: I There was one girl who looked like she was like 14 So you may have just barely turned 18. and there's this one kid who looked like he was 19 And then I was the next youngest person and every single other person was at least in the late 30s.
Rym: And what most of them looked like they were in their 40s or 50s and this is out of about 600 people.
Scott: I guess I know that I probably should you know, my odds of getting jury duty increase as I get older.
Rym: Well, also it seems interesting that the most jurors are old.
Rym: I mean, it's just that this area has a lot of old people.
Rym: a lot of people though had to drive an hour or more To get to this court.
Scott: Oh, wow.
Scott: We only had to drive like 20 minutes to get to.
Rym: well Remember it's a county court and a state court And in fact one of the cases that I almost was on selection for was for a state Supreme Court case that could have gone On forever.
Scott: Yeah, don't just the thing is in New York State.
Scott: It's weird because the Supreme Court of New York State is the lowest state court.
Scott: It's it's totally backwards.
Rym: Yeah, no I have.
Scott: it's like if you commit a state crime The first court you go to is the state Supreme Court.
Rym: There was a chance.
Rym: I had a suspicion that one of the trials that was gonna go on was the crazy murder case that happened in Fishkill.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: I think that might be coming up soon.
Scott: I don't think it was one of those.
Rym: Yeah, well the thing is it sounds like the big case.
Rym: they were doing the jury selection well ahead of the case and it was The.
Rym: even the Commissioner couldn't really tell us anything about it.
Scott: So maybe they were getting ready for it because they knew it was gonna come in the future.
Rym: Now they also made a point of telling everyone very specifically not to talk at all while we were there about anything to anyone.
Scott: No, oh you mean anything that related to?
Rym: no just don't have Conversations among yourselves until the trial itself because you don't want anyone to have any sort of pre-existing relationship.
Scott: Oh Okay, so you can't even like say hi.
Scott: How you doing?
Scott: My name is Rym.
Rym: now the other Living.
Scott: that's nice.
Scott: How's the weather?
Rym: most people didn't seem to bring any form of entertainment with them?
Rym: And they basically just sat there quietly.
Scott: Whoa, it seems like they didn't have anything like magazines there anything.
Rym: Well, here's what I saw.
Scott: It seems like there was this paper.
Rym: The older a person was the less likely it was that they had anything with him at all Except all the old people brought their own pens and paper and all that stuff.
Rym: They brought supplies For I don't know jury duty, but they didn't bring any form of entertainment.
Rym: The younger the person was the more likely were to have something Mode.
Rym: by and large people had like New York Post's and just you know little newspapers and magazines.
Rym: I was the only person in the room who had a book.
Scott: Did you see a DS?
Rym: Didn't see a single video game system.
Scott: I didn't play a game on a cell phone.
Rym: Nope I saw nothing but like newspapers and magazines.
Rym: I had a book and another book and my One woman.
Rym: actually they were explaining You know what you can do during a trial and she asked if there was any way we could get internet access over the lunch To check on our stuff and the answer was basically internet Blackberries, uh, I didn't see any.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: My aunt went to court For a jury duty like a while ago and she said they had like a little room with some computers that had some internet access.
Scott: Oh, we didn't.
Scott: you could use while you were waiting like, you know, there are only a few of them.
Scott: But because he doesn't have anything they had that something.
Rym: actually the lady said to the woman Well, if you have a laptop and you can find a jack that works or a wireless signal go nuts.
Rym: Yeah, okay.
Rym: She didn't know.
Rym: like there were jacks all over the room and she didn't know what they were.
Rym: Alrighty then I thought about inspecting them, but I didn't want to draw attention to myself by standing up and poking around the room.
Scott: Yeah, then you would have a pre-existing relationship.
Rym: You got a weird guy.
Rym: Yeah, I I was weird.
Rym: Anyway God Everyone there was.
Rym: so it's hard.
Rym: I don't know how I could explain it.
Rym: I mean, I'm not I don't want to be derogatory but everyone was so just totally mundane.
Scott: No one had anything interesting other than the 19 year old did have something interesting But they couldn't because they couldn't talk to you.
Rym: Oh, yeah I mean, I'm not saying they weren't interesting people possibly but there was.
Rym: everyone looked so generic like it.
Scott: Maybe the process is working like the process is supposed to make you.
Rym: I stood out like a sore thumb.
Rym: I'm a guy with a day stubble long hair Untied wearing a trench coat carrying the god delusion and kryptonomicon playing a DS with earrings Awesome.
Rym: Everyone else was like frumpy wearing, you know, just boring normal clothes.
Rym: Everyone had like a standard jacket.
Rym: They were all.
Rym: anyone who talked at all when they walked in was just making small talk about the weather.
Scott: So what happened next?
Rym: Well, they sent me home because I have a job and then and then I was on call for the rest Of the week.
Rym: I have might I have to find out if I'm gonna show up tomorrow for my last day But regardless I have fulfilled my duty and I am not eligible for jury duty again for six years.
Scott: So what what's?
Scott: how old do you know?
Scott: 25?
Scott: Yeah, so when I'm 31.
Rym: So now here's the thing.
Rym: when I'm 31 I will have at least the same kind of job I have now if not a more important job.
Rym: I cannot serve on a jury unless they change the rules or maybe the people who make these decisions change the way they decide.
Rym: but Basically I was told that because of my line of work I am free to leave jury duty at any time.
Scott: Well, you know who could go on juries.
Scott: like the immediate thing is like, okay The people were probably gonna be on juries or people who don't have jobs like homemakers or whatever people who work at shit jobs like McDonald's or Unimportant jobs, but also really rich people who don't do anything but live off their richness.
Rym: Oh if I was rich, I would have stuck around and tried to get on that jury.
Scott: Yeah, so it's it's kind of weird.
Scott: It's like people would you know?
Scott: normal productive people?
Scott: You know the kind of people that are probably peers are the kind of people that are least likely to end up on juries.
Scott: Yes, Lee is gonna be poor people and rich idle people, you know I'm gonna sound horrible.
Rym: and I'm saying this more to be funny than to make an actual point if a jury for a crime is going to be a jury of your peers and Generally lower-class poor people are gonna be on juries That might just be a jury of your peers in most cases.
Rym: Yeah Considering crime demographics.
Scott: Yeah, but if someone like me goes to you know, have a trial.
Scott: here's a skipping jury duty.
Rym: Here's another interesting thing that I noticed.
Rym: there were almost no black people really.
Rym: Oh and yet I know there are a lot of black people around here.
Rym: There's also a lot of Mexican people around here, but there were almost no Mexicans.
Scott: Well, I don't know.
Scott: you could possibly explain the Mexicans by saying this illegal immigration going on Even though I know not all of it is illegal.
Rym: Yeah, though.
Rym: Actually it worked.
Rym: today.
Rym: I drove past a street corner that obviously had all the day laborers waiting for people to pick them up.
Scott: Wow, but yeah, that's just kind of weird Do they?
Scott: there's no way they can know when they mail out to send the summonses.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It was just I thought it was interesting.
Scott: I mean, you know, it's not like everyone has those names that it's like, ah, my name obviously gives away my race and creed.
Scott: I Will say a Jewish one Avi Avi Goldstein bag.
Rym: Yeah names Avi That is the stone.
Scott: Yeah, or Donna Chang?
Scott: Okay
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: all right
Rym: But yeah My jury duty experience basically just taught me that I will never get a jury of my peers because no one in my line of work Will get jury duty unless maybe I guess there's a chance that the jury duty place I went to or maybe just this court is weird and maybe it's different elsewhere.
Rym: because the whole time even yeah I'm sure.
Scott: if you went to like a court and say where's a really happening place like Austin, Texas or Where else is happening?
Rym: I don't know New York City.
Scott: No, New York City is not so happening.
Rym: You'd get a crazy mix of people there San Francisco or LA maybe the local court in one of those rich suburbs somewhere.
Scott: Yeah Like the town court in the in the rich suburb or something like that I'm sure if you went there, then you would get a totally different mix of jurors.
Scott: Yeah, but I I think it speaks more about the Kipsy than it speaks about jury.
Rym: Yeah But I want to ask all of you out there because the the person who decided that I was free to leave jury duty Obviously knew what she was talking about and was well versed in how juries work.
Scott: This is the deputy.
Rym: Okay, and I wonder if that criteria is the same everywhere.
Rym: if basically anyone with an IT job because I didn't Try to get out of it.
Rym: I didn't write some fancy like oh, well, I Maintain critical systems in a hospital blah blah blah.
Rym: I basically just said I'm I'm a cable monkey and a supervisor at an IT company.
Rym: Yeah, and then they said oh, well, you can't serve on a jury go home Yeah, and it had nothing to do with the trial.
Rym: This wasn't even for the trial.
Rym: This was pre-screening solely to determine if people had valid reasons to not be on jury duty period not to not be on this case.
Scott: Yeah, this was before they started asking questions.
Scott: Like have you heard the news?
Scott: When's the last time you read a newspaper which newspaper etc?
Scott: Oh wasn't it this?
Scott: you didn't even get to the jury nullifications or the.
Scott: that man is likely to judge based solely on evidence And not on lawyer rhetoric.
Rym: Oh, well, I guess the moral is now I'm not eligible to be on jury duty unless I lie about my job.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what I'm gonna do.
Scott: I probably won't get jury duty.
Scott: Who knows watch one will show up tomorrow.
Scott: I'll be crazy.
Scott: That'd be great.
Rym: Yeah Well, I know where the court is.
Rym: It's right next to the train station.
Scott: The thing is if I went to jury duty Oh, here's the other interim funny thing.
Rym: So I took the train up, right?
Rym: Yep So I'm already.
Rym: they keep talking about parking.
Rym: like talked about parking situation for a while and people were grumbling a little bit on Parking.
Rym: blah blah blah.
Rym: I went to leave after you said.
Rym: All right, uh You're not gonna be on any of these trials.
Rym: and she says it's quicker to the parking lot out that way and I said oh I took the train.
Rym: and she says like.
Rym: she stopped for a second says what I was like.
Rym: I took the train.
Rym: She's like, where'd you take the train from?
Rym: Like I live down in Beacon she's like.
Rym: so you took the train up here instead of driving and I was like, yeah, it was faster and It was cheaper than paying to park.
Rym: and she was like, huh?
Rym: and then I left.
Rym: like.
Scott: people don't even think that there's a train to take around because that train is Primarily a commuter train to bring people in New York City.
Scott: people don't realize that what you know, that's its purpose Basically, they don't realize that no it has a secondary purposes.
Scott: It's sort of it's.
Scott: it's cuz they're not hackers.
Scott: hackers are the only people who think to use things for purposes other than their main Intended purpose, you know only a hacker would say aha.
Scott: I see that train.
Scott: I could use that train to do this in addition to what it is mainly supposed to do and Normal people would never think to do that ever.
Rym: I can't wait to try someday to use that special flag stop.
Rym: That's basically just a wooden platform in the middle of the woods.
Scott: You really want to go there.
Rym: I really want to try that.
Rym: I mean I could drive there.
Rym: I know how to get to that platform on foot.
Rym: I just wonder I want to see how it works to go to the conductor and say I want to get off at breakneck Ridge.
Scott: Get off at breakneck Ridge, you know what happens?
Rym: I want to see to bring your neck because the thing is These trains some of them are driven really well and some of them aren't and There's only one platform and it's about as wide as one train door Mm-hmm.
Rym: I want to see if the whoever's riding the train that day can actually hit that platform so I can get off easily.
Scott: I imagine they'll miss it slightly or they'll slow down before it and then creep up to it and then the conduct the the Engineer not the.
Scott: the conductor not the engineer.
Scott: the conductor will flag the engineer and tell them when to go.
Scott: go go go go Stop and then tell they'll get it lined up.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I know all the other stations have electronic signals.
Rym: I don't think that one does.
Scott: no no.
Rym: No, but yeah, I didn't get to actually go through jury selection.
Rym: I didn't get to see if anyone noticed that I had the God delusion on me.
Rym: I didn't.
Rym: I was really hoping for some sort of interesting experience and it was just really got a day off work.
Scott: and what 40 bucks?
Rym: No, though.
Rym: I I'm pretty I don't know what my employer's policy is.
Rym: either I burned a vacation day and I got an extra 40 bucks on top of that or I got 40 bucks or my employer just paid it.
Rym: I really don't know.
Rym: and they I didn't see a written policy document.
Rym: I didn't ask anyone.
Rym: So yeah, tell us your jury duty experiences.
Scott: Yeah, you know what these stories are often filled with humor and I know we have lawyers listening.
Scott: So they probably have jury stories also.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: In fact, if you've got a good jury selection story, that'd be great.
Scott: Yeah, also like if you're a lawyer, can you get on a jury?
Scott: That's kind of weird.
Rym: Actually, they told us kind of specifically that if you're a lawyer in the area, you're pretty much confused automatically.
Scott: yeah, but what if we're a lawyer not from the area?
Scott: like what if I?
Scott: or what if?
Scott: uh, I was a lawyer and now I'm not or maybe I'm a big-time national lawyer?
Rym: Well, one of the facts I read I was I've read all this stuff before I went in the handbooks Basically said that if you have a lot of knowledge of the legal system, you were generally discouraged from being on juries.
Scott: No, is he gonna mess it up?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I don't make a decision.
Scott: That's too correct.
Scott: I went into this with an open mind Have a good understanding of what reasonable doubt is instead of a vague understanding.
Rym: I basically came out learning that it is So trivial to get out of jury duty like you just blink and you're not on a jury.
Scott: So I mean even if that didn't work you could have just gone.
Scott: Hitler Hitler Hitler.
Rym: Oh, well that might mean if you do it, obviously it stupidly like that the judge and fried you say all right asshole contempt You're not on the jury.
Scott: Now.
Rym: You're contempted punned No, I can see you know, especially with some stupid chintzy child be like you're on this jury.
Rym: That'd be great.
Rym: But no, you got to be more subtle.
Rym: you just stand up and say, you know at the end They always ask you some sort of question.
Rym: I hear tell like Can you think of any reason why you could not serve on this jury and give an objective blah blah blah and at that point?
Rym: regardless of your feelings you just say I Feel the need to inform the court that I am aware of the idea of jury nullification and I feel that I could not Separate my logical decision from my knowledge of this and therefore I want to make it known to the court so that you can decide Accordingly.
Rym: if you want me to be on this jury knowing full Well, my personal love love love love love and basically keep talking to the lawyers laughs as they get the hell out of here.
Scott: I Don't know if that would work.
Rym: probably I Would bet money that it would work.
Scott: it might it might.
Scott: of course
Rym: if they don't ask that question I don't think you should stand up and say well
Scott: I think if I just if I ever went in for anything I would just answer everything honestly and let them do whatever they want because you know, what's the worst possible thing?
Scott: Oh, Jimmy Yeah, oh, oh, oh, oh.
Rym: So like I'm sitting there right and someone dropped a pair of leather gloves by the front.
Rym: So so the Commissioner comes out the guy and he picks him up and he looks around and I see him.
Rym: So I'm just gonna looking around the room and he smirks for a second and then the smirk goes away.
Rym: Then he goes back to his desk.
Rym: He putzes around for a while like he's planning it out.
Rym: Then he walks up to the front of the room and says did anyone lose the pair of leather gloves?
Rym: and without a beat He says don't worry.
Rym: We're not gonna make you try him on And I I lo I just lost it.
Scott: It sounds to me like the Commissioner of Jurors in Poughkeepsie, New York And the deputy Commissioner of Jurors are the awesome and they make their crap as jobs.
Scott: entertaining in some way.
Rym: He was a jolly funny chubby cool guy.
Scott: I Kind of want that job, but I don't think I should take it away from him.
Scott: I should be the fun jolly Commissioner of Jurors somewhere else I don't think.
Scott: where the Commission of Jurors is an asshole.
Rym: I get the impression that we make more money doing what we do now than we would ever make in any sort of local Governmental role.
Scott: but wouldn't that be fun being the Commissioner of Jurors?
Scott: You see all those people every day and yeah You know, it might be.
Rym: see it's always the crazy.
Scott: I could maybe you could do that fun thing like Commissioner of Jurors for a day.
Scott: ha There might be like mayor for a day.
Rym: I could see legal problems with that.
Scott: I wonder what other interesting civic jobs there are that you don't even realize they exist.
Scott: Like I didn't even know till just now like I knew it, but I didn't consciously know.
Scott: There's a guy whose job it is to deal with juries every day.
Scott: That's his only job.
Scott: and uh now I understand Oh, there's a guy.
Scott: Is there a guy who does something else crazy?
Scott: I don't know about.
Rym: maybe I can guarantee at any rate We'll find out if I have to go to jury duty tonight tomorrow.
Rym: I'll bet no, but you never know.
Rym: I got a call in the number again and make sure yep, and unless something crazy happens.
Rym: I think that's it.
Scott: Are we gonna go to work tomorrow?
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: but in any case tell us your funny jury stories.
Rym: see this one.
Rym: I wish we had a live kind of ISDN line and a live radio show people call Intel's funny jury duty story.
Rym: We could basically just do pendulate show only with us.
Scott: Yeah, it sucks.
Rym: We could do it once a week.
Rym: That would be funny.
Scott: I think yeah, I'm just looking forward to the shows you can do next week.
Rym: Yeah, we got some good shows lined up as always and of course Katsucon is coming up.
Rym: I didn't mention it much yesterday, right, right, right?
Rym: We'll talk about it next week, but look it up Katsucon calm.
Rym: It's a great convention and anime con with some good gaming at it in.
Scott: we're gonna rock the house at it.
Rym: Oh, are we going to rock?
Rym: We're pretty much gonna.
Scott: We're not gonna rock the house We're gonna rock the hotel the whole thing us too.
Scott: We're gonna rock the whole thing back and forth.
Rym: also I just confirmed my staff position again at an amazement which I think is in May in North Carolina.
Rym: if you're gonna be there I'll at least be there.
Rym: Maybe Scott will be there.
Rym: We're thinking about that if I go.
Scott: What's my position there?
Rym: I don't know I could.
Rym: we'll see.
Rym: we could talk because they need smart intelligent people and to if nothing else We could do all this stuff.
Rym: or are you gonna do it Katsucon?
Rym: Yeah Alright, alright.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.