Scott: It's Tuesday February 13th.
Scott: I'm Scott and I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we review the awesome board game turn and Texas.
Rym: Let's do this So while we're sitting here in the geek house recording in the studio You'll be pleased to know that outside.
Rym: There is currently a quivering maelstrom of snow.
Scott: Did it actually start snowing yet?
Rym: It's been snowing for the last hour and a half.
Scott: Oh, I haven't looked at it.
Scott: Like I had my window open so I would see the snow start but I guess I haven't looked out the window when it started.
Rym: In fact after we hit that salad I looked out the window like as I was finishing up and I said hey, I don't think it started snowing yet.
Rym: Then I looked and I thought oh it in fact just started snowing.
Scott: Yeah, you know when you live across from a car dealer It's actually pretty useful because when there's gonna be a crazy storm they move all the cars into an optimal configuration.
Rym: Yep, the thing is I had no idea.
Rym: there was bad weather coming.
Rym: I'm at work, you know doing my work stuff I'm planning on leaving and then someone all day people keep making references to like man.
Rym: Is it gonna snow?
Rym: I don't know something about snow snow snow snow.
Rym: But no one said outright.
Rym: the weather said it's gonna snow and I don't like to make small talk.
Rym: So I blew these people off and ignored them and it didn't look like it was gonna snow.
Rym: In fact, it was really warm.
Rym: I took a short nap in my car.
Scott: It was pretty warm today.
Scott: I mean I drove to the dentist that I found out about the snow from the dentist's office.
Rym: Oh, yeah, cuz they always get small talk at the dentist.
Rym: Yeah, I know instead of taking lunch I just took a nap in my car for the half hour 45 minutes or so and I was plenty warm without running the car or anything.
Rym: Yeah, and it was nice and you whatever.
Rym: and then just as I'm about to leave work I look outside and suddenly it's really gray out.
Scott: It was super gray most of the day here.
Rym: So I go on to you know, no a dot gov and it says horrible snow next couple.
Scott: Yeah, they're big red letters whenever something's written in red.
Scott: That's bad.
Rym: So then I'm like, alright horrible snow in yawkers and then I check beacon.
Rym: Oh horrible snow and beacon.
Rym: and then I check DC because now I'm worried about driving to Katsu.
Scott: Come here now more at the snow.
Scott: I don't mind.
Scott: if it snows tomorrow if it stays shitty bad on Thursday, that's gonna suck.
Scott: We're gonna have to drive to DC really slowly.
Rym: thing is we're not leaving.
Scott: It can't be as bad as the drive home from uber con.
Rym: god, we should tell that story.
Scott: Did we tell this time we told the story?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: maybe someone go and see if we've ever done a podcast about the drive back from uber con.
Rym: Yeah, cuz we need a special for this Thursday.
Rym: Anyway, if we haven't done it, we'll tell that story.
Rym: That sounds good, especially since we are going this weekend to Katsucon Which is famous for what?
Rym: three four five years.
Rym: I forget how many years ago was Katsucon.
Rym: it was the year before I went so it's three years ago got snowed in.
Scott: Getting snowed into a convention can either be awesome or terrible.
Scott: now I if I was a convention and we I got snowed in I would just keep it rolling at least the parts that didn't need me Planning.
Scott: I mean, he's a video game open.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: from what I heard a lot of the people who went it sucked for them because they you know Most people can't deal with having to take extra days out of your life suddenly.
Scott: Yeah, that does kind of something colony work.
Scott: I'm just lucky in that right now.
Scott: I'm in a situation right off to work until March.
Rym: But imagine after they call a job you're like, hey, yeah, I'm down in Washington DC Snowed into a hotel.
Rym: I can't come back until Wednesday.
Scott: Yeah, maybe that's pretty bad But you know when stuff like that happens, it's beyond your control.
Scott: Just accept it and deal with it.
Scott: Yeah, that's the best way to get through with the least suffering.
Scott: Let's just sit there worrying about it.
Scott: It's gonna be a long two days of trapped in the hotel.
Rym: Well, that's kind of people we are.
Rym: but also Remember we have money.
Rym: So whenever something like that happens we are immediately prepared to deal with it.
Rym: The credit card can always get us out of any situation like that.
Scott: That's why you know Penn Jillette always has that thing where he won't go anywhere if he can't save his ass with money.
Scott: It's like in the middle of the jungle in Africa.
Scott: No even if you're carrying all of Bill Gates fortune in a briefcase that won't save you if like a snake bites you or a Guerrilla attacks you.
Scott: so he won't go there.
Scott: He only goes places where money can save his ass no matter what happens.
Rym: Yes, I think is a good plan.
Rym: He also steals cars, but you know, that's not.
Scott: Yep, hopefully this bad weather will not affect our Katsucon plan and hopefully you will get to Katsucon despite weather.
Rym: Yes, Katsucon is this weekend in Washington DC at the Omni Shoreham Hotel.
Rym: You can find out all the information at I believe Katsucon.com.
Scott: Go to Google and type in K A T S U C O N.
Rym: Yes as in our friend katsu and then khan all one word.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yeah, we're gonna be staff in the video game room.
Rym: We're gonna be doing all sorts of crazy stuff live shows various tournaments anime match game.
Rym: It's gonna be awesome way Awesome.
Rym: Also, we're gonna have our DS's and we just got Diddy Kong Racings and we'll probably want to play that a little bit.
Scott: Yep Diddy Kong Racing.
Scott: it didn't meet my original expectations, but it beat my secondary very much lowered expectations.
Scott: So we'll talk about that in a couple weeks probably.
Rym: Yep, but a lot of gaming a lot of fun.
Rym: We'll have some things to give away but not things that any of you will probably want.
Rym: They're mostly things for people who don't listen to the show yet.
Scott: Yep Oh, and I think in the future of GeekNights, I don't want to.
Scott: I don't want to be a hundred percent sure on this But there's a possibility that I might be acquiring something for free which I will give away that is worth Substantial but not incredibly large amounts of money.
Rym: Oh, really?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: This is news to me.
Scott: I know it is.
Scott: I forgot to tell you.
Rym: Well, what is it?
Rym: Are you not gonna say
Scott: I might as well just say it All right I'm probably gonna buy this laptop because you know I had to give my old one back to my job and it's going to come with a perfectly free Creative Zen 512 megabyte mp3 player and I don't need it.
Rym: We're gonna have to have one hell of a fucking contest for that.
Scott: yeah, the other thing is if I The reason I'm buying this laptop is there's a chance that it.
Scott: the only thing that could be wrong with it where I would be Dissatisfied would be if it's too slow and I was lucky.
Scott: I read the return the official return policy the fine print if I don't like it and I return it within 15 days Which I will do if it is too slow.
Scott: I have to return the mp3 player.
Scott: Also, we're all set to pay for it?
Rym: No, well in that case, we'll just give away my Carcassonne instead.
Scott: Yeah, we're gonna give that away no matter what.
Scott: we're gonna give that away katsukan.
Rym: Yeah for that Carcassonne I was thinking about setting up a little booth in the video game room a little table kind of like those three card money guys That you see out on the street and really poor towns Ronnie and you know I'll just.
Rym: you can come up and if you wish you can challenge me to a two-player game of Carcassonne and if you win I will give you a brand new unopened copy of Carcassonne.
Rym: But if you lose you have to buy me another copy of Carcassonne.
Scott: Yeah, we got that copy of Carcassonne real cheap.
Scott: So why not buy another one?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Hey, I don't know what we'll do But we'll give it away at some point either at the con or in the future.
Rym: We'll probably bring a couple of board games to katsukan since we'll be in the gaming room, which is mostly video.
Scott: But I'm sure we might bring maybe third in taxes.
Scott: Maybe something smaller.
Scott: Who knows maybe Dracula for the night time.
Rym: Ooh, that might be a good con game at night at night time.
Scott: Hells.
Rym: Yeah That's the kind of game where you get in big enough crowd and some people would be happy just to hang around and watch.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is it takes a little bit too long.
Scott: if it was shorter.
Scott: You could really get it going.
Scott: Maybe Scotland Yard, you know.
Rym: Yeah, well as long as one of us was Dracula and then one of us was teaching people as we went instead of team.
Rym: Yeah, we'll figure it out.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway in the news the virtual console has been as it is always doing having more and more games put on it in order to Trick Scott and I into spending money on games.
Rym: We already own in multiple copies And the three latest games are two Absolutely.
Rym: Fantastic games though.
Rym: That is a very Weighted statement and one game that is not worth five bucks, but it's definitely an important game.
Rym: Yep ice climber I don't think I need to say anything about it.
Rym: It's an old classic Nice climbers fun.
Scott: It's a classic but it's not worth five bucks.
Scott: It's worth maybe one buck because it's a simple old game.
Rym: I'd wager that most people who play Nintendo systems today have never even seen ice climbers because this game is an old Game.
Scott: it is real old.
Scott: it came out.
Scott: It was one of the first Nintendo releases.
Scott: It wasn't you know, the old style box and everything.
Rym: Yep ice climber was before the NES was really that popular.
Scott: Yeah, I put ice climber in there with say like Galaxian, you know, it's a great old game But it's so at such.
Scott: it's so old and minimalist that it's not really worth paying for Pac-man on there.
Scott: pac-man is great.
Scott: I love pac-man.
Scott: dig-dug is great.
Scott: I love dig-dug but not paying five bucks for it because it's so simple, you know, there's not much to it.
Rym: But I'll bet.
Rym: the only reason anyone knows about this game is because they put the characters in the game Keeps.
Scott: I knew about ice climbers way before we did.
Scott: because yeah, most people I imagine heard about the ice climbers.
Scott: So Smash Brothers Melee and perhaps some other games recently they've made appearances in because remember we don't know what game they're actually from.
Rym: We were pretty much the forefront of the Nintendo generation.
Rym: I grew up on Nintendo to the exclusion of all other activity.
Scott: So if you actually if you have extra money like you don't care and you have never played ice climbers That would be the only time I would recommend you pay five bucks for it or you know Emulate it because it's not worth.
Scott: Yes on the yeah, if you can just emulate.
Scott: once you've played it twice You'll be done playing it unless you want to master it which you might want to do.
Scott: No, you know that would be pretty impressive.
Scott: Someone mastered ice climber?
Scott: little ice climber speedrun.
Rym: It's not that hard to master ice climber.
Scott: I don't know somebody.
Scott: at the early levels I can just whip them out, but later levels get pretty tricky.
Rym: ice climber is easier than bubble bobble.
Rym: It is easier than bubble bob and I fucking beat bubble bobble all the way through is it?
Scott: you're a crazy man?
Rym: Yeah, me and my brother played that game forever.
Scott: I eventually just got tired of going through all those levels.
Rym: Oh, you know who does know about ice climbers?
Rym: Yeah, it is VG cats.
Scott: Oh, does he really?
Rym: yeah There was nice climber joke a while ago.
Scott: One of the games came out.
Scott: the two big ones All right.
Rym: Well number one Kirby's adventure, which is probably the best Kirby game.
Scott: Kirby's adventure is a game I had for the NES and I beat the hell out of that game.
Scott: I got every single secret a hundred percent completion.
Scott: I beat everything.
Scott: I got everything.
Scott: there was nothing left for me in that game and I did that on the NES The original release of this game and it is without a doubt the best Kirby game ever.
Scott: every Kirby game that came after took from Kirby's adventure.
Scott: I mean there was Kirby's dreamland, which is the original Kirby platform game for the Gameboy.
Scott: But Kirby's adventure was really made Kirby, you know, he swallows something and then he gets a power.
Scott: You couldn't get powers in Kirby's dreamland.
Scott: only in Kirby's adventure Could you get powers from eating different guys and that's what made Kirby awesome.
Rym: See I never owned Kirby's adventure.
Rym: I rented it once I liked it I gave it back and ever bought it and I didn't really realize how great it actually was until when I was living alone in the mountains on co-op and I had nothing to entertain me, but Read or die TV that was already on my hard drive.
Rym: Oh gunslinger girls And a bunch of NES ROM.
Rym: so I started playing pretty much every NES ROM one by one as far as I could stand to.
Rym: When I hit Kirby's adventure, I played through that entire game.
Scott: Did you get all the secrets though?
Rym: I think I did.
Scott: there's a lot of them and they're really cool secrets I play.
Scott: some of them are really tricky like this one level We have to swallow two fireball bad guys to get a hammer and then get somewhere without getting hit and then use it.
Scott: It's all really good stuff.
Rym: I played it every day for like three weeks.
Scott: Yeah the bosses are also really fun and of course is awesome.
Rym: the last game that is on the virtual console a game that a Lot of people hate or had a lot of difficulty with it.
Rym: Even I I had mad difficulty with it even though I like I never ever ever ever legitimately beat this game or In fact got past the second level without cheating.
Scott: I never got past second level without cheating.
Scott: I barely can get past the first level like if I tried to play it today.
Scott: I can't beat the first level most times.
Rym: kid Icarus, which I owned And sold and then bought again.
Scott: my cousin owned it.
Scott: I played it a few times.
Scott: other than that I never really played it just because I was so hard at his house There was no way that I was gonna pay money for a game that I would never get anywhere in.
Rym: I mean kid Icarus is very similar to Metroid except it's a thousand times harder.
Scott: And it's not doesn't have really the exploring of Metroid.
Scott: It's sort of like just go forth.
Rym: It's two types of games.
Rym: remember you didn't play it far enough.
Rym: That is true because well there's three types of games.
Rym: you start off And it's an up scrolling.
Rym: if you fall down you die game platformer up scrolling platformer.
Rym: Then it's a side scrolling platformer.
Rym: Yeah, and it's an up scrolling platformer again and Littered throughout are the labyrinths which are basically a Metroid.
Scott: yep And it's just there's also isn't there side-scrolling shooting later on on the very very end of the game.
Rym: Yeah, it becomes a shmup.
Scott: yep It's a lot of games in one.
Scott: or you're this guy named Pitt who's sort of like an angel type of thing Cherub something like that.
Rym: yeah, you're a little angel.
Rym: I mean I could go.
Rym: the plot of kid Icarus if you read the instruction book is actually more than a lot of anime I've seen.
Rym: well.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's really good.
Scott: It's a game that's been forgotten and never got any sequels or anything.
Scott: Pitt the main character is gonna be in Smash Brothers brawl So you should get familiar with him.
Scott: now the thing about this virtual console release.
Scott: if you've never played kid Icarus It might be worth five bucks.
Rym: however Icarus fights Medusa.
Rym: angel packing packing packing packing.
Rym: eight followed by as many lowercase use as you can fit.
Scott: yeah Well if you didn't know back in the day?
Scott: Not you know Zelda 1 was like one of the first games to have a battery in it where you could save Your game on the cartridge.
Scott: well in the u.s.. In the u.s.. That's right.
Scott: Every other game like Metroid or what are the games Fex Antidoo, Pitt Icarus, you know Metal Gear?
Scott: Yeah, all these games.
Scott: you couldn't save your game.
Scott: You got a password and you would type the password in.
Scott: you would write the password down on paper And then you would type it into the game And it would bring you back to where you left off or to where you got the now usually the way the passwords actually worked.
Rym: Basically they turned your piece of paper into a very small memory card where the password was actually all the data of what stuff you had and what level you were on and what your score was or whatever data They needed to save.
Rym: when you typed it in you were just telling the game to give me all of this stuff and start me At this point.
Scott: yeah And you would buy books or magazines just to learn Passwords.
Scott: that would bring you to the end of the game with everything like punch out.
Scott: You know the Mike Tyson password.
Rym: some games like one Megaman game I forget which one where you have the dot passwords.
Rym: I figured out how the passwords worked a little bit by experimenting like I get an energy tank and I'd save the game and see what the password was and I think I figured out how to always give myself another energy tank.
Scott: Well, that's pretty cool.
Rym: Well, that's cuz that game didn't have so rigorous checksum.
Scott: Yeah, later Megaman said much more difficult password systems.
Scott: But yeah, anyway in this virtual console release of kid Icarus They have taken out the password system so you can only play the game straight through.
Scott: you can't just go to the end with All the weapons or anything like that.
Rym: Well, how do they do it?
Rym: Can you save your game?
Scott: I think I don't know if you you might be able.
Rym: I don't know because this might be interesting.
Rym: if Cuz I mean.
Rym: obviously we don't know the full details if we didn't buy it, but I got to read up more.
Rym: But if they give you they wanted they might have done is given us instead of the NES version Which was kind of gimps they might have given us the FTS version from Japan, which not only had Battery save games it had better music like all those FTS games did.
Scott: Yeah, the only thing I can say though is for gaming purists possibly like us.
Scott: This is sort of sad because now all our passwords and our retro cool is no longer there.
Rym: Yeah, I mean Icarus fights Medusa angel is engraved.
Rym: Those sacred words are ingrained into my head for all eternity.
Scott: However Nintendo was wise and good enough to that.
Scott: when you go into the Nintendo we store to buy this game It says in text before you pay money the passwords in the original are not in this game.
Scott: So, you know what you're buying before you buy it.
Scott: So it's not like a surprise.
Scott: you bought it without the passwords.
Scott: Hahaha, it's this doesn't have the passwords.
Scott: Are you still gonna buy it?
Scott: and that's cool that they actually bother to tell you good on them.
Rym: Yep, so I did I defy any of you out there to legitimately beat kid Icarus in any reasonable span of time.
Scott: Someone's gonna do it.
Scott: I'm sure this speed runs, but whatever.
Rym: Hey I was a hard core Nintendo gamer as a kid and kid Icarus that that's one of the few games where I would Halfway through playing just start yelling obscenities and pull the game out and throw it across the room.
Scott: I just died and gave up and played something else one time.
Rym: I got the credit card in the game not as hard as silver sir and the credit card.
Rym: I was so happy He's like I can finally afford something.
Rym: cuz I could never afford dick, you know I'd be fighting monsters and getting a million hearts and I thought I was doing great.
Rym: and then I'd get to a store like the First store in the game and I'd have like a hundred hearts.
Rym: and that took me an hour to get.
Rym: I go into that door And the cheapest thing the guys selling is like 800 hearts.
Scott: Yeah, how are you supposed to get 800 hearts by then?
Rym: You want to know how you're supposed to do that one.
Rym: you have to do all those challenge rooms, you know There's rooms you went into that was full of monsters that killed you immediately.
Scott: No, I just remember rooms I would go in that were full of monsters and I couldn't.
Scott: I knew that I was supposed to do something in there But I had no idea what the hell to do.
Rym: Yeah, you know what kill them all.
Rym: they're worth a lot of money.
Scott: I would kill them all and it still wouldn't do anything for me.
Rym: Well, no, they all drop the big hearts which are worth more than one heart.
Rym: And also you can sometimes get bonuses and all that.
Rym: but what you're supposed to go to the rooms?
Scott: They'd be like empty like what the hell am I supposed to do in here?
Rym: Well, sometimes you could stand in the middle and jump up and down and stuff would happen.
Rym: really There's a lot of secrets.
Scott: there's a lot of weird shit like that that that that makes the game kind of arbitrarily more difficult.
Rym: I mean part of it was that the game was glitchy like Metroid and part of it more glitchy and part was glitchy in the Same way.
Rym: Yes more glitchy in was that the game put a lot more complexity than a game of that Caliber warranted and it didn't really document any of it.
Rym: Yeah Yeah But no, you know how you made all that money.
Rym: You sit there at the beginning of the game where those five cute little snakes will fall down and you shoot them all and They give you a few hearts and then five more fall down and you shoot them all.
Rym: five more fall down and you shoot them all.
Scott: if anyone sits there shooting the first five snakes in the game until you get like a thousand hearts Why didn't you just play World of Warcraft?
Scott: you've been better off so I got to cover for me.
Rym: So I got the credit card and I got it and it lets you buy something if you don't have enough money.
Rym: I'm like hot diggity Damn, and I bought something and a credit card went into debt and now I couldn't buy anything until I pay it off the debt.
Rym: And like two hours later, I wasn't even close to paying off the debt and the item was long since useless.
Rym: Oh God, yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right, so there have been some rumors going around lately.
Scott: So I wanted to be clear.
Rym: go and run.
Scott: I wanted to be very clear that everything I'm gonna say is completely rumored and could be just bullshit.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: Yep For example Scott is intelligent.
Scott: Yeah anyway, the rumors all concern the possibility of Dungeons & Dragons fourth edition.
Rym: now, I have one response to that.
Rym: if it's true and that is me standing in front of Hasbro going You expect me to pay money to you again, you know, I have all my money.
Scott: Yeah, well, no, we didn't give them that much money.
Rym: when you really think about it We can start in turn.
Rym: I'm back in the day.
Rym: I bought a lot of second edition D&D books.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: I have probably eight hundred dollars worth of various books for Dungeons & Dragons.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, here's some of the especially if you count all the back issues of Dragon magazine.
Rym: I bought and didn't read.
Scott: Yeah One rumor says it'll be announced this year and released next year.
Scott: Another rumor says will be announced this year and released in 2009 or like 2011 or something crazy like that.
Rym: Well, the thing is D&D third ed is good in a lot of ways and bad in a lot of ways.
Rym: Whatever D&D 3.5 ed was it felt mostly like a money grab and it annoyed me.
Rym: and the only reason I have a 3.5 edition book is Because my current players handbook is falling apart to the point of look.
Scott: if you don't know how to take care of your D&D Phbs, I think you'd like harass them on purpose.
Rym: See Scott you say that except I only had one PHP That looked like that ever and in fact all my second ed books are pristine.
Rym: for some reason the cover of that book Just fell off right away through no fault of my own.
Scott: It's cause you removed the CD.
Rym: What do you mean that cursed seal?
Scott: Yes, anyway another rumor says that Wizards slash Hasbro might spin off like get drop the D&D product like the whole D&D thing from them and Some people are saying oh they're gonna keep third ed going and they're gonna bring fourth ed Alongside and not get rid of third ed.
Scott: some people say fourth ed is gonna replace third ed over time And all sorts of crazy stuff.
Rym: I submit that it doesn't matter anymore.
Rym: and with the advent of the Internet once someone knows the rules to a role-playing system Yeah, you don't need to buy anything from the company anymore at all.
Rym: Yep I mean there was no internet.
Rym: back in the day I bought D&D books cuz that was the only way to get all these rules and all this material And I wasn't about to write it on my own and I didn't have the wealth of the Internet.
Scott: I think it's like with a board game or something like that or the video game.
Scott: You need to have a physical thing to play the game with a role-playing game.
Scott: All you need is knowledge of the rules.
Scott: I mean like, you know, cuz all they're really selling you is a rule book.
Scott: Imagine if monopoly didn't need a board pieces or paper money or anything.
Scott: All you needed to know is the rules of monopoly.
Scott: you could read the rule book of monopoly once.
Scott: Get rid of it and you can play monopoly whenever.
Rym: I've run into some poor people who when they like German games But they can't afford them.
Rym: They'll find out the rules recreate them and play them.
Rym: And actually we did that once with liar's dice.
Scott: We did do that.
Scott: liar's dice is not really German.
Scott: It's not a complicated game.
Scott: You're supposed to make liar's dice.
Rym: Yeah, but that our making was so ghetto.
Scott: It was a ghetto making but anyway, you know with it rather RPG.
Scott: once you know the rules There's no reason to really buy anything.
Scott: All you need is paper pencils and dice.
Rym: now then again what you can buy and what there's a good market for are Supplements and story ideas.
Scott: That's what they make.
Scott: all their money is a book of spells.
Scott: They're like, there's no way you can know all these spells.
Scott: You need to buy the book.
Rym: Hahaha Well, no I'm to see.
Rym: the thing is what they what they used to do.
Rym: a lot of the D&D books I have that I actually bought from back in the day include almost zero Actual rules from the game and they were mostly back story story ideas character stuff things to help you as a dungeon master or a player flesh out your game.
Rym: and All those books are just as useful in third ed as they were in second ed because I'm smart.
Rym: if I need to come up With what this second ed character would look like in third ed I can do it.
Scott: and about.
Rym: yeah Like less than 10 minutes, you can change all the numbers without difficulty So I don't need to buy another book telling me about Elminster or race Lynn or whoever.
Scott: Yep Now that actually brings us to the last rumor that I remember is that D&D fourth ed might be more miniatures centric.
Scott: So it's like huh, you know they I guess they realize.
Scott: if this rumor is true if They realize that selling the rules doesn't really work now because people get the PDF learn the rules and they don't need to give you Any money making it more miniatures centric.
Scott: They can make money selling more miniatures to people, you know that D&D miniatures I guess has been pretty successful.
Scott: I mean, yeah, I don't play it But I know some people who bought the miniatures and I see people who playing normal D&D.
Scott: You just have the miniatures, you know, and I guess they're making some money off of them.
Scott: So hey, they're making more money off of them that they made off of chain mail or anything.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean what if I bought from them in the past several years other than a new players handbook Nothing by me.
Rym: in fact The last thing I bought for Dungeons & Dragons and I regret it to this day was the book that was supposed to have the blade Singer in it because I played this long campaign way way back in high school Where I played a blade singer and it was a great campaign and I we didn't have rules for a blade singer in third ed.
Rym: So we made something up.
Rym: it worked.
Rym: Okay, and I was kind of excited about the official thing.
Rym: I was gonna remake the character and see how it worked.
Rym: So I bought the book on my way home Like I got home and I opened the book the blade singer in the book was broken.
Rym: It was full of typos and missing all the information.
Rym: Nah, I I was flabbergasted.
Rym: The store wouldn't take the book back.
Rym: They published for free online the corrected blade singer.
Rym: like a week later And pretty much from that day forth I just wouldn't buy anything from them anymore.
Scott: Yeah, well, here's my is my personal suggestion to people.
Scott: if all these rumors are BS then whatever just keep Role-playing however you want.
Scott: if the rumor if any of these rumors are true and fourth edition D&D starts to rear its ugly head Buy burning wheel and pretend it's fourth edition.
Rym: Yeah Okay, cool or I don't know.
Scott: inspectors Inspectors, I don't think it's a replacement for D&D.
Scott: That's sort of a you know, if you.
Scott: but if you have inspectors and you have burning wheel You don't really.
Scott: I couldn't see many other role-playing systems that you would need to have.
Rym: the only thing burning wheel lacks Currently for us and we haven't bought more recent books is high magic like burning wheel doesn't work for the realm said I don't think the magic burner is available.
Scott: There's also burning empires, which is the sci-fi instead of the fantasy.
Rym: Oh, yeah But I'm just saying the only thing we can't do with burning wheel easily right now is a forgotten realms kind of high Magic setting without a lot of tweaking.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, well.
Rym: Yeah, but we've talked about burning wheel.
Rym: We'll talk about it again in the future.
Rym: Someday.
Rym: We'll actually play it on our own more than once shittily at 3 in the morning.
Scott: Yeah We're also gonna play.
Scott: it will probably play more inspectors sooner.
Scott: We could probably do an episode on that eventually.
Scott: Maybe I can get that guy on the show.
Rym: He's really awesome things of the day.
Rym: I Had some video game thing, but I had to talk about this.
Rym: Apparently this company is putting out a product called horn tones FX 550 the what?
Rym: now what this does is a little box that you put in your car and you hook it up to a bunch Of other things and it has a spot for a USB flash drive.
Rym: You can get files off of it.
Rym: All right, and it allows you to save up to eight files Audio files on it of any set.
Scott: Oh, I guess as much as you can fit on the USB flash drive.
Rym: Well, you take the flash drive out.
Rym: That's just to put them on.
Rym: it doesn't say how long they can be Uh-huh.
Rym: Now what it does is it ties this into your car's horn?
Rym: and now you can tell your horn to when you honk it.
Rym: either honk or I don't know play a funny wav file.
Scott: Doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo?
Rym: Aside from the fact that this is illegal in most states.
Rym: Yeah for obvious reasons I mean, I mean I we live in New York and I don't know how many people who listen to this show considering how many Australian and British well albionic listeners we have.
Rym: But in New York City, there are a lot of places where there's a three hundred and fifty to five hundred dollar fine if you honk your horn.
Scott: well if you honk your horn when you you know you're not supposed to I mean yeah someone's about to hit you and you honk the horn.
Scott: that's the cops not gonna give you a ticket.
Rym: yeah but legally the.
Rym: the rules for honking horns in the u.s.
Rym: especially in urban areas are actually really strict.
Scott: yeah let alone written law is much stricter than the enforced law.
Rym: let alone modifying your horn to play an mp3.
Scott: no modifying your horn or not having a horn.
Scott: you won't pass inspection with a modified horn.
Rym: there's no way you realize that when they inspected my car they didn't check the horn a real full inspection.
Scott: it was theoretically.
Rym: they actually checked everything else.
Rym: they found my broken front control arm.
Rym: yeah yeah which I knew about because the car wasn't turning so well.
Scott: it reminds me I need an inspection pretty soon.
Scott: I'll go next week.
Scott: but anyway yeah I could see some funny uses for that one like.
Scott: I don't know the sound of an ambulance.
Rym: yeah that's not illegal all right.
Scott: maybe likes you know a gangster going coppers never catch me alive.
Rym: something like that I don't know.
Rym: I'd probably have something along the lines of put down that cell phone and pay attention or turn on your goddamn head low turn on your goddamn headlights.
Scott: I would put that right.
Scott: I was right.
Rym: yeah I was driving home from work today and I passed.
Rym: probably see I could exaggerate and say like a hundred people but instead I'll say the actual number like 99 people who just didn't have their headlights on or had their parking lights on despite the fact that it died that it was dark.
Scott: if you're not in a parking lot do not turn on your parking lights.
Scott: god alright.
Rym: anyway this product has bad idea written all over.
Scott: it also has awesome entertainment for Scott written all over it.
Rym: I'll bet in the end it's gonna have videos on YouTube written.
Scott: all I bet you in the end is gonna be a local news story about these things saying oh danger on the highway.
Scott: something son.
Scott: anyway I got a little theme going this week and I started off yesterday with some old awesome jazz and I was gonna continue it today with some more old awesome jazz but instead I got some sort of modernish jazz if you will.
Scott: this video just came up out of nowhere almost of an idea that I've had for a long time which was make a robot that plays an actual music instrument.
Scott: I mean we've had MIDI instruments for a while where a computer sends digital information to a digital instrument and the digital instrument is then played like a player.
Scott: piano is played but no one's really made like a robot that you attach to say an actual acoustic guitar and then the robot strums it and fingers it.
Rym: see the difficulty here comes down to how you interface with the instrument.
Rym: I mean a piano.
Rym: a robot that plays the piano would be easy.
Rym: all you have to do is hit the keys hard or soft and manipulate the.
Scott: yeah I think there probably were piano playing robots but that's not the.
Rym: yeah but like a trumpet playing robots real hard cuz.
Rym: not only do you have to do the keys and everything but you've got to simulate human lips.
Rym: yeah not easy not easy at all.
Rym: I mean I have enough trouble simulating good trumpet playing human lips with my actual trumpet playing human lips.
Scott: yeah anyway we have here's a video of a robot that plays a saxophone.
Rym: it's pretty impressive and a little scary looking.
Scott: yeah I mean obviously the music that comes out of the saxophone is sort of emotionless because it's the same exact blowing for every note.
Scott: so it's very mechanical sounding.
Rym: yeah there's no vibrato or anything.
Scott: yeah however it's a real saxophone being played by a robot and it's playing a John Coltrane solo like to the T like as the music is written.
Scott: yeah doesn't sound so great because it's a robot playing it but that'll get better in time.
Scott: there's no reason the robot couldn't play in a way that sounds good to people.
Rym: I look forward to the day where you can record.
Rym: I mean like we do now.
Rym: you set up a system somehow to record a great musician playing a thing and then instead of playing an audio file or you know some sort of recording of this band playing you have a stage with all these robots and they just perfectly recreate whatever the band played with actual instruments.
Scott: yeah I mean no matter what kind of recorded audio you have recording is lossy by definition.
Scott: you know if you put a microphone right up next to like a violin and record the violin master playing on the best violin you can get it to sound good enough to where someone couldn't tell the difference but it's still not the same.
Rym: it's not absolutely perfect.
Rym: just by the fact that a lot goes on in audio.
Rym: I mean subtle vibrations here and there and audio files like to BS about all that stuff but the fact remains that it's very difficult to argue that people couldn't tell the difference between a live performance and a recording.
Scott: yeah if I got you a super audio CD which is just about as goddamn good a recording as you can get of an orchestra at doing a whole symphony and I played it for you on like a $30,000 sound system that would sound damn good.
Scott: but then if I took you to the orchestra it would still be better.
Rym: well hopefully it could be worse if the acoustics of the theater were bad.
Scott: I guess I guess it.
Scott: yeah I'd hope that the orchestra would be better at least the way it feels.
Scott: but if you just had the instruments and you somehow recorded the actual movements of the people in the orchestra like how they move their arms and their lips and how much they blow and you had robots copy what they did you could actually recreate the symphony as it was played in the orchestra in your house if you had enough room for all those robots and that's pretty cool.
Scott: just one of Scott's crazy ideas that I actually came to fruition somehow.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: so as long as we don't get the power to stop time everything's still okay.
Rym: yep all right.
Rym: so we haven't talked about board games in a while because we've been playing a lot of other games mostly DS and Wii games though we have been playing a lot of board games just not board games we really needed to review though.
Rym: now just before this we busted out a bunch of old board games forgot how much we liked it but yeah it is definitely DS season though.
Rym: up until very recently however I had been on a far longer than should have been winning streak at German board games.
Rym: I was winning a sickly disproportionate number.
Scott: that might have something to do with us playing a lot of Carcassonne.
Rym: well not just Carcassonne but also Antecker.
Rym: we're playing tile laying games where there's my undisputed domain.
Scott: yeah Rym likes the.
Rym: Yeah I don't like them so much I'm just good at them kind of like how you're good at Web of Power even though you hate it.
Scott: well you don't hate Carcassonne.
Scott: no like I don't like Web of Power.
Rym: true true true but finally it was brought to a bitter end where we brought out El Grande a game that I'm pretty good at and Alex won and then we busted out.
Rym: uh what else did we play the game we're gonna talk about all right the game we're gonna review because it's GeekNights and we review board games occasionally.
Scott: the game we're gonna talk about today is Thurn and Texas.
Scott: now Thurn and Texas has been pretty hot stuff lately and this is why first of all it won the spiel des Jahres in 2006. now for anyone who doesn't know what the spiel des Jahres is it's litter.
Scott: it's German for game of the year and they give it out every year to the game of the year.
Rym: think it's like the equivalent of the Oscar for Best Picture.
Scott: that's pretty much what it is.
Scott: if a board game wins spiel des Jahres that's holy shit.
Scott: that's the fucking game.
Rym: this year we own most of the spiel des Jahres in recent memory.
Scott: well yeah except for that weird Towery one with yeah pieces but yeah now the game is designed by Andreas Seyfarth.
Scott: I'm pretty sure that's how you say it.
Scott: yeah he's one of our men yeah and his wife Karen Seyfarth.
Scott: really yes now another game by Andreas Seyfarth also won the spiel des Jahres.
Scott: that game would be Puerto Rico the best board game ever.
Scott: yes so the fact that Andreas Seyfarth wins another spiel des Jahres means that this game is probably hot stuff and you know what it is.
Rym: I mean it's not the best game in the world.
Scott: it's not the best game in the world.
Rym: is he really Tigers and Euphrates and Puerto Rico?
Rym: for the longest time nothing has unseated those two in terms of best game and most fun game.
Scott: but this game sort of combines like all the hot trends in recent German board game design night very perfectly into just one game.
Rym: yes it did very specifically adds and takes elements that I like that you never really see these elements in the same game and here they are very elegantly done.
Scott: yep all right now how did I get this game?
Scott: I was in the city and there's a store there called complete strategist C O M P L E A T strategist and I always knew it was there.
Scott: but I didn't know exactly physically where it was.
Scott: but I wrote down the address and I went there.
Scott: now I expected it to be holy crap a game store in New York City.
Scott: this must be the greatest game store ever.
Scott: well I got went in there and it looks with my eyeballs like the typical Scuzzy game store and I'm like.
Rym: you know what those stores are.
Rym: they're all smelly yeah but staying.
Scott: the reason I didn't leave immediately was it actually didn't smell.
Scott: I was quite surprised Wow because my eyes told me this store would smell but my nose didn't smell anything.
Scott: maybe it's because the street outside smells so the inside does not I don't know but it didn't smell.
Scott: and the employees were nerdy but intelligent and helpful.
Scott: and I must say though for as small and kind of really crammed in this store is I mean physical space was at a loss in this store.
Scott: there were no tables to play games or anything like that that I saw.
Scott: but the stock of this store was phenomenal.
Scott: they had games up to the ceiling.
Scott: every game you could think of was there from like the oldest to the newest and games that other stores have like zero or maybe one copy of.
Scott: if you're lucky they had like 10 copies of or more.
Scott: it was crazy out of control and most of the games were sold not at super low prices but not overpriced either.
Scott: I mean I got third in taxes for 30 something bucks.
Scott: it's you know it's only a few dollars more than I would have paid online and after shipping it was probably like a dollar cheaper.
Rym: yeah plus I mean that's what board games cost.
Rym: you can't get him cheap unless you have a friend who buys games on impulse and then decides he doesn't like our friend who makes games.
Scott: so the American release of this game is by Rigo Grand who is quite a good bringer of board games to America.
Rym: yep pieces are all high-quality boxes nice.
Rym: what can I say?
Scott: yeah the box is like.
Rym: there's good panning across the center channel.
Scott: there's a lot of extra room in the box for like more stuff and I think that as expansions come that might be good because you can fit it in there.
Scott: the only really complaints I have about the physical miss of this board game are that there's these cards that they're kind of small and they're not super durable and you use them a lot.
Scott: so over time they might get kind of worn out but they're pretty much the whole game.
Scott: it's not really a big deal when you when you get right down to it and the price is right for what you get.
Scott: the wooden houses I also like they're very nice.
Scott: so what kind of game is thrown in Texas?
Rym: it's kind of like ticket to ride.
Scott: yeah ticket to ride has the card drawing mechanism where there are face-up cards and also a face-down deck and on your turn you can take face-up cards or face-down car.
Scott: you know you take from those cards.
Scott: and third and taxes the same way there will be six face-up cards and a face-down deck and you can take cards from the face-up or from the deck.
Rym: now it also has this element of you're trying to make paths among all these cities on the board.
Rym: the board is basically a map of Germany.
Rym: all these cities and the cities are different zones of different colors and they'll have names.
Rym: and you're trying to make routes along.
Rym: you know contiguous routes from city to city to city point to point along the roads to accomplish various goals.
Scott: I can't even begin to count how many games involved connecting nodes on a map.
Rym: yep but one one primary difference that in this game you make the routes with cards that you lay in front of you instead of on the mat and you can't block other players.
Rym: so another player moving around the board does not directly influence you moving around on the board.
Scott: yeah now this playing cards in front of you to make a set reminded me a lot of Mario Nostrum that we played.
Scott: didn't we do a show on it?
Rym: I don't know if we actually did.
Scott: now we played it one set uber con so I don't know if we know enough about it to play a show on it but that's what it reminded me a lot of because in Mario Nostrum has the same thing where you get cards and you kind of make sets of cards in front of you by playing them in sequence.
Rym: so I'll have a card of one city and then I look on them and I have you know a card of a city that on the board is next to it.
Rym: so on my turn when I play the next city I can just play it on either side like next to the card that would be on the board.
Rym: so in the end I'll have a chain in front of me that if I follow that chain on the board it makes a continuous line.
Scott: yep now the other thing about this game is that there are four guys right and the guys are basically special powers.
Scott: one guy lets you draw more cards one guy lets you play more cards one guy lets you score more when you score and one guy lets you take the six cards that are face up and flush them down the drain and draw six new ones which is he's the fun guy.
Rym: yeah that's an interesting part of the game where especially if you're playing with a bunch of people and you know someone's planning ahead like they alright I need this card and oh yeah that card came up on Scott's turn.
Rym: in two turns it's mine and then on Alex's turn he says you know what fuck this I'm flushing it.
Scott: no you basically just can't look at the what's going on until it's your turn except you have to because you do have.
Rym: another trick of this game is that you know you play these cards from the deck in order to go around on the board.
Rym: there are only three cards for each city on the board.
Rym: that's right.
Rym: so I get one game.
Rym: we were playing in one city.
Rym: all three of them came up right away and no one picked him up and then they got flushed.
Rym: so all of us now while we're playing the game we know that until the deck runs out and gets reshuffled there is no way to build anything in that city.
Scott: that's right yeah and especially if you play with more players that gets kind of.
Scott: it gets even more tricky because then people will be drawing more cars that are face down and thus you'll have less information.
Scott: you have imperfect information about what cities are out there but at the same time people's hands a decal cycle faster.
Rym: so you're getting the cards you need.
Scott: that is true.
Scott: I did notice that.
Scott: that's something great about this game actually is that if you you can play it with two three or four players and no matter what you don't have to change the rules at all.
Rym: that's a rare game.
Scott: most games require some modification yeah and that's why I think this game is so perfect.
Scott: when you look at tickets a ride you know and it's got the drawing mechanism and you look at Mario's dream is the card playing in a row mechanism.
Scott: but all those games are sort of they're not a hundred percent clean.
Scott: yet somehow this game takes all those mechanisms and combines them into one game and it's perfectly clean across the board.
Scott: you don't have to change a damn thing whether you're playing with two three or four players.
Scott: that is phenomenal.
Scott: I mean you don't have to change the amount of starting money because there isn't money.
Scott: you know you have to change how many cards people start with.
Scott: everyone starts with no cards.
Scott: you know it's just there it is.
Rym: and the turn order aside from the special abilities which really simple there's the four of them and you just pick one every turn.
Rym: yep and whichever one you pick then whenever you do that thing you get the bonus.
Scott: basically it's draw a card play a card and then if you want score what you've already played.
Rym: total yep and there's a lot of nice tricks about that too.
Rym: I mean you play a card you play a card once you've got at least three cards in a route at any point once you've made three.
Rym: well technically once you've made two because you make the third one and then you can score it when you play a card on that turn.
Rym: you can then say after you play that card I now choose to score this score it and then those cards flush out you discard your hand down to three and you begin again.
Scott: so now here's the thing I really like about this game.
Scott: you on your turn you must draw one and you must play one and you may score right.
Scott: so if you don't score then the route you're currently building just kind of stays in front of you.
Scott: then the next turn comes around.
Scott: you must draw will drawings never a problem.
Scott: there's always cards for you to take.
Scott: you must play.
Scott: now.
Scott: you can add a city to the right side of your route or the left side cuz all your cards are played in a horizontal row.
Scott: so whatever card is right most in your route you have to put something adjacent to that or whatever card is left most yet to place it adjacent to that.
Rym: you can build up.
Rym: you can't build down.
Rym: it has to be one non branching line.
Scott: now what if you must play you must play a card.
Scott: if you can't play a card that adds to your route you have to get rid of that route.
Scott: it's.
Scott: and then you put another cart.
Scott: you start a new one by putting a card down.
Scott: so if you decided not to score the route last turn you get to the next turn and you can't add anything to it.
Rym: you lose it which is good and bad.
Rym: I mean on one hand you thought yourself if that happens to you probably lose this game depending on how big the route you lose.
Scott: I mean you might lose one card you put down one.
Scott: the next turn comes around you get rid of it.
Rym: but that also it's a nice mechanic.
Rym: or if you've built a dead end route that's not going anywhere.
Rym: it forces you to cut and run and get back into the game.
Scott: yep it's also adds this sort of building risk as your routes get longer.
Scott: you know it's like unless you have the cards you need already in your hand you can choose to gamble and sort of try to flush the cards to see more of them to try to get the card.
Scott: you need to make your route that little bit longer but that's a big risk.
Scott: if you don't get the card you might lose the whole route if you don't have it in your hand already.
Scott: so it sort of gives you this chance to maybe win with incredible luck you know.
Scott: or play it safe and only continue a route if you know you can keep it going because you've got the cards in your hand already.
Rym: now nicely and this is something I really like about the game to just because it's so different from all the games I'm used to.
Rym: I mean the error of board games that we play.
Rym: the most are the ones were around the edge of the board.
Rym: there's some sort of victory track thing yeah and you count up victory points going across.
Rym: this is one of those other kinds of games where you count up to get at the end.
Rym: the end of the game you score all the stuff in front of you but you know.
Scott: what I really like though is that scoring this game takes like two seconds.
Scott: yep it's like other.
Rym: granted granted I'd.
Rym: sometimes there are some games where I love the suspense of.
Rym: I don't know if I won or not that's true.
Scott: but this game still has the suspense.
Scott: the suspension doesn't last very long because everyone counts and like less than 30 seconds you know as opposed to spending a minute counting which I was actually kind of found annoying having to count and then recount if you're not sure you know what kind of game has that?
Scott: Puerto Rico actually kind of has that.
Rym: just as a rule whenever I no matter how simple a board game is pretty much actually not just in board games my entire life if I ever have to count anything I always count it twice.
Rym: yep just automatically by instinct.
Scott: but you know what?
Scott: in third and taxes I only have to count it once because it's just so simple.
Rym: oh no but I count twice anyway.
Scott: it's kind of like I've counted twice once.
Rym: it's like my own internal error checking where up because if by chance I don't get the same result then oh yeah something's wrong with my brain or something's wrong with this counting.
Scott: yeah but anyway the way you score in third and taxes is well.
Scott: first there are these chits on the board that you can get for attaining certain goals.
Rym: it's kind of like in through the desert where when you do certain things you take a chit with a number of points on it right away and put it in front of you.
Scott: for example there are three purple cities on the board.
Scott: if you get a house in every one of the purple cities there's a chit.
Scott: there's a stack of chits and each of them is worth a certain number of points.
Scott: the one on top of the stack is worth three points.
Scott: so if you get a house in every purple city you take the top chit from the stack.
Scott: that's worth three points.
Scott: now the top chit on the stack is worth two points.
Scott: so if you're the second person in the game to get a house in every one of the purple cities you get two points and you just collect these little chits as you achieve these goals throughout the game and they're actually worth a lot of points and you add them up.
Rym: yeah one point is a big deal in this game yes but the thing is also because I mean there's the diminishing returns of.
Rym: if someone else gets something it's now worth less to everyone else but the difference is only one point in each one.
Rym: so being the first one to everything is really not a feasible goal.
Scott: it's really more about getting more stuff and not always getting it first.
Rym: yeah so you like.
Rym: you want to get some things first in order to get the five points instead of the four and you want to get all the rest of the stuff.
Rym: like you pick a few things you're going to get first everything else you plan on getting before the end of the game just to get some points.
Rym: yep it's like I get the thing that's worth five points.
Scott: it's like I won the most recent game by picking up something at the last second that was pretty small like three points.
Rym: yeah and you won by just that little bit.
Rym: if you hadn't gotten that I would have won.
Scott: that's right.
Rym: but you did it and you did it well.
Rym: but say scott gets the five point thing.
Rym: now my goal is not.
Rym: maybe I want to get the four or the three point thing to mitigate.
Rym: so now he doesn't get as many points in the differential.
Rym: yep so he gets the five.
Rym: I squeak by with the three at the end to mitigate some of his five.
Rym: so effectively his thing was only worth two.
Rym: so if you were able to do something that other players aren't able to do you're hugely ahead.
Rym: or if you are unable to do something that all the other players dead did you're hugely behind.
Scott: yep now here's the other way is to get points.
Scott: there are these carriages a three four five a six and a seven carriage.
Scott: now that looks when you first read the rules of the game you think that these carriages are where the game is at.
Scott: you know because if you make a route you start out the game with no carriages.
Scott: if you make a route that is at least three cities large you can take the three carriage.
Scott: then you have to get the four carriage.
Scott: you can't jump to the five or to the seven right away.
Scott: yeah.
Rym: so if you build seven routes that have seven cards each you get the three the four the five the six the seven.
Rym: each time you build one in order.
Scott: yeah you can't just get the seven right away.
Scott: if your first route is seven cards you get the three.
Scott: if your next route is eight cards you get the four.
Rym: yep now some of the bonus chips are things like make a route that's six long so you can get.
Rym: yeah you can get more points but yeah and the game ends when either you have put all your houses on the board which we'll get to the cool mechanic about that but basically you put houses along all the routes you've made.
Scott: and if someone gets the seven card yeah see it looks at first like hey i want to build bigger routes and i want to build them faster than anyone else.
Scott: that way i can get all the carriages and get the seven carriages is worth the most points.
Scott: but really when you actually play the game you realize that the carriages are more of a timer than they are a scoring mechanism.
Rym: yeah like if you everyone's gonna get the five maybe even the six carriage unless you're stupid yeah so you don't really need to blitz the carriages unless you're trying to end the game and even then that's hard to do.
Rym: yeah what you what people tend to do is it?
Rym: it's like a when you're doing a standardized test and you look over at someone's paper not to see what their answers are.
Rym: you're not trying to cheat but to see how far along they are as a gauge of how far along you should be.
Scott: yep it's like you know if someone if other people are multiple carriages ahead of you that means the game is close to an end and you haven't been making that many routes or you've been making way too many small routes and not really doing anything productive you know.
Scott: so the game will punish you for lagging behind everyone else but it won't really punish you for not getting the seven because only your biggest carriage counts.
Scott: so if you get the six carriage and someone else gets the seven you get seven points and they get ten.
Scott: it's only a three point difference and the game will come down to all those chits.
Scott: now the final bit of score is the houses.
Scott: you have all these houses and you want to get these houses on the board and every house you don't get on the board when the game is over is minus one point.
Rym: now usually this only comes down to being like two or three points by the end because everyone will generally have all their houses out.
Rym: but in the most recent game one of the things that fucked me was i made a great route at the end and it brought me right within an inch of beating scott but then i had a couple more houses than him.
Rym: yeah
Scott: i had one house left at the end just one
Rym: yep and i had three because the route i made at the end was perfect except that it overlapped one of my other routes and i got to put one less house than i should have and all together it just
Scott: ah yeah this is how the houses work right.
Scott: let's say i make a route and the route contains three gray cities and an orange.
Rym: see the cities are all different colors and like if you get all the how all your houses have a certain color on the board you get chits for those colors and all that.
Scott: yeah there are ways to get points with the colors.
Scott: anyway i make a route.
Scott: all the cities had to be adjacent and all the cities have colors and all the cities of the same color are near each other.
Scott: so all the purple cities are adjacent and such right.
Scott: so let's say i make a route that is three gray cities and an orange city and i score the route in addition to doing all the other stuff you do.
Scott: when you score a route you can decide to put houses either on all cities in the route of one color which means i would so in this case i would put a house on every gray city but not the orange.
Scott: one or one city one city for one house for each city of a color in the route.
Scott: so i would do one house in orange and one in gray and you get to pick which one and you get to pick one which one of the gray cities you put the house in.
Scott: so usually i would pick to do gray because that's three houses versus two.
Rym: but maybe you're not gonna get the great shit anyway it's near the end of the game.
Rym: and getting that orange how the house on that orange city is gonna get you the orange chit?
Rym: yep that's worth far more points than nothing.
Scott: or maybe i've already got houses in some of those gray cities and i don't need anymore you know.
Scott: so you can't put more than one house per city.
Scott: so if you've already got a house somewhere then you don't need to put a house there anymore.
Scott: so if that you can use the city as part of a new route.
Scott: but it won't help you put a house there because you've got one so there's no point.
Scott: so yeah it's pretty cool.
Scott: you're trying to get as many houses on the board as you can but sometimes you make routes where you know.
Scott: you make a route of six cities in a row but you can only put down maybe three houses.
Scott: so not it's.
Scott: it's pretty easy to make big routes.
Scott: it's difficult to make big routes where you can put down houses on every city in the route
Rym: and while there is a lot of randomness at first like when you first start playing the game it's like you'll have a master stroke and like oh i'm getting all the cards i want.
Rym: or uh i didn't get the cards i needed at all.
Rym: but the randomness really is mitigated by the fact that the game is the perfect length.
Rym: like i've never seen someone in all the times we've played it so far including myself have bad luck or good luck.
Rym: that was not evened out by opposite luck before the end of the game and it really comes down to skill.
Rym: it's not really a random game as far as we can tell.
Scott: i mean there was one game we played that had a big asterisk on it because we messed up a bunch of rules.
Scott: but that doesn't count.
Rym: yeah you and alex messed up a bunch of rules.
Rym: yeah i was sipping wine in another room.
Scott: yeah but every you know later on.
Scott: it's like at first.
Scott: i when we started playing the game and i wasn't really too good at it i kind of felt like oh i'm not getting the cards i want i lose.
Scott: or aha i got all the cards i want.
Scott: watch this and i would win.
Scott: but now that we've had more experience after playing five or six games you know at one point i felt like i wasn't getting what i wanted but i still managed to pull something out that scored enough houses and points and when i did feel like i was getting everything i wanted i did.
Scott: but it wasn't a complete blowout amazing thing.
Scott: it was just as good as what everyone else was doing.
Scott: so you know you might it might.
Scott: at first when you're inexperienced luck might have a larger factor but once you know when to flush the cards down the toilet when to draw two when to draw an unknown card you know what to keep in your hand and what to play.
Scott: the luck really kind of goes out of it and it's all about what you know.
Rym: overall it's a really good game.
Rym: i'd recommend it as always.
Rym: it's fairly abstract and it's one of those games that isn't extremely cut and dry.
Rym: to people who aren't used to german board games i don't think.
Scott: yeah i don't know.
Scott: if you're not a german board gamer you might want to still stick with like ticket to ride or something like that as an intro or settlers as the introductory.
Rym: yeah i mean i hate to sound like one of those people like oh this is an advanced board game.
Scott: it's not not for you it is not as advanced as you know Tigris and Euphrates or Puerto Rico or any of those really heavy games.
Scott: so it does fill sort of that niche of the in-between like you've played the beginning german board games like Carcassonne and settlers and ticket to ride.
Scott: but those are still.
Scott: you know you're losing interest in them and you want something a little harder.
Scott: but you don't need to jump off the deep end.
Scott: i think that this game is like right in the sweet spot right
Rym: there in fact maybe just because we played it again recently but it feels like it's at the same level of El Grande and all those because i remember we started with settlers and that was our first game and we loved it and loved it and loved it.
Rym: and then when we when we cut our teeth and we started you know looking for better board games we moved toward Entecker and El Grande and all those games and then eventually we ended up at Puerto Rico and Tigris and Euphrates.
Scott: something else i really like about Thurn in Texas is that not only is it two three and four player without changing any rules but if everyone is experienced setting up is really fast playing is really fast and cleaning up is really fast you can just whip this thing out like wow
Rym: yep i mean Ra has the same advantage but Ra's not nearly as good a game.
Scott: no Ra is more.
Scott: Ra is fun.
Scott: i don't know if it's as fun but Ra is much more random.
Scott: you know this is more fun than Ra less random and you get sat you're satisfied playing it.
Scott: you know it's not too heavy not too light and it takes like a half hour.
Scott: if everyone knows what the hell they're doing that's really cool.
Scott: oh there are some misprints in the uh instruction book.
Scott: not misprints like broken rules misprints like typos.
Rym: yeah whatever i mean that's the first edition printing.
Scott: what do you?
Rym: yeah well also if you look at the game while the rules are printed in english the board the game itself is obviously set up to be bilingual english and german and i think that the german board gaming market in the us is strong enough now.
Rym: i mean obviously germany's known because more and more these games are coming over here for by various means.
Rym: but they know this game was going to be sold here and they sold it here real quick compared to how games used to come over in the past and i'll bet that they made it bilingual and all the only thing they had to reprint between the two editions now was the actual rule book.
Rym: yeah they saved a bunch of money the board.
Scott: they didn't have to change the cards they didn't have to change like the rule summary card thingies.
Scott: all they changed was the actual rule book and they designed the box and they didn't really change anything else and thus they were able to bring the game over really quickly.
Scott: of course in the rush there are some typos in the rule book but big deal the rules are still fine as written.
Scott: it doesn't cause a problem yep.
Rym: and of course last and certainly least this game is one of the few german board games ever that's actually set in germany.
Scott: yeah i was gonna mention that because it's about the german post office and how it was created and all that stuff.
Rym: yeah we could talk about the.
Rym: you know the the theme of the game but you guys have wikipedia.
Scott: yeah the only real theme that the game has built in is that each city has sort of a building attached to the city.
Scott: that is the post that you know it's like in this town the post office is in a castle and there's a picture of the castle and then there's a little guide that tells you about all the buildings.
Scott: you know it's like oh in that city.
Rym: yeah the post office is in the town hall you know yeah the the that part of the theme is definitely hacked on in the same way that in uh railroad tycoon they hack out all that stuff to teach you about locomotives.
Scott: yeah there's also like uh one like page worth of information about like thurn and taxis and the people who you know the people in the olden days who actually started all this stuff and the history and it's semi interesting.
Scott: i guess it's not like a big history lesson unless you're super interested in german post offices.
Scott: but uh there it is all right.
Rym: so if this snowstorm doesn't kill us all uh expect only one more normal GeekNights this week tomorrow where we'll review some form of anime manga or comic and darryl starrett will beg the question.
Rym: oh actually i think it was gerald oh pun.
Rym: and uh we'll have a special thursday.
Rym: don't forget if we didn't tell the story about us trying to get home from ubercon.
Rym: we'll make that the special on thursday.
Rym: so let us know before tomorrow because a special doesn't get recorded the day it gets put up.
Rym: a special gets recorded in advance because we're out of town.
Scott: hey you know maybe if it actually snows tomorrow we can record everything during the day.
Scott: yeah won't that be weird?
Scott: we won't actually be recorded at night.
Rym: you realize this will be if i don't go to work because of the snow my first snow day since high school.
Scott: i think i had some snow days last year.
Rym: my job i mean ibm was right there so they never canceled anything and one time i drove there in a blizzard and no one was in the office and i didn't have anything better to do.
Rym: so i just stayed at work playing around with stuff in the lab.
Scott: you mean sieve too.
Rym: uh no only half sieve too.
Rym: the other half the time i actually worked on this project.
Rym: but the thing is i was building a big server right so it was.
Rym: hit enter on the giant websphere installer that's going to take 10 minutes and then hit enter to start the next turn.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott special thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the rss feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: mondays are science and technology.
Rym: tuesdays we have video games board games and rpgs.
Rym: wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: you can send us feedback by email to geekknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via odeo.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an odeo on the right side of our website.
Rym: if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in itunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.