Rym: So you might notice the lack of music lack of all the normal accoutrement of a GeekNights episode.
Scott: What does that mean?
Rym: It means it's time for a GeekNights special.
Scott: Oh, man's right now.
Scott: I'm in Flushing.
Scott: well as when we normally would have been recording this.
Scott: I'm in flushing New York at some baseballs Yep, and I am just home doing nothing probably playing bioshock Of course, you're probably listening to this the day after in which case I'm probably at work or who knows.
Rym: but yeah The point is I know we have a lot of new listeners And I just want to tell you all that this is not a normal episode of GeekNights.
Rym: It is a GeekNights special which is a code word for We're too lazy to do a whole show for whatever reasons or coming out some.
Scott: something ending with Z Is is what usually provokes a special busy lazy nosy?
Rym: Right so tonight we realized we haven't really talked about this.
Rym: I mean it's Tuesday.
Rym: It's gaming night.
Rym: We talked a lot about German board games and sometimes crappy American board games and video games all those things occasionally sport related things, but We haven't talked about something that a kind of game that we used to play a lot And we don't so much anymore, but I kind of want to.
Scott: yeah the kind of game obviously is the card game now You know nowadays.
Scott: There's a whole lot of kinds of card games.
Scott: You know mad just collectible card games like Magic the Gathering.
Scott: There's non collectible card games like Guillotine yeah, but the great dal muti Lux or Chrononauts.
Scott: But we're talking about traditional card games that you play with a standard You know deck of playing cards.
Scott: you know the 52 card deck with the spades the diamonds the hearts.
Rym: you know Euchre P-knuckle gin rummy Romy Michigan rummy.
Rym: Yeah Of course fish.
Rym: Yeah, I mean there's a lot of these games old maid old maid.
Scott: You actually play with an old maid deck.
Rym: It's bad.
Scott: you realize an old man with an old maid day.
Rym: while that is true You do realize that an old maid deck is just a normal deck of.
Scott: I know but an old maid deck is superior.
Scott: Yeah, so the game.
Scott: We want to talk about is perhaps.
Scott: We're not going to talk about why but well We're not gonna talk about the other card game.
Scott: We will Because someday.
Rym: today the thing the real issue here Is that card games are really on the decline and you don't see a lot of younger people playing these games that poker in the you?
Rym: yeah, but I'm not gonna talk about poker.
Rym: I don't want to anger anyone just yet But I'll say this we're talking about not poker in the popular games like that But trick-taking games, which is the majority of good card games.
Scott: well I don't know about they're not all good, but we're gonna talk about hearts.
Rym: Specifically what I would say is that trick-taking card games are they make up the body of them of good card games on average?
Rym: Yes
Scott: in terms of games played Games that are popular and well known and have a long tradition that are played with a deck of playing cards that involve some measure of Thinking and strategy and skill in order to win as opposed to just luck or some outside Something outside the game like betting or
Rym: in the case of Euchre cheating.
Scott: Yes The trick-taking games like hearts and whist and spades and such are the best and of those I think hearts is the most enjoyable.
Rym: I think hearts is honestly probably the most experience with it's the most strategic, too.
Rym: I mean, I'm not gonna argue about the finer points.
Rym: or what about cribbage bridge or what about bridge?
Rym: bridge?
Scott: I think is technically, but I don't know how to play bridge and but from what I've heard bridges is a pretty good game.
Rym: Here's here's what I would say bridge is a really good really strategic Great game.
Rym: the problem is bridge.
Rym: I think tries to do too much with it.
Scott: Yeah, I've seen those old people play.
Scott: they have like this big like plastic thing with flags and lights.
Scott: I don't know if there's lights, but it's got all this.
Rym: no lights.
Scott: It's got all this stuff outside of the cards.
Scott: It's like a bunch of extra stuff.
Scott: go well the thing is really complicated.
Rym: the reason car There's a looks complicated to kind of existed is that it was kind of a standardized thing.
Rym: you know everyone could get a hold or make or find a deck somewhere and People didn't.
Rym: really there weren't a lot of board games.
Rym: You could just buy especially not good ones anywhere.
Scott: Yeah, imagine if you had to buy You know like a different you know deck of cards for each game.
Scott: It's sort of like we went backwards in terms of you know technology in terms of games.
Scott: We used to have one set of cards And you played every game with the one set and that's all you needed.
Scott: now you got a freaking collect 10,000 cards to play one game.
Scott: so like money the wasting.
Rym: So as we had this you know standardized deck.
Rym: that kind of evolved over the years.
Rym: People started making games that only required this deck.
Scott: I gotta say also.
Scott: I'm a fan of looking at really old decks of cards.
Scott: They're always cool.
Rym: I am also a fan of that.
Scott: I have a couple of really old decks of cards from foreign countries also awesome.
Rym: I have a really cool.
Rym: It's a set of cards from a old defunct brand of cigarettes that my grandpa had Awesome, and it's actually a leather case and there's two decks of cards in it.
Rym: It's really cool.
Scott: like Nintendo They used to make those playing cards.
Rym: Yeah The real issue is that there's a certain level of complexity you can reach with such a simple deck.
Scott: You've got 52 cards with only four colors and 13 suits and maybe some Joker's and maybe some other like rule.
Scott: You know extra cards they throw in there that say like you know bicycle on them or whatever.
Rym: There becomes a point at which while you could make a better game the game becomes so Abstracted and so arbitrary and so limited by what the cards you're using you can't make a game.
Scott: I mean there are some games you could make with say 100 cards that you couldn't make 52 and you sure you can get two decks and stick them together But they're not 50 And not even that.
Rym: just the fact that you're so limited in what you can do with just a deck of cards that I Think hearts is the perfect balance.
Rym: and I think I would say that hearts is probably the perfect card game just in the terms of the fact that I Think it's as complex and as strategic and as interesting as a card game can be without hitting that Arbitrary or solved or ham-fisted or overly complicated with the material.
Scott: look at something like can ask to say can Asta is.
Scott: I don't know all the rules of can Asta, but it's played with two decks of cards like combined into each other.
Scott: It would probably be a better game if you just made a custom deck You know for it or like a pinochle would probably a better game if you just made a custom deck instead of using you Know a deck of cards with different amounts of things in it.
Rym: god.
Rym: I used to play pinochle in high school.
Rym: I'm done with that.
Scott: but hearts is where it's at.
Scott: hearts uses all 52 cards.
Scott: without Joker's.
Scott: all the cards are meaningful and There's a lot of stress if there's some luck going on.
Scott: You know if you have four hearts masters playing against each other.
Scott: It's gonna come down to what cards they get dealt mostly.
Scott: Yeah Well the deal
Rym: with hearts is the deal with most card games and in fact most games that in the end eventually People are all equally skilled at the game or closely to equal scale and the only way to find out who's truly better is To keep playing and keep playing and keep playing press a and eventually Whoever is better will win a statistically significant percentage of the time.
Scott: Yep, but you can tell that it's still a meaningful game because even if you're really good at the game Someone who is really really good at the game will beat you every time or just about every time.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I played hearts a lot as a kid.
Rym: I played it in high school almost every day.
Rym: I played in middle school almost every day.
Rym: I played it with my family all the time.
Rym: hearts and Euchre were the big games.
Rym: we played Euchre because that's a really big game out in the Midwest not so much down here in New York.
Rym: No, I only seen it played a few times But when I grew up it was just hearts and Euchre and we take to every play hearts one day Euchre the next day.
Scott: Yeah, we were more big on the rummies in the gins But there was some hearts going on mostly.
Scott: the thing was is like every see hearts really got big once people started playing Microsoft hearts and then we played real heavy played hearts with actual cards.
Rym: Yep, but my dad I mean I played so much and no matter how good I got My dad always won like I'd win a game here and there but on average he would Most of the time win Game of skill.
Scott: if it was a game of total luck, then it would just be random.
Scott: all the time You know, sometimes you win.
Scott: Sometimes I win.
Scott: who knows?
Rym: that's actually how we determine when a German board game is broken.
Rym: for our group of friends is when over a long period of many many plays The winners even out and every and no one has tried an innovative strategy in that time.
Scott: Yep So the way hearts works.
Scott: if you have never played it or if like you opened up Microsoft hearts and not had a clue what?
Scott: To do and didn't read the help.
Scott: It's pretty simple You deal out all the cards to four people so everyone has 13 cards.
Scott: Then you sort of pass cards around the ones you don't want whatever.
Scott: I'm not gonna bother getting too specific here.
Scott: and every turn Someone some beginning with the person who has the two of clubs you throws one card out Right and you go you had to throw it to the left.
Scott: So if I throw a card than the person my left does and then the person to their left and then the fourth person Well from here, it's basically it's a trick-taking game, which is a whole class.
Rym: I mean, there's all different other kinds of card games.
Rym: There's reflex games and whatever.
Rym: This is a trick-taking game.
Scott: So the idea is that I'm gonna explain what a trick-taking game is.
Scott: I think tricks.
Rym: Well, what's the trick?
Scott: that's not the kind not the kind where you know, you turn you take you don't turn.
Rym: Yeah basically a trick-taking game is this class of games where generally Cards are laid out by players in some sort of clockwise order and you have to follow suit.
Rym: So if the first person plays a club then everyone else if they have a club has to play it now.
Rym: They can play whichever club they want, but they have to play a club now.
Rym: Different games have different rules for if you don't have a card of that suit But you play and then all of the cards laid out when everything's gone around.
Rym: whoever played the highest card Takes all of those cards and does something with them.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: And the idea is either you want to or don't want to take the cards depending and in hearts.
Scott: You generally don't want to take the cards But sometimes you might because it won't matter because depends what cards you take.
Scott: generally you don't want to take hearts.
Rym: yep, the gist of hearts is pretty simple everyone score starts out at zero and Getting points is bad.
Rym: And anytime you take a trick that has a heart in it.
Rym: You get a point, right?
Scott: So let's say I put down the two of clubs.
Scott: All right guy to the left of me.
Scott: He has the only wheels in one club in his hand the five of clubs.
Scott: He puts that down.
Scott: the next guy is a whole mess of clubs, right?
Scott: He puts down the party.
Rym: He puts down the highest club.
Scott: He's gonna put down the king of clubs, right?
Scott: The fourth person doesn't have any clubs.
Scott: It's like a miracle.
Scott: Mostly me and the guy across from me have him.
Scott: It's crazy situation, right?
Scott: So he throws down the ace of hearts.
Scott: So then the guy who put well, you can't do that That's right.
Rym: No, yeah, you can't know you can't play a point card on the first trick.
Scott: All right the first one, but anyway I thought you were going with the open rule, but doesn't matter.
Scott: So he puts down the ace of hearts just for the example Right.
Scott: So now the guy put down the king of clubs is the highest of the suit.
Scott: that began the whole thing because clubs started The whole thing.
Scott: So this trick is a club trick and he put down the highest club.
Scott: So he has to take all four cards and one of them is a heart.
Scott: So he gets one point.
Rym: now Think about that.
Rym: Theoretically you could play like a five up to a diamonds the lowest diamond.
Rym: But if no one else somehow had any diamonds and they all play hearts you play the highest diamond you take all those cards.
Scott: Yeah, so there's a lot of strategy and you start out with 13 cards and once you play one It's gone.
Scott: whether it ends up you might end up in your in front of you It might end up in front of someone else and you gotta you know sort of You know decide when you want to take a trick.
Scott: when you don't want to take a trick whose turn is it gonna be?
Scott: if so And so because someone so takes a trick then they're the one who has to play the next card to start off the next.
Rym: go Yeah, which can be good or bad.
Rym: Sometimes you want to be that person.
Rym: Sometimes you don't yeah.
Scott: So if your hand is full of certain cards You might want to take one trick that say doesn't have any hearts in it.
Scott: Right and then that means you get to start it off and if you set it up just right you can start it off And start it off and start it off and clear out a bunch of cars that aren't worth anything And then as soon as the iron is hot throw out cars that get sent to other people and go
Rym: ha ha ha.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now the way the game works.
Rym: There's another factor I'm gonna bring up in a second and that's kind of the really fun is the most fun part again.
Rym: but the way the game ends up being set up is that each suit kind of has a different property like each suit ends up being Different because that every no matter what every game starts with whoever has the two of clubs has to play it.
Rym: So clubs always get played first.
Rym: and There's kind of like this thing of you want to get rid of the clubs early and all sort of whatever.
Rym: I mean, I'm not gonna get into the deep strategies of this game.
Rym: Yeah diamonds in real like traditional hearts are the neutral suit because there's not.
Rym: they have nothing special about them.
Rym: They're just cards.
Rym: They're diamonds.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: You don't have to start with them.
Rym: You never forced to play them.
Rym: They're just there.
Rym: Yeah, though a lot of people play a variant where the jack of diamonds is special and gives you a negative 10 points or something.
Scott: I never heard of that.
Rym: a lot of people play hearts.
Scott: that was BS.
Scott: The way the play hearts is the way Microsoft hearts plays hearts every other way is bullshit.
Rym: That's not gonna say Well, the thing is a three player.
Rym: hearts is just as good as for play.
Scott: Well, yeah, you know I'm talking about the rules of the game.
Scott: Not the number of players, but Spades.
Rym: I haven't brought up spades here cuz you know hearts.
Rym: Oh hearts are just worth a point and all what you don't want to Take.
Scott: hearts.
Scott: spades are normal except the queen of spades is worth 13 points, so if you'd end up taking the queen of spades in a trick, that's as bad as taking every heart.
Scott: It really sucks.
Scott: So generally what happens is the Queen.
Scott: someone one person has the queen of spades.
Rym: Someone's always got it unless you play in the three or five player game.
Scott: Yes, so that person right?
Scott: They have to sort of fight - they have to play the card eventually because you keep going until everyone runs out of cards.
Scott: They have to play that card in such a way that someone else takes it.
Scott: But let's say for example Right the queen of spades is the only spade they have and someone else plays the five of spades as the opening card.
Scott: They have no choice.
Scott: They have to play the queen of spades and take it they or else they're cheating.
Scott: There's no other decision for them.
Scott: So they have to sort of keep track of what cards are out and set up a situation.
Scott: Maybe you know take another trick.
Scott: that's only worth two points on purpose so that they can get control of the game So that they can get rid of the Queen, you know take two to not take 13 later.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now this game as we've that's it.
Rym: That's the whole game and it seems very simple.
Rym: Very simple cards.
Rym: Very simple rules.
Rym: there's not much to it, but I will say that the depth of strategy is Somewhat staggering and it'll take.
Rym: I haven't solved the game.
Rym: I'm not I'm not an option.
Rym: I mean, I'm a very good hearts player I'm pretty good.
Rym: I really I mean Scott and I are both really good.
Rym: we played it a lot at RIT.
Rym: actually we were freshmen, but Well, I'm nowhere near optimal and I don't know if I'll ever get optimal because it's a difficult game to mostly.
Scott: There's one thing that I'm so far from being optimal at and that is the one rule is shooting the moon.
Scott: now The rule shooting the moon works like this.
Scott: Let's say you really suck ass.
Scott: Let's say you get the worst cards possible, right?
Scott: You have like you couldn't get worse cards.
Scott: Well, if you manage to somehow take every single heart and the queen of spades You took all 26 points in the whole game, right?
Scott: You got them all.
Scott: You instead lose 26 points.
Rym: well good the original rule as far as I've seen is everyone else gets 26 points.
Scott: Oh, it's either way.
Scott: It doesn't really matter.
Rym: It does matter because then as a variant was you can choose there I lose 26 or everyone else gets 26.
Rym: The reason being I don't think we really said the victory condition because you play you don't just play like one go.
Rym: Whenever is the most points wins you just keep playing and playing and playing Until someone anyone in the game reaches an arbitrary score like a hundred or five hundred.
Rym: and The moment someone crosses over that high score the game is immediately over and whoever has the least points wins.
Rym: so sometimes shooting the moon if you're playing with the strict old everyone gets 26 points could make you lose the game even though you played awesomely or Conversely, let's say we're playing the not conversely.
Rym: We're playing a game me and Scott and two other people and Scott's really sucking for some reason.
Rym: He's got 99 points.
Rym: 100 is the win.
Rym: Now say our friend Alex has eight points.
Rym: He's doing great and me and the other guy are.
Rym: you know, we're in the middle somewhere.
Rym: No one wants Scott to take a trick because that ends the game and then Alex wins.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of the a lot of the strategy.
Scott: the game comes in the long term.
Scott: play, right?
Scott: Like for example, let's go back to the guy who had the Queen of Spades in his hand and no other spades in his hand Right.
Scott: He's trying to get rid of that thing.
Scott: He doesn't want to take 13 points and he doesn't have the stuff.
Scott: He can't shoot the moon, right?
Scott: So he's got it.
Scott: put it on someone else.
Scott: But let's say there are three other players in the game.
Scott: One of them has like 99 points one of them is 75 points and one of them is two points.
Scott: Not only does he want to get rid of it But he wants to give it to the guy who has two points.
Rym: and the game is complex enough to where you can set up Strategies to do that.
Rym: I mean like think of this.
Rym: you get to you pass cards around a little bit and the rules are pretty much Every round.
Rym: you either pass three cards to the person on your left in front of you to the right or maybe you don't pass Any and you have to pass three if it.
Rym: lets you so say you've got the Queen in your hand.
Rym: now You have to think to yourself.
Rym: All right, I have the Queen.
Rym: you might think oh obviously get rid of it You don't get stuck with it, but not so fast.
Rym: If you have the Queen you have control over the Queen.
Rym: well on a measure of control You have control as long as you were careful.
Rym: For example, let's say I have two diamonds and the Queen and a bunch of other cards, right?
Rym: So if I pass those two diamonds and some other card and I keep the Queen Huh?
Scott: Now I don't have any diamonds and you just wait because someone is really proud most likely 99% chance Someone's gonna put a diamond down and then you go Queen haha.
Rym: So the game tends to progress per hand as everyone's real cautious and people tend to try to Like a king and a seven.
Rym: I'm gonna play that seven because I'm worried the Queen might pop out but eventually the bitch comes and then Then the game just gets a lot faster and people aren't as worried.
Scott: The only one major flaw I find in hearts, but it's not specific to hearts It's a flaw in pretty much every trick-taking game with you know, Trump suits and what that.
Scott: what not is that app?
Scott: You're you're playing a game where basically it consists of playing 13 cards one at a time After you play about seven or eight depending on which cards they are.
Scott: It is usually the case that the rest of the round is just you know, a foregone conclusion.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like you get to a point and you're just like oh the rest of the tricks go to Rym.
Scott: You just give him all the cards and you don't bother but there's no more decision at the same time.
Rym: I like that because once there are no more decisions to be made among advanced players You just stop know how many points everyone got and play another hand.
Rym: because like Scott said the strategy the game Isn't directly in the play this hand as best as I can It's play the game over the long term as best I can.
Scott: I mean, yeah, I'll take tricks to prevent someone else from shooting the moon or I'll or sometimes I'll try to trick someone else into taking tricks, you know, like someone my guy my right is shooting the moon.
Scott: So I make a play such that the guy on my left is forced to take the trick with a heart in it.
Rym: I go ha ha ha.
Rym: or I know that the guy on there I'm pretty sure based on the cards the guy on the right gave me.
Rym: because say he gave me a two and a four of.
Rym: So I'm pretty sure unless he's bluffing me that he just gave up all his time.
Scott: That's not a good bluff because you don't want to do that.
Rym: No better off.
Rym: See this is another one of those games too where?
Rym: bluffing against novice players Only hurts you.
Rym: Yeah, but like if you're playing with four people who are all like super awesome at hearts Like seeing all right Scott just getting is just.
Scott: you know, you got a bluff with like a specific plan in mind.
Scott: Be like, uh-huh bluff him and that will throw him off.
Scott: No, you have to specifically be like, okay if I get rid of these two diamonds He'll think this and he'll play like this Which means I can do this with the hours that I have in my hand.
Scott: and if you don't have this specific plan Getting rid of like the two and the four diamonds if they're your only diamond is just crazy.
Scott: Well, if they're not your only diamonds, it's just stupid.
Rym: Yeah, but like here's a good strategy.
Rym: Let's say I've got a nice semi long run, but non-contiguous of die.
Rym: I got a bunch of diamonds Six or seven of them and I only have one club and One let's say heart.
Rym: Yep, cuz even you still it's nice to not have any hearts unless you only have low hearts.
Rym: But alright, so what I want to pass?
Rym: you might think alright pass the club.
Rym: No, you don't want to do that because if you pass the club It's easy to get rid of that club.
Scott: you get rid of it on the first turn.
Scott: Well, not only that.
Rym: Alright, I give up the club.
Rym: now the first turn happens.
Rym: I don't have any clubs I gotta play.
Rym: can't play a heart cuz it's the first turn.
Rym: You can't play a point card on the first turn because that kind of breaks the game.
Rym: Mm-hmm So great.
Rym: I have to reveal that I don't have any clubs immediately.
Rym: Yep Oh now everyone knows I don't have any clubs now.
Rym: either I have the Queen or I don't and one other player possibly to know if I have the Queen or not.
Rym: it's a game of knowledge and bluffing and skill and tactics and go and go and go and yeah plus remember you're at the Beginning of the round.
Scott: you usually pass some cards to someone.
Scott: so you know that.
Scott: let's say I get you think about.
Scott: you got to Think about it in two ways.
Scott: You got to think about it in.
Scott: Okay, I've got three spades here.
Scott: I'll get rid of the three spades.
Scott: I'll pass them the guy on my right.
Rym: So that's super dangerous.
Scott: No, no, but I'll let the high spades right but you pass three spades to the guy on your right, right?
Scott: Not only do you now you just did a good move getting rid of all your spades say, right?
Scott: But at the same time you got to remember that guy has those three cards.
Scott: that way as you go around.
Scott: You know you think huh?
Scott: Well, well, this is a good card to play and you think that guy has those three cards.
Scott: Yeah, and you go and he plays one of them.
Scott: You got to remember say he has those two cards.
Rym: Yep, and you also have to remember and look.
Rym: All right, someone else gave me three cards.
Rym: What does that tell me about what he has?
Rym: and then you also have to think?
Rym: What does my opponent to my left know based on the three cards?
Rym: I gave him.
Rym: Yep And the game is just fantastic and I really like playing it.
Scott: It's a pretty good game I gotta say and if you aren't playing hearts, you should probably a good place to play hearts.
Scott: actually, it depends on you know, if you play on Yahoo Games you could.
Scott: there's a little Java thing that lets you play hearts against People and for free.
Scott: the problem is some of the people in the community.
Scott: You're kind of a but you can find some nice social games on there where the people aren't so and where there's.
Scott: you know They don't really care about the score and the bullshit and it's a. it's a good place to play hearts against Novices and people who are amazing and will kick your ass all the time.
Rym: Yep Now we've left a lot out in terms of stress.
Scott: Oh, you can talk about hearts like I.
Rym: just I just want to say die if anyone out there tries to say well you guys overlook the blah blah strategy or You guys were really like.
Rym: that was a really simplified and dangerous strategy.
Rym: It's a special member lazy busy nosy Yeah, but I mean we know the strategies of hearts pretty well, and if you want if you wanted us to we could probably Talk about almost all of them Maybe almost all of them.
Scott: I got a. I got a study some more.
Scott: I haven't played hearts in a good long while.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: oh, it's a good idea though It's like I keep being bored at work playing flash games and the boss Microsoft our week.
Scott: I think no not Microsoft are saying you'll play hearts on Yahoo because I got Linux at work.
Scott: Ah Maybe Microsoft hearts also.
Rym: who knows Microsoft hearts ain't so bad.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's pretty good.
Scott: Plus they you know The one in Vista is pretty shiny.