Scott: It's Wednesday September 5th.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we review the old Oav L hazard.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: You may recall that I have been suffering for a little over a week because I've been forced to use the shitty ass Sony $10 headphone things instead of my usual Etymotic six-eye Solation thingies,
Rym: you know, I'd totally forgotten about that, but I just ordered a pair for me and Emily.
Scott: Yeah, but they're basically for anyone who hasn't listened to show ever before.
Scott: They're awesome earbuds, but it's unlike normal shit earbuds.
Scott: If you put them in your ears You can't hear anything except the music or podcast that is coming through them.
Scott: Thus you can turn the volume down really low.
Scott: even when you're in a loud place like the subway You're still able to hear what's being played and you save your ears a lot of damage.
Rym: and mr.
Rym: Train stop.
Scott: Yeah, I mugs you maybe but they're awesome and they're worth the money Especially if you care about having hearing later in life or even in very, you know soon in your life People lose a lot of hearing just going to concerts by the time they're like 30-something.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway anyway.
Scott: So I said there was a problem with them not that they were broken or anything at their fault.
Scott: But you know after being used for two or three years so much, you know They they become worn out and the wire going into the right ear was kind of loose and this audio would cut in and out.
Scott: So, you know rather than buy new ones because they were kind of expensive I call I emailed the company and I was like, alright company, you know, if I send you these that are working Can you just like rewire them because there's nothing wrong with the buds, you know, the things themselves, which is the expensive part.
Scott: I just need a new wire which is like a you know a few dollars, you know What can you do for me?
Scott: And they said well if you send them in for an RMA then we'll determine if the warranty is valid or not Which I know it wasn't because it's only a one-year warranty, right?
Scott: And if it is they'll just replace them and if it isn't then they'll charge me like $75 for replacement pair which is fine because that's a lot less than what they cause.
Scott: new, you know me That's and there's like one website that sells them for like seventy six dollars.
Scott: Yeah So I sent him in for FedEx, whatever and They didn't ever confirm that they received them which is sort of annoying.
Scott: But I had a FedEx tracking so I knew they received them and they never told me You know that they were sending them back or anything like that.
Scott: But I get home today and there's a box sitting on the porch.
Scott: and like what's this box?
Scott: and the return address was them.
Scott: So I'm like, oh, okay, and there was just a new pair in there and I read inside and it was like they were like Yeah, something, you know audio intermittent at the something whatever, you know.
Scott: They confirm the problem that I described and they just replaced them even though I had no warranty whatsoever on them anymore hot or anything.
Scott: so, you know if you're Deciding between those and say like I think sure has a new Isolation earbuds that like $100 now.
Rym: There's also the super expensive Bose ones that are totally not worth.
Rym: You
Scott: don't want those, you know, if you're trying to decide and these look, you know Too expensive for you or something like that you might want to consider going with them because the company has the customer service that is like a bajillion awesomes and honoring your warranty when it's not necessary to.
Rym: So as you all know this past weekend was Dragon Con and despite the fact that a bunch of our friends went we were just Too busy with life.
Scott: Yeah, cuz where is it Atlanta?
Scott: Yeah, and what kind of con is it?
Scott: Isn't it like a sci-fi fantasy?
Rym: ish con looks like it would be a good time and a lot of our friends went.
Rym: I actually wanted to go.
Rym: I just one.
Rym: I hate flying not for any fear of flying or anything like that.
Rym: I just I'm unlucky and every time I have flown since I was in high school Has been with incident.
Rym: either the flights all get canceled or there's a blizzard or my flight gets delayed.
Rym: I have to take some crappy little puddle jumper prop plane in the middle of nowhere.
Scott: I have never had a flying Incident ever though.
Scott: the worst that's ever happened to me is I had to wait in line For like an hour at West Palm Beach to get on a plane But I got on the plane on time because I got there early and there was no problems
Rym: and the fact that they made me Take my shoes off every time I tried to fly.
Rym: Yeah, I really don't like that.
Scott: So I don't like it either but I've never had a problem and amazement was the last year not this past year.
Rym: But the year before that was the last con I flew to and as much as I wanted to go to Dragon Con It wasn't worth flying and there's no way in hell.
Rym: I was driving to Atlanta.
Scott: I really didn't care about going to Dragon Con.
Rym: we're going to enough cons, but anyway friends from anime world order went and You know, they're about to drive home and I get a chat message.
Rym: Hey Rym, check it out.
Rym: We got some really great Audio from the con.
Rym: I can't wait for you to hear it.
Rym: I'll send it to you as soon as I get home.
Scott: I have someone to be that excited.
Scott: It must have been something pretty awesome going on.
Rym: well, apparently the reactions to the crowds at the con about Anime and anime related things were somewhat funny Uh-huh.
Scott: Well, it doesn't sound to me like it's an anime con.
Scott: So if you go around animating, you know, there's usually a lot of there might be a bunch of grumpy nerds.
Scott: We're like, yeah those anime kids, you know, it's funny.
Rym: you know now that I think about this because one of the primary things that anime world order always rails about is People who go to a con and aren't all about the topic of the con, you know A guy at anime con dressed up as a stormtrooper.
Rym: You were anime podcasters at a non anime con.
Rym: shut your holes Yeah, but anyway.
Rym: so uh the next morning I See a chat message to our email from them and it basically said yeah that audio all silence.
Rym: No, I fucked up.
Scott: What happened?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: How could that happen apparent?
Scott: Well one I think we're the only people out there who have an actual solid-state recorder worth a damn Well, everyone else uses like the I River and stuff, which is a solid-state recorder, but you know, it's it's really well.
Rym: What's it?
Rym: barely an mp3 player and I'm not gonna expect.
Rym: apparently one of the audios Something where someone was saying something about Dave and Joel is the only thing that got recorded Alrighty then.
Rym: So yeah, I found that hilarious.
Rym: and that's all I really got to say Nothing.
Rym: I didn't go to the con.
Rym: But oh the panels were subpar and all the things I would normally say.
Rym: But I don't know.
Scott: I don't know anything about the con really other than it's called dragon con.
Scott: It's sort of famous and it's in Atlanta and I guess enemy world order went For me.
Rym: that con is in the same list is like Jana, ma, ma Boston.
Scott: Oh and me.
Scott: it's in the same list as gen con.
Scott: It's one of those just general nerdiness cons that I don't really care about or go to.
Scott: that's sort of old and tradition.
Rym: But whatever see I like cons like that.
Rym: I just none of them are near us.
Rym: So that's the end of that.
Scott: Yep, anything else?
Scott: Not really?
Scott: Okay, so DC Comics who we are not the biggest fans of at least We're not the biggest fans of comics with the DC label on them because they're usually underwear pervert crap.
Scott: they sell their books in comic book stores and also in bookstores.
Scott: right and comic book stores, of course the company that brings the comics from DC to the comic book store is diamond because that the only company that brings things comic book store.
Rym: Yeah, we we've talked about diamond distributors before.
Rym: we're not gonna get into that.
Scott: No, we're not.
Scott: what we're gonna get into is the company that brings DC's books to the bookstores.
Scott: and Basically what was going on?
Scott: was the company that was doing this for DC was like Warner Books or something?
Scott: I think it was Warner Books.
Scott: and Because DC is owned by Warner Brothers, you know, that's why you see all the DC sort of cartoons.
Scott: I'm like the WB and stuff like that.
Rym: All right.
Scott: So obviously Warner Books would be distributing the DC Comics to the bookstores, but this company like Hachette book group purchased Warner Books a while ago.
Scott: so DC Finally said alright, we're gonna have someone else bring our books to the bookstores they're gonna have Random House do it and this might seem kind of like a What-the-fuck money pages news.
Scott: who gives a shit?
Scott: Well, the point is is that if you haven't noticed the manga and such things has been Doing real well in the in the bookstores.
Rym: Well, yeah I believe the last time we looked at statistics pretty much every like all the comic books combined didn't outsell even the moderately popular manga yep, and The comic books.
Scott: they're trying to print trades and things to sell them in the bookstores But they're not selling too.
Scott: Well, and it's like why wouldn't you know one comic sell too?
Scott: Well, you know and the other one doesn't and a lot of people like oh, it's the authenticity of the manga.
Scott: Oh, it's you know.
Scott: There's something else of the manga and that's just BS because the OELs are doing just fine and they're totally fooling everyone.
Scott: and there's no reason that you know, the Marvels and the DCs couldn't do the same thing.
Scott: and Random House, which I think all you know, it does what they do.
Scott: I think they own Del Rey don't the story have a point.
Scott: The point is is that you can expect DC to do a much better job of selling their books to bookstores.
Scott: And I think that with the help of Random House who actually knows what the fuck they're doing You know selling graphic novels to bookstores You're gonna see them catch up at least in the bookstore area and if they catch up enough The comic book store might be taking another hit which is fine by me.
Scott: Uh-huh, it's actually sort of like a premonition of things to come.
Scott: it shows the DC actually cares about what the bookstores stuff is happening and they're gonna try to make a move on it as Opposed to what we previously thought which is they're just complex store nerds doing everything stupidly.
Rym: Well, it wasn't that they were doing things terribly stupidly.
Rym: It was more that their business model seemed to be get a devout fan following and then milk them for all their worth.
Scott: that still seems to be their business model, but I think that The reason that they you know have been continuing to do the monthly comic crap is because they can make a lot of money there You know and then with the ads and with you know The incredibly high price for incredibly little content and then eventually they collect things into a trade and they're able to make a little bit more money in the bookstores.
Scott: if Random House does a good job, like it's been doing with their other comics and things then They can make so much money in the bookstores.
Scott: Maybe they'll just give up on the comic bookstores.
Rym: huh, I don't know about that because a lot of the really hardcore comic fans they like their little subscription where you know, They show up to the comic store once a month and pick up their box, right?
Scott: And those people make X dollars, you know They make them X dollars per whatever.
Scott: if you start making just so much insane amounts of money from the bookstore Where you could have been making the money all along and you just haven't been Then you don't need to waste your time with that small change anymore.
Scott: And the only reason they waste their time with that small change is the only small change they've got.
Rym: See, it's really hard to say I mean, I don't really like a lot of those comics I don't really pay attention to them.
Scott: Yeah, well being decent, you know, this also Reno counts for everything else DC publishes not just the underwear pervert stuff So all the vertigo stuff and the wild stuff.
Rym: That's a lot more interesting.
Scott: You see that's DC.
Scott: Oh that that's all DC Comics.
Scott: It just doesn't say DC on it.
Rym: I think that's a very calculated move on their part.
Rym: Yeah Anyways, so, you know, we normally talk about anime news But I was looking through the various news sources we have and there's basically Jack all There's really nothing I care about.
Rym: and you know, oh this show was announced this show wasn't.
Scott: there was nothing particularly Interesting or fascinating and all con seasons over every anime companies made their announcements.
Scott: What else is there to say?
Rym: Yeah I mean I could talk about stuff that's coming up.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: in December.
Scott: I think in December we'll talk about December.
Rym: Yeah, maybe in November.
Rym: We'll start previewing what we're gonna be doing.
Rym: But So this is so barely related to anime that it's kind of sad.
Rym: But it's on the anime news network and it happens to be about Japan.
Rym: So I'm going with it.
Scott: Yeah, anything that happens in Japan is anime news apparently.
Rym: So what other anime news sources there?
Scott: anime news service dot-com Right.
Rym: So DVD according to this article love hotels in Japan Make more than twice as much money as the anime industry.
Scott: that makes sense.
Rym: Yeah, I don't doubt that at all and My only point is simply why don't we have love hotels in the US?
Rym: I think they'd be really convenient particularly in big cities.
Scott: I think we do have love hotels.
Scott: They're seedy.
Scott: they're seedy and we don't have a lot of them and they're not sort of public But they're just.
Rym: there's no place in New York City where a guy can just get his groove on Nicely with someone who isn't a prostitute.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, there really isn't and I don't know.
Scott: I think if we open those things a lot of crazy people would be trying to shut them down.
Rym: Now what I find more interesting though I'm highly dubious of this number.
Rym: the article makes a claim that in according to a study about 50% of all sexual intercourse between Japanese people living in Japan Occurs in love hotels, that's a bit much.
Scott: I don't I. I think I think that's just reported.
Scott: I mean there's so much going on in places that they don't know about that.
Scott: They're not counting.
Rym: highly dubious remains Doubtful.
Rym: he doubt she has.
Scott: I mean I would.
Scott: I would accept maybe 30% of all Japanese sex is in love hotels because love hotels are really popular there and really awesome.
Scott: And if I was in Japan, I'd Brian I was having sex.
Scott: I'd have sex in love hotels a lot.
Rym: Anyway enough of that.
Rym: It's time for things of the day alright.
Scott: Let's get to the good business now Not that crap business.
Scott: You're just dealing with.
Scott: so you know about 4chan the website.
Rym: Why?
Rym: yes, I do.
Scott: well some people out there might not in which case lucky them.
Rym: lucky indeed
Scott: regardless if you would like to get familiar with say I don't know the The aesthetic stylings of 4chan and in a rather you know quick manner There is a video here on YouTube, and if you watch this you will know everything there is to know about 4chan.
Rym: It's pretty much a documentary About.
Scott: I call it a documentary because it doesn't actually document, but well certainly the same function in that you watch it and You get all the knowledge that you need to get.
Rym: so you see the way I would say it was the documentary.
Rym: is that from the perspective of a 4chan or in the fortune if 4chan made a documentary This is what it would look like.
Scott: oh probably this is what you would get.
Scott: I fortune Collectively made anything.
Scott: This is what it looked like because it looks like fortune.
Scott: It's just fortune in in the form of a five-minute video, and it's worth watching.
Scott: so you never have to go to fortune.
Rym: The the best part in this video.
Rym: I was going to avoid this and just say seeking and let Scott say the response to that And then move on.
Rym: but
Scott: yeah
Rym: There's this style of humor that wasn't started by fortune And it was started as far as I know with a comedy goldmine on something awful entitled Lord of the Rings on the go and it is the style of take a face of a Character from a movie and make it big and put it on something and possibly change it or anime.
Scott: I'm pretty sure that Lord of the Rings on the go is not the original place for that style of comedy.
Rym: originally however I've never seen anything before that was like that.
Rym: if anyone can find it enlighten me, but Fortune has really jumped on this concept with my favorite King King Leonidas.
Rym: It's not just fortune, but it is a mostly fortune That's doing this and I just want to say in this video the scene from that terrible movie final destination Or the sequel what I know is one of the final destination movies because I remember seeing that scene.
Rym: There's a scene where King lion Leonidas kills a guy, and you'll know it when it happens.
Rym: All right, I quite enjoyed that.
Rym: it was a good one definitely, but anyway Ha ha ha the suit suit Ava who bazot zot numb.
Rym: I can't believe Who a ta a ta who a ta a nom nom?
Scott: I can't believe this hasn't been a thing of the day before.
Rym: so I think we talked about this way back And we had Jeff to Tarik on the show and we were talking about anime music videos.
Scott: Yeah, this is a classic thing of the day right here.
Rym: This is I would say I would argue One of the top 50 anime music videos ever made I'd say top 15 I would.
Rym: I think I could definitely go there.
Rym: It's just so perfectly timed so fit to a concept Original in its choice of song.
Rym: the song by the way is I believe haba haba zoot suit by the band Caramba But I I'm not sure if I made that up anyway.
Rym: and the sad scary thing is that Scott and I both know the entire song by heart and It might sound silly because it sounds like the song is just gibberish, but now we could karaoke this and we could do it convincingly.
Scott: Yeah, I've seen the video so many times and it's not exactly that complicated.
Scott: all I remember like three verses And you're good to go, and then you have to remember the timing of like the mori mori.
Scott: That's the best part.
Rym: ava ava mori mori yep You're good to go now also Coincidentally this video happens to be concerning The show we're talking about tonight one of my favorite anime one of the classics definitely a top 20 anime I know is that 20 anime, but it's a top 20.
Rym: It's definitely it's.
Scott: it's an above-average anime everyone should watch.
Scott: It's not like an a-plus anime.
Scott: It's like a.
Rym: I think it's a minus b-plus anime.
Rym: It's right up there.
Rym: Yeah, but we're talking about El Hazzard the magnificent world the original Oav.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: wait wait we're talking about an OAV here.
Scott: How many episodes was it like?
Scott: six I think Seven seven a seven episode OAV named El Hazzard the magnificent world.
Scott: we are not talking about all right.
Rym: well First off if you think you can buy this anime You're wrong if you see it for less than a hundred dollars.
Rym: It's either bootleg or it's not the right thing.
Scott: So uh or tell us about it right because we haven't been able to find it.
Rym: yes in fact I will pay like up to seventy five dollars for a non bootleg copy of the original OAV of El Hazzard The cheapest I found it at Otakon was a hundred and nine.
Scott: Anyway, that's a lot for seven episodes.
Rym: it is so El Hazzard the magnificent world was no a V Directed by a man named Hiroki Hayashi.
Rym: You might know this gentleman from the original tenchi muyo Oav but not from a lot of other tenchi stuff, and I'll get to that.
Rym: so uh they directed El Hazzard Which is magnificent?
Rym: It's great.
Rym: That is what we were talking about.
Rym: Not too long after that they made a spin-off called El Hazzard.
Scott: the wanderers don't watch it.
Rym: It was a TV show.
Rym: it's 26 episodes.
Rym: It's basically the exact same show only drawn out and for reasons that we'll get into when we review the real show It's not that good And it's not that funny And it's not worth watching.
Scott: someone takes seven episodes of stuff and stretches it out over.
Scott: what 26 episodes?
Scott: It's not gonna be worth your time.
Scott: you could have just watched the seven episodes.
Rym: it has some funny moments But it's not worth watching seriously.
Rym: And if you doubt me watch the OAV then watch the first Episode or two of the wanderers, and you'll see that it's just.
Rym: it's not up to stuff.
Rym: So anyway that whatever they decided then and by they I mean people other than the original creator and director To make a sequel to El Hazzard.
Rym: El Hazzard to the magnificent world which is also an OAV.
Scott: But isn't it not only bad, but also Lesbians?
Rym: well the first El Hazzard was good.
Rym: the second El Hazzard here is Pretty much just edgy kind of porny crap.
Rym: It's just it's dribble.
Rym: It's not good It's not worth watching.
Rym: wasn't directed by the same guy.
Rym: Kind of crappy, but wait.
Scott: There's more is there really?
Scott: is there a manga there.
Rym: Ah yes There is.
Rym: it's not so great, but then there is El Hazzard the alternative world.
Rym: now We've already got to at least two Alternative worlds to El Hazzard the TV show and the OAV world.
Rym: as far as I'm concerned the real OAV world stops at the end Of the first one, but then there's this alternative world.
Rym: Ho-ho, it's after the second OAV and all our friends get transported to another dimension and everything's all kooky And it's just shit.
Scott: so we've got here.
Scott: we have an OAV a Sequel to that OAV a TV series that tells the same story as the original OAV and a Another alternate universe that tells a story.
Scott: after the sequel to the OAV is that a TV series the the alternate world.
Rym: But they're all OAVs except for though.
Scott: It's like 12 for the wanders.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, and we've got a manga and all of them are complete shit except.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: I'm wrong.
Rym: alternative world was a TV.
Scott: They're all complete shit except for the original OAV.
Scott: There's only one of these things is worth watching yet all of them are called El Hazzard.
Rym: now funnily enough I said that this director You know he only did the original first OAV of Tenchi and like one other thing the Miyoshi special Which is actually pretty funny.
Rym: I will note that almost all I mean I like Tenchi.
Rym: I think Tenchi Muyo was a pretty good show.
Rym: Almost all of the Tenchi Muyo TV shows and OAVs and spin-offs and specials After that much like El Hazzard were not directed by this person and are really crappy.
Scott: It seems like this guy has sort of a habit of starting something that people like and then Rather than continue on and make more of it other people come along take the property and they make more of it And they seem to ruin it completely so that the people who like the original do not like what they continue with.
Rym: now There's a lot more to that story, but unlike other shows I don't think you want us to talk about the director for an hour, so I think we'll leave it at that.
Rym: Yeah But I cannot stress enough.
Rym: do not bother watching El Hazzard unless it is the original OAV.
Rym: Now you might ask us well Rym and Scott How can we get a hold of the OAV?
Rym: and the answer is I don't know.
Scott: I don't know either.
Rym: I really want to see it.
Rym: No It's not.
Scott: We watched a tape of VHS tape of it that Rym taped off the sci-fi channel when he was a kid and happened to still Have when we were freshmen at RIT.
Scott: That's the only way we were able to see it.
Rym: yes there there were some fan subs of it in the anime club library But we threw those away.
Rym: I forget why?
Rym: probably because they were illegal.
Scott: I don't know, but there are DVDs.
Scott: We just have a hard time finding them and when we do find them.
Scott: They're expensive, and they're you know.
Scott: I'm sure There's bootlegs out there also, but you know they're bootlegs.
Rym: I'm not down with that.
Rym: no because the I mean actually I really want to own the original DVD even though I really think at some point this show is gonna get re-released in some fashion.
Scott: Well, it's one of those shows that you know only that like people who were it's sort of like one of those shows.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's not an unknown show But it's not a super A+.
Scott: everyone knows about it show and thus people who are really into anime at the time When the show comes out notice it, but people who are into anime at any other time don't notice it And it's just gone.
Scott: You know it just sort of disappears, but people were into anime at the time it came out.
Scott: It's a show they noticed and only those people seem to remember the show or care about it at all in any way.
Rym: But anyway, if you want to know what the hell is this show about now We're going to be very careful to avoid spoilers because the show is short enough And it moves quickly enough to where it's pretty easy to ruin a lot of the seven episodes.
Rym: If I tell you what happens in the second episode we're already well into the story ruining things Yeah, but what I do want to say is that the show is a drama and a comedy And it's one of those rare shows that pulls off both and a fantasy.
Rym: well Yeah, but it pulls them off equally and well And that's saying a lot because a lot of shows tried to do that and fail.
Scott: This is one of those shows where it's.
Scott: it's really just about a cast of characters and all but none of them suck.
Scott: They're all awesome in some way particularly mr.. Fujisawa and also jinai and his sister and The bug queen pretty much everyone.
Scott: yeah, right and those magic girls the the one with the red hair who's all crazy.
Rym: So the story of El Hazzard is basically there's this guy Makoto and he's in high school, and he's really kind of awesome.
Scott: He's a stalwart stand-up really smart guy, and there's some other people in the high school who are Annoying or funny in their own ways like jinai his rival.
Rym: Yes The original.
Rym: when you watch the show like the issue is makoto is just a good guy and jinai is well jinai if you If you want to understand this character music video thing of the day pretty much spot-on.
Rym: So Makoto is friends with jinai nominally and likes him and just really nice to him and doesn't seem to have any issue with him.
Rym: but jinai has unspecified issues with Makoto Also, he's scheming and evil, and he pulled some shady business to be the head of the student council and all this business.
Rym: Makoto ends up getting him kicked off and There's kind of this flashback montage of all the reasons why jinai hates makoto And that is one of the funniest things in the entire show.
Rym: It's definitely a pretty funny bit and it's basically just makoto is better and smarter than jinai in every Possible and conceivable way and even when he isn't by dumb luck he just always wins.
Scott: and jinai Just keeps getting more and more pissed off and he tries more and more crazier things to come out on top.
Scott: But he sort of doesn't care about being evil or anything like that.
Rym: So it kind of ends with it.
Rym: Well in the beginning that plot with him snapping and like trying to kidnap makoto and tie him up in an office somewhere.
Rym: I don't know what he planned to do with him.
Scott: Yeah, that was just sort of crazy.
Rym: That was to prevent him from testifying in an impeachment trial.
Rym: I forget exactly, but that's not the plot.
Rym: because then sure enough Underneath the school they find some ancient ruins.
Scott: Yeah, sort of completely randomly, but they do foreshadow it because they show you the ancient ruins a few times.
Scott: But the characters in the show Really have nothing to do with these ancient ruins until they randomly stumble upon them.
Scott: so
Rym: one thing leads to another and makoto ends up in these ancient ruins and a thing happens and opens up and we don't really Know why and there's a woman in there and she falls into his arms and says something to the effect of I've waited so long To see you again, and then she sends him off to El Hazzard and then the story really begins.
Scott: Yeah basically it's one of those get transported to a fantasy world shows where a bunch one or more people in the Normal world that is a lot like our world end up in a fantasy world and they get tied up in the adventure and the politics Of that fantasy world.
Scott: and then do they get back at the end to the real world?
Rym: You Really got to avoid spoiling.
Rym: but what the thing that really works about this show that a lot of you know Someone gets sent off to a magical world shows fail at is that all the characters deal with it and interesting and sometimes Hilarious ways and it's really not kind of ours.
Scott: I think one thing that's really cool is how normally, you know Like an eska flown if she gets transported to the other world, right and what she's just a girl in another world That that's it in this a sort of comedically and also plotly I guess if that's a word.
Scott: every person who gets sent to the other world ends up with some sort of power.
Rym: Um, I think you forget that.
Rym: who told me dad's quite a bit of power in Eska flown a and she's pivotal to but not like not like this.
Scott: This is more like they have a direct superpower.
Rym: She has a superpower.
Rym: She just doesn't realize how powerful it is until near the end of the show.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I know what you're saying.
Scott: I'm like, mr Fujisawa is the is the teacher and he gets sent to the other world.
Scott: now mister Fujisawa is the is the comedic relief of greatness.
Rym: He is the smokiness drink in his Fuji saw a kick kind of awesome professor.
Scott: and when he gets sent to the other world He basically becomes the drunken master as long as he's Inebriated.
Rym: No, it's the exact.
Scott: All right.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: He's so drunken in the normal world But so.
Scott: but when he's in the fantasy world when he is sober He has superpowers of fighting and kicking ass, but it's hard for him to stay sober because he's an alcoholic.
Rym: There's an awesome scene in the beginning.
Rym: when they're first in this world it's just cuz actually the other cool thing.
Rym: all the characters get split up and then all kind of comes back together later, but Makoto and Fuji saw her together and they're.
Rym: they get attacked by giant bugs Oh Noah's.
Rym: and Fuji saw would discovers he has superpowers and starts kicking their asses.
Rym: So Makoto says oh man I bet I have superpowers too.
Rym: This is great and he totally doesn't and he totally gets his ass.
Rym: He has some other powers Yeah, but that doesn't come in later.
Scott: No, it doesn't.
Scott: but yeah everyone everyone who gets transports the other world has powers and Some of them are.
Scott: they're all different and they're all hilarious or useful in some way that you'll just have to find out.
Rym: I love out.
Rym: I mean Jedi's sister.
Rym: You don't really see a lot of her but she's in the world and she's basically just getting by Being a shopkeeper and selling food to people and working as a waitress and just kind of living her life.
Scott: Yeah I don't.
Scott: she's definitely like one of the best characters in the show because she she's a lot does a lot of the things that You would never see a character in the same kind of show do like people who go to other worlds.
Scott: You know in anime they don't do that sort of thing.
Scott: So to see her do that sort of thing It's like yeah, that's what I would do.
Rym: All right so Jenna and this is the part where I'm gonna kind of leave you.
Rym: after this Jenna ends up by himself and these same bugs kind of come around and Realizes that he can talk to these bugs and he kind of likes him and they kind of like him.
Rym: So they sit around and talk and one thing leads to another and he ends up leading The Empire of these bugs and he's a great general among their people.
Scott: now The guy who was super annoying in high school that was evil and scheming is now the bug Emperor It's got.
Rym: I mean it's kind of an interesting thing that now that like jinn I has actually a lot of potential and he's very smart and he's just He's actually a very confident person.
Rym: Yeah but the real world the world of you know you and me going to school really didn't let him get out his full potential because When is he gonna be a general of a bug army in high school unless he finds a jar of ants somewhere?
Scott: I think that's one thing that makes the show pretty interesting.
Scott: Is that if you have a short attention span like a YouTube watching kid?
Scott: You have all these different characters that you're looking after.
Scott: right?
Scott: some that are that we're always living in the fantasy world and some that were from the high school and travel to the fantasy world and others that who knows you maybe meet later and They're not together in like this party.
Scott: So you're always looking at all these different things going on.
Scott: You'll see the bug rooms, then you'll see something with these characters.
Scott: then you'll see these characters wandering in the woods and these characters in the castle and these characters in the other castle or something.
Scott: and It keeps moving around and you've got all these different things.
Scott: you're watching and they all sort of come together like they do in good stories and You're never gonna be bored watching it because as soon as some part of the show gets boring like you're tired of Janai and his Bug room, they're not funny anymore You'll be back in the castle where there's some castle hijinks going
Rym: on.
Rym: See now this is actually one of the show's greatest strengths And I think it's also conversely the exact reason that the Wanderers was pretty crappy.
Rym: The show was short enough to where and the action moves at such a pace.
Rym: It's seven episodes people pretty much the moment you start getting bored with any given plot line or any given situation.
Rym: It just kind of moves on just as you start to get bored with it And as a result, you never really get bored with it.
Rym: and then the show's over.
Scott: I mean you've seen how many you know travel to another fantasy world animes, right?
Scott: Well, usually that you get you're like.
Scott: I seen this before I'm done here.
Scott: I got nothing to see whatever But when it's only seven episodes, you'll be done before you start saying I've seen this before whatever.
Scott: I
Rym: mean eska flown a did this really well, too even though that might have been by accident because According to the story eska flown a was supposed to be I think 39 episodes and they cut it short so they compressed a whole bunch of plot into the end
Scott: didn't seem to hurt it
Rym: well.
Rym: as a result the show got a lot tighter and This show took that to the extreme.
Rym: The show is really tight.
Rym: It's no AV it's yes, but no part of it drags out Really?
Rym: It just keeps moving along and it's really solid in that regard.
Rym: The Wanderers meanwhile just drags and drags and drags and drags and drags and I couldn't bear finishing it.
Scott: And while the story itself is not some like, you know Amazing literary story that's going to enlighten you for all time with some amazing message.
Scott: It's not a bad story.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's a very good story and it's well-written and there's no like loose ends hanging around and everything makes sense.
Scott: And it's cool.
Scott: and the characters are all there.
Scott: There aren't any really characters.
Scott: You don't like in the show.
Scott: I mean some are better than others, but there aren't any characters like all that character again.
Scott: I don't want to watch them fast forward.
Scott: It's all of them are good.
Scott: All right, some were paying attention to someone now.
Rym: All right Yeah, I mean like Scott said the plots really solid and it you know it starts out a kind of this there's ruins under the high school.
Rym: blah blah blah girl says something go and Everything gets resolved in a very well done way and it's not an ending that I predicted at all.
Scott: No, it's definitely not something that you would predict mostly because you don't know enough about what's gonna happen.
Scott: You know until you're into it and then it ends so quickly You didn't have time to think about what was gonna happen.
Scott: It's like just as you start to think Oh, maybe it'll end like this.
Scott: Oh, it just ended.
Scott: It's only seven episodes.
Scott: Oops Okay, the end awesome.
Scott: Anything else to say about El hazard?
Scott: Oh, it's not El hazard.
Scott: By the way, if you say that I'm gonna smack you.
Scott: Yeah, El hazard and only the first OAV is worth watching.
Rym: I guess we could talk a little bit about the dub because the dub is you know It's from that era of anime like the late 90s.
Scott: It's like all those other dubs from that time.
Rym: It's not great It's not terrible.
Rym: It's watchable.
Rym: I don't believe there are too many terrible inaccuracies But I can't recall because I haven't seen the dub in I don't know nine years Did I never see the sub?
Scott: I think because we've only watched that dub VHS from sci-fi channel.
Rym: I've seen both but I can't recall.
Rym: I mean when I saw the sub that was back when I wasn't as Familiar with the Japanese amazing.
Scott: I remember as much about the show as I do considering I haven't seen it in like six years.
Rym: Well, because it's a really good show.
Scott: It was really good and I want to watch it again.
Scott: That's not good.
Scott: It was one thing.
Rym: I remember from the dub is that there's a scene early on where this.
Rym: You'll know it when it happens, but ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Maybe that was taken from the sub.
Scott: It's tough to tell ba ba ba.
Rym: No, that was definitely from the doubt.
Rym: now They might have done something similar in the sub.
Scott: But yeah, you notice sometimes we'll say something like ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba that that's from El Hazzard.
Rym: That's a fairly obscure El Hazzard reference a very obscure El Hazzard reference.
Scott: you go around anime con you go ba ba ba.
Scott: No one's gonna know what the hell you're doing.
Scott: However, if someone does that person is either a really scary nerd or they're us.
Rym: I Think we'll leave it at that.
Scott: Yeah, you should try to find El Hazzard.
Scott: help us try to find it.
Rym: Maybe that'd be nice Yes, but because I mean I don't want to ruin anything about the story in the plot.
Rym: But the show is super worth watching and I highly highly highly highly recommend it.
Scott: and Before you spend money on it You might want to contact us to make sure you're buying the right thing because we don't want anyone out there to accidentally buy One of the other hell hazards.
Scott: That's a complete waste of time.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.