Rym: It's Tuesday, May 22nd.
Rym: I'm Rym And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we talk about how to get into role-playing games twice.
Rym: So a funny little fact about resound the program we use to record GeekNights.
Rym: So while you're recording it gives you this nice little interface where you can click and add a queue and it shows you you know Where in the episode you just clicked.
Rym: so I can go back and edit stuff out.
Rym: I can add an anchored cue which gives me a cue based on time.
Rym: so I could say this is the five-minute mark.
Rym: No matter what editing I do It'll always be at the five-minute mark and it shows me the levels and how much I've recorded and how much I can record And how much memory it's taken up.
Rym: It shows the DC offset.
Rym: I can do a bunch of stuff and Right along the bottom here.
Rym: There are three buttons record slash resume stop slash pause and redo slash reset.
Rym: now.
Rym: Well when I do the show I normally click record we do the show click stop and then I click OK and it writes it Out to the disk.
Rym: I do point out that redo reset is directly next to stop pause and a little while ago as we had just talked for 26 minutes and change about the news today.
Rym: I went to click on stop pause and for some reason I moved a little bit too far to the right and I clicked on Redo reset and before I could even blink the entire show was gone and Rym could die in a fire.
Rym: It totally sucked because we didn't know the last time we lost a show.
Scott: I can be done with the show right now.
Scott: I'd be go playing pokemons right now, but no no I'm here talking and saying shit.
Rym: I already said the last time this happened I didn't feel so bad.
Scott: a quantum recorder that can go back and get things.
Rym: I already said back from well You know This is more case that we should just buy an SSR because then we could always record to that Simultaneous to the computer as the backup no matter what happens.
Scott: I've been saying this and you still haven't bought one.
Rym: Well, cuz we're splitting it 50/50.
Rym: I'm not dropping 300 bucks on an SSR.
Scott: I'll go find one first.
Rym: Mr Genius, I found several which one a bunch of them.
Rym: They're they're all the same.
Rym: They all work.
Rym: We'll pick one out All right, then.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, we're gonna force ourselves to go through the news again, though We're probably not gonna make all the same jokes we made last time and we're probably not gonna talk for 26 minutes.
Scott: We'll probably talk for significantly less minutes cuz my pokemons there.
Rym: Luckily much of what we lost was us talking about Puerto Rico, which we played over the weekend.
Scott: Yes, and we just decided hey, we never.
Scott: I don't think we ever did a Puerto Rico episode.
Rym: So we're gonna do one Yep, so luckily you won't have to hear that story twice.
Scott: Nope you won't Okay, so what was the news?
Scott: My news is that Nintendo put out a thing that basically listed all the Wii and DS games that are coming out between July and September and most of the games are crap like I don't know Holly hobby and friends.
Rym: all that games gonna be awesome.
Scott: Yeah, Crayola treasure adventures.
Rym: Oh fuck Advance Wars.
Scott: That's my new game Yep, so I'm gonna go over the games that pretty much are gonna be possibly worth playing, you know I'll tell you if they're gonna be definite buys or maybe buys.
Rym: I will point out the joke we made last time and I just want to bring this up.
Rym: Yeah, and it's been kind of my shtick lately But I can't eloquently will elegantly bring it back in now out the magic's gone But pretty much any time I play any game on the Wii I say it's the best game out for the Wii right now Which lately has been mostly?
Scott: Soul caliber - I'll tell you that the we everybody votes channel is the best game for the Wii.
Rym: Yeah I don't know.
Rym: ice hockey is really up in the running for the best game on the Wii.
Rym: that - cuz the thing is There really aren't any good Wii games.
Scott: No, not really not at all.
Scott: There aren't gonna be a apparently many more until beyond September.
Scott: Cuz the only.
Scott: there's only two games on this list for the Wii.
Scott: I hate to say it about.
Rym: I would be better off if the Wii were doing less Well, because if it were doing less well, Nintendo would be putting out more games to try to make it do better.
Rym: Instead it's still selling.
Rym: it's still sold out practically everywhere.
Rym: They're selling so many they could never make a game again and still have made tons of money.
Scott: Yep So the first game we're talking about is Mario strikers charged Which is the sequel to Mario strikers and it's coming out for the Wii on July 30th.
Rym: I'm looking forward to this.
Scott: Yeah, I think we told this story in the pre.
Scott: I'm not gonna keep saying that we said things in the pre cuz.
Scott: you know what everything we're about to say.
Rym: We already said earlier today, but suffice to say we fucked up when it came to strikers.
Scott: Yes, Mario strikers an excellent game.
Scott: I played the store demo and I loved it But I didn't buy it because it was 50 bucks and I thought that that was too much to play for a soccer game.
Rym: Never mind the fact that back then we were actually bored and needed games.
Scott: We were bored and we needed a two-player game.
Scott: badly.
Scott: Here was a great one.
Scott: We didn't buy it because we thought it was too much.
Rym: We'd stand there in the store like 50 bucks.
Rym: I'd pay 40, but let's just wait until the price comes down.
Rym: and the price never came down.
Scott: It never came down ever.
Scott: as a result.
Scott: We bought Mario strikers for the same amount.
Scott: We're like $50.
Scott: We eventually broke down and all that did was we played Mario strikers but we got less fun out of it because we bought it weeks later and we Basically paid the same amount of money in order to have like a couple months less playtime with the game.
Scott: I mean we could play it now.
Scott: Maybe we should but it's I don't know.
Rym: Suffice to say it's a great game.
Rym: And while we played it and enjoyed it we missed out on the Golden Age of it.
Scott: Yep, and in July 30th, it's gonna be replaced by the Wii sequel.
Rym: I'm kind of looking forward to that.
Scott: Yeah, very much.
Scott: So I think it's gonna have internet play.
Scott: So beware.
Rym: Oh, that would be hot.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: the next game August 20th Metroid Prime 3.
Scott: I'm all about it.
Scott: I'm kind of indifferent but uh, his rims-e-heathen who doesn't like Metroid.
Rym: I don't terribly enjoy Metroid games now.
Scott: That's all there is to it.
Rym: So, uh, what'd you think of Metroid hunters?
Scott: Metroid hunters is probably the only bad Metroid game the only bad Metroid game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Can you think of any others?
Rym: Uh, see I could be funny and say yeah Metroid But I can't cuz.
Rym: well I didn't I mean.
Scott: the one complaint you can have about Metroid Prime 2 is that it was basically the same thing as Metroid Prime 1 only with a different map and they change.
Scott: they had like all the same bad guys But they changed the colors on him.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: It was still more Metroid Prime 1 and Metroid Prime 1 was great and Metroid Prime 2 was just more of the same.
Scott: So it was still good.
Scott: It wasn't bad.
Rym: I think my problem was more with the Metroid Prime games that I played.
Rym: FPS is a lot before I got to college and I played FPS is pretty much every single day constantly up until Metroid Prime came out.
Rym: so Metroid Prime was the first game.
Rym: It's not a first-person shooter really but it is a game that takes place in the first person and it was the first First-person game I had played since Goldeneye Where I wasn't using a mouse and a keyboard
Scott: and while
Rym: I know that it's not that kind of twitch game
Scott: The
Rym: fact that I didn't have the level of control I was so used to just really bothered me and distracted me so much that I couldn't get myself to enjoy the game.
Rym: I'm hoping that now that I haven't really played FPS is for a couple years That I can play these Metroid Prime games and not be bothered by that.
Scott: Well, I think you'll be significantly helped by the fact that Metroid Prime 3 you'll probably be aiming with the Wiimote Yeah, nunchuck and not trying to use two analog sticks.
Rym: I'm actually kind of looking forward to it for that reason.
Scott: Yeah, but in addition to that Personally when I play Metroid Prime You know, I don't get the same feeling as an FPS.
Scott: So it doesn't bother me even though normally it would you know Even on a PC.
Scott: if I played descent which is a first-person view game It's like a totally different feeling from playing half-life 2 even though it's a first-person camera.
Rym: No, it's interesting.
Scott: understand how someone would be thrown off if they were like a super FPS player.
Rym: I think part of it because notice too that all first-person games I use inverted mouse or inverted joystick always no matter what the game is if it's in the first person I cannot deal with it unless it is inverted.
Rym: and I think part of the problem for me It's just that I probably played ten times more FPS is than you.
Scott: Yeah, maybe I'm
Rym: not saying that I'm not saying that as a badge of honor because I played a lot of bad FPS is - yeah I wasted a lot of time with
Scott: only good FPS
Rym: but I played FPS is constantly for a very long time and I played them a lot.
Rym: and I think That because I'm not gonna try to stroke an ego here, but I was really good at FPS.
Rym: is I would.
Rym: I was really freaking good at action quake and I think by today's standards You're not so good, but by the olden days.
Scott: standards, maybe but I don't know even by today because I remember You'd really don't stand a chance with like the fatality guys.
Scott: You got nothing.
Rym: Well, no, I didn't say I was great or the best or even near that.
Rym: I was just really good.
Scott: I don't think you're good on pub servers.
Rym: I generally just always come out on top on pub servers.
Scott: You have a pub server.
Scott: That's like saying man.
Scott: I'm the I'm the king of the the trailer park.
Rym: I'd say that that's really good because beyond that level of being better than most people on a pub server It's like the upper 1% that almost no one has an even chance with.
Rym: it's like this other scale.
Scott: Regardless Metroid Prime 3 definitely gonna buy that.
Rym: no matter what I think my brains control of FPS is is all kind of unified into one part of the brain.
Rym: that is Unyielding and will not accept change.
Scott: The only other Game that I see for the we worth mentioning is battalion wars 2. and well battalion wars 1 was.
Scott: so I knew it was Crap, I didn't buy it cuz I knew it was gonna be crap.
Scott: I was right.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: You didn't buy it You didn't play it.
Rym: How do you know it was crap?
Rym: What if it was awesome?
Scott: You want to bet on it?
Rym: I will bet you a nickel.
Scott: aha that it was awesome rims classic nickel bet.
Rym: Here's my problem Scott and I got into a long discussion about this where basically And you can I can tell how well off I am by how much money I will round down to zero.
Rym: and Currently I will round a nickel down to zero.
Rym: a nickel isn't money.
Rym: if I see a nickel I don't bother to pick it up.
Rym: if I drop a nickel.
Rym: I don't care I will give someone a nickel and not feel that I have lost anything.
Rym: So I'll pretty much bet a nickel on anything.
Scott: in other words Rym is not too confident that battalion wars is a good game.
Scott: Don't buy battalion wars people.
Scott: it is basically.
Scott: I won't even mention the fact that they supposedly put it in the advanced wars universe Because it is a tarnish upon advanced wars.
Scott: now if ours is great battalion war sucks.
Rym: if I was gonna bet eight cents It's a whole different story.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: I do also want to say space station tycoon.
Scott: now I usually you know who cares about space station tycoon But I've actually been kind of in the mood for one of those tycoon sim type of games lately.
Rym: Actually, I really kind of want to play some railroad sim games And well really I want to play railroad tycoon the board game But it's a pain to get it going and we need a bunch of people.
Scott: yeah So I don't know.
Scott: maybe the Sid Meier's railroads came out.
Scott: Maybe when your PC is working you can go get that.
Rym: I probably will you realize I'm probably gonna buy like 40 games for my PC within a week of getting it working.
Scott: well you can get them on Steam.
Scott: Yeah, and you know what that's it for the Wii games for until the fall granted.
Rym: Then we're gonna get brawl which is all I get.
Scott: the brawl we're gonna eat the Mario.
Scott: That's what we need and that brawl will probably keep us going for a year while all the other games get developed.
Rym: God.
Rym: So the Wii is gonna go from a Wii Sports system and nothing more to a brawl system much like the Gamecube was nothing more Than a mechanism for playing Smash Brothers.
Rym: Melee 24/7.
Scott: also the new Mario Party is out now or soon and Yeah, we'll see about it.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: I sort of feel like I should buy it But I but I learned my lesson from previous Mario parties that Mario Party.
Scott: We play it a whole lot, and then we go all right.
Rym: It takes forever, but then again I remember that Mario Party was great when I had a lot of free time Because it took a lot of free time, but here's the thing Mario Party.
Rym: one thing it does very well is it combines have a bunch of people who are playing a game together?
Rym: And it's a video game.
Rym: so it takes care of all the rules stuff You don't have to worry about it, and yet it allows ample ability to socialize while playing the game.
Rym: Yeah It's kind of a setting for socializing.
Rym: the other thing is that if you're playing Mario Party correctly as we talked about in the Mario Party show you will fill all of that spare time between moves trash talking and nothing more.
Scott: I'm sure also the Wii action of the new Mario Party might make it worth buying.
Rym: Maybe I imagine we'll get it and do a show on it.
Rym: I It's not like Wario where where I'm wary.
Rym: I still think that I don't think it's gonna fall from what Mario Party was.
Rym: it might Not exceed it, but I don't think it's gonna be worse.
Rym: Yeah, because you really can't beat the travesty that was Mario where we let's see we just counted How many Wii games.
Scott: not so many two two basically all right?
Scott: Let's count the DS game.
Scott: is you ready?
Rym: I'm ready.
Scott: July 30th pie cross DS.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Scott: isn't that the same as the same data strikers?
Scott: I guess I'll be buying a twofer on Amazon.
Rym: God damn it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Oh, let's see doo doo doo doo doo.
Scott: Sim City Maybe Sim City DS.
Scott: Maybe I don't know.
Rym: I don't have patience for those.
Scott: It depends if it's actually.
Scott: if it's like Sim City 2000 then yes, if it's anything else no.
Rym: But the thing is Sim City 2000 was ruined for me after I played it for years and one day I just started a city and Built it up and built it up and built it up and it was big as it could be.
Rym: and from that point on Like I'd mastered the game and alright I can build those awesome Arcologies and I started slowly filling my city with our colleges, and then I realized that it wasn't a game anymore.
Rym: It just wasn't fun, and I never played Sim City again.
Scott: No yeah, I also got tired of Sim City, but lately I'm feeling like I want to play it.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I want to play some other kind of simulation game.
Rym: Maybe I don't know something like a Sim Ant even though Sim Ant was pretty piss-poor.
Scott: I kind of like Sim Ant.
Scott: I love the fact that once you've got one got one place going all you did was look at the map of the backyard And every few minutes breed to a new square.
Rym: Oh no no I loved Sim Ant, but at the same time I don't think Sim Ant was a good game.
Scott: No I like Sim Tower a lot.
Scott: Sim Tower I really didn't like.
Scott: I like Sim Tower.
Scott: Anyway, DS games here we go.
Rym: I like Sim Earth.
Rym: My only goal was to wipe out all life.
Scott: DS games worth mentioning.
Scott: Namco Museum.
Scott: I talked about this before.
Scott: Oh, yeah I'm totally buying it no matter what just for the Galaga.
Scott: the other games are bonus.
Scott: Heroes of Mana, maybe it might be some tactics-y action Worms.
Scott: now there is a worms for the DS.
Scott: It kind of sucks though.
Scott: the problem is worms for the DS could potentially be an awesome game of all time super awesomeness.
Scott: Well, they're gonna put out worms open warfare 2 for the DS.
Scott: Maybe they'll correct the mistakes of the first worms for the DS.
Scott: I hope they do.
Rym: If they don't I'd rather than just put out scorched earth or gun bound.
Scott: Yeah, without modifying it at all in any way.
Rym: Yeah, because scorched earth I mean worms games are great.
Rym: the worms games that have been released on Nintendo systems have been worse than Scorch the first good game like that.
Scott: Yeah, I don't get it man.
Scott: It's not hard.
Scott: They've made awesome worms games in the past.
Scott: awesome worms games exist.
Scott: Don't modify them.
Scott: Just put the same game on every platform.
Scott: Yeah, the worm that everyone likes.
Scott: just take that game and just port it.
Scott: You don't need to update it You don't need to change it.
Scott: It's fine.
Scott: Everyone loves it.
Scott: Just make it multiplayer and put it on all the console.
Rym: I mean, there's that 3d worms on the GameCube.
Rym: That was okay.
Scott: It was okay, but it doesn't need to be 3d.
Rym: I want 2d worms.
Rym: The 3d was kind of cool.
Rym: I think it suffered from the fact that the controls to make a 3d game like that work on a Console with a controller like that just make it not fun.
Scott: Yep, basically.
Scott: All right.
Scott: next game luminous arc.
Scott: This is coming from Atlas.
Scott: It looks another one of those tactics II kind of games and you know I I'm not.
Scott: I've never been a big fan of the tactics II games like the final tactics.
Scott: I never even played any Final Fantasy tactics ever but I played the second Fire Emblem and I kind of liked it like the Gameboy Advance 1 number 2 and the only reason I stopped playing is because I stopped playing it for like a week and then I forgot the plot and what was Going on and everything and I in order for me to get back into the game I felt like I had to start over in the beginning which I didn't want to do and I Starting from where I was I forgot what I was doing.
Scott: So it was kind of like got out of the game.
Scott: But if I kept playing it and didn't stop I'd be able to stay in it And I think my interest would hold.
Scott: so I might buy one of the tactics II games and see if I can stay in it.
Scott: And without getting bored, I don't know.
Rym: I might just force myself to beat one of the Fire Emblems before I go any further.
Rym: Maybe maybe because I played them both and then I just kind of stopped.
Scott: but you liked him, didn't you?
Scott: I did like him while I was playing him.
Rym: You liked him.
Scott: Yeah, which I did too.
Scott: But then you get out of it and you're like, huh and it's sort of like this barrier to re-entry.
Rym: I guess part of the other problem is that I have played Advance Wars and I like the Advance Wars style of that kind of combat so much Yep, but I also like the the way that you slightly customize like the weapons on the guys.
Scott: Yep Yep, and I don't know how everyone's a character.
Rym: instead of building units during the map I think those games come in and out of season for me and I think I'm just not in the season.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, it seems like those games get into season whenever I have a lot of idle time with my DS Which currently I've been stuck with Pokemon and Pokemon is definitely occupying that space and I've been reading that awesome Dragon book that Emily gave me.
Scott: when Pokemon runs out one of these tactics games might come in and fill the hole man.
Rym: Every time I want to play a game other than Pokemon I realized I could be reading that dragon book or playing Pokemon and of course the only game left to mention is In September Phoenix Wright 3.
Rym: I guess I should finish.
Rym: Phoenix Wright 2.
Scott: Perhaps you should.
Rym: I'm near the end.
Rym: I just Pokemon came out.
Scott: Hey, nothing you could do about that.
Rym: Nothing in the world.
Rym: All right All right, I had I had news about Starcraft 2.
Rym: I don't feel like talking about it again I don't think I need to say anything.
Scott: Starcraft 2 is coming out and South Korea is gonna explode.
Rym: God South Korea, this is all I'll say if you were unaware.
Rym: South Korea Starcraft is big there.
Rym: I mean it was one of the biggest and most popular games in America ever when it comes to PC gaming and RTS is.
Rym: But it's kind of transcended that in South Korea, which is already the land of video games.
Scott: Yeah When did Starcraft 1 come out?
Rym: fuck if I even remember.
Scott: I'm gonna look it up because it came out a long time ago Perhaps pre 2000.
Rym: I remember the year it came out.
Rym: It was the number one selling PC game.
Scott: it came out in 1998.
Rym: that was a long time ago.
Scott: So check this out.
Scott: Starcraft came out in 1998 in the US right and It's still the number one game in South Korea.
Rym: that well other than some of those a decade of this game I guess I mean other than possibly a lot of those online games people play.
Scott: No, it's still the number one game.
Scott: I mean.
Scott: sure they play a lot of lineage and Warcraft 2.
Rym: It's number one in that it is a part of their culture.
Rym: if you are really good at that game in Korea.
Rym: I am by really good.
Rym: I mean Professional level like you.
Rym: just kick everyone's ass.
Rym: fatality level FPS style only with the RTS is.
Rym: You're not just a cool guy on the internet in Korea.
Rym: You're a celebrity Really?
Rym: You're on national television and you were basically a professional athlete.
Rym: Starcraft tournaments are held on multiple broadcast networks in Korea.
Scott: Yeah, check this out.
Scott: Starcraft 2 was officially announced May 19th at blizzards worldwide Invitational in Seoul, South Korea.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean we have the Super Bowl and those sorts of things here.
Scott: They have Starcraft tournaments there South Korea Invitational like you can't just walk up and enter.
Rym: this video game tournament Invited is for many people in the United States possibly their idea of utopia.
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: It's just so crazy to think that there is a game development company named Blizzard.
Scott: They just a bunch of guys who make video games.
Scott: That's all they do and Somehow they've got an entire country by the balls by the balls.
Scott: Imagine this explaining that world Situation to someone from the year 1998 when Starcraft came out.
Scott: just tell them see this game that just came out.
Scott: This game is going to hold an entire country hostage.
Scott: They're going to be three television stations in the year Dedicated to this game in South Korea now, it'd just be unbelievable.
Scott: It'd be like what crazy.
Rym: what I wonder.
Scott: What I really wonder is I mean Japan had enough problems every time a new Dragon Quest game came out on a school day So much trouble that they made a law that you can't release video games on certain days Because people kids won't go to school.
Scott: Wasn't?
Scott: it?
Rym: wasn't just Dragon Quest games?
Scott: I don't know, but it's definitely because of Dragon Quest.
Scott: That's the rumor.
Scott: actually I should look that up on.
Scott: Yeah, that might be just a big story that that might be perpetuating internet for you.
Rym: It might be an apocryphal tale and my guard list it is not Above to say that mass chaos did ensue when Dragon Quest games were released in Japan.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: I think the only solution Korea has is to one tax every single citizen of South Korea for the price of Starcraft 2 and then on the day of launch just airlift boxes into every major city by the millions.
Rym: and If you want that tax money back You have to prove before a government body that you do not have any interest in Starcraft and do not wish to play it.
Scott: I Think it might just be better if Blizzard just sold the entire game Lock stock and barrel to the South Korean government in one giant lump sum payment Or they could sell it to the North Korean government and then they wouldn't need missiles anymore.
Scott: Oh, man Wow, think about that.
Scott: That might actually work.
Scott: if Blizzard sold Starcraft 2 to North Korea North Korea could say all right, South Korea You can either become part of North Korea and get Starcraft 2 or you can just stay your South Korea And you know what.
Rym: if they put it to a vote?
Rym: I wouldn't have too much confidence.
Scott: No me either that that's pretty scary, right?
Rym: It's kind of like didn't Michael Moore go around somewhere saying hey if we gave you a thousand dollars Would you vote to turn over the citizenship of your state to wherever?
Rym: and most people said yes Yeah, sure Starcraft is worth a lot more than a thousand dollars.
Rym: to a lot of people in Korea It sure is Things of the day.
Rym: I think this is pretty cool.
Rym: It's a someone took a bunch of yarn and they made an Atari 2600 complete with controllers and a TV and on the TV is Pitfall.
Rym: does it work?
Scott: Yes Awesome.
Rym: No
Scott: Yeah, I'm glad they chose pitfall as the game because that is one of my Preferred Atari 2600 games because actually out of all the Atari 2600 games I think pitfall is the most slick and stylin and smooth and polished whereas a lot of the other ones are Rough around the edges to say the least.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Yes Now the fact that it was pitfall was the only reason it was pushed over the edge and to be in my thing of the day Watch out for them scorpions.
Rym: I just love that noise Man, you always had to be a chump to go underground.
Rym: cuz underground just sucked and you couldn't get very far.
Rym: There's always scorpions and walls and almost no treasure.
Scott: Yeah Basically the whole game is Stay above ground unless there's a treasure underground in which case go down there and get it then immediately come back above ground where?
Scott: It's much safer.
Scott: I don't know why you would ever go underground.
Scott: scorpions are so hard to get past.
Scott: Yeah All right, my thing of the day if you ever played the game Contra Rym, you know Contra 1 for the NES.
Scott: Oh, I remember that was the game where game that made the Konami code famous the game where you'd put in the Konami code And it'll give you 30 lives and you thought I gave you 70 love.
Rym: no gave you 30 All right, and then you have three continues of those 30 lives.
Scott: Oh, that's right.
Rym: That's how and despite that I still half the time couldn't beat that fucking game.
Scott: Yeah Contra was a platforming shooting game.
Scott: You basically walk to the right.
Scott: you couldn't walk back to the left, you know Cuz they would only scroll one direction and you could shoot your machine gun.
Scott: you could get different weapons in your machine gun, but it was always a machine gun of some sort and You'd shoot bad guys and walk to the right a few levels.
Scott: you would walk up instead of to the right.
Scott: You'd walk into the screen, but it wasn't that much different and eventually you got.
Scott: it was sort of like You know a space shooter only without the flying basically.
Scott: It's just the platforming.
Scott: Well Contra was a fucking hard game only really really good people could beat it.
Scott: I could beat like two levels and then I would like die in the third level.
Rym: My brother and I would often put the code in play two-player and then fight to get to the end and half the time.
Rym: the Goal was all right.
Rym: We just have to beat one more level before we continue and we're okay.
Scott: Yep Well some guy on the Internet's made a video of not a speedrun of Contra.
Scott: No speedrun.
Scott: who cares, you know You can get some computer to figure out how to get through this game as fast as possible Whatever.
Scott: and it doesn't appear to me.
Scott: I do not believe that this is a machine.
Scott: assisted run.
Scott: I believe a hundred up almost a hundred percent that this is an actual video of someone playing the game.
Scott: I mean I can tell by the way he's playing that it's not a machine.
Rym: I can tell by the pixels.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Well also If it's uh, if it is a machine playing then they have done a very good job of masking The fact that it is a machine playing.
Rym: what the player might have done is use save states here and there before troubled spots.
Rym: You might not have done it all in one.
Scott: go up.
Scott: That is possible.
Rym: There's no real way to know.
Scott: There's no way to know but I'm pretty confident that this is actually a real run through Contra with no Deaths.
Scott: he did not die.
Scott: now keep in mind Contra.
Scott: one hit you die.
Rym: Not only that there's bullets Everywhere and constantly the game.
Rym: I have the time especially in the later levels.
Rym: It's literally up dead dead dead dead dead.
Scott: This guy beat Contra in this video without getting hit at all without dying.
Scott: he didn't beat it as fast as possible, but he beat it pretty damn quickly and he just mowed right through the game.
Scott: and it's Amazing and you should watch this cuz conscious not really that long if you don't die.
Rym: Yeah, the game always seemed like this long terrible struggle that took hours.
Scott: But yet there's only like five levels.
Scott: I know six or seven not too many.
Rym: It doesn't take that long to beat.
Rym: It's just I guess I sucked.
Scott: I also said I think we also.
Scott: I think if I practiced it now I could get good.
Rym: Have any of you out there ever Beaten Contra or even gotten to the end or even gotten me.
Rym: I did save states on an emulator once without Cheating or using the Konami code or using an emulator.
Scott: not probably nobody.
Rym: well, at least without the features of an emulator I guess you can use an emulator.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, so as we've probably mentioned in the first half of the show we're now recording the second half of the show and then we're gonna go back and record the first half of the show that I Stupidly deleted.
Rym: Damn you reset button rims fault.
Scott: It is my fault.
Scott: You owe me something.
Rym: What do I owe you?
Scott: I did all that hard work of talking and now you just threw it away.
Scott: So you owe me something.
Scott: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: I give you the talking I put into that thrown away footage.
Scott: So we're even but I don't you threw that Away, also, that's like it's like if I gave you something you threw it away And then you were gonna pay me back with some money, but then you threw the money away.
Rym: all fine You know what?
Rym: I will give you the market value of the portion percentage of the geeky episode of GeekNights.
Rym: That was lost.
Rym: Alright sure Good game Creative Commons.
Scott: Hey, if one day we ever, you know get some royalties or so Who knows some?
Scott: no because on this particular episode?
Rym: I'm gonna get your head except that no matter what we sold the episode for It's still available for free under the Creative Commons.
Rym: Thus making the value zero.
Scott: No, no, no if we let's say we satellite radio pays us five bucks to air this episode Normally, I would get 250 and you'd get 250 but for this episode in this episode alone I get five bucks.
Rym: No, it wouldn't be five bucks because we have to prorate it based on the percentage of the show actually lost.
Rym: So the longer we retalk the less your money's worth, I guess.
Scott: so.
Scott: Anyway, we're gonna do the first half of the show real short.
Rym: It is getting into it weak and yesterday We talked about getting into Linux tonight.
Rym: We were gonna talk about getting into German board games, but that's kind of easy.
Scott: Yeah, play Settlers of Catan then play other games.
Scott: Puerto Rico's a good one, too.
Rym: Plus we actually kind of talked about that a lot just as a side.
Scott: So it's also something that's talked about a great deal on the Internet.
Rym: But something that's not talked about a great deal on the Internet is how to get into role-playing games.
Scott: Yeah I mean the only place I've seen talk about how to get into role-playing games is the Dragon's Landing Podcast and they talk about it here and there and Most of their advice is okay.
Scott: Well some of their advice kind of normal.
Rym: I'll just admit I don't really I wasn't a big fan of their show.
Scott: I stopped listening to the show.
Scott: I'll admit right now.
Rym: Yeah, okay There don't seem to be too many good D&D podcasts out there in general.
Scott: No, I mean some of them tried to you know, do the thing where they record their own campaign But that I don't see why anyone would listen to that.
Rym: but pretty nerdy I guess you could do it with the proper cast of Burning Wheel, but Regardless Real.
Rym: briefly the purpose of this week is most we have.
Rym: we have two audience in mind.
Rym: audience number one We are talking to people who are interested for whatever reason in geekeries that they are not currently Involved in.
Scott: and yeah, if you're you know, there's a lot of geeks out there.
Scott: They're just anime geeks.
Scott: and it's always kind of weird like going to an anime convention and people there like don't know about computers.
Scott: And I'm like, are you a geek or not?
Scott: It's like because I'm used to hanging around with a group of geeks that are pan geeks Renaissance geeks.
Scott: We know computers, you know anime we know video games.
Scott: We know everything.
Scott: so we run into these people that just like anime They don't know video games.
Scott: They don't know Freaking board games.
Scott: They don't know role-playing.
Scott: They don't look computers.
Scott: They just know anime.
Scott: Yeah, if you're the type of geek who only knows video games, you just play Guitar Hero 2 all day and night You don't anything else.
Rym: That's a pretty good life.
Scott: It's a good day.
Scott: It's a good life, but or you're a computer nerd.
Scott: You don't know anything else.
Scott: We're gonna help you out.
Scott: We're gonna.
Scott: we're gonna teach you how to get the role-playing groove on and maybe spread out your geek isms to other areas.
Rym: now Audience number two and this is very important.
Rym: We are also targeting this at people who are into something and want to get other people into said thing.
Scott: Yeah, like let's say you're role-playing but your friends they don't like the role-playing.
Scott: They're always going.
Scott: what's with your role-playing?
Scott: Like I know a lot of people they play that they want to play the German board games But their friends won't do it and they can't get their friends to do it.
Scott: Even if they have friends, they can't get them to play the German board games like a struggle.
Scott: Well, we're gonna help you because you can just make those friends listen to this episode and then they will hopefully get into role-playing
Rym: or in the very least use the techniques that we're Presenting here because a lot of the ways people try to get their friends into things tend to be very counterproductive.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, I want to get someone to the Linux so I'll just be like, yeah Go straight to here.
Scott: You got to do Linux from scratch.
Scott: No, it doesn't work.
Rym: or you want to get someone into anime.
Rym: So you show them all your favorite anime?
Rym: Including the really obscure weird crap that you like because you've never seen anime before.
Scott: Nope Well, I think you might like it here.
Scott: Watch my favorite show Genji Ken.
Scott: Yeah Guess what people?
Scott: if you show someone Genji Ken who's never seen anime before they're never gonna watch anime ever again.
Scott: It's just how it's gonna be I guarantee unless they're a weirdo.
Rym: So I guess what is a role-playing game?
Rym: because a lot of people have a lot of different definitions though I think most people What they think of when they hear role-playing games that aren't video games is Dungeons & Dragons D&D.
Scott: That is what most people think of and they a lot of people think that that's the only role-playing all tabletop role-playing.
Scott: We're not talking about larping here.
Rym: Nope, totally different.
Scott: Yes tabletop role-playing is basically in my definition is You get a bunch of friends together and you tell a story but you don't just tell a story like in the old Storytelling days.
Scott: you tell a story using a particular structure.
Scott: what you do is you have one person who is sort of like the chief story guiding guy or girl and They sort of hold everything together the setting the events and all sorts of random lesser Important characters and each other person playing telling the story Controls one character one of the main characters in the story and all they can do to tell the story is say what their one Character who is a main character does.
Scott: so all the actions and happenings and speakings and dialogue of the main Characters are each controlled by one real person and everything else is typically controlled by one more person.
Rym: So it's collaborative storytelling pretty much straight up.
Rym: But because I mean you could do this without any rules you could get a bunch of friends together.
Rym: This used to be a pastime in high school and middle school a lot around the campfire.
Rym: People would just make characters come up with a quick setting and with absolutely no rules Just kind of roleplay and come up with the story over the course of it.
Rym: Yeah, but as we've often found in our lives oftentimes the Limitations that are placed upon you are what caused you to excel or to do something.
Rym: You never would have thought you'd do So.
Rym: role-playing games are systems that we use to create a Framework around which we can roleplay.
Rym: it sets the boundaries it sets the rules it sets at sometimes arbitrariness sometimes luck randomness.
Rym: It gives you a method of having order and it forces you to take the storytelling in most likely more interesting direction.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you're just allowed to tell whatever story you want I'll be like alright my guy spreads wings and flies and up to the top of the castle and he fights the evil wizard But he's more powerful than evil wizard and he beats him and I'm the hero.
Scott: Haha and the end of the story.
Scott: now It's not so interesting.
Rym: It might be easy to say that oh Well, if you have discipline then that won't be a problem.
Rym: and role-playing systems and games are just for people who lack discipline.
Rym: And that is really not true because the systems themselves I think serve in most cases Well, maybe not most cases in a few special cases to enhance the role-playing and I think that like we said the limitations and the rules Actually end up bringing about a better story.
Scott: Yeah plus think about telling whatever story you want is not so fun.
Scott: What's what is fun is being challenged to tell a story about something specific like, you know that nanofictionary card game.
Scott: Yep It's like you get these cards and you have to tell a story about what the cards say and that's when it's fun because it's like.
Scott: Okay, here's a challenge for you, you know, let's see if you can you know beat this challenge tell the best story You can using these elements.
Scott: So when you're playing D&D good D&D It's no different.
Scott: when you're in a fight you roll some dice to see how the fight turns out and you're forced to roleplay.
Scott: You know the results of whatever that is.
Scott: who knows what the results will be?
Scott: but you're forced into it.
Scott: It's just like nanofictionary forced you to tell a story around some cards.
Rym: I remember when I was young and I was in middle school and I was trying to get other kids into D&D so I could play a game because it was incredibly hard to find people other than at Conventions who wanted to roleplay with me.
Rym: So I remember once very one specific conversation.
Rym: I was trying to explain to someone what the game is and they were dubious and The only way I could really explain it because they're like, well, how do you win?
Rym: What do you do?
Rym: And I said well basically you just say what your character does and they do it and there's rules about how to resolve that and They couldn't understand it.
Scott: They absolutely it's not.
Scott: and the problem is a lot of people go into it and you say game and they automatically think You know in the structure of a game this winning this losing this competition this rules.
Scott: I need to make decisions or do certain things in order to achieve victory something something and that's where you get the role-playing of dungeon Crawling collecting treasure whatever but those people might as well play hero quest.
Rym: now I'm gonna narrow our definition a little bit here because we're talking about role-playing games and tabletop role-playing Yep, and Dungeons & Dragons and all that sort of thing.
Rym: But there are two very different schools of thought and how to play and I think that both are equally valid.
Rym: So for the time being I'm going to ignore beer and pretzels D&D, but I'm going to come back to that point.
Rym: yeah, so if you think that I am what I'm about to say and the thing Scott is also about to say are Disparaging straight-up beer and pretzels Dungeons & Dragons don't get any other sorts of beer and pretzels role-playing because there are.
Scott: there are many types.
Rym: We'll come back to that.
Rym: Yes, but for starters, we're just going to talk about role-playing games where the intent is to role-play.
Rym: now another way to look at this is Basically, you're acting.
Rym: everyone is acting in a play But you're also the audience of the play and instead of having a script you have a rule book that tells you what the rules Are for acting.
Scott: you're also the not only the audience and the actors But you are the writers and the screenwriters and the director and every.
Scott: well the DM is more to the director But yeah, you're everything in the play all at once.
Scott: So you're getting the entertainment from watching other people act.
Scott: you're acting yourself You're facing challenges of.
Scott: you know what to act you're improvising you're being directed at you're directing You're doing everything that's involved all at once without the fancy lights in the fog machines and such.
Rym: now How do you get into?
Rym: role-playing is a very difficult question because I hate to say it But the majority of people who play Dungeons & Dragons or any sort of role-playing game Don't actually role-play or role-play in such a Limited or shallow yes shallow.
Rym: I believe is the perfect word manner that it's not really role-playing at all.
Scott: Yeah, like if you ever watch that famous thing of the day That's still one of our.
Rym: are there any girls there?
Rym: cuz if there are I wanna do them.
Scott: Oh, that's a good one.
Scott: I was thinking of a murder duck.
Scott: That is the typical D&D game.
Scott: yes of people who don't know how to play properly.
Rym: So rule number one here.
Rym: the first thing we have to get across is that if you think that role-playing is like that you have Been watching the wrong people role-play.
Scott: well well No, you've you.
Scott: role-playing is like that for a great many people, but though most people do it wrong Yes, again.
Rym: Don't worry about beer and pretzels.
Rym: We'll come back to that.
Rym: well Yeah, I think we can stop saying that I got it because I don't want someone to go.
Scott: Oh, you're making fun of my D&D.
Scott: well they can shut up.
Rym: But So many people who I've tried to get interested in Dungeons & Dragons throughout my life for any role-playing game Always come back with.
Rym: but I played it once in high school and it was totally lame and it was a bunch of nerds sitting around a table fighting, but goblins in a square dungeon and rolling to see how many maidens they had sex with afterward and they were creepy and they hit on me if it was a Girl, and it was just garbage.
Rym: and anytime we tried to do anything the DM Would just make sure it didn't work, and we spent more time rolling dice and no one was ever in character.
Rym: No one even had a character.
Rym: They were just fired are very right.
Scott: that is garbage And that's not good D&D and sadly that is the majority of D&D.
Rym: yep that has become the stereotype of D&D.
Scott: So how do you get into the good role-playing?
Scott: well step one if you've never role-played before you pretty much?
Scott: Can't do it on your own.
Scott: You don't if you get it, but you can.
Rym: it's called writing a novel.
Scott: yes Well, I mean even if you find some other people who have never role-played before let's say you get five people And none of you have ever role-played.
Scott: It's not going to be easy.
Scott: you need to find someone somewhere who knows has done this before Properly and in the good way to help you out.
Rym: now for any of you who are lucky We are going to give you the easy way out.
Rym: if you ever see a gaming convention where a man by the name of Luke Crane is going to be there running an event Just go and talk to him and he will convince you whether you want to or not to join one of his games and at The end of it you will know exactly what role-playing is.
Scott: But if you are not so fortunate you can still go to a gaming convention near you and maybe if you're lucky There will be some people there that are role-playing properly.
Scott: You could probably tell because if you sit down with them or if you look over at their table They will be laughing and having a good time and some people will stand up and say dramatic things or something like that as opposed To a bunch of scary nerds who smell going rolling dice a whole
Rym: lot You can.
Rym: the easiest way to tell if some people are actually Role-playing is if you come upon them while they were arguing or talking and you think for a second that they're actually Arguing or that they're actually angry at each other.
Scott: you can pretty much tell looking at a table of people who are playing an RPG Whether that RPG is good or not.
Scott: It's not difficult.
Rym: Well, I guess what are the signs of good role-playing?
Rym: and then we can go through.
Rym: what are the signs of bad role-playing?
Rym: Cuz I think they're pretty evident.
Rym: Okay, good role-playing a lot all the things we just said.
Scott: people yelling people People speak ending up in the first person people look like they're being passionate about something Not so many dice being rolled.
Rym: if when dice are rolled people stop and pay attention Yeah, if characters will walk away from the table and in character continue to discuss That's a good one anything like that.
Rym: Basically, if you see people who are acting in any capacity or even if they're trying to act even if they're not doing a good Job, they're trying to be in character.
Rym: their characters have motivations.
Rym: It's not just a dungeon crawl.
Rym: There's an actual story.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yeah, because remember we said before that role-playing is acting.
Scott: So if you come across some people role-playing and they're doing a good job of it You're gonna feel sort of like you're watching a play might not be a good play But it'll be entertaining to watch Unlike two people playing Puerto Rico.
Scott: not so fun, but it's not really a spectator game.
Scott: Puerto Rico But Nora's hero quest but D&D played right is very much a spectator game.
Rym: now from the perspective of a player Actually in a game.
Rym: Here are some of the signs of bad role-playing.
Rym: First and foremost is if you have a dungeon master or a game master Whoever who no matter what the players attempt or what the players put forth He always foils it and it's kind of adversarial him against you.
Scott: That's bad.
Rym: That is generally not good role-playing.
Scott: yeah, if you have a Dungeon master who no matter what you do, they may not foil you but they don't let you go off the road.
Scott: You know, it's like let's say you're in a town and you say well I want to do this because that's what your character would want to do and the dungeon master is like I don't know.
Scott: a large tree blocks your path or The guards.
Scott: don't let you go that way or you go there and the the store is closed.
Scott: go to where the story that I?
Scott: Wrote is.
Scott: that's not good.
Scott: It's called railroading and that is bad.
Rym: if you're playing and the only setting that seems to exist is the town outside of the dungeon Confrised of 10 foot by 10 foot squares or the dungeon comprised of 10 foot by 10 foot squares full of monsters inexplicably.
Scott: Yeah, that's also bad.
Scott: if you spend more time rolling dice than talking Mmm, that's pretty much what it comes down to yes.
Rym: or if you spend most of your time in combat regardless of whether or not you're rolling dice.
Rym: if In combat, no one speaks in character.
Rym: Everyone just talks tactics Mmm, I mean if you're sitting around a table and oh well you cast blah blah blah And then I'll circle back 10 feet and do this and you do this and we'll do this.
Rym: Oh, we got to heal him.
Rym: Oh fireball the Lynch blah blah blah and no one says anything in character.
Rym: You're just playing World of Warcraft in person.
Rym: You're not actually roleplay.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of people do that though, and I don't know why they use D&D to do that But you could.
Scott: there are a lot better systems to do that sort of.
Rym: well I'll admit that happened to our group quite a bit and we realized it and we forced ourselves to stop and get back in character.
Scott: Yeah, it was so weird though It's cuz like we played D&D to be combat which we kind of expected and did but like I would just when it happened I just kind of sat there bored because it took a whole lot of time and blah.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I didn't like it.
Rym: see here's another very subtle hint.
Rym: if you're playing a game if Combat should be dramatic if there is a fight if there's a conflict in a role-playing game It should matter.
Rym: you should care.
Rym: if you're ever involved in a conflict where you don't care and it doesn't matter Barring the chance that your character actually doesn't care and that it couldn't affect them then Why are you even having the conflict?
Rym: because it's not part of the role-playing experience.
Rym: It's just crufts.
Scott: Yep Now a lot of people will tell you that if you want to get into role-playing and you can't find people to do it with.
Scott: You know your local game store is just a bunch of scary people.
Scott: You don't have one.
Scott: You can't find any conventions nearby.
Scott: You don't have any friends who will do it with you.
Scott: a lot of people will say hey, you can go role-play in forums online and There you can get into it.
Scott: Well, I actually disagree with those people for the most part while it is possible to do lots of you know forum role-playing stuff And this stuff is widespread across the internet.
Scott: In fact, we played in a game for quite some time Yep, and there's IRC role-playing and all sorts of other things.
Scott: It is my opinion that tabletop role-playing does not work Basically well enough in knowing you're not in person to warrant doing especially if that is your first role-playing experience.
Scott: That's just bad.
Scott: I mean if you've played role-playing games before and you know what you're doing and You just want to do something in a forum, you know more power to you, but as a first experience Forum D&D or forum tabletop role-playing of any kind.
Scott: I don't think it's gonna work for you.
Scott: You're gonna not get the right feeling from it.
Scott: You're not gonna know what to do.
Scott: so much It.
Scott: I just don't think it works out and I've seen a lot of people.
Scott: they try to get into that and then they go To the forum a couple times.
Scott: they never come back and that's that and now they turned off from role-playing forever.
Scott: So don't do that.
Rym: So then how do you get into it?
Rym: How do you find a gaming group?
Rym: What if you're in a town and you're you?
Rym: you think you're the only person who was interested in role-playing?
Rym: You own all the Dungeons & Dragons books But you've never actually played.
Scott: you go to Craigslist and you find people and you say hey man, what's up?
Scott: And you make sure they're not scary.
Rym: Yep Or or more likely especially since a lot of you probably I haven't been to college yet if you haven't role-played at all.
Rym: I played a lot of D&D in high school and such but when I went to college Particularly if you go to a big or more importantly a nerdy school You will automatically find a lot of people who are into these things and a good percentage of them will probably be pretty good At it.
Scott: Yeah, I learned how to play D&D Accidentally, I went to nerdy summer camp where I was pretty much forced to play D&D at the nerdy summer camp.
Scott: So go to nerdy summer camp if you're a little kid and that'll teach you some D&D's Yep, but I guess the.
Rym: the moral is don't lose Hope because before I found people to play with I did in fact own all the D&D books and I knew like one kid Who knew about D&D and he was really scary and I avoided him at all costs because he was.
Rym: I really didn't want to play In a game with him and I read the books all the time, but I had no one to play with Yep, and then I found people to play with.
Rym: eventually you just got to stick to it.
Scott: The thing is is a lot of people sometimes have a hard time getting into role-playing because they start out of course trying to play Dungeons & Dragons, which is fine.
Scott: There's nothing wrong with that.
Scott: But Dungeons & Dragons is sort of like this high fantasy world high fantasy system.
Scott: There's magic and spells and wizards and all this sorts of stuff.
Scott: It's also in my opinion not a very good system all things considered No but it works and it teaches you role-playing and it.
Scott: the thing is it only works on nerds and it seems that because of Most role-playing game systems tend to be centered on high fantasy or science fiction cyberpunk type things that it's really
Rym: a whole genre
Scott: of gaming that is sort of restricted to geeks and geeks only and People who are in any other sort of lifestyle, you know, let's say jocks or whatever.
Scott: They might enjoy role-playing games, but they don't play them because the themes of them are so nerdy.
Scott: Well, there are many role-playing games out there which do not have such themes and if you don't even if you don't say You know the people that you're gonna play with that these are role-playing games or anything You can probably use these games to get people into role-playing who normally would not be.
Scott: but yeah basically there are a lot of people out there who recognize this problem that most RPGs tend to be nerdy and theme and they make Tiny simple easy to learn very cheap Role-playing games that you can play with your mom.
Scott: You could probably trick your mom and your brother and your dad and your whole family into playing these things and they'll have a good Time and they won't even know what they just did.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: In fact, the Wii has already done that with video gaming Yep.
Scott: Now one of these I think is pretty good.
Scott: You got inspectors.
Scott: That's a pretty good one.
Rym: Yeah, we've been playing inspectors not often but more than once lately Yep, and we're already thinking about how to modify it slightly to play much more serious game with it than it was probably intended for.
Scott: Yep, inspectors is basically like Ghostbusters the RPG.
Scott: So if people like Ghostbusters or whatever, then they'll probably like to play inspectors.
Scott: Don't even tell them D&D Don't say role-playing just say, you know what just say.
Scott: hey, let's play this inspectors game.
Scott: I got you get some Six-sided dice and print out some pieces of paper and give everyone a copy of the book and you could probably get it going on.
Scott: Another one good one is primetime adventures, which is all about like TV type stuff people like TV.
Scott: you can get them to play primetime adventures and I'm not sure.
Scott: but besides us I get the feeling a lot of people like TV.
Scott: What do you think?
Scott: Ah, Possibly possibly possibly.
Scott: So yeah There are lots of independent RPGs out in the internets that you can find to get into if you're having a hard time finding Nerds to play the classics.
Rym: So just don't be put off by your possible image of what role-playing is and don't think that all Role-playing is nerds sitting around a table playing Dungeons & Dragons Cuz.
Scott: that's so far from the truth.
Rym: Yes now while we said a lot of that kind of role-playing is crap.
Rym: You know playing without story playing without characters just going through a dungeon crawl because a lot of people do that really poorly.
Rym: There is this other kind or this other style of role-playing that's pretty much 180 degrees around.
Rym: It's generally referred to as beer and pretzels D&D or beer and pretzels role-playing.
Scott: Yes as in not serious We don't care about the story.
Scott: We're making.
Scott: let's just take this and have fun.
Rym: As in I got a flag and a beer I got a bag of pretzels and I'm gonna kill some orcs with my sword Awesome.
Scott: Yeah, basically this is nerd fun.
Scott: That is not so Deep intellectual interesting.
Rym: Yes, but it's still fun.
Rym: I mean, I'm not gonna deny that late at night at a convention Nothing's more fun than sitting around with a bunch of geeks playing some sort of high and mighty hack and slash.
Scott: Yeah, it basically, you know, you play D&D and you net good D&D Generally, you never get to the point where everyone's wicked powerful and slaying a bunch of monsters and all sorts of stuff.
Scott: It's it's always like we're like level four Maybe and it.
Scott: we don't have too many spells and everything sucks.
Scott: and it you know You don't get into that sort of fun, but a beer and pretzels game.
Scott: It's like I am the super night of Lord.
Rym: I am son.
Rym: You're God Akan.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I am King.
Scott: testicles fear my mighty sword I slay with you.
Rym: Haha Now the thing is I still make the distinction between beer and pretzels D&D and bad D&D because beer and pretzels if run properly still avoids all the problems of bad D&D.
Rym: if you've got a DM who doesn't let the characters do anything or gets in their way constantly and is Adversarial and annoying and no matter what clever thing you come up with They just automatically make sure it doesn't work or they cheat with the die rolls to make sure they can't lose.
Rym: It's still bad D&D.
Rym: No matter how you slice it.
Scott: Yeah, I think the best example of beer and pretzels role-playing is that kobolds ate my baby game Which actually says on the bar on the book the beard pretzels role-playing game.
Rym: It pretty much is.
Scott: Yeah It's a game where everyone's a kobold and you have to eat babies or rest.
Scott: take babies back to the kobold.
Rym: Rescue is not the word.
Scott: Yes You go steal babies from the human.
Scott: perhaps them back to the kobold rescue them from life and deliver them into my belly perhaps and The game itself is silly.
Scott: you roleplay a little kobold and it's silly and everything is silly.
Scott: but you still left a roleplay this little furry kobold and it's still kind of fun and It's not as shallow as it first appears.
Scott: I mean you could play in a shallow bad manner where it's just a game of walk around the map.
Scott: collect the kobolds Like the babies.
Scott: Yeah, but that's Basically, the game is written so well that if you actually try to play it You're gonna end up role-playing this little kobold and it'll be beer and pretzels.
Scott: It won't be too serious, but it'll still be good.
Rym: So in some one not all role-playing is bad Dungeons & Dragons role-playing.
Rym: two Not all role-playing is Dungeons & Dragons.
Rym: Yeah, three not all role-playing is solely the realm of geeks and or nerds.
Scott: Does that cover it?
Rym: I think so.
Rym: I mean beyond that the only advice we can give you is try to find a good group of people and more importantly if you find a group of People and you're not enjoying yourself and either they're not role-playing or it's not the kind of game you want to be in Or if you're not having fun, don't feel obligated to keep going quit find a different group.
Rym: You're better off not playing than playing a game that you don't enjoy going to.
Scott: yeah I know a lot of people have this.
Scott: problem is that they go to a game and they just feel obligated to keep going because They're in the game and if they leave then that game will be somehow ruined.
Rym: There was a game like that I won't mention who ran it at RIT that basically someone tricked me into joining it for the sole purpose of quitting without guilt and It was probably the worst Role-playing experience I have ever had more so than the guns game that I ran in high school.
Rym: Perhaps the worst role-playing experience I have ever inflicted upon others.
Scott: Yes, but yeah, don't feel bad about.
Scott: you know If you're in a bad role-playing game with with people who you know, like suck They think no bones about.
Scott: basically if you're role-playing and there's a problem.
Scott: You've got to open your mouth or move your feet.
Scott: That's pretty much.
Scott: you have to just do it immediately.
Scott: Don't hesitate at all.
Scott: Let's say I'm playing with a group of people and it's a good game But some of the people don't show up all the time and it's kind of hurting the game.
Scott: I basically the next time they show up I'd be like hey you guys don't show up if you're not gonna keep showing up Why don't we just stop this because it's not worth it.
Scott: or if We're role-playing and one of the characters just he's playing the stupid way and he's not saying anything or acting He's just rolling the dice doing the combat like hey Are you gonna roleplay?
Scott: or what are you doing here?
Scott: Why are you here?
Scott: Maybe you should just leave, you know, if someone's being a problem and ruining your party say hey We're having fun Except you're ruining it.
Scott: go home Yes, or if you're a role-playing with some people and they're all nerdy and you don't like it just say hey listen guys This isn't the kind of game that I like.
Scott: I'm not having fun here.
Scott: We can either change it in this way Or I'm just gonna have to leave and find something else to do because this isn't fun for me.
Rym: I guess the real answer is if you haven't gone to college yet Go to college and you'll meet a bunch of people who roleplay and you'll probably find some good games.
Scott: And also do not hesitate to use local geeky shops and the internet to find people in your area.
Scott: There are probably a lot more people nearby Willing to roleplay than you think and even if you can only get together once a month or six times a year.
Scott: That's not too bad because you generally roleplay for hours on end.
Scott: Yeah, you'll still remember as long as the DM writes down what happened and gives a little recap.
Rym: I mean our current game.
Rym: we only play once a month and even that is being interrupted by things going on in our lives Yet mostly conventions and GeekNights.
Scott: yet the game still seems to be going strongly enough.
Scott: I don't feel like the game is weak or bad or anything.
Rym: Yep Now I guess any more we would say wouldn't really be how to get into role-playing.
Rym: It would be how to cause good role-playing which is a whole other show.
Rym: Yep, and no point talk about that here This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at frontrowcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.