Scott: Wow today.
Scott: I've said it before but it's true today is the hottest goddamn day.
Rym: warm today.
Scott: it's very warm today.
Scott: it's intolerably warm.
Scott: I got home.
Scott: my tomato was falling over.
Scott: I had to go to Home Depot and get some sticks to hold the tomato up and everything I work.
Scott: I didn't every work to do.
Scott: I sat there bored for six hours.
Rym: meanwhile I'm just exhausted and this tetanus shot is not doing me any favors.
Rym: I gotta say yeah it basically everything sucks except bacon.
Scott: yes not everything sucks bacon and everything does not suck but it's con season.
Scott: real soon this weekend begins the onslaught of doom.
Rym: yeah we'll have a normal episode tomorrow.
Rym: don't worry about.
Scott: yes and stuff is bothering us now.
Scott: so today we're just gonna do a special episode like 10 minutes or not very long episode.
Scott: this is a special episode.
Rym: in fact this is I want to point out this might be one step below a special.
Rym: this might be a flash whoa.
Rym: anyway continue what.
Scott: yeah I would you say if you have never listened to GeekNights before this is not a normal episode of GeekNights.
Scott: this is a Rym and Scott are really tired and lazy episode of GeekNights but we still want to put something in the feed so we don't look like shit talker.
Rym: you see the words.
Rym: the assholes the word special for us means Rym and Scott are too lazy to do a real show.
Scott: think of it this way.
Scott: you know sometimes a webcomic artist puts up like just a pencil sketch without any words or colors.
Scott: this is it's basically a dead dead Rym and Scott day.
Rym: yep so I need to go to sleep.
Scott: there's no news there's no things of the day.
Rym: well there's a ton of news.
Rym: I really want to talk about it kind of news.
Rym: I want to talk about the PlayStation 3 price draw.
Scott: I don't care about that.
Rym: I care about that because I want to tell everyone it doesn't freaking matter yeah whatever.
Rym: anyway forget all that.
Scott: get all that bullshit.
Scott: we're just gonna talk about a happy little game that everyone well I guess maybe some people should play.
Rym: I'm actually really sour on the game.
Scott: yeah I was really hot on it and then I was really sour.
Scott: the game we're gonna talk about today is a nice happy little non collectible car game called chrono knots from looney labs.
Rym: looney labs makes a lot of fun little things.
Scott: looney labs they make the flux.
Scott: they make the nano fictionary.
Scott: they make Aquarius which I have.
Scott: they make chrono knots.
Scott: of course they make a bunch of fun little games and the themes of these games are really fun and the games are really fun and I've heard that the people who make the games are really cool and I would not doubt that for a second.
Rym: so chrono knots which we're gonna talk about very briefly.
Rym: in some.
Rym: the way the game works is you lay out the history of the world in cards many of which can be flipped over the history of the modern world like it starts in the late 1800s and goes all the way up to like the 80s.
Rym: in the 90s yeah it's like you know World War one World War two and all that up until nuclear bombs.
Rym: yeah near like.
Scott: the events near the end are like you know Challenger exploding and World War three stuff like that.
Rym: right now you all play as travelers and the thing is there's a bunch of different travelers they all have different goals and every player gets a different one.
Scott: secretly yes the story is that there are many different universes and in each universe history happened differently.
Scott: you know in one universe there was a nuclear explosion in World War two like on London or so.
Scott: I'm just making stuff up because I don't really remember the details like in another universe the Lusitania didn't sink right.
Scott: so you're a time traveler and this you're in a universe with a bunch of other people and everyone sort of shares the same universe this row of cards.
Scott: it's actually a grid of cards and everyone on their turn attempts to manipulate all the cards on the board in such a way that your universe the universe that you the traveler are from is the one that comes to be.
Scott: for example if you are squadron's the cockroach from the future you want World War three to happen now.
Scott: that's the only way in which you can exist.
Rym: now.
Rym: there's two really cool things about this game and one effect that you all have a secret mission.
Rym: you don't know what everyone else's me.
Scott: yeah you don't know what the other people are trying to do.
Scott: you just know that the other people are trying to do something.
Scott: that's not what you're trying to do.
Rym: so there can be a lot of bluffing and a lot of stuff like that.
Rym: yeah I believe it's a complete information game but not a perfect information game.
Scott: yes you you don't know what other people have in their hands.
Rym: is the thing something like that?
Rym: I might have gotten the terminology wrong.
Rym: it's late.
Rym: yes I'll talk about game theory another time.
Scott: basically you have a deck of cards.
Scott: you put out the history of the world and you set it to the default.
Scott: true I guess true history right and everyone has some cards and on your turn you sort of draw and play cards and the cards do things.
Scott: some cards let you draw more cards some cards let you alter the history.
Scott: some cards are artifacts.
Scott: you can.
Scott: you can get like collections of artifacts to do cool things like if you get all the Mona Lisa's you might be able to win or something like that.
Scott: you know and you can.
Scott: on the board there are two types of cards in the history.
Scott: there are lynchpin events in history and there are just normal events and the way it works is the lynchpins.
Scott: you flip them over right.
Scott: so let's say the Lusitania sinking let's say I flip that over I look on the board and there's a cool system with these various symbols and I'm like okay if the Lusitania didn't sink then that means that this card over here about World War one.
Scott: we're gonna flip that over and it turns into like a paradox card.
Scott: right and basically you try to you know someone else might need that card to not be a paradox or maybe they have a card in their hand that says you know I don't know Archduke Ferdinand not assassinated kills assassin right but they can't play that card unless the card that's currently occupying the spot is set to paradox.
Rym: you see what I'm saying I don't know if I'm explaining it that basically you manipulate history to change the configuration of the board and everything has far-reaching consequences.
Rym: and once the board is in the configuration of your players victory condition you win immediately in the games over.
Scott: yeah so it's kind of a fun game because the actual theme of the game is hilarious if you've never played it before.
Scott: I mean yes the text on the character cards is funny the artifacts are funny.
Scott: the different historical situations that can come up are funny like oh man look at that.
Scott: there's a history in which John Lennon wasn't assassinated and now he's protesting the space shuttle.
Scott: oh man that's hilarious.
Rym: now the other neat thing is that we talked about those paradoxes.
Rym: there are two interesting things that can happen in the game.
Rym: one if too many paradoxes appear on the board and no one fixes him the world ends and everyone loses.
Scott: yeah unless you there's one person one character where if you have that character you win in that situation now I do.
Rym: if there if you set the history up a certain way World War three happens and then there is just no history beyond that point yep it's pretty cool when that happens actually.
Rym: so the game.
Rym: I highly recommend.
Rym: playing this game at a con with someone else who owns it with a bunch of people who collectively have never played it before yeah it'll be hilarious if you've never played it before.
Scott: the thing is like guillotine.
Scott: yes these games.
Scott: it's a non collectible card game.
Scott: it's a game that's just a deck of cards and an instruction book and you don't have to collect anything even though there is an expansion and it's like about 10 15 bucks something like that.
Scott: it's actually a pretty big deck of cards but you're only gonna play it so many times before you're bored of it and you don't really play it again.
Rym: yeah because the humor runs out and once you strip the humor in the theme away it's a fairly straightforward manipulation game.
Scott: yeah the game pretty much comes down to you know everyone is manipulating this shared resource to try to configure it the way they want and basically whoever wins comes down to what cards you draw.
Scott: you know what you draw the cards that allow you to switch the board to be the way you want then you win.
Rym: it's a simplified version of let's say you had a game where four people take turns making one move on a Rubik's Cube and everyone has a secret configuration that if the cube looks like that they win yep and you just go around until someone makes it.
Scott: yep that's pretty much what it is.
Rym: so don't buy the game.
Rym: I really I like it.
Rym: I like looney labs but it's not really that worth buying unless you're the kind of person who tends to have people over.
Rym: aren't so into gaming?
Rym: or you meet new people all the time and you want something you can whip out that will entertain them quickly and easily.
Scott: yeah definitely good for the families and the kids and that sort of thing.
Scott: you know.
Scott: you just whip this thing out with some people who aren't necessary for gamers that care about gaming.
Rym: this isn't gonna do it for you you know except unless if you're at an Akan with friends and you've never played this before.
Rym: it is really fun the first couple time it is.
Scott: it's really fun a bunch of times until you've seen every all the content and that the humor is gone.
Scott: but it's really good for entertaining normal people and it's actually looney labs.
Scott: games are a really great gateway into getting normal people to sort of slide them on in because you can slide them from looney labs over to like Steve Jackson games and then once you're in Steve Jackson games you can go just about anywhere.
Scott: you know but yeah I don't know it's it's worth it.
Scott: ten bucks fifteen bucks for some people not for others and it's grown or not you can get it just about anywhere.
Scott: oh it's also good filler like if you're having a big gaming night and in between some big heavy games you can whip this out for just like a quick little.
Scott: you know refresh it's good for that.
Rym: it's also good if you got too many people over to all play one game.
Rym: everyone who's not hardcore can just play this and have fun.
Rym: while the other ball though I don't want to say well the men are playing their family game because they're definitely not true.
Rym: but more if you're not like if you don't care about board games to the kind of freakish level that we care about board game and you
Scott: want to play a game that's not a typical American game and you know you want to have something that's got a lot of humor in it.
Scott: it's way to go right.
Rym: so on that note stay tuned tomorrow night when we'll be back to our regularly scheduled GeekNights.
Rym: but I'm going to bed.
Scott: I'm going maybe take a shower and then go to bed madness.