Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday April 13th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we review the battle for Wesnoth an amazing turn-based strategy game for the PC.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: This is a very momentous occasion for GeekNights for you see on another show.
Rym: indirectly We have probably received what I would call our first actual legitimate hate mail ever.
Scott: Well, I mean, I think we've gotten things before that they weren't like they might have been considered hate mail But no one was actually really hating us or we weren't a hundred percent sure that they were not kidding.
Rym: and well There was that one that started out Okay, but then it went a little weird at the end and there was that Admiral beefy or whatever his name is thing.
Rym: But if that was actually real I feel sorry for that, dude.
Scott: Yeah, that dude's a scary, dude Gary.
Rym: uh, this is not the.
Rym: I'd like to play a clip.
Rym: We're not gonna talk about this tonight since it's Tuesday and it has nothing to do with video games at all.
Scott: I don't even know why we're playing it tonight.
Scott: That's all Rym.
Rym: Well, I thought that it was hilarious and furthermore to make sure that you get the entirety of the hilarity I edited out everything but the actual craziness from the response.
Rym: We got to a fairly innocent question that Scott asked a fellow podcaster.
Rym: There are multiple questions.
Media: Do you think that if I concentrate hard enough I could kill him with the power of my mind?
Media: The thing is like his email is stupid for reasons that have nothing to do with the fact that it's not.
Media: It doesn't take all our fucking powers combined because this is such a retarded question that no any one of us could answer this.
Media: Even if it was shoujo, you would still be a condescending sexist asshole.
Media: Oh It's straight-up sci-fi So it couldn't possibly be shoujo.
Media: You don't want to say that a shoujo work could be on par with Tezuka.
Media: I think Hagio moto, you know the female Tezuka as she's referred to you would have something to fucking say about that First off.
Media: Do you have any idea what shoujo means?
Media: you have any idea with these?
Media: Classifications mean in Japan.
Media: She's one of the women who helped to fucking define shoujo.
Media: God how insulting is this?
Media: Like I just can't get over how Dismissive this email is of shoujo manga Insinuating that.
Media: oh, how could such a solid sci-fi series possibly be a girl's manga?
Media: and that kind of as if to imply that Only guys girls can't write sci-fi.
Media: You know, it doesn't excuse the stupidity of this email.
Media: Oh What that's retarded.
Media: There's no words for how retarded that is.
Media: And I guess it pisses me off more because like this is GeekNights.
Media: I mean these guys do a podcast Where they talk about anime and you guys are always boasting about how much you know Mr.
Media: Z. We ran the RIT anime club.
Media: So our otaku cock is the biggest.
Media: what now?
Media: No, I'm not cool with this.
Rym: If that's the kind of hate mail we get I'm all for it.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, I don't know what.
Scott: what her problem is.
Rym: She figured out our secret.
Rym: if anything our otaku cock is in fact that big.
Rym: she must have spied it from space.
Scott: Oh, I don't know.
Rym: Well, there was that eclipse.
Scott: Maybe she was just getting pissed off at it poking her in the eye.
Scott: Anyway anyway It's video games right all games in general.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, so if you haven't heard the Xbox 360 Elite is Coming out now.
Rym: this really really reeks of ultra FARC.
Scott: Why was it Rico of ultra FARC?
Rym: Well in terms of people always joke about how stratified FARC is at least people in FARC how there's FARC.
Rym: and then there's the people Who are so rich and beyond that they can afford the five bucks a month or whatever to get that little total FARC icon next To their name even though I've been tempted to buy it a couple times Mostly because it also gives you the ability on FARC to block people.
Scott: Well this Xbox 360 elite is an Xbox 360.
Scott: It's gonna be out on April 29th, and it's a bit different from the Xbox 360s that are currently available.
Rym: So it's not just a money grab.
Scott: no not really well.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: No it depends.
Scott: first of all it's black Opposed to me.
Rym: wait so it's you mean It's the same color as the original Xbox or all the consoles from the previous generation except the Gamecube?
Scott: Yeah, it's basically Color of the old Xbox shape of the new Xbox.
Rym: I always thought it was interesting how everything kind of went white and now Microsoft's like oh check this out black.
Scott: It's pretty much.
Scott: people only know how to do industrial design with two colors.
Scott: these days It's white and black and either the you know they'll do white as the default and then the special one is black You know.
Scott: and meanwhile before it was black was normal and the special one is white.
Scott: It's like what the hell just it's just the color.
Scott: it doesn't mean anything.
Rym: well, I'm seeing this in cars lately I'm looking at cars.
Rym: just because my current car might Positively be honest last legs I got to see how much it's gonna cost to fix part of the cool.
Rym: It's just but all the cars.
Rym: I looked at.
Rym: I went to a bunch of dealers that were around 90%.
Rym: of them are either white black or gray.
Scott: Yeah, actually when I was buying my current car there was like a selection of like 10 to 12 colors.
Scott: You could pick for the car.
Scott: But like two of them like I remember one of them was like this pearl white something that cost more than the other colors And I'm like what the hell is just it's just a different color.
Scott: What why are you charging more for one color?
Rym: Yeah, it's not like you're buying the gold-plated Mazda 3 should cost.
Scott: shouldn't the engine be the part that cost more anyway?
Scott: also this elite Xbox 360 will have a 120 gigabyte hard drive uh-huh which is that's actually a good thing.
Scott: because Well Xbox is right now don't have big enough hard drives.
Scott: so when people download all this extra stuff and they play a lot of games and they start downloading videos and Demos they run out of room real quick
Rym: especially since this whole xlive download stuff thing is going really well And I got to say I applaud Microsoft for their efforts.
Scott: secondly.
Scott: They're adding in well.
Scott: thirdly I guess they're adding an HDMI port.
Scott: so you don't have to use component cables for HD.
Scott: you can use the HDMI cable for HD.
Scott: Aha I'm of the mind that I I'm not a hundred percent sure that there is no difference in the visual quality when using a component cable versus an HDMI cable.
Scott: But I'm pretty sure that the majority of people could not tell the difference in a double-blind.
Rym: I'd really like to see some double blinds.
Rym: I remember double blinds from the audiophile people who couldn't tell the difference between some super-leet audio file awesome Gold cable system and a 1989 boombox.
Scott: Yep Also this Xbox 360 is four hundred and eighty dollars.
Scott: Aha So what this is done?
Scott: really I mean if you think about it It's not that much better than the Xbox 360 premium Which is like three hundred dollars.
Scott: right because I mean what does it have?
Scott: it has HDMI hole which isn't a significant difference.
Scott: It has a significantly larger hard drive.
Scott: But that hard drive is going to be available separately for a hundred and eighty dollars Which basically if you bought an Xbox 360 premium and the hard drive it would cost just as much as the elite 360
Rym: but then you also get the HDMI port and you don't have to have this extra thing.
Scott: Now the problem that everyone's complaining about is of course the things this elite doesn't have.
Scott: first of all it doesn't have that HD DVD drive built in.
Scott: it has just the regular drive, so you still need that external HD DVD drive to watch the HD DVD movies with it.
Scott: it doesn't have Freaking wireless internet, so you still have to connect it to the internet with a cable which granted That's the number one complaint.
Rym: granted for us at least the Wii by default only comes with wireless And I'd rather it just had an ethernet hole so I could plug it in.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: wireless I think is better because it increases a lot of play in your house.
Scott: I mean most people don't have a wire.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I agree for not.
Rym: for 99% of people the wireless is bad right.
Scott: also If you're going places with your system, which you tend to do with the game console these days It's you're not gonna be able to get a wire near your system.
Scott: You're gonna need to use a wireless like a hotel or something.
Scott: so wireless these days at least is generally better than wired and having wired only on the 360 really Means that a lot of people are not gonna be able to use the Xbox Live and we're not using the Xbox Live.
Scott: why buy An Xbox?
Rym: see I say for us mostly because we happen to have a switch Sitting next to the TV that really wants to be used by more than one day.
Scott: Yeah, just because we're geeks and we have a cable down there.
Scott: See what's happening here actually is.
Scott: a lot of people are seeing this and they're saying all right.
Scott: first of all that hard drive is way overpriced 120 gigs for $180.
Scott: you could buy a better hard drive than that at the store.
Rym: for a PC you can buy a 750 gigabyte hard drive for like 120.
Scott: by granted This is a two and a half inch hard drive and not a three and a half inch.
Scott: But that's not that big a deal these days that anymore.
Scott: the thing is this is four hundred eighty dollars.
Scott: a ps3 is $600.
Rym: well the high-end ps3 what about the low-end ps3?
Scott: low and ps3 is about the same as this thing, huh?
Scott: So it actually kind of makes the ps3 look okay.
Scott: Yeah I mean what they should have done is they should have brought this out and charge the same amount of money for this as they charge for the high-end Xbox 360 and then lower the prices on the other 360s that already exist then they wouldn't make the ps3 look so good.
Rym: But then again while the ps3 is looking a little better now that little big world which is perhaps the only game I have seen that well I'm not gonna buy a ps3.
Rym: if I were the kind of person who could be swayed to buy a ps3 That game would have done it.
Scott: Yeah The PlayStation 2 and the PlayStation 1 had all sorts of great games, and it looks like even though Developers you know are not so hip to the ps3 as they were There's still gonna be a whole bunch of awesome type games for it probably in the long run But it's just not worth the money at least not right now.
Rym: Yeah especially since there has been a lot of talk that IBM and other companies have been refining the manufacturing process of the cell chip and While not in the near future so no one who really wants a ps3 can worry about it in the long run the ps3 is Going to get a lot cheaper like every piece of technology in the history of technology.
Scott: Yeah, I mean when I'm 30 something years old.
Scott: I'll probably be able to get a ps3 for like $100.
Rym: granted look at us We're now bulking it paying nothing to get a ps2.
Rym: yeah Granted part of that is that if we get a ps2 we're gonna play guitar heroes, and if we play guitar heroes We're not gonna have any time to do anything else in our lives for at least a month.
Scott: probably not Yeah, so Xbox 360 elite is really not that elite.
Scott: and the other thing is the head.
Scott: It's comes with that with the headset.
Scott: You know you can talk to people But it comes with a wired headset instead of the wireless one.
Scott: ah it's like what.
Scott: if you're gonna make the elite Why don't you give it like with everything?
Scott: give people a full set of controllers.
Scott: give people?
Scott: Four wireless headsets.
Scott: give people the HDTV drive the biggest hard drive the best everything.
Scott: make it the full set.
Rym: well You know what they're probably gonna.
Scott: Do charge the same amount of money.
Rym: There was the Xbox now And then there's gonna be the Xbox complete, and it's gonna have everything and it's gonna cost slightly more than the elite costs.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't even know why they bother like.
Rym: oh, I know why because people are gonna buy it.
Rym: They're gonna make money off of this They're gonna make a lot of money.
Scott: because I don't know.
Scott: it seems to think the news is saying At least the word on the internet switches completely unreliable is like Hardcore people aren't liking the elite.
Scott: They're all complaining about it.
Rym: Well that is the one issue.
Rym: hardcore people already own an Xbox.
Scott: yes But the PD word is also that you know if hardcore people don't buy it Then there won't be the trickling down to the non hardcore people.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I think people who don't care about how much money it costs and don't have a 360 already will probably buy the elite one just for the bigger hard drive.
Scott: and You know if you have an HDMI TV by the HDMI port you might as well use it.
Scott: It's not gonna hurt you.
Rym: plus regardless of the possible future potential of the ps3 Right now the Xbox has a lot more to offer.
Rym: so even if you pay this premium for the Xbox Which is comparable to the price for a low-end ps3.
Rym: I think you get a lot more out of the deal.
Scott: Yeah, you definitely get something for it, but it's still.
Scott: they're giving you their shorthand.
Rym: And I also think it doesn't cost Microsoft very much more to make this thing and I imagine every one They sell is pure profit.
Scott: Probably so if you want one April 29 $480.
Rym: so there's been a lot of buzz about the PSP lately which has also been really surprising because the PSP was launched and Almost a long time ago fell flat and its sales were absolutely nothing compared to the DS.
Rym: even the early days of the DS It was just selling like hotcakes relative.
Rym: And then UMD failed and there weren't any games for the PSP and a lot of the mainstream gaming press kind of forgot about it.
Rym: Recently the PSP while it's definitely not doing well went from an also ran to a doing kind of okay Gonna be a decent second place.
Scott: as soon as they stopped paying attention to those stupid UMD crap movie things And they just said all right Let's make some games.
Scott: for this turns out that some people actually made some games for the PSP And there's quite a few of them out there.
Rym: Yeah, if I owned a PSP.
Rym: I'd probably buy three or four games.
Scott: right now It's like I look at that PSP shelf, and I see some good stuff there.
Rym: It's almost like Sony realized that Everything they had done for the past couple years had been an abortion.
Rym: so they decided all right Let's do a couple things smart.
Rym: Let's make a game called little big planet, and let's make games for the PSP.
Rym: and now this is the news Let's lower the price of the PSP.
Rym: 30 bucks all right $170 is not that bad.
Scott: It's only 40 more than a DS.
Rym: Yeah, that's what I'm saying cuz the PSP while it doesn't have the nearly the Library that the DS has the PSP does have the fact that you can listen to podcasts on it.
Scott: you can download.
Scott: It's the only thing that I've heard of the only reasonable reasonably available Common device that you can get.
Scott: they can subscribe to and download and listen to podcasts all in one portable device.
Rym: also There is some fantastic NES Emulators for the PSP and in fact everyone I've ever met who had a PSP Proudly showed me their NES emulator and their giant pile of ROMs.
Scott: another thing I've noticed about the PSP Is that they've realized I guess a lot of people who own it like you know the old-school games And they've been releasing a lot of PSP games that are just rehashes or remixes Or you know just rereleases of older games like there's some Castlevania action on there And there's a Mega Man action on there.
Rym: Well.
Rym: They must have seen how well Nintendo is doing by selling Mario 1 to me again.
Rym: Plus imagine this and this is total speculation.
Rym: I don't think Nintendo will actually do it because we all know that Nintendo only does things if they make a lot of money off of it, but Imagine if Nintendo coupled the fact that the Wii can download stuff with the DS and say you could pay to get I don't know Mario 1 in your Wii And then you can do the download demo play and get Mario 1 in your DS until you turn it off like they do with demos.
Rym: now That would be an absolutely killer app for a lot of people.
Scott: yep Yeah But I think what's happening with the PSP is the same thing that we're seeing on the Wii and the same thing we kind of Saw on the DS is that the game development industry is becoming ridiculously risk-averse.
Scott: They don't want to take any risks Especially since it costs way too much to develop a game.
Scott: even a DS game costs a reasonable amount of money to develop Even if you don't have to pay Nintendo a lot of money.
Rym: Yeah, and a few people took a bath on the n-gauge.
Scott: Yes, so no one wants to develop a game and have it be for a system That isn't gonna sell or make a game that has no chance of selling.
Scott: so when a system is new no matter What system it is?
Scott: Nobody wants to make a game for it that cost any amount of money.
Scott: They'll make a cheap game for it Which is why the PSP came out and there were just crap games.
Scott: a DS came out There's tech demos.
Scott: we came out just tech demos Because no one wants to pay You know and make a huge investment and develop a real game For a system that just came out or isn't even out yet.
Scott: You have no idea how well that system is gonna do.
Scott: so I think from here on out unless suddenly games become cheaper easier to develop or You know people stop buying games that cost so much to develop and maybe game developers and publishers Want to take some risks
Rym: you're
Scott: always gonna see a new console come out no matter what console it is Not have any games for it for quite a while and unless a lot of people buy the console and buy the tech demos for It then and only then will you actually see the real games come out.
Rym: But then if consumers are smart you have this chicken-egg scenario where I won't buy a ps3 until there's good games for the ps3 And the developers won't make good games the ps3 until I buy a ps3 Exactly.
Scott: and the only way this cycle of doom is gonna stop is either.
Scott: if we keep buying Consoles that don't have good games for them publishers decide to take some risks.
Scott: games become cheaper to develop.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I think in the immediate term This is actually slightly beneficial to gamers, and this is some roundabout logic here.
Rym: But think of this.
Rym: the only people who buy a console at launch are the people who are hardcore about gaming in sorry babe.
Rym: Yes, well, but the ps3 was mostly eBay as we learn.
Rym: but for the DS I mean the average gamer wasn't just gonna buy a DS an opening day because there was nothing for it.
Rym: nothing at all.
Rym: But people like me and Scott when I bought the DS to me.
Rym: I was voting with my dollars.
Rym: I was saying I'm going to put forth X money Because I believe that X money is worth faith that this console is going to be worth it to me someday.
Rym: and by buying it Now I am giving it my vote And I think at least aside from the ps3 People who buy a console ahead of time like that are voting for that console and all the potential of that console whether they realize It or not now.
Rym: the ps2 didn't have to worry about that because the ps2 had so much momentum from the ps1 that Developers just jumped on it immediately because it was a sure thing.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is with this voting is that it's not free voting.
Scott: It's one thing if you go to the election booth and you vote for someone for president.
Scott: They don't I agree.
Scott: It's definitely a vote with six hundred dollars, and then you lose.
Scott: you just lost six hundred dollars.
Scott: It got nothing for it.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Hence.
Rym: The only people who vote are people who are rich confident or stupid.
Scott: Oh well, maybe one day our Answers will come.
Rym: yep, though I also think Nintendo is one of the few companies that has the really really Prime position to take this cycle and break it with consoles if they were just hit with more first-party games early on.
Scott: I also think another good solution which is sort of falls into the Lower your development cost solution is when you make a game make the game and then just make more of the game.
Scott: You don't need everyone freaking updates their engine and as the graphics and everything just make Ten more levels and put out the same game again.
Scott: We don't care if your game was good.
Scott: We want more.
Scott: It's like looking like half-life 2. they just made more levels.
Scott: I bought it.
Scott: You know, what other games is that DDR?
Scott: They just make more songs.
Scott: we buy it.
Rym: Yep Guitar heroes definitely has that infinite product cycle of constantly buying new versions because there's always something new And you don't have to do anything to the game because the game already exists.
Scott: Yeah, maybe we release old games That people can't find anymore.
Scott: Yeah, take games that are already made in other countries and already profitable.
Scott: just translate them and sell them.
Rym: with Nintendo I see I mean with the GameCube.
Rym: they hit us right away with Smash Brothers Melee, which Effectively the GameCube was a Smash Brothers Melee machine for a long time after most people bought it And I think that that drove a lot of sales.
Rym: the first party games that hit right away.
Rym: I think they hit right away because the GameCube wasn't really positioned very well, especially after the n64.
Scott: That is something else.
Scott: is that the GameCube while it hit pretty poorly it did hit with like Two first party games the Luigi's Mansion, which wasn't so good but it was still a first party game that people hadn't played and The Smash Brothers and then a little while later came the Metroid Prime.
Scott: So it's really three first party games right away.
Scott: The Wii still has really only one.
Scott: I don't even want to count anything other than Zelda.
Rym: Yeah but I'd wait trucks.
Rym: okay the reason that it's different here?
Rym: because Nintendo could have hit with the Wii and they might even been planning to But notice how they pushed off some dates for games and things.
Rym: Yeah I think that because the Wii is still selling solely on the virtue of Wii Sports and the fact that it's oh, yeah I mean Wii Sports single-handedly is selling I'd say currently if not the majority at least a significant percentage of probably all of them.
Rym: Yeah, well because all the gamers who bought one already bought one, but all the grandmas who want to bowl and play tennis They're selling like hotcakes.
Scott: It's basically a bowling and tennis machine.
Scott: as far as they're concerned They're never gonna buy another game for.
Rym: so I've said this before but Nintendo is gonna wait and I'll bet pretty much as we sale Slack the pressure they put to make first party games come out is going to increase directly proportional.
Scott: Well, well super paper Mario comes out.
Scott: I think next week I'm excited about super paper Mario because why that's a pre-order that Amazon.
Scott: Oh, you better get to that.
Scott: I think I will.
Scott: I got.
Scott: I'll get a pre-order all the video games.
Scott: actually probably this weekend I don't know.
Rym: ever since I started playing some Smash Brothers melee again recently I'm feeling the new Smash Brothers real hardcore.
Scott: It's not gonna.
Scott: they haven't dated that or showed us anything other than solids.
Rym: No, no, no, no, but I'm more excited about this game that I've been about any game since Twilight Princess.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, well not counting PC games Things of the day.
Rym: so Scott and Alex had both been it.
Rym: Well Scott more so than anyone been on this tower defense game kick for a while.
Scott: Yeah, I played pretty much every free tower defense game on the Internet's.
Rym: I resisted this mostly due to the fact that every tower defense Game I saw sucked ass.
Scott: Well, some of them were good some of them better than others.
Scott: Some of them did suck ass in general.
Scott: It's sort of one of those game genres where it's either Playable or unplayable.
Rym: Yeah, well plus I don't really have time to play flash games at work Like I might have at other jobs I've had.
Rym: so I really just didn't play him.
Rym: but Alex started getting into him and we started playing this one in the living room and What was originally going to be a German board gaming night?
Rym: Ended up with us sitting there for like an hour or two Each of us on a computer in the same room not talking playing the stupid tower defense game.
Scott: This one is actually a lot better than a lot of the others because in other tower defense games Generally, there's a path that the enemies follow and at one end they come in the other end they come out and you put your towers in between the path and Try to position them to do the most damage to the bad guys as they fuck go along the merry way And you don't let them.
Scott: you want to kill them before they get off the map.
Rym: now see the basic idea of a tower defense game is kind of a genre of gaming is You've got a thing and you want to protect it from other things that are coming to get it.
Scott: yes, you allocate resources into damage dealing things and then position them so that you get the most out of them and therefore you most.
Scott: You try to spend your resources to most efficiently get as much damage as possible.
Rym: Well this game called desktop tower defense probably is the best tower defense game out there And if anyone knows of one better, I implore you to share it with everyone in the forums.
Rym: This game has enough variety in enemies and in structures to keep you interested pretty much the whole way through.
Rym: Yep It has a very unique setup where you build your structures and not only do the structures attack the enemies in different ways But the structures themselves form the path that the enemies follow.
Scott: Yes If you don't if you just build your structures like in the middle of the map all the bad guys that come from the top Will go straight to the bottom and leave and all the bad guys that come in from the left will go straight to the right And leave.
Scott: but if you build your towers like to make walls You can never block it off so you can never trap the bad guys so they can't get off the map Because that would just be stupid.
Scott: but what you can do is you can make a maze you can use your towers which deal damage and position them such that they make a maze and the enemies have to go in between the towers and you can give them a Very long path to follow before they make it to the other end of the map and are able to escape.
Rym: Now we've all beaten level 50 pretty handily after playing this game a little bit And I think you'll be able to do well at it, too.
Rym: They'll warn you it is difficult and you're gonna have some trouble early on until you figure out a cue a cue a few key ideas like Maybe you should take a narrow path for your guys to follow.
Rym: Maybe you should try to funnel all the guys coming in into one spot and then have them go off together So you can maximize firepower, huh?
Rym: That one structure seems to damage things adjacent to it.
Rym: Maybe I should increase its surface area.
Scott: Yeah, all kinds of stuff like that.
Scott: It's pretty good.
Scott: There's a. I think the one thing that's about it That is the best is that in other tower defense games generally some towers are just better than others and it's a matter of do I build which tower do you build and are you gonna build more towers?
Scott: You're just gonna upgrade a few towers and this one.
Scott: you kind of have to buy the cheap tower a lot even though it sucks relatively speaking because well You you have to build walls and there's no other way to build enough towers to make a maze other than using a lot Of the cheap tower and it's kind of annoying.
Scott: I just want to build a big tower, but no you can't.
Scott: I got to build a small tower.
Rym: I'll yummy many times and you find yourself making your thing pretty much out of these cheap pellet towers and you can also.
Rym: Then you'll augment that by putting special towers and key locations.
Rym: Everything's upgradeable.
Rym: You can sell stuff.
Rym: There's different kind.
Scott: Every tower defense game there's always been the option to sell.
Scott: this is the first time I've actually used it because I'll basically build a Maze with the shitty pellet towers and then you know That'll hold me out and I'll be able to get more money and then I'll sell pellet towers to put better ones in their place.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So, you know those bio Tapestries ba why you X?
Rym: yes.
Rym: Yes, I do.
Scott: It's the real.
Scott: it's a really long and narrow tapestry that shows the Norman invasion of England.
Rym: dodongo dislike its smoke.
Scott: Yep, those this this Saxons dislike if the Normans Exactly, but that same tapestry.
Scott: Well some guy decided he was gonna make something in the vein of that tapestry Involving, of course Super Mario, of course, of course.
Scott: So he made this really long image.
Scott: It's like a few.
Scott: I guess if you printed it out It'd be a few feet long and as you scroll to the right it plays out a fucked up version Of level 1 - 1 in Super Mario Brothers.
Rym: It reminds me a lot of various walk down the street and fight games like.
Rym: the aesthetic is definitely there.
Rym: You know, we're your Hagar and you're punching guys and hammer locking them and killing them as you are.
Scott: Yeah, it also reminds me sort of a chromatic plus a communist Mario sort of thing Hagar and Freddy.
Rym: You're kind of similar.
Scott: yeah, yeah, they are and I'll just say that when you finally scroll to the very very right end of this tapestry if you will There is a joke waiting for you.
Scott: So make sure you start on the way left and scroll to the right very slowly.
Rym: Scott very pointedly took control of the mouse and showed it really revealed it to me bit by bit much the way you'd reveal a Newman.
Scott: Yeah, if you view this as just one large image on some tremendously tremendous wide screen monitor or Many monitors side by side and have a really wide browser window You'll lose the whole effect.
Rym: If you have a monitor and a resolution such that you see this entire thing at once without having to do anything without having to Zoom out my head is off to you.
Scott: Good, sir It's pretty long.
Rym: So we've talked about a lot of different games lately and one thing we haven't talked about our PC games.
Scott: Well, I think that's partially because a lot of the PC games that we really like are old and dead and we all run Linux.
Scott: So we're not playing new PC games and our PCs suck.
Scott: So we're not playing new PC games.
Scott: Yes Particularly gaming is dying or dead.
Rym: Yes as is evidenced by the fact that Walmart is all but eliminating their PC game section in several of their cell.
Scott: if you went To an EB a few years ago.
Scott: The PC section is like one shelf.
Rym: Yeah, last time I went to an EB in New York City.
Rym: The only PC games they had were in this bin for five bucks.
Rym: I went over there, but there was nothing worth five.
Scott: well if you go to the GameStop at Near us there's like, you know GameCube section the DS section the Wii section a giant ps2 section a giant Xbox 360 section.
Scott: They take up like big chunks of the wall of the store.
Scott: the PC games take up one Freestanding wheelie shelf in the middle of this man.
Rym: I remember a day when if I went to an EB They sold nothing but computer games pretty much.
Rym: Yeah, and if I wanted a non computer game I had to go to Toys R Us to buy a Nintendo game.
Scott: Yeah they used to be.
Scott: it's a good like software etc.
Scott: to get computer games and the PC games and the Console games were sold in completely different places.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I think about this.
Rym: there were stores dedicated to selling PC games.
Scott: yeah, cuz PC games were considered software and Console games are considered toys.
Rym: I would go to Babbages and pay 15 bucks more than I should have to get a PC game and it would be on the same shelf as a C Plus plus compiler from Borland Software etc.
Rym: I just had a bunch of memories of when I was young wondering what the hell a compiler was and why I would $90 C++ compiler that for Windows 3.1 that is on like 14 floppy disks.
Rym: I also remember owning more PC games than I had hard drive space and having to rotate games in and out depending on what mood I was in.
Scott: anyway Wes Noth is an interesting PC game because number one it works no matter what your OS.
Scott: so Windows Mac Linux.
Scott: You can play this game dude.
Rym: You can play this on net BSD open VSD Solaris risk OS the GP 2x Windows BOS.
Scott: All right.
Rym: All right Amiga OS 4.
Scott: Also, it doesn't require a whole lot of system resources.
Scott: You can play this without a 3d card just fine.
Scott: If you've got a computer with a screen and a mouse and a keyboard and a modern CPU I guess you could probably play this on a Pentium 3 if you wanted to probably handily.
Scott: Yeah You can play this game.
Scott: And thirdly this game is free as in all types of free.
Scott: It is free isn't beer free?
Scott: isn't speech free isn't free free free.
Scott: It costs nothing to play.
Scott: You can edit it.
Scott: You can do whatever you want.
Rym: So the battle for Wes Noth is a game designed by a man named David White.
Rym: He made it and I think 2003. he started it and he's now the lead developer for the project.
Rym: I'm obviously semi quoting Wikipedia And it's based very heavily on several of those old Sega Genesis turn-based strategy games.
Scott: Yes This is a turn-based Strategy game.
Scott: you have a hex map and you have units on the hex map and you click on them and you move them And then if they're end up next to a bad guy you tell them to attack and they do some damage.
Rym: now I have a dark secret to reveal that Despite all of my PC gaming and I had command and conquer and red alert and Warcraft and all these games And X calm and everything.
Scott: I've always hated RTS's like really Well, the thing is I liked Warcraft 1 just because it was a fun game in.
Scott: in those days I wasn't really thinking about it.
Scott: I also like command and conquer for the same reason.
Rym: I liked Warcraft 1 and I liked command and conquer 1 but aircraft 2 also.
Rym: But I didn't enjoy them as much as I could because I spent half the game going Wow, this is really neat and half the game going.
Scott: god damn it.
Scott: Get out of the way the tank what?
Scott: Yes, I think over time the Frustrations with the RTS genre and the lack of change in it frustrated me enough that it was no longer fun Like when it I Warcraft 1 was a new idea.
Scott: Like when I saw Warcraft 1 I was like what the hell kind of game is this and the RTS was new and exciting And it was pretty much Warcraft 1 Warcraft 2 command and conquer command and conquer red alert.
Scott: Those are the four RTS's I guess total annihilation is.
Rym: you know, I know Is in a class all unto.
Scott: yes I never played it enough But I have a hard time disagreeing that it is like the RTS of RTS's and maybe supreme commander.
Scott: I don't know if I can say about that yet But yeah, I've heard good buzz on the internet.
Rym: But the only people who can play supreme commander with $5,000 computer like the hardest of core PC gamers.
Rym: And if you're a hardcore PC gamer, that's like being a hardcore Cubs fan.
Scott: Yeah, and while Warcraft 3 and Starcraft and those sorts of you know, and the newer command and conquers was probably technically RTS's they weren't really fun for me like even Starcraft which everyone loves.
Scott: It's not fun for me because it comes down to just being annoying.
Scott: I mean, it's click on know what buildings to build in the right order and know how many units to build.
Rym: Yeah, real-time strategy games are barely well one.
Rym: They're almost not about tactics at all or even about strategy.
Scott: It's like you.
Scott: eventually I mean I watched my brother play Warcraft 3 because he didn't play too many RTS's in his childhood.
Scott: So he got Warcraft 3 when he was into PC gaming and all he would do is know what order to build the buildings in.
Scott: Have the hero walk around the board getting levels.
Scott: Then he would eventually get like a supreme unit build as many as he could Select them all and click on the enemy base and that was it.
Scott: Yeah
Rym: I just play a lot of command and conquer online with a lot of people with my modem and then my cable modem back in the day and there was all those gaming networks, but I Weren't my friends who lived in the neighborhood who played the same way I did and I always would build units Like I'd build a squadron of tanks and then I'd send it off to a corner to the map and have him wait there.
Rym: Well, I built another group of units put somewhere else and I try to coordinate like pincer attacks and ambushes.
Scott: None of that stuff matters.
Rym: I tried to have strategy and one day one of my friends who was good at the game But I never really played against.
Rym: I asked him if I could just watch him play online because he always won and all he did Was build the tank producing buildings build a billion tanks select them all click on the enemy base weights Yeah, and I was like what?
Rym: Ah, that's how you win.
Rym: and he's like, yeah, what were you doing?
Rym: trying to build a wall?
Scott: Yeah, they put like command-and-conquer alert had walls cement walls barbed wire walls land mines.
Scott: All that stuff was useless.
Scott: Yeah Pretty only strategy was if you're the Soviets build as many tanks as you can and click on the enemy base Much like the actual Soviet military doctor.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It was quite accurate.
Scott: Anyway, this is why Regardless of accuracy or realism or anything else turn-based strategy games are fun.
Scott: Because this strategy you get to do whatever you want on your turn you have time to think about it.
Scott: You get there's.
Scott: actually it matters what you make and where you move it to.
Scott: You can look at numbers and figure out.
Scott: you know How much damage is gonna be done.
Scott: this terrain that matters.
Scott: and when you're done you push End by turn and then the other person goes and they take their turn because it's turn-based and not real-time.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now a bunch of other turn-based games.
Rym: I would definitely recommend advance Wars.
Rym: any advanced Wars game Especially advanced Wars 2 for the Gameboy Advance and X come X calm is very good.
Rym: If you're hardcore, I'd recommend this game called gem fire for the SNES But I don't think anyone's gonna be playing gem fire.
Rym: Jet fire is a badass freaking game.
Rym: You can die in a fire.
Scott: fantasy empires if you count that fantasy empires is turn-based and real-time.
Scott: Is it her.
Scott: I didn't know it was real time at all.
Rym: combat itself is real time.
Rym: Oh, right, but it's statistically based and it's not.
Rym: it's not really real - it's basically it's real time.
Rym: That doesn't pretend to have all this strategy.
Rym: basically all your units will be AI and they'll charge and all the enemies units of the AI and they'll charge.
Rym: and it call.
Rym: it comes down to is statistically which army was better and The one guy you were controlling?
Rym: you could do something specific like run over and smash up the enemy Yeah, that sort of thing.
Rym: Yeah, so that's really a special case.
Rym: But all those things aside for the PC right now I would say that Wesnoth is the premier RTS.
Rym: If not, what not RTS turn-based game if not one of the top ten?
Scott: Yeah, and civilization doesn't count because that's not like a strategy war game That's a strategy civilization game is different.
Rym: Yes Now Wesnoth is not a deterministic game.
Rym: Advance Wars is for the most part of determine.
Scott: Yes in Advance Wars it's deterministic.
Scott: that means if You have an infantry You know from this CEO and an infantry from that CEO and they're both standing on planes and they shoot each other This and this guy is the attacker and that guy's the defender.
Scott: every single time the same amount of damage will be done Pretty much like 90% of the time.
Scott: there's like so little difference in how much damage is done that it doesn't matter.
Rym: I mean I can know playing against Scott that if I'm grit and I've got an artillery and I shoot it at his tank and It's in this terrain and it's this damage
Scott: and he's in this terrain
Rym: I will do X damage to it and I can plan accordingly and so can Scott.
Scott: Yes and Wesnoth it is not as deterministic.
Scott: if yes, I have a Foot pad and he attacks a bat He'll do pretty much almost the same amount of damage each time.
Scott: But he it's sort of like D&D where it's like you might miss is it he might miss?
Scott: sometimes they do.
Scott: they just go miss miss miss.
Scott: sometimes they'll hit hit hit and kill the bat right away and Sometimes he'll do some in-between.
Scott: there is sort of this randomness in the game.
Scott: They were.
Scott: it's like the game is rolling dice for you where you can't see.
Rym: Yes, but the did the key thing here.
Rym: now We're not gonna go into a whole debate of deterministic versus random games.
Rym: Yes, I think that both methods have very much merit.
Rym: They really depends on what you're going for Yep And you can't say that one is better than the other and I I strongly disagree with people who do.
Rym: a lot of people do.
Rym: In fact, there are a lot of people who have forked Wesnoth and made deterministic versions and there's a bunch of them and they're all pretty bad.
Scott: Yeah, notice how the.
Scott: if any of the deterministic versions running good then the actual Wesnoth probably would have inherited those Deterministic traits and it hasn't therefore.
Rym: Yes,
Scott: obviously those deterministic games are no good,
Rym: but a common pitfall of Random damage games or any game where there's a lot of randomness or things that determine randomly like this Is that if you don't have enough of the randomness if you don't have enough instances where randomness is a factor?
Rym: Randomness can affect the game more readily because there's less time for it to even out.
Rym: Mmm, I think a battle lore is a good example of a game where while it can be fun I'm not gonna argue about this the randomness is concentrated to the point that one short run of bad luck can make you lose a battle Wholly and immediately.
Rym: well in Wesnoth, there is enough testing of randomness to where overall it would take one Freaking bad run for you to lose solely on red.
Scott: Well, I think the thing in Wesnoth is that randomness while it's there It serves two purposes and The first purpose is that it makes the game very simple.
Scott: part of the goal of Wesnoth is to have a turn-based war game That is simple that anyone can play it and not have to be a hardcore war master.
Rym: Yes yet at the same time He very much wanted a simple game that is not trivial a game that still has great tactical and strategic depth But yet doesn't force you to do mundane calculation.
Scott: yes, the other part of the advantage of the randomness is that it Removes any paralysis.
Scott: analysis paralysis if there was if it was a deterministic game.
Scott: It's a hex map with a whole bunch of different units and a whole bunch of factors.
Scott: You'd be sitting there Exactly calculating everything.
Scott: with the randomness.
Scott: It encourages you to just take your goddamn turn because and you just you just kind of go with it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: and also one big thing about war games that I have a love-hate relationship with is that Actual real warfare?
Rym: if you study history, I mean most people would say yeah in a video game You want it to be a hundred percent?
Rym: deterministic or even if it's random You want skill to no matter what.
Rym: if you send a better unit against a weaker unit you think that the weaker unit should always Die no matter what.
Rym: but actual warfare Relies a lot more on luck happenstance and just dumb circumstance.
Rym: Yes, then it ever has.
Rym: Okay, I mean battles turn on the fact that oh shits it rained one day or oh no Hitler was asleep And they didn't send the troops out in time.
Rym: Things like that.
Rym: Yeah, so a real a realistic war game has a lot more randomness than a pure gamer might like.
Rym: So a balanced war game that is based on randomness at all or as randomness in it You have to straddle that fine line between having someone to you know You have to make the decision of.
Rym: my cavalry might not come back if I send them into that plane.
Scott: The last comment I want to make about the randomness in Wesnoth is that it definitely adds some drama in the game.
Scott: Yes, sometimes, you know if the stronger unit always wanted it was deterministic.
Scott: when you send a guy out to fight It's not exciting and it would actually make the game less fun.
Scott: If you know aha my giant troll smashes your puny zombie, right?
Scott: But if it's sort of random Sometimes like a guy with a sword will go and cut up a really strong bad guy and do a lot of damage.
Scott: And now that guy has to run away and it's like haha.
Scott: Look at that.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and sometimes, you know it'll be random and a guy will go up and Attack and it won't do anything and you'd be like oh shit cuz.
Scott: now your guy is standing there out in the middle of the War zone and he didn't do any damage and there's a really strong pissed off guy right next to him.
Rym: Yep ah, I'll be watching like my last holdout standing in the elven fortress and Scott zombies are surrounding it and I'm just come on man.
Rym: Just hold out one more round.
Scott: Just hold out just hold out.
Scott: Yeah, well if you haven't gathered Wesnoth has a fantasy theme.
Scott: It's not outer space.
Scott: It's not Real military guys, it's wizards and goblins and all that shit.
Scott: and there are basically six different races.
Rym: You can choose to play as yeah in the normal default game because one remember this is open source.
Rym: So the game is entirely extensible and people is actually a Wesnoth programming language.
Scott: You can make campaigns and you can pretty much make anything it for Wesnoth in this language.
Rym: There's also a very active community around this game And if you go into the Wesnoth forums There are a lot of people who would love for you to commit to add things to this game to submit comments Critiques to make art for it music anything.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Well, the six races are the rebels who are basically the elves.
Scott: Yes, the elves they have lots of elves on their team and they're very good in the trees.
Scott: when an elf is in a tree He's pretty dangerous and when he's out not in a tree, he's pretty weak.
Scott: They also have ends on the elven team which are when they're in the trees You can't even see them and then they pop out of the trees and they're really big and they do a lot of damage because well They're trees.
Rym: that well, this is another key factor in what I think makes Wesnoth great.
Rym: Now look at the game like advanced wars and it's largely Symmetric in that any two forces that are fighting will be similar.
Rym: like every force has anti-aircraft.
Scott: Yeah, everyone pretty much has the same units in advanced wars.
Scott: Everyone has infantry mech small tank medium tank neo tank mega tank, etc.
Rym: Now there might be variances like this guy's artillery are more powerful or this guy's infantry are weak.
Scott: Yes But the other people still have infantry.
Rym: it's still largely Symmetric that both sides are generally equal or generally similar.
Rym: Wesnoth is very asymmetric.
Rym: each of these factions or races or whatever you want to call them have Completely different sets of units and types of units.
Rym: some are have a lot of artillery not artillery But a lot of cavalry and foot soldiers while other ones have a lot of flying dragons.
Scott: it's a lot more like Starcraft where the Zerg's and What the humans?
Scott: the Terrans?
Scott: I think it was the third one.
Scott: Well, I don't remember but there's three completely different races.
Scott: You know.
Scott: one of them is a few expensive really strong guys And the other ones are really good at the night time and there's lots of undead bat.
Scott: There's like weak flying guys and strong ground guys.
Scott: Another one has lots of guys with ranged attacks, you know, they're all completely different.
Rym: There's basically dragons undead Looks like orcs and trolls humans dwarves elves.
Scott: The dwarves have this one really interesting unit I want to mention called the olf surker and He is really cool because the way he works is when most units in this game Have an attack such as like three five Three five means when they fight they try to hit three times and if they do hit they'll do five damage.
Rym: Right now this harkens this idea all the way back to a bunch of old RTS especially on Sega systems.
Rym: Yes, well, and I keep saying RTS is turn-based game.
Rym: Yes Because TTS just doesn't feel so good.
Scott: No TBS or whatever you wanna but the olf surker guy anyway, he will not stop attacking He just keeps attacking until either he kills the other guy or he died.
Rym: Well what I was gonna say before you continued was that a lot of these turn-based games in Order to prevent the game bogging down into once two units meet they fight until one of them dies.
Rym: They'd often have an idea where when two units fight There's a set number of turns or a set number of actions Like I'll get to attack twice and he'll get to attack twice and then combat stops until the next turn.
Rym: this game does that in terms of any unit can attack X number of times for X number of damage and Counter-attack X number of times for X number of damage.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So yeah now also think instead of Artillery or long-range attacks.
Rym: There's no such thing as that.
Rym: instead It breaks it up in terms of normal melee combat, but based on type.
Rym: So if I attack a unit with Archery or ranged attacks then it can only respond with ranged attacks.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: There's no ranged attacks from multiple hexes away.
Scott: So like if you're three hexes away from me, I can't shoot you with my arrows.
Scott: You always have to be adjacent to whoever you're fighting.
Scott: But the thing is if I use arrows on you then if you don't have a ranged attack You're pretty much I shoot at you and you don't shoot at me at all.
Scott: I don't take any damage You don't even have a chance to damage me.
Scott: But then if you go into melee with me, I can go into melee with you if I have a melee attack.
Scott: So usually when you fight this counter-attacking like hit hit hit hit hit hit hit hit hit it in both directions.
Rym: Yes now also aside from being ranged or whatever.
Rym: There's a lot of different kinds of attacking.
Rym: There's your blade weapon attacks piercing weapon attack.
Rym: It's like slash Pierce bludgeon magic all kinds of fire cold and it comes down to.
Rym: there's a lot of strategic depth here.
Rym: But again because it's asymmetric and you'll only have a subset of the total kinds of units There's not so much information for you to manage and it's all really straightforward.
Rym: Piercing weapons don't work so well against skeletons because the arrows would just go right through them and the Spears just go right through.
Scott: You want to use some bludgeons on those.
Rym: yes, but hammers or magic take him right out.
Rym: Yep, or a spear or something like that does a whole ton of damage against a cavalry unit.
Scott: And this is where the strategy comes in.
Scott: is let's say the other guy has the elves.
Scott: He has the big trees, right?
Scott: So you get some mages who shoot fire to go out and burn the trees down.
Scott: But those mages are pretty weak and if some elves of swords come along, especially in the woods They're just gonna chop up your mages and it's not gonna work.
Scott: So you have to sort of build the correct numbers of units and send them out in a well arranged group and like just the Right hexes so that you know The enemy can't get your guys and you can get your guys that are strong against them in the correct groupings.
Rym: now It's a jumping switch.
Scott: You're gonna lose.
Rym: in addition to that There is a continuous passage of time and it'll oscillate between day and night slowly turn by turn.
Scott: Yeah, like every three or four turns it'll change from day to night and there's a though.
Rym: There's dusk day dawn all those things and some units fight better at night some fight.
Rym: Okay, all the time some fight better during the day.
Scott: Yeah, so generally if you're the undead right at night You're gonna be on the offensive because you're way stronger than your opponent unless your opponent is also the undead in which case it doesn't Matter and during the day you might actually run away.
Scott: if you're the undead because you you're really weak.
Rym: but yet some factions will have neutral guys who aren't affected by day and night and Lawful or and Chaotic chaotic being the ones who are better at night and lawful being the ones who are better during the day.
Scott: Yeah So there's actually you know every few turns sort of the tide of the game has to change.
Scott: you have to mix up your guys Accordingly.
Rym: now along with one other important tactical consideration, which is terrain which basically summed up terrain matters an Incredible amount in this game.
Scott: Yeah, it's like a dwarf in the mountains will fuck you up.
Scott: an elf in the forest is like twice as Powerful.
Rym: Yep a merman in the water.
Scott: You've got no chance But a merman on the land.
Scott: What's he doing there?
Rym: Yeah, he's pretty much just gonna die.
Scott: Yeah, the merman are pretty cool.
Scott: I like merman.
Rym: Yeah, now all of these factors combined make it so where the game has a very dynamic field.
Rym: now Look at advanced wars a deterministic game where in order to reduce analysis paralysis and all the problems inherent in deterministic games They basically had to make the game incredibly simple and make the maps very small and terrain matters But not nearly as much as it does in Wesnoth.
Rym: Wesnoth because the maps tend to be much larger and Wesnoth works even on gigantic maps Depending on how you set it up as long as you have enough players.
Rym: Yeah But the game is such that it's very dynamic and strategies can very much be along the lines of I want to send a scouting party To the south to secure all those villages.
Rym: Well, I muster troops in the north and send them along a line to secure the front along the water.
Rym: I'm then gonna wait overnight in this strong defensive position Because I'm lawful and then once dawn breaks, I'm gonna rush over the water and attack the undead.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of you have to keep changing what you're doing.
Scott: There's no like one straightforward way to win in Wesnoth.
Scott: Yeah You can't build a bunch of not like Starcraft or you can just build your strongest unit as many times as you can and then send them over to the enemy's base and Win, this is not gonna work.
Rym: This is where Wesnoth shines.
Rym: It's one of those rare games but one of those rare any kind of combat games with strategy and tactics where you have to consider the situation.
Rym: and we're.
Rym: Retreating is not only often prudent But retreat reading will often win you a battle.
Rym: an orderly retreat regroup and counter-attack is a very valid and important tactic.
Scott: Yeah, I think the reason that is is because generally if you're attacking with a like a homogenous You know group or a lot of the units are the same type.
Scott: It's gonna be real weak because the other guys is gonna send the type of unit that destroys your guys over there.
Scott: so you generally want to mix it up.
Scott: and The problem is is some units are fast and some are slow.
Scott: So some of them you send out into the battlefield.
Scott: the other ones still need to catch up and then night will come or day Will come.
Scott: and now your guys are weak.
Scott: So you retreat a little bit.
Scott: It allows some guys to catch up.
Scott: it allows some other guys to fall back and not get killed.
Scott: then the day changes again.
Scott: Now you've got this nice little army all grewed up grouped up full of all the different types of units.
Scott: You can move it forward take back the territory.
Scott: You just retreated from and take some more.
Rym: Yep There's also the fact that you can only generate Generally units with your leader.
Rym: every side of it has a leader and you lose if your leader gets killed.
Rym: if the leader is in A keep he can recruit units and you can only generally.
Rym: I mean you can Theoretically move your leader to any keep and recruit units there.
Rym: But a lot of maps will only have two one where you are one where your enemy is.
Scott: Yeah or one for each guy.
Scott: So if there's four players, they'll be four keeps.
Rym: So as a result the further you spread out or the more you were on the Defensive the longer supply chains are the longer it takes units to get to back up your troops or to make a fallback line.
Scott: yeah, the only way to solve that problem is to make a giant army and then move your leader out into the field and bring Him to the enemy's keep.
Scott: win take that keep and use that one.
Rym: But while you're making this giant army Depending on how you're playing because there can't you may or may not have fog of war and shrouds and all sorts of things Where you can or cannot see what's going on?
Rym: Maybe the enemy has a scout up there or you can just see and he watches the army you were building and he just makes at his leisure a Defensive army ready to hold out again As soon as your leader is out of your keep.
Scott: you can't make any more units and he's still making them while you're walking over There.
Rym: yes now also units generally don't heal on their own.
Rym: You either need to send units that can heal other units by being adjacent grab your guys into towns hold them behind the lines and let them rest not moving for a while or Build new units.
Scott: Yeah, or level them up.
Rym: Yes Now this is a game mechanic that I've seen in a few games But the first time I ever saw it was in a game for the Sega Game Gear called crystal warrior.
Scott: Well, the first time I saw it was actually at least in a strategy game was Warcraft 3.
Rym: Well, I guess if you maybe crystal fucking warriors for the game gear.
Rym: Yeah Yeah basically The idea is units have experience points and you get like fire emblem.
Rym: you get experience points every time your unit Survives combat regardless of whether or not he started it.
Rym: You also get a ton of experience points.
Scott: if you take out an enemy unit Yes, now here's where the strategy comes in.
Scott: Let's say there's a unit that is worth a lot of experience points.
Scott: You've got one guy on the cusp of leveling and you've got another guy who's actually really strong against that type of unit Who's not in the cusp of leveling?
Scott: So you have the guy who's really strong attack and he doesn't kill it.
Scott: He brings it real low.
Scott: then your guy in the cusp of leveling deals the final blow and gets all the XP and levels up.
Rym: Now this is important for a number of reasons.
Rym: one Anytime a unit levels up it gets full health back and this is a strategy and crystal warriors.
Rym: back in the day I used all the time where I use a unit and I use a unit and he's on the verge of death or I plan It to where right as he's near death.
Rym: He's gonna level up and get all his life back.
Scott: Another thing I'll do is I'll take a unit and I'll try to get it Experience and then heal it.
Scott: and if it's close to leveling and I'll heal it just enough so that it won't die I'll put it out in a dangerous position Just to tempt the other guy into attacking it and making it level up.
Rym: or if you've got a unit that's close to leveling but it's also close to dead you bring it back behind your lines and Heal it just to make sure it doesn't die and then send it back.
Rym: the game Rewards you for trying to keep units alive and retreating as opposed to just sending units off really nothing to die.
Scott: Also when guys level up they become real dangerous.
Rym: Yes every unit has a leveling tree of some kind where some units just get more powerful.
Rym: some units like say you've got a Cavalry guy.
Rym: he has a sword and he levels up.
Rym: now You can choose if you want a knight who has X hit points and has a lance that does a bunch of charging damage But also has a sword or a lancer who has a crazy lance attack, but no sword attack and he moves further.
Scott: And depending on which one of those you choose that will determine their future Upgrading if they ever get to level three or four or five or any other level.
Rym: Yes So generally you're rewarded by having units that survive a long time.
Rym: so you're rewarded by playing the game like an actual person in battle and Tending to wounded units and having a primary line and a secondary line Yeah all that sort of stuff.
Scott: the other reason that saving units from death is really important is because the way the resources work in.
Scott: There's pretty much one resource gold.
Scott: you start with an amount of gold and you get a base income of a certain amount of gold.
Scott: A turn usually not very much for every unit you have on the board.
Scott: yeah, if you have too many then you have to start paying money to support them.
Scott: sort of an upkeep if you will.
Scott: and There are cities on the board.
Scott: now if you send a guy into a city then you put a little flag in that city that has your color on it.
Scott: that City gives you a certain amount of money each turn and it helps you out with your upkeep action.
Rym: Yep, see units cost upkeep and it's per level.
Rym: So higher level units cost even more upkeep Yep,
Scott: so what you're trying to do is in addition to building units and destroying the other guy You're trying to basically touch all these cities To get flags in them to increase your income to make it so you can build units faster.
Scott: Yep, also cities are highly defensible and heal Yep, so it's sort of like you can't just march in an army straight towards the enemy base.
Scott: You need to go around collecting cities and making sure the other guy doesn't sneak around stealing them back from you because all you need to do to take a city is make a guy move into it and a lot Of the races you can choose like the undead have these flying bats.
Scott: They're real weak relatively cheap.
Scott: They can fly real far and real fast.
Scott: If you don't kill the bats.
Scott: if a guy builds like four bats You can fly them around the map and just take all the cities and like two turns.
Scott: It's pretty crazy.
Rym: Yeah effectively in the end the game no matter how you're playing it Rewards actual tactical and strategic play to the point that you get a dynamic ever-changing Awesome experience just about every time you play.
Scott: It's also simple enough that you don't have to be a war genius to figure it out.
Scott: You might need to be smarter than the person you're playing against to win Often but you're gonna have fun regardless, and there's an easy single-player games that you can play And it's real easy to set this game up for all sorts of multiplayer.
Rym: Yes, now let's talk about the different modes of play a bit because the game comes with a bunch of single-player straight-up story-based Campaigns that are mostly awesome.
Rym: I highly recommend if you're picking this game up for the first time that you tried the South Guard and pick whatever Difficulty level you deem appropriate to your level of intelligence.
Scott: There's also a one really really easy campaign.
Scott: I don't know the name of it But basically it's like four missions and you just chase an evil wizard around to like four different maps.
Scott: But it's real fun because it's so easy.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Now the single-player Regardless of anything else is fun and you can just play it like a straight-up game.
Rym: If I had bought this game and it had these campaigns in it I probably would have felt okay with it because they're.
Rym: the stories are pretty good The scenarios are interesting the some of them are very interesting and the game is so extensible that there's one in one campaign Where it even tells you you can't win.
Rym: All you were doing is holding the line.
Rym: You have a bunch of units and your goal is to hold off the undead scourge as long as you can Dying to the last ban and depending on how long you hold out more troops or less troops are mustered at the actual castle Where you make your real last stand.
Scott: a lot of fun stuff that shows you how powerful the Wesnoth language is and that you can Make a campaign like that, you know that it even allows for that sort of craziness that go on.
Scott: but yeah There's in addition to all those cool single-player campaigns.
Scott: You can just play a multiplayer game against AI.
Scott: Yeah, and the AI in this game is not the best AI in the world, but it's pretty smart.
Scott: It'll get can beat you.
Scott: Yeah I spent like.
Scott: we tried.
Scott: we thought oh the AI is dumb and we played against it with like by giving it more resources than We had.
Scott: cuz like we're smarter than the AI will give it more resources and it just kicked our asses.
Scott: So we played it with even resources and it was a semi even game.
Scott: We still won but it was just pretty even.
Rym: yeah, I mean compared to Advance Wars AI This game is a thousand times better AI.
Scott: I think it's part of the goal of the Wesnoth project actually is to have AI.
Scott: that's kind of smart And they have succeeded in doing that.
Rym: now in terms of multiplayer.
Rym: You can play on official Wesnoth servers.
Rym: You can run your own server.
Rym: You can run your client and have other people connect to your client.
Scott: Yeah, it pretty much allows for every sort of multiplayer connection.
Rym: You can do hot seat where everyone just shares one PC and it dings when it's your turn.
Scott: Yeah, it lets you do just about everything, you know, you can customize pick whatever map make your own maps Make whatever rules you want random a random apps.
Scott: You could decide random races or pick your races or you know, one guy starts with this much gold.
Scott: No, the guy doesn't start with any gold.
Scott: You can also go on two on one three on one seven on one.
Rym: you can go online and download all sorts of campaign scenarios races rules extensions everything you can make every everything you want.
Scott: also
Rym: I mean in some if you call yourself a PC gamer and you have not played the battle for Wesnoth Not only are you missing out on one of the best PC games out there right now But you're missing out on one of the best turn-based strategy games ever
Scott: and one of the only good free open source games Cuz.
Rym: while open source software is awesome open source games are perhaps the worst things ever.
Scott: most of them are anyway.
Rym: We spent a whole day.
Rym: We're gonna do a show on this later.
Rym: We spent a day looking for open source games that were good.
Rym: me Scott and Alex sat here Just each one of us picking games and trying to play them and the fact that some of these games None of us was able to make them work let alone play them or enjoy them.
Scott: I got some of them to play but they were just bad.
Scott: Yeah unplayable I mean like you I could get them to run and function but some we couldn't get to function Some we couldn't get to function or some there was only a server and we couldn't find the client.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, so anyone out there knows any open source games besides Wesnoth that are good and worth playing?
Scott: Let us know.
Scott: I mean, I know a few of them.
Scott: There's like is a few.
Scott: our FPS is out there that are pretty good, but it's not much else.
Rym: I highly recommend this game.
Rym: if you have trouble with it Try playing one of the easy scenarios or maybe read some of the instructions So you'll learn how to actually play.
Rym: there are instructions in the game.
Scott: Yeah, if you do what's the one campaign that's supposed to be the main campaign?
Rym: why that would be heir to the throne?
Scott: Yes So if you've never played this game before you probably want to play at least the first half of the heir to the throne campaign because that's the original one that tells you how to play in the early missions and It takes you know, it gives you progressively more and more stuff, you know It's like oh here starting this easy Mission where you just have to walk to the other end of the map.
Rym: see though at the same time that campaign later on Gets a little bit arbitrary and annoying.
Scott: it is I didn't like it's not the best campaign I will agree, but if you've never played it is the learning camp.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: However, the South Guard especially if you set it to one of the easier difficulties is also an excellent learning campaign because it starts you with just peasants and then you get other units from there and The South Guard will teach you how to play the game if you are smart enough to take a cue from the game and look At what's going
Scott: on?
Scott: Yeah, the tale of two brothers is the incredibly short and easy campaign.
Scott: I talked about before.
Rym: Yes Play this game.
Rym: I almost guarantee if you like turn-based strategy games at all.
Rym: You'll like Wesnoth.
Rym: Yeah, you're not a human being and you like shitty games.
Scott: If you like fantasy war games, you'll also like this.
Scott: probably.
Rym: Yeah, now granted.
Rym: It doesn't have to be fantasy.
Rym: The system is set up to be that way.
Rym: you could reskin this game and redo it to make it spaceships fighting.
Scott: if you want It you could make it freakin blobs of goo versus.
Rym: well, it is in fact blobs of goo in one of the campaigns.
Rym: It's true I haven't played through much of that one yet.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Also if you go to the Wikipedia I'll warn you some of the campaigns have better art than other ones.
Rym: That's just through the fact that it's open source.
Rym: So if you're a good artist out there if you want to make a little bit of a name for yourself You don't have one yet.
Rym: submit art to Wesnoth.
Rym: if you're good, they'll take it and they'll put it in the game.
Scott: Yeah, you should see the art and some of the older versions of Wesnoth.
Scott: Oh god, basically It's like the game had art, you know had icons for all the units and everything and then they slowly go through like, you know One at a time making things better and then they just make things better in random places.
Scott: one You know.
Scott: It's the nature of an open-source game and the game is constantly coming out with new versions.
Scott: One thing that is annoying is if you don't have the same exact version as all your friends You can't play against each other because like right now I've got feisty fawn.
Scott: So my version of Wesnoth is like super new and everyone else is still running edgy EFT.
Rym: Yeah Only ever a problem.
Scott: if you decide to run beta versions of Linux operating system Well, you have to because they all the ones don't work on your laptop as well.
Rym: Yeah, Scott because of you We couldn't play some Wesnoth.
Scott: What you gonna do?
Scott: It's not my fault using the old busted.
Scott: Well, you know what?
Scott: We did.
Rym: we just played Wesnoth without you.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: I have more important things to do like laundry, but I say this because on the Wikipedia page I might go edit this but I'll wait so you can all see it.
Rym: There is a picture of a lich and I gotta say it's one of the silliest looking liches I've ever seen.
Scott: Yeah, another thing was not.
Scott: actually I don't know who made the music, but it's not bad.
Rym: It's also gotten a lot better recently.
Scott: Yeah, the music has been changed and is better.
Scott: now It's still.
Scott: it's not the kind of music that you'll be like dancing to and it's not super awesome like the civilization music But it's getting there.
Scott: It's definitely to the point where it's not annoying and you won't just turn it off in frustration.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.