Scott: It's Wednesday February 7th.
Scott: I'm Scott and I'm Rym and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We review shoujo kakumei utenna.
Rym: Let's do this All right, so today odd Something kind of interesting after me.
Rym: I was walking into a Starbucks on my way home from work.
Rym: I wanted a Starbucks.
Rym: I wanted a cookie and I wanted some espresso.
Scott: There's a Starbucks doesn't have good cookies.
Scott: They're all weird crazy cookies.
Rym: I got a standard cookie.
Rym: It was pretty good.
Rym: Yeah, but the thing is for various reasons.
Rym: I have the Russian national anthem stuck in my head, you know And I just happened to be whistling it as I walked in and there was this guy you know kind of obviously college-age stand in there outside the coffee shop like looking through a book and He gets his look on his face and he looks up at me as I'm walking by and he says That's a Russian national anthem.
Rym: and I said, hey, yep, and I went in and got my coffee and my cookie And then I went on my way.
Scott: It's a good thing.
Scott: You don't know the the Israeli national anthem?
Scott: It's much catchier and it gets a lot more attention if anyone recognizes great granted.
Rym: the other day I was walking into one of these hospitals and I was also humming the Russian national anthem.
Scott: What the hell's wrong with you?
Rym: It's been stuck in my head.
Scott: You can't even read cerulex.
Rym: No, I can you know what I can?
Rym: it's just I read it wrong.
Scott: Yeah, right you got me doing this all pockner.
Scott: now you suck.
Rym: yeah pockner is an in-joke from high school ECCP.
Rym: Okay, yeah, but I'm humming it and I'm walking by all these old people waiting at a hospital slash nursing home And one of them looks up at me.
Rym: now I don't know I can't know ever if this guy knew it.
Rym: if I just you know Maybe he's just an old man in a hospital, you know, it hurts.
Scott: when he peed He saw a young punk kid with long hair and he said girl or maybe he was just going girl.
Rym: cuz it hurts when he Pees, I don't know who knows.
Rym: but the thing is I'm humming the Russian national anthem.
Rym: He looks up and I would swear that the look he was giving me was damn this country going to hell.
Rym: Communists wandering around.
Scott: I think it's safe to assume that you know.
Scott: But the other question is, you know, if he was an old man, even if he was all crotchety and anti commie He still has to be smart if he recognizes the Russian national anthem.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah plus I mean back then Communism take it or leave it.
Rym: the Soviet Union wasn't the best place to live.
Rym: It's not.
Scott: It doesn't mean the national anthems are no good.
Rym: no, actually I really like their night.
Rym: in fact, I like all Old-school Soviet Russian music a lot.
Scott: It's always a problem.
Scott: You know when something is like a song, you know has maybe let's say someone made a really racist song But it was such a good song.
Scott: like you like listening to it cuz it sounds good There's good music there, but it's also horribly racist.
Scott: You know, if you don't agree with it somehow listening to the song can cause you trouble.
Rym: That's come up with a lot of reggae music.
Rym: Well, maybe not a lot but more than you'd expect where if you actually listen to the lyrics, they're really kind of homophobic and anti-gay Really?
Rym: Yeah, it's kind of weird.
Rym: Maybe it's just a few of the songs I listened to but it was kind of weird.
Scott: No woman no cry, I don't think.
Rym: Anyway I don't want to talk about this cuz I don't want to give these people any I don't know press But at the same time I got to talk about how dumb this is.
Rym: So the finalists have been announced for those BS anime awards.
Rym: Oh, yeah the American anime Awards Which I cannot say for sure and this is strictly my opinion.
Rym: So I can't be sued for any sort of slander.
Rym: But it is my belief that the anime American anime Awards are nothing more than a scam - they're just a crack to either make some money or get enough clout to trick people into giving them money.
Scott: I think the only reason the anime Awards exist is because one some guy thinks he's all smart and he says You know what?
Scott: Anime is all popular here now, and there isn't an award ceremony for it.
Scott: We should make one and another guy says hey, you know what this New York Comic Con is gonna be big.
Scott: It's gets way out of control.
Scott: I mean they already sold out the Saturday You know and anime has got to get a bigger presence to show that we're bigger than those stupid superhero comics.
Scott: So we're gonna have our award ceremony at the same time Right down the road in a hotel.
Rym: I just.
Rym: it's got to be a scam and I'm not exactly sure how they plan to make money off of it.
Rym: But it's just.
Rym: it's such crap.
Scott: It's just a big press event where they push anime by having awards.
Scott: You know.
Scott: that way all the companies can put little label on their DVD case that says what an American anime award.
Rym: OMG Yeah, speaking of that.
Rym: I mean, I'm not gonna read this list of the things that got nominated by this stuff But one they've got categories like best actor best actress Best actor in a comedy best cash.
Rym: now, that's the one that really bothers me because best actress or actor whatever You know good voice actor considering that a lot of voice actors are on board with this thing.
Rym: I can understand that Best cast.
Rym: now, does that mean best voice acting cast?
Rym: or does that mean best character cast?
Scott: I Have no idea.
Rym: because if it's and if it's if it's the former I don't know.
Rym: and even then all the anime they pick I mean what?
Rym: FLCL fma ghost in the shell standalone complex second gig in a yasha and Naruto.
Scott: I think the major problem with these awards is twofold.
Scott: number one It's the categories are ill-defined and the requirements for what's nominated or ill-defined and it's sort of fast and loose Like they don't even care.
Scott: and the second problem is it's an entirely fan voting.
Scott: now I have no problem if you have won the category of fan favorite or something like that.
Scott: But to have.
Scott: I mean most award ceremonies, you know, I don't even respect the Oscars Which are probably the premiere award ceremony on the planet, but if you're gonna get if you're gonna approach Respectable levels you got to have some method that it you know, at least has criteria.
Scott: We're X, you know experts in the field in quotes, you know Yeah vote by some ballot or something.
Scott: You need to have some sort of system that at least someone can look at it and go, huh?
Scott: There's some credibility here and not just random picks by fans that have no meaning.
Rym: they had a poorly put together Woefully inaccurate and broken online voting thing.
Scott: Yeah the thing that really bothers me is just how some of this stuff turned out because It seems like anything goes in this no matter what year it came out as long as he came out in America.
Scott: Right and they have a category best manga.
Scott: now Don't even get me started on why there's a vote for best manga in the anime Awards.
Scott: That's like having a vote for like best TV show at the Oscars.
Rym: more important beyond all that I gotta read the list of what's nominated for best manga and I think it will be painfully obvious to everyone out there one What's missing from this.
Rym: and well there bleach death note fruits basket Naruto and here's the one that really burns me.
Rym: neon Genesis Evangelion.
Rym: Oh if it stopped right there, I would have said alright because that's actually a really good month.
Rym: Okay, um colon angelic days.
Scott: Alright now Considering there's no time limit on this and it's the American Anime Awards.
Rym: So Anime, I have a nomination.
Scott: What's your nominee?
Rym: I'd like to nominate a Hinata re.
Rym: yeah I was on with Tezuka G.
Scott: I don't know that's tough.
Scott: I mean, uh Maybe we should nominate.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: maybe ghost in the shell.
Scott: Yeah, how about Akira?
Rym: Ah, Buddha?
Rym: Oh gee, I don't know almost everything Tezuka did.
Scott: I mean, there's no time limit on these things, right?
Scott: I mean these things came out in very different years.
Scott: They've got stuff on this list like a Rhonda one-half OVA all the way up to like Helsing ultimate Oh, which is even out yet.
Rym: Alright best anime feature Akira.
Rym: Alright, I'll respect that Inuyasha movie for Pokemon movie 8 what the hell.
Rym: the Fullmetal Alchemist movie and advent children.
Scott: Yeah If you're gonna do best anime feature, I could respect the awards I could respect Akira being on the list But if you're not gonna have I don't know Any Miyazaki's on the list?
Scott: You're not having.
Scott: I don't know what else could go on there.
Rym: I don't know everything good ever.
Rym: I mean look at best comedy talk about.
Rym: they've got.
Rym: oh my god is TV Which is a very new show.
Rym: flcl Koto chop surprised the internet even knows what that is anymore.
Rym: run my head now.
Rym: Rama was the big thing a long time ago, but I Rarely run into anime fans who have even they even know what Rama is these days and The Tenchi Muyo OAV which wallet is hilarious again.
Rym: No one watches Tenchi anymore.
Rym: How did this get voted up?
Scott: I don't I have no idea.
Scott: I think that this award is just a bunch of crack of shit.
Scott: No one cares about it.
Scott: And that's that's all it's gonna be.
Rym: so we're never gonna talk about this again Unless I don't know.
Rym: maybe we'll talk about how stupid it is after they have the awards.
Scott: All that you should know is that if anyone ever tries to brag about winning the American Anime Award Or if they're proud of winning an American Anime Award, you should look on them with disdain.
Scott: disdain That's the word that should be used.
Rym: alright, so what do you got for me?
Scott: Well, you know when you watch movies from Japan, they usually have logos at the beginning of all the companies that made them.
Scott: Well, I guess that's true in America, too Yeah, and you seem to notice the same logos recurring like.
Scott: you'll notice touchstone Which is actually Disney in disguise or new line or Miramax or Universal.
Rym: my favorite one was always the Easter Island guys.
Scott: Oh, yeah, so in Japan when you watch certain things, you notice emotion, which is the Easter Island guys Which I think is actually a secret codename for just Bandai movies.
Scott: that I'm not sure.
Scott: and you'll also notice things like Toho Which is usually before a Godzilla movie.
Scott: and another one you'll notice is the one with the little Phoenix bird.
Scott: This is katakawa.
Scott: Well katakawa happens to be a very smart company.
Scott: very smart Because what they are going to do is they are going to sell sell.
Scott: so I must assume DRM is gonna happen.
Scott: But they're going to sell some of their movies about 200 of their movies in the United States on Bit torrent, so I imagine there's going to be some sort of system where you go to their website And you pay the money and then they give you a torrent file and then you run the torrent file and you Get the movie in some sort of DRM format, and then you watch it.
Scott: That's the only way this could possibly work, so That's pretty smart of them.
Scott: actually.
Rym: yeah, I mean it's as if a dozen Local American anime companies went oh snap and were suddenly silence.
Scott: Well.
Scott: It's mostly not gonna be anime.
Scott: I mean they're bringing over the ring the live-action one.
Scott: So Expect you know a lot of these live-action Japanese movies are probably gonna be big-time ones you've seen before But in a list of 200 this bound to be some good stuff We've never seen.
Scott: and if it wasn't DRM Or if it was DRM didn't played in Linux even I might be willing to actually pay Maybe.
Rym: yeah, I mean a lot of these movies.
Rym: We really like to say I mean one of the primary things I do at anime cons now is watch live-action Asian cinema.
Scott: Oh, that's the best part because you go to the anime rooms, and it's all stuff.
Scott: You've seen stuff.
Scott: You know what it is stuff.
Scott: That's coming out soon.
Scott: You don't care about.
Scott: you're not wasting your time in an anime con seeing it because you could see it later on DVD.
Scott: If it's live-action stuff you at a convention usually It's not gonna be easy to get those DVDs in the United States with subtitles.
Scott: So the ability to watch them there is special so it's worth your time at a convention to go to that room Especially since a lot of times at least maybe it's just because of the kinds of live-action movies We like.
Rym: they're also the kinds of things that are very much enhanced by having a lot of like-minded people in the room with you.
Scott: Yep, well, it's actually Kadokawa like has a US like subsidiary or something that's actually doing all the work And it's gonna put the subtitles and all that jazz on there.
Rym: Well.
Rym: I guess we'll see how this goes.
Rym: I mean this could usher in a new era.
Scott: it could and if I see good stuff on there I'm like.
Scott: I don't know if I'd buy it if it's DRM But I would definitely write them an email like if you weren't DRM I totally would give you like a hundred dollars.
Scott: you get all those movies.
Rym: OMG Things of the day now.
Rym: as you are all aware I threw down with a theme week my own theme week on my things the day this week And I have to continue it now.
Rym: the theme was Hitler.
Rym: it was born to be alive And I've already had two born to be alive one of which had Hitler.
Rym: so to make up for that second born to be alive I gotta have another Hitler in here.
Rym: Thus this is someone took a movie about Hitler and Replaced the subtitles with something very funny about Hitler trying to get a new car.
Scott: I said the original movie about Hitler was like a serious historical movie, right?
Scott: I'd imagine so I don't like a historical drama where it's not exactly what was real, but it was you know An interpretation of what actually happened in a dramatic cinematic fashion something like that.
Rym: see I'm not really sure it I didn't look into it, but the fact remains that Hitler trying to get a new car is actually pretty funny Especially especially cuz it's so true everything he says about cars.
Rym: Yeah, that is kind of sad that part, but it's it's just interesting to watch Hitler.
Rym: You know the horrible dictator, and he just wants a new car.
Scott: well actually a really good Hitler actor Not the actual Hitler.
Rym: well.
Rym: Yeah, I mean there was that rare video of the actual Hitler with his rice doubt civic, but All right, so what do you got?
Scott: well, I'm sure everyone is aware of the sport of competitive eating Aka food fighting.
Rym: I'm aware of it in the sense that some Japanese guy always wins.
Scott: Yeah, there's that guy.
Scott: What's his name?
Scott: Kobayashi, he's like the grand famous master of eating lots of food.
Rym: for some reason all I think is Kaiser.
Scott: So say yeah, well, there's this whole Article on wired about this girl Who sort of I don't know she's like the hot stuff in the food eating these days named Natsuko, Sony.
Scott: She's 21 years old five feet four inches, and she weighs 95 pounds.
Scott: Get this ready.
Scott: she can guess how many pieces of sushi she can eat in 30 minutes.
Rym: all right in 30 minutes I could eat about a little over 30 pieces of sushi.
Rym: So maybe for your stomach like get full embargo it would be full where I wouldn't feel so good.
Rym: But I think I could eat 30 pieces of sushi in 30 minutes.
Scott: She can eat a hundred and eighty three pieces of sushi ah And she can eat 20 pounds of food in one sitting.
Scott: So so part of this wired article.
Scott: this is a video the Kobayashi guy eating dumplings and stuff here And there's some others.
Scott: There's some other videos and a lot of text in the article But my thing of the day is the video at the top which shows a generic Japanese daytime variety TV show and this chick who's actually kind of cute and She starts off the show by weighing herself, and it's like 43 kilograms.
Rym: I thought you're gonna say pounds, and I was picturing this tiny little stick of a.
Scott: no She's not that tiny, but she's pretty small.
Scott: She's a little Japanese person right?
Scott: she weighs 95 pounds and They have this giant bowl of ramen bigger than like all of us could eat this bowl of ramen Collectively, and it would be a good meal.
Scott: It's like kind of like getting a giant sub you know yeah, and She eats.
Scott: She just keeps eating it and like all these other people on the show cuz you know how these shows go.
Scott: you've watched enough of them on YouTube You know they're eating their normal food and laughing it up and telling jokes and she's saying stuff and I can't tell what they're saying cuz I don't know the language, but they're saying funny stuff.
Scott: and She just keeps eating keeps eating keep playing keep playing and this bowl Like disappears over time and at the end.
Scott: She weighs herself again, and it's 50 kilos.
Scott: She had she put seven kilos of food in her stomach, and she even says like Nana kilo.
Rym: Wow Yeah, I don't know how I feel about this sport.
Rym: I can't imagine.
Rym: That's good for you.
Scott: I can't imagine.
Scott: It's good for you either.
Rym: I mean we just ate at the cafe Maya, and I ate more food than I should have.
Rym: there was a piece of fried banana with cheesecake and ice cream a little tiny piece sitting on the plate and I couldn't bring myself to eat it, and I still feel kind of bloated my stomach sticking out like ah Imagine eating this thing had to be.
Scott: I don't know how many bowls of ramen could have fit in this giant bowl.
Rym: You know what you can't eat ten bowls of ramen.
Scott: I guess seven kilos of ramen.
Rym: God that's a lot of Robin right, so let's get out into something more erudite.
Rym: So like we said we're gonna review shoujo kakumei utena which is one of our favorite anime ever.
Rym: It's in.
Rym: it's in the top list.
Scott: It's I like it a lot, and it's like rims.
Rym: super favorite Yeah, like pretty much this and irresponsible captain Tyler Just do it for me, but in particular utena is probably in my top three anime ever and Scott isn't at least your top ten I guess.
Scott: yeah, probably it's really good.
Rym: Yeah now surprisingly a lot of people don't know a lot about it or haven't seen it partly because it's 39 episodes long and partly because It doesn't look like the kind of show it actually is.
Scott: it's a very deceptive show I mean when you first look at imagery from the show you think of like a Really froofy kind of like.
Scott: you might think it's gonna be like or on high school Or you might think it's gonna be like rare, so you might think it's gonna be like Rosa Versailles.
Scott: Yeah, like that.
Scott: now part of it's not.
Rym: I mean it actually is stylistically.
Rym: it draws a lot from things like Rosa Versailles If you ever watch brother dear brother Which you shouldn't.
Rym: These style like the way the world works and the way people talk to each other kind of reminds me of it.
Rym: It's not actually like any of those shows and I Guess I mean honestly even me.
Rym: I probably wouldn't have given the show a second look.
Rym: I mean I had seen like one episode of it the first episode.
Rym: I thought all right the show's kind of whatever.
Rym: I don't understand it.
Rym: It looks like some shoujo crap.
Rym: But of all things Dwayne the stoner Caused me to watch the rest of the show.
Scott: To give you an idea of how the show is weird right.
Scott: let me read for you the genres Listed on the anime news network encyclopedia ready Drama okay show Joe all right.
Scott: Yeah Fantasy all right they got swords and stuff.
Scott: Psychological huh that doesn't fit does it.
Rym: I can only fit.
Rym: I mean what.
Rym: I would put that on perfect blue.
Scott: Yeah, maybe millennium actress, but perfect blue isn't fantasy or show Joe I.
Rym: Maybe it's some sickos fantasy, but it's not fantasy like candidates fantasy, but yeah I mean you look at utenna without knowing anything about it, and you see pretty boys cute girls Princesses swords high school.
Rym: you think all right?
Rym: It's all pink and pastel.
Rym: in fact the show is real pink and real pastel, and you think man.
Scott: This is gonna be bad.
Rym: So real bad for one.
Rym: They're all the people who are older and wiser than me in the ways of anime would talk about utenna in these reverent terms like oh ten of blah blah blah and they'd make references to it fairly often.
Rym: and Then one day I was visiting stoner Dwayne with a friend of mine Ken and among other things They were watching a bunch of utenna so we watched two episodes with them from what I now know is the middle of the black rose saga and it was amazing and Scary and weird and dark.
Scott: imagine watching card captor Sakura and having it be Actually scary and fucked up, but it looks like card captor Sakura.
Rym: I mean I realize now that this show is probably not what I think it is.
Rym: and then I saw this anime music video To tenna though this much the one I've listed to the cars one.
Scott: Oh not the oh baby, baby.
Rym: Yeah that one set that's got cars, okay, it's mostly from the car saga I guess.
Rym: but yeah the hit me baby one more time.
Rym: anime music video Which is also one of my favorite AMVs ever?
Rym: But while that AMV is funny and hilarious it also shows scenes from the show that are really kind of you wonder What's actually going on in the show because it looks actually really serious and really well put together.
Rym: But I guess before we go any further Utenna was directed by kunihiko Ikuhara.
Rym: Oh he this is oh Yeah warning lights.
Rym: now the thing is he is one of the few anime directors I knew about by name before I listened to anime world order.
Rym: I actually and about.
Scott: I actually knew about this guy to remember this name Ikuhara Ikuhara.
Scott: now hear the name Ikuhara in relation to anime which isn't gonna happen too often, but if you hear this name Watch out now you might think wait a minute.
Rym: I can't think of anything you kuhara's done and the answer is he didn't do much Because he's scary.
Rym: the thing is scary does not preclude.
Rym: Awesome this guy for what it's worth for whatever weird issues.
Rym: He may have Created a great freaking show and there's no way the show would have been even though even though it might not all be Because of him it definitely would have would not have happened without him at worst.
Rym: He is like George Lucas in terms of he accidentally made something awesome exactly cuz he.
Scott: that's a great analogy there.
Rym: Basically he worked on Sailor Moon, and you know he did a good job on it.
Rym: He had a lot to do with it, but Sailor Moon is what it is.
Rym: Yeah, it's no It's Anna and according to the story He was bored with Sailor Moon because he while he you know he had control of all various aspects of the show.
Rym: He didn't have really any artistic control, and they wouldn't let him do.
Rym: quote interesting things unquote that he wanted to do with the series that that that warning lights, so Eventually he went to form this group called B. Papa's with among other people the the famous Chiyo Saito Mm-hmm.
Rym: now Chiyo Saito tends to be very cute and show Joey and he kuhara tends to be very creepy and when you combine the You get Utena.
Scott: yeah if you read the original Utena manga Which is by Chiho Saito and no one else.
Scott: it's a cute show Joey thing.
Scott: there really isn't this scary stuff so much?
Rym: Yeah, no before we go any further.
Rym: I'm saying that a lot.
Rym: I mean, it's really hard to talk about this show, but without spoiling or just telling you the whole story.
Rym: I know warning out.
Rym: We're not gonna spoil the show at all.
Rym: We're being very careful about he's not in this episode.
Rym: Yeah, we're gonna do a spoiler show way down the road or a spoiler week or whatever we need to do.
Rym: But we're not talking about the movie.
Rym: Don't even watch the movie.
Rym: Don't even look at the DVD cover of the movie.
Scott: We're only talking about the TV show.
Scott: There's only two words.
Scott: You need to know about the movie.
Scott: You know what those words are in.
Rym: I know what those words are.
Scott: you tell me the first word.
Scott: I'll tell you the second word naked cars.
Rym: We're not fucking kidding.
Scott: if you watch the Utena movie the only reason you should watch that movie is to find out what we Mean when we say naked cars, and you know what.
Scott: if you end up doing that you're gonna Be sorry you tend.
Scott: a movie is bad.
Scott: We're not talking about it.
Scott: Well, I guess we'll price will refer to it I'll say one tenement is bad only the TV show is good.
Rym: the Utena movie as bad as it is is however Beautiful.
Rym: it is a moving art book much like shamanic princess was a moving art book with almost nothing to it.
Scott: Yeah and if you want to understand how creepy Ikuhara is the Utena movie is what happens when you let Ikuhara have pretty much complete control over all the artistic everything.
Rym: and Yeah, naked car naked car and razor blade incest.
Scott: that's exactly right.
Scott: That is why the Utena TV show is much better because it is Ikuhara But he is heavily restrained But not restrained so much that he does not have any influence at all.
Scott: and hence the Utena TV show.
Scott: Which is the awesome?
Rym: now Utena is about a lot of things.
Rym: I mean if you ask someone who has seen all of Utena what it's about they can't tell you without spoiling everything.
Rym: I mean they can't give you a straight answer, and it's not like the matrix We're like once you know like oh, it's about that as opposed to that.
Rym: Oh, okay It's actually Complicated to the point that there is no simple answer as to what Utena is about.
Rym: You really can't say in any small number of words what the show is about.
Rym: all we can really tell you is what the show Appears to be about.
Rym: it is basically the story of a girl whose parents are dead And she's very sad.
Scott: and she's a young girl And she's at some high school, and it's a high school with dorms and everyone lives there.
Scott: Well,
Rym: then yeah but but way before that when she was a young girl her parents were killed and she said and she has no reason to Live and a prince appears a straight You know fairy book fairy tale Prince appears, and he kisses the tears out of her eyes and tells her blah Something childish about you know being a prince and growing up, and you know the world is good.
Rym: It's okay that kind of thing and She decides that when she grows up.
Rym: She wants to be a prince.
Rym: She doesn't want to be a princess.
Rym: She doesn't want to be saved by anyone like she just was by this prince.
Rym: She wants to be a prince herself, and that's kind of a strange thing for a girl to want to be.
Scott: yeah It's kind of freaky.
Rym: Yeah, that's what the show is about.
Rym: they tell you this a bunch of times to let you get going.
Scott: We're at the beginning of like the first bunch of episodes.
Scott: They show you this little like prologue.
Scott: You know story of the fairy tale of.
Scott: you know the girl who wants to grow up to be a prince and all that.
Rym: But that's all in the past where the show really picks up.
Rym: is that utana the main character?
Rym: She is going to this high school this prestigious school.
Rym: It's a high school and a middle school stuck together, and it's a boarding school.
Rym: It's Weird that's the first way to put it.
Rym: It's a weird anime crazy architecture pretty people walking everywhere Weird angles and giant classrooms and fancy fancy fancy fancy.
Scott: No classes though think or on but less ornate, but still crazy.
Rym: Yeah And you know she's attending here and at one point she sees a woman a girl who goes to the school Arguing with a male student, and you know she comments like ah some sort of lovers quarrel, ha ha ha.
Rym: And then she sees the guy just haul back and smack the girl And that crack a like the pimp hand.
Rym: no, I'm not talking just like a slab.
Rym: This is the open palm equivalent of a punch to the face.
Scott: Yeah Like she falls down And it's just laying am?
Rym: that pimp hand was double-sized and she's about to react.
Rym: and then she sees that you know Oh this other guy stopped it.
Rym: this other guy intervened like okay.
Rym: It's cool Fast forward a little bit and now she's got her friend walk about.
Rym: her really really good friend who goes to the school with her walk Has Feelings for one of the members of the student council sayonji who has the green haired guy.
Rym: That's all you need to know.
Rym: you'll recognize him.
Scott: yet You can tell people apart in the show by hair.
Scott: Utena has pink hair welcome eyes brown hair.
Scott: sayonji has green hair toga I'm a man red hair.
Rym: He's the awesome jury has orange hair.
Rym: Miki has blue hair.
Scott: Everyone else sister has purple hair.
Scott: yep Not gonna tell you any of the care.
Rym: We can't tell you any other characters But anyway, so then her friend walk about his feelings for sayonji.
Rym: now sayonji is the guy who's just beating up his girlfriend So she writes him a love note and she's excited about it.
Rym: one thing leads to another and sayonji just takes this love note and Instead of responding to it or throwing away or whatever.
Rym: He just pays it to the school bulletin board and this causes is Embarrassment concern and crying in walk about.
Rym: this is a pretty horrible thing.
Scott: You can see this whole beginning of the show here is all sort of a generic shoujo Romance high school kind of plot.
Scott: There's nothing weird going on.
Scott: There's no crazy psychological or fantasy stuff.
Rym: and while there's this prince thing the way it's presented it feels more like a Tale or a story and not like something that actually happened to her.
Rym: yep, so you know whatever if this was the show It's just some generic show about kids in school.
Scott: Yeah, but at this point it's not even as good as What's it called.
Scott: boys over flowers?
Rym: What's a honey or a dango?
Scott: Yeah, it's not even that good.
Rym: yet now Here's where the show takes the first turn the turn where you realize that the show is not all it appears to be.
Rym: So she goes and confronts the sayonji guy straight up.
Rym: He's the captain of the kendo club.
Rym: She takes a kendo sword and challenges him to a duel Because she's pissed at him and he doesn't seem to care about what he did to this poor girl.
Rym: He says oh Can't fight me.
Rym: I'm the captain of the kendo team, but then he notices the ring that she's wearing.
Rym: you see She wears this ring that has the pretty much the logo of the show that rose seal.
Rym: you'll see this everywhere Constantly.
Scott: they just shove it in your face like they'll just have a scene.
Scott: It's not even animated It's a still frame and they pan across the still frame and they'll have this rose like spinning on the screen in random places And it's all.
Scott: you can't miss it.
Rym: it is ever-present.
Rym: hmm, and She had this ring.
Rym: now supposedly she got it from this Prince way back when the other thing happened.
Rym: But sayonji he sees it and he shows that he has the same ring and he says oh You're one of the duelists meet me in the dueling arena in the forest behind the school at tonight And she's like what the fuck?
Scott: All right.
Rym: I'm not allowed to go back there.
Rym: Okay, and she shows up and Alright, she climbs this stairwell after the ring opens the door and you start getting the twinges of maybe this is a fantasy.
Rym: and then an interesting song plays.
Scott: Oh Oh Oh It's one of my favorite songs ever.
Scott: yeah that song Really in the stock footage rolls.
Scott: Don't forget.
Scott: Yeah when she's walking up the stairs Oh that little animation of her walking up the stairs is awesome.
Rym: Yeah, that look at determination on her face.
Rym: But yeah, she's why she walks up this giant staircase that has no right to exist by the laws of physics.
Rym: Yep, she gets to the top and it's hard to describe.
Rym: you'll just have to find a picture of it.
Rym: There is basically a dueling arena in the sky on this giant pillar and there's a giant castle Hanging from the ceiling hanging not from the ceiling from the sky.
Rym: it is just floating in the sky upside down.
Scott: the top of the castle is pointing down Onto your head like if the castle fell you would die because it's above.
Scott: it's fucked up really fucked up.
Scott: It shouldn't be but it's there.
Rym: So you watch the show to that point and now you realize the show is probably not about what I thought it was about.
Rym: To not go into what happens that I mean.
Scott: at the front one part You're like oh that poor girl got slapped and oh our friends feelings are hurt.
Scott: I'll defend my friends feelings.
Scott: and then you go.
Scott: what the fuck is there?
Scott: a castle hanging from the sky two different shows.
Rym: So this isn't really a spoiler because you learn all this right away.
Scott: This is all in episode one.
Rym: the actual plot of utenna which you learn at this point Is that in the school?
Rym: There are people who wear these rose seals.
Rym: They are drawn to the school.
Rym: They all end up at this school.
Rym: wearing the rose seal ring means that you're a duelist.
Rym: at the school There is the Rose bride and currently it is anti-hymemia.
Rym: Whoever has currently won the duel wins.
Rym: the Rose bride has control over her.
Rym: That might sound weird, but that's exactly what's going on And that's all they tell you.
Scott: if you like you want to know the details like what does control mean?
Scott: blah blah blah.
Scott: It's all answered in the show kind of not really.
Rym: yeah, well We really can't go into more but suffice to say this is kind of a weird thing.
Rym: you know.
Rym: magical dueling arena Castle floating in the sky.
Rym: you're fighting duels with members of the student council of this school in order to win control.
Rym: Some girl who goes to the school who seems to have absolutely no will of her own other than to be the Rose bride to Whoever has won her
Scott: mm-hmm
Rym: and That is what the show is about and the members of the student council and utenna and other people from outside End up dueling with each other with varying stakes ranging from you know fighting with wooden swords to Fighting to the death with actual swords with the purpose of gaining control of this woman in order to unlock the castle of the sky to gain eternity and To essentially smash the world's shell for the sake of the revolution of the world.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Scott: it's crazy fucked up abstract shit.
Scott: They never make clear.
Scott: What's really going on until the end?
Rym: see there are a lot of ways.
Rym: I said you know we're talking about what utenna is about.
Rym: we've already told you two things that it's about.
Rym: Really utenna is a straight-up Anime, you know just a straight-up face value.
Rym: It's an anime.
Rym: weird stuff like that happens.
Rym: It is also a fully self-consistent very well done science fiction.
Rym: It is also a fully self consistent very well done fantasy.
Rym: It is also an Adolescence metaphor straight up mm-hmm.
Rym: It is also a number of a number of other metaphors straight up, and it is combinations of all of those Inside of itself.
Scott: It's also a pretentious art flick with lots of fucked-up symbolism that you're not supposed to understand because you're not as smart As Ikuhara.
Rym: yeah, except the thing is I mean there are a lot of shows that put you know symbolism and sometimes It's obvious sometimes.
Rym: It's arbitrary sometimes.
Rym: It's just BS.
Scott: Utenna is not subtle.
Rym: Well.
Rym: It is subtle in some ways sometime.
Rym: It is subtle in that you will see a symbol you will know what it symbolizes.
Rym: You will think you've got it down and then 20 episodes later They'll show you something and you'll think back to that symbol you saw 20 episodes ago And you'll suddenly realize that you were an idiot And you didn't understand anything.
Rym: and now you get it.
Rym: yeah This is a show where symbolism is bleeding out of every single instant.
Rym: Everything that happens in the show every point of direction every I guess camera angle every expression on a character's face everything that's going on in the background is directly relevant Self-consistent and they're on purpose.
Scott: and sometimes it's there on purpose just to mess with you.
Rym: There's one point in the middle where it's like the show they'll just keep you showing stuff.
Scott: They'll show you stuff.
Scott: That's weird.
Scott: like this character keeps playing with a stopwatch and ever and you'll just hit the button at random times seemingly random times And they'll show it.
Scott: they'll zoom in on the stopwatch as he starts it and stops it and pushes the lap button And it's like why the fuck did they keep showing the stopwatch?
Rym: yep, or the best example of that is really the student council.
Rym: You see the school is run by the student council which includes all of these duelists and they're conducting the duels and they are running the school based on the orders of quote the ends of the world.
Rym: they get letters from the end of the world about what to do and They follow.
Rym: they follow these letters straight up.
Rym: It says.
Rym: Oh have a duel someone should fight so-and-so blah blah blah.
Scott: It's fucked up shit.
Rym: now They also have the student council meetings and the student council meetings are where you see a lot of the ranging from extremely subtle to Extremely hit you over the head with it.
Rym: metaphorical scenes like they'll be talking and there'll be an apple and then the apples cut up and Or they'll be talking and playing darts But someone's standing in front of the dartboard or a train goes by and it muffles some of the words.
Rym: You heard me.
Scott: a train goes by Or there's an apple and then suddenly the apple is full of forks.
Rym: yeah, Oh God don't remind me of that.
Rym: yeah Yeah, no the thing is this stuff all sounds weird like totally weird.
Rym: whatever why the show is just like Excel saga only trying to be serious.
Rym: Just keep playing keep playing.
Rym: this stuff is all.
Rym: It's really hard for me to get across just how deep this show actually is in a non pretentious way.
Scott: Yeah Now the thing about the show that really that I notice is that Unlike other shows which just have a plot and then follow the plot along until its conclusion.
Scott: You know they have the build-up then they have the the exposition and everything like that.
Scott: utenna has this Structure.
Scott: it's like a very defined structure like each episode follows this defined structure, and then each season Follows the whole structure.
Scott: It's sort of like the same thing three times.
Scott: really.
Scott: yeah, there are three seasons.
Rym: The show is like this recursion in and of itself.
Rym: I mean there's the main thread of the plot which goes through the whole show.
Rym: But there's one character who has this whole set of subplots that like they'll be like normal episode normal episode normal episode Nanami episode which are usually silly and funny and crazy and over-the-top with Thousand X potent curry sauce.
Scott: I love the thousand X potent curry sauce.
Scott: those actually harken back a lot to the manga.
Rym: But if you take all of those episodes out of the show and string them together and watch them as a show in and of Themselves they tell the story of the entire show just in a different way.
Rym: if you take like the second story arc the Black Rose saga Apart and watch it on its own it kind of tells the same story of the show just in a different direction.
Scott: Yeah, now the way each episode is structured is you know you'll come in they'll show you that.
Scott: maybe if it's an early episode They'll show you that fairy tale thing all right and the plot will kind of pick up where it left off.
Scott: And you know you'll see some characters doing some stuff.
Scott: And then you know there's a bunch of different characters in the student council and usually you only Concentrate heavily on one of them in any one time.
Scott: and it sort of starts each season with the lesser Important ones and it get it builds up to the bigger ones the more important people on the student council.
Scott: towards the ends of the season You know.
Scott: so you'll start out with an episode and you know it'll be dealing with the plot of always Zutena because she's the main character and one person on the student council and It sort of shows you everything and people are getting along people aren't getting along and then eventually You know everything sort of builds up to the maximum and then the shadow girls show up.
Rym: now the shadow girls are another one of those very interesting things about this shot.
Rym: They're the student council meetings, and there are the shadow girls, and they serve a number of purposes.
Rym: They're almost like the Greek chorus.
Rym: they're kind of like the vibe of the students or What people are saying about what's going on even though?
Scott: They just talk about monkeys and UFOs and submarines and pirates and God knows what?
Rym: Yeah, it's just they're there.
Rym: They add another layer to this show.
Rym: and all I really have to say is if you're watching utenna pay Attention to what those shadow girls are saying and you'll understand the show a lot better.
Scott: Yeah, or less.
Scott: Yeah, if you think about it too hard.
Scott: You might hurt yourself.
Scott: So after the shadow girls come you always 99% of the time hear that music again, and it's time for the duel.
Scott: and Pretty much, you know sometimes it only takes one episode for them to build up to a duel sometimes takes two episodes But there's pretty much most of the time a duel at the end of every episode and then at the beginning of the next episode It's another student council character, and we continue with their plot.
Rym: Yep now the we you know they've got these different story.
Rym: I mean the show is basically broken up into four story arcs or four seasons And they have really three, but there's a little.
Scott: the end is like a tiny little season in its own.
Rym: Yeah I mean basically there's the student council saga or at the beginning and It's kind of like.
Rym: this is the first bit of the show the first 13 episodes.
Scott: Less weird.
Rym: yes, if you watch the first 13 episodes up until the last five minutes of the last episode episode 13 You'll think all right this show didn't get so weird.
Rym: I don't know what Rym you can actually trick it.
Scott: you could actually tell someone that that's the whole show and they would totally believe It.
Rym: yeah except for that tiny cliff at the very end.
Scott: Yep The last five minutes of the 13th episode are what prevent it from just being the end of the show entirely because it could have been.
Rym: So that's before we continue.
Rym: if you're going to give utenna a chance And you're seriously going to trust us on this you have to watch beyond the first 13. the first 13 are good But they are not the meat of utenna.
Rym: They are not what we rave and go nuts over.
Rym: They are not what made us love the show.
Rym: They are just good enough to set you up for what is about to come.
Scott: I actually like the first 13 the most.
Rym: I Like them because they're still very deep and there's a lot of.
Rym: I mean the symbolism in this show is just so amazing and that Might sound pretentious, but you can die in a fire.
Rym: It's actually really amazing.
Scott: It's not that amazing.
Scott: a lot of it is just kind of silly and random.
Rym: Yeah But until you know when you've seen the whole show and you go back and you see you can Wear it was coming from.
Scott: that's the problem with the show is that when you watch it through for the first time a lot of?
Scott: The stuff is silly and random and there's no going around it.
Scott: But if you watch it a second time once you know everything then a lot not all of but a lot of the silly random Crap actually meet make sense.
Rym: It's like what the fuck how did the hell?
Rym: They do that and not just make sense like there'll be a throwaway gag about something right and you watch it the first time through The show you're like haha, whatever.
Rym: Then you watch the show again, and you know what's been going.
Rym: like you know the plot You know what I've seen the end You know everything and you'll see that throwaway joke and it's not funny.
Rym: in fact It's kind of disturbing or and terrible.
Rym: yeah like you watch you like wow What kind of show is this yeah?
Scott: Imagine if you watch Star Wars and it was Star Wars.
Scott: then imagine if watching Star Wars a second time it was Completely different and all the jokes were actually like suddenly turned into dark humor instead of slapstick.
Rym: like you know when there's the Jawa traders Right mm-hmm, and you know we met they go with the Jawa traders, and they're kind of antagonistic and whatever.
Rym: What if at the end of Star Wars Luke joined the Empire and genocided all the Jawas?
Rym: And he'd been planning to do that from the start and he always hated them.
Rym: And then you go back and you watch the show and from the beginning again the movies you're like oh Yeah, cuz you know he doesn't like the Jawas you're like hey, he doesn't like him cuz he wants to go kill him all.
Scott: Yep, it totally changes the way you look at it alright.
Scott: So that's the structure of like an episode.
Scott: the structure of a season right is that they start with the small end of the student And they work their way up and then something crazy happens.
Rym: yep and crazy is Generally ever-increasing as the season and episode numbers increase.
Scott: yeah It's like any season starts off kind of easy to understand and a lot of mundane things are happening.
Scott: And then as you get closer to the 13th episode because it's what 39 episodes right.
Scott: yep Yeah, the 13th episode with this three seasons 13 each you it gets really freaking weird and crazy.
Rym: Yep, so again watch the first 13 episodes.
Rym: They're good.
Rym: They're deep they're interesting.
Rym: the 13th episode will kind of let you in on what's actually going on and Then starting with episode 14 the black rose saga.
Rym: That is when the show becomes what it actually is.
Rym: the show becomes dark.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is the black rose saga.
Scott: It's like you should watch it.
Scott: It's important You know and that's part of why the show is great.
Scott: But you could actually not watch it and just go straight to episode 25 25 25 and you wouldn't know the difference you wouldn't miss anything.
Rym: the black rose saga is like this recursive Cyclical part of the story that doesn't really need to be there and kind of just tells the story again from a different.
Scott: It's like the second 13 episodes are the same as the first 13 And they're the same as the last 13 only they're not.
Rym: The only real difference is that.
Rym: well, I guess other than the things we can't talk about Yeah, is that the first 13 the the issues that you're dealing with are mostly things that I mean.
Rym: They end up being sad or serious or scary but at the same time they're also very not the biggest deal like ah there was a love triangle and someone ended up losing out or someone was heartbroken or someone has problems with their family or their sister.
Rym: and While they're serious issues, they're not.
Rym: you know end of the world kill yourself horribly depressing things.
Rym: The black rose saga it's the same.
Rym: You know the same structure of the show except the problems the characters are dealing with and the reasons they have for dueling are So much more sinister and horrible.
Scott: And then in the third season which we're not going to talk much about except for the fact that it is called the cars Season by us anyway, yes, it's called the Akio saga or the the end saga by most normal people.
Scott: We call it cars because there are many.
Scott: you'll know why when you watch it and there are many cars in it Specifically one car which looks like a red Miata, but it's not really a Miata.
Scott: It just looks like one.
Rym: Yeah, and then there's like the last five or six episodes are kind of the end of the world song.
Scott: Yeah, like when you get towards the end of the the cars series, you know towards the end.
Scott: The last few episodes are just way out weird and they don't really kind of go with the cars even though they do.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: But you'll know.
Rym: I mean, you know exactly when that happens because each of these story are really like the last two gets weird.
Rym: Well, yeah, but there's a break.
Rym: once cars ends There's a definitive point where there's a duel and after that duel that is when the show takes a turn like the show ends and Then it doesn't end.
Rym: it's really hard to explain but the show will end.
Rym: you like All right, all the duels are done.
Rym: whatever is going to happen has happened.
Rym: all we have now is the epilogue.
Rym: what happened because of this?
Rym: and the epilogue is Actually the end of the show.
Rym: the epilogue is the part where everything is revealed.
Rym: you figure it all out.
Rym: I was.
Rym: I can say in all seriousness that when we watch this for the first time and there was a bunch of us It was like us and Lara and I forget who I figured it out like a few minutes before they revealed it Like I didn't.
Scott: I wasn't a hundred percent sure so I didn't open my mouth Which is why a lot of people don't believe me.
Rym: I believe you because I was almost there.
Scott: I was like I was like could it be could it be?
Scott: but I was like.
Scott: I didn't know how it could be You know, but I was like it could be that it could be.
Scott: that is it that?
Scott: and then all of a sudden They come out and they're like, not only is it that but this is how it was done.
Scott: Booyah, and I'm like
Rym: no But there is a point in near the end where something happened something pretty bad happens to a real
Scott: bad
Rym: and There's this metaphor with candles going on just so anyone who's seen the show is will know or when you off the show we're Anthony him EMEA the Rose bride is holding this candelabra with candles and one by one the candles go out and Then the third candle goes out and we know at this point what this is symbolizing.
Rym: and then it happens and we're all taken back like everyone in the room kind of gasped like we didn't think it would really happen.
Rym: and it happened like.
Rym: and Then we're watching and we see something in the background and we backed it up to make sure we saw it and Two people in the room scream like actually screamed when they noticed it.
Scott: It's pretty fucked up shit right there.
Rym: Yeah, this show is not for kids.
Rym: The show is not for people who don't like being depressed.
Scott: Yeah It's not.
Scott: if you don't like being scared or freaked out You shouldn't watch this either.
Scott: Yes, you're so dumb that you won't understand what's going on.
Scott: then you'll just be like It does.
Scott: you can't just watch this show casually.
Scott: I think is one of the problems with it.
Scott: You have to pay fucking attention.
Rym: That's why I mean, I'm really glad that the first time I saw the show We pretty much watched the last ten episodes in a row non-stop Partly because we couldn't bring ourselves to stop.
Rym: It's not like that, but there are some scenes.
Rym: There's some powerful scenes and there's been a lot of.
Rym: I mean people talk a lot about Chiyo Saito and how she writes things and how sometimes what she would do is come up with a scene like an idea for a scene and then write whatever she's writing around that scene.
Rym: and I'm not sure where I heard this but someone told me that her idea for utenna would resolve revolved around one scene that she had come up with.
Rym: and When that scene happens in the show, it's a very powerful moment, but it is not the only powerful moment.
Rym: They're the scenes in this show like the stage scenes.
Rym: There are probably 10 or 12 of them that are just absolutely amazing and how well they're executed.
Scott: Mm-hmm All right.
Scott: Now let's talk about three other things.
Scott: We gotta talk with the animation.
Scott: Yep, the music and the voice acting All right animation.
Rym: very briefly.
Rym: The animation is not bad However, it's so bad.
Rym: The opener is really well animated openers and the closers are pretty cool and they obviously Save up their budget in order to animate the last few episodes better than the rest of the show.
Scott: and while the Animation is bad.
Scott: The character design is great.
Rym: The character design looks kind of weird, you know tall angular Bishonin bishoujo people crazy costumes that I don't even really like them that much but some reason they're okay.
Rym: But the character designs are so iconic and so strong.
Rym: It's like, you know in an opera there's the light motifs like the little song that plays when a character, you know appears.
Rym: These character designs act like their own light motifs Like.
Scott: they're so iconic of the characters and mostly the hair color of everyone is so different.
Scott: you identify people by their hair color And the color of their hair kind of matches the character really well, and it's all yeah, perfect.
Rym: Also every character, you know, they're associated with this color.
Rym: and you know, we talked about those spinning roses.
Rym: Every now and then you'll be watching and suddenly there'll be a frame around the action with four roses spinning of One of the hair colors of a character.
Rym: Oh, yes But sometimes it's white and not a color of a character.
Rym: and this sound just bear with me but that means something.
Rym: and After you've seen the show once and you watch it again and you you kind of figure out what that is trying to tell you The viewer it again puts the show in an entirely different perspective.
Rym: and when I say entirely different perspective This show.
Rym: a lot of times you'll be going along and suddenly if you realize something your perspective on the show is 180 degrees.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Now, yeah It's like in the matrix when he wakes up and he's a battery.
Rym: in terms of it's like that level of wait a minute.
Rym: Yeah, oh man, I get it.
Scott: Yeah, but for the most part the animation is lots of panning over still frames Lots of you see a character's face and only their mouth moves.
Rym: Some of the duels are really really well animated but many of the duels are barely animated.
Scott: It's like a picture of a guy with a sword a picture of a girl with a sword.
Scott: You know a picture of the swords hitting while the screen shakes.
Rym: sometimes they'll cover the action with a giant spinning rose.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, of course that again it could mean something.
Scott: It could be just saving money on animation.
Rym: now Here's my hypothesis and I found a few people who agree with me.
Rym: I think that part of what made Utena as good as it was Was that they were so constrained in their animation budget and they were so constrained in their time frame that they ended up having to come up with really really creative ways to get a lot of information across and a lot of Symbolism across in a very short span of time with very little animation and very little budget.
Scott: There is definitely something to be said for the fact that it's you're all.
Scott: it's always easier to be more creative and more Interesting when you have some sort of limitations, you know when you have no limits, it's really hard to do anything.
Scott: But that's awesome because you can do anything, you know.
Scott: So it's it's difficult when someone puts some limits on you, even if they're artificial limits.
Rym: that's what you can get creative because you're doing more with less and Utena does that pretty well and also because the animation is kind of you know Slow and choppy and still frames through a lot of the show.
Rym: Whenever important things happen it ends up being animated really well.
Rym: They can as well as they could have and in the last few episode is a lot of repeat footage to like.
Scott: when she walks up The stairs to the dueling arena, you'll see that same footage like in most of the episodes.
Rym: Yep, kind of like the transformation sequence in a magical girl show.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Scott: it's pretty much only longer.
Rym: However, that song and also, you know The song means a lot and it really does.
Rym: I'm glad they left that stock footage in because it really like the stock foot Really sets you up for the duels.
Rym: Yeah, like it gets you in this Kind of strange move once you know how the show goes and you just take the show at face value just running with it.
Rym: now That music and that opening sequence really set you up.
Rym: if you're in a big way and the duels feel so much more powerful because of That well all the music in this show is really powerful and sets you up for crazy stuff.
Rym: Yeah, now we really have to talk about that.
Rym: The music in utenna is also one of the things that made it amazing.
Rym: We talked a while ago about.
Rym: you know music and anime and how like a show like initial D is nothing without its music.
Scott: No initial D without music is nothing.
Scott: utenna is less than nothing without music.
Rym: or and also like a show like dot hack sign Which was a crap show, but it had amazing music that pulled it.
Rym: just the music.
Scott: Yeah, the music of hack sign was able to pull me to episode 13 where nothing happened until then.
Scott: But without the music utenna is nothing but with the music it is everything.
Rym: I don't know how I would describe the music in utenna other than that half of it is instrumental symphonic music with maybe a little bit of jazzy stuff in there and the other half of it is rock Opera chorus music.
Scott: it's kind of crazy.
Scott: We're gonna.
Scott: we'll play some of it for you in the episode, but it's awesome All right.
Rym: Now the story there is.
Rym: for one reason or another Ikuhara wrote most of the lyrics to the dual song.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah, every time there's a duel.
Scott: There's a song that plays during the duel, you know and Each duel has its own song.
Scott: now these a lot of episodes and there's a lot of duels.
Rym: So there's a lot of songs and they're all Very very distinctive like each one.
Rym: like if you've seen the show You'll hear one of the dual songs for the most part and you'll remember which duel it was from to a certain degree.
Rym: Maybe I don't really remember.
Rym: I mean you'll forget a lot of the black rose ones, but I remember.
Rym: I've seen the show three times But there are three or four of the duels that I hear the song.
Scott: It's like ah, oh, man Yeah, but it's not like an initial D. if they play a certain eurobeat song during a race You remember which race had which eurobeat song playing, you know, now the lyrics to the songs are very strange.
Scott: They're fucked up and most of the time.
Scott: Whoa, like my favorite one is a Jurassic Cretaceous Night, yeah, it talks about all the different ages of dinosaurs.
Rym: It's kind of crazy again If one if you're watching the show for the first time as much as I want to say you should don't even try To read the lyrics to these songs while you're watching the duel.
Rym: just pay attention to what the characters are saying.
Rym: There is no way you will be able to follow those lyrics and the duel and figure it all out.
Scott: Yeah, and it's not like I don't even know what the hell spirit of Milla Billy's era Mira Billy suit.
Scott: Yeah That still really doesn't have that much meaning and it's not really necessary.
Rym: Yeah, well it's not necessary though after you've seen the show a bunch of times if you just like you already know what the characters saying if you watch what the lyrics are and what they're translated as They're about as relevant as something like that could be and some of them seem like they're not that well inspired.
Rym: But some of the duels the songs are.
Scott: yeah, some of the duels the songs make more sense than Jurassic Cretaceous.
Scott: What are the other eras?
Rym: Because the thing is even that song.
Rym: You could you could I could at least make an argument as to what that song was trying a pretty weak one But yeah You could you give me that week?
Rym: because eco horror like pointedly wrote the lyrics on by himself for each duel And the music itself.
Rym: He got it scored by a man named J a Caesar Caesar.
Rym: I've seen his name before.
Rym: I think he actually has another name in Japanese.
Rym: I don't remember it.
Rym: Mm-hmm and all the other music was composed by some other guy and that other guy also did some of the work for the duel choruses, but I Don't think we need to talk about anymore.
Rym: I'm just going to play two or three of the dual songs for whole things.
Rym: Yeah, they're real short.
Rym: All right, just so you get an idea of what kind of music this is.
Scott: All right Oh Oh Oh Oh.
Scott: The last thing we got to talk about is the voice acting.
Scott: now The problem here is that in a show where there's not a lot of animation and you're gonna need some pretty good voice acting To get everything across.
Rym: Yeah I mean luckily they put almost all of their animation effort into the characters eyes and the character designs do emote a lot Yep.
Scott: Well the voice acting in Japanese is awesome.
Rym: It is so excellent.
Rym: it I mean not only is it so excellent and amazing and not only did these actors Go all out and do exactly what this show needed But Scott's gonna tell you a little bit about perhaps our favorite voice actor ever.
Rym: Yeah, who is not only Kiryu Toga my favorite character in any anime ever other than maybe captain Tyler but he is Everyone cool in every anime I've ever liked just about yet.
Scott: There is a guy and his name is Takehito Koyasu, right and He was Toga in utenna, which is a very important character in a tenet.
Scott: Perhaps my favorite character in the tenet.
Scott: He's also Takahashi Ryo Suke.
Rym: He is also initial D. Hoto Hori from Fushigi Yugi.
Scott: He is also Moolah Flaga in Gundam seed.
Scott: he's also like a bajillion other Characters that you love.
Rym: he is in Everything.
Scott: he is in everything and everything he is in.
Scott: he is awesome And I don't know what else I can say about this guy then.
Scott: he's the greatest Japanese voice actor to ever live.
Rym: Yeah And the thing is he can only really play like this one kind of at least as far as all the roles I've heard him in because he's done a lot of stuff that I've never seen.
Rym: Yep, he plays the iconic Really really cool guy Mm-hmm.
Rym: His voice is just so dark and deep and smooth.
Rym: Yep, I don't know.
Rym: This guy's just amazing.
Rym: I would love to meet him.
Rym: He's one of the few Japanese voice actors in the world I would actually Honestly really want to meet and talk to.
Scott: he was Ken shiro and new fist of the North Star.
Scott: Oh, I'm just going on the list picking up crazy stuff here.
Rym: Yeah, he I think he's a boba boba boba boba.
Scott: He's bud mint in KO century.
Rym: Oh bud mint best character in that show.
Scott: He's Luke Valentine and hell sing.
Scott: He's bonbon gatekeepers.
Scott: Wow, yeah, he's a lot of stuff.
Scott: he's in some Harlock he's in samurai Champloo He's ill palazzo and Excel saga as well as some other characters in Excel saga.
Scott: God, this guy is like the god of voice acting.
Rym: now and when he's in a show, you know The voice acting is gonna be good at least his voice acting Yeah, but seriously not to disparage any of the other voice actors in utenna.
Rym: I yeah, they're all.
Scott: whoever they did whoever they were They were all awesome.
Rym: Now.
Rym: I wish this weren't the case, but I have to say utenna in America has Unequivocably the worst dub ever done.
Rym: I say that with authority.
Scott: Good fucking God It is so bad as to be painful and unwatchable under any circumstance.
Rym: Now you might say but wait a minute There's got to be some hentai with the worst dub.
Rym: and the answer is there might be but I haven't seen the answer.
Rym: The answer is probably but the reason this is the worst worst dub ever?
Rym: because not only was the Japanese voice acting just so good but the show Relied so much on voice acting and was so good.
Rym: This is probably the biggest disparity in quality of dub to quality of show ever.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's just that you know, there are some shows that don't require such a great voice acting.
Scott: You know, you can get by with an easy voice acting.
Scott: So if you just do a standard effort voice acting the show will still come off.
Scott: All right, who tenor requires the highest quality of voice acting?
Scott: Yeah, I think a good example nearly impossible to be satisfactory.
Scott: So putting in the same effort as you put into another show like if you take the raw, you know The numerical quality of the voice acting from with tenor and put it on another show you might say oh, it's okay job But no fruit Anna.
Scott: It's a terrible job It's.
Rym: I mean, I watched like four episodes dubbed near the beginning and they were painful and I thought you know what?
Rym: It's got to get better.
Rym: It's gotta get better.
Rym: I watch dubs from near the end of the show and not only is it not better But it might have gotten worse in some ways.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: I can't describe to you how bad this dub is.
Rym: Don't watch it.
Rym: I know when anime world order tells you not to watch something you watch it.
Rym: We're I'm not kidding.
Rym: Don't watch the dub.
Scott: Yeah, I mean this even has a couple good voice actors like Crispin Freeman and some other people But they're not good in this show and they might be good other times.
Scott: They're not good here.
Rym: I wonder why.
Rym: I mean did they not get the show?
Rym: did they not where they just directed?
Rym: poorly?
Rym: maybe that their writing was bad?
Rym: I mean I have no idea the dialogue ever know the dialogue in the show?
Rym: part of the problem Is that it's very complex, and it's layered with metaphor upon metaphor, and I think it was really hard to translate that.
Scott: yeah It could be.
Scott: I don't know the voice acting in the English dub is bad.
Scott: Utena must be watched with subtitles.
Scott: There is no alternative.
Scott: anything else we can say about this crazy show?
Rym: I mean all I can really say.
Rym: eventually I'd love to do one or more episodes on Utena and what I really feel about.
Scott: Yeah, we noticed that Rym just can't stop talking about it.
Rym: I mean I had to check myself And I like every time I was starting to talk about the plot I could pretty much tell you the entire plot the order of All the God.
Rym: I could talk an entire show just about toga.
Rym: Seriously, I could do a whole show just on toga.
Rym: his motivation where he came from where he's going all the things that happen to Him why it's important?
Rym: what metaphors were there.
Scott: I don't think anyone wants to hear that.
Rym: no probably not.
Rym: however I've been to some decent panels on Utena over the years.
Rym: actually there was a really good one at Katsucon last year.
Scott: Utena Is a show that you can just have a lot of panels about because there's just so much stuff.
Rym: You can just keep talking and talking and talking and talking, but the thing is unlike Ava which people do the same thing for Ava the debt.
Rym: there's only so much depth to Ava.
Rym: I mean obviously the also.
Scott: Utena does have 13 more episodes yes, which helps out.
Rym: But obviously the psychological depth of Ava whether you like it or not is actually really deep and really well done.
Rym: But in terms of the rest of Ava It's not as deep as a lot of people try to make it out to be and it's really hard To have a real argument about what Evangelion means beyond the psychological stuff.
Rym: mm-hmm Utena you a lot of people agree as to exactly what Utena is about.
Rym: if they've seen it all once you've seen it all.
Scott: It's very hard to argue against a lot of the things that mostly because the main thing they just come straight out with it Yeah, and everything else sort of falls off of that.
Scott: It's sort of.
Scott: it's sort of like.
Scott: you know it's sort of like there's a tree And you're trying to see the tree all right And you're not sure what shape the trunk is or what kind of tree it is.
Scott: and you got.
Scott: you see leaves and maybe you See some fruit and then at the end of the show They're like they show you a picture of the trunk, and you're like motherfucking goddamn sons of bitches.
Scott: And then the rest of it kind of follows is like well now they know what the fucking trunk looks like.
Scott: yeah Everything else is fucking you know obvious.
Scott: now great Oh, oh well That's terrific.
Scott: And then you start looking around the tree and seeing all the things that are obvious you just hadn't thought of and you just want to Frickin hit your head against the wall sometimes yep Especially watching the show the second time through.
Rym: it's one of the few shows and we've said this but really Watching you ten of the second time through is an entirely different show.
Scott: all right I think I know how I want to end this a little here.
Scott: all right.
Scott: now one piece of.
Scott: I'm not gonna spoil the show For you, but here's a piece of advice to help keep you a little bit more sane.
Scott: when watching utana Every episode just keep asking yourself this question you ready how the fuck is a castle hanging from the sky?
Scott: How the fuck is a castle hanging from the sky?
Scott: what the fuck yeah?
Scott: You keep asking yourself because he eventually what happened to me is I just accepted it.
Rym: I'm like oh, there's a castle hanging from the sky of course yeah It's not just the castle everything in the show I mean.
Rym: when utana first runs into these duels her reaction is basically What the fuck is this shit Charles?
Scott: and then by episode 3 it's no longer what the fuck it's.
Scott: oh yeah That's the way it's gonna be.
Scott: yeah You know now a lot of anime as never stop asking yourself How the fuck the castle is hanging from the sky and then the show will make a lot more sense to you And you will not be driven completely batshit into the Arkham assignment.
Rym: so in the end really just I Can't recommend shoujo kakumei utana enough.
Rym: It is seriously an absolutely amazing anime.
Scott: Oh, how do we buy the DVDs?
Rym: Just buy them.
Scott: Yeah, who are they from CPM?
Rym: I think I think so.
Scott: I don't there.
Scott: they should be kind of cheap now if you buy three separate box sets one for each season But they're really bad DVDs.
Scott: actually yeah, well they get the menus are terrible and the extras are terrible.
Rym: It's partly just because they're kind of older DVD especially the first season the first season of utana that I bought.
Rym: I play bad.
Rym: Yeah, yeah was so like old-school DVD menu.
Scott: Yeah, they're pretty bad DVDs But they're cheap and there's a lot of episodes per disc and they're kind of worth it.
Rym: and also I mean they're only bad DVDs in terms of the extras and stuff.
Rym: in terms of the show they're great.
Scott: You can't the DVDs.
Scott: they show you the show and the best quality that it can be shown in.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott special, thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.