Rym: So you may have noticed the lack of opening music.
Rym: that can only mean one of two things either this is a GeekNights special or We're doing the second half of those questions.
Rym: We did way back in the day.
Scott: Yeah, we did questions week.
Scott: I forget what date it was But if you go look at our website You'll find a week of episodes consisting entirely of us answering questions And we only answered about half the questions people sent us and now we're gonna answer the other half.
Scott: Do you want to disclaim how we answer the questions?
Rym: I think we'll just jump right into it.
Rym: suffice to say these are questions submitted by all of you our listeners.
Rym: We picked the best or the ones that we can make the most fun of and we just kind of put them in a random Order mo pretty much in the order that we received them.
Rym: No research.
Rym: No planning.
Scott: We're just gonna jump right into this with nothing and we're not giving credit to whoever asked the question.
Scott: You know who you are.
Rym: So without further ado Joey Jojo Shabbat who writes?
Rym: What What one game have you guys played the longest as in?
Rym: I've played X game for why years?
Rym: well Not longest as in.
Rym: you know, I've played Civ 2 more than any other game combined.
Scott: But yeah, I mean, yeah It's tough because like the I guess one of the I guess I played pac-man for the Atari maybe and then I played that recently.
Scott: So, you know between the first time I played it in the most recent time I played it's probably the longest amount of time Yeah, so that would be kaboom.
Rym: Yeah, we're talking video games, right?
Scott: But if you're talking well, I guess, you know, if you're talking hours of play Total it's like two or a quick two might be like Civ 2 or Counter-Strike or something like that.
Rym: You know while I think Counter-Strike and while I played it almost every day at RIT for many years When I was in high school, I played Quake 2 mods longer than that every day.
Rym: Yeah, but for me, I guess Counter-Strike me, I guess probably yeah, I mean in terms of board games it Probably Settlers just because games I played before that I don't play anymore.
Rym: Yeah, and even Settlers I barely play I mean like.
Scott: I guess the first board game I ever played maybe was like Candyland.
Rym: No, it was the Uncle Wiggly.
Scott: No, I didn't play Uncle Wiggly.
Rym: Uncle Wiggly was the first game I ever played that I can remember.
Scott: My sister had Uncle Wiggly But it was better than Candyland.
Scott: I haven't played Candyland in a long time.
Rym: Candyland is not as good as Uncle Wiggly.
Scott: Maybe like like Jin Rummy or something cuz.
Scott: you know card games are sort of.
Scott: you know I played them when I was young and I played them semi recently maybe like backgammon.
Rym: I've been playing backgammon for when was the last time you played it though?
Scott: like a year ago.
Rym: Maybe it might be hearts.
Scott: Maybe you know cuz I didn't play hearts until Microsoft Windows 95 taught me how.
Rym: Oh, really?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: My dad taught me how.
Rym: Yeah To this day.
Scott: My grandpa taught me all the card games.
Scott: I know it was mostly like poker and Rummy and that sort of thing.
Rym: Rummy.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right What else we got here?
Rym: Let me see.
Rym: Already lost your space?
Scott: Yes, cuz I didn't have my space to begin with.
Rym: What characters in Team Fortress 2 have your highest playtime points?
Rym: This question is a little bit Not relevant anymore since we really don't play Team Fortress 2 anymore.
Scott: Yeah, I haven't played Team Fortress 2 in a few weeks But if I remember correctly The medic might have my highest playtime because there was a string where the game was hot where I was the medic all the time.
Scott: But then I sort of stopped and then the game declined, but I think one time I got like 24 points to the Demoman.
Scott: That was my big score.
Rym: Engineer is double all the other classes combined in terms of playtime, but Sniper has far and away the most points because if I do decide to be a sniper I shoot everyone
Scott: All right,
Rym: especially on these new maps that are way too big for the way this game is designed.
Scott: Yep What do you guys think about people putting their names on games?
Scott: E.g.
Scott: Sid Meier's Civilization, Clive Barker's Jericho, Peter Jackson's King Kong.
Rym: Once again proper use of Exemplia Grettis, props.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, the thing is it's sort of a two-way street.
Scott: It's like number one.
Scott: I don't like it when you have sort of like this work of art and it doesn't say who made it at all on it.
Scott: You know, it's like, you know because knowing who made something who is primarily responsible for something is huge because then you find out what else they did and you Can find more things you will enjoy, you know If I buy a manga and it doesn't say Tezuka on it and then I buy another manga that doesn't say Tezuka I don't know.
Scott: They're the same.
Scott: Well, I guess it'd be hard not to know.
Scott: they're the same but you don't know for sure, you know.
Scott: but if they all say Tezuka you can buy one if you like it you look and then you buy a whole bunch and It's a good thing.
Scott: but
Rym: I mean one thing that got us way back when we first made friends with anime world order and they talked a lot about anime directors and then we started paying attention to all the different anime directors not just the big ones but all of them and We discovered a lot of anime that we liked and we noticed that all the anime we hated were made by the same car of idiots.
Scott: Yep, but there is a problem with this.
Scott: and the problem is is that a lot of these things, right?
Scott: I mean, you know a painting by Van.
Scott: Gogh.
Scott: No one made it but Van.
Scott: It was all Van.
Scott: Gogh.
Scott: No one else, right?
Scott: No one else did it.
Scott: but you look at something like a manga right where it has writer or writer and artist.
Scott: But they had a bunch of assistants and a bunch of other people working on it Editors and stuff and those people get no credit whatsoever.
Scott: and The problem is it could end up like a movie where sure you give them a little tiny credit in the back You know that no one ever sees but then no one knows or cares about them.
Scott: You might as well give them no credit at all.
Rym: But at the same time What's the purpose of having the name there?
Rym: If the purpose is to kind of identify?
Rym: because look if you look at Sid Meier, he made all the same kind of games.
Scott: Yep, he did.
Rym: So it's more of a benefit to the people the consumer just from a very much.
Rym: I like the kinds of games that are directed by Sid Meier or I like the kinds of games that are designed by Rainer Canizia
Scott: yep, and you look at something like American comic books where they do give credit to all like the different people who work on it like the colorist and a letterer and Everything right.
Scott: and those people fought to get their names on those books and they got them there.
Scott: But now it's sort of you know, people do pay attention to the writers and the artists mostly but there's a lot.
Scott: It's not as it's not like a manga where there's one big name on it, you know It's easy to identify.
Scott: it's it's a tough call because on the one hand some people aren't getting credit for work They did.
Scott: but on the other hand, it's more useful.
Scott: If only the most important person it's more that they still get the credit.
Rym: It's more that this is just making what like a name prominent like just selling a movie as in.
Rym: you know, King Kong or Peter Jackson's King Kong Cuz I mean King Kong is one thing.
Rym: but by calling it Peter Jackson's King Kong Now you kind of just from the title.
Rym: No.
Rym: All right.
Rym: This is Peter Jackson's take on King Kong.
Rym: I like Peter Jackson.
Rym: I like King Kong.
Rym: Let's see what happens.
Rym: Yep The only problem I have with this at all is just a lot of times I've seen people well marketers try to sell one thing that might have been done a little bit by someone who's been big and other things like When when utenna was first marketed in the US They made a big deal on all the packaging that by the creators of Sailor Moon because Sailor Moon was popular and they tried to kind of Steal all that popularity and ride on the coattails to sell utenna.
Scott: Yeah I noticed a lot of that stuff goes on where someone who is like You know a major creative influence on one project has like their pinky toe dipped into another project.
Scott: But then the plaster that person's name all over it like, you know, like if Steven Spielberg like looks at a movie They'll be like Steven Spielberg Oh my god When he didn't even really most of it just to sort of profit off of his name.
Rym: But at the same time the people who tend to do that are the people who dilute the value of their name.
Rym: And then I ignore him.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, it's tough call.
Rym: I mean Sid Meyer has rarely done me wrong.
Scott: No, we're definitely rarely.
Rym: rain-air kinesia always on top.
Scott: No, you remember what was that game?
Rym: a Tower of Babel that one Babylon Tower?
Scott: Babel.
Scott: Yeah, I remember.
Rym: Okay, as far as I'm concerned That game does not exist.
Scott: Okay Next question here.
Scott: What is one thing you would do to make video games better as a whole?
Scott: What kind of vague question is that?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: take more risks Make better game.
Scott: let anyone make any game they want.
Rym: I would make better games Thereby making video games as a whole better.
Rym: That's a stupid question.
Rym: You're a stupid person.
Scott: games free.
Rym: Okay, that that would be a whole show at mo at All right.
Rym: What's the most inventive game you've ever played?
Rym: Kata Mari gets a lot of points for just being weird kinda Tetris.
Rym: Tetris kind of spawned a whole genre of gaming space war.
Scott: Space war was actually not that fun, but there was the most inventiveness going on.
Scott: Well, I think about how much they invented.
Rym: by that logic Almost every Atari game is one of the most inventive games ever because they took nothing and made something.
Scott: I think it's just another vague question like the previous Like what games stand out as being?
Rym: I don't know mold breakers or games that changed the industry.
Rym: I mean Final Fantasy 1 changed video gaming in a profound way.
Scott: Yeah, kind Mario Super Mario Brothers 1 Zelda 1.
Rym: Mario 1 was the first platformer that didn't suck.
Scott: Yeah, something like that Space Invaders, I don't know.
Rym: All right, I guess you don't want to answer that.
Rym: Not really now All right Do you think it is allowable and should be legal for people to modify the firmware of handheld such as the PSP and the DS?
Scott: Yes, if you own something if you own a physical thing You should be able to do to that physical thing Whatever you want, but at the same time the person who sold it to you is within their rights to no longer support you.
Scott: Yeah, they don't have.
Scott: your warranty could be void which is fine or whatever But if you own something you should be able to do to it Whatever you want to do to it.
Scott: as long as you don't you know break the law like if you take your car You shouldn't be able to take out the catalytic converter, you know stuff like that, but that's a different story.
Scott: But for the most part you own something.
Scott: you can do whatever you want to it as far as I'm concerned.
Rym: So what in your opinion is the saddest moment in gaming?
Scott: The saddest because I've heard that Final Fantasy 7 is sad, but I ever beat that game.
Rym: Well, it has a scene where someone yeah, I know all about that wasn't said.
Rym: even when I saw it I wasn't sad.
Rym: All I could think was why doesn't anyone do anything?
Rym: Why are they letting this happen?
Rym: What the fuck?
Scott: Yeah, I didn't beat it.
Scott: So it's not as I guess the saddest but is what they're asking.
Scott: but my saddest I don't know.
Rym: I got a little choked up when Eris tried to commit suicide in final.
Rym: Yeah Eris What was Sarah Celeste?
Rym: not Eris Celeste in Final Fantasy 6?
Rym: I got a little choked up when it played the opera song again, and then she threw herself off the cliff.
Rym: Yeah, that was a good scene.
Rym: Yeah, I used to kill the fish to see that scene.
Rym: cuz I didn't want to save Cid And it was faster just murdering Poison fish that it was to sit there and try to save him.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: It's really sad in gaming because I don't really play a lot of games that have sadness in them so much.
Rym: Quest for glory 4 has something terribly sad happen near the end that I don't want to ruin.
Scott: Uh-huh Yeah, I can't even think of any sad games that I've played.
Rym: I can think of a few when uh, cuz it's mostly you're gonna find the sadness and like the Japanese RPG types When Cid committed suicide in Final Fantasy 4 Yeah, that's where you're gonna find when Yang committed suicide in Final Fantasy 4.
Rym: Yeah, when palim committed suicide in Final Fantasy 4.
Scott: Oh, yeah when they get turned to stone man, that's pretty sad.
Rym: I got a little sniffly there too.
Scott: Yeah, it's that's a rough one But yeah, that's the only place you're really gonna find the sad moments at least as far as I'm concerned.
Rym: I don't know of any other games that really have the the sadness I would say when you know ex game designer died in the real world, but all my favorite game designers are still alive.
Scott: Oh, yeah, saddest gaming moment.
Scott: when that the guy who invented the Gameboy Oh Gupta.
Scott: Yeah I got my good pay.
Rym: Good pay.
Rym: No, I was thinking of Samir Gupta.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: That's a different guy All right.
Scott: I'm done with this question.
Scott: All right No, you want me to keep going?
Scott: Yeah, go ahead dear Nostra dumbass.
Scott: Okay Please predict with your best use of imagination where gaming will be in a hundred years.
Scott: or will technological advances make it completely unrecognizable?
Rym: Well, it's gonna be perfect VR That's obvious.
Scott: if we're going to assume That gaming will be around at a hundred years and they won't be the end of the world or the humanity will not will Not just transcend the idea of games and only do things that benefit society directly.
Rym: is our daughter, right?
Scott: You will be able to experience anything you want to experience with no risk whatsoever.
Scott: I think I exactly real as if you are really experiencing it and that will be it.
Rym: I really believe that I mean 100 years.
Rym: Think about how much gaming has changed in the last 10 years and it's changing faster in the next year than it did in those 10 years.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: All right.
Rym: What are your opinions of those other non burning wheel games Luke crane recommended?
Rym: I think this is referring back to the interview.
Rym: We did with Luke crane where he recommended a whole bunch of indie RPGs Mm-hmm.
Rym: I think he mentioned lacuna kill puppies for Satan.
Rym: the rest escaped me at the moment.
Rym: There's also dogs in the vineyard and Inspectors.
Scott: we've played Lacuna and we've played inspectors.
Scott: I haven't played kill puppies for Satan and I haven't played time for a primetime adventures, but Lacuna and inspectors are the awesome especially lacuna you any game by Jared Sorenson.
Scott: You should get.
Scott: That's their awesome games.
Scott: They're they're really good.
Scott: They're really simple actually a lot easier to learn the burning wheel and they'll really force you to kind of refine your role-playing chops.
Scott: Yeah, they're not really the greatest for like huge campaigns But they are excellent for like one-time convention games.
Scott: That's like perfect.
Scott: or yep friends coming over need a party game and you're tired.
Scott: apples to apples Perfect,
Rym: or if you want to get people who aren't great role players to be better role players play a game like inspectors, yeah where the actual game mechanics are really simple and the game really just forces you to Tell your part of the story and everyone takes turns telling their parts of the story and use rolled dice to find out if a good Happened or a bad thing happened.
Scott: and if a bad thing happens the DM decides and they tell your part of the story for You.
Rym: yep.
Scott: All right What is your favorite out-of-the-box tabletop RPG setting without consideration the actual mechanics associated with using it?
Scott: So they're talking probably about like forgotten around.
Rym: my answer is forgotten realms.
Scott: My answer is I don't really.
Scott: I'm not a big fan of out-of-the-box settings so much.
Scott: Why I don't know.
Scott: Okay, maybe I can.
Rym: what makes an out-of-the-box setting any different than say a setting that our DM Alex Road?
Rym: I mean nothing.
Scott: I'm just not really into them so much.
Scott: I'm not like.
Scott: I know a lot of people.
Scott: they're crazy You know with the world building like they're so into that You know developing world and like they also it tends to go along with people who like like living for a hockey comic books.
Scott: you know because it's like this universe and it's all about the setting and all the details of the setting and that it doesn't Excite me the way I know it excites a lot of other nerds and geeks out there.
Rym: The reason it excites me what the reason I like to play in a setting that's very fleshed out is Especially when there's a wealth of resources and it's commonly known like.
Rym: it's like forgotten realms where a lot of people know The basics of the setting in the history.
Rym: It's a lot easier to play in character and be able to liberally sprinkle details or know things that your character would know Without having to constantly ask what.
Rym: I know this.
Rym: Yeah, is it there that that's all fun?
Scott: That's all well and good.
Scott: But I'm saying is that it seems like there's a lot of people who are just into settings like.
Scott: they just love settings and you Know there's nothing wrong with that.
Rym: If you're one of those people you would have probably been playing living Greyhawk Even though I think they killed that and now it's living forgotten realm.
Scott: I didn't say there's anything wrong with it.
Scott: I said I'm not one of those people.
Scott: so setting I don't really enjoy settings like set.
Scott: a setting alone doesn't like get me excited.
Scott: So I don't really like one over the other.
Scott: so maybe I could say like I don't know This is Star Wars RPG.
Scott: I could say that.
Scott: or there's the Cthulhu RPG.
Rym: so maybe I could say, you know 1920s call it Cthulhu or something like that, but See, I'll say this though pirate setting the shadow because it says independent of game mechanics the shadow run setting.
Scott: Oh shadow seems.
Rym: I mean it's futuristic cyberpunk plus Fantasy 7c is also kind of cool 7c is really cool and anything involving pirates But you know, none of them really in the air.
Rym: Yeah, none of them really get me that excited Actually one I thoroughly enjoyed and I really wish we had a DM who ran a great game But then he just kind of petered out which got happen often with multiple different DMS.
Rym: But we played an l5 our game Legend of the Five Rings.
Rym: That is a really cool setting.
Scott: It's alright.
Rym: Yeah, of course.
Rym: It's basically just semi mythical feudal magical Japan.
Rym: Have you guys ever played a non grid miniatures game like war hammer or war machine machine?
Rym: and If so, how was your experience?
Rym: I'll let you feel this one Scott.
Scott: Well, I've never actually played war hammer or war machine even though I know of them.
Scott: I've played that mech warrior clicks game that sort of like mage knight and hero clicks, but with back warrior.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think that counts.
Scott: That was a tech.
Scott: It was a non grid miniatures game, but it was terrible.
Scott: independently of it the fact that it was non grid nous Battletech can be played without a grid as just a miniatures game.
Rym: That's crazy.
Scott: It's basically, you know, I don't really think that it has that much of an advantage over battle tech on a hex map.
Scott: Well, it's basically the same game but with rulers.
Rym: Well, no because the difference it adds and this was brought into stark relief way back.
Rym: But I tried to play and played a little bit battle system, which used to be the official Dungeons & Dragons system for mass combat Which was you know, there's terrain and you give troops orders and orders get through and you say, you know march forward 100 meters and they'll march give or take a hundred meters forward and their formation might get messed up But you can't measure before you march.
Scott: So looking at that you kind of have a battle tech you can.
Scott: it's just You can measure whatever you want.
Rym: So you're not allowed to measure.
Rym: you kind of have to eyeball it.
Scott: That is I was talking specifically about the battle tech.
Rym: Yeah, I'm talking about battle system where in that sense there's it's kind of a lot more realistic and that you have a Vague overview of what's going on as the commander of your army and you're sending troops out to do things.
Rym: But it's not like you can tell your troops to move forward eight hexes and then fire because you'll know that you'll be exactly in Range of shooting the tank that can't shoot back.
Rym: There's a lot more realism there.
Rym: Yeah, the only drawback is it takes a lot more time.
Rym: You need a basement that can go undisturbed for months on end as you play four hours of this game every Sunday.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not opposed to playing a non-grid miniatures game.
Scott: I'm actually I kind of like to but the problem is is that it costs a lot of money Especially something like Warhammer.
Scott: the setup is insanely long.
Scott: The play is insanely long.
Scott: It takes a lot of time with the rulers and such and it's just.
Scott: you know All that stuff around.
Scott: it is very difficult.
Scott: If you if I could say play Warhammer on the computer and get any units I want and get you know The rules and a PDF I'd be willing to play.
Scott: that probably see.
Rym: that is one thing.
Rym: games like that are really fun But they get really close to that line where you're better served by playing a really good PC war game.
Scott: Yep I don't.
Rym: it's one of those things a hobby that I would definitely be into without question if I were a member of the member of the idle rich Mmm, which is still our goal.
Scott: Yeah, if I had a basement I might set up something like that.
Scott: But I probably wouldn't play Warhammer or war machine even though I know they're okay.
Scott: I'd probably go for the one of the cheaper ones like Sutton with normal military soldier guys, you know They're like some old war like a Napoleonic war or something.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: All right.
Rym: This one's a long one.
Rym: I'll take this one.
Rym: I purchased a copy of Wario ware for the Wii based on all the hype You guys were spouting prior to its release emphasis added by Rym.
Rym: I would like to point out now this isn't the question that the hype was all pretty.
Rym: everything We said was basically the other Wario ware was great.
Rym: I'm really looking forward to this Wario ware as long as it's the same as that previous Wario ware.
Rym: It's gonna be great.
Scott: Yeah, anyway pretty much what we said.
Rym: Will you give me a refund for my wasted money?
Rym: No you're the dumbass.
Rym: you listen to us and didn't do any other research and bought the game before you heard us review it because we Reviewed it like the day after it came out saying how shitty it was.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, come on He's gonna do everything we tell you to that.
Rym: Well, you should but the thing is you should wait until we review a game before you buy it.
Scott: Yeah, if you're if you're going out and buying products based on what people say who have not used that product yet That's your fault.
Rym: I like Wario ware for the Wii.
Rym: Maybe it has something to do with whom you're playing.
Rym: That that sentence bothers me.
Rym: I'm just gonna skip it.
Rym: Yeah, I've heard from people who have played the prior Wario ware games that this iteration is pretty bad.
Rym: That is a hundred percent, correct?
Rym: I've never played those that know how it compares Wario Where we is a garbage game and it should not be even looked at again.
Scott: No, I mean, I guess it's eager.
Scott: rent It'd be fun for like five minutes only in single-player.
Scott: Yeah, just rent it beat the single-player bring it back.
Scott: However be warned that you can use the game.
Scott: fly the Netflix of video games.
Scott: that'll work.
Rym: be warned However that if you just hold the Wiimote in front of you and kind of shake it you can win 80% of the minigames.
Scott: Yeah, but it won't be enough to actually beat it.
Scott: You'll actually you know, plus it will be less fun if you try that.
Scott: Okay, getting back to the original topic.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I guess these are all the same person even though we don't know who that is What elements does it take to make an enjoyable game in other words?
Scott: Why is XCOM UFO defense a better game than lair or is it not a better game?
Rym: Well, it is a better game.
Scott: I don't know about lair but it is a better game.
Scott: Okay I think for me at least that there are many things that can make a game fun, you know.
Scott: Like for example, I'm playing that Lego Star Wars right now and it's fun because they're amusing things going on.
Rym: But in other ways the game is not so fun or portal which is fun because it's just so slick and so perfectly designed.
Scott: Yeah, but I think the things that make me feel like a video game is fun.
Scott: the thing that you know I enjoy when I'm playing video games is when there are decisions to make or there are tests of my skill And they are or appear to be meaningful.
Scott: You know where I have a choice and that choice feels meaningful.
Scott: or if they're gonna test to see you know Can I do this?
Scott: and it's it's me.
Scott: you know.
Scott: the amount of skill that I have at doing that thing feels like it makes a difference in terms of whether I Achieve or fail and that that is what makes a video game fun when I feel like I am challenged and then I rise to The challenge
Rym: that's pretty much it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Hey Roman Scott Why the hell do you guys think everyone stopped playing pogeyman pogeymenas?
Scott: I believe he means Pokemon because it just after you beat the game and the earthbound part of the game is over It just becomes a World of Warcraft Grinding game pretty much.
Rym: This is probably in reference to the fact that people on our forums were losing their shit over Pokemon and now only one person who has always lost his shit over Pokemon is continuing to lose it.
Rym: Yeah, it's like else has their shit back.
Scott: I never assumed more of Pokemon than it was I had.
Scott: this is the third the most recent Pokemon games the third real Pokemon game I've played.
Rym: I had never played a Pokemon game before and you play it and it's a.
Scott: it's an.
Scott: it's an RPG Almost as good as earthbound and earthbound is a great single-player RPG.
Scott: And then as soon as it's over and there's no more new RPG stuff to do The only thing left to do is level up Pokemon and collect Pokemon, which is not fun Unless you like that sort of thing, which I don't pretty
Rym: much people a lot of people try to make the argument when we talk about how shitty World of Warcraft is that.
Rym: Well, you guys play other games that just as bad.
Rym: do the things.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: And I just have to point out once again that any time someone makes that claim usually by the time they make it we've already Given up or figured out on whatever game that we're talking about and Pokemon is no exception.
Rym: I have not touched Pokemon in like five months.
Rym: I don't think I'm ever gonna even put it back in my DS.
Scott: I might but I can't for I can't.
Scott: I wouldn't plan on it.
Scott: It might just be like a spur-of-the-moment thing.
Rym: if I lost my Pokemon cartridge right now I wouldn't even care.
Scott: Yeah, I wouldn't be too upset.
Rym: I wouldn't be so upset at all.
Scott: All right What do you think is the most fundamental component to obtaining high scores and FPS?
Scott: is tactics precision mouse controlling reflexes?
Scott: Defending attacking fighting the team going solo center.
Rym: I think I can answer them because I'm no slouch.
Rym: I'm real good at FPS.
Rym: I've been playing them for almost as long as they've existed better than most people.
Scott: but you know fatality?
Scott: No, I'm not.
Scott: we're sort of like in that in-between area like where you know Millions of people around the world playing FPS is.
Scott: we're better than most people, you know any random guy.
Scott: we can probably beat them But there are those people who are on like the professional level and we are not on their level.
Rym: I am better than Scott though, you know It's sort of like.
Scott: it's sort of like the guy bought baseball player in town would get crushed in the major league.
Rym: Oh and any old style or twitch FPS?
Rym: You can't pretend that you have even a chance against me as was demonstrated when we tried to play quake 3.
Scott: I could with some Practices.
Rym: Yes with some practices.
Scott: Yeah, you're dying like a few minutes More than that as ice that map was not my.
Rym: you chose that bad.
Rym: I chose what poorly.
Rym: Anyway Pretty much.
Rym: It was 20 minutes of me standing anywhere with a railgun shooting Scott as soon as he spawned.
Rym: Anyway, but you want to know how I got so good at FPS is.
Rym: I've been playing them for over a decade Semi-continuously and that's the only way to get good.
Rym: and furthermore Playing modern FPS is will not make you great at.
Rym: FPS is make you pretty good at.
Rym: FPS is but like Team Fortress 2 Will not give you FPS skills beyond a very low level.
Rym: No, you want to get good really good.
Rym: You have to get a copy of quake to beat the game first off just to get you know The basic skills and then find some people or some bots and play the game without cheating by the way.
Rym: Yes play quake to lithium deathmatch until you are good at it.
Rym: Then play quake 3 until you beat it on the hardest difficulty level and then play that with your friends until you never lose.
Scott: And if you do that, then you're problem is don't just play with your friends because you'll run into a situation where you know Some of our some one friend of ours told a story that he went to his friend's house.
Scott: They were all playing quake 3 right and they were all like, yeah, we're so great.
Scott: This was go Joe, I believe yeah, but they were only playing against each other and they thought they were so great.
Scott: So Scott Johnson sat down and played it.
Scott: just killed them all killed them all killed them all killed them all killed.
Scott: So you have to actually find people at a at the higher level, you know, that will just kill you instantly.
Scott: It's that you can build your skill up to.
Rym: yeah also, you have to figure out ways to play that will maximize skill gaining for example in counter-strike.
Rym: if you want to get really Good at counter-strike in a hurry only play FY maps and play them all the time And if you're dominating a server leave and find a different server that you can't dominate and stay there until you dominate it.
Scott: You need to sort of raise the bar in order to actually jump over it.
Scott: You know if you keep the bar at four feet high and keep trying to jump higher You'll still only be four feet high jumping good plus by playing on those FY maps.
Rym: think about it now It's not.
Rym: you know a minute of Maneuver maneuver maneuver maneuver and then the shootout and then you got to spend all this time between shootouts not learning a lot of skills.
Rym: You have to play just the shootout continuously.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I'm really good at FY maps.
Rym: Yeah, and if you wanted to get really like I think the game that probably made me gave me the most skill over time was playing Action quake - and I have several friends who were agreed.
Rym: that game will give you some Motherfucking skill in a hurry if you get enough people to play it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, the game is hard as ball.
Scott: I think.
Scott: in general the problem is a lot of the twitch FPS's have sort of fallen out of favor and they're mostly old and new FPS's are not that way.
Scott: So it's very hard to get skill in sort of the twitch aiming high speed FPS's with the modern FPS.
Scott: Yeah, but if you get the skill in the old FPS's when you start playing modern news slow ones You're gonna rock.
Rym: I mean think of this when quake 3 came out Everyone was excited about it and all the hardcore people were like, oh man all the mods are moving to quake 3 we're gonna play quake 3. and then everyone started playing quake 3 and All the hardcore people immediately complained about how slow and easy the game was compared to quake 2. it was how big the models were and how easy it was to hit people.
Scott: and Yeah, yeah, if you want just find out whatever game fatality is playing and play that and that way you'll.
Rym: yeah Cuz I don't think that guy would be playing a game with a low cat.
Scott: No, he mostly plays like quake 4 and stuff now, which I heard is pretty twitch.
Scott: So yeah I played it once and it was pretty twitch.
Rym: So Okay, what is the worst game you have ever paid for?
Rym: monkey ball for the Wii.
Scott: monkey ball for the Wii?
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Rym: I've never paid for a worse game.
Scott: Nope, don't think so.
Scott: Okay, have you ever owned and used a Tamagotchi?
Scott: I never owned one.
Scott: I think I might have used one.
Scott: once I got a funny story about one at summer camp.
Scott: one of the counselors in the in the adjacent cabin had a Tamagotchi that was caring for and People would sneak in there and feed it till it died to upset him.
Rym: now That raises an interesting ethical question At what point is that murder and not just nothing?
Scott: When it's a biological organism that you fed until?
Rym: but what if we made an artificial intelligence that was equally complex to a human?
Scott: Intelligence, I don't know.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: That's for another question.
Rym: If money and resources were no object and you were asked to make a video game exactly as you wanted What would it be like now?
Rym: He goes on to say, you know, what platform would be for now?
Rym: you made a really fundamental error in asking this question.
Rym: You know you asked what platform, you know Xbox ps3 we all of them.
Rym: No, no, no, if money and resources are no object one.
Rym: I make my own platform.
Rym: That is exactly what I guess I would make an arcade machine To if money is no object.
Rym: I make perfect VR that and that's my game.
Rym: Yeah, this question takes way too much.
Scott: It does.
Rym: follow-up question if you had to change the games that had mass-market appeal.
Rym: Would you change anything?
Scott: Yes, you're making the false assumption that my perfect game has no mass-market appeal.
Scott: Also, I would also with infinite money any game can have mass-market appeal because I can have infinite marketing.
Rym: Also, if it's perfect VR, I just tack on some sort of VR sex hall.
Scott: Yeah, sex and violence.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: Yeah You go into the fighting room and then you go into the sexing room and then humanity starves to death because no one leaves The VR world, you know, that might be the perfect game.
Scott: is the VR sexing room?
Rym: Aliens come in.
Scott: I just answered the whole thing.
Rym: No because to paraphrase Futurama When Fry is first exposed to the VR internet of the future, he walks into the sex area.
Rym: He walks out five minutes later and says well, I am now bored with sex.
Scott: It's true.
Rym: I Can say one thing?
Rym: Furries and pretty much anyone with a fetish no matter how weird Would pretty much be in heaven at that point probably if you could yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So yeah, that's the game I'd make if I'd infinite money, okay What is the longest in terms of length board game you've ever played?
Rym: I marker it took four hours.
Scott: We're about We're about to play it.
Scott: It's the second time rims played.
Scott: It's the first time I've played it But I think I have played games of Monopoly that were pretty goddamn long.
Rym: there was that one game of Monopoly We played with Ken and Nicole and most of the original FRC.
Scott: I've also played some games of risk that were pretty goddamn and I think Peterson 3 or maybe Sally and also Shogun.
Scott: That was pretty goddamn long.
Rym: Yeah, but not four hours.
Scott: No, I guess we played RPGs for like a day straight So like D&D for a day straight, does that count?
Rym: Yeah in high school every Sunday.
Rym: We used to play this board game, though Yeah, we used to play D&D from like 10 in the morning until like 10 11.
Scott: I mean even now when we play burning wheel on the weekend, it takes more than four hours to play You know, so even die marker.
Scott: take if it took four hours be less than you know Just an RPG.
Rym: it still might be that one game of Monopoly play battle tech that's gone on pretty low God battle.
Rym: that games took eight hours easily
Scott: yeah, but that
Rym: that one game of Monopoly just kept going and going and eventually everyone was bankrupt except Ken and Nicole and Neither one of them would just quit and give up because the other one would say well then I win if you quit and neither one of them could lose because they both had a ton of money and It was basically hours and hours of them playing.
Scott: Monopoly was actually x-men monopoly and they had mutant powers that were kind of stupid.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I forgot all about that.
Scott: Don't play.
Scott: Oh, don't play any monopoly variants.
Scott: Actually.
Scott: I have a monopoly That's like the best one.
Rym: Actually if you want to play Monopoly Play it one more time and play it with the actual rules and I mean read the rule book do what it says.
Scott: Got it.
Scott: If the rule book you have doesn't seem very different from what you think the rules are go online and print out the oldest Monopoly rule book.
Scott: you can find a picture of very simply those rules.
Rym: Here's what matters one.
Rym: if Someone lands on free parking nothing happens to.
Rym: if someone lands on a property and does not buy it It immediately goes up for auction and is sold.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Those two things make Monopoly almost a worthwhile game.
Scott: Yep, but not quite Alright, okay do either of you miss FMV's in PC gaming up they went somewhere.
Scott: Well, I don't know.
Scott: I see lots of FMV's in games all the time.
Scott: However Personally, I'm a fan of the game.
Scott: The reason I'm such a fan of games like half-life 2 and it's it's sequels and all those other you know valve games Is that they sort of you know They have this very cinematic experience where you don't really have these.
Scott: you don't stop the game and watch a video that often You know, I mean a couple times but what you do is add You lock the protagonist in a small room.
Rym: You can't escape all two NPCs blather on for five minutes.
Rym: Yep, which?
Rym: because that's so much different It's not that much different.
Scott: but you know the the plot sort of.
Scott: you know, it happens around you and it does provide a more cinematic experience that you know.
Scott: When you switch to an FMV, you're really taking me out of the zone here And I'm like, I noticed that it's an FMV now.
Rym: I was cool with like the Resident Evil 4 Resident.
Scott: I say it was very good.
Scott: I say that was.
Rym: the problem is every game has now been aping that Poorly have they?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: a lot of new games I've been told cuz I avoid game.
Scott: Resident Evil 4 is the only game I've played like that.
Scott: So I guess if there are other games doing it, they must suck and I'm not playing them.
Rym: I guess it's just Theoretically.
Rym: I like games to have good stories But it bothers me if the only way to present the story is to stop the game and show me a movie because then I might As well just show me all the movies.
Scott: now the game.
Rym: There are two cut times where I'm really really okay with an FMV.
Rym: one if you have a starting FMV and an ending FMV.
Scott: Yeah, like an FMV at the very beginning, you know, even before I push start on the main menu That's fine.
Scott: Alright, that could be cool.
Rym: or like an FMV at the climax of the game like the climax of the plot and everything.
Rym: when now You watch a 10-minute movie and then the game continues right there.
Scott: the one thing I think though that really helps out the way half-life 2 does it even when it traps you there and you know Forces you to.
Rym: you know, I play games with myself Like how far can I jump off of this computer that stuff but wonder if I can kill anything?
Scott: But also is that the FMV is generally they have like this incredible like pre-rendered graphic quality.
Scott: That is so much different from the in-game Like, you know live rendering and it's that also sort of takes you out and in final fantasy 7 was notorious for that.
Scott: Yeah, so I actually like it better when you just keep do it within the game rendering engine, you know And that way it looks the same.
Scott: It doesn't sort of throw me for a loop.
Scott: I know people are crazy about their graphics like OMG.
Scott: Look at them graphics and that FMV, but it's pre-rendered.
Scott: It's not exciting.
Scott: pre-rendered is actually the reason mist looks the way it looks even on shitty old dogs Also barely animated mostly static nothing moves.
Scott: Yeah, and that is the reason that you know graphics and games is ruined all the way today.
Scott: today.
Rym: So, all right, how the hell do you get good at FPS?
Scott: We just answered baby some Ted if we can let it duplicate get in here because we didn't really check him.
Scott: All right next.
Rym: All right, you two come across as incredibly competitive Especially with each other if you ever tried to work together at a board game like Lord of the Rings or a video game Cooperatively.
Rym: well, well, we played the Lord of the Rings game at our way.
Rym: I like that game a lot.
Rym: I am a little game.
Rym: It's a great game.
Rym: I own it.
Rym: the thing that you suck you weren't you didn't even participate in the victory.
Scott: I don't think I've played it enough time.
Rym: So everyone other than Scott was determined to beat that game on the difficult difficulty.
Scott: I had already played it a few times and decided it was crap.
Rym: so we kept playing and kept playing it and I realized the benefit of that game because when we beat it like we got to the end and I think it Luke was the one who had the ring and he did all the checks and we stopped.
Rym: and we'd been playing this game so long and so hard over so many weeks and always failing.
Rym: and We finally did it.
Rym: and we all look around and someone says Did we just win?
Rym: and he picks up the real book.
Rym: He flips through it.
Rym: We look at the board.
Rym: Yeah we just won and we jumped up yelling and screaming and ran around the room for like 10 minutes and High-fiving everyone.
Rym: and there there's a couple there's a hundred two hundred people there and That was worth it.
Scott: Yeah, I generally do like co-op games or you know, people are working together.
Scott: I mean, sometimes we play Advance Wars like two on two or something like that.
Scott: That's that's fun times.
Scott: The only thing is it playing Lego Star Wars recently, you know.
Scott: It's like when Rym will run off the screen and try to trap me or playing River City Ransom and he'll beat me up.
Rym: I point out that Scott says I run off the screen and traffic and usually what it is is we're playing the game and Scott just runs off somewhere and without saying anything because he wants to do some puzzle and he just runs off and then as soon As he hits the edge of the screen, he can't run any further.
Rym: He yells at me who is trying to actually beat the game for not following.
Scott: I'm the leader and you're the follower.
Scott: That is how it works.
Scott: Yeah, no, but co-op games are fun.
Scott: The problem is sometimes if the people don't really work together so much you can sort of get diversions.
Scott: Also, like sometimes they'll play a competitive game and say we're gonna work together And what ends up happening is we get we destroy everyone else and then we end up turning on each other to see who actually Wins.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, I really like games like especially board games that have conditions for shared victory.
Scott: Yeah, that's where it's good times.
Rym: I think Illuminati did that really well.
Scott: Yeah, because you can trick someone into thinking you're gonna give him a shared victory and then dick him.
Rym: But also at the same time more than one.
Rym: Scott and I have both just said You know what fuck everybody and just one Illuminati by just totally ganging up on it.
Scott: Yeah, cuz like we just say in there you look at the board and you say hey Rym You know, we could get a shared victory if we do this.
Scott: No one can stop us.
Scott: Okay, dink.
Scott: We got it.
Scott: And co-op games are fun like co-op doom.
Rym: good time playing doom.
Rym: co-op is great and also crystal chronicles with three other people.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: But still seriously one of the best gaming experiences of my life.
Scott: All right With all these conventions you talk about as a little surprised to see you hadn't talked about quake con.
Scott: Unless you haven't heard of it then it's understandable.
Scott: Well, I know about quake con.
Scott: It's in Texas, right?
Scott: And did they play quake?
Rym: What do you think about quake con?
Rym: Have you ever considered going?
Scott: I never really considered going so much.
Scott: I mean, I like FPS is but I don't like enough.
Scott: an FPS is enough to go.
Rym: the farthest I've ever gone for a convention was Chicago for anime central, which is a pretty big anime con or Raleigh for an anime con where I was staff.
Rym: Yep, and beyond that we're going to PAX.
Scott: I was a guest at quake con and they paid for my badge and they paid for my plane in my hotel.
Rym: I would go yeah, I guess for a gaming con.
Rym: There's a million gaming cons near me So I'm not gonna go far even for a prestigious or big one unless it's Essen.
Scott: Yeah, I'm mostly gonna go to like, you know, I mostly go to board gaming and tabletop role-playing game cons You know because that's where you really play with other people for video games, you know, we have internet.
Scott: I can play quake in my house.
Scott: going somewhere to play quake is sort of outdated, you know.
Rym: I mean I used to go to land parties, especially in high school before there were Lands and then that kind of died in college when I lived on a land.
Scott: Yeah, so it's sort of like.
Scott: what's the purpose?
Scott: You know, I like good to go to a gaming concert tabletop and role-playing action where I need other people in the room with me.
Rym: You know, all right.
Rym: What games would you murder each other for to have on the virtual console?
Scott: I don't think I'd murder anyone for any game Way to kill the spirit of that question.
Scott: Maybe if it was the true virtual reality sex.
Scott: Oh then I would murder somebody.
Rym: I guess just what games should be on the virtual console that aren't.
Scott: oh I know a game I would murder you for to be on the virtual console, huh?
Scott: Push a button and two rims pop out.
Scott: that way I you know I'd kill you and then there would be two and then I'd be like, hey actually maybe you could have that threesome You've always wanted.
Scott: Oh, but it would be.
Rym: does the week does the we excite you at all?
Rym: If so, what the fuck for?
Rym: well my we excites me on a daily basis, but that's really none of your business.
Rym: Oh I saw that question a minute ago and I've been staring at it the whole time Just waiting to say that the we only excites me in it.
Rym: the unfulfilled potential, but I don't really get excited about it I think is Part of this question was written back when we were still in the weed route and now we got Mario Galaxy coming out today.
Scott: Yeah, now everyone knows the day we recorded this.
Rym: no I'm excited about these games and I'm excited about eventually games using the DS and I Think a lot's gonna come to the Wii.
Rym: I don't think the Wii is gonna die anytime soon.
Rym: I think we're gonna have some great stuff for it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Oh What would it take for you to buy a 360 PS 3 besides more free time?
Rym: Well more free time a ps3 There's almost nothing because I can't imagine a game that would come out for the ps3 That would warrant the cost that wouldn't also come out for the 360.
Scott: Yeah, I mean for me for that right now.
Scott: if I look at the ps3 There are some games on there that I might want to play but if I look at the price I say no.
Scott: So in order for me to buy a ps3 I'd literally have to be so incredibly rich and have so much free time that I played all the other games.
Scott: I want to play more than those games and still want to play more games.
Scott: The 360.
Rym: if I had more free time if I didn't if I was in a podcaster, we'd probably have two 360s Yeah, probably and an HDTV cuz that's two HDTV.
Rym: so we could play against each other Probably seriously.
Rym: That's not a joke.
Rym: We would probably seriously each have a 360 and a computer in our bedrooms and Yeah, the 360 is fucking awesome.
Rym: It's pretty good almost entirely because of Xbox Live.
Scott: I mean right now.
Scott: I mean look at me right now.
Scott: I just I have more video games than I have time to play.
Rym: I just bought a thousand dollar office chair.
Scott: every every minute of the day that I want to play a video game.
Scott: I have a video game available more than one.
Scott: that design it fills my desire.
Scott: So why in the world would I buy another video game until I beat one?
Scott: I've got and thus, you know that that's pretty much how it goes It's barely even spend money on gaming anymore.
Rym: because I mean, what am I gonna buy now?
Rym: I'm buying a go board because I've exhausted almost the entirety of German board gaming.
Rym: Yep That's it.
Scott: All right Has a video game made you cry scream?
Scott: We talked about this every yes didn't as a video gamer made you cry scream.
Scott: We just talked about sad video go sad.
Rym: How about scream?
Rym: because I've had a few games.
Rym: startle me.
Scott: the end of Zelda 1 when I was a kid was fucking scary.
Scott: Yeah Doo doo doo doo doo
Rym: when I actually when I saw the hammer doo doo when I was playing Zelda 2 and I saw the hammer for the first time and I cast the jump spell and I jumped over that guy because I couldn't fight him because I wasn't that good at that game and I had one life left and almost no health.
Rym: and I went and I was about to get the hammer and I had it and then I Grabbed it and the standard going dah, dah, dah, dah, and I went yes and then one of those maces came flying over and hit me and I died and I went No, and then I yanked on the controller because I was mad and that unplugged the power and I went And my mom came in thinking I cut my finger off or something
Scott: also in Zelda 2 Yeah, that that other island as soon as you get the raft and go across the ocean.
Scott: It's scary over there real scary.
Rym: Also, I Screamed once when someone was playing.
Rym: I forget what one of those, you know Resident Evil kind of games it was but I was watching someone else play it and I wasn't really paying attention.
Scott: and then something jumped out and I went ah Yeah, eternal darkness a few times jumped out at you and it's sort of.
Scott: it's not like a cry or a scream But it's like boo, you know surprise and I go,
Rym: ah, yeah surprise I was frightened and so was Scott for a few seconds by one of the thing the insanity things that did near the end of The game just that one.
Scott: Yeah Do you really throw controllers slash mice in anger?
Scott: Well when I was a kid, I'd throw the NES controller around.
Rym: I'd ever see.
Rym: every kid had a different mode of dealing with their video game.
Rym: frustration the video game nerd Watching him do stuff.
Rym: That's exactly it.
Rym: That feeling was expressed in different ways by different kids some of my friends through him.
Rym: Some of my friends would pull on him thus pulling the Nintendo out, which I only did once or twice.
Rym: I was the kind of kid who had squeezed the controller as hard as I could.
Scott: just Yep Yeah, but not anymore.
Scott: now I'd really video games don't anger me so much cuz I just if I games is gonna anger me.
Scott: I just stopped playing.
Rym: that's cuz you don't?
Scott: when I was a kid I paid $50 to that game.
Scott: That was the only game I had and I had too much free time and not enough game.
Rym: Also when I was a kid, I wasn't gonna let the video game beat me.
Rym: Oh, hey video game No way was gonna be playing Mario 3 get near the end of the game I would die like nine times in a row on one world in world 7 one level in world 7. and You know the seventh or eighth time you die the ninth time you die.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: Hmm in Smash Brothers Melee What characters do you play Falco?
Scott: I play as Samus mostly but I also go with dr.
Scott: Mario.
Scott: I'm pretty good with dr Mario.
Scott: I pretty much also I you.
Scott: I tend to use all the characters mostly.
Scott: I mean, there's some.
Scott: I don't use it all like.
Scott: I don't really use Captain Falcon really, but you know I spread it around.
Scott: I spread the love even though most of the love goes to Samus and dr.
Scott: Mario.
Rym: Pretty much it's like I'll go Falco Falco Falco kind of like how in Soul Calibur - I'll go Volto Volto Volto and Soul Calibur.
Scott: I am Siegfried slash nightmare 100% of the time see but then I get bored with that or if I'm winning I never get bored with that.
Rym: So I always switch it up for a while and then I swear I always switch back to Falco.
Rym: It's like Falco Falco Falco princess peach Pikachu Falco.
Scott: Mmm.
Rym: Sometimes I got a picture that Pikachu Everyone is because she's a very bitchy character Yeah, and the new one.
Scott: what characters you're looking forward to playing as well?
Scott: I'm gonna play as all of them King today day King today day today.
Scott: They're pretty hot.
Scott: Yeah You know Samus, dr.
Rym: Mario assuming it's a decent conversion what tabletop RPG board game card game miniatures game Would you like to see as a video or computer game?
Rym: This is all of them.
Scott: Yeah, any any board game or any board game not RPG or tabletop game?
Scott: But a board game card game or miniatures game can be a computer game and that will always make it better because well It won't always make it a hundred percent better
Rym: But it will
Scott: always allow you to play that game without dealing with the setup or dealing with the rules Administration and it'll help you learn the game at the very least.
Scott: So as far as I'm concerned every Bored miniatures and card game should also be have a video game form because that can only be good.
Rym: It cannot be bad now in terms of role-playing games.
Rym: I've thought about this a lot and now I suddenly realize we should.
Rym: this would be a decent programming project We should try to work on because this would be so great especially at least for those of us who will have laptops playing burning Wheel.
Rym: Yep, but a companion system to a tabletop rope I mean one.
Scott: a companion system is one thing but like they're trying at D&D now with their fourth edition is trying to basically make It so you can play D&D online.
Rym: I can see a way to play burning wheel online if everyone had video chat because my office has this thing where like all the Offices have constant like video chat and audio chat.
Rym: Yep, and that sort of thing coupled with a network companion system companion cube that could Deal with all the die rolls centrally and just you know Keep track of all your crap for you.
Rym: and like you're doing a dual wits.
Rym: it does all the picking you can do all the picking and it it like iterates through all the things and does all the Rolling for you and maybe like the DM could approve and disprove afford.
Scott: Yeah, you just choose your you know, you just choose your action.
Scott: then it goes poop and it says what happens.
Rym: You know anything like that.
Rym: to let people who live far apart play a game like burning wheel online be awesome Super awesome.
Rym: and now I feel like you me and Alex should make a companion system for burning wheel not for the whole system But just to track a character as and I'm sitting there with my laptop with my character sheet in the game.
Scott: I definitely like having compute, you know laptops as a companion system.
Scott: You're still playing a tabletop game Maybe even still rolling real dice, but being able to not have a piece of paper, but use your laptop.
Scott: That's good stuff.
Rym: No, just in burning wheel very specifically every time I test a skill I just tell it how many dice I rolled and it takes care of all the tracking every other tracking of the advancement.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, that's good stuff too.
Rym: We could make that pretty handily.
Rym: Yeah, we probably should.
Scott: that's good stuff.
Rym: Let's do it.
Rym: Yeah, maybe you want to.
Scott: I don't know Stuff to do.
Scott: first assuming the same what video or computer game would you like to see a material equivalent to?
Rym: They've already made a railroad tycoon as a board game, which is fine.
Rym: I'd like that.
Rym: Yep Obviously, I want to see portal the board game.
Scott: Yeah, you know While it goes really well from board game to video game It doesn't really go so well in the other direction so much.
Scott: I mean like Half-Life 2 the board game.
Scott: They may doom the board game.
Scott: kind of crap.
Scott: world will craft the board Do.
Rym: the board game is just one of those hero quest type game Yeah, which are fun until like we played hero quest again not too long ago with Alex.
Scott: I think what it is is when you take a board game and turn it into a computer game You're basically it's the exact same game just in a different format, you know.
Scott: But saying converting a like.
Scott: when they convert video games to be board games.
Scott: It's actually a completely different game Just happens at the same name.
Rym: going back board game turned into a video game specifically Twilight struggle, especially if you change the rules to take advantage like if it were a well-done Computer game that were otherwise a lot like Twilight struggle.
Rym: They'd be awesome.
Scott: yeah be good cuz.
Rym: Twilight struggle suffers primarily from the fact that it's uh, a Board game and I have to twiddle all the time are also probably.
Scott: But yeah video games into board games isn't the greatest because it's really a different game entirely.
Scott: doom The board game is not the same as doing the video game, but you could take say settlers of Catan you put it on the computer.
Scott: It's unchanged.
Rym: So obviously you got to adapt it.
Rym: make it first-person.
Scott: Yep, but I mean yet video game to board game.
Scott: Not good.
Rym: What is your opinion of the new art style story direction of Advance Wars DS 2?
Rym: Do you like the fact that they dropped all the CEOs for new ones?
Scott: I don't really care.
Rym: Yes one reason alone I've transcended Advance Wars.
Rym: I'm done with it.
Rym: The game is solved.
Rym: It's not that hard.
Rym: I beat Advance Wars 1 & 2 with all S's on normal and advanced campaign.
Rym: I beat everything in the DS except all the war rooms that were already in Advance Wars 2 because I didn't want to do them Again, I went every time the game and all the new CEOs didn't really add anything to the game in terms of strategy Because they were all effectively either Brokenly powerful or worse than just great or Hawk.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It was just They.
Rym: they couldn't extend the game other than making more maps Unless they completely redid the game because the CEOs were no longer a paper-rock-scissors.
Scott: You know all we know about the game so far is from the screenshots that I've seen but it mostly seems like a sort of Graphical style revamp more than a gameplay revamp.
Rym: if they hadn't gotten.
Scott: But there's a few more like motorcycles and stuff.
Rym: if they hadn't gotten rid of the old CEOs They would have had to leave grid in and unless they gimped him or something Which would have made all the fans of Advance Wars except me bitch and moan.
Rym: Then the game would have still been kind of a little tiny bit broken.
Scott: Yeah, it'll.
Scott: it'll depend on what the the powers of all these new CEOs are which are yet to be revealed.
Rym: What would you have to say is your personal weirdest video game moment, I have an easy answer to that one All right, you don't have anything.
Scott: not really weird moments Playing counter-strike and like weird graphical glitches or somewhat and doing I don't know.
Rym: there was one time I was playing Castlevania 2 a game that unnerved me as a kid.
Scott: Anyway, I have a moment.
Scott: Okay, so you can go.
Rym: All right, so I'm playing Castlevania 2 and I was always fascinated.
Rym: I was trying to get to areas that Seem mysterious that I couldn't get to and I was just I would go around that game throwing holy water everywhere and looking and one time the game kind of glitch and I ended up.
Rym: it was in like the third or fourth mansion and There's like water in the ceiling like you can see water above the highest place you could get to and I ended up glitching and stuff and I end up getting up there and Then there was a glitchy area above that and it was full of nothing But those hanging dead skeleton bodies and they were all moving up and down Uh-huh, and as a kid I was up there walking around and it was just really weird and it really creeped me out and I couldn't get out and I Eventually turned the game off kind of a nerves.
Scott: Mm-hmm One time I was playing Megaman 2 and I remember I was a little kid I think a babysitter was over or something and I was fighting bubble man fight bubble man.
Scott: And then I jump up and the door, you know the little doors that go into bubble man.
Scott: So, you know like the Megaman boss doors it opened and I exited bubble man's room But the bubble man music was still playing and I was like what the fuck What the fuck.
Scott: that door is not supposed to go that way.
Scott: It's a one-way door Yeah.
Scott: And then I go back it opens again and it lets me back into bubble man's room and I guess I'm still fighting him Kinda, but it's super glitched out and there's like platforms I can't see and everything's fucked up and I don't know what the hell was going on.
Scott: and then I just sort of did everything I could do in that room with my little NES controller just playing around Figuring out what the hell this glitch was going.
Scott: Whoa until I had to go to bed.
Rym: There was one time too.
Rym: I was playing Metal Gear and I went.
Rym: I was going into the room with the supercomputer but I ran back like I ran back out the door by accident and I went back in and The game glitched.
Rym: and I just skipped the supercomputer and I was in the room with big boss.
Rym: Oh, yeah spoilers, but Spoilers for Metal Gear Metal Gear for the NES.
Rym: Yeah, you know what big boss.
Rym: He's trying to murder you the whole time.
Rym: He's actually the bad guy and you can only kill him with rockets.
Scott: All right What is more annoying an impossibly hard game or a stupidly easy one?
Scott: Neither of them are annoying cuz I just stopped playing either one.
Rym: I don't know a stupidly hard game Or an impossibly hard game I would beat my head against to try to become good as a kid.
Rym: It depends on how.
Scott: okay.
Scott: Here's the thing right.
Scott: if it's stupidly hard in a way that I is just you know If it's stupidly hard, right then I wouldn't even try.
Scott: I'd be like fuck.
Scott: this is just stupid, right?
Scott: like but if it was actually a Challenge like a challenge that was.
Scott: that meant that my skill or my figuring out skills were low.
Scott: as you know If I actually felt that I was inadequate and I was not Succeeding where others have succeeded and it was my fault that I was not succeeding then I would keep beating my head against it.
Scott: You know, but if it's just stupidly easy, I just like yawn and I stopped playing, you know I guess if it has to be so impossibly hard Well, if it's impossible, then I just wouldn't play it either.
Rym: the difficulty of this game is legendary.
Scott: Yeah It has to be.
Scott: the only time that a game can be annoying to me is if it's not Impossibly or stupidly hard.
Scott: is just heart is just above what I can do and I have to build up to it and all those Hundreds of times I fail until my skill grows will be frustrating.
Rym: maybe Alright, we're at it.
Rym: This is the end.
Rym: This is the last question.
Rym: Oh, no Do you think big FPO is a dumb question?
Rym: Oh, well, we can do a little bit of history here.
Rym: Do you think big FPS games can still be distributed using the share where model that made doom so popular?
Scott: Uh-huh share where is dead?
Rym: Well share where is stupid share?
Rym: where is dead share?
Rym: where has been dead for over a decade?
Rym: Some people still make it but it's stupid share where is not a viable business model.
Rym: No one cares about it.
Rym: It's a crap idea at best.
Rym: There are demos now and you know what the demo for bio shock did really well and a lot of people probably bought bio shock Because of that demo.
Rym: yeah a demo is not shareware.
Scott: back in the day the shareware was basically All right.
Scott: We'll give you the game most of it share where an annoying message on it And if you pay us money, we'll give you the rest of the game.
Rym: share where only existed because there wasn't an easy ubiquitous way to distribute software.
Rym: there was no internet like there is now.
Rym: so People would sell discs of shareware and then if you liked it You could mail for the full game and things.
Rym: and I paid $5 for a share where of doom won Mm-hmm, and then I pirated the wads to get real doom from a BBS that I dialed into pretty much share What was something that existed before the days of the CD ROM you see?
Scott: Because you would get share where on floppy disk for free and then if you liked it You would send away to get the rest of the game on a bunch of floppy disks or you would dial into a BBS and pirated Or that.
Scott: but when once the CD ROM came around, you know people could just buy CD ROM with the whole game on it at CompUSA and that was pretty much like all right.
Scott: You know share where I started to go downhill and then the internet just put the final nail on the coffin.
Scott: Everyone could download everything.
Scott: also, you know, it's either freeware or open source or proprietary.
Scott: Those are pretty much the three ways.
Scott: also any no matter whether which one of the three it is.
Scott: a demo is probably a good Idea.
Rym: also while share where was just the method used when doom came out?
Rym: I don't think share where had anything to do with doom being successful was successful because it was the first real FPS.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much straight up.
Rym: It was also Pretty 3d.
Rym: I mean it was actually kind of 3d.
Rym: It was a 3d game.
Scott: Wolfenstein 3d was kind of 3d but less much less.
Scott: It's woven snake one was the one that was really 3d.
Scott: first.
Rym: The thing is quick.
Scott: one was the worst game than but even quake one didn't let you aim up and down.
Scott: So really it was quake - that was the first real 3d all the way.
Rym: Well, what I would say is that doom - well doom itself was the first real FPS quake - was the first Modern FPS.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's about right.
Rym: All right, if you like this I suggest you go back to.
Rym: I think October 16th was when we did the first questions week Episode for this where we answer another hours worth of these vidya game board game role-playing game questions And now we're gonna go eat dinner and now we're gonna go cook some chili and play die ma.
Scott: Yeah, it's day marker.
Scott: Ma you suck.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week Covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row.
Scott: crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.