Rym: It's Wednesday May 16th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we talk a bit about ghost in the shell standalone complex first and second gig.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: We're running a little late tonight mostly due to the fact that there was a sudden and very intense thunderstorm Which in a very freak occurrence because this almost never happens here the trains were delayed a little bit.
Scott: Yeah, it seems like there was some stuff that fell onto the tracks.
Scott: So they closed all the tracks, but one.
Scott: so you know there's trains going north trains going south.
Scott: They have to switch the trains onto the track that you know is okay, and then they let one train Go south and then when no trains going north can do anything and they had to stop all these trains.
Scott: And I sat in Ossining for like a half hour around.
Rym: yeah luckily I was out of the train and I sat at Croton Harman in a very comfortable train station for a half hour.
Scott: I sat in a train, and I got tired.
Scott: I took a little nap and stopped playing my phone.
Rym: now the best part was I didn't really care because I have my dragon book That I've been reading that Emily gave me and I was rather enjoying it.
Rym: So I just sat down and kept reading.
Rym: But you could tell
Scott: people
Rym: who commute often or commute into the city on a regular basis or who are in generally
Scott: cool
Rym: Affairs people who can deal with difficulty as Opposed to the people who can't because half the people who were sitting around waiting We're just sitting around waiting reading their papers whatever calling people like hey Can you pick me up in Croton Harman whatever?
Rym: But the other half of the people were either complaining loudly a train people who are just saying What do you want me to do?
Rym: or sitting there not complaining but going?
Scott: I just watch every five minutes.
Rym: Yeah, I'm just huffing and puffing and generally annoying me.
Scott: Yep, those people can go.
Scott: Well, they can go do something.
Rym: Yeah now the funny thing is we were only actually delayed a half hour.
Rym: No big deal, but we had to get groceries tonight.
Rym: Also.
Rym: No big deal, so we think all right Let's go to that good sushi place right next to the grocery store Get some quick sushi rolls and then get.
Rym: take care of our business.
Rym: come home do the show go to bed.
Scott: Yeah, that'll save us some time.
Scott: No cooking.
Scott: We'll just get some sushi rolls while we're here.
Rym: well sadly I guess sadly for us not for the sushi place.
Rym: It was really crowded and it took forever for us to get our sushi.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't think it would take that long.
Scott: I thought I would sit down at the little thing and I would say give me one of those and one of those and the Guy would go And I would eat and then walk out, but that was not to be yep.
Rym: And then we took forever grocery shopping and Scott needed a sponge for some reason as my other sponge died.
Scott: So I bought a new one.
Rym: yeah, yeah, so now it's 10, and we're just starting the show And I'm already kind of tired.
Rym: I'm real tired So I will see where this goes.
Scott: yeah, all right.
Scott: There's not too much anime Comic news this week.
Scott: I mean there were these Eagle awards which are this comic awards that aren't as important as the Eisner awards And they were handed out.
Scott: you can just go look online and see who won and determine if you agree or not whatever.
Rym: Wow that was the laziest ass news I've ever heard.
Scott: no no no no that's not my news.
Scott: That's like a sub news.
Scott: That's why it's not the main news.
Rym: You didn't actually say anything I know.
Scott: I just wanted to let people know the Eagle Awards exist, and they were just awarded uh-huh.
Scott: Anyway, my real news is that last week, or was it two weeks ago May 5th, so it was 11 days ago It's a week and a half ago was free comic book day.
Scott: And if you were awesome you went and got free comic books.
Scott: And if you're not awesome or perhaps unlucky you did not get free comic books.
Rym: granted Not every store or comic book place has free comic book day Which we used to complain about until we realized well?
Rym: I guess learned that it cost the stores money to have free comic book.
Scott: yeah But when you go to a comic book store And they have free comp books they have to pay like 25 cents for each issue that they get there.
Scott: So when they have limits like two per person or when they don't carry every single one of the free comic books that are you?
Scott: Know on the list on the website.
Scott: don't blame the store heck.
Scott: if the store doesn't have any free comp books Don't blame them because I mean
Rym: if anything free comic book day is almost like this Situation where the people who make the comic books and the publishers are almost extorting the comic book stores saying hey in Order to make our product sell better in your stores We're going to charge you money to basically pay for our promotion.
Scott: Yeah, I don't want to get into that rant again But it seems like a large one of the.
Scott: the problem of the comic book industry in American can be summed up in that the Publishers have put all the onus onto the retailers for responsibility of sales and the retailers are not up to the challenge.
Scott: Regardless last year we did a whole episode on the free comp books and that we got and I don't think that's necessary this year Because most of them were a yep in fact.
Rym: I read about half of them, and I was so unimpressed I honestly just gave up.
Scott: Yeah As far as I'm concerned if you're gonna read any of the free comp books from free comic book day The only ones really worth reading are the Mickey Mouse one which is awesome because well Mickey Mouse is awesome and the spider-man Which is surprisingly awesome?
Rym: I didn't read that one yet yet.
Scott: the thing about the spider-man one that you got to understand is written by Dan slot who I?
Scott: Never heard of this guy and then someone started pimping the fact that he wrote this miniseries about the thing you know the thing for Fantastic Four.
Scott: so I bought the trade of that miniseries, and it was so funny like it wasn't a serious superhero comic or whatever.
Scott: It was just completely hilarious.
Scott: so he wrote this spider-man, and I'm beginning to think that Dan slot is the Possibly one of the less than five people living who can write an enjoyable superhero comic an underwear perfect comic.
Scott: That is funny and not crap.
Scott: so if you see a comic book written by Dan slot Easy, I think he works for Marvel, so you're not probably not gonna.
Scott: See me Dan slot DC comics.
Scott: You should buy it.
Scott: I'm gonna pretty much buy anything with his name on it until he proves that I shouldn't.
Rym: yeah I. I would just like to point out the one that stood out as being particularly crap.
Rym: Oh The transformers won the transformers one.
Rym: one was well Archie DC one.
Rym: see Archie I don't expect anything from.
Rym: I really don't care about Archie.
Rym: But I read the transformers one because I kind of like transformers And I figure all right.
Rym: There's the movie coming out and everything this might be cool.
Scott: Yeah, the transformers come because a movie prequel.
Rym: It's so lame and poorly written and poorly executed and just it's everything I hate in a comic book.
Rym: It's trying to take itself seriously But yet at the same time the premise is pretty weak and the characters Okay, if the movie is gonna be like this.
Scott: I don't think I want to go see it now.
Rym: I really have almost no hope for the movie.
Scott: my only hope for the movie was that hey It's gonna be pretty cool to see Transforming action on screen except.
Rym: It's not cuz you know what.
Rym: it's just gonna be the same CG We see all the time.
Rym: We're just gonna happen to have some cachet from our childhood.
Scott: Yeah this I just want to point out that this kind of comic this transformers comic is a lot of Independent comic publishers in America like the Battlestar Galactica comic is the same deal.
Scott: What they're doing is in order to get people to notice them because you know they're not Marvel or DC's.
Scott: and who buys their comics?
Scott: Not many people.
Scott: they go and they license properties like Battlestar Galactica.
Scott: Oh, it's for firefly or firefly or something like that.
Scott: They get a licensed property and that way they can put their comic on the shelf.
Scott: and even if people go who the hell is This publisher?
Scott: they say ooh Transformers and they'll buy it anyway, and that's the way that these small comic publishers can get sales.
Scott: the problem is They don't back it up by writing a good comic.
Scott: They just say hey, you know it's transformers.
Scott: It'll sell to whoever likes transformers and no one else.
Scott: I mean matter how good we write.
Rym: the firefly comic sold really well the prequel to the movie But the comic was garbage and had not nothing.
Rym: that made firefly good was in it Yeah And the Battlestar Galactica free comic book day was garbage And it was also drawn in that muscly big-breasted women's style that I hate so much.
Scott: The only other comic that I think is worth mentioning is the Wolfman one.
Scott: now the thing about the Wolfman one is it's written By Robert Kirkman and Robert Kirkman is sort of this strange comic writer.
Scott: He's written a few things and it seems like sometimes you write something, and I love it.
Scott: It's awesome.
Scott: sometimes you write something and it's crap.
Scott: like.
Scott: he wrote the mark the recently Canceled Marvel team-up series which is awesome, and he writes walking dead which is awesome Which is the like the current number one zombie comic that keeps selling more and more copies every single month.
Scott: You should read walking dead.
Scott: if you're not reading walking dead.
Scott: You're a fool.
Scott: But he also writes invincible Which is a kind of crappy generic superhero comic for image this kind of bleh, and he wrote this wolf man Which is bleh.
Rym: Yeah, it was just.
Rym: I hate to use a word like this.
Rym: It's kind of like calling something pretentious on the internet, but I found wolf man to be very pedestrian.
Scott: Wolfman was indeed quite pedestrian.
Scott: Yes, so pre comic book day, they're free.
Scott: so who gives a shit?
Scott: you might as well get him.
Scott: But if you're thinking about you know purchasing any comics based upon.
Scott: You know the free ones I recommend purchasing all Mickey Mouse comics and all Dan slot comics.
Rym: So we haven't had a lot of convention news lately even though there has been a lot of convention news.
Scott: Well, you know why?
Scott: because unlike last year where we had a convention in June conventions in July convention in August.
Scott: this year We have nothing in June.
Scott: nothing in August.
Scott: three conventions in July.
Rym: Yeah one two three at least three.
Scott: If we were going to the San Diego comic-con it would be one two three four God.
Rym: and when?
Rym: his packs?
Rym: luckily.
Scott: well I guess I think the first week in August.
Scott: I'm not sure let me.
Rym: sadly we're not going to pack.
Scott: Yeah, we vowed we would we vowed we would go to packs, and we vowed incorrectly.
Scott: we were shit talkers.
Scott: someday It's actually gonna be August 24th.
Rym: Oh, I guess we could go through 2607.
Scott: Oh wow if you go to the packs website, which is penny arcade expo calm.
Scott: There's a countdown to packs There's a live clock ticking down, and I gotta say I really like anime conventions.
Rym: I mean I've been going to Otakon for a long fucking time.
Scott: God is this gonna be Otakon?
Rym: six five Yeah, five or six for us.
Rym: I mean so many?
Rym: okay I mean I went to gaming con since I was a little kid, but anime cons I never really went to him until when he were at RIT And I suddenly went to a whole bunch and I realized that I liked them.
Rym: I liked them a lot, and I love going to Otakon.
Rym: I love going to Katsucon.
Rym: I love all these anime cons, but oh with one exception Never has one of these cons said.
Rym: by the way We're getting so and so musical act or so and so guest and I said anything other than oh cool I mean when Otakon got Laru ku I was like oh shit Wow.
Rym: but other than that I like the cons, but I never get excited about the guests.
Scott: A couple times I might be excited about a guest like when Otakon Almost had the penny arcade guys, and then they copped out or when they had mr.
Rym: Try gun.
Scott: Oh, yeah, when they're the try gun guy that was pretty damn cool You know, but that's mostly because I had never really been to Otakon before.
Scott: so what did I know?
Rym: yeah?
Rym: But even then like the musical acts I never really care about cuz.
Scott: I mean I like the music bar was I was all about that.
Rym: TMR was awesome But I wasn't like.
Rym: I freaked out.
Scott: I didn't freak out, but I was pretty excited.
Rym: But when it comes to packs they have without fail as long as packs has existed Always had musical acts to where I would have paid quite a bit of money to see them.
Scott: Well, I think it's cuz.
Rym: they have some of the same musical acts every year Yeah, but they're musical acts that I really would like to say.
Scott: You know they get your mini bosses and your MC front the lots and your MC Chris's.
Rym: and yeah Well, I've seen MC Chris.
Rym: Yeah, at least I've seen one down.
Scott: Yeah, and they this year they have frickin What's the name?
Scott: freeze pop.
Scott: you know you might know them from Guitar Hero, you know God it's a good thing.
Rym: We don't have Guitar Heroes.
Rym: Yeah We might just have to take a week hiatus whenever we get it man.
Scott: I can see this gonna be crazy Oh god.
Scott: I want to go to pack.
Scott: so bad.
Scott: I feel bad that I've missed all the past.
Scott: packs is like I was there at those concerts in spirit But at the same time I missed out on those concerts, and I can never go experience them again.
Rym: I mean packs.
Rym: We'll have to do a show about packs before we even go to it.
Rym: before we go to it.
Scott: what we expect from packs?
Scott: We go to packs we come back.
Scott: how we were disappointed at packs did not live up to our fantasy.
Scott: Dissipation is always better than the reality.
Rym: people remember that Sometimes I've had a few cases where the opposite was true very few.
Rym: the first anime central I went to was the exact opposite.
Rym: my expectation was mighty low and what that con actually was was one of my greatest con Experiences ever.
Rym: Yeah, but I digress way back.
Rym: We got a hint ahead of time that you know Otakon's guess we're gonna be say you and they were gonna be big name say you and We just didn't get around to talking about it a lot.
Rym: and then they announced the say you And I didn't recognize the names too much so I didn't really pay attention to it.
Rym: and on a lark I was looking at the site and I saw that one of the guest is Tomokazu Seki a voice actor and I saw that the list of things he has done is very long.
Rym: and Then I noticed that he's in initial D and he's in eska flown a and he's in this giant list of anime.
Rym: that Reminded me very much of another certain voice actors list and I thought for a second Oh shit Is this the man that guy whose name I always forget my second favorite voice actor in the world the guy who plays?
Rym: Takahashi Ryosuke in initial D who plays every suave cool guy in every anime ever.
Rym: No, that man is Takahito Koyasu.
Rym: But Tomokazu Seki is none other than the voice of Takahashi Keisuke Ryosuke's brother Oh snaps and he's a voice actor of equal caliber.
Rym: and just as The former guy plays all those cool suave hip to the ladies be shown in characters.
Rym: This guy plays the punk kind of not necessarily young kids, but Punk spiky haired prickly character.
Scott: Yeah, all the blonde spiky haired guys, like he plays Nobu and Nana.
Scott: Yeah, and he plays Isaac in Gundam C.
Rym: Yeah, and while Vaughn isn't a while Vaughn isn't blonde.
Rym: He's definitely spiky haired and prickly Yep.
Scott: So I think that if you had both of these guys together at one Convention like the world would implode at the double combination of voice acting awesomeness.
Rym: It's amazing how the more I pay attention to voice actors I think back to characters that I thought were voice acted really well and I start to notice that all the characters I liked were all done by a relatively small number of people.
Scott: Yeah, there's only like five less than ten people out there who do all the awesome voice acting most of it.
Scott: Anyway, at least in anime.
Rym: Well in anime in Japan.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Yes, cuz if we're talking about English voice acting I guess you're assuming that there's good voice acting.
Scott: I hope no voice actors listening.
Scott: They're gonna be like, oh that was cold.
Rym: You know what it should be cold.
Rym: granted I don't actually blame them because as Emily pointed out we were talking about this one day and She kind of I mean, we don't obviously know how they do it.
Rym: But she said that we could probably blame the ADR people a lot more than the actual actors.
Scott: Yeah We could probably blame the ADR people a lot more than the actors and also it seems that there are depending on which Studio is hired to do the dubbing like the expensive and fancy dubbing studios Like there's a few of them out there that seem to always do a good job.
Scott: You know the people who do the ghost in the shell and the cowboy bebop and all that's like the same.
Scott: Say that's that one studio doing all those good ones.
Scott: Why don't they do everything else?
Scott: Because they cost a lot of money and they actually take their time to do a good job instead of doing a rush job to Get it done.
Rym: God I mean while with the whole anime industry people always talk about we want to pay less to get more I would actually pay more to get actual good dubs If everything was done was a dub.
Scott: if you made a dub that I could prefer to the subs You know like the cowboy bebop dub Which I prefer to the sub or I would pay five bucks more per disc to get a dub that I preferred to the subs.
Scott: It's gonna be.
Scott: I could not have to pay so much attention when I watch it.
Rym: Yep I mean you can't play Pokemon while you're watching a fan sub.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: And also since we're talking a little bit about convention news This is all I mean not set in stone But I'd just like to mention it that if any of you want to see us live and you want to see us do Awesome things at a convention you want to see us do panels you want to see us run game shows you want to see us?
Rym: BMC's or whatever.
Rym: well if you go to ConnectiCon this year Or if you go to the New York anime festival this year And there's a decent chance if you go to Otakon this year.
Rym: You're gonna see us do quite a bit.
Scott: We're gonna be you like if you thought it was good last year when we you know We had a video a game show here or a panel there.
Scott: You ain't seen nothing.
Scott: yet.
Scott: You're gonna see us lose our voices Friday night after doing like 10 panels or whatever.
Rym: Yeah Cuz I basically I mean we break up the duties of GeekNights And I'm effectively like the producer and like the PR guy and Scott does a lot of the computer stuff And he's like our art director or whatever.
Rym: so uh I spent the last several weeks working with various conventions and doing my annual You know.
Rym: hey conventions blah blah blah.
Rym: Here's my resume.
Rym: What do we do?
Rym: we work stuff out and this year?
Rym: I was going over all the things we've been confirmed to do and all the things cons have asked us to do and I Realized that we're going to have to probably at some cons Not talk outside of our events because we will not have voices.
Scott: otherwise We'll be sitting our artist alley table with like pictochats like waving at you like we're really.
Rym: basically We're going to a lot fewer cons this year, but we're hitting those cons a hundred times harder.
Scott: We are hitting them like a hundred times harder.
Scott: There is no doubt, but I don't think we're going to a lot fewer.
Scott: I think we're going to like one or two fewer and Because three of them are squished into one month.
Scott: It feels like we're going to allow you.
Rym: well Let's see.
Rym: I mean I backed out of an amazement because I'm overworked.
Rym: I spent a lot of money.
Scott: one convention.
Scott: You didn't go to torque on that's - one can there was no ubercon It's - two three.
Rym: We're not going back to Philly wizard world.
Scott: that doesn't really count.
Rym: We went though.
Rym: we went and those six hours.
Rym: I could have spent on the beach.
Rym: Yeah, those are beach hours.
Rym: I won't get back.
Scott: It was a learning experience.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It was.
Rym: don't go to Philly wizard world.
Scott: Actually, there's a funny thing happening this year.
Scott: whether you realize it or not you probably don't care Which is why I don't know.
Scott: but Philly wizard world a comic convention right and heroes con another comic convention, which are Relatively in in close proximity are being held on the same weekend And they're having sort of this battle to see which one it holds up.
Rym: That's Crazy and stupid.
Scott: I don't know which con set their date when but neither one of them is changing and comic fans everywhere deciding Am I gonna go to heroes con or am I gonna go to Philly wizard world?
Scott: Which one's it gonna be?
Scott: and I have a feeling that one of these cards might not do so well as the other.
Rym: Well, the thing is that's not what you want to do to your fan community because especially when comic books in America I mean non-manga, but like a straight-up superhero kind of comic books, even if you like them It's not as though they're doing very well.
Rym: Yep I mean not compared to pretty much any other printed media in the US and the last thing you want to do is Cripple one of the conventions you've got left Yep.
Scott: Yeah, the Philly wizard world is June 15th through 17th And of course Philly and heroes con is June 15th through 17th in Charlotte, North Carolina.
Scott: Not too far apart.
Rym: It's further apart than I expected.
Rym: I was getting the impression.
Scott: It was like once in East Philly once in West Philly No, but like I I know comic fans in Philly who are like we're going to heroes con bitches.
Scott: Wow Cuz they're.
Scott: they're supporting that instead of the crap Philly wizard world.
Rym: But the point is we'll have more details once we work them out.
Rym: But if you go to the anime cons that we go to this year, you can expect us to be doing a lot.
Rym: Yep, bring your friends things of the day.
Rym: Well, I was pining looking for a thing of the day.
Rym: I noticed that our friend I do had emailed me a bunch of cool things and one of these things I Could not pass up because I had not seen it and I believe she found it by accident while researching something else and it's pretty Damn, cool.
Rym: It also happens to be subtitled so you can watch it straight up.
Rym: Apparently in the 80s someone made a comic called Valhalla And it is a Danish comic about if you couldn't guess the Norse gods.
Scott: Oh Danish comic you say.
Rym: well Someone has or at least it was the Danish comic or Danish cartoon adaptation of the comics.
Scott: They might both be Danish See I likes me some European comics like some tin tins and some asterix is but they're pretty hard to get in English.
Rym: well, very simply my thing of the day is a link to the video on YouTube of this Adaptation of this comic and it's pretty damn cool.
Rym: And I really like Loki.
Rym: What can I say?
Scott: Yeah, I watched this for like a minute or two and it was pretty weird seeing an animation with I guess
Rym: Dutch
Scott: Being spoken because it's not a language I hear often like when I first started watching anime with subtitles like hearing Japanese is weird But now hearing Japanese is natural, but hearing Dutch was weird I
Rym: don't know.
Scott: to me it fit really well because it felt like it did fit but it stood out to me like I was It would.
Scott: it was like sticking out and I noticed it and I would have had to watch probably the whole thing before I wouldn't notice it anymore.
Scott: But yeah, it definitely looked really cool.
Scott: And if I had some time to watch things like that, I would totally watch this dude.
Rym: The first half is like 10 minutes long.
Rym: Just watch it.
Scott: I might I might.
Scott: it depends five time All right.
Scott: So what's GeekNights.
Scott: GeekNights is a late show, but for geeks.
Scott: well There are other late shows out there where you know, we got our late show ideas from but not geek ideas from.
Rym: not Terribly much so not really because I've lost.
Scott: see what we have in common is that we're late.
Rym: I've watched a lot of late shows and I don't find them funny at all.
Rym: No late shows are mostly David Letterman just isn't funny.
Rym: No And he's not all those other.
Rym: none of them are funny at all Like their jokes are so predictable and crap.
Rym: and even you know, this is probably blast me to a lot of people But people always talk about yeah, Johnny Carson.
Rym: He was the best entertainer ever.
Rym: It's great.
Rym: The show with Johnny Carson was like this amazing thing and I've watched a ton of episodes of Johnny Carson's show And uh, I don't think I laughed more than once or twice at all.
Rym: I just didn't really find it funny.
Rym: Yeah, I like Johnny Carson.
Rym: I like the things he says and does but I don't like his show.
Scott: I think the thing about a lot of those late night shows is that they're sort of like the only sort of thing that we have that can be called say a variety show and Usually if anything's gonna be funny on the show It's when some you know, someone trying to break into the entertainment business comes on the show and they're actually good.
Scott: You know like.
Scott: you'll always watch clips of people who are super famous now and how they got their start on like The Tonight Show or something and That original thing they did was really funny.
Rym: I wish we could just have variety shows without David Letterman.
Scott: in my way yeah, but regardless David Letterman did a little bit here and Basically he sent his crew out into the city because he's in New York City and They got a bunch of people in spider-man costumes to sort of flash mob.
Scott: this Jamba Juice Jamba Juice is a chain of Basically juice stores in the city where you get juice.
Rym: They're pretty cool.
Rym: I really like they're okay.
Scott: the only thing I don't like about them is that the juices are sometimes a little thick and I can't finish them.
Scott: and Also, they put these BS like booster herbal crap thingies in your juice And I always tell them not to put that in there.
Rym: RIT always had that too.
Scott: Yeah, like the medRx whatever like.
Scott: yeah I'm sure that that powder you're gonna put in my juice is gonna make my memory better.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Keep it to yourself, man.
Scott: But it's pretty funny because see all these people dressed up as spider-man go into the Jamba Juice.
Scott: But I don't want to talk about the people dressed as spider-man going to the Jamba Juice That's that's not really, you know that funny.
Scott: I mean we see stuff like that on the internet every goddamn day.
Scott: Maybe it's a normal people.
Scott: that's funny, but to us whatever He does send in like a Superman later in the video and like a Moses or something But whatever.
Scott: but I want to point out is that they got a camera pointed at a Jamba Juice.
Scott: They got the costume.
Scott: people going in the Jamba Juice, but it's New York City.
Scott: It's a sidewalk and normal people are still walking down the street as normal.
Scott: And I want you to look at the way New Yorkers react to seeing a bunch of spider-men in a Jamba Juice They sent up.
Scott: they look at it Definitely they turn their heads and notice it but they keep walking and going about their business.
Scott: No one stops and stares like one guy in the Jamba Juice takes a few pictures of the cell cam But that's about it.
Rym: And you know, all that guy did was when he got home.
Rym: He said hey check it out There's a bunch of spider-man at my Jamba Juice.
Scott: Yeah, that's the way New Yorkers are.
Scott: shit doesn't phase them.
Rym: Compare that to whenever there's a flash mob I don't know almost anywhere else in America where usually the police show up right away.
Scott: There's a giant crowd and people are yelling Yeah Imagine if this happened in a place in like a suburban town and like the grocery store.
Scott: People be freaking out.
Scott: it'd be like holy shit.
Scott: Look at that.
Scott: Oh, but just spider-man in the grocery store.
Rym: Holy crap I guess part of it's that in New York City.
Rym: I walk past stuff like that every day and I don't even blink.
Rym: Yeah I mean the one time that we were given pause was that time in Chinatown where there were people selling questionable meat out of a Obviously blood-soaked cardboard box in an alley.
Scott: I saw when I was at the Chipotle like last week We saw a guy carrying two bags of what was obviously meat into the Chinese restaurant across the way.
Rym: I once was walking with Emily in Manhattan and it was night.
Rym: I tried to take a picture but I couldn't.
Rym: there was a guy riding a bicycle and While riding the bicycle he was holding not one but two garbage cans on wheels Kind of tied together like next to him kind of pushing him along in the street.
Rym: Wow I was so expecting that man to die in front of me, but no he didn't.
Rym: he just kept going Good for him through a red light and then he was off.
Scott: So for all of those of you who are sheltered and such Behold, New York.
Scott: It exists.
Scott: This is what the people are like.
Rym: I guess the answer is no one cares about you in New York.
Scott: That's exactly right.
Scott: Even if you're spider-man.
Rym: So, uh ghost in the shell standalone complex.
Scott: Yeah, we talked.
Scott: see I looked cuz.
Scott: I thought we talked about this before on the show and that is technically true.
Scott: I searched the archives for ghost in the shell and apparently in 2005 we talked about ghost in the shell second gig.
Rym: Yes, which we?
Rym: when did we finish watching it?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: just now not too long ago.
Scott: So it takes us two hours to watch it 22 years to watch a 26 episode anime.
Rym: Well, I think part of it was.
Rym: we got the first DVD and we watched it up to the kind of cliffhanger at the End of the DVD and then we realized that the not only did the rest of the DVDs not even have dates yet But the second DVD was nowhere near coming out Yep.
Scott: So it took two years for the rest of the show to come out and for us to watch to watch it all and then Make an episode about it's kind of like my thing of the day yesterday.
Scott: Rym weights Rym does wait but in this case Rym no longer has to wait and your patience was rewarded with the great anime.
Rym: now I don't really want to talk about the plot of ghost in the shell standalone complex and I don't really want to bother Distinguishing too much between first gig and second gig or the Tajikamatic days, which aren't really a separate show.
Rym: They're just awesome Yep but I think more.
Rym: I'd like to talk about why I like ghost in the shell standalone complex because what it is is Really good, and I also would highly recommend that anyone regardless of whether or not you like anime Check out ghost in the shell standalone complex.
Rym: just watch first gig and then second gig.
Scott: you should also whether you like comics or not the first manga.
Scott: you should read not so much the other ones, but definitely read the first manga and See the first movie, but the second movie is good But you might not enjoy it if you don't enjoy this sort of thing.
Rym: now a funny little bit that I would like to point Out because I talked to anime world order about this and Scott laughed at me.
Rym: It was a while ago, but while we were starting to watch second gig I made some comment like Man, you know, I love oshi and all this but I gotta say I think he's doing standalone complex differently.
Rym: Look, it's not like he normally does stuff and Scott says that's cuz he didn't do standalone complex.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Yeah, ghost in the shell standalone complex is done by Kenji Kamiyama and not Mamoru.
Scott: Oh, she yep Yeah, basically ghost in the shell has manga movies and TV shows and there's two TV shows And the first one is standalone complex and the second one is standalone complex.
Scott: second gig.
Rym: now the general way to put all this together because the world is kind of contiguous and kind of in order but not Officially.
Rym: all can and linked together.
Rym: But basically the manga is like the real deal in terms of story Like the manga is beginning to end the ghost in the shell story like the core.
Rym: Mm-hmm What were these people doing for the many years before?
Rym: and it goes right up through until the end of second gig is Pretty much right at the beginning of the manga as far as plot would go as far as continuity would go.
Scott: Yep, I mean think about any police movie you've ever seen right?
Scott: Just pick a police movie I don't care which one and it's always like some amazing incredible crime that the police have to solve, you know Over the course of a career of police people a police station that only happens a few times and All the other years and years where they're just working being normal police go by.
Scott: well This the standalone complex the standalone complex second gig are sort of like hey, what did section 9?
Scott: You know the police group that is the focus of the ghost and most of the ghost in the shell stories.
Scott: What were they doing?
Scott: Most of those normal years they were just doing police work.
Scott: Of course, these are.
Scott: there are specific cases that they get into that are slightly larger than you know.
Scott: The day-to-day stuff.
Scott: but most of the episodes are day-to-day police action.
Rym: Granted it's day-to-day police action of a semi secret reports to the Prime Minister Semi militarized it's like this paramilitary super secret double police.
Rym: So they really go only go after the big things to begin with.
Rym: but I mean their equivalent of a mugger is yeah We just stopped a multinational terrorist network from attacking Again, no biggie now in terms of how they actually flow.
Rym: I mean, we're not gonna turn this into the ghost in the shell episode But if you rank them in terms of seriousness and cerebral miss versus just fun and action and humor There is a distinct line because
Scott: at the
Rym: bottom would be the manga which while it's very serious and cerebral It's also really kind of goony and funny and has some slapstick in it.
Scott: The manga is actually well, it's very shirotastic in that way.
Rym: Oh, it's sure which has him.
Rym: we could do a whole episode explaining exactly what that.
Scott: it's also very Tezuka ish in that you have this serious story that you are telling.
Scott: but even at the most serious moments You're like up wacky SD character saying something funny or OMG, something cute randomly like when they put the car bomb in Aramaki's car.
Rym: I Don't remember that in the manga.
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: they get mad at him and they blow up his car and then I don't remember That.
Scott: well, okay.
Scott: Yeah, I could I could imagine it.
Scott: I had to read manga again, I guess Meanwhile, the movies are like dead serious without any humor whatsoever.
Rym: Yeah I mean actually a lot of people sadly didn't really like the second ghost in the shell movie innocence because it was primarily People just talking philosophy and quoting old books while they walked around and there wasn't a lot of action and there wasn't all the stuff that people expect from ghost in the shell of guns and boobs and things exploding and procedural crime drama.
Rym: It was just quote.
Rym: that's meaningful quote that's meaningful Funny quote that's meaningful.
Rym: slow scene of Bato walking Incredible CG imagery.
Scott: that is meaningful.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It was a very intellectual exercise and not very much a visceral exercise.
Scott: So standalone complex.
Scott: the two TV shows are basically if you took the ghost in the shell universe and everything that fans really like about it and you boil it down and can use it in such a way to Basically tickle the fans and it's not fans service in the way that you know.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: having a Gundam fight Voltron is fan service But it is very in service to the fans without being fan service.
Rym: Yep I mean basically it doesn't alter the world too much but what it does is you get to see all these characters interacting with each other a lot more than you see in the movies or even in the manga and Even independent of that because while that's interesting the characters themselves don't matter nearly so much as the plots they are unraveling
Scott: and it's
Rym: primarily an Action mystery kind of show.
Scott: Yep, you've got it's got all the elements that basically create entertainment without being too cerebral or too corny.
Scott: You've got you know, you got the tachikomas to bring in some comedy relief, you know You've got.
Rym: yet at the same time the cut tachikomas provide probably the greatest drama in all of standalone complex.
Scott: You've got a great varied and interesting cast of characters for you to identify with and love.
Scott: you've got Incredible action scenes of super awesomeness.
Rym: You've got Absolutely amazing music.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You've got a lot a a in-depth and complicated mysterious plot with things to be revealed that is very Interesting and is all sorts of good stuff going on and you get a piece here and a piece there and it drags you long.
Scott: You've got police procedural action, you know, you see police investigating things.
Scott: You've also got the cerebral stuff like oh, what's this weird thing going on in this episode?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, oh, it's supposed to mean something.
Scott: Look at that symbolism there with those paper crane granted in second gig.
Rym: There is one scene where normally the symbolism and when things like that happened was generally very subtle and well done.
Rym: But there is one scene and those of you who've seen all of standalone complex will know exactly what I'm talking about Where Bob someone is talking to some
Scott: of that one
Rym: and they mentioned bottles name and then it cuts to bottle and he is holding a piece of wreckage from a building on his shoulder and it is exactly in the shape of a cross and He's screaming.
Scott: So That's like the only time that the show used the symbolisms like heavy-handedly.
Rym: It was so.
Rym: it was almost painful the way it hit you But yet it was beautifully animated and that almost made up for it.
Rym: But it reminded me a lot of way back when I was bored and let working for IBM.
Rym: I drove back to Rochester a lot to hang out with like my friend Kate my friend amber and all these people.
Rym: So we I swear this is related.
Rym: So we watched this god-awful movie called boxing Helena or boxing Helena All right, and I'm pretty sure it was a fetish softcore pornography flick.
Rym: But we didn't realize that at the time and it was really creepy and it's a messed up movie.
Rym: I don't recommend watching it.
Rym: but there is a scene where something's happening and basically a character is being trapped by society by herself and Physically because the dude cut off your arms and legs huh, and it flashes for a second to a birdcage and there's a bird in the cage freaking out and then it Flashes back to the girl and me and amber simultaneously turned each other and go.
Scott: Symbolism Wow, that's equally heavy-handed right there.
Scott: I need to see it to recognize it was hilarious.
Rym: But yeah other than that one moment The shows are really really good and even that moment the animation and the story and the emotion really kind of offset that One minor drop into cheesiness.
Scott: I think the other thing about ghost in the shell Especially standalone conflicts is that it it seems to have something for everyone.
Scott: unless you want, you know Wow, I guess it even does have that.
Scott: it's like if you're a pervert.
Scott: Well, some of the female characters are hot.
Scott: if You want to see lots of shooting and guns you're gonna see that too.
Scott: If you want funny robots You're gonna see that - you want science fiction You're gonna see that.
Rym: - if you want political drama like straight-up hardcore political drama and political theory if you want Sci-fi about the nature of consciousness and the internet you want philosophical debates.
Rym: It's all in there and each bit is done well enough to where if you don't like that thing You're still drawn on by the rest of it and it doesn't detract.
Scott: Yeah I just happen to like like a human interest story as human interest stories and like in some of the episodes It's it.
Scott: Wow, it really is sort of like the everyone show when you think about it.
Rym: Now one thing that I really find interesting is that now I'm not gonna say I'm gonna call him get sack instead of ghost in The shell standalone complex.
Rym: Yeah from now on.
Rym: but in the first one, you know first gig the first get sack The plot basically was broken up into two kinds of episodes and they'd have these standalone episodes that were just a standalone Unrelated story in this world where the team busts something up or something happened.
Scott: Yeah Like there'd be an episode like Bato catches a bad guy and it would have nothing to do with the plot whatsoever.
Rym: And it was a lot like cowboy bebop where at the same time occasionally there would be the complex episodes that all strung together form the overarching plot.
Scott: and So like how in cowboy bebop if you watch episodes 5 I think 13 14 25 26 and maybe another one a few others.
Scott: Yeah, that's the plot of cowboy bebop and every other episode has nothing to do with the plot.
Rym: It's just character building and character development and emotional attachment and also awesome standalone action.
Rym: Yep but second gig went one step further and they broke it up into like three different kinds of episodes like the Individual the divisual the whatever.
Scott: don't even worry about it Yes, but needless to say like there's one kind of episode in second gig that has nothing to do with the plot But there's very few of those episodes.
Scott: Most of the episodes are either individual or divisual or whatever they're called and they relate to the plot in different ways.
Rym: Now here's the part.
Rym: I was getting it in first gig the.
Rym: there's an overarching plot, but the plot is a mystery.
Rym: There's the laughing man, you know, you've seen that Spirally kind of face that has the quote from catcher-in-the-rye on it spinning around.
Rym: It's like the happy face.
Rym: Yeah A lot of people cosplay as it at conventions because it's a funny simple clever cosplay to do and you see it around a lot.
Rym: It's from that show and the plot of figuring out what the laughing man is and how all these events related to it all come together.
Rym: and it's kind of this mystery and That's kind of how first gig goes and it's really awesome and really well done.
Rym: Second gig goes in a completely different direction and unlike first gig where not only did you not know what was going on But you didn't actually know who was behind it.
Rym: There was no villain There was just events and you were trying to piece it together.
Scott: Yeah, and you knew that certain people are on different sides and fighting for different things but you weren't quite sure because everyone was all secretive.
Scott: you it's like And it is basically difficult situations lots of people on different sides.
Scott: You don't know what anyone's trying to do and Somehow section 9 has to decide if they should do anything at all.
Scott: if they're gonna do something What should they do?
Scott: How should they do it?
Scott: And It's kind of a lot like sanctuary in a way and where it's like, oh, we're in a situation.
Scott: What do we do?
Rym: Yeah more more so second gig I think
Scott: yeah,
Rym: but yeah first gig, you know It's this whole mystery and you're trying to piece it together and you can't really figure it out on your own and you kind of Figure it out as the characters do or particularly as togasa does.
Rym: Yeah In second gig they do something really interesting that I didn't expect cuz I wondered how could they have more standalone complex.
Rym: It's just gonna be the same thing.
Rym: They show you a villain right away and there they make no bones about it.
Rym: They're like this guy is the bad guy.
Scott: Well, they don't say it.
Scott: Oh, they said there's some doubt but it's obvious.
Scott: cuz they who else no one looks like that.
Scott: Who isn't the bad guy?
Rym: and while there might be some doubt It's the same level of doubt as to whether or not the guy in the red coat was actually Vashta stampede or not exactly, you know, it's the bad guy.
Rym: and you might second-guess yourself and think no They're just setting me up.
Rym: No it they totally.
Rym: there's no way he's not the bad guy.
Rym: So the show is still interesting because now it's not what's going on.
Rym: who's behind this?
Rym: What's the plot?
Rym: It's all right.
Rym: If that's the bad guy What's he trying to do?
Rym: and how is he gonna pull it off?
Rym: because they know he's the bad guy.
Rym: I know he's the bad guy.
Rym: everyone knows he's the bad guy and Yet he still pulls things off and you wonder hide it.
Rym: It's this totally different vibe and yet it's equally good.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty awesome mostly because it while you know who the bad guy is You're not quite sure what he wants or what he's doing or how he's doing things.
Scott: There are other players besides just section 9 and the bad guy.
Scott: it's not a one-on-one It's like a three or four way go around here.
Scott: And
Rym: also another thing that both series do extremely well, is that the pace of the plot and the pace of what's going on kind of Increases episode by episode along with the plot
Scott: and then both
Rym: of them the last several episodes Just kind of rush at this frantic Awesome pace of just it pulls you along with cliffhangers Just keeps going and going and going to go and then everything explodes in a moment of awesome.
Rym: And then it's over and you feel Spence.
Scott: Yeah, it's definitely exponential Which is why I recommend watching the episodes pretty close to each other and not not like, you know One every.
Rym: you know another show that did that really well Gundam seed.
Scott: Yeah, it's like the show starts off introducing things.
Scott: Get the ball roll.
Scott: It's a snowball, you know, it starts out small It's big and big and big and big and that's awesome.
Scott: And then it hits the wall and the snow everywhere.
Rym: Actually vision of escaflowne is another show that did that really really well.
Rym: granted Escaflowne did it by accident because the show was supposed to be 39 episodes and they had to cut it short.
Rym: So they crammed 26 episodes into the last 13.
Rym: Granted that worked out really well.
Rym: another case for Sometimes things are good because the limitations instead of because you got what you wanted, but I digress.
Rym: Yep Obviously this wasn't a straight-up review.
Rym: We just kind of wanted to talk about these shows because they really need to be talked about.
Rym: they're fantastic anime.
Rym: They're really accessible.
Rym: I highly recommend you.
Rym: Yes, there is.
Rym: they're beautifully animated.
Rym: The music is absolutely amazing.
Scott: right for anyone doesn't realize like if you were in jet in Japan.
Scott: Let's say you're a Japanese person living in Japan and you want to watch standalone complex second gig, right?
Scott: You know how you watch it?
Scott: Well first you can buy expensive as DVDs because now the show is finally out out.
Scott: But who can afford those DVDs?
Scott: not many people?
Rym: Yeah DVDs are like $10,000 in Japan and they have one episode.
Scott: But of course you're in Japan.
Scott: So you watched it when it was on TV, right?
Scott: Didn't you?
Scott: didn't you?
Scott: No, because it's pay-per-view.
Scott: It's pay-per-view for this.
Scott: That's how good it is.
Scott: Yeah The fact that you're getting these shows on normal DVDs at normal prices as long as you don't buy the crazy special editions in America.
Scott: you're basically ripping them off.
Scott: Hey, they had to pay-per-view to watch this.
Scott: It's that good and you can watch it on a cheap DVD or Netflix it and it's so worth it.
Scott: Don't miss the opportunity to basically rip off the production IG and watch their amazing show for all.
Scott: basically what's basically free?
Rym: Yeah, watch these shows and remember I said they're accessible.
Rym: You don't need to know anything about ghost in the shell.
Rym: I know a lot of anime fans when they talk about things.
Rym: there was like oh, yeah the major major Kusanagi Yeah, the major Bato the major and they know all about the ghost in the shell universe and all of them.
Rym: You don't need to know anything coming in to ghost.
Scott: You can watch second gig without having seen first gig and you'll be all good.
Rym: Yep and I'm not gonna spoil anything but Another.
Rym: I just want to point out that first gig does something that brought a tear to my eye.
Rym: there is a very touching and extremely emotional and well done scene near the end and Something almost identical Happens in second gig.
Scott: it's like they pulled the same trick twice and I was like you can't do the same thing twice.
Rym: It won't work this and I knew they were doing like crap.
Rym: now They're gonna do the thing and they think I'm gonna cry.
Scott: They just like they did this last season how they gonna do it again this season.
Scott: I do it again and it works again.
Rym: I was thinking I'm not gonna cry.
Rym: I saw this already.
Rym: They're doing the exact same thing.
Rym: They're not fooling anyone.
Rym: and then the exact same thing happened.
Rym: But the way they did it a tear came to my eye.
Scott: Bastards, how could they pull off the same thing twice?
Scott: Well, we know they can't pull it off a third time.
Scott: That's just not gonna happen.
Rym: You know, they will.
Scott: now there's no way.
Scott: well, it's not fast.
Rym: I don't think there's gonna be more.
Rym: I don't think there's other unless they do like super super double.
Scott: well, the only ghost in the shell that I have not experienced is the solid state society movie and also the Ghost in the shell 1.5.
Scott: Manga because they've read goes in the show one and two manga, but not the 1.5 Manga, but I have pre-ordered the 1.5 manga, so I'm gonna get it and read it.
Rym: So we'll probably do an episode some kind of final thoughts thing or a straight-up review.
Scott: We'll actually talk about what the plots are.
Rym: Yeah Because actually the one thing I like about ghost in the shell the movies the manga the manga Especially when it comes to not just science fiction But real concerns that are actually going to matter probably in our lifetimes.
Rym: Yeah in terms of what consciousness really is especially if you can start mapping out how brains function that It's really like.
Scott: if I made a computer that did everything that a brain did would it be a brain?
Scott: would it be a person?
Scott: You know
Rym: all
Scott: those sorts of questions,
Rym: but ghost in the shell and even standalone complex despite its more actiony Accessible roots brings up a lot of interesting issues and While it gets a little bit hard to follow in second gig I actually got lost a couple times had to rewind.
Rym: I was lost a few times as part of it because I had to read subtitles that were and normally subtitles aren't a problem.
Rym: I'm so used to reading subtitles.
Rym: in fact I kind of get startled when even if I'm watching something in English, and there's not subtitles there I'm so used to watching subtitles.
Rym: Yeah, but in fact in RIT We always watch your ratio hornblower with the subtitles on.
Scott: yeah, well, that's so you could you know yell and scream yep?
Scott: Yeah, you could yell and scream and then still beyond know what's going on even though everyone's yelling louder than the characters are talking.
Rym: But the political and the social social.
Rym: I think I was gonna gay sociopolitical, but I already said political so I'll just say social issues.
Rym: that second gig raises are Fascinating to say the least yes.
Scott: But what ends up happening is the characters when discussing things will say these really long complicated sentences with lots of things about politics economics and society and It's kind of hard to follow in subtitles everything that they're saying and keep it in your brain.
Rym: It's also hard because what like?
Rym: they'll have this huge monologue where the majors explaining some social phenomenon And I started thinking about it because it's really interesting and it's not something I'd considered before and then There's a gunfight, and I totally forget what the major was talking about because now batos shooting some guy
Scott: and then in the next episode it's like I don't really bring over any of the things they talked about in the last episode and It's sort of like I get little pieces as I go along instead of getting the whole picture because I'm reading it doing the subtitles And the dub is an okay dub.
Scott: So I think it might actually even if the dub isn't as good as the Japanese voice acting it might be worth it to watch Just so you can get enough of the show into your brain.
Rym: yes It is definitely one of the far and away superior dubs of modern anime.
Scott: yep All right, I think we're done, and I have to go to bed.
Scott: cuz good.
Rym: Yeah, God damn This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at frontrowcrew.com Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.