Rym: It's Thursday June 14.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we talk a bit about the nimby's and the bananas.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So Rym how cool is your work?
Rym: Um I don't want to answer that question really because it makes me kind of sad.
Scott: Cuz your work's not cool.
Rym: Well.
Rym: Here's the thing I used to complain a lot about working at IBM But to IVM's credit that was my first Job where I wasn't in college and didn't care and showed up late and left early every day like it was an actual job.
Rym: And I realized now that I didn't really hate IVM.
Rym: I just hated working nine-to-five, and I don't want to say my current job sucks, but I spent four hours today sitting Watching service pack 4 for Windows 2000 install on a computer with 64 megabytes of RAM Awesome.
Rym: so job is not cool, so I think it was when I get to go into the ER Which is not so much cool as frightening.
Scott: so a couple days ago My company is run by these four people who are all equal partners.
Scott: right a couple days ago One of the partners rolls into work on literally like Katamari like on some rollerblades into his office And then he just doesn't take him off and every time he leaves his office.
Scott: He goes whoosh whoosh.
Scott: ah You realize that when I worked at IBM and the floor in my office is like this flat sort of bare concrete floors He was just whooshing all over the office.
Rym: The the campus where I worked was kind of big.
Rym: I mean if I had to walk to like certain other buildings or within Buildings two other like parts of buildings it could take a half hour or more sometimes just because they were that big Every day for the three years that I worked there.
Rym: I thought man if only if only I could wear my rollerblades in here without being fired.
Scott: All right, you want to hear something else that it's even.
Scott: that's a little bit better than that.
Rym: I don't hear it.
Scott: So there's some big busy.
Scott: You know my company.
Scott: It's like where whatever you want.
Scott: We don't care pajamas He gives you shit.
Scott: right I have to wear but dress shirts, but every day, but They told us there was a big meeting.
Scott: like some people business people are coming right you know we got it.
Scott: we got a dress nice today right and Basically what they told us was wear long pants and don't wear flip-flops.
Scott: Some people came in wearing you know nice shirt and shoes and then you know pants and whatever.
Scott: but I wore jeans in this.
Scott: I guess it's a short sleeve shirt with a collar.
Scott: and Of course the business people didn't show up.
Scott: They'll probably show up on Monday, but yeah the the point is is that they say dress nice Wear long pants and not flip-flops.
Scott: You know my job's not cool.
Scott: Jobs not go.
Rym: so I mean the only thing.
Scott: oh, I finished pretty much all of my work today.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, I'm like I'm gonna.
Scott: I'm out of work.
Scott: Which is awesome because I love it when all the work is done.
Rym: I've taken upon myself a lot of extra work.
Rym: I keep writing these proposals.
Rym: like you know the company will work better.
Rym: if you guys did blah I just keep sending them up the chain and nothing ever comes back down.
Scott: Probably just haven't been a pile on in the shredder bin now.
Rym: They're probably like yeah that punks writing this thing again.
Rym: What's it this time?
Rym: He's saying something about having a DNS?
Rym: Something to control printers instead of just doing it randomly like we do now.
Rym: Good I think my favorite one is you know guys might be useful to have some sort of documentation server Somewhere to store.
Rym: I don't know Documentation cuz the currently isn't any.
Rym: yeah, there is where?
Rym: And I think the words that my boss's boss gave me in return were Yeah, they've been working on that for a while.
Rym: Don't hold your breath.
Scott: Uh-huh Well my work's cool.
Scott: Your work's not cool.
Rym: Does your work need an IT guy?
Rym: I'm a highly trained professional.
Scott: Well, you might need a technical writer soon.
Rym: I'm a technical writer.
Rym: I took classes on it.
Rym: That's on my resume.
Rym: I would take we have an IT guy.
Scott: the thing is like he's like the admin for everything and he's sort of like a big windows guy and You're probably smarter than he is.
Scott: I don't think they're looking to replace him and I don't think they he needs any help either because he spends most of his day Playing MMOs.
Rym: I will tell you sadly that I I am.
Scott: I have more experience still with windows admitting the Linux admitting Yeah, even so, you know, this guy is like a super windows guy like.
Scott: he knows stuff that I know you don't know.
Scott: Yeah, luckily all that's like if there's an exchange something going on he's like ban there it is.
Rym: That's just not that hard really to be perfectly honest, but he already knows it.
Rym: Whereas you would have to look it up Yeah, but I have to look up everything once.
Scott: Yeah, this guy's already looked it up.
Rym: Oh, well, I could be a tech writer.
Rym: I'd take a pay cut just to be able to wear rollerblades.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, we'll see what happens.
Rym: I Mean I wrote that article for imagine FX.
Scott: The thing is if they do get a tech writer will probably be like, you know We'll keep you until you write all the documentation we need and then we don't need you anymore.
Rym: God, I could do something like that on the side maybe.
Rym: Anyway, so it's Thursday, which means we really we're tired from doing shows all week.
Rym: We don't really have anything to talk about.
Rym: There's no direction.
Rym: we can pick anything in the world and it's funny out.
Rym: when I have to pick a tech news or something About I don't know anime it always is easier because while there's fewer news I just have some direction.
Rym: but now I could pick any of the thousand stories on FARC and I have something funny to say About all of them.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, which one did you pick?
Rym: Well, the one I picked is one that's very near and dear to me for apparently Somewhere in this country in a Waterbury Connecticut.
Rym: In fact Waterbury Waterbury.
Rym: It's Waterbury I know it's.
Scott: we drove through there on the way to Connecticut.
Scott: It's sort of half city.
Scott: It's you know, you drive through it on the highway.
Scott: It looks like a city, but it's not quite a city.
Scott: It's like a. it's like a busy town with actual tall buildings in it.
Rym: I'll be honest Connecticut is a blur to me and other than your parents house and Danbury I really have no concept of where anything is in Connecticut at all.
Scott: I know where things are in Connecticut.
Rym: But anyway, so at this school, they've decided to get tough on absenteeism, you know people skipping truancy and it looks like about 2,000 students who otherwise I get from what I can assume the article is not as Descriptive as I would like it to be.
Rym: who otherwise would have passed will now fail after repeat a grade solely because they missed 19 or more days of school without valid excuses.
Rym: now I have mixed feelings about this because on the one hand Attending school in a perfect world is important because you learn things at school Yeah but at the same time I went to public school and I know well exactly why those students were skipping and I Probably applaud them and would have been skipping with them.
Rym: Yep - At least in high school I'm definitely of the mind that if you can pass all the tests and do all the projects and get good grades.
Rym: Attendance shouldn't matter at all.
Rym: And I say that mostly because I was fairly notorious in high school for skipping all the goddamn time.
Rym: I'd show up like two hours late.
Rym: I just leave for an hour lunch.
Rym: We'd go to Cedar Point instead of going to school.
Rym: I never told my parents ever told anyone.
Rym: I just sometimes I'd get up like I was gonna go to school and I get up On time and I just wouldn't go to school.
Scott: Yeah, where'd you go anywhere?
Rym: We go to the park?
Rym: I'd grab some people and hang out.
Rym: we'd go to first period so they wouldn't be wise to us and then we'd leave.
Rym: The best thing was now here's the thing technically if you had three or more unexcused absences in my school you failed the class automatically and There was one interesting moment near the end of the year.
Rym: we're a good friend of mine trumpet player.
Rym: I won't say his name because I haven't seen him in a while and I don't know where he is right now.
Rym: And Anyway, we both pretty much skipped the same amount of class.
Rym: We both tended to skip together.
Rym: even if we didn't do things together.
Rym: We both used each other as excuses like I'd go up in the middle of I don't know third period and say hey Blah blah blah blah.
Rym: There's a band thing I gotta go work on to make something up in the band room for the musical next week, blah blah, okay Sure, whatever and I'd leave and then he'd use that later like oh crap I gotta help with that too and you know that sort of thing.
Rym: So we were near the assistant principal's office and he calls us both in.
Rym: I'm there for unrelated business and he's there.
Rym: He's not sure what he's for and they call me in and they say something like alright Brandon we have on record that you have one unexcused absence from English class and we would like to know what was going on.
Rym: And I said, oh Doctor's appointment.
Rym: now note that I didn't even know what day they were referring to.
Rym: They didn't say what day or anything.
Rym: and the assistant principal says, oh, okay I assumed it was something like that.
Rym: You can leave and as I'm walking out turns to Brian who skipped the same number of classes to me and they say Brian You're going to fail most of your classes.
Rym: You've been missing class without any sort of excuse.
Rym: and he turns and looks at me as I'm walking out the door Like what the fuck Rym?
Rym: What the fuck That's all there was to that anecdote.
Rym: but it seems like in most schools the teachers tend to at least go to schools cover for the kids who are smart and just let him skip when they want to or when they need to And no harm comes of it.
Rym: I did.
Scott: Okay, I Think just what it comes down to is the current school system, of course sucks And but if you're going to have it and you're going to you know Take all the go with all the assumptions that it makes that you know.
Scott: better grades equals smarter person.
Scott: You know A's are better than B's, you know, if you get all C's you pass etc.
Scott: etc, if you're gonna go with all those assumptions and you're going to take them as true then you can't really Also say that attendance matters if someone gets good grades.
Scott: I mean if the test matters because if someone doesn't do attend doesn't come and get straight A's Not likely, you know, you know very rare, but if it happens then you can't have both those rules.
Scott: It makes no sense.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: because if you're saying that someone can fail by something arbitrary like that in high school Then what you're basically saying is yeah the tests don't matter just show up which is kind of true because in all through high school in most high schools in the US if you just show up even if you put forth pretty much zero effort,
Scott: that's what I did.
Rym: You're gonna pass.
Rym: Yep, it's so hard to fail high school.
Rym: Like it's it's really hard to actually fail Out of high school in the US.
Scott: I never I never studied in all my years of school high school in college.
Scott: I have a Bachelor of Science in computer science from RIT, which is not easy.
Scott: I never once Quote studied for a test.
Scott: when people said I have to study for a test I didn't know how to do that.
Rym: We made fun of Pete pretty badly because Pete would always thought this is the worst thing.
Rym: He'd always come back.
Scott: What is studying mean?
Scott: Do you just like read the textbook again or something?
Rym: Pete taught us exactly what studying means cuz it'd be about 11 o'clock on Sunday night and we'd be playing games and Pete would say Alright guys, I gotta go home.
Rym: I got an 8 a.m.
Rym: Class and I got a study for something and He'd leave and then the next day he would tell us that yeah, I woke up around noon.
Rym: I missed both those classes and I didn't study.
Rym: so I think that's what studying is.
Rym: I think studying is an excuse to go somewhere.
Scott: What were all those people doing in the library?
Rym: See that was the scary thing.
Rym: cuz I saw a lot of people at RIT especially like in the first week of classes when nothing happens and They'd already like they'd have this pile of books and they just be in the library for hours and hours.
Scott: Like maybe they were trying to learn more than you know, just on their own.
Rym: what learning at a Institute of higher learning.
Scott: I Can't imagine what else they were doing.
Scott: But yeah, I never studied.
Scott: I never took notes in a class.
Scott: All I did was go to class.
Rym: I took the test but but the notes I took were very specifically I'd sit there after sleep and I'd listen and every now and then pretty much most of my class experience were Womp womp womp, you know the Charlie Brown voices.
Rym: Yeah, womp womp womp womp.
Rym: The exam is on Tuesday.
Rym: Womp womp womp.
Scott: Yeah, that's exactly.
Rym: it will cover chapters one through nine.
Rym: Womp womp womp womp.
Scott: Yeah, I did all the assignments that were graded.
Scott: if it was a non graded assignment I usually didn't do it usually every now and then I do something if I really like.
Rym: there was an Active Directory optional lab.
Rym: once that I did because I Wanted to learn about Active Directory and by the end of it I didn't want to learn about Active Directory I would never do an assignment if it couldn't affect my grade in any way.
Scott: And I went to class pretty often actually especially in college, you know I guess there's one class that I sort of skipped almost every single class of it.
Rym: well, what's the record?
Scott: because the record for me this I think for Let's see first software engineering lecture of which I think you only get like seven of them I went to like three and the third one was the exam.
Rym: All right, I win that one Visual basic for programmers like the set like the advanced one like the end run a visual basic for IT majors Back before they switched over to Java.
Rym: I Showed up on the first day and I accidentally showed up on the second to last day because I forgot what day it was.
Rym: I was gonna show up on the last day to take the exam but I accidentally showed up on the second to last day and it just so happened that the exam was a two-part exam that took both days and There were only nine other people there with me.
Scott: Yeah, taking that part of the exam how many people showed up for the second half?
Rym: 60.
Rym: And and I remember sitting there thinking and the shit but for the grace of God go away.
Rym: And I just remember he passed out the exam and I that I think he did this on purpose because he realized that no one Came to a stupid class.
Rym: and it wasn't his fault It was just the class was stupid.
Rym: and unless you were an idiot The class was like the most basic dumb programming after a much more rigorous programming class.
Rym: Like they should have reversed the order.
Rym: I don't get it, but it said very specifically Final exam part two and it started with question 51 And the whole like the first ten minutes were people like muttering yourselves like what's going on.
Rym: But I don't get it.
Rym: and then he very calmly just says I see a lot of faces that I really don't recognize.
Rym: good luck on the exam by the way, you got to get at least 60 right to pass and And Yeah Awesome.
Scott: Yeah, that's why I went to class and I did graded assignments or assignments that could affect my grade and that was all I ever did and I Graduated.
Scott: I have all the pieces of paper that I paid for and it didn't take many longer than anyone else.
Scott: It took me exactly as long as it was supposed to.
Rym: my grade suffered in my senior year not from my grade suffered.
Scott: I didn't get A's.
Scott: I didn't get all B's and A's.
Scott: my GPA was like under three in college But I got the piece of paper.
Scott: a different piece of paper with extra Latin words on it would make would have made no difference in my current life other than Depriving me of pleasures in college.
Scott: I think I won for me.
Rym: it would have because if I hadn't graduated with honors IBM wouldn't hired me in the first place.
Rym: They have GPA requirements.
Scott: Yeah, I would have gotten the job I have now and the job I quit before With or without Latin words.
Rym: Yeah Though my I was funny cuz I pretty much had a 4.0 and then middle way and I'm not more here.
Rym: Yeah, you do now, but I made more money than you for a while.
Rym: I think I've made more time.
Scott: I made a very small amount more than I did now.
Scott: I make much more than you do, but I also made without Latin words.
Rym: I made much more than you do when you worked at that other company before you got a real job.
Rym: Cuz I was working at IBM even back then.
Scott: Oh, I want to work with.
Scott: that was a co-op though That wasn't a job.
Rym: IBM was a co-op at first and even the co-op paid 50 grand.
Scott: Yeah, my co-op paid like, you know, it was actually pretty sadly But I had such low cost of living.
Scott: it paid well.
Rym: Oh god, when I had that like $8 an hour tech job at RIT.
Rym: I was rolling in dough.
Scott: Yeah, I wasn't with my $7 an hour office job.
Rym: Oh because I had the think about it I got paid like a dollar more than you and my job was like being Worked a lot more hours than I did.
Scott: I worked like 10 hours a week at that.
Rym: Oh, that's cuz I had no money.
Rym: I was out of money by then.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I had squandered all the money I made at IBM.
Rym: I remember that I came back to school and it was like I have all this money.
Rym: This is gonna be great.
Rym: and four months later.
Rym: I realized where did it all go?
Scott: All right.
Scott: All right, that's enough of this.
Rym: Yeah, it's nice to say.
Rym: I just want to point out that while I might have had a little bit of outrage about.
Rym: You shouldn't make these kids fail.
Rym: I Want to point out that Here's the question that channel 3 eyewitness news reporter Leon Collins asked.
Rym: one of the students Who was caught in all this who was making the ruckus for the media now quote you were out 70 days this year 70.
Rym: I Have a feeling that Many of the students who were affected by this weren't doing so well in school anywhere and probably should have been going to school.
Scott: Yeah, of course, that's obvious.
Scott: But in principle if someone gets all good grades and you are going to go with a school system that you know Puts this, you know emphasis on grades and actually things grades are real and matter and such Then it's kind of hypocritical to fail someone who gets good grades just because they don't show up.
Rym: What it really says is if you can get good grades without showing up then they're not teaching you anything.
Rym: So the school is broken.
Scott: That's also true.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Anyway, that's enough of that.
Scott: So there's another Fantastic Four movie coming out and the first one sucked according to everyone.
Scott: I never saw it what the one from the 70s know the one that was recent.
Rym: So the second one sucked.
Rym: the first one just sucked more and was well.
Scott: There was actually three of them.
Scott: if you there's one from the 70s.
Scott: There was one for the 90s that was never released, but you can watch it all the Internet's.
Scott: they just made it to like hold on to some copyrights or something even though it was some terrible movie.
Scott: and Then there's the newest the new one that was actually in theaters a year a few years ago or so I'm not sure.
Scott: and then there's the sequel to the new one that is going to be in theaters very soon.
Scott: and some Projectionist, you know a guy who runs projectors at a movie theater for seven dollars an hour Saw the movie early as someone who with that kind of job Occasionally gets to do for whatever reason and Because whatever reason for whatever reason he's running the projector.
Scott: No, I think there was actually like, you know something happening like.
Scott: he wasn't running the projector like he got to see.
Scott: but Basically, he's a cool guy who happens to be a projectionist and he wrote a review of the movie for ain't it cool news calm All right soon after he was fired from his job.
Scott: Well, I guess mostly cuz he made a negative review of the movie Uh-huh.
Rym: So you're saying that if the review had been positive they might have overlooked it.
Scott: No, basically, there's all this sort of Is a basically a lack of verifiable information.
Scott: But basically we do know I'm pretty sure that 20th Century Fox called the movie theater You know corporate and said you are someone is unauthorized, you know reviews of Movies at your company somewhere and that's all you know.
Scott: I know they said at least that much and we know the guy was fired most likely because of his too early Review of this movie.
Rym: Well, here's the really important question one.
Rym: Did he sign an NDA?
Scott: No - he said he would have if they gave him one, but they didn't All right.
Rym: So if he didn't sign an NDA and there's no policy in whatever contract or whatever thing allows him to be employed Saying that this sort of thing is grounds for firing and He didn't really violate any laws It really depends on what state it was in and whether or not it's a right-to-work state and all that business.
Rym: But he might have some sort of claim that I was fired unjustly.
Scott: He might have punitively very may well have some sort of legal claim that he was fired unjustly.
Scott: However, I want to say just regardless of the law right forget the law for a minute pretend It's just about right and wrong here.
Scott: What Scott thinks is right and wrong.
Scott: All right First of all, I think you should be able to fire anyone for any reason at any time.
Rym: Oh, I agree.
Rym: So luckily we live in New York where that's the case.
Rym: Yes, so except for the protected things You know age raised for live.
Scott: Oh, yes.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yes, obviously, you know, yeah, you're black you're fired.
Rym: Yeah cool that now That's that that's different.
Rym: Yes, secondly, but you're ugly you're fired.
Rym: It's perfectly fine.
Scott: Yes, but secondly The job was $7 an hour.
Scott: you can go to make any McDonald's and get paid that much and get that job in like a minute.
Scott: who gives a shit if you're fired from your $7 an Hour job.
Scott: Yeah, you're making chump change.
Scott: I could go out and get three of those jobs in ten minutes.
Scott: Well, what the fuck you so upset about?
Rym: Oh, here's why he's so upset.
Rym: He's either an idiot or brilliant because he would have toiled in obscurity in that job.
Rym: But now he is going to be internet famous.
Rym: the more ruckus He makes the more people will know who he is And as long as he keeps the momentum going he can have a moderately successful blog somewhere.
Scott: Yeah, I think he said he plans on becoming a movie reviewer of some.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, you know what he's all set.
Rym: So I think he's pretty canny about all this.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I don't think he did it on purpose though like he did, you know It's like now that he he doesn't have a job.
Scott: He's like well now I'm gonna go for my dream.
Scott: now They don't have a job.
Scott: It's not like he planned it out like ha ha ha.
Scott: I will review this movie early and do it on the internet.
Scott: fire me and I'll make a ruckus.
Rym: What I'm saying is it's after the fact now and he has to take advantage of this good turn.
Scott: Yes, of course, but Why would it?
Scott: people all it's not just him being upset about losing his $7 job, right?
Scott: It's people on the internet are outraged that a guy lost his own.
Rym: People on the internet are outraged about something but how could you be outraged about someone losing a $7 job?
Rym: I think it's the principle of the thing that the guy worked for a company and he did this thing and he didn't sign any NDA and no one told him he couldn't do this.
Rym: There was no law saying he couldn't do it No contract saying he couldn't do it.
Scott: So he did it on his own time, but that means that these people Don't agree that you should be able to fire anyone for almost any reason at any time.
Rym: Oh, no I think what that.
Rym: what I would say is that I agree that legally they should have the right to fire him and There's really shouldn't be any problem with that.
Rym: However, I think that they're all asshats.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I didn't say they weren't.
Scott: I'm just saying no reason to be outraged You know, that's something.
Scott: you point out and go, uh-huh Not something.
Rym: you go ravel ravel ravel, but the internet all the internet can only go ravel ravel ravel.
Rym: It has no other unified cause.
Rym: there is no way to harness.
Scott: it can also go.
Scott: Hooray.
Scott: Hooray But that happens so rarely and among very small time Steve Jobs opens his mouth.
Rym: No, but that's just the Apple people.
Rym: Yeah, there's all these different stands in the internet and they can all hooray hooray about individual things But they never hooray hooray with one voice.
Scott: I think there would be a unified hooray hooray if something big happened.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think the only thing that can pull out of Iraq or something.
Rym: No, because you realize that half of the internet is filled with those people don't know how to use the internet.
Rym: Yeah, they do.
Rym: Granted there's the possibility the internet that those people are all trolls that everyone you disagree with is a troll.
Scott: Someone trolling counts as hooray hooray because they're getting a lot of enjoyment out of it.
Rym: Well, I thought I've never seen the internet.
Rym: you combine and be positive about something.
Scott: I have however about the existence of the internet.
Rym: No because a lot of people who are on the internet hate the internet.
Scott: You get off.
Scott: I mean no one's making you.
Rym: actually I'm not gonna.
Rym: I'm not gonna tell this whole little anecdote, but the other day at work I was talking to a doctor who was kind of a Luddite who didn't even work for the place I worked for.
Rym: I just met him in the street outside of some other hospital and They were complaining into a cell phone about cell phones and people talking on them in public And I just stared at this woman like do you even understand the words that are coming out of your mouth?
Scott: That's pretty funny right there.
Scott: that's like typing into a website man, I hate the Internet Man, I hate podcasts.
Rym: Well, I do hate podcast.
Rym: Dave and Joel are a podcast for people who hate anime and video games and a podcast.
Rym: Yes We just hate podcasts.
Scott: Yeah, although I hate almost everything.
Rym: It's just Things of the day.
Rym: It's a video kittens a robotic mouse and a mirror.
Rym: That's really all I can say.
Scott: Alright my video is a cow and a swimming pool.
Rym: That's pretty self-explanatory.
Scott: No, but here's the thing about this video, right?
Scott: I'm looking at the cow in the swimming pool and I'm like, how are you gonna get that cow out of the swimming pool?
Rym: Well with the crane.
Rym: No, you drain the pool.
Scott: No draining the pool.
Scott: Now, what do you do?
Rym: Then you let him out with the crane.
Rym: No, you kill him.
Scott: No.
Rym: All right, how do they get the cow out of the swimming?
Scott: I'm not gonna tell you that's a surprise But all I'm gonna point out is that Basically, they call the police as you would probably do and then the police calls the farmer and the farmer comes and the farmer knows Exactly what to do and gets the cow out quickly and easily
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: Does he trick the cow into getting out of its own volition?
Rym: Nope, huh?
Rym: It's pretty it was the farmers Superman.
Scott: No The farmer just really must fucking know about cows and I guess that's what it's like when I go to someone's house and fix their Computer now, I guess so.
Scott: Yeah Watch this and if you're not a farmer if you're a farmer you go.
Scott: I know how to do it.
Scott: If you're not a farmer you go.
Scott: Ah, well, look at that.
Scott: It's like I couldn't.
Scott: I couldn't think of this.
Scott: and you know while the video played for about two minutes I couldn't think of how they were gonna do it and then there were that they just did it.
Rym: I'm gonna try to guess before I watch the video and I suggest you all do the same.
Scott: Yeah, it's a fun game.
Scott: Think about guess how to get the cow out of the pool and then after about a minute You'll see the answer floaties and put them under him.
Scott: That's a good one.
Scott: But no, all right.
Rym: so every now and then we do a show on people or things or places we dislike and Near the very top of the list Near the very it's pretty much like Nazis homeo Pitti homeopathy people Nazis flim-flam medicine people.
Scott: Yep Ignorant people who are also indignant and then Two groups of people that sort of go hand in hand.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Now what we were referring to?
Rym: I don't know if you've heard this term before.
Rym: I don't know if this is just an Americanism or if it's in the rest of the world, but it'll be quite anyway.
Scott: It's only places that speak English.
Scott: It's obvious an acronym of English words, but there might be similar terms in other places.
Rym: Yeah, but then again, they're also places like China where the government just basically says, you know what fuck you all here comes We're talking about are the nimby's and Why not in my backyard and also the bananas.
Scott: Absolutely, nothing anywhere near anyone.
Rym: now They used to be just nimby's.
Rym: banana is a fairly recent term.
Rym: that I think really rather fits because the heart of this issue The very very core to put it in no uncertain terms.
Rym: Is that in America people let's use electricity as an example People want electricity.
Rym: They need electricity.
Rym: They cannot live without electricity.
Scott: Well, they can live without electricity, but they will live very unhappily without electricity.
Rym: well They effectively you cannot exist in America without electricity and still be connected.
Scott: American lifestyle and society cannot exist without electricity.
Rym: I mean even body can live but pretty much even the the deeply impoverished most times have electricity.
Rym: Yeah, it is it.
Rym: everyone needs it.
Rym: Everyone wants it.
Rym: It is there.
Rym: It is a necessity of life for most people.
Rym: Yep, now electricity has to be made in something called a power plant.
Rym: Now this could be coal nuclear natural gas solar tidal whatever wind geothermal fusion cold fusion microwave.
Rym: But The fact remains that like it's in city You gotta build it somewhere because you see you need a power plant to make the electricity.
Rym: now here in lies the crux of the issue.
Rym: Most Americans want electricity.
Rym: However, they do not want a power plant to be there near them.
Rym: They want it to be somewhere else.
Rym: They don't care where.
Rym: they just don't want it in their backyard.
Rym: They don't want it in their town.
Rym: They don't want to see it.
Scott: Yes, and if you play Sim City, this is pretty obvious and if you think about it, you know I don't want really you don't want your house next to a coal power plant.
Scott: If there's a coal power plant right next to a house in Sim City The houses don't get populated because no one wants to fucking live with all this coal smoke coming into their lungs, right?
Scott: I wouldn't want to live next to a coal power plant either but at the same time the power plant has to go somewhere Someone occupy like the fourth dimension.
Scott: it has to be somewhere.
Rym: so think of this.
Rym: everyone wants the power plant But no one wants it in their town.
Rym: There's nowhere to put the power plant and as a result large patches of America the United States Require services or have deficiencies that could be easily solved by everyone in the world.
Rym: that the economics are right The demand is there the money is there the resources the land everything is great Except the people everywhere do not want these things to be built near them and thus these things don't get built.
Rym: Yeah, and thus we don't build new power plants often.
Rym: We don't build nuclear power plants.
Rym: We don't build trains.
Rym: We don't build freeways We don't build anything.
Scott: I mean look in Sim City right in Sim City.
Scott: Okay, obviously if you build the coal power plant right next to the residential area, it doesn't work out so well, right?
Scott: But if you build it in the industrial area, it works.
Scott: It's far enough away from the houses.
Scott: It's radius of effect doesn't get over any residential zones only industrial zones.
Scott: So the game doesn't punish you in any way because people don't care if it's far enough away.
Scott: in this country.
Scott: It seems like a lot of people now if they know it's there even if it's like in another state.
Scott: They still don't like it.
Scott: They want to build absolutely nothing anywhere near anyone not just not in my backyard.
Scott: They don't want it built but they want the electricity.
Rym: Now the funny thing is these are people I think the worst example of it other than the wind power thing that Emily Went into in great detail a while ago our cell towers cellular phone towers.
Rym: That's my number one thing because Everyone needs cell phones.
Rym: in America.
Rym: just about it's getting to that point.
Scott: Everyone complains that their cell phone cuts out.
Scott: they complain that their cell phone coverage is shitty.
Scott: They complain that cell phone data isn't fast And it's a plane that cell phones aren't cheap enough.
Rym: like when I lived up in the mountains There wasn't enough cell coverage, so there were a lot of dead spots and the house I was living in just didn't get cell service.
Scott: I had to drive down the mountain to get cell service and people don't realize that in order to have cell coverage You need a tower that's connected to the.
Scott: you know the network that has big radios on it now.
Rym: the people in this fucking town Complained about the cell service all the time.
Rym: they complained to Verizon they complained to Sprint.
Rym: they banded together and wrote petitions How they wanted their cell service to be better?
Rym: Verizon said all right.
Rym: We'll build a cell tower there and the town said oh no no no You can't build your cancer-causing cell tower in our town the cell tower that doesn't actually cause cancer or harm you in any way.
Rym: cell Tower where there's no evidence of any harm whatsoever where in fact It's just off in the distance on the peak of the mountain, and I think looks rather pretty.
Scott: It's just a metal tower that's standing over there somewhere.
Scott: It doesn't hurt you in any way.
Scott: sure if you got right up next to it and like you climbed up it while it was Then yes It would probably hurt you because the radio waves are pretty powerful.
Scott: if you're just standing across the street from it You are.
Scott: unless you stand there for like hours and hours and hours and like you get some Reflectors to aim the radio waves at you or something like that it basically can't hurt you.
Scott: anyone who says that it can hurt you Is full of shit now?
Rym: Here's the better part.
Rym: they didn't even complain so much about how they think they're dangerous.
Rym: The primary complaint was that they will spoil the view that they look ugly.
Rym: Now I've noticed that the people who say that these sorts of things look ugly Have no problem with power lines because power lines have been around a long time.
Rym: I think the real heart is that a lot of people are comfortable only with things that they're used to and are afraid of new things.
Scott: well is a good example that Shows that that exactly what you said is true.
Scott: There was a I think I'm not remember the exact details of this story, but I know it's a true story.
Scott: There was some city and they wanted to put up like a like a bull a billboard with like some lights.
Scott: it was like a big gaudy kind of thing right and When they wanted to put it up way back in the day right people fought it and fought it and fought it and said don't You put up that gaudy thing don't you put that up?
Scott: and they got it.
Scott: put up.
Scott: They the people who wanted it got it and the people who didn't want it got pissed off.
Scott: But after time the people realized they couldn't do anything about it, and they just remained pissed off until they died Like 50 years later.
Scott: You know when the thing had been around for a while people said you can't get rid of that.
Scott: That's like a part of the city.
Scott: It's like it's it's yeah, and they didn't want to get rid of it.
Scott: Huh, huh?
Scott: Maybe it wasn't gaudy or in the way actually change that upset at them.
Rym: the same thing Happened Probably to a lesser extent.
Rym: I don't know all the details, but when the Eiffel Tower was built a lot of people living in the area Saw it as this gigantic monstrosity this ugly ugly just black hideous thing they wanted to turn down.
Scott: I think it was a monstrosity.
Rym: Yeah, but a lot of people just they didn't like it.
Rym: It was like this eyesore and now the Eiffel Tower is probably like the ride up from the ultimate icon of France.
Scott: Yeah, they gave us the better statue though dumbasses yeah Themselves a plain metal tower.
Scott: We got a lady with a torch and lights and stuff real smart Thanks, we win you lose.
Rym: Yeah The just people want things, but they're not willing to deal with the consequence of the things.
Rym: I mean.
Rym: and the worst part is all right.
Rym: so say you try to build something off in the middle of nowhere.
Rym: Then they complain that you're ruining the natural environment.
Rym: So then say you try to build it bikes up.
Rym: all right environmentalist to complain about coal power and nuclear power and whatever.
Rym: fine We'll build air power.
Rym: air power is perfectly clean.
Rym: It's probably it's exactly what they want, but they don't want the turbines because they say it'll kill the birds.
Scott: It doesn't kill the birds.
Scott: Yeah, I mean and it also they complain.
Scott: It's makes noise.
Rym: Well, yeah, it makes noise, but not that much noise and only if you're standing right next to it.
Scott: Yeah, if it's kind of far away.
Scott: It's not you're not gonna hear it.
Rym: I mean back in a Rochester Emily.
Scott: I mean a hydroelectric dam.
Scott: now that makes some fucking noise.
Rym: There were a bunch of people.
Rym: they like they want to build a big wind farm out there and a lot of people started getting together and protesting it.
Rym: and Most of these people happen to be wealthy people who own land and were worried about property values and BS like that.
Rym: Well, I think the lady who was like the forefront of it didn't even live there.
Rym: She just owned the land or something.
Rym: But their arguments were absurd.
Rym: one of the arguments they made against them was that the Rotating blades if the shadow passed over someone's window could with the alternating light and dark cause epileptic seizures.
Scott: No, I can't.
Rym: that's just crazy.
Rym: One gentleman in an open letter said that the sounds that they make when you're standing right next to him Which is kind of this low groaning.
Rym: I think it's a kind of interesting sound.
Rym: I like it and also you have to be really close to it to hear it.
Scott: Yeah, you got to be like standing next to the thing to hear it.
Rym: He said that the noise they make reminded him too much of the concentration camps.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, yeah Godwin's law you lose.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well Godwin's law doesn't state that you lose.
Rym: It just states that the probability of Nazis being brought up approaches one.
Scott: Yeah, and then it's over.
Rym: Well, no, not that it's over just that's it.
Rym: Nazis get brought up.
Rym: Yeah, I guess there are corollaries that say then you lose or whatever.
Scott: But yeah Anyway, these people all need to learn two words that I have to tell them.
Scott: you.
Scott: ready for the two words?
Scott: I'm ready tough shit.
Rym: Uh, I don't know.
Rym: I have them.
Rym: I have a much different set of two words cost-benefit.
Rym: It seems that people want things but aren't willing to actually consider the consequences or the prices.
Rym: You can't get anything for free.
Rym: the laws of thermodynamics State that the world is a zero-sum game.
Rym: The universe as far as we've been able to tell for as long as we've existed is a zero-sum game.
Rym: anything you want cost something and People want things but they don't want to pay.
Rym: they want electricity.
Rym: Alright build a coal power plant, but coal makes pollution.
Rym: fine build a nuclear power plant, but nuclear radiation.
Rym: OMG.
Rym: fine build a hydroelectric plant, but they're loud and they screw up rivers and we already built them all.
Rym: Oh fine build a win air plant.
Rym: No, it'll kill the birds.
Rym: fine build a solar plant.
Rym: No, they're expensive.
Rym: fine build a natural gas plant.
Rym: No, they're even more expensive.
Rym: There's no more options.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: It's either pick one of them or it's not like there's an option that satisfies you and us.
Rym: tough shit.
Rym: You have to make a compromise.
Rym: You have to decide what price you were going to pay for that Electricity and people are just too stupid to realize it.
Rym: and it really bothers me if you can't tell because I haven't breathed in The last minute.
Scott: Yeah, basically, I think that the government just has to eminent domain a lot more.
Scott: yes, eminent domain a lot more.
Scott: the problem is is You want a government that does things that are in the best interest of the people but you you sort of have.
Scott: That's why we have a representative government as opposed to a pure democracy.
Scott: because of the pure democracy We wouldn't be able to do anything in the best interest of the people when the people don't know what's in their own best interest.
Rym: I believe the words we're looking for are the needs of the many outweigh the needs of the few exactly.
Scott: but The problem is is a lot of these nimby banana issues are very local issues.
Scott: They're usually on the town or state level.
Scott: Usually they're not sort of federal issues where the you know The government can kind of go ha take that and there's nothing you could do about it.
Scott: right because there's so because the you know, there's so many the whole country's voting and only your town says no you lose.
Scott: or The whole state is voting and only your County says no you lose when it's a local issue and the mayor says no This wind farm is better for our town and the mayor does it.
Scott: The mayor loses the election and then the next mayor takes down the wind farm.
Scott: waste everyone's money taking down the wind farm and The people vote for that mayor again and again and their town continues to suck and suck, but they're still happy.
Rym: Yep, and this happens with everything like where we live now.
Rym: there's really only one north-south road and there's really only one east-west road and Traffic is getting worse and worse as more and more people move to this area and a lot of people are saying hey Let's stop letting people move to the air.
Rym: Yeah, they don't say alright, how can we fix the roads?
Rym: maybe mass transit?
Rym: Maybe a freeway maybe some sort of solution?
Rym: No, just well, let's just buy up all the land and not let people move here because that'll work in the long run.
Scott: Yeah, and maybe they they don't even stop to think uh, then our economy will suck.
Scott: if we let these people move It'll be awesome for us.
Scott: No, they just don't want anything to change.
Scott: They don't want anyone to move there.
Scott: They don't want it.
Scott: They want it to be the way it is and never have anything change.
Scott: Yep, don't cut down a single tree.
Scott: Don't lay a single brick.
Scott: Don't do anything.
Scott: Let's have it.
Scott: stay this way.
Scott: It's like in the year 2500 when there's all these Jetsons towers your town will still be sitting down there.
Scott: You'll be an old man living in your same cruddy house.
Scott: Nothing changed.
Rym: I mean, I think you have to strike a balance because I think keeping Relics of history is important.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: I mean, of course, it's like if you don't knock I'm not saying we got a world here.
Rym: Yeah, you don't knock down the Colosseum in Rome to build a new condo.
Rym: No, but at the same time if you have 40 Colosseum's keep one of them like the New York City.
Rym: They build brand new buildings all over the place because old old skyscrapers suck, but you know what?
Rym: They're probably never gonna tear down the Flatiron building because that was the first skyscraper.
Scott: Yeah, like that's our estate building isn't going anywhere.
Scott: Yeah, but you know what that cruddy random building that no one cares about on like X Street.
Scott: If someone buys that building and has enough money you bet your ass.
Scott: they're gonna tear it down if they can and pay someone to build it back up.
Scott: and you know what.
Scott: that's good because jobs for the construction workers What the building now has can fit more things in it and it's taller.
Scott: So you get more business more people can be around there and it's just better for everybody.
Scott: Some guy is basically investing money in that spot and that's just.
Scott: that makes things go.
Scott: That's what makes things good is when people spend money on stuff.
Rym: I think my favorite point about this whole issue it always comes back to the cell towers people.
Rym: the primary complaint regardless of what people say is always that they don't like the way they look.
Rym: and First I'll make my logical argument and then I'll make my funny argument the tree.
Rym: Yeah the tree.
Rym: the logical argument is simply that to me as a technologist and a futurist and someone who I guess I Don't want to say that I'm more in tune or I'm more enlightened because that sort of thing is really pretentious and crappy to say.
Rym: but you got to at least be a little bit forward-thinking.
Rym: and when I see a cell tower or a new Technology or a new freeway or a new maglev train or something like that being built or I see a wind farm on the horizon I don't think ah that ugly new thing marring the landscape.
Rym: I think wow Look at all that science and progress sitting right there.
Rym: That's the future May.
Scott: I go to the city every day and I just like look at something right.
Scott: you look at a building and the building's made of like a bajillion bricks and you go People made that.
Scott: not only that people made that like 50 years ago and you look at the whole thing and you're like people made that.
Scott: when I look think about what we had to do to make that when I look and there's Like a thousand more of them and you're like, how the fuck did we do that?
Rym: Look at this when I look up at the top of mountain beacon at night and I see all those blinking glistening cell towers and Communication towers.
Rym: I don't think they've just foiled the beauty of mountain beacon.
Rym: I think wow, that's how my cell service works That's that's it.
Rym: That's how I communicate with the world right there.
Rym: I can see it.
Rym: That is a monument to technology.
Scott: Yeah, when I see a cell tower, I'm like, yes data's I need them.
Rym: now normal people seem to think about this on a much baser level because the solution that has been used at least in downstate New York, and I've seen him in other places too is All right build a cell tower.
Rym: It's ugly.
Rym: It looks like a cell tower.
Rym: What if we made it looks like something natural like say a tree.
Scott: that's fine.
Scott: If you have like a big, you know tree thing that they've it actually looks like a tree.
Rym: What if we camouflage it?
Rym: So, uh, I'm driving down 84 toward Connecticut.
Scott: It's on the hutch.
Rym: Yeah Well, no, there's.
Rym: there's one on 84.
Scott: The hutch one is the biggest most gaudy one.
Scott: Yeah, the one right after 9 the one on the hutch at the like the New York Connecticut border.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yep Yep, where it hits like 287 when I go over to hit and then pass that one.
Scott: 684 that's yeah, we're 684 and the hutch meet at the corner of New York and Connecticut.
Scott: But I was working at Mount Vernon.
Rym: I was over there a lot.
Rym: Here's the scene you're driving and you see the tree line along the hills this gigantic just line of trees.
Rym: They're all about the same height and they all look about the same because they're all you know pine trees.
Rym: And in the midst of them is one gigantic ugly motherfucking tree That's twice as tall as all the other twice as tall as all the other ones twice as thick and incredibly sparse.
Rym: It has these sparse obviously fake metal looking leaves on it and an antenna sticking out of it and it's painted brown.
Rym: Who's that fooling?
Rym: that looks a lot worse than a sleek shining like red and green cell tower with lights on it.
Rym: It just looks stupid.
Scott: It's really stupid.
Scott: Maybe I should like we can find a picture of one of these things to show you how stupid it is.
Rym: I mean good It just.
Scott: they wasted money and resources on making that cell tower look like a fake tree Where they could have spent those money resources on another cell tower down the road where there's no service.
Scott: Ah Now it's not just for me the nimby's and the bananas.
Scott: It's not just you know The government wants to build something or we need a public service or someone wants to build a new business or a housing development, right?
Scott: It's also within It's people against each other and not it necessarily against companies or the government.
Rym: It's whenever someone has a decision to make and just doesn't actually make the decision or doesn't actually think about it
Scott: Like somewhat like for example if I want to build a garage the law says I have to ask my fucking neighbor Why the fuck should my neighbor get to say what I build on my lawn?
Rym: Well that only matters if you live in some stupid.
Rym: We'll talk about that in another show.
Scott: You want to talk about another show?
Rym: Homeowners agreements?
Scott: Homeowners associations?
Rym: Yes That's the other show.
Scott: Basically a homeowner's association is if you live somewhere in which there is a homeowner's association You are not allowed to live there unless you join this agreement.
Scott: and then because
Rym: it's tied to the land In most cases
Scott: and if you join the agreement You're basically agreeing that any rule the homeowner's association comes up with you have to follow Which basically means a bunch of people who live where you live and have nothing better to do because they have no job.
Rym: Yeah, the only people who actually work and run the homeowner's associations not to sound stereotypical It's always old and bittered people with nothing better to do and no jobs.
Rym: Well, basically and they always make the meetings at like two o'clock on Wednesdays So all the working people can't show up to them.
Scott: Yep and they will just Decide on rules and then you must follow them or you can't live there and they can just kick you out and do a whole Bunch of nasty things to you and they'll make rules.
Scott: Like you have to bring your trash can in back by a certain time or else you pay a fine or you're not allowed to Park a car in your driveway.
Scott: All your cars have to be in the garage.
Scott: if you can't have car You can't have more than X cars.
Scott: You can't have a car more than X years old.
Scott: if you you have to replace your roof every three years whether it needs repairing Or not.
Scott: your house can't be that color.
Scott: You can't make an addition to your house.
Scott: You can't build a porch.
Scott: You can't have a pool.
Scott: you can't remember.
Scott: you're in you to do this.
Scott: you do that.
Scott: What the fuck you I'm telling you.
Scott: don't tell me what I can do to my house.
Scott: All right, fuck you I don't care if you have to look at my house and you look out your window.
Scott: That's tough shit.
Rym: now I realize just cuz we've gone long but we talked.
Rym: you know We kind of listed in order the people we dislike and I realized something frightening.
Rym: There is almost nothing more disturbing to me in the world than an indignant NIMBY dump dump dump indignant banana.
Rym: The phrase indignant banana just strikes me as being wonderful.
Scott: Yeah, I just need I see like this banana.
Scott: He was about to do some peanut butter jelly time, but instead he does something else.
Scott: It's not good.
Scott: He says you can't build ten cell towers.
Rym: I think we're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front road crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.