Rym: Hey, it's Thursday April 5th, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we present the prestigious worst in podcasting awards.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: I gotta say the forums have been rocking have they now?
Rym: There's been more people there lately than I ever would have really expected to be at a forum that I guess I made I don't know.
Scott: I mean I think my part of my problem is if I wait all day and don't read the forum and then I go Late in the day.
Scott: There's a billion posts, and I don't know what to do, but if I read it constantly It's not posting so fast that I can't keep up.
Rym: it seems like most people will wait X amount of time and then suddenly pop in and Respond to like every single thread on the front page and then come back a week later and see what people had to say in Return.
Scott: yeah, and some people just reload it constantly.
Scott: and when I'm at work And I have no work to do you'll see me reloading it constantly when I have a lot of work to do.
Scott: you'll see me load It like twice a day.
Rym: Yep, suffice to say a lot of new people have been joining the forum.
Rym: So I begin with this mostly to say to all of you who have applied and not gotten an email back.
Rym: You actually did get an email back.
Rym: We have never ever.
Rym: well with the exception of one person who reapplied like eight times after we banned him Ever denied someone an application.
Rym: so if you applied to our forums and didn't get a response You probably use Yahoo email And they probably hotmail or hotmail and they probably blocked it thinking it was spam.
Scott: I think hotmail is the one that's blocked, but I don't know about Yahoo mail.
Rym: Oh, yeah, hotmail is blocked at pretty much a hundred percent.
Scott: Yeah, if you got hotmail Get Gmail get Gmail.
Scott: There's it's free and better.
Scott: Why would you bother using hotmail?
Scott: I don't get it.
Rym: Yes, and also a few people pointed out that mr.
Rym: Period hasn't been around lately.
Rym: He has informed us that he has a life And he hasn't had time lately.
Rym: He swears that like general Douglas MacArthur.
Rym: He shall return And until then we're probably going to at least look into getting one or two more moderators because even if he comes back full-time There's too many of you for him to police anymore all on his own.
Scott: Also you people haven't been so bad lately.
Rym: Yeah I mean it's all been little things that While they irritate me a little bit but that's just cuz I'm a nut and they probably pissed the hell out of him.
Rym: if you Were actually reading the forums lately.
Rym: They're not that big a deal.
Rym: There's.
Rym: no one is doing the egregious horrible things that you used to be doing.
Scott: I mean the worst things I've seen lately are people saying then instead of then and Some there's there there's that are incorrect.
Rym: while that is terribly bothersome.
Rym: At least no one is posting 70 sentence long paragraphs without capitalization.
Scott: Yeah, that pretty much stopped.
Scott: I don't know if the people who did that sort of thing learned or if they just got pissed off and gave up.
Rym: Well, it helps that I would say most of the people in our forums are reasonably intelligent.
Scott: Yeah So we are in the midst of the Jewish holiday of Passover or Pesach.
Scott: if you are a Jew and that is what you call it and I am a Jew but not religiously Didn't you used to call yourself an open-source juggle?
Scott: No No, that was something that you you made up but not cuz.
Rym: you went way on about open-source Judaism for a while.
Scott: I talked about it because it was a cool thing.
Scott: I didn't say that I was it.
Scott: Aha Anyway, anyway The Passover is the holiday where the Jews celebrate being freed from Egypt.
Scott: You ever watch that, you know, Charlton Heston movie Ten Commandments that let my people go.
Scott: Yeah it's actually a pretty cool story pretty cool movie.
Scott: and The thing is a lot of people Jew and non-jou believe that it was true that at some point in history Jews were slaves in Egypt and Moses freed them.
Scott: and some people, you know, well might not believe it that he parted the Red Sea.
Scott: But you know who knows about that.
Scott: The thing is, you know, parting the Red Sea is obviously didn't happen.
Scott: I mean, come on, that's just silly.
Scott: but a lot of a lot of reasonable people do believe that Jews are slaves in Egypt.
Scott: That's not unreasonable.
Rym: Well, a lot of people also believe that slaves built the pyramids.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: Well, we don't know about that.
Scott: But the thing is there's only one piece of evidence ever to suggest that yes Indeed there were Hebrews because they weren't Jews yet They were Hebrews or Israelites who were slaves in Egypt.
Scott: one piece of evidence ever.
Scott: Pretty much anyone who knows anything about Egypt every Egyptologist every archaeologist will tell you any reasonable Archaeologist will tell you the Jews were never slaves in Egypt.
Scott: and that's all made up and it's just a story And it's not real.
Rym: Yeah, how are they had gotten down there anywhere?
Rym: Did they start there?
Scott: if you if you question this and you think that Jews were slaves in Egypt?
Scott: This is how you can figure out that you're wrong.
Scott: first answer this question.
Scott: What year were Jews slaves in Egypt?
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Now go look in history and see what was happening in that year.
Scott: No matter what year you pick Jews won't be slaves in Egypt in that year.
Scott: Obviously.
Scott: That's sort of simple and silly.
Scott: but really think about it.
Scott: What year you pick a year like, you know, how many BC?
Scott: are you gonna go and then figure out what was happening?
Scott: You know according to archaeology and the best historical records We have in that year and you will find that we have evidence for things that were happening that will directly contradict Jews being slaves in Egypt like.
Scott: I don't know Jews not being there Jews being elsewhere other people interacting with Jews and Hebrews and other places at the time Etc, etc.
Scott: So yeah.
Rym: So taking a page from the previous year's New York Comic Con six flags over Georgia decided to go forward with an ill-conceived Idea, they thought you know, it'd be a great promotion.
Rym: Let's say that anyone who shows up Today between 6 a.m.
Rym: And 9 a.m Gets in free and let's advertise this all over the place and it'll generate a bunch of buzz.
Rym: We'll market it as some sort of ditch work and come to six flags day.
Scott: That's a pretty good idea.
Scott: because number one What was today Thursday?
Scott: Yeah, people aren't going to amusement parks on Thursday.
Scott: However, it is spring break So you are gonna get some people now.
Scott: amusement parks are pretty expensive to get into But they make their real money in the park with our carny games and their well over.
Rym: Even back when Cedar Point was double awesome as a kid and it cost like 50 bucks to get in for one day and another 30 or 40 bucks to go to the water park on top of that, but you got in there All right, you want a soda or a water from one of those vending machines?
Rym: It's like three bucks.
Rym: You want a hamburger and fries nine bucks?
Scott: Yeah, you got to bring your own food in but they don't let you.
Scott: they don't let you know they don't stop you.
Rym: What are you gonna do with that food while you're riding roller coasters?
Rym: Uh, you can't put it in a locker.
Rym: Yeah, the lockers that cost a lot of money and are basically Dutch ovens.
Rym: Yeah, bring a hamburger and stick it in one of those lockers and see how you feel about eating it an hour later.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: So 6 a.m.
Rym: To 9 a.m.
Rym: Free entrance.
Rym: All right.
Rym: What do you think happened?
Scott: Billion people came.
Rym: well, apparently well before 6 o'clock the highways in every direction from this park were Completely stopped by people trying to get to this place.
Rym: Then because traffic was stopped people just abandon their cars on the freeway and started walking.
Rym: So this unruly mob gathers and eventually makes it to the Six Flags to find a previous Unruly mob that had gotten there before the highways stopped already filling the parking lot.
Rym: a bunch of fistfights broke out And it was general chaos.
Rym: furthermore the people at Six Flags were telling people not to line up because they didn't want to be responsible for it and They were telling anyone who didn't show up with a car that they don't accept anyone who isn't in a vehicle and they tried to Turn him back.
Scott: Uh How could you not accept anyone who's not in a vehicle?
Rym: a lot of places do that to keep the riffraff out?
Rym: Uh, in fact most drive-throughs if you try to walk through a drive-through, they'll call the police.
Rym: really Yeah, I tried to do it twice as a kid once on a bike and once on foot.
Scott: Wow Wow, they call the police both times.
Rym: They said go away or calling the police.
Scott: There's no law.
Scott: All right call the police.
Scott: what are you gonna do?
Rym: well, here's what they do.
Rym: They say don't come through the drive-through.
Rym: if you don't leave I'll call the police.
Rym: and if you don't leave you're not trespassing and then you've broken the law.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, yeah, so Obviously they didn't learn the fundamental rule that has been known in ages past mostly in nightclubs where the cover charge does not exist To make you money.
Scott: Well, it does make you money, but that's not.
Scott: it's for you.
Rym: Don't have it to make money unless you're the anime club and we're trying to make a dollar.
Rym: Yeah The cover charge exists to keep the the the riffraff out and my riffraff not.
Rym: definitely not to sound I don't know classist or anything like that But the cheaper something is the more people will show up and the wider cross-section of society you will get.
Scott: yeah I mean imagine if you opened up something for free.
Scott: Homeless people will show up.
Scott: and not to make fun of homeless people because not all homeless people are bad But many homeless people are insane, but they're not insane enough that they won't show up to your free thing.
Rym: Well more importantly depends on what you're giving away.
Rym: if you're giving away t-shirts and you get a million of them That's not you're not gonna be.
Rym: it doesn't matter One.
Rym: it doesn't matter who shows up because you give them a t-shirt and it's no skin off your back and - if you're on Out of t-shirts you break down your little cardboard box and you walk away.
Rym: Yep If you've got a limited resource and you offer it for free and there are more people within I don't know 400 miles of you especially if it's something that has any perceived value who want that thing.
Rym: They're all going to show up.
Rym: people will come out of the woodwork.
Rym: You didn't even know existed.
Scott: You know amusement parks haven't been doing well in recent years actually.
Rym: no they haven't.
Rym: cedar point even which is like the king of rollercoaster Parks, they make a crazy stupid amount of money.
Rym: yet everyone who on the internet has talked about going there has pointed out the incessant horrible Roman s decline of the cedar point Empire.
Rym: every year the people get crappier.
Rym: They're at x-ray machines because more and more people are bringing guns in and fights are breaking out and things are breaking down and vandalism Everywhere.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much amusement parks.
Scott: Just getting crappier and crappier.
Scott: Yet all of a sudden they make one free and now people show up.
Scott: It's like people have forgotten about amusement parks maybe and they need of you know The opportunity to go to one for free to remember they exist.
Rym: I think there's a lot of factors at play.
Rym: I mean amusement parks still do.
Scott: well I mean obviously people want to go to them.
Scott: if people didn't want to go they wouldn't go even if it was free.
Rym: well I was trolling around Google news just looking at various things about current amusement parks and trying to look at Wikipedia And it seems like the problem is that amusement parks get the same number of people But they have to pay a lot more in maintenance because the people who show up are Generally a lot more destructive than people used to be and there's a lot more damage Vandalism liability fights and police action.
Scott: Hmm.
Rym: I don't know if it's a consequence to society.
Rym: Maybe they need to raise their prices because regardless of how classist it may be the fact remains that the higher price you set on Something the more discriminating you can be in who shows up.
Scott: that is true.
Rym: the operative thing here is not an argument about class values or The horrible cycle of poverty where people have problems because they're poor But then they're poor because they have problems.
Rym: and it's this never-ending cycle and even if you're smart It's hard to break out of it and it sucks.
Rym: We're not.
Rym: I'm not talking about that I'm not trying to make any sort of judgment here.
Rym: The fact remains that whoever runs this six flag is a consummate dumbass who doesn't understand how the world works.
Rym: And here's the kicker before 6 a.m.
Rym: Before it even opened at the last minute They decided you know what we fucked up and canceled the promotion.
Scott: Can you do something like that?
Rym: Yeah, and you know what the angry mob was still there?
Scott: Yes, it was.
Rym: I didn't really read the follow-ups, but I can't imagine that ended.
Rym: Well, though According to two articles.
Rym: There's a zoo nearby and that zoo had more people show up than it's ever had.
Rym: go zoo Go probably because people pissed off and already taken the day off work.
Rym: What else are you gonna do?
Rym: There's the amusement park the zoo or I don't know the real world, but most people don't think of that.
Scott: Are you wasted a day off work?
Scott: That's really terrible.
Rym: if you do that I don't know if I took a day off work ever.
Rym: even if I failed at everything I plan to do I'd still get more done that day than if I'd gone to work Things of the day.
Rym: you might remember way back when our internet was out We did things of the day from our real life because well, there was no internet.
Rym: We had no way to in any way short of calling people or finding Pieces of dead trees with this dark stuff splattered all over him to find out what was going on in the world.
Rym: So we had to observe our surroundings and make you know, what's the deal with bla bla bla kind of?
Scott: Yeah, these pretzels are making me thirsty.
Rym: Anyway, I got one of those kinds of things of the day today.
Rym: You see one of the places I work.
Rym: I'm setting up all these computers for him and Most of the people there are really cool and on.
Rym: more of them than you would expect are totally metal.
Rym: When I say metal, I mean no.
Rym: people who run very popular metal sites get into metal concerts free Have pictures themselves hanging out with musicians from Queens, right?
Rym: Mm-hmm, and this girl not only she totally metal, but she's also totally Scottish And with tartan week and all that while I'm setting up computers and everything.
Rym: she offhandedly mentions that.
Rym: yeah tonight She's hanging out with the well I guess this was last night the previous president of Scotland and Sean Connery And sure enough today I go into work and I'm fiddling with other computers and she has a picture of herself Standing on a chair next to Sean Connery.
Scott: Is she short?
Rym: No, Sean Connery is just gigantic.
Scott: Is he really?
Rym: All right, Sean Connery looks really big and impressive on screen, right?
Rym: It looks about six something Yeah, but also like he has this charisma in this presence You know real and usually when you see someone like that in real life They're a lot smaller than they look on screen Sean Connery looks twice as big in person.
Scott: Is he really?
Rym: his head is bigger than other people's heads.
Scott: Whoa.
Rym: It's really big.
Rym: Okay, and according to her he is Exactly as charismatic and awesome as you would guess from his movie acting as he is in real life.
Scott: But isn't he all I've heard?
Scott: he's also kind of like an ass like.
Scott: not an ass like, you know A guy you don't want to talk to but like a wise ass.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I really like wise asses I'm.
Scott: well, I like to be a wise ass too.
Rym: I know I'm just saying but Scott you like to be a wise ass.
Rym: You say I never would have guessed.
Rym: What's the deal with Scott being a wise ass?
Scott: What's the deal with the Rym not being original?
Rym: What's the deal with making fun of?
Rym: Anyway, I thought that was pretty cool.
Rym: So that's my thing of the day My thing of the day.
Scott: earlier in the week Rym did a thing of the day of a flash tower defense game.
Scott: Cuz you know, we love them flash tower defense game.
Rym: Yeah, very briefly all those of you who aren't in our forums Everyone in the forums is crazily addicted to the stupid game and posting their scores.
Rym: So join in on that action.
Scott: But anyway, anyway, there's another flash game that was all over the internets today called chick chick boom Which is pretty cool name because you know chick chicka boom chick chicka boom chick chicka boom.
Rym: I don't know when I hear chick chick boom.
Rym: I think someone cocking a shotgun.
Scott: Oh, I think I think of the mask with John Kerry.
Scott: Nah Jim Carrey John Kerry is the senator.
Rym: Yes Anyway, I think part of that is that I spent most of my childhood playing doom and you like the mask.
Rym: So yes, so I don't like the mask.
Scott: chick chick boom has nothing to do with shotguns or Jim Carrey movies.
Scott: It's a Nintendo flash game.
Scott: Nintendo makes it and it's free to play.
Scott: and the way the game works is You've basically got what looks like a volleyball court and on one side are these little balls that are yellow and they're chicks on the other side of these black balls, which are evil.
Scott: and You've got all these things.
Scott: you can click on.
Scott: you can click on and I've only played level one.
Scott: So, I don't know what all the things are But basically of a left arrow a right arrow a weight and a bomb.
Scott: Right and you click on one of these things and let's say you click on the bomb.
Scott: All right, a picture of a bomb shows up.
Scott: You have to trace it with your mouse.
Scott: It's a lot better if you have a tablet PC because then you can trace it with your stylus.
Rym: I watched Scott trying to do this on his laptop with the touch with a touch pad on a laptop.
Scott: It's impossible.
Rym: It's pretty much like trying to play that Carney game of pull the ring up the snake without touching harder than that.
Scott: Anyway, depending on how accurately you trace the bomb you get a greater percentage.
Scott: if you don't do it Well enough you don't get anything.
Scott: So let's say you trace the bomb with 86% accuracy.
Scott: All right a bomb with 86% power flies over into the enemy territory where the black balls are and tries to blow them up.
Scott: Let's say you do the left arrow.
Scott: All right, you draw the left arrow with 90% accuracy.
Scott: So with 90% speed all your chickens yellow balls will run to the left side of your court.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: You know would be really good at this game.
Rym: any of our artist friends with a Wacom tablet?
Scott: Probably yeah Wacom tablet would own especially since they can draw Yep.
Scott: But basically you click on the different maneuvers you want to do and attacks you want to execute and then you have to trace the symbol for that attack or Maneuver with better accuracy in order to execute the move better and You try to blow up the other side and not have your side get blowed up.
Rym: That's really cool.
Rym: I kind of like the idea of having Simple direct competition kind of games like that where the skill isn't just knowing what to do But being able to do it which is hard to do in video games without just making like a twitch FPS.
Scott: The thing is the game is sort of real time because you can just keep clicking you can keep doing stuff.
Scott: It's like as soon as you execute a move it like D and once the move executes you can try to do it again.
Scott: So it's it there.
Scott: It's not like a turn-based thing where you do what I do when you do what I do one but at the same time.
Scott: Well, I guess there is nothing else at the same time.
Scott: That's the whole game.
Scott: The only other thing I can say about this game is when you beat levels you unlock power-ups.
Scott: But they're not work power-ups in the game They're power-ups in real life like in the first level.
Scott: if you beat the first level it lets you download a Mario basketball Wallpaper and if you beat level 2 it lets you download some other wallpaper And you get Nintendo goodies for beating levels in this game.
Rym: That's kind of cool.
Scott: Yeah, you could get these goodies at the Nintendo.com website But I guess if you want to get them this way, that's cool, too.
Rym: Well, so I suppose a lot of you especially those who have submitted have been waiting for this for a while But is finally upon us.
Rym: I thus present to you the worst in podcasting awards with Rym and Scott Alright, just to let everyone know these aren't the worst podcasts on the internet?
Rym: far from it in fact.
Scott: we Asked our listeners to nominate podcasts.
Scott: They were thought were the worst and therefore most of these podcasts involve Video games anime and other geeky things like that.
Rym: yes It wasn't so much a what is the worst podcast or who out there sucks?
Rym: It was more of a what can you find with some iTunes dig podcast searching yes?
Scott: And our listeners came through and they submitted many a podcast and pretty much all of which were bad.
Rym: Now before we continue with the actual awards we've got a lot to say because I've learned a lot in listening to a bunch of bad podcasts and also in reading their the writings.
Rym: people sent us about these bad podcasts And there's a lot of similarities between many of these and other ones in general that I listen to that weren't actually submitted.
Scott: So what did all these bad podcasts have in common?
Rym: well one common thread among bad podcast is the repeated?
Rym: unlicensed use of unlicensed music.
Scott: Really you think that like podcasting like the culture of podcasting the podcasting community That's like.
Scott: their number one issue is you know what music can you play?
Scott: play pod safe music only blabbity blah?
Scott: You think that someone being a podcaster would recognize basically the number one thing the community talks about and Do something about it at least acknowledge that you're playing copyrighted music or say something about it.
Rym: now granted many of the people I listen To out there don't seem to be a part of the podcast community.
Scott: I know for a fact that we are not really part of the podcast community not so much But at least partially like I got a toe dipped in there well And I keep my ear to the wall.
Rym: You know we happen to have met a few other podcasters And I noticed that we mostly only listen to their podcasts.
Scott: I listen to other podcasts.
Rym: Yeah, I listen to.
Rym: maybe 50% of my podcast are people I know and the other 50% are just good podcasts mmm.
Scott: I think actually I should increase our involvement in the podcast community.
Rym: well another thing I've noticed is that a lot of really bad podcast really talk up a lot of Podcasting awards that they have won and really I don't eat the only.
Scott: there's so many different people who've tried to make Podcasting awards and all of them that I've seen have been pretty much like who cares well.
Rym: Here's my assessment.
Rym: This is my rims Professional opinion here and by saying professional.
Rym: I hereby lend all sorts of authority.
Rym: No, but I've noticed that web Podcasting awards are almost exactly like web awards were in the early 90s You see does anyone if you might not remember this?
Rym: but way back in the day when websites were new like 1997 98 like when you could go to the bookstore and people would sell for a lot of money Yellow pages of the internet that would list a good percentage of the web pages out there.
Scott: Yeah in those days There were different.
Scott: websites would get awards for being having good design or whatever and basically the way this worked is.
Scott: you would go To a website and you would say you know I nominate my website for the award or something like that.
Scott: And then if they decided that you won the award they would send you an email and say congratulations you won.
Scott: Here's an image to put on your site and people would put a bunch of images on their site of all the awards They won.
Scott: I even did this when I was a punk kid.
Rym: I did too.
Rym: It was right.
Rym: next to that Don't use Netscape Navigator.
Rym: It's garbage icon.
Rym: Yep And and the flaming skull that rotated and said email.
Scott: The lesson that I learned was that the people giving out the awards are much smarter than the people who won the awards because basically You linked that image to the site that gave out the awards so that people knew you weren't just faking it.
Scott: as a result The people who gave out the awards would give the awards to anyone who asked as long as your site wasn't complete crap I at least I don't know.
Scott: maybe they did just give it to anyone who asked.
Rym: furthermore All of these sites that gave out the awards happen to have a lot of ads on the front page yeah,
Scott: and basically they just got links to their site all over the internet and people would come to their site and see ads and they would get a lot of visitors and You would feel good about yourself.
Scott: But really all you did was ask someone to give you an image and they did.
Rym: Yep now a lot of the other awards and podcasting.
Rym: there's a lot of this now to where there's.
Rym: There'll be some sort of web page with the thing and you got to send all your listeners to go and vote for it And then you get people to vote on the internet.
Rym: Yeah, and I don't think I need to explain what's wrong with that.
Scott: It pretty much just comes down to you know, which Podcast got which listeners to go to which award site?
Rym: now I will note for anyone who doubts us look at the the super big professional podcast all the twit stuff things like that.
Rym: How many podcasting awards have they won that are listed on their websites?
Rym: Versus how many awards the five listener podcast about?
Rym: I don't know Animal-crossing has won about the same number.
Scott: The difference is the twit.
Scott: people tend to win the more legitimate awards that happen at like, you know podcasting conferences or things like that or play or Awards where nominations are completely open and no one sends their listeners to go vote in it And it's actually decided by some sort of actual system of some sort.
Scott: Yeah, and these other awards are just like the web Awards.
Scott: Well being that as it may is the webbies are the only real level.
Rym: I hereby declare ribbon Scott of GeekNights to be the runners-up for best podcast.
Rym: best podcast of course being 12 Byzantine emperors If you say so.
Rym: another thing I've noticed is that there's a Direct correlation between how lame a podcast is and how much they try to sell merchandise Really?
Rym: I mean I listen to some bad podcasts and they all had a cafe press and some of them that aren't in this contest.
Rym: the worst they were the more they plugged their cafe press and the more they talked about how much stuff they got for sale and The more they asked for donations the more they tried to make money.
Scott: Hmm Maybe there's some people out there who just want to do this podcasting thing to make money and don't actually care about Podcasting.
Rym: go to the bookstore and look at all the books on podcasting.
Rym: a lot of them are basically how to monetize your podcasting.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's all happened mostly because that stupid MTV guy kept you know marketing the idea of quit your day job Blabbity blah and he's like we're gonna help people quit their day jobs and they can podcast for a living.
Scott: Yeah A lot of people sort of have this dream of not having to do the job They hate and just being able to talk into a microphone and internet all day and that's that's a dream Many people have.
Scott: I live that dream and it sucked so I don't know what you want so badly.
Rym: Yeah I've also noticed that a lot of lame podcast nice not that they have bad websites and that they don't have websites at all.
Rym: They're just a feed in iTunes and I can find neither hide nor hair of them anywhere else on the Internet.
Rym: the feeds often go down.
Rym: Sometimes the feed is just straight-up broken and sends me gibberish.
Rym: instead of mp3s.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of one site one part of the same names as other podcasts.
Scott: Oh God harder.
Rym: Yeah, there's one that actually is already gone as far as I can tell that was submitted for an award.
Rym: Well one of our awards yeah submitted to this contest.
Rym: now before we go any further with this However, I would like to point out a few things.
Rym: that one This is all in good fun.
Rym: If you can't tell.
Rym: if your podcast is mentioned here and you you know saw a bunch of hits and you came and listen to This don't feel bad one.
Rym: We hope that at least some of what we say is constructive criticism - we're not saying you were the worst podcast.
Rym: We're saying you were the worst podcast that our listeners told us about.
Scott: that's what we're saying.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, but also it comes down to you're doing a podcast anyone who is doing something like this anyone who decides that they're going to take their Valuable free time and make free content for the internet and just give it away.
Rym: You're whether you're gonna make music or a webcomic or a blog or a podcast or anything and you're doing this on your own For nothing in return.
Rym: you're already better than everyone in the world who doesn't do anything like that.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much even the worst podcaster in the world the guy who just makes a podcast that sounds like this Hi Yeah, that guy is still better maybe not as a person but as a Constructive creator of content is still better than the guy who sits at home doing nothing about playing World of Warcraft.
Rym: Especially because lately on the internet as time has gone on There's been a lot of this culture of entitlement where there was the error when mp3s you could just get anything you wanted on the internet Download it automatically.
Rym: and then the RIA started suing people and a lot of younger tech guys always like to say yeah information wants to be free free society.
Rym: everyone will just do stuff because they want to and it's gonna be great and you won't have to pay for music or anything.
Rym: and Unless those people are also willing to either help create Facilitate the creation of or in some ways support that free content.
Rym: They're basically just shit talkers.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much It's a good thing.
Scott: enough people are not shit talkers that and we actually do have lots of free music and free podcasts and free Everything.
Rym: Yes so one last time and I can't stress this enough even if we give you the award of the worst podcast from our listeners You're better than most of our listeners who submitted you because most of them don't do anything like this.
Scott: Also, if you hear your podcast mentioned We would hope that you would try to improve your podcast and because you actually probably do have a bad podcast We're not gonna lie too much here.
Rym: Of course due to I guess the full disclosure here I hate 90% of everything.
Rym: Yeah, that includes podcasting.
Rym: So I'll point out that some of the podcasts that were submitted are above average.
Rym: They're well above average for podcasts at least.
Rym: yeah, that's what I'm about to say in terms of podcasting.
Rym: They're so above average and bordering on the upper 10% of podcasts.
Rym: That is amazing But in my eyes, I still don't like him at all.
Rym: All right, so without further ado, all right.
Scott: now We're not gonna go for every single podcast that was submitted by someone We're just gonna go over the finalists.
Rym: So these are the worst of the worst or the most Interesting to talk about because remember I did offer bonus points if your podcast was bad, but had a lot of listeners.
Scott: Yep Okay, so here is the least worst of the finalists.
Rym: Well in order of what percentage of the podcast Scott was able to listen to before he turned it off and discuss.
Scott: that is correct.
Scott: every.
Scott: I listened to two episodes of each of these podcasts and I wrote down how long the episode was and How long I listened to it for before I just turned it off.
Scott: now I didn't actually calculate the percentages.
Scott: So I'm just gonna like estimate here, but We're gonna go by how much of the podcast I listened to.
Scott: so we're gonna start off with this podcast called mech head.
Scott: I listened to episodes 11 and 32.
Scott: I listened to the most recent episode and some random one near the beginning Yep and I listened to a hundred percent of this podcast mostly because episode 11 was seven minutes long and Episode 32 is four minutes long.
Scott: I listened to the whole thing without killing myself.
Scott: Now mech head is a podcast about battle tech.
Scott: this guy basically Reviews mechs in the game of battle tech.
Rym: now before I'd like to read the actual submission from John C Who.
Rym: he's the one who submitted this podcast to us.
Rym: All right, I have this locked down leadpipe lock for the worst of all time.
Scott: Sorry, you didn't win.
Rym: No, in fact you sent us probably the best podcast we heard.
Scott: still bad.
Scott: This is a bad podcast but better than the rest of the finalists were about to go.
Rym: All right, he says it has some of the worst sound quality of all time.
Rym: I beg to differ.
Rym: It is pretty bad.
Rym: It's not that bad though It's.
Scott: it's okay audio quality compared to some of the other ones.
Scott: My number one problem is a problem a lot of podcasts had where the music was a lot louder than the talking.
Rym: Well, he goes on to say the guy has no idea what dynamic range means to someone trying to listen to a show.
Rym: one minute Loud one minute super soft.
Rym: I like how super soft was in all cabs.
Scott: It did not have noise though There wasn't a lot of annoying sounds.
Scott: I mean a couple of times there was some breathing noise.
Scott: that was annoying.
Scott: but other than that, I mean it wasn't like Where I was gonna kill myself.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The podcast is so bad mostly because it doesn't have a terrible theme to make it wretched.
Rym: He basically just seems to think that it's really boring and poorly produced.
Scott: It was boring and poorly poorly produced.
Scott: He had poor transitions.
Scott: like he would just be talking about one thing and then without Transitioning at all would be talking about something else.
Scott: Like he would say what is gonna his show is gonna be about.
Scott: it was like Yeah today.
Scott: I'm gonna talk about Animal Crossing, you know, not Animal Crossing.
Scott: It's a different five Today, I'm gonna talk about the Timber Wolf Mac.
Scott: The Timber Wolf Mac is a bloody bloody bluff, you know, and it's like whoa.
Scott: You just jumped right into it there.
Scott: You kind of lose him and he does that in every episode.
Scott: He didn't change that.
Rym: No I will point out that to someone who doesn't know anything about battle tech or any of that this podcast is useless and I can.
Scott: This podcast doesn't teach you anything about battle tag.
Scott: He assumes you pretty much know all there is to know about the game of battle tech and if you don't know anything You're just gonna be completely lost and say what the fuck?
Rym: Yep Now the guy who sent the email in also says that he found out that supposedly this guy has never played More than two rounds worth of a battle tech game.
Scott: I listened to what he was saying and I've played quite a few battle tech games in my in my day and How many.
Scott: it doesn't matter how much this guy has actually played the game.
Scott: he does have an understanding of the rules and has definitely read the books and What he's saying isn't really useful to a battle tech player.
Scott: like even if you're a battle tech player There's no reason to listen to this show, but he this guy does know what he's talking about a little enough.
Rym: Yeah, when he talked about the max all the things he said were dead on.
Rym: so because this is definitely the best of the podcast We got I have some actual constructive criticism here.
Rym: All this guy needs to do to have a good podcast is one get a better logo.
Rym: He has probably the worst logo in the history of podcast.
Scott: Oh, that's bad because in one of the episodes I think I heard him talking about how he's gonna have a cool new logo soon.
Scott: Oh, well, alright I thought no, but I think that's the one he's referring to.
Rym: really I'm not sure but maybe it looks like someone just kind of Poorly drew the word mech head on a piece of paper and scanned it in off-center.
Rym: Yep, but - all he needs to do is come up with some transitions some good dynamic content and he reviews max Which is okay.
Rym: You can have a podcast about that.
Rym: got to go into more depth He pretty much just describes the mech and what it's good at.
Rym: He doesn't offer much insight.
Rym: Well, I know the guy knows enough about the game where he probably could offer a lot of insight And I think he just needs to tap that.
Scott: I think basically it's we during the world needs a podcast about battle tech.
Scott: There is no question and all this guy has to do to have a good podcast about battle tech and maybe to become the premier Battle tech podcast is all right.
Scott: Your show is seven minutes long about a game.
Scott: That is incredibly strategically deep.
Scott: Good job guy.
Rym: Yeah I could probably talk for an entire week's worth of GeekNights on the various strategies using that.
Scott: Uh, we're doing a battle tech episode.
Scott: I'm adding it to the list.
Scott: Yeah, I think we're gonna have to yep But you just have to say something about the battle tech game that is actually useful Interesting or entertaining and there are a lot of things to say.
Scott: I could think of them right now.
Scott: You just have to say them.
Scott: imagine if someone is a battle tech player.
Scott: They play battle tech every week.
Scott: What do they want to know?
Scott: What do they want to learn and say those things and you'll have a good show?
Rym: Alright, but anyway, we shouldn't dwell on this because we don't want to turn it into the review of one podcast.
Rym: No we don't.
Rym: we're gonna breeze through some of the rest of these because they're.
Rym: This is the top of the tree.
Rym: This is the apex of the pyramid.
Rym: This is as good as it gets.
Scott: I think the next one it would be the Nintendo podcast aka the lithcast.
Scott: now I listened to episodes 30 and 23.
Rym: I'm not sure what I listened to because it was hard to tell if the Nintendo podcast and a lithcast are the same or not.
Scott: Or yes, I'm not I'm not sure.
Scott: but episode 23.
Scott: I listened to two minutes and 45 seconds.
Scott: Oh, no, wait, okay, maybe you got this wrong.
Scott: It looks like it was two hours and 45 minutes long and I listened to five minutes and 17 seconds.
Scott: Oh, and the other one was an hour and 16 minutes long and I lasted seven minutes and 25 seconds.
Rym: Well, Jay Wallace submitted this one and he wrote up a freaking essay on exactly why this podcast is bad.
Rym: I'm not gonna read the whole thing because it's very long, but it's very to the point and very harsh.
Rym: He talks about how the microphone etiquette is bad and the sound quality is bad and the guy says um Okay, and smacks his lips all the time.
Rym: He goes on to say how.
Rym: he emailed the dude and pointed out some of the problems he had with the audio quality in iTunes and the guy responded saying that he got new equipment and Apparently the podcast didn't sound any better afterward.
Scott: Yeah, this guy has the same problem of music too loud talking too quiet.
Scott: There was a lot of pausing and hiccups and stuttering.
Scott: He had bad pronunciation.
Scott: He said Miele instead of melee which granted.
Rym: granted when I was a little kid and I played that Robin Hood game for the NES I never I said the word Miele because I never heard anyone say the word.
Rym: I'd only ever seen it in books.
Scott: Yeah, there was actually another podcast that made the same mistake.
Scott: I'm gonna mention later.
Scott: But yeah, at least this guy recognized that his music was too loud and his voice is too quiet.
Scott: He actually said so much in episode 23.
Scott: Also, it's he seemed reasonably intelligent.
Scott: It's just he didn't say the reasonably intelligent things that it sounded like he knew.
Scott: All he did was say in a monotone completely boring and useless information.
Scott: It was like a bad high school teacher.
Scott: Yep, all I get about Nintendo.
Rym: All he really would need to do is have a writer or plan ahead a little bit and have some I don't again Dynamic content say something interesting.
Scott: I mean he actually got some people onto the show as co-host with Skype and those people didn't really talk so much and He would like ask them stuff and they would answer most of the time with just like two words Like two word answers or three word answers.
Rym: Yes, and there would be pauses, you know We we're here at GeekNights have something I like to call the Rym and Scott sound smarter filter Which does a great many things to our audio.
Rym: One of the things it does is it dynamically reduces silence.
Rym: so if we pause for a second like between bits it gets rid of that and This guy it's like he runs the opposite filter.
Scott: Yeah, there was a whole lot of pausing a whole lot of dead air going on.
Scott: I don't know what he was doing.
Rym: I get the impression that pretty much every podcast from this point on in our show doesn't edit at all.
Rym: I think they literally just record upload record upload.
Scott: That is not good.
Rym: Yes it's one thing I mean if you're doing a live show like actually live where people listen on Skype or talk show or whatever and It's live.
Rym: then you upload it and you do that.
Rym: But if you're not doing that to be live There's no reason to limit yourself to all the problems that are inherent in doing live audio.
Scott: Yeah, it's like why.
Scott: it's like if you're not doing a live concert or a live radio show you have the luxury of Being able to edit it before you give it out to the world.
Scott: Why would you deny yourself a luxury?
Scott: That's like going to a store and they say free ice cream and you say no.
Scott: Thank you.
Scott: What the hell?
Scott: The only other thing I got to say about this guy is that he's he started actually discussing.
Scott: I actually listened to one of the shows long enough for him to discuss a topic and he was talking about why.
Scott: someone asked Him in an email.
Scott: I can't believe someone emailed him why?
Scott: People were all excited about you know new Pokemon games, but they weren't excited about smash brothers brawl Which is kind of a weird question, but he started to answer it and his answer just made no sense.
Scott: There was no logic to his answer at all.
Scott: It was I don't know I don't know what he was trying to say, but it was either wrong or Pointless or meaningless.
Rym: Yeah, honestly if I weren't tired I would have pulled up that audio and played it just so you could hear it.
Rym: But I got enough audio clips to deal with here.
Scott: Yeah, so she moved to the next show.
Rym: I think so because pretty much from this point on we're going down into the debt.
Scott: All right, the next podcast up for bashing is anime pulse.
Scott: I am Ichigo.
Scott: I'm Bato Charlie Max help me out.
Scott: You're gonna get.
Scott: you're gonna get phalons calendar way.
Scott: No new new Okay fine, so this is the anime pulse podcast and We are here bringing you the love do I do?
Scott: do I need to step it up a notch or something like that?
Rym: BAM I?
Rym: Still got plenty of water.
Scott: What you said you're gonna?
Scott: The story revolves around a young girl named coup coup coup, okay a Shirotori.
Rym: this was submitted to us by Gabe, and I'm not gonna read his whole paragraph.
Rym: It's not very long.
Rym: He says that the show is a lot of potential basically and that they could live up to.
Rym: I guess all the accolades He's heard about them except for the fact that quote they deliberately talk over each other during their segments.
Rym: It pisses me off to no end between that and their propensity to eat directly into the microphone I want to rip my hair out and shove down their bleeding maws.
Rym: all right.
Scott: Well.
Scott: Let's talk about Well anime pulse.
Scott: Let's see I listened to episode 73 and 69.
Rym: I'd heard of anime pulse But I didn't really know who did it and I had never actually heard it until it was submitted to our contest.
Scott: yep Episode 69 was about 90 minutes long.
Scott: I listened to about 10 minutes and 36 seconds and Episode 73 was little over an hour, and I was able to listen for seven minutes before force.
Scott: I couldn't listen anymore now.
Rym: This is where it gets interesting because anime pulse is audio quality Technically is far superior to many of these other podcasts.
Scott: Yeah, it was actually pretty good.
Scott: they still had the problem of.
Scott: music is a lot louder than talking and You know some of the volumes would be kind of uneven.
Scott: one guy louder than another guy.
Scott: well part of that guy moving farther away And closer to the mic.
Rym: it's obvious that they have one Omnidirectional mic in the room and they all just kind of talk at it And they make a lot of noise in the background.
Rym: Constantly people are poking at things and popping at things and eating and I hear stuff going on and things bumping into other things.
Rym: But other than that the audio quality is better than most podcasts out there.
Rym: however Despite that and they're relatively high production values It's obvious that they don't edit at all or if they do they leave a lot in that they shouldn't leave in.
Rym: Lot of pausing um's and ah's and just the podcast trails off constantly.
Rym: and the worst thing is one of the guys in the background.
Rym: It's like he constantly just yells random things.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: There's a guy.
Scott: I don't know who it is chocolate.
Rym: Yeah They just yell out Yeah chicken, it's just not funny at all It's just annoying.
Scott: this podcast in general it felt to me like they had a lot of intentionally planned out jokes beforehand Or a lot of like they just had impulsive jokes You know like they thought they were being spontaneous like haha spontaneous funny thing.
Scott: that just came to mind But none of it was funny.
Scott: It was just incredibly annoying.
Scott: These are the kind of guys it was obviously apparent after listening to this shows for a few minutes.
Scott: You know when you go to an anime convention and you stand in line and a guy comes up to you And he just starts talking at you, and this is not a guy you want to talk to.
Scott: he's an annoying guy.
Scott: He's saying things you don't care about he's telling you about his hentai collection or whatever and you just want him to go away.
Scott: This podcast anime pulse is made by those kind of guys.
Scott: It's just three of those guys talking to each other now.
Rym: aside from that it takes them forever to get to what they actually talk About and to not go into a lot of detail.
Rym: Whenever they get finally on topic they actually do what their shows about they were.
Scott: I never got to that point.
Rym: so tell me I forced myself to listen to a whole episode and then half of another episode And then I went to a third episode and skip to the review part.
Rym: whoa they review shallow anime And they review it in a shallow manner.
Rym: so not only do they watch shows that are the equivalent of kagehime They're just garbage anime.
Rym: There's shows that we watch the first episode of and they're not even worth talking about on the show.
Rym: They're just garbage.
Scott: Well.
Scott: I mean are they reviewing them in the Dave and Joel style of wow this suck.
Rym: No, they're reviewing them in the.
Rym: I really like this anime And they rate it on this scale.
Rym: they rate every anime, and I haven't figured out the scale But I've heard such ratings as burn it crackers and like super crackers.
Scott: so I guess crackers is good and burn it is bad something like that.
Rym: and The anime.
Rym: the review is just abhorrent and terrible and they don't provide any insight.
Rym: like the reviews Are could be okay if you took a bad show and reviewed it fully.
Rym: like anime world order does.
Rym: it'd be good.
Rym: But they review it in such a shallow manner that I would learn more by reading the frickin Wikipedia about that show.
Scott: Okay, like what do they just say what happened in the show?
Scott: like this show is about blah.
Scott: This is what happened.
Scott: yeah, the main themes of the show or this?
Rym: the main genres are that and they kind of trail off a lot and they focus on fan service bids.
Rym: and It's just I. it's bad.
Scott: Those are the people who like fan service.
Rym: They like the kind of shows that we make fun of as being stupid.
Scott: ah so they're the reason anime sucks in the u.s.
Scott: I buy it all this shit now.
Scott: I know who to beat up at the next convention.
Rym: They also really seem pro bootleg And there's a whole bit in one of the recent episodes where they were talking about fansub groups And they seem to get mad if a show gets licensed and the fansubbers stop fansubbing Like they got mad at some fansubbing group for dropping their fansubs.
Rym: if I think it was death note after I got licensed Cuz it was licensed fools.
Rym: They also spend a lot of time.
Rym: They watch one piece Naruto in bleach, and they review the most recent episode which basically comes down to So so and so far so and so and it was awesome and then so and so far so and so and it was awesome.
Scott: All right listen if you're someone who likes those shows you're gonna watch them, and if you watch them I mean they could be just summed up in like a few sentences like so and so far so and so so.
Scott: I guess if you Like those shows you don't want to spend the time to watch them.
Scott: That's a decent service because now you don't have to watch 30 minutes.
Scott: You can get the whole thing in two minutes from these guys.
Scott: however if you don't like those shows You really don't want someone describing them to you.
Scott: Yeah, if you do watch the shows you don't need someone describing them to you.
Scott: So who is that for?
Scott: really?
Scott: it's for people who like it, but don't want to watch it Which is so few people now again?
Rym: It would be okay if They at least provided some insight.
Rym: or I mean I could see where if you watch the show and you've talked about it every week You could provide a lot of running commentary or insight or point out like notice how this character is fighting with this character.
Rym: But yet he says this line well if you go back to episode 23 remember that dream sequence.
Rym: yeah That's where they're going with this metaphor metaphor or things like that.
Scott: or the music in this episode was actually done by so-and-so as a Blah-blah-blah, but I think the problem is is that these shows are so shallow that those things just don't exist to be talked about.
Rym: But they could do more.
Rym: I stand by the statement that they review shallow anime in a shallow manner.
Rym: Yeah, I beyond all that the best part Clarissa from anime roll order went nuts about Complaining that Scott was supposedly sexist because he asked if some manga Was why some manga that was in a shonen magazine was published in shoujo magazine.
Rym: none of that matters.
Rym: We talked about it yesterday, but if she wants to get mad about sexist anime podcasters I submit the following from anime fucking pulse We like see.
Scott: we like CPM.
Scott: John's a good guy.
Scott: I'm good guy.
Scott: his wife runs a yaoi label called be beautiful.
Scott: I'm not too thrilled with that.
Scott: Well, you know you gotta let the women have their side projects.
Scott: Oh, yeah, this is purely a guy's Thing but then they'll turn around and you're like wait a minute.
Scott: No.
Scott: This is this is something for the girls Something for the ladies, but you know, it's out of a shonen magazine.
Scott: I really have a hard time seeing this being in a shonen magazine, honestly Crab chips.
Scott: And one of the things that makes me really think that this is more of a girl's anime or girls story is because it revolves around her life and the way she sees things.
Scott: and and one of the things that helped me think that this was more a Series for girls was like the animation styling.
Scott: The girls were drawn very beautifully, but so were the guys.
Scott: like the guys are sound very very be shown it You know, they use a lot of pastel colors.
Scott: but then you get these moments of Purely guy thing where like you got the one girl gonna be helping another girl have a bath, you know scrubbing your back for whoo.
Scott: I couldn't figure out who this was written for because there's a lot of action in it But at the same time they're sitting there and they're discussing the feelings of something or you know These relate to each other.
Scott: It's like this isn't what goes on in an action.
Rym: So there is action in it.
Scott: Yes But there's a lot of dialogue that has nothing to do with the shonen.
Rym: So, uh, I expect a tirade next week.
Rym: Yes
Scott: The only other things I could say about anime policy is to seal it up is that they read every single email Regardless of whether it's useful or not which is annoying as hell and It seems like only one guy on the show has command and the other people are just the interrupting guys and those interrupting guys Have to go.
Scott: if this one guy just did the show in his own it would probably double the quality.
Scott: still I wouldn't listen to it.
Scott: I wouldn't listen to it still because it still wouldn't be good.
Scott: But maybe if he got another co-host that was intelligent then he could have a show might be worth listening.
Rym: That's all he needs to do.
Rym: get rid of all those other people.
Rym: maybe get one or two other new people who are good or just do the show himself and Do a little bit of research and have any Any more insight than he currently has.
Rym: yeah Because even if he doesn't go to the depth that like anime world order does or the hilarity that David Joel do in the very Least he's reviewing stuff that most people wouldn't review.
Rym: There aren't many podcasts about that kind of anime and while I don't like that kind of anime if you reviewed that kind of anime Well and had some insight.
Rym: It'd probably be okay and you'd have a market.
Rym: All right all right.
Rym: now further into the rabbit hole We're gonna.
Scott: we're gonna talk about a podcast now.
Scott: that was the first one I listened to of all the bunch and as soon as I listened to it.
Scott: I said this is the winner.
Scott: This is the worst podcast that anyone submitted, but I was wrong now.
Scott: There are worse podcasts that were submitted.
Rym: We don't have to say a lot about it.
Rym: I'm just gonna play an opening bid from it here, and I think you will gather everything.
Rym: We will have to say oh Recorded live here we go.
Scott: Welcome to this episode of Animal Crossing and other games.
Rym: Hello, everybody.
Scott: This is episode 25 Titled Pogo Island DS.
Rym: Which is the game we're going to talk about?
Scott: It is an exchange for tickets and drawings for prizes.
Scott: There are three types of free accounts, which is the $50 daily the $250 weekly The $1,000 monthly.
Scott: Now for the clone Pogo members, which are the paid accounts?
Rym: you have the those three drawings?
Scott: and you have the This miscellaneous drawing which will have something random usually of around a $500 value And the current one is a scrapbook game.
Scott: The podcast is called Animal Crossing and other games.
Scott: I listened to episode 3 which is about Halo 2 and episode 25 about Pogo Island DS.
Scott: I listened to.
Scott: let's see the episode 3 was 10 minutes long.
Scott: I turned it off after 4 minutes and episode 25 was 16 minutes long And I also turned it off after 4 minutes.
Rym: now I give this kid props for trying and I don't know what else I can say.
Rym: really He if his audio quality were better That'd be a big step because you can't really even understand what he's saying.
Scott: No, this guy is doing his podcast with talk shoe, which is that thing that lets you have listener partition participation and such But he's not using it.
Scott: Well because I've heard you know twit uses talk shoe now To do stuff and their audio quality is still awesome, so this guy is doing something He's basically not caring about.
Scott: audio quality is constant hissing and static.
Scott: I mean episode 25 had worse audio quality than episode 3. he blows into the mic.
Scott: It's just God if the audio quality here is the worst audio quality.
Rym: now Here's another interesting point.
Rym: anime pulse has good production quality if the content was to in our opinion in a word Garbage.
Rym: by the same token this kid has probably the worst audio quality in podcasting and yet and yet his show is Relatively coherent and together and he's obviously trying to keep it in what a single thread.
Rym: He's got his little topics and segues He's he's got his act together better than the audio quality would lead you to believe yes The thing is his voice is really nerdy.
Scott: He says uh a lot and I mean he talks about Halo 2 for 10 minutes.
Scott: I mean, what are you gonna say in 10 minutes?
Scott: That's not very.
Scott: you know he doesn't say anything meaningful But he's obviously trying really hard.
Scott: he obviously cares He's obviously putting in the effort.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: I think that's.
Scott: I don't know if he has more potential than that.
Scott: I mean you might have just be that's the best he can do.
Scott: It could be that he doesn't sound like he's a kid that can do much more than that.
Scott: He also sounds like a really young kid like he must be in elementary or middle school probably.
Scott: So maybe this is the best a middle school podcast can be but a middle school podcast Is still not as good as a better podcast.
Rym: now.
Rym: this was submitted by water is poison and quote.
Rym: I present to you the animal crossing and other games podcast.
Rym: I'm not exactly sure what it is about because it's too hard to listen to.
Rym: He goes on a bit.
Rym: the episodes range from one minute long to an hour and a half.
Scott: Really I didn't see any of those hour-and-a-half ones.
Rym: I didn't try.
Rym: okay now you might think well isn't that the bottom?
Scott: No it is not the bottom.
Scott: now we got two left here I want to talk about but one of them might be ineligible.
Scott: you want to talk about the ineligible one first?
Rym: Yeah We'll do that one first because if this Podcast had met the rules of submission and the person who submitted it even stated straight up that it does not meet the rules of submission But it was so bad that there was no way it couldn't be brought up.
Rym: and good fucking God.
Scott: Yes, so the podcast that was.
Scott: if this was eligible to win the contest according to the rules We mentioned at the beginning when we announced the contest originally this would be the winner.
Scott: this would be the worst podcast I've ever heard also.
Rym: It was submitted by the one the only Jeff to Tarek whoa Jeff to Terry and quote.
Rym: I'll read his whole email.
Rym: I nominate the i-game podcast.
Rym: it hasn't been updated since August 2006 so it's automatically ineligible But I don't care.
Rym: Why is it bad?
Rym: It's little more than some kids talking shit over their cell phones acting cooler than they could possibly be.
Rym: not only that But they just talk all over each other.
Rym: It's painful.
Scott: Basically I listened to episode 21 and I listened to another episode which didn't have a number But was called our debate.
Scott: the our debate episode was four minutes.
Scott: I didn't last to.
Scott: the episode 21 was 13 minutes.
Scott: I lasted less than two.
Scott: It's though.
Scott: It's the audio quality might be actually worse than the Animal Crossing guy.
Scott: It's all scratchy and and it just.
Scott: it just couldn't be worse.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it really does sound like kids talking over their cell phones.
Rym: like Jeff says there isn't actually a show It's just nothing.
Rym: I listen to one episode.
Rym: It's just.
Scott: it sounds like elementary school kids yelling at each other about Nothing.
Scott: It's like if you had a conference call with some fifth graders And they were talking about who was smarter.
Scott: that go brainy brainy poo Stupidy doo-doo head.
Rym: now the worst thing about this is that there's.
Rym: no I couldn't find the podcast at first.
Scott: I had some trouble because there are a bunch of other Podcasts also called I game and there are a bunch of other things called I game that aren't podcasts.
Rym: And when I went to download it so I could grab some clips the link was broken, and it was gone.
Rym: Luckily, it's still on my iPod Again.
Rym: Humidity there, but still it's hot.
Rym: let's skip a bit.
Rym: Maybe it gets better Based on science or whatever Except ninja consultant who is revealing this?
Rym: please all right?
Rym: I can't I can't.
Rym: I had to turn that off.
Scott: It's just kids yapping at each other.
Scott: There's nothing that human beings want to listen to less than kids yapping at each other.
Scott: Me even Bill Cosby said it best when he said parents don't want justice.
Scott: They just want quiet.
Scott: We don't want to listen to kids talking.
Scott: shut up kids shut up now.
Scott: Now it was I don't.
Rym: it's hard to describe how painful it was to try to listen to this and I Tried.
Rym: I resolved that I was gonna listen to all of at least one episode of everything that anyone submitted.
Scott: well You're a braver soul than I.
Rym: I made it 45 Seconds on this and whoa I lasted a few minutes.
Rym: Only reason I made it 45 seconds was that I was going down the taconic at about 90 miles an hour And there was some traffic ahead, and you couldn't reach it to turn it off.
Rym: I could not take my hand off the wheel to stop it.
Rym: I Couldn't make it stop.
Rym: so Jeff to Tarik even though you cannot win the contest you're going to be getting a prize anyway Because I'm not sure how you found it.
Rym: I knew what it was and I had trouble finding it.
Rym: you gave me a link and I had trouble finding it.
Rym: This is probably the worst audio on the internet.
Scott: It just if it's not.
Scott: I'd like to see what is because goddamn well I anything worse than this starts to get crosses the line where you know it's like you don't have.
Scott: some things are so bad.
Rym: They're good, right Yeah, like if you watch an old robot show.
Rym: most people don't pretend They're good.
Rym: even people who love robot shows won't say with a straight face that this is some deep meaningful show.
Rym: Some of them are but not many yeah, but many of them aren't and most you know which ones are rich.
Scott: Yes, but yeah, this is basically.
Scott: you're about to cross the line where it's so bad.
Scott: It's good, but they didn't cross the line.
Scott: It's just so bad and it's the worst there is.
Rym: and the reason Animal Crossing and other games is better than this is Because at least that was a show Regardless of the problems the kids having doing his show.
Rym: it was a show.
Rym: There is a concept.
Rym: the kid is following through with the concept.
Rym: He has a format He talks in an order that somewhat makes sense.
Scott: Yeah, this is just nothing.
Scott: This is just kids talking to each other all right.
Scott: now the worst Podcast that was submitted to us.
Rym: What's the deal with these?
Scott: bad vodka that is eligible for the contest according to our Rules is called powerup now.
Rym: I'm just gonna play a clip, and I think well I don't know what else we'll need to say.
Scott: All views expressed in this podcast and not a video game buddy and belong to the participants of powerup My nose Good computer to 1999.
Rym: Like they're pumping money into these businesses like it's going out of style making the rich richer making themselves poorer stupider and fatter.
Rym: and God bless America.
Scott: And what's up everybody?
Scott: Like wacka's Today.
Scott: for all you probably people that listen to us on the weekly base You broke up real badly, I broke up really.
Scott: yeah, yeah, hey well I didn't hear it.
Scott: I heard music the whole time.
Rym: You heard nothing.
Scott: Well, maybe that was the sound effect I was going for.
Rym: Hey, who's that guy?
Scott: we already completed another episode of powerup because I wasn't paying attention to the sounds.
Scott: Yeah, it's hard.
Scott: I'm getting fucking.
Scott: I am again by.
Rym: It's basically as far as I can tell.
Rym: imagine if you gave a bunch of 14 year olds phones
Scott: Yep, and then
Rym: you set up some sort of Big Brother spy thing where whenever they had a conference call with each other You just recorded it,
Scott: and they're all friends, so they have stuff to talk about that with each other.
Scott: That's powerup.
Scott: That's it now.
Scott: What's good about powerup.
Scott: There is one thing.
Scott: That's good.
Scott: their opening music was actually relevant.
Scott: It was an OC remix of some sort, but they played the same one for every episode.
Scott: I thought they were gonna mix it up, but they didn't.
Scott: nah Let's see why was this podcast so bad.
Scott: Let's see everyone has an annoying voice.
Scott: the audio quality is terrible.
Scott: They even said that they don't care about audio quality.
Scott: They don't edit and they're proud of it.
Scott: They have to say I don't know if it's the same guy, but it might as well be the same interrupting guy from anime pulse.
Scott: they spent like a lot of time just making fun of each other as People would if they knew each other.
Scott: and why do I want to listen to other people make fun of each other?
Scott: I don't know how they have a girl on this show, but they treat the girl like shit and the girl just Talks to them like you know.
Scott: blah blah blah.
Scott: you guys are all just pissed cuz I'm not with you And she doesn't say anything interesting.
Scott: none of them say anything interesting.
Rym: It's like being in a room with a bunch of 14 year olds who are two feet shorter than you and think they're tougher than You and they're all talking shit to each other.
Scott: They're all have different volume levels.
Scott: They all have annoying voices.
Scott: They spend the entire pod well as much of the podcast as I listen to.
Scott: they pretty much just bickered the entire time.
Rym: Isn't this the one that has really freaking long episodes?
Scott: - yes Episode 25 was two and a half hours long.
Scott: I lasted less than four minutes.
Scott: Episode 60 was two hours and 49 minutes long.
Scott: I lasted five minutes.
Scott: that the worst part of this podcast is actually something very specific.
Rym: in episode 60 some guy was making horrible mouth noises into the microphone like ah Actually that happens a lot in anime pulse, but yes, not nearly as badly.
Scott: Did you just listen to me making those math noises right now?
Scott: wasn't that incredibly painful ah?
Scott: Stop doing that again.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, and keep in mind.
Rym: That's with a downward expander getting rid of much of that.
Scott: yeah um I just made That is the worst noise One of the worst noises you could possibly make.
Scott: I mean they might as well have made a podcast of chalkboard scratch Nails on a chalkboard and it would have been just as bad.
Scott: Just the noise that is coming out of the headphones listening to power-up makes me want to put a knife in my ear and I'm almost would have put a knife in my ear if it weren't for the ability to turn it off Which I did.
Rym: now of course we just did a show here on worst podcast ever and power-up wins the contest.
Rym: however Because I'm totally unprofessional now in a stroke of irony I actually don't have the email with the submission in front of me, so I don't know who submitted it really.
Rym: however I can look that up handily.
Scott: Okay, I found it.
Scott: the winner is DJ.
Rym: Jen I DJ.
Rym: Jen I we're hoping to meet someday at a con cuz he's pretty cool.
Scott: Yep Let's see let's I'm gonna read his email cuz it's short.
Scott: all right two GeekNights.
Scott: It would have to be power-up site feed links whatever.
Rym: Oh here.
Rym: It is wow he has nice bullet points.
Scott: They have more than 10 minutes just to take care of technical difficulties And they don't edit it out now.
Rym: compare that to Dave and Joel where they often would record themselves having audio Difficulties, but yet it was still funny.
Scott: Yeah Or they'd use that as the like the stinger at the end of the show.
Scott: ah the stinger poor Organization too much steering away from the game topics.
Scott: one of the guys shouldn't be on radio at all.
Scott: more of an interference than useful Kind of like chocolate Interrupting guy.
Scott: yeah glitches galore lots of audio crap audio levels Random laptop beeping from overheating.
Scott: sometimes they throw racial jokes slurs handicapped jokes etc.
Rym: a segment But I believe Scott you mean etc.
Scott: Etc.
Rym: I only reason I bring that up because I was gonna rag on two of these podcasts for saying etc.
Rym: wrong And then I forgot to.
Rym: so I had to at least rag on you for that.
Scott: Yeah, and a segment where they mentioned games coming soon.
Scott: the girl talks like.
Scott: it's off-core phone sex, and she's underage Outstanding.
Scott: yeah these is basically a bunch of trashy teens talking to each other Occasionally about video games, and it is the worst podcast eligible for our contest.
Scott: DJ Do now you have one and we will send you a prize.
Rym: yes, however We will be contacting all of our finalists and probably sending all of you some form of prize because every one of you did your Part and provided us with a lot of pain a lot of agony, but also a lot of entertainment.
Scott: Yes, do not be surprised if your contest prizes are actually revenge in an envelope.
Rym: Now also again like I said at the beginning one this was all in good fun, and two this is our 289th episode.
Rym: give or take yeah, and We've come a long way.
Rym: I mean GeekNights used to sound like this Sit far away If I talk.
Rym: So we're kind of shot today because all we really want to talk about is Jack Thompson.
Rym: So I don't blame any podcast ever for having trouble getting started And I wish the best of luck to all of our finalists and our finalists submissions.
Scott: however if you're on episode a lot and you haven't improved or in fact you have Not improved and gone downhill from your earlier episodes Just stop.
Scott: I mean it's one thing for people to complain about pod fading But in some cases pod fading is the way to go sort of like sometimes just got to put the pet to sleep.
Scott: It's it's too sick.
Scott: It's better to let it die than to keep it alive.
Rym: now our listeners had better be warned because if anyone ever crosses our ire We'll probably just replace our random episodes in our feed with i-game Cuz.
Rym: luckily even though it seems to have disappeared.
Rym: Maybe it'll come back.
Rym: I've got several hours of it on my iPod and in iTunes And I'm gonna keep that around cuz.
Scott: that's a powerful weapon that is you could just if people are being annoying.
Rym: in fact the next time People the visit costs are at our house And I need the dishes to be done.
Rym: I games going on and not coming off so someone starts doing dishes.
Scott: I got to order that amp and those speakers then so we can crank it up real loud.
Rym: Yes, especially put a lockbox over the powers.
Rym: They can't unplug it.
Rym: Oh I'm all about this.
Rym: Yeah Alright stay tuned next week when I'm not gonna tell you what we're doing next week.
Scott: But I ain't gonna tell you a secret though.
Scott: We've managed to plan out episodes weeks in advance?
Rym: Yes, in fact in in certain days.
Rym: Uh-huh Wednesdays anime days We've got pretty much the next several months easily available to us.
Scott: Yeah, I mean we used to come home every day from work and say huh, what do we do the show on tonight?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: What should we do the show on?
Scott: so in a secret Google Calendar?
Scott: Not accessible to the rest of you fools We have written down what shows we're doing on what days and we planned out topics for weeks to come.
Scott: But we still need Thursdays because you only got like two or three Thursdays planned.
Scott: so send us Thursday ideas.
Rym: Yes, now of course for those of you who don't listen to Thursday remember that Thursday Thursday.
Scott: yeah in a Thursday podcast real smart.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Yeah, it is Thursday, isn't it?
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Rym: Oh, well This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.