Rym: It's Wednesday October 24th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: final thoughts try gun.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So last week in questions week.
Rym: I remember one of the questions was what anime in the upcoming season you excited about.
Rym: We didn't really answer it.
Scott: All right.
Scott: This is what we were gonna.
Scott: Do is the opening bit.
Rym: well I finally got around to watching some of the anime from this season and Cody.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: well, it's not Cody.
Scott: It's code E in code Code and then the letter E as in Cody.
Scott: yes, no.
Scott: well you said it sort of like Cody like cod y Cody It's code.
Rym: I definitely emphasize the.
Scott: yes It's a good show.
Scott: he watched one episode, and I want to see more episodes.
Rym: so far It's my favorite show this season.
Rym: just because it's it Reminded me a lot.
Rym: just the character designs and the way they moved and moved their mouths and just a project echo like.
Scott: it's one of those cute funny Remind me a project a carrot.
Rym: Yeah They did.
Rym: Emily said the same thing too especially the one girl when her mouth like.
Rym: the way mouths open Widely is a lot like how mouths open widely in project a Cohen I guess The girl who likes show even if it's not like the girl who likes the boy Not the main character, but the other girl.
Scott: Yeah, okay, kinda.
Rym: Yeah pretty much exactly.
Scott: Maybe we should look and see if there are any creators in common.
Rym: I haven't looked at anything yet.
Rym: I'm just saying that it reminded me a lot of project echo, and it's just.
Rym: it's a really cute show And it's not creepy and moe.
Scott: no it's definitely surprising because you look at it And I mean there's like six or seven moe shows this season.
Scott: It's like fuck fuck fuck fuck fuck right.
Scott: and like some of the ones that aren't moe I checked him out like I checked out I think rental magica Which had a pretty good premise of you know renting magicians to help you out when you had problems.
Scott: that sucked.
Scott: That was a crap show.
Rym: well.
Scott: I expected as much yeah, but now the Cody is good This ghost hound is that what it's called.
Scott: I think that's a massive moon a shiro slash project studio I G or production IG whatever you want to call them show, but I haven't watched that yet.
Scott: So we get to see on that.
Scott: there's doubt it could be bad.
Rym: There's the yuri kind of sci-fi and space show.
Scott: I forget what that's called.
Rym: drop blue drop blue drop.
Scott: you're right.
Rym: that show gives me all the vibes That moonlight mile gave me before I actually saw moonlight man.
Scott: We haven't seen this so we'll watch blue drop And then we'll tell you how it is.
Rym: But I got to say just from skimming through and looking at like the opening bit It feels like how I felt about moonlight mile.
Rym: like this is gonna be some hardcore serious sci-fi.
Rym: But I in what I saw and what we watch so far not one Sherpa had sex.
Rym: So I got some high hopes could be somewhere between moonlight mile and to Tara if that's where it is.
Rym: That's pretty much Uncharted awesome waters right.
Scott: it's not a bad place to be for sure.
Rym: that's a really good place to be.
Scott: we haven't watched that one though, and there's only two other shows to mention and that is the Gundam show which is okay?
Scott: Yeah, I watched two episodes and the first episode was mostly shooting and the second episode was better.
Rym: The premise is good like I could see where it's going.
Rym: I kind of like that.
Rym: It's different from other Gundams.
Rym: I could dig it, but at the same time I I don't really like the character designs.
Scott: the character design is pretty crummy But Gerald from animal order said that some like Bisha Shown in like boys love character designer designed all the characters.
Rym: I mean the women's breasts.
Rym: Just don't look right.
Rym: They're way too big, and they're just Bloons full of helium.
Scott: is what they are.
Rym: that and I'll be honest the show is a little Heavy-handed, it's kind of like it's set in our world.
Scott: I know it's it's tough because on the one hand right It's sort of this heavy-handed, but they didn't do anything interesting with the heavy-handed.
Rym: It's like right look at the United States.
Scott: But this on the other hand right they've got it's sort of like the heavy-handed is gets the obvious shit out of the way Right away like in the second episode.
Scott: They're like yeah the obvious Contradiction to fighting war with war.
Scott: and it's like Gundam shows used to be at the end like you know the whole time at the End they'd be like yeah fighting war with war doesn't work.
Scott: and like the 26th episode of the 50th episode now They're getting that out of the way.
Scott: and the second episode which gives me a tiny Hope that the rest of it will be something new and interesting.
Scott: I guess that's sort of a I don't know I Expectation.
Rym: I have really dubious Dubious, but it's possible.
Rym: the characters as they've been introduced feel really shallow.
Rym: now They could make him with more depth.
Rym: I mean there could be a lot more things.
Scott: because whereas in other Gundams right they sort of introduce some of the characters and they Sort of expand to give you the bigger picture over time You know they start with like just some kids and then they expand out.
Scott: this one is like starts showing you everything.
Scott: So the first episode is like you to see each character for like five seconds.
Rym: But even like when you see him just like they all react like half the people are like mysterious.
Rym: Oh, it's begun say something cryptic and look off to the camera.
Scott: We're gonna yeah, let's not do a whole episode on it, but yeah it.
Scott: if you like Gundams you like it.
Rym: I guess we'll see.
Rym: I'm really I hate to say a little pessimistic about this.
Scott: It's on an episode by episode basis sort of like when some You're one of your athletes is on the the day-to-day injury list which means you know their day-to-day.
Scott: They might be playing today not playing all the shows.
Rym: I'm given a chance this season.
Rym: It's my least liked one.
Scott: Yeah, the one the one there was oh the under arrest.
Scott: you're under arrest.
Scott: There's a new.
Scott: you're under arrest, and if you don't know about.
Scott: you're under arrest.
Scott: It's very old I guess not very old, but it's.
Scott: it's sort of a somewhat classic.
Rym: It's one of those old awesome show.
Scott: it's sort of like for the 80s 90s ish kind of thing.
Scott: It's a funny show.
Scott: all I knew.
Scott: I never actually saw it even though I knew about it and knew it was good.
Rym: It's one of those slice-of-life camaraderie shows.
Scott: Yes, it's a it's a buddy show about like two women on the police force.
Rym: You know about them.
Rym: You know what it's about.
Rym: It's about all the awesome side character.
Scott: pretty much Yeah, but they are you know they're actually interesting.
Scott: the main characters though They're not you know it's not like one of those shows.
Scott: the side characters are awesome.
Scott: in the main character suck It's.
Scott: the main characters are good and the side characters are more good.
Scott: But yeah, there's a new season of it I guess and you know not.
Scott: no not ever having watched it before, but only knowing the you know the most Publicly known details about it.
Scott: I you know had a little bit of.
Scott: there were some spots where it's like.
Scott: yeah I don't get this because I don't know these characters like I'm supposed to but it's definitely an anime made now.
Scott: But in the say they haven't changed the style.
Scott: it feels like.
Scott: you know you gave some people from like 1995 2007 animation technology And they just made a show the way they knew how to make one and if you like You know that kind of anime if you like you're under arrest already.
Scott: You should probably watch this.
Scott: It was funny, and I'd never seen you're under arrest before.
Rym: so right so in the news.
Rym: I don't have a lot to say about this, but people are talking about it.
Rym: The Japanese government has formally requested slash demanded that the u.s.
Rym: Government do something about all this anime piracy going on in America And they.
Rym: one of the reasons they cited for this request was that it's very difficult to Actually go after or prosecute anyone over international boundaries for copyright, especially When the things they're going after are you know peer-to-peer kind of things to begin with where it's hard to even say who did it?
Rym: Basically they admitted that they can't get the fan subbers And they're hoping that the US government might have a little bit more truck Fun.
Rym: I Don't think this is relevant at all.
Rym: I think the real fear they have is not that there's anime piracy going on the US.
Rym: I think the fear is that more and more Japanese people sick of Insane DVD prices and sick of having to watch on TV with commercials or something are just downloading American fan Subs.
Scott: I say go them.
Scott: if you are Japanese in Japan download our fan subs.
Scott: They are gift to you.
Rym: How don't you just buy our DVDs?
Rym: You'll still save a lot of money.
Scott: Yeah, buy our DVDs.
Scott: What do you know?
Scott: you don't need to see them right away?
Scott: I mean you could see stuff on TV.
Scott: you understand Japanese if you're living in Japan right?
Scott: so you know watch it on TV And then you watch it again.
Scott: Just wait for our DVDs to come out.
Scott: who cares?
Scott: It's a long time.
Scott: you're not in any kind of rush.
Scott: You got more new anime on TV.
Rym: I just really like how this is basically like oh, we're gonna We want to go after those people, but you really should stop price gouge.
Rym: No, but if you read between the lines it really says we're powerless to go after these people.
Rym: There is nothing we can do to stop these people.
Rym: They're pretty much able to get away with whatever they want.
Scott: We can't do anything.
Scott: Please do something.
Rym: so uh yeah, take that as you will.
Scott: all right My news is sort of I guess off ICV - which is I don't know exactly what that stands for.
Scott: I think it stands for something comics version - I'm not sure But I know that it's a it's part.
Scott: It's a company.
Scott: That's sort of like a sub company of diamond distributors in some way.
Scott: I'm not yeah, but anyway.
Scott: They are hosting an Industry conference before the New York anime festival, so it's not part of the New York anime festival.
Scott: like you Can't get into this conference with your New York anime festival badge.
Scott: It's not gonna happen.
Rym: Yeah, and this is not a conference or a convention or anything like that for I guess you guys out there fans This is one of those pay a whole bunch of money to see a bunch of big wigs talk about it.
Scott: This is sort of like one of those.
Scott: the very the big wigs in the industry Hold a one-day conference for the little wigs in the industry You know to come and learn from the big wigs.
Scott: and what?
Scott: basically all the big names in the u.s.
Scott: Anime and manga industry they're all listed on anime news network But some of the big ones are Kurt hassler who is pretty much Single-handedly responsible for all the manga at the shelves at your bookstore.
Scott: You should kiss his feet.
Scott: The person Lawrence Nevis, I think that's how you say.
Scott: the name is the editorial director of Pokemon in the USA.
Scott: This is the Pokemon guy in the u.s.. He controls all your pokemons.
Scott: does he have?
Scott: he caught them all ten times?
Rym: I'm not even gonna make the joke.
Scott: You got the at the anime news network the top guy at anime news network.
Scott: You got James Killen the person who buys all the graphic novels for Barnes & Noble.
Scott: so this person's job Is just decide which graphic novels manga and otherwise are on the shelves in Barnes & Noble and which ones are not.
Scott: His job is to spend Barnes & Noble's money on comics.
Scott: That's what his job is and a lot of other equally important people and They're gonna give like you know four panels or so.
Rym: well the conference is you know inside the otaku generation?
Rym: And they're trying to talk about Fans and what fans want and how to sell things to fans and what the culture of anime fandom in the u.s.
Scott: They're gonna talk about everything they know about trying to sell things to otaku I guess in the u.s.
Scott: And what they think and all that sort of stuff, and it's $200 and you can sit there all day.
Rym: Oh here.
Rym: We go.
Rym: Here's all that the the for conference.
Rym: I'm quoting from the anime news network the for conference sessions.
Rym: We'll discuss the overall trends in the anime and manga industries the way the way to market to otaku The female half of the otaku audience and the effects of technology on future market.
Rym: so there you have it.
Rym: That's what they're talking about.
Scott: so We're going to try our best to attend this thing because we're doing big stuff in New York anime festival anyway.
Scott: We might as well try to go to this.
Scott: I mean if it's 200 bucks Maybe one of us will go.
Scott: maybe we'll spend the money.
Rym: pretty much just depends on if I can get time off for my new Job to go to this in addition to the New York anime fans.
Scott: Did you tell you a new job about all the stuff that you're not.
Scott: you're already taking days?
Rym: I'm not too worried about that.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: My new job is awesome.
Scott: Okay, but yeah.
Scott: So we'll try our best to cover this for everyone, and we'll see what happens.
Rym: Yeah, best-case scenario will be there as press and we'll do our press thing.
Scott: Yeah, the best-case scenario we get in for free and we interview all these people.
Scott: worst-case scenario One of us goes and sits through four boring conference.
Rym: well I guess.
Rym: worst-case scenario while we're there There's an assassination attempt that goes bad And we're both killed and then the gig night's hosting goes down And then the large hadron Collider actually kills everyone.
Scott: I guess that is but I'm talking about the worst case within this context Not the worst case.
Scott: you want to talk about the worst case in a complete universe context.
Rym: everything blinks out of existence But then we wouldn't know.
Rym: I think the worst case would be everything.
Scott: I'm just horrible pain forever.
Rym: Okay, the worst possible pain forever Things of the day, so I don't like baseball so much.
Rym: men off playing baseball I love playing softball don't like watching baseball.
Rym: So unless it's Japanese baseball.
Scott: Oh Suddenly everything's.
Scott: yeah, you freaking weaboo.
Rym: You want to know why life if anyone ever doubts the awesomeness of Japanese baseball watch?
Rym: My thing of the day and I think no more needs be said.
Scott: I think your thing of the day does not talent the awesomeness of Japanese baseball, but instead further Cements the awesomeness of Japanese television.
Rym: I might have to agree You know if I were if I go to for not having a thing today on Wednesday I could get Translated like maybe an hour time shifted while some sweatshop translates it into English with subtitles Japanese TV and a TiVo.
Scott: I'd quit my job.
Rym: I'd pay for that.
Rym: I'd buy one of those fancy glasses never HUD of Japanese TV as long as my TV just for that.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So my thing of the day is sort of underwear pervert related.
Scott: It's actually this incredible blog.
Rym: You've seen blogs right and blogs I like how general that's kind of like in middle school.
Rym: And they're like you start with a global statement and then you coalesce your first paragraph to a thesis exactly.
Rym: You've seen blogs?
Scott: Yeah, of course.
Scott: All right.
Scott: and blogs are usually.
Scott: you know, what's a blog?
Scott: some blogs just about everything.
Scott: some are about.
Scott: You know one person some are liking gadget about gadgets, you know, this blog has such a narrow focus.
Scott: it's not even like a Blog about like comics or blog about underwear.
Scott: per this blog has Even it's even more narrowly focused than a blog about like a specific comic.
Rym: It is so narrowly focused It is perfected the art of attack only one.
Scott: Oh, it is indeed this blog which has been going for quite some time.
Scott: they've got like three pages worth of posts here is only about Panels from Comics mostly underwear pervert comics in the u.s.
Scott: In which Someone gets hit in the bean bag Mean bean machine.
Scott: the URL of the blog is nad shot calm nad shot calm and all you see here are pictures from comics of Someone getting hit in the crotch.
Rym: I think nothing more needs to be said than Robin hates your junk.
Scott: Well, I Think my favorite one, you know, even though it might not be the best one is the one where Hercules just punches Galactus, right?
Scott: Well, she's Galactus doesn't even have Jokes, he's like some energy.
Rym: forget the words But just look at that shot of him kicking him in the nads.
Rym: Well the the place where nads may or may not be on a being like that.
Rym: But I'm like the next panel.
Rym: just the.
Scott: the look on Galactus is face and then Galactus It says godling cuz it cuz it's Hercules that punched him, right?
Scott: So he says he's Galactus says in the Galactus voice which I can't I guess repeat because I'm not some sort of all-powerful space planet eater is Godling savor thy next breath you take for it will be your last If anyone kicked me in the balls.
Scott: and I could just say that Especially if it was Hercules that punched me in the balls.
Rym: Well, I remember I got punched in the balls once by Hercules by some kid named Dennis, okay So it wasn't Hercules.
Rym: Well, uh, you know in Braveheart when he yells freedom and it's like, oh man, he yelled freedom.
Rym: That's how I felt except instead of yelling freedom.
Scott: I yelled Galactus with no balls.
Rym: I Favorite one is the guy just kneeing that bear in the car.
Scott: That was a good one.
Scott: So the guy the girl can't knee a bear Kicking the guy in the crotch and it like tore his torso off his legs.
Rym: There's there's some good ones.
Scott: It's a good blog.
Scott: You should check every post and get subscribe to the RSS.
Scott: You can see new ones.
Scott: But yeah, they were.
Scott: they were talking about this on a forum somewhere.
Scott: I posted a link to the penny arcade of you know, right in the mean bean machine I think that's in my top 10 of penny arcade Definitely in my top five of penny art because one it's hilarious You my bean bag.
Scott: I like tribes too, and I mean I routinely make poor decisions.
Rym: now to write in the mean aside She's being funny.
Rym: It was true.
Rym: Every update for tribes was being kicked in the nuts Metaphorically and almost physically.
Scott: Yep If my computer had a leg with a shoe on it, that's what it would have been man, right?
Rym: But without further ado because I want to get right into this.
Rym: we've been talking about doing a You know final thoughts episode for a while because the first time we did this was for big Oh big Oh, too And it was an incredibly popular episode.
Rym: And if you've seen big Oh and big Oh - all the way through I highly recommend you go back and listen to our spoiler spoiler spoiler Show about big Oh -.
Scott: yeah, and I think you know from listening to a lot to other podcasts like, you know You should see in such where they review like an entire movie and talk about the whole thing even It's like, you know You review an anime or something or a comic and you're basically you're trying to introduce someone to what it's about.
Scott: So sort of you know, you get a feeling when you read something and you want to you know If someone will know if they want to read it or watch it or you know or not If you can communicate the feeling you had to them Then they will know if that is a feeling they want and they'll know if it's something they want to want to buy.
Scott: So that's that's the purpose of a review.
Scott: but sometimes, you know, you watch something and watching it again Doesn't exactly give you the same feeling as watching it the first time cuz you know you've seen it before You know, it's a little.
Scott: sometimes it's still good but it's not exactly the same.
Scott: and by these final thoughts episode the sort of the goal is by Discussing in full something, you know in a total spoiler manner.
Scott: We just talk about everything You know and the target audience is people who have already seen it
Rym: or people who don't give a shit about the show or people
Scott: Don't give a shit and they just want they you know They'll listen to all about it because they know they're never gonna watch.
Scott: it is to sort of Let them or help them to relive the feelings they had when they watched it the first time.
Scott: So that is what we were going to try to do.
Rym: and also it's luckily the show we're talking about is one that we didn't need to rewatch because it's a show that affected us kind of profoundly and We actually remember enough about it even despite having only seen it once.
Rym: I seen it twice I think I've seen it one and a half times.
Rym: Hey, I think pretty much.
Rym: Okay, cuz I skipped out on much of that marathon.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but yeah tonight we're going to do a final thoughts episode on Trigon.
Scott: sorry to all you people who voted for something else.
Rym: Well, the reason we're doing try gun also is that don't have to rewatch it.
Rym: Well all I want to do one on Ava and I want to do one on eska flown.
Rym: Gotta rewatch.
Rym: Scott's got to rewatch both of those.
Scott: Maybe I'll start then.
Rym: Uh, did we do?
Rym: No, we didn't do one on utenna yet either.
Rym: We didn't do anything.
Rym: God utenna will need like his big.
Rym: Oh, well need like final thoughts.
Scott: a week is the second one in two years.
Rym: Awesome.
Rym: Yeah, that's our trend.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: I think by next year.
Rym: We'll have watched Ava again.
Scott: I think so, too, right.
Rym: But if you haven't seen try gun yet first I want to tell you you should go back and listen to our review of try gun because I Am of the I don't know.
Scott: Is that a good show?
Scott: It's so old.
Rym: I have the feeling that try gun is one of the best like top 10 top 20 anime ever made.
Rym: Yeah, probably in fact, it might be one of the best television shows ever made.
Scott: It's just Everyone should watch it.
Scott: I would know there would not be a human being on this earth where I would say no you probably shouldn't watch try gun.
Scott: Everyone should watch it and I think everyone no matter who you are You can get some sort of enjoyment out of it.
Rym: But regardless listen to our review.
Rym: if you've never seen try gun.
Rym: and Also, if you've never seen try gun if you have any inkling that you want to see it I would really recommend that you do not listen to the rest.
Scott: Oh, yeah If you do you should only watch.
Scott: listen to this episode of GeekNights If you have already seen all of try gun all of it Or if you definitely definitely plan to never ever watch it now if you do not fall into one of those two categories Turn your iPod off Now.
Rym: well, you're obviously still listening.
Rym: now We'll stop at one point further on.
Rym: cuz you're a lot of you're probably thinking I don't really care to give you a second chance because there's a point at which we're gonna go.
Rym: super spoiler Here's your second chance.
Rym: No, no, I mean like later on But let's get into it.
Rym: we don't need to talk about try gun.
Rym: is?
Rym: you've already seen it?
Scott: you've already seen it So we're not gonna synopsize the plot.
Rym: I think the biggest thing about try gun was that it was one of those shows that Kind of reels you in with one concept.
Rym: cuz Ava did the exact same thing like try gun is a show.
Rym: Yeah, like you're not even sure.
Rym: like is that fascist and feed?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: and that was definitely good stuff.
Scott: cuz I mean I didn't you know the manga.
Scott: As long as say about the manga the manga is bad.
Scott: Don't ask me why I'm buying it.
Rym: Yeah, just forget it.
Scott: forget the manga.
Rym: It is incomprehensible if you think wait a minute, but if I read the manga I can get more insight into.
Rym: no you can't.
Scott: No, it's like when I was watching the anime I felt like I'm missing something and the manga has probably got it.
Scott: No the manga doesn't have shit.
Rym: Those things are best left unthought about.
Scott: yes, just ignore.
Scott: pretend the manga doesn't exist in the show is all you've got.
Scott: Okay, so you got this show and I was the first time I was watching it.
Scott: You know they sorta.
Scott: it's sort of like so obvious that he's washed the stampede, but they don't.
Scott: they don't actually Confirm it a hundred percent until like what episode five four takes a while.
Scott: I think it's episode five where he fights the really big guy.
Rym: It's not even that they don't even let you Figure out like you you're not even sure if he's competent whoever this guy is and they keep hinting and hinting.
Rym: It's like was that an accident.
Rym: I don't know what it may be Kinda, and then there's a few scenes like I remember when he's down in the water episode where the guy stole all the water Yeah, and the guy pulls out the gun and he's about to shoot him and he dodges the bullet Yeah, and then they kind of like write that off, but at that point it's like huh Maybe the show's not about what I thought it was
Scott: one of those things.
Scott: It's so obvious You know you're so sure But they do such a good job of instilling doubt in you that you can't just go with it a hundred percent.
Scott: It's like they're feeding you this doubt and you want to hold on to that doubt.
Scott: so you do.
Rym: But I think the first inkling I got that the show was really really not what I expected it to be was the other shows Going along and it's you're not sure.
Rym: and then they get on that I'm gonna say the train, but it's like a boat that goes over the desert.
Scott: It's like a desert steam train.
Rym: boat thing doesn't matter.
Rym: I'm gonna call it a train cuz it's it in the style of like an old Western movie.
Rym: It's effectively a train.
Rym: Yep, and That episode like that set of two episodes where he fights dynamites, whatever neon die.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's his name Dynamo.
Rym: I actually forget, but it doesn't matter.
Rym: the episode is going on.
Rym: and so yeah, it's like a normal episode, but there's that Pipes those canisters out into the area where the guards are and he flips out behind and he's trying to shoot him and He shoots one of the guys and wounds him pretty badly and he's
Scott: all trying to bandage him up and stuff.
Rym: Yeah, the kids like come on.
Rym: Let's go.
Rym: and he starts freaking out like no, I can't let this man die and That really came almost out of nowhere.
Rym: Like you kind of got the impression that he was a nice guy or maybe a pacifist or something.
Rym: but the tone of the show changed pretty much at that point because that whole episode from that point on is just him Getting hurt and getting screwed and just it's not going well.
Rym: and suddenly he's not as badass as he was and it's because and you Realize he won't hurt these people.
Scott: Yeah, I mean for this you don't realize he's a hundred percent.
Scott: You don't erase all doubt of him being washed the St.
Scott: Pete until episode 5 because for the first four episodes.
Scott: he doesn't fire the gun.
Scott: the show's called try gun.
Scott: They get these guns in the opener.
Scott: He's carrying around this tremendous gun his guns everywhere.
Scott: This dude doesn't fire his gun until episode 5 and when he does he fires a bunch of bullets into this gigantic flying fist.
Scott: You know, he's not hurting anyone with him.
Scott: Really.
Scott: He's not killing anyone.
Scott: That's for sure.
Scott: And that's the moment where they go.
Scott: Oh my god, he's washed the stampede and she makes that big funny face and she's like, oh it's like home alone.
Rym: Yeah But I think like that episode just and then it leads up to the fight where Bosch couldn't win the fight.
Rym: There's no way he could have won.
Rym: It was obvious that like he would have died right then and there.
Rym: and The guy is just so impressed by I guess his testicular fortitude that he basically concedes defeat and leaves.
Rym: Yep, and It seemed like the show is really silly like the way things are set up.
Rym: and look at that guy Look at that character design.
Rym: That's silly.
Rym: That's crazy.
Scott: That's crazy because that's the style that was in the manga.
Scott: That's even crazier in the manga the cat.
Scott: That's one thing.
Scott: the character designs I mean.
Scott: usually they change a lot from manga to anime, you know.
Scott: but they change so much.
Scott: like the character designs are completely different and it's so different.
Scott: but Some of that craziness carries over and you can see it all over the place.
Rym: But I just it was interesting how that scene that set of scenes was so ludicrous in terms of what that bad guy was and what those people were doing.
Rym: and Yet what's going on on a deeper level?
Rym: You know what people are fighting for and what people are saying was I don't know very poignant.
Rym: and you almost start to Suspend disbelief and forget that it's this crazy guy with a neon gun and you start to just Only see the drama like you put on blinders and you just see the drama of these characters these personalities.
Rym: There aren't many shows.
Rym: they can pull that off.
Rym: Fist of the North Star, not so much.
Scott: I think part of the reason the show succeeds with that so well is that unlike a lot of other shows There is sort of a character development But it's sort of twofold right.
Scott: on the one hand you have these characters who already developed a lot before the first episode you Chronologically speaking, right?
Scott: but they keep a lot of those developments hidden from you and they reveal them with flashbacks or Characters to keeping secrets from other characters.
Rym: Yeah, I remember wasn't it episode 13 where we actually thought we put the wrong DVD in?
Rym: Okay, because remember it it starts out as a different show.
Scott: That's episode like 17 is it?
Rym: yeah, I remember some point.
Rym: it was like right after in the big plot development in the mail.
Scott: It's a spoiler episode here.
Scott: It's episode 17 where they go back and it's you know, Vashj and knobs and they were kids and in space.
Scott: Yeah, that's episode 17.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: 13 is the one where Vashj goes Diablo where the guy Oh, yeah, he freaking shoots his mask off and stuff.
Scott: The guy.
Rym: that was an episode.
Rym: I think we even talked about that in the review where just Up until that point the show is kind of a mystery.
Rym: like you've got this character Vashj you don't know what's going on and he has visions and he says things to himself.
Rym: and there's all these little scenes where You get glimpses of the depth of this character and you get glimpses of the sadness that he bears.
Rym: But you don't really you're not sure what the deal is.
Rym: and then that episode when you still
Scott: don't know what the deal is in That episode but he goes crazy with the crazy power you
Rym: know what the deal of the show is because in that episode there's that murderer and he's just killing people in this city left and right and He doesn't care and he just kills these people without even thinking about it.
Rym: and Then Vashj just loses it and he's standing over him and he shot off his mask and he's got the gun to his forehead.
Rym: And he just keeps saying you killed those people.
Rym: They're dead.
Rym: They're gone forever.
Rym: They can't come back.
Rym: you did this to them.
Rym: There was cocks the gun.
Rym: There was no reason why I shouldn't just kill you and the guys just crying and I was moved by that scene not to tears.
Rym: But just you can feel the fear of that person.
Rym: and on one hand I feel like how horrible would it be to kill that person?
Rym: He's crying.
Rym: Look how absolutely suddenly afraid he's feeling the most fear that you can possibly feel.
Rym: and Yet he deserves to die and he's killed hundreds of people.
Rym: if you've killed hundreds of people Then you really shouldn't be crying when someone's trying to kill you.
Rym: but yet Vashj is there and can kill him and he says he should kill him and I don't want him to kill him but yet I do and then he doesn't kill it.
Scott: That's also important because that's like the moment where Vashj reveals that he's got like this, you know hidden gun like in his arm.
Scott: It's like you just learned, you know more hidden secrets of previous character development that like, you know He's got he's like a mechanical arm or the gun inside of it, you know, and it's like wow He's he's a lot more fucked up than we thought.
Rym: And then you remember there's all those little things like little bits of technology and things that Vashj has that are really Anachronistic like they don't fit into the world in the setting and that starts to come together a bit more.
Rym: And then you realize that it's actually a sci-fi Straight up.
Scott: It's nothing like that.
Rym: I remember at that point when he revealed the second gun that machine gun I was thinking like right away.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: The show is called Trigun.
Rym: Where's the third gun?
Rym: Yeah, and when you find out what the third gun is like, oh, man Yeah, but I guess people you know, the third gun is you've seen it.
Scott: Yeah, but I Okay, but anyway the other part of the character development right is that you know a lot of shows.
Scott: you start off with these sort Of cliche characters and then they do what you expect and they don't really change.
Scott: here You've got characters who developed in the past.
Scott: chronologically they reveal those developments.
Scott: You know as if they are secrets that they're revealed and then they continue to develop as the show goes on.
Scott: more new things You know like they change for episode to episode.
Scott: I mean, you know, they start out silly and then there's less silliness guys, you know start out bad And then they change a little bit.
Scott: and you know, like even like Brad he's in there for like what two episodes I'm like, I gotta talk about Brad that that the guys in there for like two episodes, right?
Scott: But in that in those two episodes He does more character changes and development than most characters in like a whole 50 episode anime that this this is a big spoiler thing.
Rym: But I really got to get into this cuz Brad reminded me of all the and when it first appears You don't like well know the thing that Trigun does so well throughout is that you know in a lot of shows people die and there's impact.
Rym: but Trigon is one of those shows where the death of any character whether it's a good guy a bad guy doesn't matter.
Rym: Death is actually kind of rare and it doesn't happen for a long time in the show and when people actually start dying The show makes you feel it.
Rym: It really makes you feel it no matter who the character was no matter what horrible things they've done.
Scott: Well, it's because you know, they pay The.
Scott: it's not like you're watching like a Gundam show where it's like, okay who's gonna die, you know, someone's gonna die.
Scott: Right, but it's like they focus so much on death because it's the whole point of the show.
Scott: They keep focusing on it focusing on it, but deaths of people, you know, don't actually happen.
Scott: all too often I could be focusing on it and you're focusing and there's nothing there and you're focusing and there's nothing there.
Scott: It's like you're honing in this microscope on nothing and then a bacteria comes into focus like oh shit.
Rym: Well, plus the show just they set it up whenever they're going to kill a character.
Rym: They make sure that you're gonna cry.
Rym: It's like they do everything right to make you feel it when that character goes.
Scott: They make sure.
Rym: you know, I cried like four or five times during Trigon.
Rym: I cried almost every time a character died.
Rym: That's how powerfully this show hits you.
Rym: I mean Brad is a good example.
Rym: Right Brad is introduced and you hate him.
Rym: He's an asshole He's an idiot.
Rym: He's ruining everything.
Rym: He's a bad person.
Scott: He's like, he's you know, he's on the good guys side Barely, but you know he is.
Scott: but he's sort of like.
Scott: he's not trusting Avash and he's like you gotta do my way.
Scott: you guys are all stupid and They like Starscream, you know, he's a Decepticon, but he doesn't like the way the Decepticons are going about things.
Rym: So he's all pissy, but then at the end of that little story arc when they're in the base He they just kill him out of nowhere That death comes out of the blue and he just dies and there's no fanfare.
Rym: just he's dead.
Rym: and That I just I lost it right.
Rym: then I just started crying and I thought wow I hated that character until just now and I think that was the purpose.
Rym: I think they really wanted you to hate that character Right until he died.
Rym: because then it's almost like that regrets like he was a good guy.
Rym: Well, it's kind of like, you know If you part with someone on bad terms and then they die and you never got to say you were sorry.
Scott: Well, I can imagine if like that just used to Starscream example, right?
Scott: Imagine if on the Autobots there was an Autobot who would just like he was good.
Scott: He was on the Autobot side hated Decepticons, but he was always fighting with Optimus Prime like oh, you're kind of stupid.
Scott: He's always sort of like the annoying guy who was you know saying that the way they were doing things is wrong.
Scott: He was belligerent, but he was on the good guys side and then he just suddenly died unexpectedly.
Scott: You'd be like, oh he was always belligerent, but it's not just guy that is on our side.
Rym: It's not just that.
Rym: he was a good guy.
Rym: He was on our side.
Rym: It's not that simplistic.
Rym: it's more that the way the scenes were set up in the character progression and the scenes were Brad had screen time and talked and the way they it's like the show tricks you into not liking this character and Then sets it up to where the only point at which you will start to like the character is the moment they die.
Rym: and now it's too late to take back your previous feelings and All you get is the reaction shot of all the people who knew him.
Scott: and now he's dead and was sort of crazy is like The way he dies like that crazy puppet master guys coming in and it's sort of ridiculous this yeah This puppet master guy, and it's it's totally crazy, but it works.
Scott: You're not going.
Scott: wow That was some fucked up shit with his puppet master stuff.
Scott: No, it's like oh my god He died.
Scott: and you totally believe all the crazy bad shit that's going on which is very hard for a show to do to have Ridiculous imagery and ridiculous stuff going on.
Scott: But you totally accept it a hundred percent with.
Scott: no you know you totally accept.
Scott: in episode 5 the guy who's 50 feet tall And has like a little his dad is like sitting in his pocket and his dad is a revolver for a bite.
Rym: And it doesn't matter the fact that the drama of this show comes out through.
Rym: that Stylized crazy, but you know Brad's death was one thing.
Rym: then there's wolf would That scene.
Rym: I to this day I have never seen the death of any character With the possible exception of one scene in cowboy bebop, and I'm not gonna say which sings is not the one you think.
Rym: I think that was the most just painful to watch Difficult to deal with death scenes and also one of the most beautifully done death scenes in all of anime.
Scott: They laid it on so thick.
Scott: I mean it wasn't like Ava where just everyone's head explodes right and it wasn't like some other Shows where it's like you know someone's in like the climax and then they say a dramatic thing and then an explosion.
Rym: It made death so real and so visceral and yet It was.
Rym: I mean look he's been shot wolf would was shot And he was seriously injured.
Rym: and he talks to vaj and he just he goes into the church and the imagery You know he kneels down, and he's not a religious man, and he's not a. he thinks of himself as almost an evil man But he was trying to do good and all the conflict of his character comes out all at once and he's just alone in this church with that cross over his shoulder holding himself up and That music starts playing and I'll admit.
Rym: I choke up a little bit.
Rym: Just hear you know that Rocco and song just
Scott: Because the way they do it is a lot less like other anime do it and a lot more like someone Would die and like you know a very melodramatic play like Drawn out and you know they get like the light coming in
Rym: Watching it.
Rym: it doesn't feel melodramatic because it's so personal It's just.
Rym: it's very much like the thoughts that would go through someone's head when they're dying and he's sitting and he's thinking what you would Think.
Rym: well no I mean look he's.
Rym: he's thinking about everything that he's done And he feels bad because he shot that kid and he thought that it was the right thing to do.
Rym: but yet he doubts it and he's kind of his life is flashing before his eyes and he's starting to resign himself to death.
Rym: and then he remembers Millie and That they had a moment just before.
Rym: cuz remember in like the previous episode or maybe the same app It was right before then where he had killed that kid.
Rym: and he's really brought what broken up about it.
Rym: and Millie comes into the room and he's on the verge of tears and She just hugs him.
Rym: and then he says something like you're a good healer And it just leaves it at that.
Rym: like those characters have this moment.
Rym: Yeah again the show sets you up.
Rym: They're like all right.
Rym: This character has found love and this character has found solace the moment.
Rym: They're happy.
Rym: We're going to kill one.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they couldn't even like.
Scott: you know they keep it so subtle - they're like They're like is it?
Scott: it's not like they just come out with it and say here's how it is It's just they're so subtle with it like huh is a little bit of something.
Rym: it's like this character just like suddenly a character shows an emotion and then the flashbacks to the few moments that they had together.
Rym: and and When he pictures her face the final moment before he actually dies and he suddenly says no like no I want to live.
Rym: and he starts to stand up like he's gonna pull himself up and walk out of the church and You think and they pulls you on this rollercoaster.
Rym: You're like he's gonna live.
Scott: he's gonna live.
Scott: I never thought he was gonna live.
Rym: well He does and he's looking and he's trying and he's like he has the will to live.
Rym: he has more will to live than he has ever had in his life.
Rym: and then the cigarette just falls out of his mouth and his hand falls over.
Rym: and I remember we were all because we all watch this like in Scott's room
Scott: like sitting in a cramped dorm room like in a low-resolution real media file on my 17 inch CRT and we're
Rym: all like standing around and There's just silence and we're just watching and nothing happens and it fades away
Scott: and
Rym: it just cuts to the outside of the place where everyone's sleeping and Then you just hear Millie shriek and start crying and that is.
Rym: There aren't many times in anime where a voice actor crying sounds realistic and sounds visceral and sounds real.
Rym: It always sounds kind of weird or hackneyed or forced or but that That shriek was painful to listen to and I I just started outright crying.
Scott: Yeah, it's just painful.
Scott: even think about it right now.
Scott: You shouldn't.
Scott: but yeah, I don't think about that.
Rym: I mean think about that this it sets you up to where the character dies and you Almost it's so powerful that you can't react to it.
Rym: and then they don't just let it in there.
Rym: They force you to deal with the reaction shot with the other characters especially that one character reacting to it and that's always been a thing for me.
Scott: where I don't react not but it's like but they give you so little to actually grab on to.
Rym: I mean like.
Scott: they don't like to give You enough to like.
Scott: poke you but they don't give you anywhere to like.
Scott: put it.
Scott: It's like it's like oh, it's coming out.
Scott: Where do I put it?
Scott: There's no buckets.
Scott: the show the episodes over.
Rym: Oh god They don't eat.
Rym: they just like show him sitting there and then the next scene.
Rym: they don't even show you Millie The boss is just standing outside the door and he doesn't know what to do and she's just shrieking Inconsolably and you don't even see her.
Rym: Yep, and then the episode just ends No music.
Rym: No nothing.
Rym: It just ends.
Scott: It's like you got this water balloon and they fill it with water and they pop it.
Rym: There's no bucket and you're like, ah Okay, and just that is one of the most powerful moments in media I've ever seen.
Scott: it's pretty good.
Scott: It's up there.
Rym: I can't say it's the most powerful thing I've ever seen but but then again I've always and it's I don't know if this is a more universal thing but a lot of times in a show like this or in any show cuz Fullmetal Alchemist had a similar thing where a character dies and I don't feel it like I don't feel it viscerally but I feel it, you know on that like the character died and I feel bad and it's kind of like with bated breath and It's not until the other characters react or like in Fullmetal Alchemist case I didn't cry or feel sad Until the funeral scene and I had to deal with seeing all the other characters react to this.
Scott: Yeah, but at the same time, you know, it's I guess that's what it sort of is.
Scott: It's like, you know a funeral in real life allows you to like come to terms with it, right?
Scott: But if you don't get a funeral in the anime, you know, if you just get like a second, you know If they don't give you enough time to to deal with it It's like you can't deal with it because now you're full of it and there's nowhere to go.
Rym: But of course Because of that scene and that scene's power in episode 23 and I have watched that scene 10 or 15 times over the course of the years just because I It's perfect.
Rym: I don't think it could have been done better in the context of that show.
Rym: Maybe not but I Forgot where I was going for it.
Rym: But okay at the end at the end the fight with knives and you know the very end of the show When you hear wolf woods voice out of nowhere that that was like.
Rym: It's almost like that scene where he pulls up the cross gun and you hear wolf woods voice for just that second saying basically You idiot blah.
Rym: It's.
Rym: it's almost like that scene and that little clip of him saying that Was able to draw on all the emotion that was pent up from when wolf would died, you know three episodes prior I mean, it's like.
Scott: it's like a lot of anime at the end, you know Have a scene where it's like, you know, there's a huge battle scene at the end.
Scott: fighting fighting fighting fighting fighting.
Scott: Everyone's you know on their last breath They're they're all tired out from this incredible battle.
Scott: And then at the last second the good guy pulls out something amazing Holy shit.
Rym: Anyway, here's like the voice of like use the force Luke or like the dead mother's final words or something.
Scott: Yeah but this show does both of them at the same time.
Scott: you get the.
Scott: it's like Imagine if it was like use the force Luke and then he pulled out like some secret weapon that he didn't know he had.
Scott: So you get both and that's pretty strong stuff, right?
Rym: But it just it draws on all like the emotion from wolf woods death.
Rym: You were given no release and Millie crying and shrieking and then just the characters dealing.
Rym: after that You just you hold you carry that inside you Until that moment at the end where you hear his voice and it's almost like everything was vindicated and at that moment All the grief comes out.
Rym: Mm-hmm But and it's like you don't get released till then but I think we have to like four episodes of trouble right there.
Rym: Yeah, and of course in that time we have probably the most important scene in the entire show when legato Legato because that one last warning we're gonna spoil the fucking end of the show at this point.
Rym: Yeah, so if you say if you if you thought I don't care about Trigun and you've gotten this far seriously stop now Right.
Scott: Yeah So legato is this guy and it's sort of rough because like you're kind of sure that knives is the big top bad guy.
Scott: Right, but you see this legato guy throughout the show, you know in a few episodes doing this Evie's an evil guy.
Rym: Legato is scary.
Scott: He looks evil.
Scott: He's scary.
Scott: He's not as it's.
Scott: his character design is not as freaky as all the other villains.
Rym: I think he is the most frightening and disturbing thing in all of Trigon probably just because he's so Understated and he's just there but all the scenes were.
Scott: he's sort of like, you know in the Simpsons He's that guy in the white suit who stands there doing nothing, but you know, he's gonna do something.
Rym: Awesome That's not the analogy.
Rym: I would have you.
Scott: that's what I was thinking.
Scott: But like remember that's why you think he's the most dangerous and the most evil and the most scary.
Rym: most dangerous.
Scott: Yeah, MD exactly is the MD cuz?
Scott: he's always there.
Scott: He's not always there, but he's there often Haunting and threatening and being kind of evil, but he doesn't actually use his evil.
Scott: I feel like the last minute.
Rym: I think what makes him frightening is much deeper than that that that character is a person.
Rym: He's basically a thrall of knives.
Rym: I mean all the gung-ho guns for various reasons have fallen under the spell of knives.
Rym: And that's another thing.
Rym: how every gung-ho gun is a horrible person.
Rym: and yet you feel terrible as each one of them dies.
Rym: you absolute like you hate them and then you just feel nothing but pity and remorse when they die and you wish they wouldn't die.
Scott: and I did the show sort of hints that there was more to them that you just didn't see, you know It's like from what you see of them.
Scott: when you do see them.
Scott: It's like other horrible.
Scott: But then there's like something about them.
Scott: That's not so horrible That's sort of like not just brought out like look they were not horrible, but it's like maybe they weren't hard You know, it's like the saxophone guy.
Rym: It's good saxophone Like even the sniper when he suddenly just kills himself out of the blue.
Scott: I remember when yes, like he didn't have to kill himself.
Rym: But I love that scene was done so well because like Vash catches him and Voss is just like I'm not gonna hurt you Let's.
Rym: and then he just pulls out a gun and before Vash can even reach over.
Rym: He just kills himself just right in front of him.
Rym: and The way Vash reacts was that I almost cried there just because of the way Vash handled that.
Rym: And then that scene when Vash and Wolfwood are talking after that because that's right when Wolfwood is shot to death.
Rym: But anyway, yep, but with Legato, I mean remember the scene where Legato just sits on the opposite park bench yeah, and And he messes with the kid and like Vash just suddenly has that vision of him killing that kid.
Rym: Yep, and then oh it didn't happen and He Legato was scary.
Scott: That's like one of the best scenes in the whole show.
Scott: over there We're like the basketball's bouncing around that and he's got like the doughnut.
Scott: I held my breath for that whole scene because it's the thing with that scene is that they get you in You know because there's parts of the show early on.
Scott: there's a lot more parts of the show.
Scott: We're sort of happy and silly.
Scott: this jokes and you know people drinking and eating doughnuts and having fun, right and towards.
Scott: You know as the show goes on that's less and less and less and this is sort of like, you know For a second.
Scott: They're like, we're gonna return to the happy doughnut part for a second.
Scott: You're like, yeah I like that part, you know, we haven't had that in a while.
Scott: and then like just kidding But he's sitting there holding the doughnut still and there's like this kid.
Scott: It's like Legato's there.
Rym: It's like oh man and well the show it just.
Rym: the show says so much at that point It almost says that you can't live the happy life.
Rym: You cannot get past what's going on.
Rym: There is no way to return to things that were before.
Rym: until all of this is resolved one way or the other.
Scott: It's at that moment.
Scott: You're like, okay, I guess we're not gonna have a lot more doughnut eating the rest of this show.
Rym: It's well, that wasn't how I looked at it.
Rym: But yeah, but that just the scene after that work.
Rym: basically, this sets up the first of the two primary moral dilemmas in the show.
Rym: and the legato scene and then the knives fight at the end are Basically everything that Trigun has to say condensed into two moral dilemmas where there is no answer Yeah And I like how they.
Rym: they let Vashj decide Both ways and show the consequences of both and it's a very morally ambiguous show.
Rym: at that point I mean look and this is where because when I first saw Trigun to the end I thought and Scott agreed and we all thought wow that show was pretty much a Treatise on pacifism and saying that killing is never justified ever.
Scott: Yeah, I mean they're like.
Scott: you can always you know.
Scott: But stop stuff, you know, you can resolve any situation without killing someone.
Scott: You can just beat them up or subdue them or something.
Scott: But it's like wait a minute.
Scott: you can only do that because the guys are freaking super powered crazy go nuts Not even human thing.
Rym: Well, it's not even that like I think that that whole part of any couldn't do.
Rym: it is doesn't even matter.
Rym: It's just that the show on its surface looks like it's a treatise against the idea of killing because the show constantly is just showing you that no matter what no matter how strongly you feel killing another sentient being will Always be abhorrent and that there is no justification.
Rym: and yet Finally Vashj is put into a perfect moral dilemma.
Rym: Legato has controlled the entire city.
Rym: They are going to murder Millie and What's her name?
Rym: Meryl Meryl straight up.
Rym: there is no way out.
Rym: they are going to murder them.
Rym: Vashj's options are to kill all of those people to kill Legato or to let Millie and Meryl die and there is no possible way out.
Rym: He has to decide in a purely moral standpoint what he is going to do.
Rym: and that scene is just so well done.
Rym: And it just.
Rym: it waits and it waits and it doesn't even show it to you.
Rym: Just hear the gunshot And Legato falls over.
Rym: Yeah, and then Vashj just loses it.
Rym: He does indeed lose it and think about that.
Rym: I mean you think oh the show says pacifism.
Rym: Yay.
Rym: Think about that.
Rym: A lot of people then said because there's another way to look at this that then at the end of the show when he doesn't kill Knives and he takes the other road out and people a lot of people I think incorrectly say that the moral of the show is It doesn't matter what you've done in the past as long as you realize it was wrong.
Rym: It wouldn't do it again But go back.
Rym: All right, Vashj realized that killing was wrong.
Rym: He did it once.
Rym: he regrets it.
Rym: He's atoned for it.
Rym: Would he do it again?
Rym: If go back to that situation if he didn't kill Legato then other innocent people would have died.
Rym: There was still no way out.
Scott: Yeah, I mean he could have somehow morally justified it to himself by saying I didn't kill the people.
Scott: But what does that get you?
Scott: He gets you no friends because they're all dead.
Rym: now My like my end Conclusion of what Trigon is trying to say because my funny answer is not that it's not about pacifism or whatever.
Rym: The moral of Trigon is very simple One fucker can ruin everybody's day Because look at it every bad thing that happens in the whole show is the direct result of one man.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much one man is the cause of everything bad that ever happened.
Scott: Yeah, I mean basically if you believe the things the way the show presents everything right if Knives Wasn't an ass then everyone would have been being all happy like they are after the end of the show where you know They're digging up the well and they found water in the desert and they're living in their happy town with the happy people.
Scott: You know all that stuff right, but no just the one guy without he ruined everything.
Rym: But that actually plays into what I think the higher moral I guess Conjecture of the show is.
Rym: is that all right Vashj estimate.
Rym: It's basically saying that pacifism is A noble ideal and it should be the goal of every sentient being but at the same time It is an impossible goal.
Rym: and it is I think the show is saying straight up unless you want to let bad people get Away, you know.
Scott: if you unless you want to let other bad people just get away with killing people, you know I think the show was saying that Pacifism is untenable.
Rym: Yeah, and I think that is the only thing you can truly take away from this show.
Rym: Yeah, well, I mean look he He chewed but I. that's why the show is so great because Vashj is basically a deity a god he is.
Rym: he is superhuman and The only reason he is able to get as far as he has without killing people to save other people Is because he's more than all those other people.
Rym: he is inhuman.
Rym: and I guess the moral.
Rym: and even then look at all these wounds The show was saying that if you are not a superhuman you cannot be a pacifist.
Rym: It is impossible that.
Scott: that is a burden that is too great for any man to bear unless you just want to let bad guys get away with all their terrible stuff.
Rym: and it's kind of it's like as The world will always have people like knives and the best you can do is try to change them and try to save them.
Rym: but in the end Killing is possibly unavoidable and I think that you should always Abhor the killing of other beings.
Rym: but at the same time you must not shy away from it if it's the only option.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and I think the the strength of the show is that at the end of the very show Vashj decides not to kill knives Even though he knows that that cannot end.
Rym: Well, he knows from all of all that he's learned that that is not going to end things and that killing him would end things.
Rym: But then again, you could look at it at the same time that alright killing knives would end that but there'll always be another knives.
Rym: Are you going to kill them all?
Rym: but yet you can't not kill them because then the innocent people die.
Rym: So it's a morally complex show and I think that is if nothing else.
Rym: That is what makes this show stand above so many other shows.
Scott: another thing unlike, you know, a lot of other shows I mean, there's some anime out there that are so, you know People go just batshit crazy.
Rym: Oh, well, I think those people are dumb.
Rym: I think Ava was pretty straightforward and what it was saying.
Scott: there are other shows like I don't know Better just heavy-handed and just out there.
Scott: They're like, this is our message.
Scott: We just say it to you in plain words, right?
Scott: In English, this is what the show is about.
Scott: Yep, like Matt cross war is bad.
Rym: or look like Gundam seed.
Rym: Gundam seed was a great show and an emotional roller coaster But it was still a pretty simplistic Simplistic moral message in the end and they come out with it was bad killings bad, right?
Scott: Okay Yeah, try gun right delivers its moral message and a not crazy convoluted existential fuck with your mind.
Scott: kind of way Right, but not an incredibly blunt and simplistic way.
Scott: It gives you stuff that you can eat, you know work with and understand and get a hold of.
Scott: it's not batshit You know fucked up, but at the same time it doesn't just say this is the one answer.
Scott: This is the lesson.
Scott: We're trying to teach you.
Scott: it just gives you this stuff and says go work with that.
Scott: Yeah, what are you gonna do with that?
Rym: Huh?
Scott: Yeah, it asks you questions and it makes you you know.
Scott: It actually puts the ideas directly into your mind But doesn't give you like the an answer to those ideas.
Scott: it's just like here play around with these ideas and you go.
Scott: and that's what makes you so upset with the show.
Scott: because it's upsetting.
Rym: the show is upsetting because it asks difficult questions that even I mean I Don't.
Rym: I mean I say and they show you the shows about.
Scott: they don't give you a definitive answer.
Scott: They show you what the different answers are and you don't like any of them.
Scott: It's like well, here's one answer to that question.
Scott: We just asked you.
Scott: Here's the other answer that question.
Scott: We just asked you pick one.
Scott: They both suck.
Scott: Yeah, don't they?
Rym: I I mean this.
Rym: I think this show is very uncomfortable to watch for anyone who has any sort of moral compass at all.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I guess you've heard an evil fucker.
Rym: You'll be like, uh Go man.
Rym: Nice was awesome.
Scott: He is kind of cool as a character even though he's bad.
Rym: look at knives.
Rym: He's a child.
Rym: almost to the end He's a. he's a child who lashes out at people and has temper tantrums.
Rym: But because he's so powerful his temper tantrums and in the deaths of millions.
Scott: Yep, pretty much.
Rym: Ah, the show is just so good.
Rym: Yeah, I I can.
Rym: it's one of those few shows that I could watch it again and again and never get sick of it.
Scott: That I don't know.
Scott: I think I could get sick of it after a while, you know, I couldn't watch it forever.
Rym: Well, no But like I could periodically watch this show every several years for the rest of my life and probably not get sick of it I couldn't watch it back to back like I could.
Rym: Star Wars.
Scott: Yeah Another thing is the structure of the show is sort of like this perfect balance between being like episodic and between being you know This this cereal where you can't miss an episode.
Scott: So it's like you could actually skip some episodes here and there but each individual episode is like an individual work except for like I guess the last three or four which sort of go together and some of the two partners and stuff.
Rym: I also like how the show is so just self-consistent like for much of the early part.
Rym: There's a lot of kind of mystical mystery like Vasch's Memories and his visions and this woman lamb and you don't know who she is and all this kind of mystical.
Rym: You know what's going on?
Rym: Why does he feel this way?
Rym: Vasch is always asking himself questions.
Rym: Like what am I and what am I doing?
Rym: And am I living up to what Lem would want and then when they ram or whatever when they give you the answer as to I like how?
Rym: the actual answer as to the back story is Straight-up face value science fiction.
Rym: This is exactly what happened.
Rym: It's not like Ava.
Rym: Oh Mystery amorphous.
Scott: It's yeah, there was the second impact.
Scott: What was it?
Scott: We're not gonna come out.
Rym: and really well actually Ava is pretty straightforward in that part like directly.
Rym: It's like the sec.
Rym: first impact was this.
Rym: second impact was this.
Rym: third impact was this guy.
Rym: This is why yeah It was if you're paying attention kind of seriously.
Rym: It was yeah straight up.
Rym: But anyway, I digress Try gun is very much this.
Rym: then this then this now this yeah, it's like here.
Scott: This is exactly what happened in the past.
Scott: This is the history of the but they don't give that to you until episode 17 two-thirds of the way through the show before you know the back story.
Scott: So it's all.
Scott: you got the the mysteries being revealed and you've also got You know things in the future things actually changing as they go forward.
Scott: So if they start you in the middle and they give you the back and the forward at the same time and it works out Really?
Rym: Well, I mean what else can I say in some try gun was awesome.
Rym: try it is super awesome And I guess I don't need to recommend it to anyone.
Rym: It's fine.
Scott: It also has good music and good design stylings and the best characters.
Scott: and It's awesome.
Scott: and it's only 26 episodes and I'm pretty sure it's really cheap right now Because it's an old popular show I feel like we should buy it cuz we had we own the last DVD cuz it has Every so ready that last DVD.
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: I don't remember cuz it's episode 23 through the end.
Rym: Yes So it's got like all the best episodes of the show on one DVD most of the best episodes.
Scott: Try again was a good show.
Scott: And those are the final thoughts of dragon.
Rym: I think so.
Rym: I can't say more than that I other than going through.
Rym: I mean, I could say more but like I think one of my favorite scenes just in general was chapel and When him and Wolfwood are having their fight Yes, that's that scene is really cool.
Scott: because in the show like this actually if you read the manga Which is impossible to understand and sucks, right?
Scott: They actually sort of you know discuss like all this stuff like something Michael something, right?
Scott: But what's the deal with the churchy people and stuff, right?
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: but in this show, right?
Scott: It's like they barely say anything.
Scott: it's like this guy appears and he's like something chapel something and you look at the guy and Obviously, he's got something to do with wolf wood.
Scott: He's related to him in some way perhaps his mentor from earlier days something like that, you know, and you know something like and They don't really need to say more than that and they don't say any more than they have to to make their point.
Scott: But it's like up wolf woods.
Scott: come to.
Scott: you know, that you knew wolf would had a secret past.
Scott: Here's enough of the secret past that all you have to know for the show to work.
Scott: here It is and here's the resolution of it.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: but just that scene and the interaction between wolfwood and chapel when they're actually fighting and both characters progress as characters in the short span of that scene and They don't show you the resolution of that scene.
Rym: You just hear it and you see the look on chapels face and how he doesn't want to do it but he's forced to and I Yep, there's no unnecessary bits and Every bit is not wasted.
Scott: There's no unimportant moment.
Rym: I feel like I can't talk about those two heavy scenes in more detail because I'll get choked up.
Rym: Seriously, the show is that emotionally impactful to me even though on the surface.
Scott: It's a rowdy comedy about a Western post-apocalyptic creature with a cross gun who puts a confessional on your head No nuts and and a really tall insurance agent with her friend who has a million derringers.
Scott: and Yet the show is just a drunken guy who is a weaponsmith.
Rym: and if a show that silly can make me cry four or five times Handily not like, you know, the one man tear like I got and like Firefly.
Rym: I'm talking like Sobbing cuz.
Rym: remember that when we first saw that, you know episode 23 with wolf or is that and the scream?
Rym: We're all like trying not to cry.
Rym: and I remember there was this one moment where everyone kind of looked around and we all saw that we were All trying not to cry and then we all started crying And that was like the man bond episodes over.
Scott: so it's not like, you know You can hide your crying behind the rest of the episode
Rym: Yep And that was pretty much when the front row crew is a core Bonded fully because we all just cried openly in front of each other at a Japanese cartoon
Scott: in a dorm room On the CRT with a real media file
Rym: and and bad
Scott: subtitles barely
Rym: legible subtitles Man, actually, that's one thing I got to say.
Rym: our subtitles were wrong.
Rym: but the scene where you know Millie comes in and just hugs wolf would and the subtitles said and I'm pretty sure it was a bad translation was all the food said was You're a good healer and I just thought that was such a great line and it kind of disappointed me when I found out that Wasn't exactly what he said.
Scott: Yeah, they're there you know, it's sort of.
Scott: I guess that can happen with anything where if you if you watch something and You get a translation of it or rendition of it and then you get a slightly different rendition There's sort of a getting used to the original one or liking one over the other and it's it's.
Scott: you know It's hard to say which one's objectively I guess better or whatever.
Rym: But yeah, you know what if you didn't cry at some point during kratri gun, you're not a human being Are you just a really cold?
Rym: you you'd have to be pretty freakin cold because Scott and I are often Called out for our callousness and we cried like little guy Lee man.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: Let's see who who is that cold?
Rym: Well, Legato wouldn't have cried.
Rym: No.
Scott: No, he probably wouldn't.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I think Hitler would have been a little bit sad.
Rym: Oh, yeah, just a little bit maybe.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think he would have changed his ways though.
Scott: No, no, and he was one fucker that ruined everyone's day.
Rym: He probably been like Yeah in a way.
Rym: He's like knives A lot.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I think the show is over.
Scott: over.
Scott: Yeah Godwin's law.
Scott: It's over.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.