Scott: It's Monday July 30th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we talked briefly about portable audio recorders while Rym suffers.
Rym: Let's do this Well after the weekend of Otakon and the week at the shore.
Rym: We're back.
Rym: We're bad.
Rym: I'm a little sick still a little sick.
Scott: You're a lot sick.
Rym: I'm only a little sick now.
Rym: I was a lot sick during the week.
Rym: you see Otakon was well and good but I caught well.
Rym: actually Emily got sick at the con the oda flu as it were and I didn't exhibit symptoms until the second day at the shore, and I recovered mostly.
Rym: but as a result I couldn't talk for most of our quote-unquote writers retreat.
Rym: So the crew got to hang out in a very strange environment where Rym is mostly quiet.
Scott: Yeah, and I didn't get sick.
Scott: I wonder why that is.
Rym: yeah, I got pretty bad sinuses I always have.
Scott: why don't you get some sort of permanent fixing going on?
Rym: because there's no such thing.
Scott: There's a such thing.
Scott: there is of sinus surgery or something.
Rym: There's nothing that can be done about that.
Scott: Yeah, don't suck in the first place anyway.
Rym: I'm mostly back.
Rym: I can talk now.
Rym: I just have to talk quietly.
Rym: I've got the gain way up on my microphone, and I'm trying not to strain myself, but at least we're here doing a show.
Scott: Yeah, I guess doing a show sick is better than not doing a show at all and I got a few quick.
Scott: I know a lot of other podcasters that would just give up.
Rym: I know a lot of podcasters who give up for far less than we give up.
Scott: I know a lot of professional TV people who just be like got my voice is slightly and not coming in today.
Rym: Yeah, so take that internet.
Rym: Yeah, but before we get started we have a bunch of errata and all that from last week.
Rym: To all of you new listeners I'm sure you are aware that last week was mostly filler episodes.
Rym: a lot of your pride from Otakon.
Rym: You're probably wondering where your Otakon coverage is.
Rym: you're gonna have to wait till Wednesday.
Rym: you see Monday for GeekNights.
Rym: Here is science and technology and computers and Linux and all that crap.
Scott: And you want me to continue because you don't want to talk.
Scott: so on Tuesday we talk about the video games and sometimes the board games and Even more rarely the RPGs, but we might actually talk about those more often.
Rym: We're gonna have a lot more RPG talk as time comes on because we're gonna start playing Pretty much everything that Luke crane ever said a word about when we talk to him.
Scott: And the Wednesdays we cover the animes and the mangas and the comics and the visual arts of geekiness.
Scott: So that is the day where your Otakon coverage will reside because Otakon is a convention of otaku generation Which is mostly the anime and the manga also a kind of crappy podcast.
Rym: Yeah But also if you are one of those anime fans since I figure most of you and I saw a lot of you hitting the Feed so I know you're there if you're looking for anime stuff I suggest that you listen to.
Rym: two weeks ago on Wednesday.
Rym: We had a normal episode.
Rym: We reviewed ConnectiCon and I'd suggest to all of you who might have been looking for it last Wednesday We had special guest host Dave and Joel from fast karate for the gentleman Do one of the best episodes of GeekNights that has ever been aired.
Scott: but Rym screwed up.
Scott: You see we uploaded the episode in advance.
Scott: however, we uploaded it well beyond the quota on Libsyn and So Rym uploaded it and he checked it and he said all is well.
Rym: and all was well.
Rym: I listened to it from Libsyn.
Rym: I sent the link to Dave and Joel.
Rym: I was like check this out.
Scott: It works Yep, and then you know, I said it to automatically post to the website and everything Yep, and the Monday posted just fine.
Scott: the Monday to the Tuesday posted just fine.
Rym: There was no Thursday.
Scott: to all of you who are saying we screwed that up, too we were gonna make a Thursday episode similar to the Thursday episode from the last week of awesome, but Rym said oh, we'll just make it tomorrow morning.
Scott: And then we didn't like.
Rym: the reason I said that was that we've recorded what like five Various episodes and bits that day.
Scott: Yeah, but it wouldn't have taken long to make that tiny five-second episode.
Rym: It was already like 11 and I hadn't even packed for Otakon yet.
Scott: It took me like 10 minutes to pack for Otakon Whatever.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, the point is there wasn't a Thursday episode.
Rym: We could probably go back and put it Thursday episode there we could but if you tried to listen to the Dave and Joel It is up now.
Rym: It has been up since actually yesterday.
Scott: Yep, but it Rym went over the Libsyn quota and it got deleted.
Rym: Yes I do this podcast by myself and I put it over the quota.
Scott: We went through great effort to Get it uploaded again.
Rym: Yeah, you want to hear a funny story.
Rym: my computer currently my awesome new computer There's a problem with Linux and the onboard NIC which doesn't manifest in Windows It's only Linux and it basically makes my NIC periodically throw out a lot of bad packets.
Scott: I'll have to investigate this problem with closer scrutiny's.
Scott: but yeah There's a problem with his network card and his computer and his Linux.
Rym: So thus we weren't able to through all of our magic log into my computer from afar and up.
Scott: We went through such great Technological feats that I will not describe because they'll probably be bore many people even though it's a Monday show.
Rym: We should do a show on remote access though.
Scott: We should do a show on what access but basically we Connected to the server in the sky and from there we went through a VPN to mock to computer in the house.
Scott: And then from there we told the router to open up a port so we could reconfigure the router to open up a port To.
Scott: well, we made an SSH tunnel so that we could visit the router With a web browser reconfigure the router to open a port to rims computer Connected directly to rims computer and then failed to do so because rims computer has this problem.
Rym: Yep, even worse was before that I had to get Emily who was at home to turn my computer on and I thought alright I'll just call her and get her turn my computer out.
Rym: and then I realized as I walked her through all the steps that it Is not a trivial process to turn my computer on.
Scott: well The problem is you turned off the power in all different places.
Scott: I turned off the power on my computer in only two places not all three places.
Scott: Well part of it I turned the UPS I guess technically four places if you count these circuit breaker.
Rym: So I had the UPS and the power supply switch in the back and then the switch in the front.
Rym: Luckily it boots to Linux by default.
Rym: So I didn't have to mess with any of that.
Scott: Yeah, I only turned off the power supply switch and the computer itself.
Scott: Not the UPS.
Scott: I kept my UPS on because it also powers my clock But of course I got home and the clock was screwed up.
Scott: Anyway, yeah Which is awesome.
Scott: That's why I don't put the 9-volt battery in my clock I just put the.
Scott: I just put the clock into my UPS.
Rym: Yeah I used to plug my clock into the UPS but I rearranged my bedroom and now the UPS is too far away and I'm not.
Scott: You can use the extension cord though.
Rym: I'm not gonna run an extension cord halfway around my room.
Scott: Okay, then get the 9-volt battery.
Rym: I'm gonna get the 9-volt battery.
Rym: That's a good plan.
Rym: Actually, I'm thinking of getting a new alarm clock.
Rym: I've had the same alarm clock since like you get one of those fancy ones of the iPod dock.
Rym: I don't need that.
Rym: I'm using an alarm clock from like 1990.
Scott: you could get the old-fashioned kind.
Scott: that's mechanical with the hammer that goes back and forth between two bells.
Scott: ding-a-ding-a-ding-a-ding-a-ding.
Rym: See I've only had two alarm clocks in my life.
Rym: I had the one I had.
Rym: now I use it now.
Rym: that sound the sound my alarm clock Nate makes.
Rym: I Could hear that from like a mile away.
Rym: It's the worst sound in the world as far as I can tell because that has ruined Dreams and woken me up for work in school for well over a decade.
Rym: Yep Before that I had a Care Bears alarm clock that When it rang it was louder than anything you've ever.
Rym: I don't know how it was so loud But my parents actually gimped it so it wouldn't be so loud So wouldn't?
Rym: we wouldn't wake up screaming every morning.
Scott: I had a. I had this alarm clock.
Scott: that was clear, right?
Scott: You could like see through it and it was.
Scott: you know It was a standard alarm clock and I had that for a long time and then I don't know what happened to it.
Scott: I don't remember it breaking but I Eventually, it was gone and I got the one I have now which is a Radio Shack one Which is I got.
Scott: it must have been in high school sometime I don't know.
Scott: but the point is one time my mom ordered me a Super Mario alarm clock.
Scott: It was the kind with the hammer and the two bells and she ordered it from the JC penny catalog.
Scott: We went to the JC penny counter to pick it up and it was broken.
Scott: So she sent it back and she didn't get me a new one.
Scott: Ah Rob So I never had a Mario alarm clock, even though I should have had a Mario alarm clock.
Scott: If I had that Mario alarm clock, I'd probably still have that Mario alarm.
Rym: They should make a new Mario alarm clock one that plays I'm sure.
Scott: in Japan they have Mario alarm clocks.
Rym: Let's get one.
Scott: All right, sure Right.
Rym: Anyway, and my last little bit of errata here if I sound different.
Rym: it's because my throat is a wreck.
Rym: It's a piece of shit.
Rym: My throat is a bloody wreck.
Scott: Everyone donate us money.
Scott: I don't we don't ask for money, but Rym needs a new larynx.
Scott: So money is needed.
Rym: It's funny.
Rym: I've always had problems with my voice.
Rym: I lose my voice pretty easily and over the years like last Otakon Scott and I both lost our voices Not from doing live shows.
Rym: we survived all that.
Scott: the problem at Otakon is it's crowded and loud and you We talk a lot.
Rym: Mostly we talk a lot.
Scott: No one would have ever guessed that and when you talk a lot and it's loud you talk loudly so people can hear you.
Scott: It's like talk.
Scott: if I talked at a concert the whole night I would lose my voice because I'd be talking over the concert a lot.
Rym: Well even worse is the fact that the front row crew is a whole generally especially more so in the past than now Centers around us and if we don't take charge nothing gets done.
Rym: We're starting to wean everyone off of that.
Rym: But back then that year we pretty much heard it the entire crew around the entire con and we made all the dinner Arrangements and involved a lot of yelling to get people we're going to this restaurant at eight.
Rym: meet us there.
Rym: Well, I'm going back to the hotel room.
Rym: You've got the hotel key, right?
Scott: Yep, and thus we lost our voices this year.
Rym: We pretty much told everyone to go screw themselves and deal with it on their own.
Rym: We spent much of the con sitting at our artists alley table taking turns talking to random passers-by.
Scott: Yeah, I still.
Scott: I almost lost my voice at that artists alley.
Scott: that day At least I tired it out.
Scott: cuz I would be like you want to take the fanboy feud survey Blah blah blah.
Scott: Do you know about podcasts?
Scott: Blah blah blah.
Rym: You don't need an iPod.
Scott: You don't need an iPod Blah blah blah.
Scott: What was the other thing?
Scott: Oh Carcassonne.
Scott: This is what Carcassonne is.
Scott: Yep We had three things that I three spiels I had to give and we took.
Rym: we kind of took turns giving the different ones as one of us would rest and it was.
Rym: It was a good time.
Scott: It was good times, but three spiels over a loud artists alley tiring.
Rym: But at least I because my voice goes bad much easier than Scott's.
Rym: I actually read a bunch of things about how vocalists and singers and people don't lose their voices and It worked for not born with larynxes of Rym.
Rym: So it worked pretty well.
Rym: actually the techniques I breathing right and making sure I make the voice come from the right part of the throat and Open everything up and all that business.
Rym: and I didn't lose my voice at all at Otakon.
Rym: I lost my voice when I got sick and the post nasal drip destroyed me.
Scott: Yep Anyway, that's let's talk about tech stuff.
Scott: All right Scott talk about the rest later.
Rym: What do you got in the news since we missed I don't know almost two weeks worth of internet.
Scott: Well, there was so much internet.
Scott: Actually, I just sort of marked all my RSS feeds as red because I don't care It's not worth me my time to read like two thousand items of RSS news when maybe a hundred of them I actually care about.
Scott: But one thing did catch my eye and that is that the koan I audio 7 is now available in the United States.
Scott: Uh-huh, you can get the 8 gig one Which is red for two hundred and twenty dollars about or the 4 gig silver one for a hundred and sixty dollars now.
Scott: Why is this news that there's a new mp3 player?
Rym: Well one think about how big those are compared to how much they cost and compare them to say I don't know an iPod.
Scott: Well, yeah.
Scott: But also let me discuss why the kawan I audio 7 is such an important player that you should take note of Especially if you're the kind of person who wants a portable audio and maybe video player Wants a small one and does not want an iPod and doesn't want to be beholden to any sort of you know DRM type things or anything like that.
Scott: The kawan iota 7 is an mp3 player.
Scott: It's also a video player but it kind of sucks as a video player because you need to convert videos of the special tool To play on it.
Scott: But regardless of that it plays mp3s Flaks and oggs without problem.
Scott: just plays them.
Scott: There's barely any other players that do that.
Scott: It's got flash.
Scott: it works.
Scott: It's just a normal drive.
Scott: It has a normal USB hole in the bottom of it.
Scott: No weird plugs at all.
Scott: So you plug it in USB.
Scott: It looks like a drive.
Scott: you drag files onto it You're done on the front.
Scott: It's got like, you know the stop button in the play button and It's got this slide II thing that lets you like slide around like an iPod.
Scott: It also lets you click forward and click back just once and it also lets you hold down either end of the slide II bit To go really fast.
Scott: So it gives you actually a lot more flexibility in moving around the menus than the iPod wheelie does and It's cheap and it's awesome.
Scott: The only thing that's wrong with it is that the volume control or There's extra buttons on the side for volume control and mode change.
Scott: it does have a microphone and I'm pretty sure it can record things and Not that we care about that anymore.
Scott: We care about that.
Scott: Yeah, we'll get to that and I would say that if you are the kind of person who needs a portable media playing device and does not want an iPod This is the new winner.
Scott: The only major problem I see with it is that it is about you know It's about the size of an iPod nano face wise and maybe even smaller But it's about as thick as three or four iPod nanos.
Rym: That's not so bad.
Rym: It's not a deal-breaker, but it's still kind of.
Scott: however as a result the battery.
Scott: guess how long the battery lasts.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: seven years 60 hours.
Rym: It's not too bad.
Rym: my iPod nano which isn't that old already only lasts a couple hours.
Scott: mine lasts like six ish hours.
Scott: When it was new it lasted seven ish hours 60 hours dams This thing.
Scott: you just don't need to plug it in.
Scott: So yeah, cool anyone listening to this on their computer?
Scott: go buy this player and listen to it on that instead.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm still kind of holding out.
Rym: I think I'm gonna keep my some semi crappy, but yet functional iPod nano.
Scott: Oh, I didn't say I'm gonna run on this.
Rym: I think my plan in general is I'm gonna keep this thing Until the perfect mp3 player appears and then I will pay almost any amount of money to have that sound.
Scott: basically right now My phone and my iPod.
Scott: I'm gonna keep them until they are dead and the point at which they are dead.
Scott: I will you know find if the if the best thing does not exist yet.
Scott: I will just continue traveling the low cheap road of subsistence Until the perfect thing comes.
Rym: of course the perfect thing is pretty much Wi-Fi.
Rym: subscribe to podcasts on it and it just downloads them whenever it gets internet access.
Scott: only ever have to plug it in to charge Removable rechargeable battery.
Rym: Yeah, that's for you want to configure it.
Rym: It's just a website lee free of DRM.
Scott: Just put files on it.
Scott: Yeah good interface small.
Rym: So anyway, I bring this up only because it's kind of relevant to what happened at Otakon.
Rym: But apparently a lot of you might have seen this.
Rym: but Fox 11 which is for Los Angeles the local guy there did some sort of Expose on this band of terrorists car.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Scott: This is actually a real Fox News story.
Rym: I'm at www.my Fox la.com.
Scott: My Fox la.
Scott: that's not like fox.com slash la or something.
Scott: It's a tough call.
Rym: I'm pretty sure this is legitimate Scott.
Rym: No,
Scott: I'm just saying
Rym: anyway, this is a video of Someone who really doesn't seem to understand what the internet is about and a bunch of other people who are victims of the internet Partly because they don't understand what it's really about Talking about the evil terrorist ways of places like 4chan.
Rym: now for those of you who don't know 4chan is pretty much just a sea of pornography Mostly the futanari variety.
Rym: Yeah, something like that.
Rym: Don't look that word up Do not you really don't?
Scott: if you don't know what futanari is you don't want to know what futanari is.
Scott: f-u-t-a-n-a-r-i.
Rym: See, I'm glad you spelled it now.
Rym: This is kind of like back in the day when you kept hearing people say Goatsy or tub girl and you think I wonder what that is and they'd say oh you don't want to know.
Rym: But then you got curious and then you looked and then you realize that they were right.
Scott: Well, you don't want to know what futanari to me.
Rym: I think that the futanari no one on 4chan actually likes it.
Rym: I think that is 4chan's defense against normal people.
Rym: normal people go in see that and go.
Scott: Ah, I do not think that it is that futanari is.
Scott: I don't think defense is the only purpose of futanari on 4chan But it is one of the purposes of having that there.
Rym: It must have some other hidden purpose that we don't know about.
Scott: maybe it's code who like futanari go to 4chan.
Rym: I can't imagine there's that many people who like futanari.
Scott: I think there's a lot of people who secretly like futanari.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't see the appeal.
Rym: but then again, there's a lot of things I don't see.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I don't see the appeal either.
Rym: but yeah what I suggest?
Rym: you watch this because it's kind of hilarious and - I would like to point out that our friends Pete and James at Otakon did a Documentary.
Rym: they had a James had a camera and released a portion of a documentary.
Rym: Yeah, they started a documentary of 4chan and they filmed the line to get into the panel.
Rym: They couldn't actually film the panel because they wouldn't let cameras into the panel.
Scott: This is quickly turning into an Otakon review show.
Rym: Yeah, well, it's kind of people want to hear about this.
Rym: We'll talk about this more once it's done But suffice to say the video footage that they got from the 4chan line at Otakon was up Interesting.
Rym: See King?
Rym: Fuck yeah.
Scott: That's the only one we're gonna do.
Rym: I think 4chan has infected the front row crew a little bit but more importantly I think they're gonna go all the way and make an actual documentary because I think I don't.
Rym: I'm gonna paraphrase Pete, but he basically said I went in expecting to see something hilarious and make fun of it.
Rym: I came out somewhat shaken and Realized that there's something far deeper and more profound and at the same time all the more horrifying going on here.
Rym: Yep Okay, the real moral of this news story however is very simple.
Rym: people who don't understand the internet don't seem to realize that the internet is the wild wild west and You've got to protect yourself.
Rym: It's not that there's some evil anonymous clan out to get you.
Rym: It's that you haven't protected yourself from the internet.
Rym: It's not that hard to do.
Scott: I like how they seem to think that there's an actual group calling itself anonymous that is doing these bad things.
Scott: I'm opposed to just you know anonymous people.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Yes people fear what they do not understand.
Scott: This is old and known.
Rym: consider this a preview because we're gonna do a show probably in the next couple weeks on 4chan and anonymity and all that and of course John Gabriel's creator internet fuckwad theory up the most important theory on all internet knowings.
Rym: Well so much for more talk about that.
Rym: It looks like it's time for things of the day.
Rym: I hate to have to explain this again But since we have a bunch of new listeners I figure I might as well at least warn you that This is the part of the show where we talk about the things we've seen that might have been hilarious on the internet recently.
Scott: Well, I haven't been on the internet for like a week and a half So you're getting something that's right at the top cuz I just cleared out everything.
Scott: I am NOT looking back if anything cool happened on the internet and last week.
Scott: I don't know about it.
Scott: So if you actually send me a link, I won't say that's so old.
Scott: I seen that.
Scott: I'll say awesome something I haven't seen but make sure it's from the last week.
Scott: if it's from two weeks ago, you'll be puns.
Rym: Yeah Alright, so what do you got for me?
Scott: So check this video, right?
Scott: There's someone they have a house and they're sitting in the house Looking at their front door.
Scott: probably it's from the inside.
Rym: I feel like your story should be interspersed with brack.
Scott: That did it done.
Scott: And they look at the doggy door.
Rym: done done done all right, that's enough of that.
Scott: and Through the doggy door comes one of the better animals the raccoon.
Scott: I Really like raccoons are alright except the rabid ones.
Rym: I like them.
Rym: I like raccoons cuz one.
Rym: they have little human hands and they manipulate things.
Rym: they pick stuff up and they're very.
Rym: They're very intelligent looking and they seem to have some sort of glimmer of understanding of what they're about to do Especially when it's something mischievous.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I like the idea of raccoons more than actual raccoons But anyway, well thing is I've never had actual raccoons mess with any of my stuff So I have no clothes.
Scott: they used to mess with their trash all the time.
Scott: We had to seal that trash up with some bungee cords or else they'd be getting in there.
Rym: We just had a really heavy lid on the trash and the raccoons couldn't get to it.
Scott: Yeah, our trash not heavy lids.
Rym: We also had dogs.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Anyway, it's raccoon Pokes through the doggy door dumb dumb dumb.
Scott: And he reaches into the house like with half his body But not the other half his body.
Scott: and they're sitting there videotaping this raccoon and it's just sitting there like hey what's up, but it's glowy eyeballs and it's evil burglar mask.
Scott: and it grabs this little rug sitting by the front door and And it pulls it out the doggy door it steals it a Raccoon wearing a burglar mask broke into their house and stole their carpet.
Scott: Oh my OMG raccoons in your house stealing your carpets.
Scott: I has a rug That's.
Scott: that's this video.
Rym: So over the week which we in the front row crew every year called the week of awesome the week we spend usually down in Wildwood at our friend Scott Johnson's house Instead of you know, wherever else we'd go just sleeping on the beach and doing all sorts of things.
Rym: we spent part of it with Yuko and Ananth and the two of them kept making some inside jokes and eventually They realized that I did not understand the inside jokes because I had not seen the video to which they were referring.
Scott: Read a book.
Rym: They then tried to find said video and it was up taken down from most of the places that had been posted.
Scott: That's because most of the places it was posted It was posted on YouTube and just about every other result on Google was a link to the YouTube that was taken down.
Rym: I think there were a couple of different youtubes taken down.
Scott: even so there were all links to YouTube where it was taken down.
Rym: Suffice to say if the link to this thing of the day breaks just keep looking for it.
Rym: You'll find it somewhere.
Rym: If anything it might re-air at some point perhaps.
Rym: if we only watch television Now people try to show us stuff for things of the day all the time And I was like, alright, whatever to show it to me later.
Rym: But they persisted.
Rym: they decided that it was too good to let go and they spent a good while looking for it and Eventually, they found it and they showed it to me and I can't pretend that I didn't laugh out loud.
Scott: It's it's too awesome.
Scott: Should we should we go through the lyrics one at a time and then just have let leave it at that?
Rym: Well, first off this is something that actually aired on television on BET black entertainment television.
Rym: It was a written recorded and produced by Bomani Amer aka not a rapper.
Rym: Yep, it seems like a pretty cool guy - I'm kind of interested in the rest of his music now Although he does say that he's not a rapper.
Scott: He's a poet with a hip-hop styling which is a rapper.
Scott: That's like saying I'm not a string.
Scott: I'm just some elongated cloth used to tie things up.
Scott: I'm not a car I'm just a four-wheeled vehicle used to transport people around town.
Scott: That's basically what this guy's saying.
Scott: That's the only thing I could find wrong with him though.
Scott: Everything else is cool.
Rym: so far from what I can gather though I didn't research this too deeply.
Rym: he made this song and BET decided that they liked it and they wanted to get their team to animate it for him and then they made a music video.
Scott: Yeah, it's actually I'm usually not a fan of the music videos, but this one's pretty good.
Scott: I like it.
Scott: It's gets good stuff.
Rym: a quote from this article This video is a great example of how the best animation can convey complex messages with great clarity and humor.
Rym: Now I would like to warn all of you that the video is not safe for work.
Scott: Well only because it has bad words.
Rym: Yeah and some of you may or may not be offended by this but I would like to point out also that Scott and I are not racist and I contend that this video is not racist either.
Rym: This video has nothing to do with race.
Rym: This video is everything to do with hip-hop culture regardless of whether or not you're white black or purple.
Scott: Well, not so much the hip-hop culture But you know a certain part of the hip-hop a subset of the hip-hop culture that involves spinner rims.
Scott: Yes, because there is also the hip-hop called the.
Scott: that's actually the largest Subset of the hip-hop culture because I there is the sex subset of hip-hop culture Which is all cool and underground and caring about poetry and music that is separate.
Rym: There's also the subset aka nerd core.
Scott: There are many cores, but we're mostly talked targeting the main core.
Rym: so the primary lyric the chorus if you will of this work is read a book read a book read a motherfucking book.
Scott: and What are the other ones?
Rym: let's see by land.
Rym: brush your teeth Wear deodorant speeds.
Scott: It's called speed stick.
Rym: It's not expensive.
Scott: It's not expensive.
Rym: I highly recommend you watch this.
Scott: I find it absolutely hilarious see myself watching it two more times tonight.
Rym: Well, we have to show it to Emily when she gets home.
Scott: Oh, absolutely.
Rym: I Gotta say I'm gonna check out the rest of this guy's music though.
Scott: Yeah, you can buy it on iTunes if you're into that sort of thing.
Rym: So our main bit tonight gonna be a little bit short because my throat is pretty much at the end of its wits right now.
Rym: I don't know how much longer I'll be able to talk.
Scott: It's end not the end of its wits.
Rym: See when I start saying something wrong, I can't just you know, oh I had a cue and edit it out.
Rym: I gotta really be judicious with the words I use.
Scott: So why are you saying a bunch of useless words right now and your voice is running out because my pride demands that I cover It up.
Scott: Haha Alright, so tonight we're gonna talk about portable audio recorders.
Scott: now Basically, we as podcasters have a great need for a portable audio recorder.
Scott: by that I mean a device which you can carry is powered by batteries in which can take an audio input signal and save it and then later deliver that signal to be used for other purposes.
Scott: and Well, we used to.
Scott: you know, these devices have been around for a long time.
Scott: I mean cell phones can do this Frickin.
Scott: they used to have little tiny tape recorders that could do this.
Scott: they still do that you can get a device that does this all over the place, but We've never needed one really in our lives even though I mean I've had cell phones that could do it and I've had Other things that could do it and just never use that feature because it wasn't something we needed.
Rym: Yep I mean in high school, I use that stuff a lot But I could just borrow the debt from the music teacher if I needed to record anything.
Scott: I had a Fisher Price tape recorder as a kid that it had built-in microphone.
Rym: I did too.
Rym: I actually apparently my brother and I recorded a little radio show all the time and I'm trying to find out if my mom still has the tapes laying around.
Scott: Yeah, that'll be some GeekNights specials for you Rym age 5 awesome, but yeah anyway as Podcasters we were looking for a new one.
Scott: You know something we could actually use for the podcast that we went to a convention mostly conventions But also other places.
Scott: we could record what went on there without having to carry a computer around or anything like that.
Rym: Yeah last year's Otakon We brought the Mac and the monitor and the compressor and the mixer and all the microphones and everything and that worked really well.
Rym: But I gotta say putting that stuff in packing it up taking it out putting it back together Was totally not worth it sucked ass base even though the episode we recorded with all that is still our most popular episode, huh?
Scott: But anyway, so we started looking for a solution to the problem and all the other Podcasters were using these I River thingies.
Scott: and well the I River is basically an mp3 player that happens to also be able to record audio and I wasn't really a fan of that so much and it didn't seem like it made the highest quality recordings.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I'll admit whenever I tried to listen to other people's podcasts, and they tried to interview anyone the audio was usually atrocious.
Rym: Yeah, like unlistenable.
Scott: so the I River was no good, so he said all right Let's go to the Best Buy and see what they got.
Scott: and they have at the Best Buy audio recorders They got tape ones which tape ones while they are useful if you're just like trying to record a lecture or if you're say Interrogating someone or taking personal notes as you walk around you know in observing things at the zoo Maybe not too useful for us podcasting mostly because it's not digital
Rym: Yep, meaning I have to sit there and at one-to-one time record onto my computer from the tape to get the data off of it.
Rym: and I actually borrowed one of these from my friend Scott Johnson at Katsucon like two years ago And I went around trying to interview people to you know do stuff with the audio.
Rym: And I learned that when I came home, and I had this tape full of audio.
Rym: There was not a single Functional tape player in our entire house.
Scott: There's actually a the thing you can buy for your computer that goes in a five and a quarter inch bay.
Scott: That will if you put cassette tapes into it will convert them to digital file formats with a piece of software.
Rym: Yeah, but by then it was too late.
Scott: Yes, of course We're not gonna go out and buy one of those devices for a one-time use anyway.
Rym: the first thing failed.
Rym: the second thing I put it into cuz.
Rym: we think we had a bunch of them.
Rym: There's.
Rym: none of them worked.
Rym: the second one destroyed the tape.
Rym: I Respooled it into a different cassette and then three and four also failed and then I gave up And I think I threw the cassette away.
Rym: good idea.
Scott: Anyway, so tape suck.
Scott: we didn't want to deal with tapes plus.
Scott: We'd have to buy tapes.
Scott: fuck that right.
Scott: so we bought this Sony thing and until someone dropped it and broke it ahem it.
Scott: It worked, but shittily.
Scott: basically the audio quality recorded was bad.
Scott: it recorded at low bit rates But if you plugged a microphone into the hole on the bottom of it and you ran filter you did post-production on the audio.
Rym: It wasn't too bad granted It was an eighth inch jack.
Rym: So I had to convert to a quarter inch and then plug in like a big Radio Shack microphone.
Rym: So the microphone was bigger than the recorder.
Scott: Yes, also the recorder.
Scott: You know, it didn't have too much space, but it could hold a lot.
Scott: enough hours of music enough battery time.
Scott: But to get the music off of the recorder It was DRM DRM on something I recorded out in the real world.
Rym: by pushing a button We run the house special crappy windows software that didn't work in Linux or the Mac to get the audio off.
Scott: Yes, only provided this software is the Sony's.
Scott: by the way, of course Sony gave this special software was the only way to get the stuff off of the player and as soon as you got it Off the player the DRM was gone.
Scott: It was a way for an mp3.
Scott: So what the fuck?
Scott: why have to DRM in the first place?
Scott: just make mp3s on a disk.
Scott: god damn it.
Rym: It was one of the crappiest things ever, but it was still like 80 bucks.
Scott: Yeah, but it broke.
Rym: Yeah Well, it was broken.
Scott: Yes, 80 bucks down the toilet.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't work.
Rym: I got a few interviews out of it, but it just.
Rym: it was kind of crap You know, so while it served the purpose of walk around a con and interview people kind of okay it didn't serve all the other purposes like Record a backup stream of audio or plug it into a panel and record the whole panel.
Scott: Yes another reason we wanted a portable audio recorder is that what we could set up is we could Take an output from our mixer because one output from the mixer goes to the computer where it's recorded and turned into the show.
Scott: We could take another output from the mixer and send it into the portable recorder.
Scott: Thus if the something happens to the computer the portable device has batteries.
Scott: so we won't lose the show Basically no matter what happens if we simultaneously record the show to the backup Portable recorder and of course the Sony thing could not do that.
Scott: So we started looking for devices.
Scott: We needed a device that was a portable recorder Recorded relatively high quality had sufficient battery life and recording hours Wasn't too big and heavy and stupid wasn't crazily stupid expensive that we couldn't afford it.
Scott: and when you plugged it into a computer to get the files off was just MP3 files or just WAV files and didn't give us shit and didn't require special software.
Rym: now I did a bunch of research.
Scott: I did a bunch of research as well And basically I found that they're a device that we wanted does not really exist so much.
Scott: I mean there were the low-end devices like the Sony thing and those things are garbage.
Rym: They're not worth the money.
Scott: Yeah, unless you're basically walking around doing personal crappy recording not for a podcast or any.
Rym: and then there's the hack together.
Rym: solutions Like buy the thing to stick into your iPod or buy the thing and all that the entire mid-range product line We're all these.
Scott: turn your mp3 player into a recorder or get an mp3 player.
Scott: That's also a recorder like the creative Zen thing, which is also a recorder and those things take pretty crappy audio.
Rym: Yes, you got a fiddle with them.
Rym: They don't always work so well.
Rym: And also you can't plug a real microphone into them.
Rym: Yep, I mean some of them you can but well not a real microphone.
Scott: for the most part They're better than these Sony craps, but they're not dedicated recording devices.
Scott: They're mp3 players that happen to be able to record or their cell phones that happen to be able to record or their Smart trios that happen to be able to record and they don't really well suited to the recording.
Scott: You just happen to be able to do it sufficiently.
Scott: and I wasn't about to go and buy an mp3 player just for the recording feature.
Rym: and From what I read all the ones that would work on our iPods were really really crappy and also really expensive.
Scott: Yes, mostly cuz we had iPod nanos.
Scott: They were pretty expensive.
Scott: But even if we had a regular iPod and not a nano the thing that makes it record decently is still like $200 which is a lot of freaking money.
Rym: But the problem was the next step up was basically professional audio recorders in the 600 to 1200 dollar range.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you didn't get the mp3 player there wasn't like a $300 product.
Scott: That was an awesome recorder for podcasters.
Scott: That doesn't exist.
Scott: I couldn't find one anywhere.
Scott: The only the next best thing was a $500 badass recorder that like professional TV and radio NPR type people would use to do interviews in the field or like police would use to you know Interrogate record interrogations and FBI people would use.
Scott: there wasn't any mid-range product.
Rym: So think about this on one end the top of the budget scale for consumers.
Rym: Cuz pretty much.
Rym: I think the real issue here is that they don't make these products for consumers at all And I can think of a lot of reasons why they might not.
Scott: there isn't a great demand other than podcasters.
Scott: It's also there.
Rym: I mean back with debt and all that.
Rym: There was definitely this idea that the recording industry as a whole wanted to keep Professional recording equipment out of the hands of the public.
Rym: that made it easy to pirate things.
Rym: That's why debt was so hideously crippled.
Scott: if you bought anything that cost a reasonable amount of money I mean imagine if people could get awesome badass recorders Right actual things that recorded in quality and brought them to concerts.
Scott: instead of bringing tiny little tape recorders They're using their cell phone to record.
Scott: then they can get it for like 300 bucks.
Scott: That'd be pretty dangerous because people have awesome concert recordings as opposed to Scratchy bootleg concert recordings.
Rym: So between the in the gap here on one end You've got like that $80 piece of crap with a 16 megabyte flash in it that you can't even remove and DRM all over.
Rym: And then you've got the Marantz PMD 660 which we ended up buying.
Scott: yeah, we basically bought the lowest end Professional thing we could find.
Scott: I mean we could have gotten the 670, you know, I kind of wanted this 7.
Scott: Yes, it was.
Scott: basically we could get an even fancier professional thing But we didn't.
Scott: we got the least professional Professional thing because it was the cheapest thing that met our needs and we didn't have another choice.
Rym: Now the thing is this thing is badass and it met all of our needs a hundred percent.
Rym: It's got two XLR inputs phantom power.
Rym: It's got a million different modes.
Scott: the phantom power.
Rym: It just takes flash.
Rym: It'll record like a hundred and seventy hours the way we've got it set up right now.
Scott: Yeah The only complaints I have about the device is that it takes four double-a batteries and they don't last very long.
Scott: If you're actually recording they last about four hours not long enough considering the fact that with my 4 gig compact flash card I can record like an ungodly number of hours of audio.
Rym: Luckily I can mitigate that.
Rym: I'm thinking of just buying a lithium battery pack for it.
Scott: That sounds like a good idea.
Rym: They're not that much money surprisingly and they're actually made for this device.
Scott: Yep Good things about the device.
Scott: basically everything it records in high quality Even though a lot of people on the internet were complaining about the preamps on the device being shitty.
Scott: It's good enough for us and it's way better than any consumer product.
Rym: It's good enough for 90% of people.
Rym: Yeah, I mean in the audio you can see the problems with the preamps.
Scott: Those problems are not going to be apparent If it's really a problem for you and you need perfect quality.
Scott: There are people that are actually selling this device with.
Scott: they Replace the preamps for you with better ones and then sell you the device And if you really need it that you can go that route, of course You could also just use the line in and use your own preamp, huh?
Scott: Huh?
Scott: Yeah, but basically the thing it records it plays back it can record multiple tracks.
Scott: It can auto level.
Scott: it can.
Scott: God, it does.
Scott: every can edit the audio on the device You could.
Scott: the device is a USB drive so you can just get the audio off or you can take the compact flash out And plug it into a compact flash reader and get the files that way because they're just waving mp3 files and they just work.
Rym: Yep, and I side effect of that is if you need to you can use this as a straight-up card reader in your computer.
Scott: Yeah, if you need a compact flash reader, the problem is is a one.
Scott: it's a USB 1.0 compact flash readers.
Scott: It's a little bit slow, but it's it's frickin useful as all hell.
Rym: It's got a pretty good stereo mic built in.
Scott: Yep Yeah, if you just put it on a table and push record without using any external microphones it can record pretty well.
Rym: I recorded almost everything we did at Otakon.
Rym: most of that I'm not gonna put in the show.
Rym: the quality is not good enough, but not because of the device But just because of the setup of recording.
Rym: Yeah part of that is due to the fact that as much as I love Otakon Their AV teams are really good except for giving me an audio feed.
Rym: Every time I ever try to get an audio feed out of them It's the signal-to-noise ratio is to the point that it's absolutely useless.
Scott: Yeah because basically at Otakon there's these people.
Scott: they contract out all their AV to a company I called DSL and They provide the projectors and the screens and the audios and the microphones and the mixers and all that stuff To all the rooms at Otakon that need AV and they do a good job.
Scott: and you know you always see the DSL techs running around doing what they're supposed to do and they get the job done, but Because this is equipment that's used often in a lot of conventions and things and It's you know that company makes a lot of money if they don't replace their equipment.
Rym: also as I look the way they set the equipment up is Not optimal for what I want to do.
Scott: Also, basically all they care about is people sitting in front of the room talking to a microphone and the audio comes out of the Speakers without hurting people.
Scott: that's what they care about.
Scott: So making sure that the signal-to-noise ratio is good or that it's nice It'll be a nice recording signal coming out of their mixer is not one of their high priorities.
Rym: So it's difficult to record panels at Otakon through the equipment at least Yeah, but anyway, since I have this device and we have all that recording time We're recording everything we do mostly so we can listen to ourselves and improve.
Rym: Yep, which is good.
Rym: And you know archival footage.
Rym: Maybe we'll make some Specials or extras out of funny things that might have happened.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So in the end if you're someone who needs to record audio out in the wild You can get a piece of crap.
Scott: if that suits your needs if you don't care about quality or anything like that And you don't care about using pan in the ass software to actually get the audio off The device or if you never even want to get the audio off the device at all Then there's plenty of things you can just pick up for like 50 bucks at the store.
Scott: if you need something better than that, you're pretty much gonna have to buy something professional or Suffer with a lesser solution.
Scott: that doesn't do everything you want and the lowest professional thing will do everything you want and probably more Than what you want unless you are a professional and it sucks.
Rym: Yeah, though what this has all taught me and I've been leaning this way before I think I've talked about it once or twice But now I'm pretty much solid in this belief I've.
Rym: there are only two Classes of purchases for me in my life.
Rym: at this point if I need something I will either buy the cheapest thing that will get Job done minimally or I'm going to buy exactly what I want.
Rym: I'm not gonna buy some middle-ground compromise anymore.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I'm doing.
Scott: Basically if I need to do something I'm either gonna get the Pete the most bargain.
Scott: I can get something that does the job for like five bucks.
Rym: Like what I do with cell phones.
Rym: I take whatever cell phone is free no matter what until the perfect cell phone arrived which currently doesn't exist at for a price I'm willing to actually I'd say it doesn't exist at all.
Scott: doesn't exist not in the US anyway Which means it's not perfect for me.
Scott: So yeah, I'm gonna buy the cheap bargain thing for five bucks that gets the job done Even though I have to suffer.
Scott: I save a lot of money on it and I get the job done.
Scott: I don't care unless the perfect product exists that fits my needs exactly in which case I will pay almost any price and I will get that device and Portable audio recorders.
Scott: Basically we bought the bargain price and it basically didn't get the job done.
Rym: Not only did it not get the job done it got broken immediately.
Scott: So we basically we bought the cheapest thing that will get the job done while simultaneously Buying something expensive that meets all our needs.
Scott: because they were the same product.
Scott: Cuz nothing less than that would have gotten the job done.
Scott: Oh So sad.
Rym: so so I gotta say this thing is worth every single single freaking penny.
Rym: We've spent on it.
Rym: This thing is beautiful.
Scott: Yeah, the only thing I can say that I'm disappointed about it Is that from the pictures online it looked like it was going to be one of those heavy Really rugged rubberized like, you know, you could kick it across the room professional black
Rym: really
Scott: Dangerous devices but upon further inspection, it's relatively light which I guess is good.
Scott: weight wise because carrying it around But it's not.
Scott: it doesn't feel like it's the strongest plastic.
Scott: It is though.
Scott: You could kick it across the room But it doesn't have that feel of.
Scott: I am tough and badass and you could beat the shit out of me.
Rym: So you're saying that perception matters more than reality to you?
Scott: What I'm saying is that I really like that.
Scott: when devices are all rubberized and have the thick plastic in this one I thought it was gonna be like that and it was not.
Rym: we could rubberize it.
Scott: Ooh That might interfere with the internal microphone of the speaker though.
Rym: It doesn't matter.
Rym: My only real complaint is the internal microphone is pretty good in stereo But it's not great and I think I'm still gonna have to drop like a hundred bucks or two on a real boundary microphone.
Scott: Yeah, a boundary microphone is also something we've been looking into and I think we'll just tap.
Scott: maybe We're not gonna need one for a long while now.
Scott: So let's just hold off on that.
Scott: Yes, I mean it's something.
Rym: earliest is gonna be December.
Scott: We're not probably not even gonna need it.
Rym: then February will definitely need.
Scott: we're gonna need one in February probably maybe earlier for uber con.
Scott: Maybe you're right.
Rym: It depends cuz I kind of want to record a whole session of burning wheel.
Scott: Mmm, good call.
Scott: But yeah, we won't need one for a few months at the least in six months at the most probably.
Scott: So we'll hold off on that and buy other things instead.
Rym: But yeah at any rate I'm sorry, if this was a little bit slower than our normal format of GeekNights a little less give-and-take I was avoiding talking as much as I can.
Scott: let myself avoid talking and Fix your throat for tomorrow cuz I don't want to have to talk about some video game or something with alone.
Rym: I expect by tomorrow.
Rym: We'll be back at our full stride.
Rym: So if you get a judge GeekNights based on episodes you're listening to I'd listen to at least one more before you judge.
Scott: It's not just awesome.
Scott: How when you know when we create the theoretical influx of new listeners from convention season We make the crappiest shows we can make and we mess up putting an episode online.
Rym: And yeah It might be something to do with the fact that we always go out of town for pretty much two weeks Right after we get all these new listeners.
Scott: Maybe that's not the best strategy for listeners, but it's a great strategy for us.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: I needed that week.
Rym: God damn Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Oh well Tune in the rest of the week and by next week We'll be proud.
Scott: next week will probably be like the best for awesome episodes of GeekNights ever Assuming that every episode of GeekNights is better than the last and assuming that none of us die.
Scott: That could happen.
Scott: I might poison you.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.