Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday April 10th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we're gonna talk about solitaire and jez ball and all those crappy little games that you're probably underestimated.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So for all these years, I actually never really had a digital camera.
Rym: so as a result I'd never had a flicker account or anything.
Scott: yeah I only had a film camera for a long time, and I finally bought a digital camera with year ago.
Scott: I think I don't even remember.
Rym: I remember when I was in middle school.
Rym: I took $70.
Rym: I went to service merchandise, and I bought a little 35 millimeter camera.
Scott: I had one of those Adventix ones with the weird film.
Scott: I actually have a roll of that film that's undeveloped.
Scott: I keep forgetting to go develop it.
Rym: actually where I'm going with that is that I found my old service merchandise camera the other day And I opened it and there's a half shot roll of film in it.
Scott: Oh Good pictures on there.
Rym: those pictures are probably from middle school.
Rym: If my pictures are probably from like when I was in Israel or something not sure maybe high school but I pretty much it wasn't worth it to take pictures because Developing film was expensive, and then what am I gonna?
Rym: Do I have a stack of photographs from my early life?
Rym: I just what am I gonna do with them if anything?
Rym: I'm gonna scan him in and throw away the originals.
Scott: Oh, we're just never big on pictures.
Scott: I mean they're probably a lot of pictures of me and family vacations or whatever somewhere my parents house in some box You know, but I have a digital camera now, and I just can't remember to take pictures.
Rym: see I do because a while ago Emily.
Rym: She got a new fancy digital camera.
Rym: So she gave me her really old one which while it's not the best digital camera in the world because it's old I've never had a digital camera so it's great.
Rym: and I had this tiny little memory card for it because I haven't even bothered to buy a bigger one yet.
Rym: and Today for the first time I actually use the thing.
Scott: Yeah, digital cameras are at the point now.
Scott: or if you buy a fancy one It's stupid fancy and like a normal average one is so much better than any normal person cares about.
Scott: And who?
Scott: you really need photos to look like super wedding photos that you would pay $1,000 for a camera when you could get four hundred dollars one that is good enough for any normal human being.
Rym: So as you all recall the other week I learned a lot about rock climbing in a short amount of time when I attempted to do some rock climbing one weekend and almost Died and almost called 911 because I didn't think I could climb back down and I needed help and all that business.
Rym: But I got out and I survived.
Rym: so today because I had my camera and I this morning I saw it and I thought I'm gonna start carrying this around everywhere because you never know I'm just gonna keep it in my car and maybe I'll get something to take a picture.
Scott: Yeah, I carry mine around everywhere and I don't use it.
Rym: Well, I keep thinking take pictures.
Rym: So I open up my car and I took a picture of the busted part of my engine And I was just taking pictures of stuff all over.
Rym: and then on the way home I took the mountain route and I happen to be driving past the mountain that I almost got stuck on before and I thought you Know what?
Rym: I'm gonna take pictures of where I got stuck and like from the bottom and then I'm gonna take pictures of all those abandoned buildings Around it and then I'll make a flicker account and put him up and one thing led to another and it was nice out.
Rym: So instead of just taking those pictures I ended up climbing the goddamn mountain and taking a bunch of pictures up there, too Mm-hmm.
Rym: So if you I'm gonna link to it.
Rym: But if you check out my flicker there are pictures of me Still in my business professional dress from work because I didn't change because I didn't expect that I'd be climbing a mountain.
Rym: Having climbed the mountain and I got some cool shots.
Scott: It's it doesn't really look like a mountain to me.
Scott: It looks like a hill.
Rym: Well, it's breakneck Ridge.
Rym: It's I forget exactly how tall it is.
Rym: It's like 1200 feet.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, if you go to my flicker, which I've had for years You'll notice that I don't take pictures too often just because I don't remember to plus Hill or not.
Rym: I bet $1,000.
Rym: you couldn't make it up to the top within two hours.
Scott: I just use a grappling hook.
Rym: Grappling hook.
Rym: Yeah, that actually wouldn't really help at all.
Scott: I throw it would grab onto some tree.
Rym: There's no trees.
Scott: This is a tree.
Rym: No, she's drawn the pictures that you took Which some of those pictures.
Rym: those trees are on the white path you can climb as opposed to the blue path.
Rym: That is not so much a path but a sheer cliff.
Scott: I'm sure it wouldn't be too difficult.
Scott: If you made it up without any fancy equipment.
Scott: I could definitely go.
Rym: Yeah The point is I don't think you realize what a grappling hook is really useful for and it wouldn't be useful for climbing that Mountain by any stretch if I could just get a rope hanging down the side.
Scott: It's all good.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see.
Rym: I don't think you could even if you're just a straight path.
Rym: I don't think you could do it.
Rym: You don't have the stamina.
Scott: even so your your constant trick that you keep thinking is gonna work of say Scott Can't do something in order to trick him into doing it will never work.
Rym: Because lately after that last game of Kayla's where once again room the Kayla's machine dominates I believe your argument was I could win and I could put all that effort in.
Rym: I just don't wanna.
Scott: That was not quite what I said.
Rym: What were you saying?
Scott: I was saying something far more complex that I don't.
Rym: Okay, but suffice to say the end result of your argument was I can I just don't wanna.
Scott: that was not the end result of My argument but my argument was such that I cannot blame you for interpreting it as such.
Rym: Regardless in my flicker if you're a crazy stalker You'll probably see a lot of odd pictures because I'm probably going to take a good number of pictures every single day.
Scott: See how that works.
Scott: I told myself I take a picture every day and I didn't and you know what lasted like a day.
Rym: so far I'm betting a thousand.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, I've added a thousand for a day.
Scott: Also.
Scott: Yeah I'll give you a few weeks though because you you said something.
Rym: so in the news John Romero Okay is in the news what I thought he was like just retired or whatever.
Rym: well No, but he's still fairly active and I've always had a lot of respect for John Romero because despite all the fun people made of him he is Despite Pronoun that people made of this entity this entity known as John Romero.
Rym: You can't deny the impact he has had on gaming.
Scott: No kind of hard to die.
Scott: I mean one of the first books about the history of gaming was about him.
Rym: Well, the reason he's in the news is there's an interview and he said a lot of interesting things.
Rym: But one of the things he said to simplify greatly is he basically said that the Xbox 360 and the ps3 that paradigm of console gaming is doomed to failure.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: I got a little.
Rym: I got a little quote here from him.
Rym: right right now MMOs mobile and PC episodic are really polarizing into the newest most important segments in gaming.
Rym: Next-gen console is but is big but the future isn't too bright with the emergence of cheap PC multi-core Processors and the big change the PC industry will go through during the next five years to accommodate the new multi-core centric hardware designs.
Rym: My prediction is that the game console in the vein of the ps3 and the Xbox 360 is either going to undergo a massive Rethink or go away altogether.
Rym: The Wii has the perfect design for a console that doesn't pretend to be a PC and is geared toward the more casual gamers Than the hardcore gamers.
Rym: the hardcore gamers?
Rym: are they gonna be playing their new PCs or their new PC like platform that sits in their Living room but still serves the whole house over Wi-Fi and even video signal that man can talk in a run-on sentence.
Rym: I tell you what.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I think the thing he's not realizing is that the ps3 whatever but the Xbox 360 is the PC-like platform in the living room that he's talking about.
Scott: That's why it killed off PC gaming because it's basically a PC that you don't have to deal with all the PC bullshit to do.
Rym: He talks a lot more and I think part of it just comes down to The Xbox.
Rym: and what makes it popular now is it's doing a lot of things that PCs did a long time ago better.
Scott: Yeah, it's just more accessible.
Scott: It's easier to play online.
Scott: you don't have to do a bunch of bullshit to set up a voice chat or a video chat or Download extra content or patch your games.
Scott: It's like PC gaming that just works.
Scott: but at the same time 360 is kind of cool.
Rym: It's PC gaming that's really limited because once the hardware is out the hardware is not going to advance for a while.
Rym: You've got to develop for the hardware.
Rym: luckily, there's Xbox Live and all that and Theoretically something for the ps3.
Rym: but it's a lot harder to just make a game and get it on a console than it is To make a game for the PC.
Scott: Well, that's the thing.
Scott: is the Xbox 360 from a developer game developers standpoint is a PC.
Scott: It's no different than making a game for Windows Like literally you can.
Scott: they have a dev kit the Microsoft XNA dev kit.
Scott: you make a game and then it builds the game for Windows and Xbox in one go.
Scott: It's not the same thing.
Rym: his main argument seems to be that PCs currently partly with this whole.
Rym: Intel is kind of busting out with new technology left and right lately and IBM has been busting out and AMD has been slashing their prices.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I'm keeping an eye on that situation for everyone because I'm pretty much gonna buy a PC.
Rym: the day.
Rym: The value is like perfect like the perfect equilibrium of chip prices and motherboard prices and RAM prices.
Scott: All the stars will just line up and then the moon will make a little eclipse and then up the chips will come out of The fab and we'll buy them.
Rym: Yep, and then holy shit rims gonna have his first new PC and going on seven seven or eight Years, I really want a new PC because there's a lot of games I want to play that I wasn't able to play.
Rym: but this argument is that PCs are getting stupidly fast stupidly quickly and They're.
Rym: it's getting to the point where PCs are ever upgradable and infinitely fast while consoles can't be can't keep up the same thing if They're still trying to do the same thing that PC does.
Rym: and I think he thinks that the games that are popular on the Xbox And the ps3 will eventually just by sheer economics Migrate to PCs and a console like that a console that is just a specialized computer Will not be a viable market in the future.
Scott: well I think the only thing I disagree with him on is the fact that he seems to think that Computing power is the limitation in game design now.
Rym: Sometimes it is.
Scott: sometimes it is.
Scott: that is correct.
Rym: I mean I don't for thanks.
Scott: in flight simulators Computing power is the limitation and how good our flight simulators can be.
Rym: or doom - did you ever see the original?
Rym: Concept demos of doom and all those game pretty sad.
Rym: No No no actually doom was going to be a lot more than what doom actually was and a lot of things had to be dropped because Computers just weren't fast enough and there was no way to do it back then.
Scott: but nowadays Unless all you care about is graphics.
Scott: if you're going for a game that is fun and entertaining and will occupy you for a long Amount of time, you know graphics are the only real thing that pushes the CPU.
Rym: Well, well it did not necessarily because supreme commander while it does push the graphics quite a bit a lot of the benchmarks and things I see point out that the graphics are a very minor part of its performance and It pushes the processor just for the shared data manipulation of all the entities that you're interacting with.
Scott: that is possible But that's one case one specific genre.
Scott: what you know?
Scott: What's really holding games back is that we only have a few Genres and we just keep churning out more and more things in those genres without coming up with new stuff.
Rym: Well, not even new stuff.
Rym: All they'd have to do is there are genres of gaming that have effectively disappeared and if someone made a game in these genres and that game was at At least in terms of gameplay as good as the old games just with updated sound and graphics and plot and things We've learned about gaming in the last decade It could re revolutionize the gaming industry in my opinion.
Scott: Well see what I've noticed.
Scott: actually in examining like the history of a lot of you know I've lived through this.
Scott: so I guess I know you look at any game genre, right?
Scott: Let's look at the FPS.
Scott: right you come out with the brand new genre.
Scott: The first game in the genre is always amazing.
Scott: It's like oh my god a whole new type of game insane.
Scott: Yeah, I mean everyone look Wolfenstein 3d.
Rym: people said what first-person shooter?
Scott: Hot shit, right, but then you have this new idea and it's hot shit.
Scott: people improve upon the idea.
Scott: You know, you get your doom 1 you're doomed to etc, etc, etc.
Scott: And eventually you reach the game the game that sets the standard your half-life 1 BAM.
Scott: There's the FPS half-life 1. some other people make some great FPS But pretty much everything after the hot shit game is finally out is just and whatever.
Scott: So I counter-strike is still number one.
Scott: I mean FPS is to that are out today are so much better than counter-strike.
Scott: I mean you cannot deny.
Scott: However, there's nothing wrong with counter-strike.
Scott: It was the first game in the FPS genre.
Scott: So they all right.
Scott: There's nothing wrong with it anymore.
Rym: so if I've got a game that satisfies my desire to play in a genre that's that 90% satisfies my desire and It 90% satisfies everyone else's desire.
Rym: So everyone's playing it.
Rym: if a new game comes out that satisfies it.
Rym: 92% mm-hmm.
Rym: How many people are going to abandon all they've been doing to try something new and stick with something new?
Scott: yeah, the same thing happened with like.
Rym: There was one MMO and then there were two and I played it.
Scott: all crappy and ever quest is crap.
Scott: Well, they were all fun.
Rym: Yeah, they just they.
Rym: they were good but they weren't good enough to get a Complete market share a complete mind share.
Rym: and they kept coming and there were more and more and ever quest got really popular.
Rym: But then another game and every time a new game came people would migrate bit by bit and the old ones would just slowly die.
Rym: And then World of Warcraft came and while it's definitely not the perfect MMO It passed the threshold.
Rym: the threshold of the majority of people who want to play an MMO are gonna play this one game.
Scott: Yep, RTS is you had Warcraft one, but Starcraft after Starcraft.
Scott: Oh, that's that's it.
Scott: That's the game.
Rym: Well, I don't know supreme commander.
Rym: I'm really excited about I really want to play it.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not saying that you can't make a better game.
Scott: But generally in any one genre I mean, I'm sort of reach a game and that's that's.
Scott: that's as far as that's gonna go.
Scott: You know everyone who comes after you might improve you might improve a lot, but it's mostly just knockoffs here and there Trying to rehash with slight improve
Rym: like look xcom mission UFO Which is lauded by a lot of people including experts as one of the greatest PC games ever made.
Rym: Look at all the sequels.
Rym: They were all basically the same.
Rym: terror from the deep xcom 2 was the exact same.
Rym: game reskins slightly So it's worse graphics.
Scott: What's the limitation in games?
Scott: I think is not that you don't have enough power to make the game you want, you know.
Scott: Yeah, that's completely different thing.
Scott: but the idea that you have to meet.
Scott: you can either come up with a new genre of gaming and then bring it up to.
Scott: You know, it's maximum game or you can find a genre that was never fully developed.
Scott: like star control.
Scott: You start control - you might say that was the one but I don't think that genre was taken all the way.
Rym: Well, there's also the that you could have a confluence of ideas where you take two things That could be integrated to make something that is more than the two things by themselves.
Scott: Yes, and I do agree that the PC has the potential to be the system where it's at mostly because unlike Consoles anyone and their mother can make a PC game.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Furthermore.
Rym: No one has to no one can tell you You can't make a PC game while the ps3 and the Xbox and even though we have where you can get stuff online To play on your machine.
Rym: It's not really like the PC where there's no limit at all to what you can get online and PCs are infinitely extensible.
Rym: I mean if you make a PC game that needs a peripheral like a Joystick people are gonna buy the joystick and they did back in the day and if games that needed joysticks came back There'd be joysticks again.
Rym: But if you make a game for a console and it needs some special thing and that thing didn't come with the console No one's gonna play your game.
Rym: Your games just gonna be this niche game forever and never expand.
Scott: Well, I don't know.
Scott: That's a lot of guitar heroes are being sold.
Scott: I wouldn't say that too quickly.
Rym: Well guitar heroes and DDR and all those games I think are an exception because it's not like.
Rym: it's not like that.
Scott: A lot of people bought that mech game scarily enough, but not as seller Yeah But not as many P.
Rym: It didn't become this huge game and then it slowly petered out fairly quickly and I played the game and in my opinion It was rubbish.
Scott: But yeah, I don't think it was a very good game overall, but it did sell a hell of a lot.
Rym: I mean it didn't sell as much as guitar here But think about it when it came out right and then the months afterward at RIT Which is like a center of gaming and all these geeks there were like five people who had that.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty good.
Scott: Most games sell almost nothing.
Scott: So that's it's a pretty good selling game.
Scott: Anyway, my point is is that because the PC you anyone can make a game for it.
Scott: The future and hope of PC gaming is if people go out and make games in Brand new genres that are like no other games we've ever seen, you know Katamari was and like what other games recently like all the games that Introversion software is making the Darwinia uplink guys.
Scott: Um, that's that's the hope of PC gaming right there and not more chips.
Rym: Effectively the hope of PC gaming is steam right now.
Scott: Well steam is just a distribution platform.
Rym: Yes, but the whole idea I think that now on PCs you can have a distribution model that entirely eliminates Anything physical on the Xbox.
Rym: no matter how much you download from Xbox Live.
Rym: Xbox games are still gonna be a disc that you go to the store and you buy You go to Amazon you buy and it comes and you keep it around on a PC.
Rym: I mean look most of the gaming stores around here in downstate, New York.
Rym: They don't have PC gaming sections.
Rym: They don't even bother.
Rym: yet PC games still sell.
Rym: people still buy steam games.
Rym: Just they just do it online.
Rym: Why go to a store?
Rym: Why even have the store?
Rym: There's no reason to sell a box for a PC game anymore.
Scott: It just goes hand in hand with the people can.
Scott: anyone can make a PC game but that won't help you if it's not easy to sell a PC game.
Scott: and Breaking the barrier to entry.
Scott: where anyone can sell a PC game and distribute it by steam or equivalent is What is necessary.
Scott: if PC games were still mostly sold in stores?
Scott: Then it wouldn't matter if someone out there made an awesome brand new PC game a new exciting genre Because they wouldn't be able to get it out there.
Rym: But yeah, this interview is pretty short and it's kind of interesting.
Rym: So check it out All right.
Scott: So yesterday in the virtual console, you know a game came out.
Rym: what game came?
Scott: one of my favorite games ever Custer's revenge.
Scott: No, it was Galaga the sequel to Galaxian and one of the best space shooting games ever.
Scott: I've gotten to like level 60 something in Galaga one time.
Rym: God I was never good at galley, but any kind of space shooter.
Rym: I'm just a sad.
Scott: I'll have to do a little how-to on Galaga.
Scott: It'll take like five minutes.
Rym: Not a very complex game, you know a Galaga how-to and I'll do I don't know by on a commando or Commandos a little more complex than Galaga zookeeper.
Rym: I set the high score at Katsucon on zookeeper Yeah, or Bart at root beer tapper.
Scott: Yeah, so Galaga it came out on the Wii yesterday But I didn't get a chance to play Wii yesterday.
Scott: I was busy and I was.
Scott: I said to myself.
Scott: All right for five bucks I'll buy it tomorrow cuz I really like Galaga.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: In fact, he said while I was editing the show We just finished up and he's like, hey, I'm gonna go buy this right now.
Rym: then he didn't.
Scott: well I didn't buy Galaga and I was planning to buy it today when I got home, but I haven't bought it.
Rym: Why is that?
Scott: Why didn't I buy the Galaga that I said I was gonna buy?
Scott: am I just a shit talker?
Rym: I think you are and you're dumb.
Scott: No, I'm actually very very smart.
Scott: You see because today a news came out.
Rym: Oh, I see you ready for this news.
Rym: I'm ready.
Scott: Namco museum confirmed for DS DS.
Scott: Yes, yeah is going.
Scott: this summer Namco is going to release a DS game one DS cartridge that will contain all of the Following.
Scott: are you ready?
Rym: Galaga, tada.
Rym: All right, so Galaxian.
Rym: All right bonus Xevious.
Rym: No, I actually really like Xevious.
Scott: This is kind of bad.
Scott: I don't really want it.
Rym: I'm bad at these games.
Rym: So I like the bad ones.
Rym: What do you want from me?
Scott: Mappy?
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: Mappy land?
Scott: I think so it's a little mouse I think so.
Scott: Okay was bad as Mappy ma PPY.
Scott: All right, if that's actually Mappy land Tower of Druaga, I've heard of that but I don't really know about it.
Scott: Uh dig dug to.
Scott: Well, I have to dig that to any s cartridge downstairs But I haven't played that game in a long time and that is sort of this long lost game.
Scott: dig dug to Because you didn't really dig down.
Scott: you dug sideways and you broke up this island into pieces.
Rym: It's almost as good as the original dig dug.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Scott: it's actually really similar, but it's kind of weird and it's a game not many people know about pac-man 1. alright and pac-man verse See pac-man verse is a game for the the Gamecube.
Rym: basically you can buy this game for the Gamecube and it came with some other Bullshit pac-man game.
Scott: Well, no you there was.
Scott: basically it was weird How they originally released this game because you couldn't buy it on its own.
Scott: It would always come with another game.
Scott: So if you wanted it you had to like buy our racing revolution for Gamecube and it would come with pac-man verse or you would Buy.
Rym: the game shall not be man.
Scott: the game that shall not be mentioned perhaps the worst game ever made.
Scott: Yeah, it came with pac-man verse.
Scott: so but pac-man versus really the game you wanted see.
Rym: now pac-man verse to me Was this revolutionary thing because it's this little game.
Rym: It's a game that you couldn't sell as a full-price game.
Scott: You could sell for five bucks, man.
Rym: It's basically just a small minigame on a little Gamecube disc.
Rym: The thing is what it was is a perfectly wonderfully executed multiplayer pac-man that used that so rarely used connected GBA to the Gamecube Functionality where one guy displays pac-man, but the other three people they're the ghosts But they can only see a little area around.
Scott: one guy's playing pac-man on his GBA.
Scott: That's connected to the Gamecube and the other three people are looking at the TV trying to catch the pac-man who's playing on the SP.
Rym: Yep Now if you catch pac-man you become pac-man and get a bunch of points and you trade controllers.
Scott: You give him your Gamecube controller and he gives you the SP or the GBA.
Rym: This starts to break down after about an hour unless you have wave birds.
Scott: Yeah, if you don't have wave birds the cables get all jumbled up and you have to untwist them after a while.
Scott: But it's really awesome.
Scott: And if it's on the DS, oh Shit.
Rym: because I got to say when we got this game We played this pac-man game for hours and hours and hours at almost every opportunity for quite some time.
Scott: I think it's actually gonna be better on the DS because you eliminate the problem of ghosts looking at each other's area.
Scott: Ah, but that's a creak a key key part of the strategy Haha, and you also eliminate the swapping of controllers and things.
Scott: now think about this pac-man verse on the game on the DS Right.
Scott: Imagine if there was a game a DS cartridge that was just pac-man.
Rym: first I'd pay 30 bucks for it.
Scott: Guess how much this Namco museum is gonna cost.
Rym: how much Scott?
Rym: $20, wait a minute.
Rym: I would have paid 20 bucks for all those other games except this pac-man.
Rym: I would have paid 30 bucks just for the pac-man.
Scott: hot shit.
Scott: Wait a minute, but think about this right 20 bucks for eight games.
Scott: The Galaga on the virtual console was $5.
Scott: Basically it cost twice as much if you buy it on the virtual console.
Scott: Then if you buy it on the DS well and the DS one is better because first of all You're getting a physical thing.
Scott: Whereas on the virtual console, you're not getting it.
Rym: But didn't we just say that that's bad?
Scott: Well, yeah Anyway, at the same time it's a portable one.
Scott: a portable one is better than it's not like.
Scott: well I got the one to be any worse on the DS than it is on the way.
Rym: the one argument I could make Would be that well the one on the DS you can't play it on your big screen.
Rym: It's Here's the thing.
Rym: So we can talk about the Wii and the GameCube and the PlayStation 3 and the Xbox 360.
Rym: But the fact remains that far and away by an order of magnitude Forever the most the best most awesome most popular most selling most perfect console in the world is the Nintendo DS.
Scott: DS is kicking all sorts of what like 25 million.
Rym: No, and the Nintendo DS?
Scott: all I know is that I look at the Amazon order I just put in.
Scott: I ordered Pokemon red and green.
Scott: that way we can get the old Pokemon and our new Pokemon diamond and pearl Played Pokemon.
Scott: No, I that's GBA and DS which are all being played on the DS and I ordered Super Paper Mario.
Scott: So so far that's two to one or four to one.
Scott: However, you want to measure it see the DS.
Rym: when it came out Nintendo was really worried about it not succeeding.
Rym: I mean it was even.
Rym: they kept making up this line of yeah, it's the third pillar.
Rym: We're not getting rid of the Gameboy And that way if it failed they could just kind of.
Rym: you know, it didn't fail.
Rym: it's serving its purpose.
Scott: Well, that's what they did with the the Virtual Boy because the Game Boy was out and the SNES was out and the Virtual Boy Came and then it fails.
Scott: They just put it away.
Rym: It didn't just fail.
Scott: I don't know if it catastrophically failed.
Rym: Actually the funny thing is despite how poorly it did I know like seven people who had one.
Scott: I only played one at Toys R Us.
Rym: I never knew I played one at Myers.
Scott: Well, I know people now who owned them, but I never knew anyone who owned one back in the day.
Rym: Oh, no, but all the people I know now who owned one owned one back in the day They bought it like when it came out.
Scott: Yeah, Katsu says he has one or had one.
Rym: My friend Adam in high school had one that he really liked except he hurt his neck trying to play it.
Scott: Yeah, the only good games for it were like Wario something tennis and Mario tennis.
Scott: all Mario tennis a shooting game.
Scott: It was red.
Scott: It basically had three games.
Rym: Wasn't that the first Mario tennis?
Scott: I think it was the first Mario tennis.
Rym: Anyway, the DS is the best console and to the I mean it's.
Rym: I use it as a primary console.
Rym: I was the first handheld where I would sit in my own house.
Rym: It wasn't just.
Rym: oh, it's a portable system.
Rym: It's.
Rym: I'm gonna sit in my house in my living room in my video rocker in front of my TV Playing a DS.
Rym: Yep So I don't really worry about Nintendo because they're laughing all the way to the bank things of the day.
Rym: So I normally lately been trying to avoid just doing something that was on or near the top of dig recently And I saw this link.
Rym: I kept seeing it - oh my god this really hard hack of the Mario 1 ROM.
Rym: Oh my god It's impossible.
Rym: Hello.
Scott: I know this happens a lot lately like hey, did you see this?
Scott: and it's like I would see the link but I didn't care to click on it and then you'll actually click on it and Then I'll see it or vice-versa.
Rym: cuz half the time you do that to me You're like rims.
Rym: You see the crazy guy going nuts.
Rym: I'm like what crazy guy.
Rym: I saw the link to that.
Scott: Yeah, I keep seeing the link to the head.
Scott: I keep reading the headline.
Scott: I didn't read the story.
Rym: Well, I decided to watch this one because I was in my room uploading to flicker and that took a while Even though I found I searched for flicker on the repository in Ubuntu and I found exactly one program.
Scott: You can use f-spot.
Rym: Oh cuz I just used a K flicker.
Scott: I use f-spot.
Rym: a flicker is actually really nice.
Scott: f-spot is really nice.
Rym: now I'll try it but K flicker was really nice.
Scott: is what f-spot does forget it.
Rym: It's Monday.
Rym: All right, so I click on this thing and It starts and Mario just falls to his death immediately.
Rym: He starts in the air and basically This is a 22 minute video of a human being who is a very good Mario one player probably I'd say a top hundred in the world.
Scott: He's better than me That's for sure.
Rym: This guy is one of those people who could like do a speedrun of Mario 1 and 99% of the time win with a decent time like remember they are the first well the first Speedrun that was all over the internet.
Scott: that Mario 3 1 where he kept bouncing on the Bob-ombs.
Rym: Oh, it was tight.
Scott: Yeah, this guy is as good as that guy.
Rym: Well that guy did it with a tool I know but that this is yeah, but this isn't a tool.
Rym: This is a human.
Rym: Yes, it's obvious.
Rym: Now the thing is this is the hardest Mario ever made.
Rym: it is specifically designed to be as Absolutely impossible as possible while still being possible to be one.
Scott: Well, I don't think that there's any mathematical proof that this is definitely the hardest that Mario can possibly be.
Rym: Oh sure, there might be one slightly hard.
Scott: However, however, this is fucking hard now.
Scott: You can't really.
Rym: The guy was doesn't matter.
Rym: I was given infinite lives and You got don't?
Rym: you have to watch the whole thing.
Rym: watch like the first five or ten minutes because it's basically he dies.
Rym: Alright start over he dies.
Rym: Alright start over.
Rym: He gets to like the first little bit and he jumps to the second bit and you see this fucking blooper there you're like, oh no, and then he dies and It is going.
Rym: it's going fine.
Rym: And then eventually there's one point where he gets past something and you're like hot shit He's gonna make it.
Rym: and then he runs and there's this gap and there's a pipe on the other end.
Rym: He runs he jumps to get to the pipe before the flame hits him.
Rym: There's an invisible fucking block at the exact perfect fucking spot and he hits it and goes right into the pit and dies.
Scott: I'll spoil one more thing from the video all the pipe.
Scott: Yes So, you know you're playing a Mario game.
Scott: Your first instinct is hey a pipe.
Scott: I've never seen before.
Rym: Let me try to go down it especially in a game like this where yes You're getting fucked at every turn if you can skip even two panels of this.
Rym: It's great.
Scott: Yep I had seen this video enough because there's like a minute in maybe I don't know.
Scott: and I had seen enough of this video to know this game was gonna pull every trick in the book to just kill you if you Fucked up at all.
Scott: and he as soon as he started ducking on that pipe I'm like that pipes just gonna drop him into a hole and sure enough The best part is the pipe drops him into a hole, right?
Rym: But there's still coins in there and there's still an exit.
Rym: he even got some of the coins.
Rym: I think No, I wish I would pay a lot of money to have a dual video where one side of the screen is the Mario and The other side of the screen is the dude playing this.
Scott: they must have had like a giant bucket of NES controllers cuz he uses to smash them on every single play.
Rym: this video is Fascinating and yet it feels just as bad as watching that video.
Rym: the guy who goes nuts in the elevator Where every time he dies, I'm just like ah, oh, I felt just like I had done it and I had died.
Rym: You can see.
Rym: he starts getting pissed off cuz toward the end he starts dying on the same trick like over and over again.
Rym: Now I'm gonna.
Rym: I'm gonna spoil one thing at the end so you won't hate me You don't have to watch to the end because he doesn't fucking make it.
Rym: He gets like a quarter of the way through the second part.
Scott: Yeah, he beats.
Scott: he eventually does beat 1-1, but he doesn't beat 1-2.
Scott: He just keeps dying and then gives up and that the video's over.
Rym: Yeah, so pretty much every beats 1-1. just look at 1-2 for like a second.
Scott: Yeah, don't bother actually sitting there watching this video because there's no climax or ending.
Scott: It doesn't go anywhere.
Rym: He if anything if you're a gamer this video is going to be wonderful and hilarious and yet it's going to piss you off All right.
Scott: So while we're talking about different genres of games there There's a genre of game that not many people know about other than super nerds and that genre is roguelikes.
Scott: No, it's kind of funny because you know, what do you call doom?
Scott: What genre is doom in?
Scott: It's it's an FPS.
Scott: It's a first-person shooter.
Scott: You know what genre is half-life.
Scott: It's also a first-person shooter.
Scott: Imagine if you called quake a doom like or a wolfenstein like.
Rym: granted there were doom likes.
Rym: There were a lot of games that ripped off - but no one called them doom likes.
Scott: not all them.
Scott: FPS is plus.
Rym: this isn't like.
Rym: you don't call Sonic the Hedgehog a Mario like and this isn't like someone just like it's the great Gianna sisters is a Mario like.
Scott: it definitely is a Mario like but you don't call it that.
Scott: you call it a platform.
Rym: now Imagine if this was a semi legitimate genre where pretty much everyone who knew about it called it that.
Scott: yes There's a game called rogue a long time ago, and it was basically an ASCII game.
Rym: Don't play it.
Rym: It's done played.
Rym: I like it only because it's cool to like it and I tried to play it and I got really into it for like an hour and in that hour I learned that I can't get very far without dying.
Scott: Basically, you're a little at symbol and you use the arrows on your keyboard to move around a map Which is made of dots and lines and slashes and all the different characters that you can possibly type in ASCII.
Rym: Don't be fooled.
Rym: This is one of the most complex fucking games ever.
Scott: Oh, it's stupidly complex.
Scott: There's like.
Scott: every button on the keyboard is a different command like dig or jump or search or pick up.
Scott: You have an inventory you have levels you have stats.
Scott: It's a Ludicrously complex game credit.
Scott: It's not as with the most primitive interface possible.
Rym: It's not as bad as that stupid dwarf.
Rym: Whatever game.
Rym: remember that Oh God that thing Oh God.
Scott: No, don't talk about that.
Scott: So yeah, that's a game called rogue and If you want to play a game like rogue nowadays net hack is pretty much the standard.
Scott: That's that's the game people play.
Scott: It's open source.
Scott: It's free.
Scott: You can just get a copy of net hack and play it and Then you'll know what rogue games are like.
Scott: roguelikes are like.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: They're like like also like net hack.
Scott: Cuz net hack is a roguelike.
Scott: anyway What if somebody made a roguelike game that was also like another kind of game?
Rym: What kind of game?
Rym: because Scott didn't really tell me what he was looking at here for this thing of the day.
Rym: And then he said come here and I come over and he showed me something that Surprised me and filled me with a small amount of awe and respect.
Rym: What if you took say I don't know Zelda and made it roguelike but still Zelda and The end result is something that you probably not can actually want to play more than a few seconds.
Rym: But the fact that the game works and is a real game is amazing And it's surprising that this game is like in every way.
Scott: This is a roguelike game except it has music a pretty good music actually well And it's completely skinned and themed.
Scott: yeah as far as ASCII can be skinned as far as asking me But you turn it on and you know it's a Zelda game.
Scott: It is it is.
Scott: they've taken the ASCII character set and they've completely It's Zelda through and through a hundred percent.
Rym: This is definitely proof that Minimalist ideas in gaming that if you're made designing a game Yeah, I mean, I'm not saying that games have to be minimalist in fact far from it.
Rym: But at its core at the very core of any game is a very simple concept and that Concept can be readily identified by gamers.
Scott: yes, and Well, it's not just Zelda roguelike.
Scott: They got a Metroid roguelike and a Castlevania roguelike Bad asses.
Scott: so
Rym: if you
Scott: know Zelda Metroid in Castlevania I suggest you go and like for just a couple of minutes Learn like the basics of playing a game like net hacker rogue And then play these things so that you can get the joke and be like oh Cuz if you just go straight to these without playing a roguelike game.
Scott: That's not one of these three You're not really gonna get.
Scott: why it's awesome.
Rym: now I'm gonna warn you because there is a it's most like much like ghost in the shell where there was that Brain virus that affects like 1% of the population And then some small percentage of those people if they see the certain thing gets triggered by it.
Rym: Rogue like games are like that you might be one of those people who back in the day Would have spent all of college playing rogue and net hack and then eventually starve to death.
Scott: Yes, roguelike games are sort of weird in that you eat.
Scott: those people don't like them But a small subset of people love them to death.
Rym: Like.
Rym: we knew a couple people at RIT who played these games a lot and they were addicted to net hack.
Scott: They played net hack all the goddamn time Just constantly.
Rym: so if you play net hack or any of these games for more than about an hour Turn it off and post in our forums And we'll get you some help.
Scott: or admit that you're one of those people and just start playing every roguelike game You can find cuz.
Scott: yeah, there are a lot of them out there And if you like them you will not be an unhappy person.
Rym: also I know that because it's basically free to play these games and you can run them on a Fucking 386.
Scott: you could run them on like a 286 if you can install like an old like Linux kernel on there, so Theoretically you could work date like one-off jobs You know just enough to buy food.
Scott: people have Linux running on just about fucking everything these days, right?
Scott: Why don't they compile net hack for like the DS which runs Linux or the iPod or trans Linux or well?
Scott: I guess you need more buttons, but that's not the point.
Scott: it could be done.
Rym: I don't think that's a good idea.
Rym: I don't think there's a great overlap between DS players and roguelike players.
Rym: Yeah, so anyway speaking of minimalist games Tonight we're gonna talk about something that may shock you.
Rym: we're going to talk about solitaire.
Scott: Well, not just solitaire, but all the sorts of simple casual video games that Everyone and their mother plays.
Rym: really my mother plays these is about all she plays games like diner - and bookworm and freestyle and solitaire and Jezzball Random flash games like my mom.
Scott: you know gotten game my mom plays more than anything.
Scott: It's the weirdest thing.
Scott: It's a flash game on some website and all it does is it shows you a bunch of letters, right?
Scott: It'll give you like seven letters, and then it says okay Spell every word that can be spelled using these letters.
Scott: So you have to spell every one letter word every two letter word every three letter word that can be spelled using that set Letters and once you get them all you're done and my mom plays that game a lot like she'll play it every day.
Rym: Well the thing is a lot of gamers well a lot of I guess hardcore or too cool for school gamers Really dismiss these games despite the fact that a lot of people play them.
Scott: for one I don't think is that people they dismiss them well.
Scott: They just they just don't even really recognize or pay attention to them.
Scott: It's like you think okay You know what percentage of the population is our gamers, and you think okay?
Scott: Well, let's see there's this many teenage boys out there And I know a lot of 20 and 30 year olds are still playing games.
Scott: And there's this percentage of old men.
Scott: and you know there's these many girls out there with DS's and you come up with like the Stereotypical answer, but really a shit ton of people play video games.
Scott: the most popular video games are like Tetris on the cell phone.
Scott: You know Boggle on the internet boggle on you know backgammon on yahoo games Hearts on yahoo hearts yuker Cribbage bridge.
Rym: those things are stupidly popular.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, they're not actually Video games originally, but they're in video game form now And you know what those freaking count.
Rym: and a lot of them are straight up like diner - which was stupidly popular Was I'll just off flash game.
Scott: I mean if your grandpa doesn't has never played a video game in his life But he plays party poker.
Scott: guess what that's a video game.
Scott: He's now granted gamer.
Scott: your grandpa's a gamer if he plays party poker.
Rym: Granted you can still make the distinction because there is a difference between someone who plays games and someone who?
Rym: Self-identifies as a game.
Scott: there is of course yes, however people just don't seem to count.
Scott: Gamers at least don't seem to count people playing normal casual games that everyone plays as being a video game player.
Rym: now Why is this interesting?
Rym: well one?
Rym: Here's another little-known fact these games is where all the money is.
Rym: yeah Did you can make so much more money making some?
Rym: Stupid little flash game putting it on the internet with a little ad or maybe a link to pay five bucks to download the full Version.
Rym: then you ever will making the next Morrowind or oblivion or whatever.
Scott: yeah think about this.
Scott: Let's say you're I don't know you're a PC game company, and you make the new hot FPS.
Scott: It's the hottest FPS.
Scott: It's it's smashing right.
Scott: you sell millions of copies for 40 bucks each right and then you split that money up among your Developers and it cost you millions of dollars to make the game in the first place And you'd the publisher takes a cut and all these people take a cut.
Scott: you still make a hardware in the servers.
Scott: You still make a smashing profit however.
Scott: You know I really gonna be rolling in it.
Rym: Yeah, I'm getting by well.
Rym: mostly the issue is you had a really high initial investment.
Rym: I'm a really high one and a chance of failure and a chance of very high Losses if the game fails.
Rym: and while you make a lot of money the margins are a lot narrower than you might think.
Scott: Meanwhile you can get one guy like me to sit down for a week Crank out a Tetris ish puzzly game for a cell phone once.
Scott: It's on that cell phone network say.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: See how many people have cell phones just everyone and they you know they charge like a dollar or whatever.
Scott: today It's like 250 so 250 times.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: 2 million people and it cost you a hundred bucks to make the game Ching.
Rym: and there's a lot of these games, and you might not realize it especially if you're a cool leak hip too cool for school.
Rym: I said that twice gamer.
Rym: I don't know why.
Rym: I don't know why this in my head lately But those games are out there and a lot of people are playing them.
Rym: more people are playing those games That are playing your halo.
Scott: Yeah, it's kind of scary.
Rym: I got a war.
Rym: any
Scott: any game self-respecting gamer doesn't really care about cell phone games You know and any any smart person as far as I would say Wouldn't buy a cell phone game because they're horrendously overpriced And they're also usually my game virtual consoles almost a better deal than cell phone games.
Scott: The way they price those things some of them.
Scott: you even have to pay monthly for the cell phone games.
Scott: like you want to keep Tetris on your phone pay three dollars a month, and I'm like fuck no Paying three dollars a month for a crappy Tetris.
Rym: I got Tetris DS bitches my cell phone because I got this a long time ago And I'm loads to upgrade because it works pretty well and the battery lasts forever.
Rym: But it came with the probably the second worst pac-man port the world has ever seen.
Scott: So it's worse than the Atari one.
Scott: well second worst because it's are you all.
Scott: I guess Atari 7800 pac-man is good.
Rym: Well, I'm sorry 7800 miss pac-man is straight up miss pac-man.
Rym: however Atari 2600 pac-man notoriously bad was an abortion.
Rym: Now alright so one day I ended up stuck somewhere without my DS and without any form of entertainment whatsoever And I was so bored that I turned on my cell phone.
Rym: I started playing this horrible ass pac-man that barely worked.
Rym: I beat the first level then it said 250 to buy the next few levels and I said And I deleted it.
Scott: And then I said there imagine how many stupid people pay that and imagine how much money you could make if you made that Game, and it was pre-installed on all those phones.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, now another interesting thing is that?
Rym: Solitaire is probably the most well-known of these games because it was really from I'd say a lot of people in fact I might even posit the majority of human beings the first PC game.
Rym: They ever played.
Scott: Yeah, I'd say.
Scott: for most human beings out there solitaire might be the first.
Rym: if not solitaire then that whole genre of solitaire and/or Freestyle freestyle, what's the other one spider?
Scott: some people were freaking badass at spider?
Scott: I can't play that game.
Scott: Yeah We were.
Rym: when I was a little kid I played the solitaire on the computer Because I was always.
Rym: yeah, it might be mine sweeper - it's hard to say but then again I think most people who aren't gamers went for the solitaire first because they knew what that was.
Rym: They didn't know what that mines me took me.
Scott: You know it took me like a couple days to learn how to play mine sweeper.
Rym: I figured it out Okay, kind of right away, and then one day like the third I was not.
Scott: if I read the help I would have learned sooner, but I refused to read the help the third time I played it.
Rym: I was like I like I was looking at those numbers.
Rym: I'm like what the hell are those numbers again, and then I'm like wait a minute wait a minute.
Rym: oh This game's stupid.
Scott: No mine sweepers awesome.
Scott: I love mine sweeper.
Scott: I'm basic.
Scott: the only problem I have with mine sweeper is that you know occasionally it comes down to you have to take a risk And it's just random whether you're gonna win or lose.
Rym: And if it doesn't come down to that then all you are doing is as a human being executing an algorithm very slowly Or very quickly if you're very good at it.
Rym: I once beat a simple mine sweeper in seven seconds.
Scott: I've beaten a simple mine sweeper in five seconds because it was so easy.
Scott: that was just like three bombs And I yeah every night.
Rym: I get lucky like all the bombs are just one spot.
Scott: The worst is like there'll be a corner right and They'll just be three bombs surrounding the corner And you don't know if the corner has a bomb in it or not and you might or may not have to click it.
Rym: But here's what pissed me off to no end when I was a little kid.
Rym: I love card games, but I never ever played solitaire because I just I didn't like it.
Rym: I thought it was dumb.
Rym: so Finally I was bored and I had a computer and I was doing everything on the computer.
Rym: So I learned how to play solitaire, and I was playing it, and I'm good at normal card games.
Rym: But I'd lose it solitaire sometimes and it bothered me a lot.
Rym: sometimes You just can't win and then one day my dad walks by and he sees me sitting there And I'm like I. I don't think I can win.
Rym: I don't know what to do.
Rym: I feel stupid.
Rym: my dad Is just like oh that one's unwinnable, and I'm like Unwinnable.
Rym: you mean that is pot that this game is set up to where you might just be fucked from the start.
Rym: And he says yeah, that's why I don't play solitaire.
Scott: Yeah, it's solitaire is basically just Solitaire.
Rym: you realize the solitaire.
Rym: They're like a thousand different solid.
Scott: well I mean technically that game where you jump the pieces over each other and then you know in trying to remove them all except one From the the plus shaped board, that's the.
Scott: that's a game.
Scott: That's actually just called solid.
Rym: well See people call a lot of different things solitaire, but the one on Windows is I believe Klondike solitaire.
Rym: Yes, there are a lot better solitaires out there.
Scott: There are many.
Scott: I think free cell at least is definitely better than free cells.
Scott: Okay, yeah, but solitaire is basically just a game where if you have a deck of cards You can exercise your brain in a very slight way to pass the time.
Scott: now Here's all the solitaires for now.
Rym: interesting thing that a lot of the people I work on computers for I work with are not Technological like me their doctors or their lawyers or things like that And I usually show up to save the day or fix the problem or install the new switches in the closets.
Rym: They can get faster internet or whatever.
Rym: and the most common request I get after Can you uncensored the stupid internet for me god damn which?
Rym: the answer is always no?
Rym: I can't even uncensored for myself.
Rym: But right after that is can you put solitaire back?
Rym: cuz my company takes solitaire and minesweeper off of all the computers.
Rym: Everyone asks for it back.
Rym: people download spyware written solitaires on the internet because they just need their fix.
Rym: Wow, but to a lot of people don't realize the reason Solitaire was put in Windows originally.
Scott: well there were actually two reasons one of which is a much bigger reason than the other.
Scott: yes when Microsoft Windows 3.0 came out people have been using DOS.
Scott: people have been using God knows what until then you know people didn't know and there was Mac.
Scott: Oh Macintosh.
Scott: But really you know Macintosh was something else.
Rym: most people did not know how to use a mouse or they just were bad at It.
Rym: and I'd watch people young people not even like parents or grandparents who just couldn't understand the concept of click and drag or just Anything like.
Rym: what's that for?
Scott: there's a big deal.
Scott: I mean the first copy of Microsoft Word ever.
Scott: the first version came with a computer mouse Which is something that no one had.
Scott: everyone had a computer with a keyboard nothing else.
Scott: they might have heard old jokes about Joystick before they had a mouse.
Rym: you might have heard old jokes about people who thought the mouse was a foot pedal.
Rym: That wasn't a fucking joke there.
Rym: that really happened more than once.
Scott: yeah I mean nowadays the mouse is a standard peripheral to the computer.
Rym: Imagine if God to me my mouse is literally.
Rym: well I guess not literally But it is as far as I can tell an extension of my brain and body.
Rym: it is a force of will it is it?
Rym: Is an extension of all that I am?
Rym: it is part of me when I'm.
Scott: but imagine if new PCs started coming with a new Peripheral.
Scott: they came out with a I don't know a wiimote and you didn't let people.
Scott: you know people never seen this.
Scott: All the computers started coming with them.
Scott: people aren't gonna know what to do with them, and they're gonna be all weirded out.
Scott: so Microsoft made solitaire which funnily it's enough.
Scott: You can play it with the keyboard if you know what you're doing and my cousin would always play with the keyboard because it was Faster, but you could play solitaire with the mouse.
Scott: It was intuitive to play with the mouse and it taught people how to double-click how to click and drag how to click one time.
Scott: it taught you how to do all the basic mouse skills how to move the mouse with precision and You know it's something people wanted to do and you basically trick them into getting Comfortable and learning how to use a mouse on a computer without having to say you know here use the boring learn to use a Mouse program that no one cares about in
Rym: a were probably
Scott: solely responsible.
Scott: without solitaire Mount computer mice wouldn't be widespread today.
Scott: Computers who knows maybe I don't know it would be a scary world.
Rym: in a word It was brilliant.
Rym: now the other thing that my solitaire the purpose that is served that was also equally important And I'm sure it was on the minds of the people who decided to put it in was that compared to previous computers people had had Solitaire showed off what a Windows computer could do.
Rym: you're dragging stuff around the screen.
Rym: There's graphics that you're dragging around in your computer not in some program It's in Windows in a window.
Rym: and also when you beat solitaire there was this for the time Fancy graphical show where all the cards bounced off the screen one by one and people would sit there transfixed.
Scott: Yeah, it was pretty amazing when you actually saw I mean there were card games on computers before then But they were nothing like solitaire.
Scott: Actually looked like cards.
Rym: those people didn't know how to play them And this is right when PCs in the home started becoming actually prevalent and not just this weird Thing that like one or two some people had but not everyone.
Rym: yeah No, it was.
Rym: it was becoming to where almost everyone had a computer or was planning to get a computer.
Scott: It was really kind of the beginning of the computer Mid to late 90s when it started to be everyone has a computer and everyone has a similar computer as opposed to hey those people Have a Commodore and those people have a ps1 and most people have nothing.
Scott: you know This was everyone's got a computer with the windows 3.1.
Rym: Oh shit That might have been a little short even though the show went on a little long.
Rym: I know we ranted a lot about a lot of things But the fact remains don't discount or ignore the simple crap games because those are The bread and butter of the world gaming industry right now.
Scott: Yeah, your video game magazines your video game blogs pretty much don't pay attention to this stuff at all.
Scott: You know I mean if Yahoo Games suddenly upgrades their chess or their hearts or their spades No one's gonna really pay attention.
Rym: But well granted he's going live.
Rym: Xbox Live has Uno, and that's making all sorts of waves.
Scott: But if you log into Yahoo Games.
Scott: there are thousands of people playing hearts right now.
Scott: That's more than a lot of MMOs.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what I really like hearts.
Scott: I really like hearts, too.
Scott: I've played a lot of hearts on Yahoo Games.
Scott: I put a lot of backgammon on Yahoo Games.
Rym: actually Scott and I are both really fucking good at hearts.
Scott: I'm about as good as at hearts as I can be yeah.
Rym: Granted that as anyone could be but as I can be yeah, well, then there's people like my father who God Today, I can't beat him.
Rym: Yeah, and also this because I know a lot of you is you're young and Idealistic and you want to get into the video game industry.
Rym: pretty much the best way to get into the video game industry at least To start is to develop these crap little flash games and these crap little Java games and these crap little games For some little company trying to advertise something.
Scott: Yeah, if you really want to learn how to be you know there are a lot of ways into the game industry be it by art testing direction management Programming, but if you want to get into Programming video games start out by making yourself like a Tetris in Python.
Scott: It's actually really easy.
Scott: You can do it in very few lines.
Rym: Yeah and if you want to but if you want to make money while you're learning all this get a job for some little developer who's Making some little game to promote his little thing and he'll pay you some money.
Scott: Make flash games and make cell phone games and you can live a happy life.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.