Rym: It's Monday September 3rd.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: spam spam spam spam spam spam spam spam.
Rym: Wonderful Spam.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: For those of you who do not live in the United States or not familiar with the United States and the things that go on here today Monday September 3rd is a holiday known as Labor Day.
Scott: It's a holiday that exists pretty much just so that no one has to go to work.
Scott: It doesn't really.
Scott: there's nothing else to it.
Scott: It's Labor Day where you don't do any labor.
Rym: there were fireworks, and that was it.
Scott: Yeah, it's not really an exciting day except for the fact that you know this is long stretch in.
Scott: you know of time On the calendar after the summer where you know there haven't been any days off of work since July.
Scott: So they figure you know well We'll toss another day off work.
Scott: Just you know Labor Day
Rym: now traditionally what late the way Labor Day is celebrated is the majority of Americans will get into cars and Then get up early sometime in the beginning of the weekend Attempt to drive at least 400 miles and get stuck in traffic for pretty much an entire day.
Rym: Yeah, they'll then get to a tourist spot overpay for a hotel Not be able to sit on the beach because there's a billion other people on the beach have a miserable time.
Rym: as soon as they try to barbecue it'll rain and Then they get in their car only to find that everyone else is trying to go home at the same time And they spend the entire Monday in the car.
Scott: Yep, so we decided on Labor Day just to stay home, and we figured hey We'll do a GeekNights also.
Scott: You know I mean I was gonna do laundry But I forgot.
Scott: you know three days.
Scott: I could have done laundry.
Rym: I didn't man you didn't do laundry.
Rym: I did every piece of laundry.
Rym: I own.
Rym: there is nothing dirty except my dress pants.
Scott: I really need to do something - I don't know.
Scott: I'm gonna wear tomorrow, but So I'll do a GeekNights and stay.
Scott: I'll do laundry tomorrow though.
Rym: I gotta say we got a lot done.
Rym: I mean I know Scott's been posting about the new website design We're working on and we've been working on for like two years.
Rym: Yeah, but now it's coming along.
Rym: We're getting close Yeah, and we've actually got a lot of banners and flyers coming working on the t-shirts and all that and got all that stuff done.
Rym: Also, we did you know domestic stuff.
Rym: I cleaned the house, and we went shopping and I got to say I Was taken aback by a product that I saw in the store.
Scott: well We went to eat yesterday like the barbecue place because you know we didn't want to cook.
Scott: so and across the street was the grocery Store and we went in to get some meat that we could eat today.
Rym: granted We were dumb, and we didn't get buns.
Rym: well.
Scott: We got buns of the grass station.
Scott: It was all right, but in the grocery store.
Scott: We saw this package of What was it?
Rym: diced pork diced ham.
Rym: the thing is nice to walk in and it's not refrigerated or anything.
Rym: just in the middle of This aisle hanging like from a stick with a thing sticking through it like hooks.
Rym: are these packages of diced ham?
Scott: They're.
Scott: they're obviously vacuum sealed.
Scott: you know the plastic was right up against the ham and there was no air or liquid or anything.
Scott: It's just like little cubes of ham all bunched up Completely sealed tight with plastic.
Rym: now that in itself is no big deal.
Rym: I really like ham and I really like diced ham, but the way it was packaged It looked like one of those fake plastic vomits.
Rym: It was like a flat piece of plastic and in the middle of the plastic was this three-dimensional bulge of ham Pink chunks.
Scott: did it look like someone vomited up pink junk?
Rym: now I'm a man who really likes his ham, but I got a little nauseous looking at it.
Scott: It was not a pleasant thing to behold.
Scott: I don't know if anyone was gonna buy something like that at.
Rym: the girl must buy it because they were selling it.
Rym: there was A lot of it there.
Scott: the grocery store sells a lot of things that nobody buys you know.
Rym: so Yeah, yet.
Rym: They don't sell a lot of the things I want.
Scott: I know.
Rym: Remember when they had koalas marched that one time and we bought like all of them Yeah, and then that night we realized that there's more trans fat in those than anything else we eat.
Scott: Yeah, so whatever Grocery stores we need better ones.
Scott: It sucks.
Rym: Yeah, well.
Rym: That's the problem.
Rym: We live in a very a fast gentrifying area, but it hasn't all gentrified yet.
Rym: So the only grocery store, it's like.
Scott: it's funny that in like the town of fish kill there's like two or three grocery stores, and then like Wappingers Falls and Poughkeepsie like a bajillion grocery stores and Beacon the city of Beacon the city of Beacon there's one really shitty shitty grocery store.
Scott: That's not.
Scott: even you might as well not exist.
Scott: It's so shitty.
Rym: I can say that I have never in my life gone into that grocery store without incident.
Scott: bad incident.
Rym: Yes, that will never get.
Rym: very rarely will someone say without incident and be referring to good things I could be a good incident anyway.
Rym: Hi.
Rym: Let's like running a foul.
Scott: our food acquisition situation is not Ideal.
Rym: yeah, yeah our hunting and gathering not so optimal right now.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: We're mostly the Like this you know the the wise men and someone else hunts and gathers.
Rym: the worst thing is if we lived in the city Well one we wouldn't have to worry because there's a million places to get good food But - we could just have one.
Rym: don't someone deliver groceries to us every day.
Scott: Yeah, but they don't have the giant Supermarkets in the city like we had you know.
Rym: ah they're good enough.
Rym: I don't know what your problem is.
Scott: Yeah, because they're just normal sized supermarkets.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: you'll find like a little stop-and-shop.
Scott: You won't find like a super stop-and-shop or a Wegmans down there, right?
Rym: Anyway, yeah, you know the news cuz I don't really want to talk about food on a Monday.
Scott: No, I'm tired.
Scott: Why is every podcast?
Scott: people seem to just want to talk about food and the listeners want the podcasters talk about food?
Scott: Why don't you watch like the Food Network on TV or something?
Scott: well?
Rym: They seem to not want to actually hear about food.
Rym: They want to hear about funny stories relating to food.
Scott: I don't get it it.
Scott: Most requested podcast discussion topics are always food.
Rym: Well one of the most popular episodes was one where we had our friend Adam on and all I know let's talk about food Candy episode.
Scott: like Dave and Joel always get bothered about food, too.
Rym: Well because they live in Philly so uh they really.
Rym: I was about to make a joke.
Scott: stop asking us to talk about food or zombies.
Scott: Yeah, all right anyway.
Rym: So you all use Google I assume because Google is really the only search engine in the world well at least in the English-speaking world worth of shit.
Rym: In China Google's not number one now.
Rym: There's a lot of reasons for that, but the number one The Great Firewall of China the Great Wall of Fire.
Rym: Yeah, the Great Firewall the number one search engine in China is something called Baidu B-a-i-d-u and there's a lot of reasons for that.
Rym: probably number one is that?
Rym: I'm not sure but I I would wager That it just doesn't index things that the Chinese firewall is gonna block.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it doesn't.
Rym: Google often will just pop up and say sorry we can't actually link you to there But that rest assured if you weren't a Chinese citizen you could view a website on the other side.
Scott: I think that's what it does.
Scott: I'm not sure
Rym: Google's a lot better about it than all the other companies out there like yeah
Scott: Yeah, yeah No the thing is is like originally the old search engines like you know whatever they all lost out to Google in the first place because Google didn't have Google was able to clear its index of all the 404 pages
Rym: Back in the day.
Rym: if you went on Yahoo or even a Alta Vista digital or web crawler a lot of time Search and like five of the first ten search results were 404s and the other five were spam.
Scott: Yeah, so that's sort of the reason that Google took off is because of lack of 404s and actual good worthwhile results.
Rym: And now you know Google also took out off for the same reason.
Rym: originally Yahoo did in that.
Rym: originally the Yahoo front page like Google was just hey Here's the search bar, and it was very minimalist and very simple.
Rym: and Google is still that way.
Rym: But Yahoo and every other search engine just has all this garbage on the site that you'll net.
Rym: There's no reason you would ever need to click on those links.
Rym: They're not efficient.
Rym: They're not gonna take you anywhere useful.
Rym: Nope, but Baidu basically has the same business model as Google.
Rym: at least Google searches They just have text ads and other than that they have the entire Chinese market.
Scott: Yeah, so what's the news about Baidu?
Rym: the news is that Baidu is still beating Google?
Scott: That's it.
Rym: well, actually I brought this up partly because there's a kind of tangential discussion where I Realized as I was going on dig looking for an article like this and I saw this article.
Rym: I kind of sparked it.
Rym: There really aren't any Good web 2.0 Indexing nice sites in any language other than English.
Rym: Well, there are but not many And not of the scale or quality of things like dig and slash dot.
Scott: Yeah, well, I think part of that is because most of the internet is in English first of all and second of all, you know, they're just the.
Scott: While you know people in South Korea and Japan and in all these other countries are crazy internet users There aren't really, you know, and while a greater percentage of their country is wired and wired faster Just the quantity of people.
Rym: Yeah Article about how in a lot of northern Europe and the Scandinavian countries They have like the hundred megabit fiber just to their house yep,
Scott: and while a large percentage of their you know, relatively smaller nation is all wired and intelligent and using the web the number of people just flat number of people who are using the internet in Like the US and China are the big ones and everyone else not so much.
Rym: also just in terms of internet culture I mean, it seems like if you go to the majority of the Japanese web like Japanese websites and Japanese news sites and all that They look almost exactly like the US web looked in the like middling later 90s.
Scott: Yeah, I don't really has.
Scott: it must have just Japan.
Rym: That was just an example.
Scott: I know I definitely think there is something to be studied involving like, you know the the cross-section between the the culture of the the Meat world and the culture of the tech world in different countries.
Scott: because it seems like in the US While our tech is a lot lower than a lot of other places like South Korea It seems like I don't know There's a bunch of people who really care about it pushing it forward and I guess in other countries.
Scott: while there are people like that There's not enough to actually make a big dent or a big present I don't know.
Rym: It might also just be a cultural thing and that partly because the internet I mean like it or not world.
Rym: the US Basically invented and built the internet and I mean now it's the international thing and that's awesome.
Rym: But for a long time it was mostly a US thing.
Rym: Yeah, and as a result, it seems like the people who are on the internet in the US not like the average Joe But like the techie people.
Rym: there's a lot Longer relative history of using the internet and maybe I have a feeling that if we fast-forward 10 years Japan and all these other places will look a lot like your internet does now and will look well I'd say like web 3.0 but web 3.0 still doesn't mean anything useful.
Scott: No, but yeah, we've got.
Scott: I don't know We do have a lot of foreign listeners and things but they're all coming to our English only site.
Rym: There is one Japanese website that is all in Japanese that links to us often called Ultimo spell peen.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta ask Emily to read the site for me.
Rym: Yeah, I translated it once automatically and I remember we almost used it as our tagline.
Scott: It said it links to anime world order on the left side.
Scott: So I think it's some anime loving blogger who's Asian.
Rym: but it said something to the effect of GeekNights is a power podcast.
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Rym: I was proud of that.
Rym: All right, that's all I got.
Scott: Okay, so this is pretty weak.
Scott: Also, you know sauce.
Scott: Yeah, you know everyone on dig is always like we want a picture section.
Scott: We want a picture sec.
Rym: Well, they should have a picture section.
Scott: They should and they did.
Scott: they say they're working on it.
Scott: You know that it'll be out soon enough.
Scott: I mean they upgraded the dig homepage already to like prepare for the inevitable picture sec.
Rym: I like what they did with the dig homepage.
Scott: Yeah, but somebody with with pearl and I guess Supposedly they say seven hours of coding using the dig API made a site called dig pics calm and It's a dig picture section.
Rym: I dig up part of that kid.
Scott: The glove is thrown.
Rym: Granted he used pearl.
Scott: Well, I know but the point is is that Open source?
Scott: that one advantage of it that people don't often see is that you can just make a release Even if stuff isn't really perfect or if stuff isn't a hundred percent complete like right away and It sort of looks like when someone does this that they're showing up, you know dig like.
Scott: ah, they're showing up.
Scott: dig dig just Probably could have done this in five hours if they wanted to.
Scott: the thing is this isn't integrated with the dig website.
Scott: This isn't bug tested so crazily thoroughly to be handled, you know with a bajillion dig users.
Scott: This isn't You know Tested to integrate with all the other parts of the dig website like the profile and all that other stuff in new interesting ways.
Scott: You know, it's just.
Scott: you know, basically I mean when you look at it, that's what do you expect from a dig picture section?
Scott: But I'm pretty sure the actual dig picture section is gonna be way above and beyond what this is.
Rym: But at the same time with open source stuff, it's cool that people can do things like this.
Scott: Oh, it's very cool.
Scott: And that's that's how I mean.
Rym: you're a corporation and some kid on the internet just because he's bored Could just take a product that you've released and make it better and you like what they did.
Rym: you could just say hey We're taking that Congratulations.
Rym: You want a job?
Scott: Yeah, but this I don't think that this is.
Rym: no this is not that that was kind of another tangential discussion.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, anyway, yeah If you're looking for a dig picture section dig pics.com is.
Scott: I guess we'll hold you over until the real deal.
Scott: Yeah, where you don't want to go as Bay image Bay image not so god things of the day All right, so my friend he told me that he bought some one of these things recently and for lack of a better Monday type Thing of the day.
Scott: I'll just show you this cool thing.
Rym: So a friend.
Rym: Yep a friend.
Rym: Yep Okay, right.
Scott: So what this is is it's actually a computer.
Scott: It's just a very small computer.
Scott: It's like what is?
Scott: it's got to be less than let's see.
Scott: It's six point seven inches by Eleven point four inches by.
Scott: yeah, it though that's the size of the case.
Scott: This is really tiny It's like a little square.
Rym: Well, I like to go ATX.
Scott: It's not even ATX.
Scott: It's just a very small Like square circuit board and it's got an AMD geode x86 processor Some RAM hunt like 128 megs or whatever.
Scott: It's got a bios.
Scott: It's got a serial ATA port.
Scott: It's got compact flash.
Scott: It's got freaking PCI slot.
Rym: All right, it's got.
Scott: it's loaded right?
Scott: It's a whole computer on this very small thing But most of all it's got four network interface holes right there.
Scott: One, two, three four lined up.
Scott: So if you want to I don't know make a router with say that's also, you know Not like a piece of crap links is that only does what it's been programmed to do.
Scott: but actually like a full-on router running Linux with a full firewall and the DHCPs and the DNS is and you know the whole Business.
Scott: you could just get one of these little guys and install your Linux on there straight up and there you go.
Scott: And it's a little tiny thing doesn't even need cooling.
Scott: You know, I guess it needs a heatsink, but it doesn't need a fan or anything.
Scott: It's really tiny and really efficient Huh?
Rym: That's kind of cool.
Scott: Yeah, I think oh, okay.
Scott: Maybe it has two PCI slots.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's a. it's really crazy Like yes USB holes.
Scott: It's got everything.
Scott: It's a computer.
Scott: So actually if you needed a computer, but you only needed to like browse the web You could probably get away with this thing.
Rym: How much is it?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Let's see because if you just need to browse the web, you can buy a really crappy computer for very little money.
Scott: Well like a hundred and Okay, that's worth it.
Scott: the net five five oh one, okay, wait, hold on that was the net.
Scott: four five.
Rym: Oh one way to do your research captain Scott.
Scott: Okay, the five five.
Scott: Oh one the better one Is like three hundred dollars, huh?
Scott: It's still not so bad considering you're the size you're getting.
Rym: it's smaller than a Mac mini But then you need to get a monitor and all that.
Scott: Well, you need that.
Rym: Anyway, yeah get a Mac because if you really just need like a crap computer like just I need to surf the web And that's it.
Scott: Oh, you can get the $20 motherboard that we got or not?
Rym: Even that just buy a used crap.
Rym: Oh laptop on eBay the batteries price shot But you're gonna plug it in and use it as a desktop.
Scott: Yeah, you could do that too.
Rym: I mean if you really need crap go and get crap.
Rym: don't get like the fancy.
Scott: But if you want small and quiet, you know, plus this is mostly better for uses say a router than as a computer true.
Scott: Anyway, speaking of crap, you don't need four network cards in your computer.
Scott: Do you?
Rym: Actually, I have two already.
Scott: Yeah, but how many of them do you use?
Rym: Well, well currently one.
Scott: and how many you ever gonna use?
Rym: I'm gonna have three eventually when I put that other Nick in.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Anyway, so Speaking of crap if you want to read a really bad piece of journalism You should check out this article called girls of ghost hunting by some woman named Christina Silva The time staff writer for the st.
Rym: Petersburg Times in Russia.
Scott: No Tampa, uh Florida st.
Scott: Petersburg.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yes, not Russia.
Rym: You know, I'd rather see something like this in Russia than the US but I've lost almost all my respect for the st Petersburg times.
Rym: not that I had much to begin with but not that I even knew the paper existed.
Scott: I guess I knew.
Scott: you know in theory, but I didn't actually consciously know.
Rym: This is an article about a group of women who call themselves spirits.
Rym: Spirits is an acronym.
Rym: I'm not gonna bother saying what it stands for stupid people And really into I don't know whatever stupid people and some letters But They are self-proclaimed ghost experts.
Scott: I'm a ghost expert.
Scott: They don't exist.
Scott: Yeah, I know everything there is to know about.
Rym: It's kind of like way back when every time there was a flame war on FARC about religion I just posted a link to the religion and God fact the god fact.
Rym: Is there a god?
Rym: I'm an expert on religion.
Scott: I know everything there is to know about religion.
Scott: It's all lies.
Rym: Anyway So, uh this article they kind of.
Rym: I don't know how this reporter gave so much credulity to these people but she basically just goes with them and takes everything they say at face value and they even so show pictures of their made-up garbage equipment and It has all the classics.
Rym: like they used an IR meter and they saw a cold spot.
Rym: Oh shit It's a ghost not a draft or anything.
Scott: Yeah, it couldn't possibly be I don't know a poorly insulated wall.
Rym: so then they get some sort of or a piece of metal some sort of electromagnetic meter and they're like if there's a ghost here make it spike and it's spiked.
Rym: if You're male make it spike and it spiked.
Rym: and then they had this conversation with the ghost and I'm not sure if it's just entirely made up or if the reporters just stupid or what.
Rym: but It bothers me that Semi legitimate press like the st.
Rym: Petersburg Times and it's not just them a lot of press in the u.s give credence to this bullshit that
Scott: when
Rym: speaking with an idiot someone who actually believes in ghosts and that sort of thing and claims to have evidence of ghosts and Especially when that evidence is easily and immediately debunked by anyone the fact that they won't just dismiss these people as idiots, but instead they'll interview them and Actually write an article about them and put it in the paper.
Rym: That doesn't just say I talked to an idiot.
Rym: He thinks there's ghosts.
Scott: well, you know, it's.
Scott: we go around and we see you know idiots on the internet.
Scott: We see idiots on the street and we have to realize that there's idiots all over the place and we see them all over the Place.
Scott: we interact with them all the time.
Scott: These idiots are not from any particular profession.
Scott: They are in all professions equally.
Scott: So there are idiot journalists their idiot plumbers and there's smart journalists and smart plumbers.
Scott: Yeah, any profession.
Scott: you can think of their idiots in that profession.
Scott: and when they're journalists You're gonna find out because eventually they're gonna write something idiotic.
Scott: if there's an idiotic author You're gonna find out cuz their book will be stupid.
Scott: So it's just the people who are in.
Scott: I see stupid people the people who are in a position their occupation doesn't reveal their idiocy to the public is You know is when you.
Scott: you know, you don't know about it.
Rym: So see at least to this woman's credit the grammar and spelling were Okay.
Rym: Yeah Because the editor and it wasn't as bad as some other.
Rym: I mean I've read some journalistic articles in the past where I could do their job better and I don't know I've never been a reporter, but I could do their job better right now.
Rym: Just bet.
Scott: Yep That's I could do a lot of jobs better than people do it, but you know what my job pays more.
Rym: Yeah and I'd and the thing is is that I'd rather be a journalist if I could make the same money just writing newspaper articles that I make.
Rym: now go apply to do it because they won't pay me that much money.
Scott: Yeah Oh some of them might.
Scott: it's just hard to get that kind of job.
Rym: Yeah Maybe I should apply to be a tech writer for some local paper or something.
Scott: try to do something I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, if I could make it actually if I could make even half my salary I might just quit.
Rym: go do that instead go for it.
Rym: Oh, well.
Rym: Yeah, it was kind of a lame thing today But you know what?
Rym: I'm really sick of just doing stuff on day.
Scott: You're lucky we're doing a show today cuz it's like a holiday and stuff.
Scott: So that's why I'm putting crap news and things of the day.
Rym: seriously anything I find if it's not on dig It's gonna be on dig by the time we do the show.
Rym: Yeah, there's no way to avoid it.
Rym: Nope Unless we really dig into the depths of the internet.
Rym: But then it's not really a legitimate thing of the day because I didn't just see it.
Rym: I sought it out and that's different.
Rym: Yeah, oh, well.
Scott: All right, so let's get on with it then tonight.
Rym: spam Spam Spam Scott really doesn't like spam.
Rym: I think it's okay While it's kind of disgusting when you get it out of the can.
Rym: I'll admit a spam sandwich is actually really good.
Scott: No, it's disgusting.
Scott: I'll never eat it.
Rym: Have you ever tried it?
Rym: Yeah, when?
Scott: when was like a kid?
Rym: Are you sure?
Scott: I'm sure.
Rym: how did they prepare it?
Rym: You can't just eat it out of the can.
Rym: that's disgusting.
Scott: That's Well, it was you know with some other stuff But it wasn't like changed in any way.
Rym: like what for you?
Rym: cube it?
Rym: you put it on some crackers with some dip and some Sauce and maybe some cheese.
Scott: It's a disgusting pink cube of disgusting.
Rym: It's not really a cube.
Scott: It doesn't It's disgusting.
Scott: Anyway, hey, we're gonna actually talk about the other kind of spam.
Rym: Yeah, we're not gonna go into technical crap.
Rym: We're not gonna get into the history of spam.
Rym: and the first spam was sent on November.
Scott: It was that guy from digital whatever and digital equipment corporation on a news group saying hey You know buy my computers.
Rym: No, it wasn't that Quaker running around chiseling that picture of himself laughing about Thompson's insoluble plate.
Rym: No, see we're not gonna get into it.
Rym: But there there's a fine line between advertising and spam.
Rym: and just for the sake of discussion.
Rym: We're just dining spam as Unsolicited communication in quantity in email not just an email because you can spam people over.
Scott: I am you can spam you can but this term spam most specifically refirms to email.
Rym: I don't know anymore because I mean blog spam.
Rym: or is that a separate word like blogosphere, huh?
Scott: Yeah, I guess because it's the same thing I think done by the same Bob people started using the word mostly when it.
Scott: you know Cuz email is the first place that most people who were Experiencing spam and then spam sort of got all over everything else.
Rym: The only thing I would disagree with that is usenet.
Scott: usenet was fast Yes, but that's not when people start it's not when the word entered the vernacular.
Rym: you see me.
Rym: Well, when was that?
Rym: I mean, where was spam first?
Scott: spam was first in the news groups But people didn't you know really start saying spam a lot or using the word a lot.
Rym: did they?
Rym: when was the first time someone?
Rym: said spam?
Scott: For I don't know that.
Scott: I don't know either.
Scott: We know that was the first spam.
Scott: We don't know what.
Scott: that was the first time someone called it spam.
Scott: That's very.
Scott: it's a totally different story.
Rym: Oh, well, I think email spam and usenet spam at least for the sake of discussion are effectively the same thing.
Scott: Yeah, if you want to discuss it on that higher level share I mean basically the I.
Rym: the problem here if you break it down is simply that anytime you have a Cost of zero or effectively zero to do anything.
Rym: There is absolutely no disincentive to not do it At his purest form.
Rym: that's it.
Rym: I mean.
Rym: in the past it cost money to send a letter to someone.
Rym: so if you wanted to send a letter to everyone in town saying buy Thompson's insoluble plates you had to spend postage.
Rym: it cost you something.
Rym: it might not have been much but it was something.
Rym: and whenever there's a cost involved there's diminishing returns and all that sort of business.
Rym: but With the Internet if you already have an internet connection.
Rym: It is effectively free to send as much communication as you want 24/7 and there's nothing to stop you.
Scott: So if you're gonna send out some sort of spam Even if ninety nine point nine nine nine nine percent of people Delete it or ignore it or get it filtered out if like three people Read it and like one of those people actually buys the product that you're selling and you aren't they Spammers are legitimately selling their products.
Scott: if you try to buy penis pills from spam you will get them granted.
Rym: There was that awesome guy who bought the penis pills tried him They didn't work and then he sued the spammer.
Rym: and I wonder what.
Scott: I wonder what came of it?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Yeah But the point is is that it cost them basically nothing to send these emails out if they make one sale from that.
Scott: They just made money for nothing almost and so if you're a company selling stuff Having a spammer send out a bunch of spam is not the worst market.
Scott: It's you know, it's at least with that, you know exactly how much your sales you're getting per dollar spent on the advertising Whereas with say a bulletin board in Times Square it could a bulletin board Billboard in Times Square.
Scott: you have no idea what that's doing for you could do nothing for you You don't know.
Rym: plus I mean not just look at it from the spammers perspective but from the sysadmins perspective for the normal person's perspective.
Rym: Think of a nightclub.
Rym: Imagine a nightclub in a really popular place like in New York City in Times Square on New Year's Eve.
Rym: Imagine if that nightclub didn't have a cover charge and no bouncer was at the gate and there was nothing to stop people from just Shoving their way in.
Scott: it would just become packed until the fire marshal kicked everyone out.
Rym: or like any health insurance.
Rym: and in America There's a thing called a copay where basically While your insurance is gonna cover like a hundred percent or ninety-nine percent of whatever your medical stuff is They often will have this copay where if you go to the doctor no matter what they cover You have to pay like ten or fifteen dollars.
Scott: Yeah, if I go to the doctor, I gotta give them like 20 bucks to the doctor every time I go.
Scott: So if I really need to go to the doctor I'll go to the doctor and give them 20 bucks.
Rym: 20 bucks is effectively nothing for me because I don't go to the doctor all The time.
Scott: yeah, but let's say I was a hypochondriac.
Scott: Would I go to the doctor five days a week?
Scott: No, it's $100 a week.
Scott: That's a lot of money.
Scott: So if it was zero dollars to go to the doctor and I was I have a contract.
Scott: I just live in the doctor's office because I'm crazy and it would cost me nothing.
Rym: now Like that's why there's so little spam on say AOL instant messengers.
Rym: They have this rate limiting thing where any given account ever tried to send someone a million Messages and I am real quick and notice how it kind of keeps blanking out your send button logger logger.
Rym: There is a lot of al instant messenger spam though but not nearly as much as there would be if they didn't limit it like that.
Scott: the other thing that prevents you from seeing a Lot of AOL instant messenger spam is the fact that there's a feature that says don't let me receive messages from people who are my buddy.
Rym: Never selected that.
Rym: Oh, and you know what?
Rym: I got almost no instant messenger spam ever and I put my.
Rym: I am Everywhere.
Rym: it was all over the place and all my websites forever and I never really got spam.
Scott: Yeah, I remember there was a time period where there was a lot of I am spam on and especially nail is the messenger.
Scott: But now there's not so much well one.
Rym: back then I remember they cracked down and they Severely decreased the rates.
Rym: if you try to type a bunch of messages really quick It doesn't let you it slows you down.
Rym: and that way if you've got spam accounts, they're just gonna send spam out.
Rym: You can't send so many spam out at a time and eventually you're not gonna be able to send anything at all.
Scott: Yeah, I think they also added to the default aim client a sort of warning feature that lets you say hey That's a spammer who just messaged me and I think they've pretty much solved spam on that.
Rym: Remember the?
Rym: I remember in high school and even in early RIT Remember those morning wars you'd suddenly get into on aim Yeah people where every now and then like I'd message my friend like hey bucko what's going on?
Rym: And then he'd be like Warren as many times as possible.
Rym: Haha.
Rym: I got you.
Scott: Yeah, that was kind of silly.
Scott: it's another reason not to use a list of messenger but anyway Spam is.
Scott: you know, it's actually kind of surprising how AOL was able to stop spam mostly I guess as far as I can see on their instant message network because it's really hard to stop it anywhere else.
Rym: Well, the reason the core reason that AOL could stop it was that it was their network.
Rym: They owned it.
Rym: They can make whatever changes they want.
Rym: They can do whatever they want to the servers.
Rym: They can change the clients.
Rym: They can block clients.
Rym: They have the power Email but the technological way that email is made Email was designed back in a day when the idea of spam was unheard of that like the idea of a virus or anything bad.
Scott: Well, they thought about it, but they realized that you know, it was being used on Computers that didn't have a lot of power.
Scott: They were very small amounts of memory and very small amounts of processor being used by a lot of people and it was a way for a bunch of people who were all using the same computer to send messages to each other.
Scott: and Basically they did.
Scott: they Expanded that framework to all the way up to working on the internet without really, you know Rewriting it completely which is what it needed and I'm talking to like in terms of the protocols and all that.
Rym: It was just that in the early days of the internet, you know quote unquote the internet Generally, most everybody knew everybody and if someone did something shady like send out a million emails, ah, haha Everyone knew who it was and they just blocked him and got
Scott: rid of him.
Scott: people did think about the potential for spam but you know They didn't do anything about it or they they didn't have the processing the computer resources to do anything about.
Rym: when the internet was a closed Garden, it was very difficult to get away with crap like that in general.
Rym: Yep, and Email has not changed since then.
Rym: the way and like one of the things was open relays Which that is a problem that has finally been solved just by everyone blocked anyone who had an open relay.
Rym: But back in the day email was set up to be super reliable and the email would get there come rain or sleep.
Scott: nor Because because every email server was an open relay which meant if it got an Email message and the email message wasn't for someone using that server Then the email server would pass it on its way to whatever email server is supposed to go to.
Scott: So you would have these email servers just passing Messages all around to each other and the email message would always get there because there were so many email Servers that there was always a way for the message to get to his destination.
Scott: However, the problem was is that because of all these open relays?
Scott: Anyone could send a message to anyone using any server any bajillion number of servers without you being able to know who sent it or they could pretend they sent it as someone else and it and it used to Be really easy.
Rym: I used to often send email to people with just completely forged headers and no one could tell.
Rym: Of course those days are long gone.
Scott: Luckily now everyone's disabled open relays.
Scott: So but the thing is this, you know, the internet is much more reliable and TCP IP is is better.
Scott: So people, you know, your man your mail server connects directly to the destination.
Rym: TCP IP is better.
Rym: What do you mean?
Scott: What do you mean?
Rym: How is TCP IP better than it was then?
Scott: Well, it's not.
Scott: the protocol itself is not better But the fact that the internet, you know that there's not a bunch of dial-up modems and now it's a bunch of five
Rym: Because the way you said that I was thinking TCP IP hasn't changed You know
Scott: back in the day, you know, you try to make it TCP IP connection.
Scott: It was not so reliable.
Scott: Sometimes you get timeouts and things just because the internet sucked and now because the internet doesn't suck and if you use TCP IP 99% chance even better than that the message is gonna get through.
Rym: but in terms of email spam I never really cared about it because to be honest and I guess Scott myself and John C Dvorak are very similar in this regard.
Rym: We never really got spam.
Scott: Well back in the ancient AOL days I got spams.
Scott: Yeah, I never had a well when I was a little kid using AOL that didn't really bother me.
Scott: I didn't care.
Scott: You know, I didn't use my email for anything important.
Scott: I didn't check it all that often.
Rym: I never got spam on Prodigy.
Scott: I mostly just played gemstone.
Scott: I didn't read the emails.
Scott: Yeah, then at RIT I was getting spams, you know after at first I didn't get any spams, you know I had that, you know brand new Email account at RIT, you know, not so many spam.
Scott: But then spam started pouring in from all the people who were sending it to everyone at RIT or to random things at RIT.
Scott: so I started using a spam filter like the one that comes in Thunderbird and I stopped getting spams.
Scott: It was all filtered out for me.
Rym: I didn't bother because to be perfectly honest once I got to college I almost entirely stopped using email and I did everything through IM and Anytime like.
Scott: I never checked my email because all there were just different things I did through IM than what I did through email.
Rym: The only things I did through email were automated things and interaction with businesses But never talking to people.
Scott: Yeah, I never really talked to people with the with the email at college.
Rym: Well now I do.
Rym: Yeah, now I do but we'll get to that.
Scott: Yeah, but when I was in college email was not for talking to human.
Scott: Well, I guess talking to professors but never talked to friends with it.
Scott: that or family.
Rym: See I didn't use email to talk to professors.
Rym: Well one, I never talked to professors, but I didn't do it that often either.
Rym: We were in IT so we had to use first class.
Scott: Oh, right, right, right.
Scott: But I used it to talk to professors a few times and you know things like that.
Scott: But it was always for business communications Which is what I used email for in college never for personal communications and there was spam but it was all filtered out.
Scott: So It was filtered out.
Scott: What what's the problem?
Rym: I don't know, but I started using email again with Gmail and all that and I'm not gonna get into the whole Why I use email again why Gmail is awesome and all that business.
Rym: But I'm gonna say this if you if spam is a problem for you There is really only one solution you need to even consider and that is using Gmail.
Rym: I don't want to sound like a Google fanboy but Gmail blocks almost all the spam in the world and it's almost never wrong and it's Far away the best free email thing out there.
Scott: yeah, and sometimes when I do get a spam like sometimes like a spam will get through I mark it as spam.
Scott: and Sometimes like for a day or two someone will figure out a way to get a specific type of spam into into Google right and I'll get like a few of those Maybe three messages that are all similar, you know in a couple days and I'll mark them all as spam and then they're gone.
Scott: And it's so such a small amount that I don't even reckon.
Scott: It doesn't even register in my mind.
Scott: You know, it's not like in the olden days.
Scott: We had to be like delete delete delete delete delete delete delete delete delete delete delete delete delete delete, you know Now it's just I mark one messages spam maybe a week.
Scott: That's a lot actually right like one a month and that I don't even notice it.
Rym: Yeah and consider this we have you know GeekNights at front recruit calm and GeekNights at gmail.com the Sheer amount of spam that is hitting those two address.
Scott: Oh if I look in the spam, let's look at the spam folder.
Scott: Let me go look absolutely ludicrous.
Rym: the amount of spam that hits those things.
Rym: but Gmail's filter is just freaking amazing.
Scott: Yep, let's go look in this.
Rym: How many do we get in the last?
Rym: I don't know whatever interval is convenient for you to look at.
Scott: well my spam folder Currently has here.
Scott: Let's look at today about a page of spam in the past 24 hours.
Scott: Wow So, let's see.
Scott: Is this I think a hundred messages here about?
Rym: I guess that's quite a bit of spam.
Scott: Yeah, maybe a hundred spams a day.
Scott: That's that's a lot.
Rym: I think the only like.
Rym: the thing that really got me about spam when I was in RIT was that Partly because I checked my email over all over campus and partly because RIT was the way it was I Usually just SSH or telnet it into one of the big Unix boxes and then ran pine or elm to check my email.
Rym: So deleting a bunch of spams was really annoying.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, I only did that when there was no alternative.
Rym: Well, plus back then Thunderbird wasn't so great yet It crashed a lot.
Scott: Well it back.
Scott: it was a period of time.
Scott: I used Eudora and there's a period of time Using like the squirrel.
Rym: as long as I was at RIT, I pretty much only use pine and elm.
Scott: Yeah, I used a bunch of different clients and now eventually just settled with the Gmail and give everything else the finger.
Rym: Yeah, I'm pretty much on.
Rym: I mean Google would have to do something pretty fucking evil for me to leave Gmail.
Rym: Yeah, oh, well, well think about.
Rym: the worst thing Google can do to me is tell the truth.
Rym: They could reveal all my emails.
Rym: Oh, no, look Rym made fun of that one podcast that he's friends with the people who do it, but he doesn't like their show.
Scott: Oh, no.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I think it's still weird that you know, there are some people out there.
Scott: We're still complaining about spam and it's like you have a filter.
Scott: They all work.
Rym: Why don't something scary?
Rym: At work.
Rym: I was explaining to someone that Google has an email thing called Gmail.
Rym: Wow, and I learned that almost no one at my job knows about or uses Gmail.
Rym: They all have like Yahoo accounts or hotmail accounts and they just don't work.
Rym: one guy just doesn't have the internet at home And he I was like, yeah, I'll send you an email if I need whatever in the morning and he's like I can't check my email till I get into work.
Rym: I Can't fathom that.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Scott: Well, they can't fathom us not having cable.
Scott: It's the same thing.
Rym: Yeah, I guess that's true.
Rym: But obviously and clearly we're right and they're wrong.
Scott: Well, actually there's something else I want to talk about.
Scott: is I saw this word.
Scott: It seems like it's someone's intentionally trying to coin this word, you know, it's not like one of those words that's coined You know, I guess naturally or organically like a meat space or spam, right?
Scott: Basically, they're trying to coin this word bacon BACN not BACO at BACN.
Rym: And no well, no thumbs down.
Scott: Anyway, what it refers to?
Scott: I think that we do need a word for this.
Scott: I don't know if bacon is the right word, but all those emails that you get that aren't spam But they're not real emails either.
Scott: like, you know Your registration with the forum Here's your activation code.
Scott: or here is your weekly update something or here is the email from cron or here is you know?
Scott: The notification that you got a message on some website.
Rym: I gotta say I don't need a word for that because to be honest I just set up filters to where all those things are put into relevant categories and then I don't even think about them.
Scott: Yeah, I also do the same thing.
Scott: However, there's some people out there who are trying to think up perhaps a more Intuitive and useful way to handle all the the sort of bacon messages.
Rym: I'm okay calling it bacon, but BACON.
Rym: Yeah Taking the O out does not make it cooler.
Scott: It makes it web 2.0.
Rym: No, that's like web 2.7 Because it's not semantic yet and it's not useful like web 2.0.
Scott: It's just stupid Yeah, but in some ways I think bacon is the new spam.
Scott: I mean if I look at my email, right, but that's not bad I want it some of it.
Scott: I want some of it.
Rym: I don't know you want then it's spam if you didn't want it, but see that sort of thing.
Scott: It's like I didn't want it, but I sort of signed up for it.
Scott: Like look here Here's an invoice I get every month from there with the hosting bill on it, right?
Scott: I don't ever look at it.
Scott: It just fills up my inbox with more messages, but it's not spam because it's not an unsolicited someone trying to sell me something.
Scott: It's just a message in my inbox that I really don't want to see.
Rym: so it's well though that's for record-keeping.
Rym: You don't need to see it.
Rym: what I for all those things what I do is I set up a filter.
Scott: I do have a filter, but it's still there.
Rym: I have a label a category goes into it skips my inbox and goes straight there and it's already marked as red So I don't even look in there.
Rym: But if I need to look up for whatever reason an old invoice or an old record, they're all there ready to go.
Rym: Yeah, I've invented space.
Scott: I do the same thing, but it there.
Scott: I think there could be a way of handling them more like gracefully because I don't know.
Scott: That's why people are thinking about it.
Rym: They're not gonna want to host a website that archives all that crap for you to look at on a moment.
Scott: They don't need to do that.
Scott: that there's.
Scott: there's other things we could do with these messages that I think they're giving them to you.
Rym: You if you wanted you could set up a thing that automatically not something they can do something we can do.
Rym: Yeah, you know what you should do it take them have them automatically populate some database You've got and delete from your email.
Scott: You could do something like that.
Scott: Yeah, I did do that.
Scott: then something like that.
Scott: But yeah, people are working on something like that ways to handle bacon That is.
Rym: that is interesting as long as you're saying the O in the bacon.
Rym: I'm cool with whatever you do.
Scott: Yeah, they're spelling it BACN to be cool.
Rym: I'm not gonna do that.
Rym: Yeah, and I think I can resist that one because it's not a name change.
Rym: It's a name coining.
Scott: it is it is.
Rym: It's not like the the revolution or capstone or physical plants physical plant Facilities management service or that Phoenix web browser.
Rym: That was so awesome.
Scott: Oh, man.
Scott: That was the best web.
Scott: I love that web browser lot better than shitty-ass Firefox.
Scott: I want you to bring it back.
Rym: Firebird wasn't so great.
Rym: But Phoenix that was where it was at.
Scott: It was definitely where it was at.
Scott: Do you have anything else to say about spam?
Scott: not really people who send it are kind of scummy.
Scott: But on the other hand a lot of the people who receipt like there are some places that send on.
Scott: You know, there's unsolicited spam, but then there's you signed up for it and now you're getting it spam Which is I sort of don't have sympathy for those people but also because they should be filtering.
Rym: Yeah, but the answer once again just use Gmail.
Rym: There's no reason not to.
Scott: there is one more thing to discuss and that is some people out there do want to send Legitimate mass emails, you know, that's not spam usually bacon actually they.
Scott: there's someone who has a legitimate reason to send email to a lot of people and Because of anti-spam measures by say AOL and Yahoo and Google You need to jump through these tremendous hoops of all sorts to get white-listed by these people or else all your emails get blocked.
Rym: my take on that and I've always been this way and I've noticed that Culturally on the internet.
Rym: There's been a shift toward this way of thinking not quite to my extent But in the early days of spam there were two camps.
Rym: There was the.
Rym: I don't think there's a bunch of ways you could break it up or call them different things but on one side there are the people who believe that Getting all the email intended for you is better is more important than blocking all the spam and the other end Blocking all the spam is more important than getting all of the email sent to you and I have always been one of those people I tended to.
Rym: I would rather not see any spam and Miss the occasional email that looked like a spam.
Rym: then ever get spam but not miss email.
Scott: Yes, I agree.
Scott: as an email Receiver I agree that I would rather see no spam and miss a few emails intended for me.
Rym: Originally, however, the culture was the opposite and I just think the internet culture has shifted lately and people basically out So fed up with spam that they said, you know what fine block it all.
Rym: I don't give a shit block all of China cuz I'm not gonna get email from there anyway in that kind of business.
Scott: However as an email sender it is frustrating for example our forum.
Scott: when you sign up for our forum, it sends you an email that says Congratulations, you have been approved.
Scott: where your forum membership is clear You know you can go sign in if using hotmail you don't get that message because their spam filter filters us out.
Scott: But again, it's not spam.
Rym: The answer is Gmail because Gmail blocks almost none of that I know but it's see.
Scott: as a reader I use Gmail, but I can't force anyone else to use it.
Scott: So I am in a situation where I am forced.
Scott: I have in a message.
Scott: I want to send to someone using hotmail.
Scott: I really wanted to get through.
Scott: so they know that they're approved for the forum They wanted to get through.
Scott: but it's not happening and it is Frustrating that my non spam is treated as spam and in order to get that undone is such a crazy amount of work It's not worth it.
Rym: I guess I'm just of the mind of I'd rather screw the senders than the receivers.
Rym: because if the receivers keep getting screwed That there there's just people stop using email.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, well And the thing is there's no other way to like contact any people I block with a broad brush.
Rym: at RIT I actually blocked any email pretty much any email from outside of the United States at one point.
Rym: Yeah Because that's where all the spam came from back then and I didn't receive email from people outside of the US back then.
Rym: and the Few people I knew overseas that I wanted to talk to I used aim.
Rym: so I just blocked it all.
Rym: and now Gmail don't have to worry but I'll like adblock.
Rym: right if I ever see an ad I block that entire domain at the lowest level.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure that probably makes some web pages look pretty ugly.
Rym: Oh, it does but you know what?
Rym: a lot of those web pages They don't look ugly because it's just text now and there's no graphics.
Scott: It's pretty good stuff.
Rym: The only thing I don't do that for as far cuz I like to see the little Florida tag.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Oh, well, I think we're done talking about spam here.
Scott: if you get spam You suck.
Rym: use Gmail use some technology.
Scott: it all works really well.
Scott: if you send spam you suck.
Scott: And if you're trying to send something that's being blocked as fan That's frustrating.
Rym: and if you the only other thing if you're trying to have a mailing list like an email list Those are so obsolete.
Rym: Oh, yeah, seriously Get a forum or a blog RSS or an RSS or a blog.
Rym: or if you're gonna do a mailing list do it through Gmail with Collaboration or something.
Rym: don't just do a straight-up like list.
Scott: Yeah, the old-school listservs are not cool.
Scott: They should all die in a fire Like the only people use.
Scott: some people have like the listserv news group integration where it's sort of like they.
Scott: they get copied to Each other's groups are equally obsolete.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know why so many people still use them.
Rym: IBM uses them internally But that was kind of cool.
Rym: that in the real world news groups are no longer useful.
Rym: There's far better technology.
Scott: Yeah, I don't even know news servers are just so confusing.
Rym: well like like that whole side of the internet internet.
Rym: you know listservs news groups and IRC.
Rym: all that's left over.
Rym: there are people who don't know there are better solutions and Really really shady people doing really really shady things because the authorities don't really know how to deal with that old stuff.
Scott: Yeah, that's the old underground like original internet communication protocol stuff And it's mostly basically a bunch of nerds and a bunch of underground action that God we should talk about.
Rym: the old IRC.
Rym: those were not good days.
Scott: No not good days.
Scott: Not the only IRC that's worth going to is like free node, but you're just a bunch of open-source people.
Rym: Yeah, but even then I just I don't care enough.
Scott: I don't go there unless there's no other solution I can find.
Rym: I'm never gonna load up Merkur perch again ever.
Scott: I could just use you know my aim client to go on there.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.