Rym: It is Thursday November 29th.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: for some reason we talk about musical instruments.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So this is probably germane more to uh I don't know GeekNights Tuesday rather than GeekNights Thursday.
Rym: But I like to point out that Scott and I together played go against each other for the first time about 15 minutes ago.
Scott: Well we sort of played it sort of off the cuff like you know.
Scott: it's a pretty simple game.
Scott: you take turns putting you Know your colored guy on the board and when you surround the other guy you get his stuff sort of like Othello or Tron in A way in a really abstract way.
Rym: But that's I don't.
Rym: the.
Rym: the deal is we've been for you Thursday.
Rym: people don't listen.
Rym: to.
Rym: Tuesday.
Rym: We're uh kind of into really hardcore You know German style brains banging against other brains kind of games not like chess But more like Puerto Rico or D. Ma care or D. Seidler for Catan.
Rym: anyway, we We were done with a lot of these games at least the two and three player versions of these games because Scott And I live together for a long time, and I think we have finished to the point of not being able to enjoy any further or gain any sort of intellectual stimulation from Any two-player game we've ever played.
Scott: So of course you know people will say and some mostly rightly so that go is like the be all end.
Scott: all of games like.
Scott: It's perfect information It's wholly abstract And it is so many different possible moves and patterns that a computer can't possibly Figure it out because it's so complex now.
Rym: I'd always been leery partly because RIT.
Rym: I didn't have to worry about go because there were still German games.
Rym: I hadn't played.
Rym: that might have been good.
Rym: now I've played them all.
Scott: Yep, granted.
Rym: We if we had more people living here we'd probably be okay because I don't think we've solved for player T and E or Four or five player k-lists or any of those.
Scott: yeah, it's just like two and three player games.
Scott: We're running out.
Rym: I'll tell you all a little thing about games in general.
Rym: Just because you know you're not Tuesday listeners, maybe Two-player games are very difficult to make With any sort of staying power because they basically break down into randomness or a Predetermined victory condition yeah, or rock-paper-scissors.
Scott: It's like think about it every two-player game You've ever played right that you could ever think of unless it's some kind of sport right like boxing.
Scott: Say it all it comes down to either rock-paper-scissors Memorization luck something along those lines.
Scott: It's never like strategy or anything like that.
Rym: It might be strategy until you solve the game.
Rym: I mean checkers.
Rym: you can place checkers tactically and strategically Unless you know the game perfectly and then you can just play perfectly and no matter what always make the good decision.
Scott: I guess maybe those miniatures war games like maybe Warhammer But then it's got some randomness in there with the dice action going on that evens out and while those games would probably solve Our problem.
Rym: Do you think we have the time to play a game like that?
Rym: I want to.
Scott: I love we can't even play like Battle lore.
Rym: I love games where I have a million fiddly miniatures And I pull out a laser pen and some measuring tape and give my skirmishers in order to go into the woods and wait while Scott's columns of Celiel troops are marching in from the north, but I Don't have time for that.
Rym: Maybe if I had a basement, and I could leave it set up and no job.
Scott: Oh, you know what if we whenever we build you know geek house version 2 the thing is most of the fun I get from those games is setting up and moving the dudes around.
Scott: I would be Better-served just had it with a basement buying a shit ton of Legos and not playing a game.
Rym: Well see the other problem is while those games are really fun You're probably better off just playing a computer simulation of war at that point yep.
Scott: So I don't want to talk too much about go now because we're complete doofuses with it, but And in the future there will be lots of go talking going on.
Scott: perhaps Go talking that go fanatics will be pissed off, and maybe we should watch a car no go.
Scott: I mean I've seen like four episodes.
Rym: I kind of like to car or no go.
Scott: It's not like Akagi because no I'm saying maybe we should watch it to learn something.
Rym: Yeah, maybe we should.
Rym: you know There's something to be said there for making shows that are educational and are entertaining.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you're street as a kid yeah If you really think about it there aren't too many things that it's.
Scott: usually when someone tries to be educational they fail Entertainment or when they try for entertainment They don't do any education, and it's very rare that something succeeds at doing both.
Scott: You know despite many people trying to do both.
Scott: And I think a car no go is one of the best successes perhaps the top ten of those of all time.
Scott: I mean it must teach some go and It's also entertaining.
Rym: But to put it really really briefly our first foray into go Scott's played go a couple times before.
Rym: I played half of a game Of go once and then I was distracted by some emergency at some anime club function I played.
Rym: I had to go be the president and stop it.
Scott: at RIT.
Scott: I played a few maybe a handful of games of go with people who actually knew what they were doing.
Scott: Actually like a few I played a few games with someone who?
Scott: Knew knew slightly more than me, but you know I still wasn't like a master.
Scott: and then I played against some people who were like go nut cases and I lost every time, but I wasn't frustrated because I lost.
Scott: I was frustrated cuz they didn't know why I lost and because it Wasn't fun.
Rym: see I have two Ideas, and I'm not sure how I feel about go because on one hand Despite really liking these kinds of games You know abstracted or semi abstracted games of tactics and strategy and patterns the thing is I'm not a fan of perfect information games.
Rym: Well the problem is that like chess.
Rym: people always bother me and give me shit about the fact that I don't like the game of chess at all and I never have.
Rym: I played it a lot as a kid.
Rym: I I'm okay at it.
Rym: one of my friends was he wasn't like a grandmaster or anything, but he was like a master.
Rym: He was ranked.
Rym: He was awesome at chess.
Rym: He was kind of a savant at chess, and I don't think I ever beat him.
Rym: But I played chess against him all the time And I basically came to the conclusion that the reason I didn't like chess was that it was The game had because of the manner and I guess depth of abstraction it basically seemed to come down to the complex Memorization of patterns and that mattered a lot more than any tactical or strategic thought.
Scott: yeah It's like you couldn't sit there and sort of Figure your figure out how to solve it.
Scott: the same way you figure out say a block puzzle in a Zelda game Or you know some.
Scott: you know that kind.
Rym: that's the kind of thinking or even the tactical situation in a war.
Scott: Yeah, it's like huh well if I move this over here Then I'll you know she it chess isn't like that chess.
Scott: I mean, I guess you could think about chess in that way But you will lose to someone who just memorized every possible pattern.
Scott: well I guess let me put a ghost feels a lot like chess only with a lot more possible patterns.
Rym: Oh, well, so uh what do you got in the news all right?
Scott: So if you are someone who still watches television right and you don't just get your TV shows on DVD or something I mean, I guess that's okay for people who have a lot of time and not much to do And they just want to watch some video, and
Rym: you should at least have a TiVo.
Rym: I mean God.
Scott: hey you should at least have a TiVo or a DVR of some sort.
Rym: I would say that if you are a fan of television like you like television shows And you have cable not having some sort of DVR That's like being a crackhead and not owning your own crack pipe.
Scott: wait a minute.
Scott: He was that a thing of the day once.
Rym: I hope it was all right.
Rym: I'll search if it wasn't Monday.
Scott: You're a crackhead.
Scott: Why don't you have a crack pipe seriously?
Rym: You think that'd be the one thing you'd own?
Rym: anyway like being a painter and Having watercolors, but not owning any other kind of paint.
Scott: Yep, now pretty much.
Scott: I've looked into DVRs a little bit and from what I can tell TiVo is Sort of the best one sort of.
Scott: you know it's got the best interface.
Scott: That's that it's seemingly, and you know they have a good You know channel guide and everything like that and a lot of people have TiVos are really happy with TiVos and big fans of Them and they work.
Scott: and if I if I was TV watching Maybe I'd have an HD TV, and I'd probably have an HD TiVo also.
Scott: the only problem I have with TiVo and the reason I would never get one right now is because You have to buy the TiVo itself, and then you have to pay TiVo a monthly fee.
Rym: Right for the TiVo to keep working well, you know there's a lot of reasons for that.
Rym: I mean the main reason why people use services like this is because you get the TV listings Yeah, integrated, which is not always the easiest or freest thing to do.
Scott: no no no but Basically the the problem I have with TiVo is that you buy this box and you pay this monthly fee And you're sort of stuck with TiVo.
Scott: the company can just like take your TiVo away.
Scott: They they have all sorts of control over the box itself like you can't do like anything you want with a TiVo.
Scott: You can only do what they want the TiVo to do.
Rym: I mean remember all the problems about how they take away like the 30-second skip so people can't skip ads as easily.
Rym: and Yeah, to me 30-second skip on a DVR is probably the most important function more important than TV listings Right, so you know something.
Scott: if I was gonna get a DVR right now.
Scott: I would opt to get something like Microsoft Media Center, which the only problem with that is it's not free or Myth TV, which the only problem with that is it's hard to get TV listings for it that are free.
Scott: At least you can't.
Rym: a lot of people have trouble setting it up.
Scott: Yeah but I would just use not myth or which just sets it up automatically and then I would pay for the TV listings only and I'd be all set to go.
Rym: well Yeah But you're smart.
Scott: and the thing yeah the thing with that is it's so much better than TiVo because you mean the interface isn't as Good.
Scott: but you have a computer connected to your television and that computer just has some software on it that happens to do DVR stuff and it's actually also a computer that you can do whatever the hell you want with.
Rym: and Whereas the TiVo is a computer that can only do one thing which is sort of like, uh, yeah Remember that guy at Dragon Con who had his myth TV set up with pretty much every ROM ever?
Scott: Yeah, basically his TV was every arcade game ever and the TV shows you record.
Rym: you might be thinking Rym and Scott.
Rym: He didn't have every arcade game ever.
Rym: I defy you to find something.
Rym: He didn't have good God.
Rym: Well, because they're 40,000.
Scott: Well, because I was like because unlike in Mame Mame has a list of supported games.
Scott: Like if you download Mame and run it, it'll list out all the games that it can run.
Scott: It's the multiple arcade machine emulator.
Scott: There's a list is a known list of which arcade machines are emulated and what games are built on those machines.
Scott: And if you get a game for Mame that game lights up and says you can play me now and there are torrents of every game.
Scott: Anyway anyway This might change soon and this is important stuff.
Scott: Nero a closed source software company, but a company that I don't really hate so much because they make high quality software.
Scott: They make high quality software for Linux at a reasonable price.
Rym: Yeah, I mean you might know them from.
Scott: Nero burning ROM Pretty much make the best CD DVD burning software out there and they make a bunch of other software.
Scott: That's sort of a but you know, they just attach it to their CD burning software.
Scott: I guess some of its okay like the stuff that makes DVD and CD cover art and whatnot but most of its just direct.
Scott: they throw in there to you know, sell you more direct, but They made a deal with TiVo and in the next version of Nero supposedly There's going to be a DVR software that has the TiVo interface like and they're gonna pay TiVo for this.
Scott: So ha what's gonna happen is you take a computer plug it into your TV and your cable box or your satellite Whatever and then you install Nero on there and then in that you have a computer that you control that happens to run TiVo, but Nero's providing it and I imagine it's gonna have all sorts of cool functionality such as I don't know download a show record it burn it to DVD with Nero etc.
Scott: etc.
Scott: and That would probably be worth it.
Scott: And I think if someone was like a super TiVo fan It might be in their best interest to stop paying their.
Scott: you know I guess maybe you'll still have to pay some someone for TV listings or something.
Scott: I don't know how that's gonna work specifically But I think the best option of the future for DVR might be get a computer Get Nero on there with the TiVo.
Scott: that's part of the Nero TiVo Nero PC DVR Acronym acronym words that end in O.
Rym: Yeah, because people are really gonna just figure that out and know what to do.
Scott: Yeah, I know right, but it does seem like it's.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's the best option for the consumer or at least it's gonna be.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is to see how much it costs.
Rym: I would I mean even if I had a lot of free time I've really gotten beyond the point of needing to.
Rym: I mean things come out.
Rym: I want to see him.
Rym: I want to see shows.
Rym: I want to see movies, but I No longer care about seeing them When they come out or as soon as they come out because I've still got a backlog of things to watch.
Scott: I've got like a whole bunch of years left in my life and Right now I'm young so I don't have a lot of young time.
Scott: I got plenty of old time.
Scott: So got to spend the young time wisely doing stuff being productive in some.
Rym: yeah, like playing a plastic guitar.
Scott: exactly You Can have a real plastic guitar.
Scott: it wouldn't sound too great, but I imagine you could.
Scott: you could make one.
Rym: I play guitar hero acoustically.
Rym: You didn't see that episode.
Rym: Did you know it up South Park?
Rym: Yeah, it's okay.
Rym: Yeah, okay, it makes the point that I would probably make.
Rym: and yeah anyway, so there's this article on slash shot I just linked to.
Rym: I've looked at it.
Rym: Finally because I saw it this morning and it was about Social networking and Facebook in my space and how it might get destroyed by something or other and I Thought the article based on these slash dot comments was gonna say a few things.
Rym: I actually read the article just now and I had to throw out pretty much everything I was gonna say because the article doesn't even get that far.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Oh even better.
Rym: I just realized it's by Cory Doctorow.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't even notice.
Rym: Okay, but anyway the title is how your creepy ex co-workers will kill Facebook.
Rym: All right, and it says in a whole bunch of words.
Rym: it seems like the gist is very simply.
Rym: the problem with social networking is that you can't refuse if someone else wants to be your friend not up.
Rym: let me finish and Therefore you'll have a bunch of people who are not your friends on your friend list and that causes all sorts of problems now one You can easily refuse.
Scott: Yeah For a while for a long time.
Scott: I was just Refusing most people who wanted to be my friend like on Facebook.
Scott: Like I don't use Facebook.
Scott: I signed up for it when it was new right way back and I just never used it because it never Really improved my life or did anything for ya.
Rym: I couldn't.
Rym: when you signed up for Facebook I think I was already at IBM maybe but I just never used it.
Scott: But I would get emails whenever anyone like friended me or messaged me or something Usually on my birthday cuz Facebook apparently told everyone when it was my birthday.
Scott: So I would go into Facebook.
Scott: I would you know, whatever messages it sent me I would handle those messages and usually it was people who wanted to be my friend people I didn't know who wanted to be my friend and I would just say no, I don't know who you are.
Scott: Why are you friending me?
Scott: You're not my friend.
Scott: You're a stranger.
Scott: and I thought recently I was thinking you know Maybe the reason that these social networks are not useful to me and I'm getting no use out of them.
Scott: Cuz I don't friend anybody.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: isn't the point to make a network of people by friending them and then it becomes useful?
Rym: So we'll see.
Rym: if I if we go back though remember before Facebook or any of that there was Orkut Yeah and we all signed up for Orkut our little front row crew and a lot of people at RIT.
Rym: we knew and we actually used it a lot and I remember like the first time when someone I didn't really know But they seem to be a friend to someone I knew and they wanted to be my friend.
Rym: and I was like, you know I'm gonna go beyond using this as my kind of Personal forum to talk with my friends and schedule events and all that fun stuff and share pictures.
Rym: I'm gonna make a new friend and I said yes, you can be my friend.
Rym: and Then the next day I wake up I'm about to skip class and play Counter-Strike and I go to Orkut and I had like 400 Portuguese spam messages from friends of friends of friends of friends of friends and I learned that day that Friending people you don't know and social networking is probably the stupidest thing you could ever do in your entire life
Scott: Right.
Rym: So recently sort of getting in cars with strangers.
Scott: Yeah So recently I said, you know what?
Scott: I'm gonna try it, you know You know people have been talking and I'm gonna.
Scott: I'm gonna friend anyone who has.
Scott: so I put out a message and I said hey I've been having a policy of not friending people.
Scott: I don't know Social networks have been useless to me.
Scott: I'm gonna friend anyone who asks and I've been friending everyone who asks and you know what?
Scott: The social networks are no more useful to me than they were before it.
Scott: It's just completely a waste of time.
Scott: It doesn't do anything for me.
Rym: I think they're because this article kind of complains about social networks and I don't really want to talk so much about this article.
Rym: but just in general a lot of people hate on social networking and they give a lot of reasons like people will stalk you or Kids will put their information up online or like this one says if your boss demands to be your friend It's very awkward and dangerous to say no and it's hard to like.
Rym: it's a social taboo to say No When someone wants to friend you even though I think anyone who feels that way has got serious problems.
Scott: I do if you put value in whether someone says yes or no to friendship on Facebook.
Scott: you got a problem, but I mean like.
Scott: maybe if Rym wouldn't want to be my friend I'd be like what the fuck.
Rym: but Yeah, but it see I can see where the social awkwardness might come.
Rym: Let's say for example, we had a friend in the crew Joey Jojo Shava.
Scott: do Joey Jojo?
Rym: and you know, we hang out with Joey Jojo, but we're not super friends with Joey Jojo.
Rym: We had a lot of people like that at RIT when we were freshmen.
Rym: like the crew We like we all met the front row crew But there were like 30 other people and all the different clubs that we all kind of knew and they were all kind of our Friends, but they weren't super our friends and over time We weren't really that much hanging out with them because a lot of them we didn't really like so much like it's not like.
Rym: oh They were bad people.
Scott: We just they're just you know, they're people that you know, you know their face.
Scott: You maybe know their name your their acquaintances, but they're not like your friends.
Scott: You don't hang out with them You don't call them up.
Scott: You don't go to their parties.
Scott: You just you see them around especially, you know co-workers and fellow students And stuff like that.
Rym: You're like at our idea.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: There was duck boy.
Scott: Yeah, they're people you see and people you know, but they're not your friends.
Scott: You don't have any emotional attachment to them.
Scott: Now imagine you don't trust them.
Rym: Well, there was also that Steve.
Rym: Yeah now imagine if someone out there Let's say I'll use myself.
Rym: I'm I think I'm cool with this group of people like.
Rym: I'm friends with this guy.
Rym: Oh, man we're friends.
Rym: and you know that scene in a lot of movies or TV shows where like the guy who's kind of awkward or not really the real friend gives someone a ride home and then the guy like goes into his house and the friends standing outside like so, uh You want to do something?
Rym: I'm kind of busy.
Rym: Ah, maybe some other time.
Rym: Yeah, maybe some other time.
Rym: click It's the same situation someone yours.
Rym: You're not really friends with.
Rym: it's like hey You want to be my friend on Facebook and saying no is basically telling them in no uncertain terms that you're not really my friend.
Scott: Well, I think the problem there right is that in person right like a lot of people like fanboys like super fanboys You know with social basically lacking social Skills completely right?
Scott: They don't.
Scott: it's sort of like this huge gray scale Like they don't like.
Scott: you can like brush someone off, but then they won't feel like they're brushed off.
Scott: and there's all these social You know Like.
Rym: nah, man.
Rym: Sorry, I'm busy blah blah blah.
Rym: Maybe some other time.
Rym: Hey, sorry got her.
Rym: anime Club was a good example.
Rym: I was the president.
Rym: my job After a showing was to pretty much
Scott: Mingle
Rym: around be visible talk to everyone in the club make everyone feel like they were my friend whether they were or weren't and Scott could tell and all my real friends could tell when I was Genuinely talking to someone and when I was fake talking to someone as in these like I'd haha.
Rym: Yeah, that's great.
Scott: When you're in person talking to someone there's so much subtlety and complexity to a social situation.
Scott: It could turn out all sorts of ways, but when you bring it down to friend or not friend It's sort of like.
Scott: you can't be subtle about it.
Scott: You can't be.
Scott: there's no delicacy.
Scott: There's no nothing like that, so it's just flat-out.
Scott: you are my friend or You're not.
Scott: instead of like, you know, the the relationship you had, you know, which was hey, what's up?
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: you're my enemy.
Scott: But what choice do I have?
Rym: either you're my friend or you're not and some things like I think or cut had an acquaintance Level and all these levels of friendship, but then how come he's a friend and I'm an acquaintance?
Rym: Of course the answer that is anyone who says that you probably didn't actually want to hang out with in the first place and you're Off when they stop talking to you, but actually my new my new thinking is this on the social networks, right?
Scott: We use Google for domains, right?
Rym: So all the front row crew people still my thunder I was gonna say almost the same thing.
Scott: We go ahead we chat with each other on our own Semi private I am Network.
Scott: We email each other.
Scott: We calendar each other.
Rym: Not just that.
Rym: we have our own forum.
Rym: I mean you guys use the front row crew forums and I really like our forums like.
Rym: I hang out with all of you on that forum and I really like it.
Rym: but The crew itself we have kind of a secret internal forum where we also use that forum for our own business.
Rym: Don't ask to be on we're not gonna give you an account.
Scott: But yeah, but I mean basically it's we already have Google for domains and a forum You know for our group of friends.
Scott: It's we have a group of friends.
Scott: This is like, you know a whole bunch of us the front row crew and we all have good things that we use already.
Scott: And I feel like if I didn't have those things I'd be all about the fan.
Scott: Facebook does those things also so I'd probably be using that, you know to schedule events or to talk.
Scott: You know invite people to things and all that kind of thing.
Rym: if you have a wide, you know Especially if you're coming out of college you have dozens and dozens and dozens of friends Hopefully even more and you all kind of get spread out maybe little clumps around the country.
Rym: But you want to stay in touch and do stuff.
Rym: But how annoying is it to have to call people to stay in touch with them?
Rym: We're like, oh, we're all gonna have a party in December.
Rym: Well, I gotta call bill and Bill's got to call Joey Jojo Shabba do.
Rym: and By having this kind of social network situation It's a great way to use technology to coordinate among friends without having to put forth effort that if life gets Difficult or you don't have time you might not have time to do and then you lose touch with people that you didn't want to and If we didn't have our own social network already, we'd be all about the Facebook.
Rym: Yeah, not the myspace I guess just for me.
Scott: I see that there has uses but doesn't have any uses for me and I also see a lot of people lately are Using it basically for promotional purposes and it's not always big companies doing marketing It's you know some guy with his blog, you know, he might use his Facebook quote legitimately But he also uses it to try to like push a blog story he wrote or something and I don't know if there's anything good or bad about that, but That's not
Rym: what
Scott: you know.
Scott: if it's really a closed circle of friends who are you know You're you're real friends and you're just doing your stuff that friends do.
Scott: That kind of stuff doesn't go down there really and that's why I kind of like Not using some social network like that.
Scott: That's all connected with a billion people.
Rym: I think the real issue.
Rym: all the people who complain about social networks Complain about not so much the technology because they come they're really complaining about the fact that people use them.
Rym: I don't want to say wrong, but a lot of people use social networks in ways that I feel personally are Counterproductive not possibly the best use of your time.
Scott: a lot of you like sit there and like they just sit on Facebook for a long time doing I don't know what like.
Rym: it's some sort of video game or something or people who There's so many of these kids who date like.
Rym: how many friends they have is such a big deal.
Rym: and look at you see a lot of like 12 13 year old punk kids in Facebook or myspace and they have like 100,000 friends and their friends all have a hundred thousand friends and they're just trying to make this number go up.
Scott: There's really some sort of psychology in this of the software and I think that's what we really have to study is like the psychology of how people interact with because really all you're doing there might not be.
Scott: Imagine if you're sitting at Facebook and it was exactly the way it is But on the other there were no actual real people using it.
Scott: It was just it's just you interacting with this, you know interface on a computer screen and there's a psychology to that that I think Gets people doing weird stuff When you study that Things of the day.
Rym: So, uh, I saw something today something bad Very bad real bad Disgusting, uh, let me put it this way this video is not that thing because I'm not gonna.
Rym: I would never make something like that my thing of the day, but This video has a little bit of merit and basically I assume they got this grandmother's permission ahead of time.
Rym: like all right grandma We're gonna show you something disturbing.
Rym: Are you prepared to watch something disturbing?
Rym: How bad could it be sunny?
Rym: Well, you're about to find out.
Scott: There's this new video going around the Internet Relatively new at least as far as I can tell.
Rym: as in I didn't know about it.
Scott: I discovered it some listener sent it to me But I was at work and I turned it on and the first thing I saw in the video was some lesbian.
Scott: So I turned it off and then I was like what the hell's up with this.
Scott: I'm at work, dude, and he's like, oh, it's just the new.
Scott: it's basically the new goat.
Scott: see the new tub girl.
Scott: You know you you saw those horrible pictures on the internet in the olden days.
Scott: Well, it's only a matter of time before there was a horrible video and here is the new Trump card.
Scott: as far as disgusting things on the internet go now
Rym: my thing of the day is a grandmother watching this thing and reacting to it and I Think I have to warn you about one thing one You might get the impression from watching the grandmother that it can't be that bad.
Rym: She's just a grandmother.
Rym: I Think I'm desensitized to Everything.
Rym: I've never seen something more disgusting.
Rym: I don't recommend you watch it but yeah watch this grandma because there's one funny thing I can say is that hearing this music and kind of just the Background noise of that video just hearing that while the grandmother watches is in and of itself Hilarious and lends a very almost sinister quality to what might be going on on that screen.
Scott: Yeah It's like this.
Scott: This is actually so disgusting that you don't want to watch it.
Scott: Like you can look at goatse and it's disgusting but you'll be alright.
Rym: I mean there is something to say for desensitization.
Rym: I mean, yeah, I remember the first time I saw goatse.
Rym: I was in a Usenet or something somewhere and someone was like bla bla bla bla bla bla bla.
Rym: goatse.
Rym: someone else's like link.
Rym: What's this?
Rym: goatse and someone else like here it is.
Rym: I was like, huh?
Rym: I wonder what that is click and it was awful and I didn't know what to do.
Rym: It was there looking at me and I was looking back at it.
Rym: I had stared into the abyss and the abyss had stared back at me.
Scott: and now goatse whatever.
Rym: goat sees nothing.
Rym: I could have a poster of.
Scott: goatse it wouldn't bother me Right, but this this new video relatively new video is just it's me.
Scott: it has raised the bar on Disgusting and disturbing things on the internet.
Rym: I applaud you disgusting people for having done this but at the same time I think it's a bar that I hope is never raised higher.
Rym: But sadly I know will be.
Scott: would you rather have not seen it?
Rym: You know what?
Scott: Cuz I Avoid watching it.
Scott: I think I'm going to succeed on one end.
Rym: I thought I should avoid it But then I decided that it was intellectual curiosity in the sense that people are really making a shitstorm about how bad this is.
Rym: and people made the same shitstorm when goatse and lemon party and tub girl and all those kind of horrible things were found by the internet.
Rym: and This time the shitstorm is justified both in a metaphorical and a literal sense.
Scott: Good God Yeah, but I take the the idea that rather than ever watch the disgusting thing itself Which I'm going to try to avoid doing because I really I mean I was listening.
Scott: I basically Rym was watching and I was just covering my eyes and listening.
Rym: Let me put it this way.
Rym: I Am pretty cool-headed like there's not much people who know me.
Rym: that can I guess get my goat?
Rym: there's not much that'll cause me to scream or lose my temper or Get frightened or anything or startled or anything, but I was watching and I was thinking to myself I'm gonna sit here stoically and watch this.
Rym: How bad could it be?
Rym: and I could not help from saying.
Rym: Oh my god Yeah, and then followed by that.
Rym: Oh my god
Scott: Yeah, so if Rym Rym was act based on what I heard Rym said I knew this is probably something I wanted to avoid and I think the your best bet is to just watch People watching it to sort of get the idea of the terribleness
Rym: kind of like when that guy showed Ron Jeremy goats.
Rym: You don't want to see goatse but seeing Ron Jeremy first looking at it and trying to figure out what it is and then Backing away in horror as he realizes what it is is priceless.
Scott: Yeah, so just watch this grandma watch the disgusting video and never watch the disgusting video yourself if you can help it.
Rym: However, I guess if something worse comes out I don't know.
Scott: Maybe maybe that if there if of a worse video comes out and you and you say that the the newer video is worse I will watch this this one that is new now.
Rym: So you're gonna stay out one step say one step behind.
Rym: Well, I guess the same rule applies to a video cards and microprocessors as it does to disgusting videos something like that.
Rym: Alright, I remember way back when we were in college and we thought that but hot dog was the most disgusting thing ever made.
Scott: You know, I didn't think but hot dog was so disgusting was more humorous.
Scott: I only thought sort of an x-rated Monty Python kind of way.
Rym: I guess the only reason I didn't think it was funny I mean, I guess I could see it being funny if I knew it was faked or at least if the second half of it Was faked.
Scott: Oh all I remember was a butt and a hot dog coming out of it.
Rym: I think you forget the second half where someone eats a hot dog unawares.
Rym: I thought that that's not cool.
Scott: Yeah, I thought that that was just a guy eating a separate hot dog and was edited.
Rym: See that's the thing.
Rym: I hope it's that way that video is really funny if it's that way But if that is not in fact a cheap edit and that they did in fact feed that hot dog not cool Dude,
Scott: not cool at all
Rym: Alright, so
Scott: whenever I can't find a thing of the day There is one thing in the world that I can always rely on to provide an incredibly humorous thing of the day.
Rym: Why would this be none other than the broadcast television of the great nation of Japan?
Scott: Have you listened to GeekNights before?
Scott: All right.
Rym: So, uh, what elaborate prank did the Japanese people beset upon some poor foreigner this time?
Scott: How did you know?
Scott: was elaborate playing pulled out of order?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: a guess a hunch maybe a notion a because that's what it always is.
Rym: Sometimes they get Japanese people All right.
Scott: So, you know, there's a sport of basically speed walking and I know a lot of people are like a speed walking.
Scott: stupid Bla bla bla screw you.
Rym: it's good exercise.
Rym: It's really hard and it's while it's boring to watch It's not nearly as boring as NASCAR, right?
Scott: So basically what speed walking is?
Scott: if you don't know If you need to know what the word speed walking I'm gonna actually get tell you specifically it's.
Scott: it's not just speed walking.
Scott: You see
Rym: well it is I
Scott: know but when
Rym: a person
Scott: When a human being runs right the the gate of a human being while running There is a point at which both feet are off the ground You're basically launching yourself into the air with one foot landing with the other foot launching yourself into the air again And it you know, it's sort of like, you know horses have different gates like a trot and again
Rym: Horses have a walk trot gallop and humans have walk skip run.
Rym: I'm not gonna get into skipping.
Scott: Let's do a show on skipping.
Rym: I think we should.
Rym: yeah, because right skipping gets a bad rap.
Scott: It does awesome, right but run.
Scott: basically you're in the air completely You might you're.
Scott: basically you could even say you're jumping right?
Scott: Walking Never when you're walking are both feet off the ground.
Scott: Simultaneously only one foot is off the ground at a time and you go one foot off the ground both feet on the ground one Foot on the ground both feet on the ground, right?
Scott: So speed walking is going as fast as you can But you always have at least one foot touching the ground always and when they when people do speed walking competitions They have like Pete judges watching their feet to make sure that always one foot is on the ground.
Scott: It's a really or else you're cheating.
Rym: It's really good exercise if you care.
Scott: Yep Anyway, they have some like world champion speed walking guy from Latin America somewhere.
Rym: You sure he's not from Spain.
Scott: He might be from Spain.
Scott: He speaks Spanish Portuguese something like that.
Scott: I can't really tell.
Scott: I'm sorry.
Rym: I watched it once.
Rym: my guess is that he is Spanish from the nation of Spain But I am probably wrong and I apologize.
Scott: I have no idea.
Scott: He's Hispanic.
Scott: so he the guy.
Scott: they bring him to Japan and they don't set this up in the video.
Scott: but apparently like he had watched some TV show like they had had a TV like I guess a closed-circuit TV like and they Tricked him into thinking that there was a prison nearby and that some dangerous Shinsengumi had broken out of the prison and
Rym: they were going around killing people and they had all these extra security guards.
Scott: I saw the event.
Scott: they bring him to this track and they have him go around the track speed walking and you know He's going.
Scott: and they have these Samurai actors Shinsengumi guys and all these cops and his police.
Scott: and so they were wondering.
Scott: the question here is if you scare the Speed walking champion guy will he run or will he walk?
Rym: When Scott showed this to me and I'm watching all I could think was all right.
Rym: Is the guy Going to actually be afraid or not?
Rym: and that just comes down to.
Rym: does he know that samurai don't really exist anymore?
Rym: Has he ever watched Japanese television or does he know anything about Japan?
Scott: Yeah So basically he goes around the track the samurai come out and they cut down some guards or pretend to cut down.
Rym: Well, it's so clever.
Rym: It starts out.
Rym: We're like they walk out like ah, and they kick down like this trash can and make a bunch of noise.
Scott: They're pretty good actors.
Rym: and you see the guy Turner like he hears the noise and the video like he looks back a little bit And he sees some commotion and looks forward again.
Rym: cuz he's got to keep his pace.
Rym: It's kind of hard to speed run and Then he'd walk.
Rym: the speed walk.
Rym: Yes speed running Slow running.
Scott: Yeah, we should have the slowest running.
Scott: You have to take both feet off the ground with every step, but you can't.
Rym: was a Calvin and Hobbes about that?
Rym: I believe Hobbes just started going backwards.
Scott: Oh Anyway, I would just stand there with one foot on the ground and one foot off the ground and be like I'm still taking my first run step here.
Rym: but the moment when I like the moment of truth in this video as I'm watching it and Scott's just watching me watch it because You know that the greatest pleasure in the world after already experiencing something is watching someone else experience the exact same thing.
Rym: That's why I can watch you 10 a thousand times.
Rym: I always show it to someone new.
Rym: Yep, but He turns around a second time to see the guard being cut down by the Shinsengumi in epic fashion and At that moment you can see his face and Scott.
Rym: What was the expression on his face?
Rym: Was it?
Rym: Haha, they're playing a joke or was it?
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I'm going to die.
Scott: I think it was oh shit.
Rym: The guy was afraid he he.
Scott: Yeah, he was actually afraid of getting killed by these samurai.
Scott: So You can watch the video for yourself.
Rym: it's uh epic.
Scott: I think it's a funny video.
Rym: It's not as good as perhaps my favorite video ever which is Yordle going on top of the building while someone's using it.
Scott: That's a good one But I actually that's my second favorite.
Scott: my number one low ski slope is in in the sauna and then up You're outside in the snow.
Rym: I think the best part of the sauna one was that oh, no, you're in the snow naked But the wall goes right back up.
Rym: so you look around and you're just some idiot who's out naked in the snow.
Rym: There's no explanation for that.
Rym: someone walking by wouldn't think oh he got pranked.
Rym: Well, I guess he's in Japan.
Rym: They think well he got pranked.
Rym: Someone normal walking by would think wow that guy's naked and outside on a mountain.
Scott: What the fuck?
Scott: I just got there's nothing.
Scott: I gotta say this again.
Scott: I don't know how many times I'm gonna say this There's nothing more in this world.
Scott: Probably not much more that I want more more More than Then for someone to do a Japanese style prank show in the United States and to have a fat and dignified person get caught in It.
Rym: that reminds me of an email.
Rym: We just got.
Rym: I think I'll use that as a geek back next week.
Scott: Go for it.
Rym: But also I would just like to note kind of a rhetorical question What does it say about Japan as a nation and as a people?
Rym: Where in wherein their television will go to such lengths to find Someone who is world famous in a sport who is a foreigner discover whether or not they know if samurai exist or not and Then fly them to Japan With no goal at all other than
Scott: I think he might have been there for some speed walking competitions.
Rym: Maybe maybe not maybe not.
Rym: I would believe.
Rym: I wouldn't faze me at all If there was no purpose to this.
Rym: they had flown him out just to prank him that I would believe it.
Rym: But I don't think it's true, but just the sheer level of preparation.
Rym: My head is off.
Scott: Yes quite so.
Scott: so.
Scott: So what are we talking about?
Rym: I think it was musical instruments.
Rym: Okay, maybe we should talk about why we're talking about musical instruments.
Rym: Saxophones see tubas are nice.
Rym: I like sousaphones, but tubas are much superior.
Scott: Well, I think I can explain the musical instrument show by telling my personal history of musical instrument playing Which is which isn't too long unlike rims, which is much longer, but it does lead up to something very important that.
Rym: Actually, I kind of feel like it'd be cool If all of you kind of I don't know joined in with us on this, but we'll get to that at the very end.
Scott: Alright, so I was a little kid and when you're a little kid musical instruments you had a toy xylophone.
Scott: I had a Harmonica like it one the kind that has two rows of holes one on top of the other and then I basically couldn't play it.
Scott: When I was a kid my favorite one move it back and forth.
Rym: I had a toy trumpet that had some buttons and all you had to do was blow into the mouthpiece and it made it Like a recorder sound.
Scott: I had a record when I got to like fourth grade.
Scott: Well, actually, you know in elementary school There was a band but they're like ten kids in it because I think you had to pay a ludicrous amount of money.
Scott: I couldn't even figure out how to get into it, right?
Scott: Because You know the school wasn't paying for bands anymore.
Scott: and I think event by the time I was done with elementary school There was no more elementary school band, you know a few schools pay for musical instruments.
Scott: I mean you could join the band, but you gotta buy your trumpet, you know We had music class in elementary school But it was basically like this There's like some bongos and like a crappy little kids xylophone and maybe those.
Scott: what are those like little?
Scott: It's not like a harp but it like it lies flat and it's got a lot of strings but glockenspiel No, it's like a little tiny one for kids.
Scott: Oh Xylophone no, it's strange.
Scott: It's strings.
Scott: Oh pluck the strings.
Rym: But it's like it's a little higher a lute a banjo a guitar.
Scott: I'm maybe is it a clavichord?
Rym: Doesn't matter.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: but you know, you know, I would just play little instruments in the class or whatever.
Scott: What you know what?
Rym: I didn't even get instruments.
Rym: my music classes in elementary school consisted of either a horrible she-bitch of a nun Yelling at us.
Scott: It's not a clavichord Scott was.
Rym: Wikipedia equals win.
Rym: but Or when I finally got to you know A public elementary school where I didn't have a nun yelling at me all the time for asking questions Like how come God doesn't do this?
Rym: or what about Darwin, but I digress.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I'm trying to figure out what it is.
Scott: It's like a harpsichord, but it's like you could sit on your lap and there's no keys to sit the strings.
Scott: You just hit him with your fingers Scott a harpsichord has keys.
Rym: That's like I know but a mental part of our Looks like it looks like a harpsichord string.
Rym: That's like saying a guitar just like a piano but instead of keys You just kind of stick your hand.
Scott: anyone knows this instrument is just tell me.
Scott: but anyway All right, so that and they also made us play the recorder and everyone had to buy a recorder.
Rym: Oh Recorders that most wonderful of it actually kind of like the recorder and I would always play.
Rym: Oh, I like recorders.
Rym: I don't like being in fifth grade 40 kids who all have recorders and there's no teacher in the room or there's a substitute teacher wearing earplugs.
Scott: Yeah, and you know what?
Scott: I learned how to play on the recorder.
Rym: do hot cross bun was that hot cross bun.
Scott: I learned I learned Something.
Scott: hot cross bun Like every toy instrument I had because that's pretty much ours I can tell the easiest song to play.
Rym: and who could forget the flute?
Scott: oh yeah all right.
Rym: so we're trying to play a song on one of those doesn't happen.
Scott: no it's like clowns use it.
Scott: so I started actually playing an instrument for reals in fifth grade when I went and took guitar lessons for reals like at the YMCA.
Scott: so I went to the YMCA and there are a whole bunch of kids and this one guy taught everyone how to play guitar and I was one of like the three kids who didn't suck royally.
Scott: so we eventually they moved you know he taught the whole mess of kids at one hour and then he taught me and the two other kids who didn't suck in like the second hour you know and then eventually those two kids who are they also didn't suck.
Scott: I don't know what happened to them but I eventually like took private lessons with the guy at the local YMCA and I was playing this guitar that my grandparents had in their basement like forever.
Scott: it's like it came from like Mexico.
Scott: it was like one of those you know.
Scott: you know the kind of acoustic guitar that a Mexican guy plays in Mexican restaurant.
Scott: you know that's.
Scott: that's what it sounded like and I was okay at it but I never really practiced it and I would just go to the lesson every week you know and I would be better at it each week from the lesson.
Scott: but I wasn't practicing or trying to get better or anything and you know I I didn't really appreciate it or enjoy it as much as I you know as I should have I guess so.
Scott: in sixth grade when there was actually a band in school to join I joined the school band because the other choices they only had three choices which is music theory band and chorus and I wasn't gonna sing.
Rym: well you had to pick a music of some kind.
Scott: I had to pick one of the three.
Scott: that's great.
Scott: actually I think that more schools should do that yeah and music theory was basically the cop-out joke for people who didn't want to actually do anything.
Rym: oh man cuz music theory in my high school was oh my god middle school.
Scott: this is middle school is middle school and music theory was basically you know get to play with keyboards and MIDI kinda and not really.
Scott: so I took band and I played the clarinet because guitar was not an instrument in the band right and you know I kind of like the klezmer action.
Scott: that's that's why I chose that more than the other things plus the clarinet was cheaper than some of the other.
Scott: I guess drums are the cheapest but I actually wanted to do something that took more skills.
Rym: drums are the cheapest in that all you need to practice especially the school provided the drums.
Scott: so you just have to buy drumsticks.
Rym: that's why it was the cheapest.
Rym: also they were to made you buy a practice pad which is great ten bucks.
Rym: yeah it's a little pad and you can play like a snare drum on it but you're not gonna make a lot of noise.
Rym: make your mom kill you exactly.
Scott: so I played the clarinet and I was actually not too bad at it.
Rym: you know I was what now clarinets a good choice because if you want to be all cool with it it's not a far cry to go from clarinet to soprano saxophone.
Rym: well which is awesome.
Scott: I should.
Scott: I could have just chosen saxophone right.
Rym: no you don't want it all the kid.
Rym: it seems like a lot of people who get into music with their kids.
Rym: they're like they look and they don't think about what they'd actually want to play or what they'd be good at.
Rym: they think about what looks cool and what looks cooler than either a gigantic tuba that's bigger than you or maybe a drum set even though to give you a drum.
Scott: so why is it always that the really like tall people who play the trombone?
Rym: I don't get it you know what I'll get to that because there are there's in people who play music not just in like high schools and whatever that I know.
Rym: a lot of you are in high school in college and playing in bands but even out in the real gig.
Rym: in world there's kind of stereotypes about who plays different instruments and I don't know if it's.
Scott: I think this is psychology of it like personality and you look at the instruments like the way they look appeals to a certain personality.
Scott: so when you aren't already a musician and you're thinking about and you're thinking about becoming one you look at the instruments and different looks and sounds of different instruments appeal to different types of see.
Scott: I don't know because it makes sense.
Scott: that's just my the other my other.
Rym: it might be a kind of self-perpetuating cycle where the people who get kids into music and the people who know music and teach music the way they teach different instruments appeal to different kinds of people more due to the instruction and the culture could be possible too.
Rym: but everyone wants to play the goddamn saxophone.
Scott: yes there are a lot more sack.
Scott: if the band teacher had chosen like I need this many this and this many this and this many this to get the best sound which we did there would have been a far fewer.
Scott: sad as middle school there had been far fewer sex.
Rym: I'm talking about middle school.
Rym: okay you realize pretty much everyone wanted to play the saxophone in my middle school and they said they're only going to be 12 saxophone players.
Rym: we are going to choose based on it.
Rym: well I'll get to that anyway.
Scott: so I played the clarinet and I played the clarinet for three years and I didn't really practice it.
Scott: but despite my almost complete lack of practicing I was able to play all the songs for all the concerts and I was one of the like top three clarinet people in the middle school and in high school.
Scott: the first year sort of by momentum I kept playing but I didn't want to join the marching band and they basically came down to the middle school and they were like join the marching band and I was like uh and I you know I thought about it.
Scott: I was like I don't want to do that right now I'll go to high school and I'll play in the.
Scott: you could play in the concert band which is basically more of this.
Scott: you know the same thing only you know in high school with the high school people and I'm like if I want to do the marching band I'll just start in the second year whatever right and in high school I just sort of got really disinterested entirely.
Scott: I was like oh yeah I don't really care so much about this anymore and I was still like one of the top five people in the concert band with the clarinet and there's reasons for that.
Scott: yeah because I actually you know I knew how to read music and play it and I played well and I tried.
Scott: it just didn't practice in my spare time or enjoy it very much.
Scott: so I didn't join the marching band and after my first year of high school playing the clarinet I gave up the clarinet and then I didn't play a musical instrument for a while.
Scott: and the problem was right.
Scott: is that in my later high school years like starting in 11th and 12th grade I realized I had made a miscalculation earlier in my life?
Scott: oh yes you see remember in fifth grade I played that guitar with that guy.
Scott: I know I was not appreciating very much.
Scott: and then in sixth grade I picked up the clarinet instead and I dropped the guitar.
Scott: and then by ninth grade I was not appreciating that either.
Scott: but starting around 11th grade I started to appreciate the guitar a lot more but I did not know how to play it anymore and I thought well all those awesome guitar people they've been playing since they were like three.
Scott: what's the point?
Scott: even starting now I can't even afford a guitar.
Scott: that old one was like piece of shit and the neck is all warped and whatever.
Scott: and it's I don't have time for it's not gonna happen.
Scott: even though I was sort of basically I didn't really have the urge to start playing the guitar even though I thought it would be fun to like have an electric guitar with the distortion all up and start you know just hitting the strings to make it go down.
Scott: I thought that'd be cool.
Scott: but other than that I didn't really want to learn or have time or care.
Scott: but I was sort of sort of sad that I lost the opportunity to.
Scott: I was I kept thinking like man if I had not stopped playing the guitar I'll be badass right now.
Scott: damn it yeah because even people and this is like think about it if I hadn't stopped ever right now like the podcast would be like opening and closing with Scott rocking out I'd be like the only reason.
Rym: it's not Rym on a trumpet it's just that I haven't played the trumpet much in the last I don't know three years.
Scott: yeah I mean I was really good at learning musical instruments.
Scott: I had a skill I wasn't like a you know sort of a awesome kind of gonna be the best in the world you know Steve Vai kind of amazingness.
Scott: but I was good at learning musical instruments and playing them.
Scott: I just didn't enjoy it so much when I was young so I gave it up and then I was upset later that I gave it up.
Scott: so recently I've been thinking you know I don't get to tell my story.
Scott: oh you want to tell your story first I do and then and then I'll do the.
Rym: recently I think we should.
Rym: we want to end on the the important part.
Rym: okay cuz the important part is kind of cool all right.
Scott: so tell your story.
Rym: we've gone on a while because we talked a lot in the beginning.
Rym: that's fine.
Rym: so I'm gonna give up.
Rym: whatever people enjoy this episode I think yeah I think they will but I'm still.
Rym: I'll qualify all this by saying that I'm going to give a very abbreviated history because unlike Scott it's not just that I was really into music or I was good at it or anything but I was into music to the point that I was very close to going to school for music and be a professional musician.
Rym: instead of going into computers I had a full ride to Arizona State and a couple other places with band scholarship whatever and I was pretty much 50/50 computers trumpets and I kind of chose to go to RIT and I kind of chose to do IT and all that stuff kind of on a total whim.
Rym: uh-huh.
Rym: but to skip all my early childhood where you know my parents bought me a million million instruments and I had a harmonica and I had a recorder and I had an ocarina and I had a little electric keyboard a Casio and
Scott: then I had a little tiny electric keyboard too but I couldn't play for shit.
Scott: actually we had a real piano in my.
Scott: we still have that piano in my house.
Scott: it's not a grand piano it's the stand-up tall kind that you always see in saloons and I think my grandmother bought it like a zillion years ago.
Scott: well I guess not a zillion but you know 50 years ago did they either paid $50 or like $500 for I think was $500 for that piano way back which is a ludicrous price for a piano.
Scott: of course I think these are like.
Rym: you know how much pianos cost a lot yeah which is why it was a great price.
Rym: okay ludicrous isn't good.
Rym: for some reason I was thinking ludicrous of course.
Scott: I think those are like 1960s dollars or not maybe even 1950s I don't know.
Scott: but we still have the piano.
Scott: it's still in tune.
Scott: my brother took piano lessons and then he stopped too and he was in the marching band whatever but they don't care brother suffice to say I really like.
Rym: I played the piano a lot and by playing the piano even my grandma had this old Hammond organ and I had a Casio keyboard and I just sit there kind of banging on it and trying to make it sound good and
Scott: I could never make my little Casio keyboard sound good.
Rym: well it didn't for a long time.
Rym: but I kind of taught myself music by ear and I started like I didn't know any words for two terms forward but I knew the difference between major keys and minor keys and I'd kind of figured out a lot of it on my own as a kid.
Scott: see at when I learned to play musical instruments basically all I did was I was I taught myself to look at musical notes you know musical score and translate that into the you know movements of my hands and mouth or whatever to actually make that music play.
Scott: I never understood or learned the music theory or any of that.
Scott: majors minors that stuff still completely eludes me I don't get it.
Rym: see I started I never tried to learn I never understood it and I think that for most people to be to become great as opposed to just good.
Rym: that is beyond a requirement not just to know it but to I would say start with that at least a basic understanding of being I mean I guess there's talent in skill and I think you can get skilled.
Rym: you can probably be the best instrument player in the world on all skill or all talent.
Rym: but I feel like having the talent or even building up the skill first of being able to kind of hear and play by ear and just understand what sounds good and what doesn't even if you don't necessarily understand why.
Rym: but just knowing kind of intuitively what will sound good will make you a much better musician in the long run.
Scott: yeah I had nothing.
Scott: all I could do is look at notes on paper or look at some sort of you know thing on you know some sort of symbology and then you know figure out which you know mechanics that I had to perform to make that turn into music.
Scott: and that's all I ever learned.
Scott: but I was really good at it.
Rym: yeah but I mean I dabbled in the piano and I still dabble.
Rym: I consider myself a mediocre piano player at best.
Rym: I would say so well I can play by ear I just I can't.
Rym: I don't have piano skill I have music skills so I know what chords I know what melody or I know what I want.
Rym: but basically I had my left hand just kind of bangs itself against the keyboard ineffectively but my real instrument that.
Rym: the reason I really got into music was that you know fourth grade fifth grade it's time to pick an instrument going to the band because it's.
Rym: it was pretty much a foregone conclusion for my parents that I was going to join the band in school.
Rym: so we had Mr.
Rym: Danforth who was this ancient, gigantically fat man who was a professional musician for most of his life and was in the military band and fought in World War II I'll get to why that was important and he wore.
Rym: every time we had a concert.
Rym: I remember he wore a tuxedo that was perhaps one second at any time from exploding.
Scott: is that why you always see that joke on Looney Tunes?
Scott: like the guys were in the tux the conductor and like the front part just like rolls up like this guy.
Rym: was that guy awesome?
Rym: but he taught in a very old school way.
Rym: very lives very this kind of like Prussian military band style.
Rym: but he came to our elementary school.
Rym: he's like are you kids?
Rym: we're gonna figure out what instruments you're good at and then if you want to join the band I'm gonna tell you what you're gonna play and you had to apply to play an instrument.
Rym: so pretty much the people who he based on his years of experience thought would be the best at X instrument would be the ones playing X instrument and you had no say at all other than you kind of had like a second choice.
Rym: but if you wanted to play the saxophone and he already decided that six other kids were better at the saxophone than you you weren't gonna play the saxophone no matter what your parents yelled and screamed about mm-hmm.
Rym: and I had this realization because he brought one of every instrument and one of every mouthpiece.
Rym: he passed them all out and I had a clarinet read and I went and nothing happened.
Rym: he didn't really tell us what to do.
Rym: we just kind of wanted to see who could figure it out intuitively.
Rym: give you a trumpet mouthpiece and I thought I have a trumpet at home that toy trumpet because I was a little kid and I blew in it and it went.
Rym: yep that wasn't what I had to do.
Rym: no and basically no one made any noises except some squeaking awful awful noises from the saxophone mouthpieces and two people broke oboe reeds before he stopped handing those out.
Rym: so then he explains how to play them all and we pass them all around again and I wasn't able to make anything sound except the trumpet.
Rym: I made a trumpet buzz it went and it sounded kind of like a little fart.
Rym: and then after we did all this he administered all these tests where we had to listen to two notes and say if they were different.
Rym: basically he was testing to see if any of us had perfect pitch and if you had perfect pitch you were guaranteed a spot in the band no matter what.
Rym: and then from there he kind of.
Rym: he basically tested us to see who would be a good musician and he wouldn't let anyone else join the band.
Rym: yeah and then we had to rank what instruments we wanted to play and he matched that up based on how good he thought we were and some other factors.
Rym: and my logic for playing the trumpet was very simple being a fourth grader or fifth grader I forget which might have been fifth grade he's.
Rym: I said to myself all right saxophone has like 40 buttons trombone has no buttons but it's not discreet and I'm worried by that.
Rym: off tube is too big.
Rym: all those things are too big.
Rym: that trumpet only has three buttons.
Rym: how hard could it be?
Rym: yeah so I wanted to be a trumpet player and that is what began my illustrious career.
Rym: now the funny thing is I learned later after a few weeks.
Rym: one day he went around the room and he talked about how the old school away like how when he was a kid you know in like 1700 how you would decide who would play an instrument.
Rym: and he went down the line of trumpet players and he pointed at us one by one and he's like trombone clarinet trombone.
Rym: you wouldn't be in a band you'd be an English trumpet player.
Rym: what's that mean?
Rym: it means you'd be bad yeah.
Rym: and he said like three of us would be trumpet players and I was one of them.
Rym: and then he did the same thing for the saxophones the tubas and everything.
Rym: and then at the end he started explaining why.
Rym: and basically being good at a brass instrument and this seems to be fairly true comes down a lot to not necessarily practice or skill or talent.
Rym: but what kind of lips you were born with?
Scott: well couldn't you?
Scott: that's something I never understood.
Scott: it's like okay obviously better lips.
Scott: you know different kind of shape you're better at playing the instrument.
Scott: it's more than just you make a different mouthpiece that would accommodate different lips.
Rym: see you can and that you're all sorts of kinds of mouthpieces.
Rym: the problem is there's trade-offs in both directions and if you have quote-unquote crappy lips for playing the trumpet or the trombone you can still make a trombone make a trombone noise but it's not gonna sound good.
Rym: it's gonna be bad tone usually and you can try to train yourself but if your lips aren't thick enough or whatever you're probably gonna hurt yourself.
Rym: there are a lot of people who play the trumpet or some instrument and they cause permanent nerve damage or otherwise damage themselves from playing an instrument just because their lips weren't strong enough or thick enough or whatever to deal with the insane amount of pressure they were applying.
Rym: and they were applying that pressure because they didn't have the whatever to actually do it properly.
Rym: they couldn't make a proper embouchure and I guess you could try to make some fancy sort of mouthpiece or some special instrument but there are reasons why that doesn't work so well and I should probably skip all that because I could go on for hours about the theory of making a proper trumpet embouchure.
Rym: all right I'll say.
Rym: however that is very similar to the proper embouchure for an oboe mm-hmm.
Rym: surprisingly but yeah skip a whole bunch.
Rym: I was real good at the trumpet real good I got to high school and I went to a high school that was different from the high school I should have gone to because my family moved so they wouldn't let me play the trumpet.
Rym: there were already like 30 trumpet players because we were a really big marching band.
Rym: so I had to play the mellophone which is basically a bastardized French horn that you.
Rym: that kind of looks like a flugelhorn that you play in a marching band even though cool people can march with a French horn but you probably shouldn't.
Rym: anyway I'll skip all that and I was real good at it.
Rym: and then after that you know marching season ends and we have to audition to join the band again.
Rym: it's not just like a lot of schools kind of like my middle school was I guess I was lucky where if you want to be in the band you're in the band.
Rym: no you had to audition and if you weren't good as in pretty damn good you were in the concert band which basically meant you're not going anywhere.
Rym: you're gonna play kind of crappy music forever.
Rym: people get a credit and that's it.
Rym: or the symphonic band which was the real band or the wind ensemble which was the really real band that went all over the country and by all over the country I mean pretty much to like five different places and Toronto.
Scott: yeah see our high school had all sorts of different bands like they had the symphonic band and the jazz band and whatever.
Scott: right but all like the symphonic band was pretty much the marching band.
Scott: people sit down and do a concert for part of the year when it's not marching band season and the jazz band was the guys in the marching band who think they're really cool also do a jazz band part of the year.
Scott: you know it was all the same people.
Rym: our high school jazz band played gigs for money.
Scott: yeah ours they all just did concerts at the school.
Scott: you know whatever.
Rym: actually we did a lot of concerts at like local venues as real event.
Scott: they might date.
Scott: I mean they went around and did stuff but I don't really know about it cuz I wasn't paying attention to them.
Rym: yeah but there was.
Rym: there's a lot of.
Rym: I mean Michigan and the Midwest are really big on marching band.
Rym: like marching band is a big deal for a lot of people out there.
Rym: so I was hardcore into the marching band.
Rym: and there's also a lot of non marching just competition like the MSBOA and all these sorts of people would compete all over the place in music and there's similar things in most states in the country.
Rym: there's probably similar things all over the world and all over everywhere.
Rym: but I played this kind of easy song my freshman year in high school with two other trumpet players.
Rym: the three of us were pretty much to quote our band director the only people who actually had a chance of being professionals in the whole school not counting the drummer but that's it.
Rym: that's a whole fun story mm-hmm.
Rym: and we played this thing called buglers holiday which is a fun little song that a lot of trumpet players play when they're young.
Rym: and we played it in a little competition and we were freshmen.
Rym: and this guy walks in after.
Rym: we're just kind of practicing in the room before and he introduces himself as kind of a recruiter for the University of Michigan and he's looking for people to give scholarships to to come play in the marching band and full rides.
Rym: and when he found out that three of us were freshmen he basically said holy shit.
Rym: yeah here's my card.
Rym: call me back in a few years and we'll talk all right.
Rym: and yeah I'll just stop there because this is probably kind of boring.
Rym: I keep skipping things as a result.
Rym: I'm probably telling the boring parts but I was super into music.
Rym: I was super good at the trumpet and I got to find some videos of like the marching band stuff or some of the solos or fun things I did.
Rym: but suffice to say I chose computers instead of music.
Rym: and here I am right.
Scott: so today the situation is such that well I'm basically not playing any music.
Scott: I like music you know kinda and not like super.
Scott: music like Rym is like 10 times more music than I am but yeah I'm more music than the most people I know.
Rym: yeah I mean you don't sit down in front of the piano every day and try to learn how to play it better.
Scott: no but you know I like it and playing it.
Scott: I guess I appreciate it more now than I did then and I'm still kind of upset that I didn't keep playing the guitar since fifth grade because I'd be super rocking out right now which I would totally like.
Scott: and guitar hero doesn't help that at all.
Scott: it in fact hurts that a lot.
Scott: so I said you know what if I would have started playing in fifth grade.
Scott: right that would've been what fifth grade.
Scott: and now I'm in what the the 12 13 14.
Scott: I'm in the 19th grade.
Scott: so it is only like maybe 15 years or so of you know maybe 14 15 years now granted you're discounting the whole.
Rym: well brains change as you get older harder to learn things.
Scott: I am discounting that but basically the equivalent of playing for those 14 years.
Scott: well if I start playing now right I'm 25 by the time I'm like 40 I think I could be rocking out don't you god of rock ever or anything.
Scott: that's pretty much a foregone conclusion.
Scott: but I could be playing songs and then you know having fun and doing cool stuff at least entertaining friends and people on the internet and making music for the show or whatever.
Scott: so I said hey that's not too bad.
Scott: but then I looked on the internet.
Scott: I said you know what guitars are expensive.
Scott: I mean you could buy like a cheap piece of shit nylon string whatever.
Scott: but if I'm gonna do something I'm gonna do it for real.
Scott: you know I'm not gonna do something half-ass or crappy it's I'm gonna do it.
Scott: I'm gonna do it.
Scott: and I kind of wasn't sure that if I bought a guitar that I would actually practice I felt like I'm gonna go online and I'm gonna buy some like $200 guitar and an amp and whatever and it's gonna sit there on a little stand.
Scott: that cost me 30 bucks or I don't know how much stands cost.
Scott: it's gonna sit in my room.
Rym: I've got a stand.
Rym: you can have it.
Scott: a guitar stand.
Rym: well no I've got a music stand.
Scott: I have a guitar stand.
Scott: probably music stand even more money right and I'm gonna buy some book that tells me how to play or something or watch who knows and it's gonna sit there and I'm not gonna do it and I'm gonna look at it every day.
Scott: sit in my room some awesome guitar you know and I'm not gonna play it and I'm just gonna feel really bad about spending a lot of money on something I don't use and it's gonna suck.
Scott: so I said you know what I got a better idea.
Scott: yeah I went and I said well is there some way that I can sort of prove that if I buy the guitar I will actually practice it?
Scott: because if I can prove to myself that if I bought one I would actually learn it then I buy one.
Rym: well you've been playing the plastic guitar quite a bit.
Scott: yeah that helps a little bit.
Scott: yeah maybe if there was a piece of software like guitar hero but it actually taught you how to play real guitar.
Rym: yeah you realize something like that is the holy grail of making infinite money.
Scott: well there makes.
Scott: I think there's some project to make something like that for the piano.
Rym: yeah people have been trying that forever and it's never really been successful or good.
Scott: yeah but anyway I need to prove to myself that I would actually practice before I would go and spend the money on the guitar.
Scott: so I was trying to figure out what to do to do that and sort of the solution sort of came to me through multiple means.
Scott: basically I listen to this podcast the Roadhouse.
Scott: I actually pay for this podcast.
Scott: it's like 20 bucks a year something and I get no ads in it and I get an extra song every week which is awesome.
Scott: but it's blues music and I like these blues music and I'd probably play blues guitar if I got a guitar and I was listening to blues music and I heard a guy playing the harmonica not too uncommon in the blues music the harmonica and typically a blues instrument more than anything else and I it sort of dawned on me hey harmonicas are cheap really cheap.
Scott: it's like you could get one for like three dollars.
Scott: I could play the harmonica.
Scott: I know how to play instruments where you blow into them and it can't be that hard right I mean well.
Scott: so I said you know what I I'm gonna go and do some research on harmonica play and on YouTube I found this video that basically convinced me and I should we link to the video?
Rym: I think we should.
Rym: there's this cool guy.
Rym: send it to me again cuz I don't have the link.
Scott: it's a cool guy on YouTube and his YouTube name is night train James which is a cool name and he used to be a marine and he learned to play the harmonica when he was in the Marines back in the day.
Scott: and he seems like a pretty cool guy.
Scott: and is this little video convinced me cuz I was looking up like which harmonica to buy and everything and all that stuff.
Scott: and this video told me what to buy and everything and convinced me that playing the harmonica was gonna be a good test.
Scott: so I went out and I bought a harmonica exactly the one this guy told me to.
Rym: yeah well beyond that Scott basically came to me and said watch this video.
Rym: and I said okay and I watch it.
Rym: then he's like let's learn how to play the harmonica.
Scott: yep so we bought harmonicas and I convinced Rym to get one.
Scott: I convinced Alex to get one too.
Scott: I don't know he's playing it but and I got it and I started trying to learn it.
Scott: I'm not I can't actually play it super good yet but I have played like simple songs you know like camp town races and you I haven't heard you I can play can tell will you play something for our listeners?
Scott: no no no I'll play some because I learn also figured out that listening to harmonica's live is painful.
Rym: it's not painful if you're far away or it's part of a band or and I don't find it that painful.
Rym: I think you're just not your father's.
Scott: it bothers me at least at least when you play.
Scott: the noise it makes is bothersome.
Scott: nah I guess it was also bothersome when you played the trumpet.
Scott: so maybe it's just Rym.
Scott: playing musical instruments of any kind bothers me.
Scott: I think what whether he's doing well or not it's just.
Rym: I think what has to do with it is how loud it is.
Scott: something like that.
Rym: I mean my trumpet with like the super silencer mutant is still kind of loud in this house.
Scott: so basically here's the thing.
Scott: I'm playing the harmonica and I'm putting some amount of my time as much time as I feel like I haven't heard you play the harmonica in a while.
Scott: I've been playing it just when you're not there when it's unlike you I play instruments with no one's around so I don't bother anybody.
Scott: but when I get home before you when you're not here when I was always here over Thanksgiving I was home for like two days alone over the one weekend.
Scott: there were other times when I'm home and no one's here.
Rym: so the last time you played the harmonicas over the weekend yeah I've actually been playing it pretty much every single day since we bought him.
Scott: well obviously this is why you were much more the music than me because you have much more of the practice.
Scott: motivation.
Scott: yeah
Rym: well part of it too and Scott actually didn't believe me but I did try to learn the harmonica as a kid and I own a harmonica maybe two I don't remember if that was mine or my brother's yeah and I was awful at it like really awful cuz I didn't get lessons or anything really.
Rym: I just tried to learn lessons.
Scott: now you're lying.
Rym: I try to learn from a book.
Scott: uh-huh.
Scott: you said you got lessons before.
Rym: well I got lessons from a book uh-huh.
Rym: anyway I was awful at it and I gave it up pretty much right away and I never got past going bitty bitty bitty bitty bitty bitty up and down in harmonica.
Scott: that I was able to do that when I was like three and I had a harmonica that somehow made its way into my toy closet.
Rym: but it's actually it's really really easy to play the harmonica at least to play simple songs and play almost anything.
Rym: on a diatonic harmonica ten hole diets.
Rym: yeah if you know about music if you know music theory and you know what you what sound you want to make and you know why you want to make those sounds it's so easy to play.
Rym: the harmonica.
Scott: thing is it's only got ten holes which is like 20 notes but then you can bend to get a few more notes but there aren't really.
Scott: there are a lot of songs that you sort of can't play on the at least a C key harmonica.
Scott: you need to get harmonic is in other keys to play other songs.
Rym: yeah but at the same time you can play a lot.
Scott: you can play a lot you can play enough.
Scott: so here's the thing.
Scott: I'm gonna keep playing the harmonica you know basically as much as I have been.
Scott: and if I'm still playing it and I'm still harmonica ing like a year from now or you know and I feel like I've actually learned it and like I could play video game songs on it or whatever and I'm not comfortable just like whipping it out and playing a song or whatever then I'll buy a guitar.
Scott: otherwise I realize that I'll just probably I'll consign myself to do the fact that I while I might like to play a musical instrument and like the idea of it I will never actually invest the amount of time into it to make it worth it
Rym: and
Scott: I'll give up.
Rym: our real goal now is to get good enough to play a lot of really geeky music.
Scott: that is my goal.
Scott: that's pretty much my line.
Rym: how cool would that be?
Rym: you're walking around some anime con and you see a bunch of guys just rocking out on blues versions of some anime song in the artist's alley.
Scott: if I reach that point I'll buy a guitar for sure.
Rym: so uh gonna practice.
Rym: yeah I gotta play something for there are for our listeners.
Rym: I know they want to hear it.
Rym: well they could stuff but they want to hear it they want to play harmonica and record it.
Scott: you need like that little ball microphone thing don't?
Rym: what do you think?
Rym: that ball microphone thing is Scott?
Scott: it's a special microphone for harmonica's.
Rym: uh-huh yeah no yeah yeah actually Scott our microphone right here is great for recording harmonica.
Rym: remember the microphones.
Rym: we use our instrument mics.
Rym: you can mic pretty much any instrument with this.
Scott: yeah whatever I'm not playing right now wait till I get better.
Rym: so all right all right but yeah my entreaty to all of you is that if you're cool at all you should buy a 10-hole diatonic key of C harmonica.
Rym: Lee Oscar I think is the one that we bought.
Scott: yeah you can also buy I don't know.
Scott: there's like three or four different companies that make them by the Lee Oscar.
Rym: what is that?
Scott: the Hauner the Hauner Marine Band is the other one.
Scott: you can get Hauner H o h n er marine band 10 and I think we as long as it's a 10-hole diatonic key of C harmonica.
Scott: that's what's important.
Rym: I think we should all learn the harmonica together and then whenever there is any crowd of GeekNights listeners much like if there's ever a crowd of one two three four five six seven eight nine or possibly ten naked men.
Rym: a heap of trouble is sure to come about for all concerns.
Scott: I can also play doo-doo-doo doo-doo-doo-doo-dee but I can't play the solo part where they're like going doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo.
Rym: I can't do that.
Rym: We should have some dueling harmonicas perhaps at the New York Anime Festival.
Scott: no I don't know.
Scott: maybe how about Katsu-Kan?
Scott: that's a better chance.
Rym: Think we'll have something for katsuka.
Rym: remember we're doing a late show at Katsucon.
Scott: yeah that'd be a good time.
Rym: we should bust out the harmonicas.
Scott: then we should have some sort of dueling nerd harmonic.
Scott: let's.
Rym: uh let's commit to that now on the air.
Scott: no why not?
Scott: and I committing ultimate I'll commit.
Scott: the whole point of this is to determine if I am at the committing ability.
Scott: I'm not gonna.
Scott: if I was gonna commit now I would be like buying a Stratocaster online or something not a Telecaster I don't know.
Scott: I have no idea.
Scott: I just name of a guitar.
Scott: I know what the.
Scott: I wouldn't even know what guitar to buy it after research.
Scott: that too all right.
Rym: yeah we went on long.
Rym: that's all I got.
Rym: it's Thursday.
Rym: I need some sleep and I made dinner.
Rym: yet.
Scott: yeah let's go eat.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feed plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays we have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: you can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.