Scott: It's Tuesday August 7th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we talked about our personal preferences for first-person shooter key bindings.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So not too long after we did a show about how it's not video game season It's video game season.
Rym: well at least for Scott.
Rym: I'm not quite there yet.
Scott: You're not quite there.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Rym: I'm mostly reading books and doing computer stuff.
Scott: Yeah, I'm doing that stuff too, but I have definitely Significantly decreased the German board gaming and I significantly decreased the anime watching and the video gaming has Snuck up in there.
Rym: see I've actually increased my video game not my video game at God my anime watching and The only reason we haven't been playing board games is that we've been busy.
Scott: Yep, and when it seems Maybe that's what it is is that when we're too busy to play board games You only have time for a video game in there because the board game you got to get a bunch of people to sit around for a few hours and Ds can go just about anywhere at any time.
Rym: it also didn't help that we usually only play board games now on the weekends and Last weekend I did stuff mostly GeekNights stuff and this this weekend probably also doing stuff like playing video games.
Rym: I'm actually foreseeing the board game.
Rym: I mean the only video game.
Rym: I want to play is the new strikers game We picked up finally.
Scott: Yep, we got to pick that up.
Scott: I'm also playing Dynamite heady and the original paper Mario on the virtual console, which are like the only two things on the virtual console worth the money and There's a bunch of stuff.
Scott: I'm gonna talk about in my news that I'm also playing.
Scott: so and Ds action with the pokemons and the planet puzzle leagues, etc.
Rym: See I'd started playing Pokemon again at the shore, but I got sick of that real quick.
Scott: You're planning yesterday.
Rym: For actually I was playing it for a little bit yesterday and then I swapped back in advance wars I'm just saying you when you did play it.
Scott: I heard it on.
Rym: Yep Never more than like 15 minutes at a time.
Rym: I can't stomach more than 15 minutes of Pokemon.
Scott: I know I was.
Scott: I'm actually playing leaf green on the train again just to beat it.
Rym: Oh fire red is so much more fun than the DS.
Scott: Well, I know at least for single-player action It's so much better just because the combat is a reasonable speed or at least it feels like a reasonable speed.
Scott: Compared to diamond and pearl it's.
Rym: it's a lot faster and my little dude walks a lot faster and the plot is more plotty.
Scott: And it's the original Pokemon plot for the original Pokemon game.
Scott: It's every Pokemon plot since then has just been not as good because it's always the same.
Rym: It's alright your kid Here's your first Pokemon pick one of the three.
Rym: Oh, no, you have a rival.
Rym: Oh, we picked the one that's strong against you.
Rym: then you go out and catch your otata and then you go off on your adventure.
Scott: I don't catch your otata or a Pidgey.
Rym: Ah, in fact, I caught a Pidgey and leveled it all the way up.
Scott: See I go and I use my main guy and I go straight for the bug forest and I get me.
Rym: bugs are crap.
Rym: There's no good bug Pokemon, uh butter free butter free can lick my balls.
Rym: dust ox.
Rym: Dust ox is worse than butter for that Scorpion thing that turns into the bigger scorpion thing is a bug Pokemon soccer.
Scott: You suck bug Pokemon own you.
Rym: I don't like bugs.
Scott: It's the one that looks like Mothra except bees and I don't like home be.
Scott: you know combi is probably the only bug Pokemon I respect but Combi evolves is only the female combis and actually I would use a male combi because I don't like the Vespa Quinn thing.
Scott: It's ugly Whatever.
Scott: No more Pokemon stock today, whatever.
Rym: So what do you got in the news?
Scott: Only like the biggest gaming news in a zillion years I will admit.
Rym: Scott came running when he read this and told me and it was a big deal.
Rym: and I was real excited until the cynical side of my brain said wait a minute Rym There's no way that this is exactly what you actually want.
Rym: and upon further questioning.
Rym: It's not my fault You want something that's pretty much in feasible and impossible and I think the real question is it's not your fault that The only reason I wanted it is for that?
Rym: if it's not if it doesn't have the thing that it doesn't have Then I don't give one shit about it because I already own most of those games.
Scott: That's your problem.
Scott: Anyway, so You may know that there are many video games made by a company called id software mostly Wolfenstein doom quake Wolfenstein doom quake mostly but also commander keen Heretic and hex in quake to quake to drink to doom to doom 3.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yes Yes, I got to say that in all those things It seems like the twos were the best in every series.
Rym: Mmm, quake 3 was garbage.
Rym: doom 3 was slightly less garbage.
Rym: doom 2 best FPS ever I guess.
Scott: I guess so, I guess on average the twos are much better I mean quake 2 compared to quake 1 or 3.
Rym: It's better than both.
Scott: I'm coming.
Scott: I mean all the commander Kean's are good.
Rym: Anyway, I don't.
Rym: keen is a whole different world.
Scott: So it's off plus up.
Rym: who's in doom - doom guy?
Rym: No, who else?
Scott: John Romero who else?
Scott: Commander keen that's right.
Scott: Anyway, so id software makes all these games.
Scott: These are very important games in the world of PC gaming and gaming in general.
Scott: Yeah Super important.
Rym: regardless of what a lot of people say Wolfenstein was really the first FPS.
Rym: Doom was I would argue the first good FPS.
Scott: You suck.
Rym: I don't like Wolfenstein.
Rym: I suck.
Scott: It's Wolfenstein isn't while it looks like an FPS a shooting game.
Scott: It is actually a maze game a maze.
Scott: Find your way around.
Scott: Oh find the secret doors Like the treasure.
Scott: really two-dimensional mostly not well In fact, unless if you want to complain it was no more two-dimensional than then doom.
Rym: No, because Wolfenstein couldn't have angles of walls that differed by anything.
Rym: It had to be 90 degrees or 180 degrees.
Rym: Yeah, I couldn't have angles or anything interesting.
Rym: You couldn't have elevators.
Rym: It was amazing.
Scott: Doom didn't have real elevation because if you show what though it had effective elevation.
Scott: It wasn't effective.
Scott: You didn't have to aim up or down.
Rym: No, you didn't have to aim, but you still had to take that into account in the puzzles.
Scott: Not really.
Rym: Yes, you did.
Scott: You could have flat.
Scott: you could flatten any doom map.
Rym: Yeah, you can but you still had to take it into account because while technically it's only 2d and the third dimension is just a coordinate number that doesn't actually do anything.
Rym: the fact remains that the imp looks higher and He's up on that ledge and you can't get up on that ledge unless you find a lift to get up there.
Scott: Anyway the point is id software makes a lot of these games so they did and It has been very difficult for a long period of time to play a lot of these games Legally or at all.
Rym: well except for you know, doom Right doom to quake quake -.
Rym: well
Scott: The problem is is that while the source code to many of these games is freely available The actual levels the wad files or what-have-you are owned by id software and if you want them legally you had to pay for them and Sometimes it was hard to get them if you didn't own them already and a lot of the DOS games Were difficult to play because you don't have a computer with DOS and they don't run just out of the box in Windows XP all the time.
Scott: so you need to set up some sort of emulation with DOS box or something like that like that.
Scott: and You know these very important games in gaming history were pretty much Unavailable to the gaming public for a long period of time.
Scott: I mean there was if I remember just less than a year ago.
Scott: I went to id software's website and they were like, yeah, you want Wolfenstein 3d legally.
Scott: give us 20 bucks.
Scott: It's like 20 bucks.
Scott: Are you out of your mind?
Rym: But I thought this was an important game.
Rym: I thought this was a big not worth 20 bucks.
Rym: Oh, I see how the die rolls.
Rym: I see how you roll.
Rym: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: So Id software announced that they were.
Scott: this is huge pretty much putting not just some but all of their games ever on steam as of Immediately.
Scott: right now you can get every id game on steam.
Scott: right now this second They're there and you can buy them and they work.
Scott: and not only can you buy them individually like for example Let's see Wolfenstein 3d cost five dollars.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: That's a nice price.
Scott: But you can buy them in packs.
Scott: They have like an all quake pack That is all the quakes an all doom pack.
Scott: That is all the dooms and all wolfenstein back.
Scott: there's all the wolfensteins, etc, etc.
Scott: and those packs are pretty discounted compared to buying all the doom separately or all the quake separately, but they also have the everything super pack which if you buy it it costs you $70.
Scott: and If you had bought all the games it includes individually on steam that would cost $214.
Rym: now think of that $70.
Rym: That's what I paid for Zelda 2 when it came out.
Rym: the day it came out.
Scott: just Zelda 2 just Zelda to me.
Scott: Let me read the list of things you're getting for your $70 ready every commander keen.
Scott: Doom 3 the new the really new Doom 3.
Scott: Doom 3 expansion resurrection of evil.
Scott: Doom 2 final doom heretic with the expansion hex and hex into hex in something else expansion.
Scott: master levels for doom 2. quake.
Scott: quake 2. quake 2 expansion.
Scott: another quake 2 Expansion.
Rym: quake 3 or quake 2 expansions.
Scott: there was quake 2 mission pack ground zero and quake 2 mission pack the reckoning.
Rym: I'll bet those are awful because I got to say quake 2 was not a game.
Rym: Quake 1 wasn't even a game.
Rym: there was the single player was garbage.
Rym: those games existed solely to be modded and into better games.
Scott: Pretty much quake 3 arena.
Scott: quake 3 team arena.
Scott: quake mission pack 1. quake mission pack 2.
Scott: Wow Expansions for quake 1. look at that return to castle Wolfenstein.
Scott: That's the newer Wolfenstein with the flamethrowers and stuff spear of destiny, which is the sequel to Wolfenstein 3d.
Scott: it's basically the same as Wolfenstein 3 only a really hard maps and ultimate doom.
Scott: and Wolfenstein 3d.
Scott: $70 but is more.
Scott: if you buy it now and you don't hesitate sound like an infomercial.
Scott: I know.
Scott: right if you buy it now and you don't hesitate that's $63 not 70 now.
Rym: while I am NOT personally excited about it This is a big deal and most of you out there should probably buy this.
Scott: I couldn't resist.
Scott: I was just like well now or never by.
Scott: the only thing that's missing here is the new quake for which I guess is not You know, it's not made by id so it's not gonna be on here.
Scott: But a lot of the things on here aren't actually developed by id like those.
Scott: quake 2 expansions are made by other developing Developers and heretic and hexen are made by other developers.
Scott: But oh, well, I guess that doesn't count I don't know.
Rym: now the reason I personally don't care is just that one I own all these games already I don't know.
Rym: in all these games at least not legally the only ones I don't own legally or the commander keen.
Rym: So if I think else I'm gonna buy all the commander Keens the ones that I own legally are ultimate doom.
Rym: Is that it?
Rym: because I bought doom I got the share where that was it.
Scott: The ultimate doom is doom 1 with that extra mission at the end.
Rym: I bought doom 1. then I bought doom 2.
Rym: I bought final doom later.
Scott: I didn't buy doom 2.
Scott: I didn't buy final doom.
Scott: I didn't buy Wolfenstein.
Rym: I bought quake 1 and I'm still quick.
Rym: I bought quake 2.
Scott: I've never bought any quakes.
Rym: I bought quake 3.
Rym: Oh, no, I guess I never owned doom 3 or any of those.
Scott: but yeah the only game on here I've ever legally purchased before now is ultimate doom, even though I've played almost all of you pirating ass.
Rym: I was like the king of pirates in high school and yet I bought all those games.
Scott: and Yeah, the only one I bought was ultimate doom which is doom 1 with one extra level at the end.
Rym: Well, not one extra level one extra hole Okay, but the thing is not only do I own all these games but they all work just fine and wine and I got them All in Linux natively and all that business.
Rym: I can just play them anytime.
Rym: I want already I have everything I need and in fact I have the exact same doom doom 2 quake and quake 2 directories That I originally installed those on a crashed hard drive.
Rym: No, okay, because I copied stuff off that hard drive long before a crash.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: Yes The only things I lost for all the documents and things I didn't care about when I made my new computer I copied all the data that I needed to use regularly which meant, you know all my games, right?
Rym: So I've got all the mods and everything that aren't gonna be in here and - uh This pack doesn't come with any sort of additional or enhanced multiplayer Which is the only reason I would care.
Rym: well, I would pay hundreds of dollars.
Scott: You want something that doesn't exist.
Rym: Yes, that's exactly what I'm saying.
Rym: It's kind of like I want a cell phone that has X things in it because said cell phone does not exist in this world.
Rym: I don't buy it.
Scott: That's like going to the store, right?
Scott: You're going to the classic car store and you're buying like a 1950s Corvette and you're saying hey, where's the fucking cruise control, man?
Scott: That's basically what you're saying.
Rym: No not at all.
Rym: because the thing is if These weren't released on Steam and they had put any effort into putting a layer between the old networking crap of these games which many of them are internet enabled anyway and Made it so I could just play doom against people in Steam or run servers or something I would pay a lot of money because I'm fucking awesome at doom - say what you will about any other video game skills I have there are very few people who can beat me in a doom - deathmatch.
Scott: Anyway, that basically the question I had when this came out.
Scott: The only thing that worried me was how are they gonna get these games to work in Windows XP or Vista?
Scott: I mean, these are old DOS games.
Scott: if you just try to run them, they don't work, you know Did they patch them?
Scott: did they rewrite them to work in Windows?
Scott: Actually my version of doom that I bought that I was just talking about ran in Windows 95. it came with doom 95.
Scott: This doesn't come with doom 95.
Scott: So I don't know how they got these DOS games to work.
Scott: What did they do?
Scott: and Rym was like, oh man, they rewrote them all to be all modern.
Scott: and I'm like, no I wasn't.
Rym: I was saying I hope that's what they did.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, because I wanted my all I wanted was multiplayer through Steam.
Rym: That is the only thing I cared about.
Scott: well, anyway what they did is They basically took DOS box the thing that you would have to use on your own to make these things work.
Rym: Well, except the ones that just run in Linux, right?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, except the ones that also just run in.
Scott: Well some of them.
Scott: but what what you said just run in Linux.
Scott: you threw me off because they do.
Scott: well, it's steam It's only on Windows.
Scott: Linux has nothing to do.
Rym: No, I'm just saying that like quake just runs in Linux.
Scott: fine Yes But the point is for all the games included in this pack that do not just work in Windows already the DOS games they basically put DOS box in there and Specially configured it to make sure it works.
Scott: just right to save you the trouble and when you run the game It opens up DOS box and it opens up the game.
Scott: It's pretty funny now.
Rym: in the very least that gives me hope.
Rym: I kind of am thinking about just buying this anyway, because while it doesn't have the multiplayer I want This peg does offer one important thing and that is I can know for a fact that pretty much everyone out there Will be using the exact same version of these games as the steam version.
Scott: So
Rym: if I cobble together or set up some sort of way of multiplayer in over the internet with these things which isn't that hard to do I've done it before in DOS box I'll be able to play against all you fools in Doom 2 deathmatch, which is my only goal.
Rym: Yeah, it's.
Scott: I personally think it's just too much trouble and no one cares and that's why they didn't bother.
Scott: You're probably the only one in the world who wants to play Doom 2 deathmatch.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's really fun to play that.
Rym: plus remember that gen game We used to play that quake to mod that basically had the Wolfenstein guy the quake guy right to guy.
Scott: I'm sure this is all correct.
Scott: But As long as actual newer better FPS multiplayer games exist like the Team Fortress 2 that's coming out real soon I believe I'm gonna strike counter-strike because counter-strike is still the most played FPS.
Scott: while those things exist Why?
Scott: There's just no point to play Doom 2 multiplayer.
Rym: Oh Because you know while Mario 64 exists, there's no reason to ever play Mario 1.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's sort of like in terms of a multiplayer competitive game.
Rym: Why rather play ice hockey multiplayer than any modern hockey game?
Scott: And that's a different game though I'm talking about.
Scott: why would you play the game the the Mario tennis for the n64 and you could play the GameCube Mario tennis?
Rym: Well in this case, I have to say that other than serious and no other FPS has ever had the feel of doom.
Scott: That's true because no other FPS really tries to be the run-around shooting senselessly game.
Scott: They always either try to be the slow and careful ones or you know half-life awesome cinematic types.
Rym: Well, not just that but in terms of the speed because quake 2 and doom were super fast And you ran really fast and the game was not terribly realistic.
Rym: It was just fun and like when all the threes came out of these games They were really kind of slow and it really changed the way the games played.
Rym: the games that I'd play with like the FOV 170 in my mouth sensitivity crazily twitching around barely even looking at the screen.
Rym: Yeah while I like that action That's my favorite.
Scott: Enjoy an FPS that where all you do is run around shooting stuff like a serious Sam.
Scott: I must say that the days of the FOV blah and The really kind of hacked up engines with all the you know, ghetto duct tape all over the game.
Scott: I while I'm nostalgic for those days.
Rym: I'm glad they're over I will say one thing and that one thing is natural selection.
Rym: now just like it was not duct tape Had they not fucked up the gorge and broken the animation So it didn't jump properly and it jumped in this weird kind of broken away because there's no jump animation That game wouldn't have been half as fun.
Rym: Yeah, okay Plus babbler's babbler's babbler's.
Scott: Yes babbler's.
Rym: so uh There wasn't really any other video game news I wanted to talk about because most of it as always is rumors and bullshit.
Rym: But I want to talk about one of these bullshit rumors.
Scott: Oh bullshit rumor you say.
Rym: so joystick announced that someone from Best Buy or someone hanging out pointed out that you could go to Best Buy's website and click somewhere and Pre-order Rock Band for the ps3 and it was $60.
Rym: Alright and according to the people in their screenshots of all this it says and I quote included drum guitar and microphone peripherals enable players to perform music together.
Rym: emphasis added on the word included Mm-hmm.
Rym: Think about that $60 for the whole game and all the peripherals.
Rym: Yeah, I'm sure that's gonna work out for you real well Well, the thing is people are saying that this was on the Best Buy website.
Rym: so of course joystick broke the news and a million people tried to pre-order it and Best Buy strangely enough made that page disappear right quick.
Scott: Huh?
Scott: What do you know?
Rym: And of course, there's now the internet outrage of yeah fuck Best Buy.
Rym: They'd better give me it for $60.
Rym: Goddamn it It's their fault.
Rym: What the fuck?
Scott: What the fuck people?
Scott: and because a company is messing around with their website somehow you're entitled to get something at a huge discount.
Scott: Did they make?
Scott: I don't get it.
Rym: the thing that's on Joystick.
Rym: one of the first comments here and this is modded up.
Rym: as far as you can mod something up Businesses take advantage of consumers every day.
Rym: whenever consumers get a chance to stick it to big business.
Rym: I say go for it.
Rym: Meanwhile, all the buried comments are things like god, how cheap are you guys?
Rym: or if you actually like this game?
Rym: Why don't you pay what it's worth?
Scott: Yeah That's what I'm saying.
Scott: I Don't know what else is there to say.
Scott: people are fucking stupid.
Scott: But also the only thing I can say bad about Best Buy in this case is Why did be companies mess around with their website with with stuff?
Scott: That's not ready yet.
Scott: What freaking.
Scott: you have a development website.
Scott: you fiddle around there and when everything is good to go only then do you put it?
Scott: On the real website.
Scott: It should be it should.
Scott: there's no reason from a technology standpoint that any Public person on the on the big internet should be able to get to anything on your website that you do Want them to get to ever I that happens.
Scott: you fucked up and your IT web people are bad.
Rym: I can tell you why because it didn't hurt Best Buy at all and they couldn't give a shit.
Scott: They couldn't give a shit, but they should still if they're right there.
Rym: Why do they care?
Rym: Remember enterprise is a different world in the in the enterprise IT world no matter what you say No matter what argument you make for or against anything.
Rym: The first question you will be asked is Will this lose the company money?
Rym: and if the answer is not yes, and the figure is not millions Then the answer is why should I give a shit?
Scott: There is a possibility that if a web if a a certain page were to go up depending on the content of that page Best Buy could be sued for false advertising.
Rym: No, because Best Buy has a very clear policy that there might be typos on their website and none of that information means shit.
Scott: In other words as long as that agreements there these people didn't read it and fuck them.
Rym: Yeah I just find it interesting because this happens all the time and there's always this seething internet outrage over it and I gotta say you guys might feel great sticking it to the man for mom's basement But someone owes you something cuz they made a typo I'm sure.
Rym: see Indignance is something that bothers me a lot But right now maybe not right under that because there's a lot of things like rampant obesity and smokers and those are related to Indignance.
Rym: Yeah, well smoking not Smoking is a way down with those annoying things like people with bad teeth or bad breath or whatever.
Rym: Yeah, but people who feel entitled especially when they have no right to their entitlement things of the day.
Rym: So, uh, I kind of like rap.
Rym: I mean, I don't like gangsta hip-hop whatever but I otherwise like rap as a medium or genre or whatever a lot and Nothing gets my goat up in a good way more than rappers dueling, especially if they're dueling Well, just kind of lyrical rhymes and like it's
Scott: all
Rym: you got served
Scott: it's on.
Rym: but our friend katsu sent us this and It's along those lines, but suffice to say it is a Mendel's son Versus Wagner or for all of you Philsteins out there Wagner.
Rym: Yeah now now I do have my opinions about the music of both of these people and I'm generally the opinion That Wagner was an insane idiot and I hate all of his operas despite the fact that they're about awesome things.
Scott: Did you see in the news today that apparently like in some Russian soldiers Attic or something like that?
Scott: They found Hitler's record collection.
Scott: There's record collection.
Rym: I did indeed see that.
Rym: Yeah, it was pretty funny but I Just want to warn you all if you ever feel the urge to go see live got her damarang.
Scott: There are any other Wagner?
Scott: kind of?
Rym: take you all of the gutter damarang because it goes on for fucking ever.
Rym: It just never ends it.
Scott: Ah bring your DS It.
Rym: what the battery won't last long enough.
Rym: good fucking God.
Rym: Was that the worst thing ever bring a spare battery and bring an iPod to bring a pistol and a bullets bring some geek Archives but uh, or you could text message with quagmire.
Rym: But anyway, this is uh, these two people Wrapping it out.
Rym: I gotta say it's actually pretty hilarious.
Scott: It is pretty funny All right, so there's an awesome architect by the name of Shigeru ban and he makes things.
Scott: as architects do.
Scott: he makes structures.
Scott: He makes bridges and churches and museums and Houses and things and he makes them very interestingly.
Scott: I always wonder how guys like this make money Like he made her the thing here.
Scott: the one I'm gonna that drew my attention was he made a bridge out of cardboard Which I can understand because you know, you can make cardboard boxes that you could stand on very easily.
Scott: Just put them on your floor.
Scott: stand on and not flat ones either.
Scott: I'm talking like a box with air in the middle.
Scott: So making a bridge out of cardboard.
Scott: It is not too big a deal.
Scott: But yeah, he made a bridge out of cardboard.
Scott: he made a church out of paper.
Scott: he made a museum out of Like shipping containers.
Rym: these things are pretty damn impressive looking.
Scott: He made he made a house where two walls of the house are just a curtain.
Scott: That's pretty cool.
Scott: And he made a whole bunch of other things and you can find them all with links on this blog page here.
Scott: You know, if you just keep browsing around you'll see all of it.
Scott: You'll learn all about him, but that's pretty interesting I still have.
Scott: the question though is how someone like this makes fucking money because I Probably how many people need cardboard bridges that are hiring him?
Rym: I'll bet a lot of it is government grants either for the arts or for science, you know Maybe the bridge.
Rym: you could construct this as some sort of an experiment or check out the the fact that I can use this Lightweight material to make something strong based solely on the design all that sort of business.
Rym: Maybe he's independently wealthy.
Rym: Maybe he has some sort of patron or benefactor.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: All right I'll just end by saying the hippies are all over this of course because hey They're like whoo a bridge made out of cardboard and paper.
Scott: Hey, it's so green.
Scott: Maybe we should take this guy out because even though they don't they probably not thinking about how many trees you had to cut Down to make that bridge versus just a bridge made out of logs or the fact that uh, it's gonna rain someday.
Scott: I mean think about that.
Scott: It takes out like a whole tree to make a paper, right?
Scott: So why would the hippies be so happy about a boy?
Rym: wait wait wait It takes a whole tree to make a paper.
Scott: no to make a lot, you know, okay, I love for a second.
Rym: I mean, well, what do you mean by a paper?
Scott: Well, no If you make paper out of a tree that paper will make less bridge than the log that you you turned into paper.
Rym: Well, depending on how you you I mean say you have some nano machines to take the atoms out of that paper and turn it Into titanium, you know what I'm saying?
Rym: I do I do.
Scott: Yes, so what you know, it just shows again another example of Hippies, you know thinking something's green and not really thinking of all the way through.
Rym: Wow, I'm really surprised.
Rym: you took something about an architect making some art and turned it into an anti hippie thing.
Scott: I had to go somewhere with it.
Scott: I couldn't just leave it at the architect cuz I didn't have much else to say about it other than it's cool Check it out.
Scott: So I had to think up one other thing to say.
Rym: I didn't have anywhere to go with my thing of the.
Rym: That's the only reason I brought it got her.
Rym: he got her fucking dammer.
Scott: The only reason I was able to take it that way also is because this is a hippie blog and that's why I came to mind Ah hippie blogs.
Rym: Yep, right.
Rym: So This was actually reminded to us.
Rym: That was an awkward way of phrasing that Reminded of this by yes.
Rym: Well, we brought this up a way back.
Rym: You know how pretty much ten times a week we say man we could do a whole show about that.
Rym: Well someone remembered when we said it about this topic and reminded us to do it and I couldn't come up with much better.
Rym: And Scott and I this is actually a point of contention among us.
Rym: So tonight Gonna talk a bit about Vertical this.
Rym: hey to me anyone who doesn't use inverted mouse in an FPS is a heathen barbarian.
Scott: You're a heathen barbarian for using it.
Rym: It's not the default for it used to be the default for the longest time.
Scott: It was the default Because in the flight simulator games it was default.
Rym: I was the default in early FPS is like which one.
Rym: I'm pretty sure it was the default in the original quake.
Scott: I don't think I'm gonna go check on that cuz I have the original quake.
Rym: Yeah, maybe there's an update that changed it, but we'll see.
Scott: I'll go check it.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it wasn't.
Rym: Anyway, you see way back in the day I always heard rumors about people would use their mouse to play Doom or whatever.
Scott: I can start earlier than that.
Scott: I played Wolfenstein 3d before there any FPS is other than Wolfenstein 3d before doom existed, right?
Scott: And I always I liked the game, but it was difficult to play.
Scott: the reason was is because I could either play with the get the keyboard or with a gamepad or With the mouse and the way the game was programmed.
Scott: you had buttons to go forward backward Turn left turn right shoot open doors, and there was a strafe button.
Scott: And if you held the strafe button you could strafe left and right without turning left and right.
Scott: This was kind of annoying because if I played with just the mouse you'd have a three button mouse with like shoot open doors strafe And you'd have to keep picking up the mouse and moving it forward to go forward a lot.
Scott: So I'd play with the keyboard.
Scott: But I played with the keyboard turning kind of sucked because I had to turn with the keyboard and I couldn't turn Faster when I needed to and there was a bad guy there and I kind of wanted to shoot with the mouse button and it just sucked all around and It continued to suck because I had those same problems up until Real 3d FPS's came out and I learned of the keyboard mouse combination.
Rym: see for some reason for the longest time I never thought to put two and two together.
Rym: I never thought that I could use both at the same time.
Scott: Well, I don't.
Scott: it's for some reason like there wasn't an option to do that.
Rym: Well for Doom there was yeah.
Rym: But to the first real FPS, yeah, but not quake.
Scott: I guess the first Cuz.
Scott: it was the 3d.
Scott: it was actually 3.
Rym: it was the first 3d FPS.
Rym: Yeah, but the thing is from the players perspective Doom was 3d.
Rym: Kind of yeah, that's so much.
Rym: it looked 3d.
Rym: you could go up and down you can.
Scott: it worked up and down.
Rym: Yeah, you couldn't look up and down but you could go up and down.
Scott: Yeah, you weren't actually going up or down you couldn't.
Rym: the player didn't know that.
Scott: there couldn't be like an imp under you.
Rym: Yes, but you know what the player didn't know that it was very difficult for the player to find that out.
Scott: I think it was pretty obvious Not so much especially in Doom 2 where they use where you had a 2d map that nothing was on top of anything.
Rym: Yeah, but part of that.
Rym: I mean the thing is I don't know why you're so down on doom than that I'm not.
Rym: do not do Really really 3d and a lot of the maps.
Scott: I'm just saying it doesn't feel 3d for me.
Rym: I play doom and it's it's well wait you're talking about doom 1 which actually was very 2d.
Rym: also doom - all did you play?
Rym: All the way through doom - yeah, because a lot of the later levels in fact, there's one level.
Rym: It was just a gigantic tower for the most part and gigantic cities where you go up massive Elevators to these high elevations and you look down and see shit.
Scott: Yeah, it just didn't really feel 3d to me.
Rym: Yeah, whatever but that game.
Rym: very clearly the year there was the option to use the mouse and the keyboard.
Rym: But I just never thought of that.
Scott: I didn't think of it either because none of my friends did it.
Scott: So why?
Rym: yeah, right?
Scott: You looked in the actual options menu.
Scott: It would always be like, you know configure the keyboard configure the mouse configure a gamepad.
Scott: They didn't if it would have said keyboard and mouse on the screen.
Scott: I would have figured it out, but it never did.
Rym: Well, the other thing was I remember that god-awful.
Rym: What wasn't that god-awful Jurassic Park game for the Super Nintendo?
Rym: I had it and it always said if you have the Super Nintendo mouse you can control the FPS parts with the mouse.
Rym: And I was always excited about that.
Rym: and I finally got Mario Paint one day and I immediately Plugged that mouse in.
Rym: it sucked.
Rym: Well, I remember trying to move forward by scroll the mouse forward pick it up Scroll the mouse forward pick it up pull it back and the dinosaurs just fucking ate me exactly.
Rym: but one day I decided to use the mouse and the keyboard and on that day
Scott: I
Rym: used one setup of keyboard and mouse where my fingers were on everything and I've used that exact same setup in every FPS from that day until today and I continue to use it.
Scott: Yeah basically What happened to me as I was playing I think?
Scott: Shogo marble armor division which came for free with my logitech wingman gaming mouse when I got my penny I'm three 450 in 1999 98. that was an actual 3d FPS.
Scott: it's actually a pretty cool game if you can find it cuz it's.
Scott: it's like an anime with an anime plot and a lot of anime references and half the FPS levels you're in a robot and Half the FPS levels you're on your own and it's it's actually really fun.
Scott: I'm gonna go play that.
Scott: Anyway in that game I was playing it using my old doom Wolfenstein controls and it didn't work out too.
Scott: Cuz you know my my habit was always to you know, if I got a new PC game I threw out I just completely deleted whatever default control configuration.
Scott: They gave me and put my own in there, you know, cuz that's what I wanted now.
Rym: That's what I also always did.
Scott: Yep But I didn't know so much about the 3d FPS is 1999 because I had been using a 486 up until then which couldn't handle them and So I kind of fucked it up.
Scott: and when I realized they couldn't play the game So well, I sort of played with the default configuration just once and I didn't like it because it was a WASD business and I was.
Scott: I liked using the arrows where the up and the down were directly on top of each other instead of the WASD where the W is slightly to the left.
Scott: and But I learned about the mouse keyboard combination Just even if the only button on the keyboard was the forward button and the back button that was enough.
Scott: You know how I could just I guess strafe left and strafe right also.
Scott: But you really only need four buttons and the mouse and I can play most FPS.
Rym: I guess for me, I was just really lucky and that the setup I used mostly by chance Ended up having enough keys at my disposal to where no matter how complicated an FPS got.
Rym: I mean I use the same friggin setup in tribes too that I used in doom and it worked perfectly for me.
Scott: Yeah See I'd use the arrows the actual arrow keys on the keyboard and then I would use like the control that was pretty close to The arrows and the shift above that and the some of the lower left numpad keys
Rym: Yep, like insert and
Scott: like the page down and the end and the insert and I would use you know Like the the the zero on the the calculator part.
Scott: I used all those buttons the enter and it was pretty good because the arrows were sort of separated from everything else.
Scott: So it was like arrows.
Scott: and then when I needed extra stuff Which I didn't need too often because on my mouse, which is three buttons, right?
Scott: I could you know change weapons.
Scott: I could jump duck and shoot.
Scott: I only needed like the secondary attack and the use item on the keyboard and that was it.
Scott: So to control and shift I'm with my pinky finger on the keyboard I'm good, and I didn't really play any complicated FPS.
Scott: is that required any more buttons for a very long time?
Rym: So I think what did it for me was mostly the fact that I because I had an internet connection and cable modem I had access to a lot of online play.
Rym: So as a result like with quake one and quake two I played a lot of those mega TF weapons factory action quake mods that For anyone who's played those games you needed like 30 keys bound to things or you couldn't play for shit.
Scott: Yeah, that's why those games aren't around anymore.
Rym: Yeah I mean those were games where I had to write complicated scripts to do basic in-game functions.
Scott: Yeah, yeah nowadays the game should be doing that shit for you, and they do.
Rym: in fact I just I do want to say that in quake 2 Remember in quake way you had the offhand grenade where you could throw a grenade, but still have your weapon up.
Rym: Quake 2 didn't have that.
Rym: I wrote a script that effectively through a lot of Somewhat dubious, but perfectly non cheating legitimate means allowed me to have an offhand grenade Awesome even to the point that I could hold it down and kind of cook it before I threw it.
Scott: and there was one actually Complicated 3d game that wasn't technically an FPS where I did need a lot more keys and that game was descent.
Scott: Oh descent Descent 2 and descent 3. but in those games I either used the joystick throttle combination in which case there was no keyboard or mouse to be seen or I used all Keyboard where I would use the numpad as sort of the move might ship around and look around and I would use the the keyboard where all the letters were for all the weapons and items and the gizmos.
Rym: well descent was really a Unique game in the sense that it was free space, but games like tie fighter were also free space.
Rym: But tie fighter had the constant forward momentum, and it felt a lot more like you're flying a plane than a spaceship.
Rym: Yeah, if it was a fanciful spaceship, I guess.
Rym: but in descent I guess it was more realistic in that there was a lot more Spin around.
Rym: go backwards you're flying like backwards down a corridor shooting up.
Scott: It says the thing about descent.
Scott: right because in a normal FPS.
Scott: How can you move?
Scott: You're a guy with feet usually.
Scott: so you can go forward backwards You can rotate left rotate right jump duck and strafe left and right and that's about it.
Scott: You can do some of them in combination.
Scott: so you can like rotate left as you strafe right to sort of pull back or You know you can duck and creep forward and turn left at the same time.
Scott: But it's not all that complicated.
Scott: in descent you could go any direction so check this out.
Scott: you can go forward backwards You could rotate the left and right you could rotate up and down.
Scott: You know you could move your ship up move it straight down Move it straight left and straight right.
Scott: so you could strafe in any direction rotate in any direction and move forward and backward and When you combined a lot of those things together You could actually pull up very complicated aerial maneuvers some of which were essential to killing any human opponents.
Rym: Man, that was a fucking good game.
Scott: Yeah, I got.
Scott: I got to send three or to end to send two.
Scott: we go play.
Rym: I have to send three as well.
Rym: I got the CDs laying around somewhere.
Scott: We could play that.
Scott: maybe we should Windows 95 game.
Scott: Yeah, anyway anyway.
Rym: Yeah, so uh I don't.
Rym: I guess we could talk about cuz I. I like.
Rym: I said I use kind of a weird setup, so I don't know if I should let Scott go first.
Scott: I changed my setup recently.
Scott: actually.
Rym: see the thing is I started with this default setup.
Rym: I think it was some game I played.
Rym: use this like the basic setup as the absolute default that you could possibly have and I was definitely influenced by the fact that if you look at the comma and the period keys on a keyboard They have the left and the right carrots.
Rym: They're like left and right arrows, and I just felt like that should be strafe left and strafe right And that kind of like my whole thing centered around those two keys.
Rym: Not bad, and I think the fact that early by default a lot of games use spacebar as jump.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of games did use spacebar as jump, but wolfenstein 3d and doom.
Scott: I think use spacebar as open door.
Scott: Yeah, I think that was before the days where there was a jump though.
Scott: You couldn't jump in those games.
Rym: Yep, see the real thing was though.
Rym: I started with this kind of rudimentary, but random chance setup But as I started playing these mega TF and quake weapons factory whatever games, and I started needing all these other key binds.
Rym: I actually sat down with a picture of a keyboard and mapped out like this whole Complicated system of how I would forever more deal with any FPS I ever needed to have key bindings for and I've struck to that system to this day.
Rym: Uh-huh, I actually broke it up into.
Rym: this will sound silly, but five different tiers of functions in games.
Rym: Aha, there's the primaries and the primaries are the things that by default if I'm not doing anything else My fingers are always on the keys to be able to do this.
Scott: move and shoot.
Rym: pretty much move and shoot Jumping strafe and duck and use.
Rym: no use is not a primary.
Scott: There's a lot of using going on in modern games.
Rym: Oh while there is use is not a primary because basically when I said the primaries what I thought was things that I need to be able to do 100% of the time in Combination with other things no matter what.
Rym: as in I should always be able to do at least some of these things and Things from other tiers at the same time and they're things that I have to be doing instinctually and without thought.
Rym: muscle memory Using like opening doors are conscious actions.
Rym: I have to think do I want to open this door?
Rym: Am I prepared for what may or may not be on the other side of this door?
Scott: That's.
Scott: but the thing is the use button is also used like flicking switches and now grabbing turrets and getting in vehicle.
Rym: Those are conscious actions for me.
Rym: I do not ever want to do those things automatically.
Rym: the moment I automatically grab something or jump into a vehicle I now my muscle memory might make me do something that my brain knows is not the right action.
Scott: Yeah, it's usually a good idea to do a lot of those things.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, don't remember those are the primaries the raw muscle memory.
Rym: The secondaries are things that I need to be able to do 99% of the time without compromising the primaries.
Rym: so these are things like Swimming like moving up and down or movements that aren't always an option like, you know And how I see I don't know why you have the swim buttons.
Scott: I use jump and duck to swim up and down.
Rym: see I did in quake.
Rym: I stopped doing that in half-life for some very small.
Scott: Why would you make extra buttons?
Rym: Hardly because a few FPS as I played didn't let you bind multiple things to the same key.
Scott: I see.
Scott: actually I think in half-life which is most of what I played recently You know jump is swim up and duck is swim down.
Rym: And also I had I used that for cycling and these other things and not all games did that.
Rym: in games Where I could move up and down with jump and duck I use those instead.
Rym: Aha, and also those were kind of secondary because I didn't need them.
Rym: and then things like changing weapons and Reloading weapons and all those sorts of thank God for the invention of the scroll wheel because it sucked before then.
Rym: Yes granted I don't use the scroll real scroll wheel that often because my muscle memory is still to use my Next weapon previous weapon from the way old ass days.
Rym: Ah, I'm all about the scroll wheel But I've started to change and now I use both because the muscle memory will always change with the old way.
Rym: But if I'm thinking I'll use the scroll wheel particularly in half-life games.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Then there's the tertiaries.
Rym: These are the primary communications like talking team talking the radio messages that I really really really need.
Rym: Things like dropping weapons or buying shit actually drop encounter strike I drop.
Scott: weapon is a really close by button for me.
Rym: See it used to be but not anymore because I'm very economical with my bullets and I will almost never run out of bullets And still be alive.
Scott: if I run out of bullets Yeah, see I would do it to pick up a better weapon not to be because I'm out of bull.
Rym: Oh, yeah But that's the church.
Rym: that's still a tertiary thing as far as I'm concerned because much more prime is being able to move Shoot get out of the way duck and use a door.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, they just aren't so many buttons.
Scott: So putting drop weapon close by isn't too hard.
Rym: now.
Rym: the fourth and fifth tiers like the fourth tier was pretty much all the weird esoteric stuff like building a turret in a game or dropping the the special grenade that you prime or switching to the special weird ass weapon that you don't use all the time.
Rym: all that stuff.
Rym: and Beyond that the final tier were non muscle memory not important definitely minor communication things like taunts Gorge, whatever playing music all that bullshit Spray.
Rym: so at the gas spray.
Rym: So at this point I'm just I'm gonna just lay out finger by finger exactly how I bind everything.
Rym: if you're near a keyboard I'd say you just put your fingers on the keyboard one by one and I'll warn you.
Rym: It's kind of weird partly because I am is weird.
Rym: well partly because I long ago dropped the idea that Just because a key will make me move forward as opposed to back or left or right it should somehow be in front of or left or right of that button.
Rym: So right hand on the mouse, obviously Fingers are pretty much one two three on the first button the middle scroll wheel and the third button.
Rym: So one two three index fingers shoot Ring finger is move forward.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: You're fucked up.
Rym: Yeah Well, see the thing is that's what doom was by default.
Scott: It was but no one does that anymore.
Rym: I still do.
Scott: Yeah There's a reason they don't do that anymore and the middle fingers always resting always on the scroll because that way when you move forward It could mess up your aim.
Rym: well also because when I'm moving forward or moving back or whatever I'm doing I can be changing weapons or Changing the state of my weapon because pushing in that button is either the menu or the alternate weapon always Mm-hmm, and that's it.
Rym: If there's other buttons on a mouse.
Rym: I refuse to use them.
Rym: He said well partly because I need I only touch the mouse with the tip of my thumb The three fingers that are just lightly rest.
Scott: like you just decide that you want to do things in some weird way that no one else does them you just and then you Like try to claim that that's the best way in the.
Scott: I'm not saying it's the best way at all.
Scott: Do it.
Scott: you do not do an insane enough.
Rym: you do say it often No, it's definitely and clearly not the best way.
Rym: It's the best way for me because as I played over the years I evolved a lot of muscle memory and I'd rather capitalize on all those years of FPS and then throw it away and do something Differently,
Scott: but if you did something differently and built a different muscle memory in the end, that might be better.
Rym: I see I don't think it would be because I'm actually pretty badass at FPS and all things considered.
Rym: But the thing is in general the way I use a mouse is unless I'm clicking I'm only touching it with the tip of my tongue in the tip of my picky finger.
Rym: No other part of my hand is ever touching the mouse.
Rym: My palm never touches the mouse ever.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, that's the way I roll.
Scott: No one else rolls that way.
Scott: So I'm just saying you're weird.
Rym: I said that.
Rym: I said I warned everyone very clearly that my setups kind of weird pretty much from the start.
Scott: Yeah, I'm just so funny.
Rym: on the keyboard my default primary configuration I have a palm mouse apobia of some sort.
Rym: No, I just the thing is I want to use my fingers.
Rym: I don't my wrist doesn't really move when I use a mouse because I'm wrist doesn't move so much either.
Rym: I just use my pinky and my thumb Yeah, and then if I need to click I touch the mouse with those fingers to click.
Rym: if I'm in a heated moment Sometimes there's extra pressure from those buttons, but that's just because I get heated.
Rym: So pinky fingers on the spacebar to jump.
Rym: ring finger is on the M key to move backwards.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: middle finger is on the comma key to strafe left.
Rym: Index finger is on the period key to strafe right.
Rym: thumb Is on the alt key right under there to crouch?
Scott: See I don't use the alt keys or the window keys at all anymore because I've noticed that in a lot of a lot of Windows stuff really likes to pay attention to the alt and windows keys and I used to use them for things and it wouldn't cause A problem.
Scott: but now pushing alt or windows just seems to cause all sorts of problems randomly in different games.
Scott: So I don't use them for anything at all ever no matter what.
Rym: see the way I get around that is one.
Rym: I don't have anything bound to alt anything in windows by default.
Scott: Yeah, it's not that I bind anything to it It's that they just things happen when you push that.
Rym: I've never had anything happen.
Scott: I've had things happen, too.
Rym: I don't use the windows key fucking ever.
Rym: Yeah on old keyboards.
Rym: I used to get rid of it or disable it somehow physically.
Scott: Yeah, but it's nothing you could.
Scott: too many problems I have slipping and hitting it during an FPS and then the start menu opens.
Rym: see honestly, I've never done that.
Rym: I've never accidentally hit the windows key.
Scott: It's happened to me.
Rym: part of it's because I've been using the same setup forever.
Rym: like I could play an FPS The keyboard could be hidden from me and I could just play.
Rym: But I said, that's my primary setup.
Rym: And also, you know, most games tab shows you the score.
Rym: Yeah for me I always unbind that because I don't want to hit alt tab because I'm holding alt down a lot.
Scott: See that's one of the things I hate.
Rym: So what I did is I bound that to Q instead and tab doesn't do anything.
Rym: That was just something I did long ago because I Got killed many a time hitting alt tab in the heat of checking my score checking my score scene Who's still alive and my team in action quake OMG?
Scott: Yeah, I don't really check the score so much.
Rym: So that's it.
Rym: That's the primary keys.
Rym: now When I need to move stuff notice how I have these kind of rings of keys.
Rym: outside of that if I move all my fingers Out in a radius.
Rym: I have this whole other set of keys.
Rym: move them out again And I have another set of keys.
Rym: and that's why I had this kind of primary secondary tertiary idea Because I can move my fingers one set or two sets to kind of change modes and my fingers.
Rym: So without further ado B and N I use for various things and is always reload.
Rym: B is always whatever special thing a game needs other than that like bandage in action quake and V is always voice.
Rym: Notice how it's like tears moving out with my pinky finger.
Rym: K is use.
Rym: it has been used for as long as there has been a use in any game ever.
Rym: J and L are either scroll through menus or swim up and down so they kind of rotate around the K key.
Rym: Weapon next is always forward slash weapon.
Rym: previous is always apostrophe grenade or whatever.
Rym: weird thing is always semi-colon.
Rym: T and Y are always talking team chat UIOP are always radio commands.
Rym: Beyond that it all really depends on the game.
Rym: So I can't really get into further details.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, you know different games have different weird shit.
Rym: you got to bind to things for whatever reason.
Rym: Yeah, it's why arm the stanza flange fire the stanza flange use the tractor beam.
Scott: That's why I basically I set the base keys and then everything else changes game by game and I kind of just get used to It, you know if I change my mind all the time.
Rym: But all the things I stated if the game has that function I always use that key no matter what.
Rym: and part of the reason is I can do a lot of things that need to be done simultaneously Simultaneously, so I kind of move my fingers through different tiers But I can strafe left crouch move forward use and shoot all at the same time if I need to and I've done things like That in some games.
Scott: I can do those things with the default configuration in just about any FPS.
Scott: So you don't need a crazy weird keyboard configuration to do that.
Rym: See I don't think it's really that weird It's just.
Rym: it's a very systematic approach that I've used.
Scott: Yeah, I think you just you seem to you know.
Scott: I don't know if anyone listening to the show has noticed it But living with Rym for a long time He likes to just try to come up with weird solutions that are just way out of the box for a different thing.
Rym: I'm really curious.
Scott: like what like all sorts of stuff like what.
Rym: I'm really curious because this setup Like I said, it came by default just by chance because that's where I happen to start playing FPSs with the keyboard And then I use that as the core and I kind of came up with a system that I would use for the rest of My life the rest of
Scott: it.
Scott: you do that for a lot of things.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: So, how is it weird that if I decide that I'm gonna do something a lot in my life I come up with the system to do it better?
Scott: because you're not really.
Scott: you don't seem to actually scientifically determine what's better.
Scott: you seem to just do something that makes sense and you do things that you know are not Usually always pick something that isn't done by a lot of people.
Scott: how so like what like?
Scott: like arranging furniture You're always right.
Scott: Yeah, you're always just trying to find weird ways to arrange furniture weird ways to organize things.
Rym: I'm curious why you say weird.
Scott: I mean, I rearranged my bedroom a little while ago and you know, like whenever something is like, you know The the accepted way of doing something you'll always try to figure out a weird way of doing it that no one else does.
Rym: at most I'd think I try to come over here out of the ordinary.
Rym: How like I name anything out of the ordinary I do.
Rym: I'm really curious.
Rym: pretty much everything like what name.
Rym: one thing since you said everything there must be plenty of examples.
Scott: Like anytime you're I don't know I'm what you do it all the time.
Rym: I just oh I do it all the time You did I do it with everything yet.
Rym: You can't come up with any examples.
Scott: Just cuz I can't remember a specific example.
Scott: and not just making this up.
Rym: I'm really curious.
Scott: All our friends are probably like yeah Yeah, he does and all the people who don't know you were probably like what the hell Scott's got talking about Rym fund him.
Rym: I really don't know though because I really don't see where you're coming from.
Rym: Like you tried to say this before when I rearranged my bedroom.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: My bedrooms a lot better now than it was before and Emily agrees because she uses this room all the time But it is this is these the way you have your furniture arranged now is a way that no Interior decorator would think to arrange the furniture.
Scott: It is very straight.
Scott: Like you were thinking of doing weird stuff like rotating your desk.
Scott: So it faces into the room.
Rym: a Lot of secretaries and things do that.
Rym: that way I could face you while I do the show instead of my back to you Like we do now.
Scott: Are you a secretary?
Rym: Also, it's just that way.
Rym: I think I was trying to see if I could fit everything along one wall to save a bunch of space.
Rym: it turned out I Couldn't so instead.
Rym: I just moved everything to the current configuration.
Rym: There's the thing.
Rym: I just looked at my room and the original setup and I realized that it's way off topic.
Scott: We should like put this is everything.
Rym: I'll just go real quick because you say this is weird.
Rym: Everything was around the walls and all the space in the middle of the room because it's actually a really big room.
Rym: it's the exact same size as the living room - the two closets and The middle of the room really wasn't used.
Rym: I don't do stuff in my room.
Rym: So that middle space was just kind of wasted.
Rym: I rearranged my room to use the middle part of the room more and as a result, I fit a lot more shit in here.
Scott: So back in the day when I originally figured out, you know and she'll go marble armor division to use the keyboard and the mouse You know, I it the default was like WASD something something and I said already that I didn't like that because I felt that the W should be directly.
Scott: You know the up should be directly above the down and I'd been using the arrows for every other game up until then And I wanted to continue using the arrows.
Scott: So I moved it over to the arrows and this wasn't a problem on my old IBM keyboard because next to the arrows There was the numpad and the page down and the end and all that business.
Rym: Wait, wait, wait.
Rym: What kind of IBM keyboard is this?
Rym: one of those clackety clackety one?
Scott: I think Alex has it now It wasn't clackety clackety.
Scott: It was like an IBM Something and it was a standard keyboard layout but it had these like four buttons on the right hand side that could be programmed to do anything and It was actually pretty cool because those buttons just worked unlike a lot of the weird buttons on keyboards today.
Scott: And actually Alex do you still have that keyboard?
Scott: I kind of want it back.
Scott: It's a nice keyboard.
Scott: I don't know what happened to it.
Scott: Anyway, it was a ps2 keyboard also.
Scott: Anyway more recently, you know, basically after PC gaming died for me after RIT You know, I stopped getting these standard PC keyboard layout.
Scott: I didn't get the hundred and four key keyboards with the numpad on them and all that jazz.
Scott: I got the happy hacking keyboard which I highly recommend for anyone who uses VI or isn't a cool programmer in any fashion.
Scott: and the happy hacking keyboard is special because it has a control where the caps lock should be and it doesn't have a numpad and it's really small and it doesn't have Dedicated F keys.
Scott: you have to hold down the FN button and then push 1 2 3 4 5 to do To do f1 f2 f3 or 4 or 5 etc, etc.
Scott: It's not a normal keyboard But for someone like me who primarily uses the computer with a lot of keyboard shortcuts involving the control button.
Scott: Linux and VI especially the happy hacking keyboard is a godsend.
Scott: Then came a problem when I wanted to play some FPS's again after a long Drought of FPS playing and I only had this happy hacking keyboard in front of me with the arrows.
Scott: It does have arrows But they're small and they're in the bottom right and they're not next to a numpad and you really can't play an FPS with them At all.
Rym: Yep See the thing is well.
Rym: I kind of like the happy I've can keyboard.
Rym: When I saw it and actually I have this problem now and that a lot of modern keyboards kind of move stuff around a little Bit.
Rym: if the keyboard is not exactly Exactly the same at least in terms of the relative distances between things as my original original keyboard that I first played Duman I can't play FPS's at all.
Rym: I also box.
Scott: I agreed with that to a large extent.
Scott: these logitech keyboards.
Scott: now We're like the delete key is vertical and double-sized.
Scott: Fuck those These keyboards where they like have like this spacebar split into two pieces.
Scott: Fuck those the ergonomic bendy hump keyboards where the keyboard at the entire keyboard is split in half.
Scott: Fuck those.
Scott: also The these new Mac keyboards with like these giant square buttons with huge caverns between them.
Scott: Fuck them as well.
Scott: Only the normal I mean my laptop keyboard I can deal with even though a lot of other people seem to complain the keys are Small but it's basically happy hacking keyboard.
Scott: or the layout has to be this the way that it's always been.
Scott: If it's changed too much, I can't deal with it.
Scott: I mean at least especially if it's not a laptop, you know a laptop I can understand to an extent compressing the keyboard, you know to fit on there.
Scott: But other than that with why?
Scott: why mess it up?
Scott: So anyway, I had this happy hacking keyboard and I want to play an FPS And this is problematic without the arrows and my original setup.
Scott: So I basically had to come up with a setup right away and I figured oh, well everyone else uses this wasd business why not?
Scott: it can't be that bad and It hasn't been that bad Despite my you know I guess it was sort of a small bit of OCD and me that didn't want.
Scott: that wanted the W to be directly above the S but really it doesn't matter.
Scott: and When my fingers are over there my pinky now has access to like the shift the control on the tab and that's really useful.
Scott: There's a whole bunch of buttons right there.
Scott: I got the Q and the E right there and I've got like the F for the flashlight and the R for the reload And the Z X C or right under and my thumb can be on the spacebar and there's just a whole mess of buttons.
Scott: But in general what I do is I use WASD for forward left forward back straight left straight right R. I'll reload.
Scott: I'll use the you know, the caps lock which is actually control on my keyboard.
Scott: I'll either use it for like secondary weapon or in a game like NS I'll use it for like to bring up the menu because use the menu and NS a lot.
Scott: Sometimes I use it for duck depending on the game.
Scott: Who knows but I unlike Rym I use a lot of buttons on my mouse on my mouse.
Scott: I got shoot.
Scott: I got jump I got duck with my thumb.
Scott: I got change weapons with the scroll II wheel.
Scott: I got like push in the scroll II wheel to like toss a weapon away or maybe throw a grenade or something.
Scott: You know I got all kind as much I can fit onto the mouse as possible because The mouse I got a lot of fingers and there's a lot less buttons on the mouse.
Scott: I mean I got the same number of fingers on.
Scott: the mouse is on the keyboard.
Scott: so and the keyboard is a lot of buttons that I can handle with just four or five fingers.
Scott: and If the mouse has three buttons That's pretty inefficient as far as I'm concerned because I could be hitting just as many buttons with one hand is with the other Because the moving has to do with my arm and not with my fingers.
Scott: So, you know, I use pretty.
Scott: I have a logitech mx-1000.
Scott: It has a lot of buttons and I use most of them when FPS.
Rym: So, I guess my problem is just that I the only part of my hand that moves at all are my fingers and I need My pinky and my thumb to control the mouse.
Rym: So I really don't have any more fingers to be on the mouse.
Scott: You see I have.
Scott: my whole hand is on the mouse.
Scott: I move the mouse with my arm and not with my wrist.
Scott: my whole arm moves around but it doesn't move much You know because I have such high sensitivity.
Scott: you want to talk about sensitivity or we talked about that before on the show.
Rym: I don't know that might be worth a different discussion all together.
Scott: Yeah, I think we have talked about it on the show and briefly before.
Rym: I mean I used to.
Rym: I played High-sensitivity back in the day.
Rym: I shifted to low sensitivity in these realistic games or whenever I was sniping.
Rym: In fact, I had a script that when I zoomed in would change the sensitivity in quake - mm-hmm Yeah, but I used to use, you know, no normal default sensitivity.
Scott: Then I went through a time period where I cranked it up all the way.
Scott: now I just crank it up most of the way because I think what's happened is just with the way things have progressed.
Scott: cranking it Up all the way is just way too much Especially because you have these accelerators that multiply by each other and the mouse does become Uncontrollable.
Scott: and when I turn everything up in the mouse driver in the game in every possible place It's just you move the mouse like a millimeter and it flies away and you can't move it a small distance at all.
Scott: But yeah Because I have high sensitivity and because he's my arm to move the mouse All my fingers on my mouse are able to do things and my mouse has many many buttons which I can.
Scott: I can also bind Those buttons to actual keys on the keyboard which helps a lot in games that don't allow for more than three mouse buttons You know, which is really cool.
Scott: You know cuz you mean mom.
Scott: Lulu my left hand is on the left side of the keyboard.
Scott: So like JKL aren't doing anything.
Scott: So if I put JK and L on my mouse I can trick the game into thinking that you know J do this and it's actually a mouse button.
Scott: when I'm at you know, it's big.
Scott: the game thinks is J.
Rym: so now I gotta say I definitely respect the WASD partly because I mean pretty much Most gamers use it.
Rym: that was like the standard gold standard whatever back in the day and a lot of people still use it to this day.
Rym: the only gripe I had with it was just that I Like a setup where there's only one direction to move my fingers when I need to spread out.
Rym: but in that system I feel like I could go up left down or right and there's always keys in every direction and I felt like that was just Too much to deal with.
Scott: see yes.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: The thing is I don't actually spread out so much.
Scott: I keep I use as few keys as possible and I only bind keys for the absolutely most essential functions the things that I'm gonna do often.
Scott: if I'm not gonna do something often if it's something I'll Do extremely rarely or only do you know when I'm like sitting still and it's completely safe and there's no danger I just I don't bind a key for it and go in the menu or use the console or I bind it Leave it as the default key and then you know Look up what the key is, you know in the middle of the game and then go and push it with like my one finger On its own, you know, like what's something I don't really need too often.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'm trying to think of a weird games that have weird things like in in tribes, too.
Scott: You had that menu where you could like customize your different loadouts, you know I would use like the farthest away button on the keyboard that I would never use to do that.
Rym: Yeah, well because once I had the loadout set up I wasn't gonna tweak them in the game.
Scott: That's crazy Yep, but you know stuff like that.
Scott: I just use the farthest away button possible I don't you know sort of branch out with my fingers while I'm playing I pretty much only use the pinky on the shift control tab, you know My two two or three fingers for was ad ws ad Qerf and maybe like G and one two three four if I need them and all the buttons on my mouse and space.
Scott: and that's Enough for pretty much every FPS out there except for you know, the crazy old quake mods Which I don't play now when it comes to mouse inversion or not.
Rym: That's a big point of contention between the two of us.
Rym: I mean for me.
Rym: I've always used any time I am ever controlling a first-person view of anything ever no matter what it is It has to be inverted be it a joystick a puck a trackball a mouse a keyboard Whatever.
Scott: just you know rims talking about.
Scott: what he's saying is that when he moves down with his mouse in an FPS The aim actually goes up.
Scott: so to shoot a guy higher up He pulls the mouse towards himself and when he wants to shoot a guy down below he moves the mouse away from himself.
Scott: But it's only a vertical inversion.
Scott: So left is left and right is right, but up is down and down is up.
Rym: It's the way airplanes and things are flown.
Rym: And yeah, I just anytime I'm ever controlling anything in the world from a first-person view.
Rym: if it's not inverted I just cannot deal with it at all.
Rym: I absolutely get fucked.
Rym: There have been games Particularly on some consoles that don't let you change that and I cannot play them period.
Scott: see I do understand that feeling because when I play any sort of flight simulator or any sort of flying vehicle like TIE fighter or descent or I don't know any sort of game that actually like virtual on or any sort of game where there's a Control stick or flying or flying vehicles like I need to have it inverted.
Scott: I need up to make the ship, you know, if I move if I push the stick forward or move the mouse forward I need the ship to crash into the ground and if I pull back I need the ship to take off into the air.
Scott: That's how I need it to be.
Scott: But in an FPS where I am, you know in I mean even a third-person FPS I could invert and I'd be fine.
Scott: But in a first-person shooter where I am a guy with feet walking around shooting with a gun in front of me I need up to be up and down to be down left to be left and right to be right because The way I play those games in my mind is the goal is to click on the bad guys to kill them.
Scott: So it's like my cursor on my screen and I'm trying to click on the bad guys.
Scott: So the way and I you know Cuz it's basically I think the difference is that in a in a flying game or a vehicle the forward the inversion You're you're sort of It's also the movement of the vehicle that you're controlling as well as the aim.
Scott: Whereas in the FPS the mouse is just the aim and because it's just the aim and I'm just clicking on bad guys heads Or trying to click on their heads.
Scott: I can't invert or else I get screwed up.
Rym: See for me I still have the feeling that I'm just clicking on their heads and that that's all I'm doing.
Rym: I mean part of it might just be that I Mouse position.
Rym: like the direction I move a mouse is so relative that it doesn't matter what direction I point a mouse Physically or where it is or anything.
Rym: I could play an FPS holding the mouse upside down on the desk and I'd be just fine.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure that if I you know, it's sort of a muscle memory thing I'm sure I could easily if I set to invert get used to it in a few minutes and then be great after a few hours.
Scott: You know of playing but that's just the way I do it.
Scott: And that's the way I'm comfortable doing it.
Scott: I don't think there's actually an advantage or a disadvantage to setting or not setting the inverse vertical on FPS is or any other game.
Rym: I would argue that there is a slight advantage in total for using inversion.
Rym: now the argument would I Mean.
Rym: when I say slight I mean slight.
Rym: My argument is thus if you pick one way and go with it forever Your muscle memory will probably be better than if you switch at midstream as we can see with people who switch between QWERTY and Dvorak Or things like that.
Rym: Mm-hmm All flight sims and vehicle things are gonna be inverted just about and a lot of them.
Rym: don't let you change that.
Rym: But FPS is you can usually pick so on average there are more.
Rym: you will run into an inverted thing Occasionally in your life, but you'll rarely rarely rarely run into a thing that is not inverted that you cannot force to invert.
Scott: But see that's just it.
Scott: the thing though.
Scott: Is that I Let if I play a flying thing I can up.
Scott: the inversion is great.
Scott: I'm like we inversion, you know It's not.
Scott: if it would that would be true if somehow by not inverting I had to play with things not inverted.
Rym: No, but see what I'm saying is to me you I think you could build up a better total muscle memory of Forward is down backward is up in all interactions with any sort of first person or third person thing.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's just like it.
Scott: It's sort of a weird thing where it feels like it's the same amount of muscle memory no matter what.
Scott: but somehow like in tribes too is the best example because in that game you would be FPSing and then you would get into a flying vehicle.
Scott: and I had it set up where when I was in a vehicle it was inverted.
Scott: when I was not in a vehicle It wasn't.
Rym: I had it one step further.
Rym: It was inverted all the time.
Rym: But when I was running around I used the mouse.
Rym: the moment I jumped into a vehicle.
Rym: I grabbed my joystick.
Rym: That was so hot.
Rym: I was like the best strike fighter pilot.
Scott: The only reason I didn't do that is cuz not no joystick.
Scott: and also I really don't like any amount of time in switching Peripherals, you know, that's why I use so many keyboard shortcuts cuz I just hate switching to the mouse.
Scott: I like to stay on one peripheral as long as I can with minimum switching.
Rym: It was worth it to me just to have the almighty power of being able to file Fly that stupid thing.
Scott: I would have liked to fly it with a joystick but that one second of putting getting my hands up and putting on the joystick You know and fearing that someone would kill me while I was doing that was just so terrifying.
Rym: I don't know for me.
Rym: I did it in that time.
Rym: It took to stand in line and wait and whatever and if someone attacked me when I was in line for a vehicle Line for vehicles I was afraid cuz I was also the guy who would go to the enemy camp.
Scott: See people waiting in line for vehicles and kill the people standing there like idiots.
Scott: Yeah anyway You know.
Scott: and I did it that way and it was weird.
Scott: as soon as I got in the vehicle my brain just like flipped Over completely and like if it wasn't inverted I would have had a problem and then as soon as I get out of the ship If it didn't un-invert I would have had a problem.
Rym: See, I just seriously can't deal with that.
Rym: I must have too much invested in inverted to where I just cannot in for the life of me And I've tried a couple times on games that wouldn't let me switch.
Rym: I just can't deal with it at all.
Scott: It definitely has to do with my eyeballs though Because like if I close my eyes and I don't know if I'm in a vehicle or whatever Then I can do inverted or not equally.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: But if I'm seeing that I'm FPSing it needs to be not inverted and if I see that I'm flying I need to invert or My eyes see that and they immediately flip my brain in one direction or the other and I can't deal with the opposite direction.
Rym: Now some people might say Rym and Scott how come you didn't talk about joysticks or game pads or game controllers?
Scott: You don't play.
Rym: FPS is with those things and I still to this day and I will argue this fiercely and bitterly Maybe not bitterly because I feel like I'm right and I think Scott agrees with me that I don't care how good an FPS is.
Rym: Controlling it with anything that isn't a mouse just feels like this backward Inefficient terrible way of controlling a game.
Scott: Okay, I must say I do think it is Possible to create some sort of new Input device that would be good for FPS.
Scott: I agree possibly the wiimote nunchuck combination seems to have a potential not yet fulfilled But a potential some sort of VR thing some sort of VR thing.
Scott: There are many ways you could combine.
Scott: You know Some sort of input device that would be but you know what good as or better than mouse and keyboard dual shock or a game Cube controller.
Rym: I don't care how much you practice.
Rym: I don't think that it has even close to the potential of goodness or control or refined power That a keyboard and mouse combination done.
Scott: and I'll tell you why.
Scott: the reason is to play an FPS.
Scott: You have their discrete inputs like shoot It's either shoot or not shoot and you have sort of these analog non discrete inputs like aim.
Scott: Well, where do you aim?
Scott: Do you aim a little bit?
Scott: Do you aim a lot?
Scott: do you you know?
Scott: do you aim way up way down a little bit to the left little bit to the right and The main key here is that all the discrete inputs are simple.
Scott: They don't matter.
Scott: your gamepad has buttons.
Scott: You push a button it shoots.
Scott: You're all good.
Scott: It doesn't really matter as long as your input devices buttons the discrete inputs are handled.
Scott: What's hard is the non discrete inputs the aiming mostly but also the moving.
Scott: and To do better to have a better time to have better performance in a game You need those inputs to be very precise.
Scott: you know if pushing, you know, like for example, if you were to use your keyboard right for Turning left and right in an FPS like in the olden days, right?
Scott: Well, how fast would you turn left and right?
Scott: It would turn left and right at a steady rate.
Scott: So you couldn't turn around faster or slower.
Rym: and if you turn if you set it to be faster all the time You can't slow it down if you need more precise turning.
Scott: Yep So a discrete input is not good for a non discrete.
Scott: discrete input Mechanism is not good when you're not putting in a non discrete.
Rym: You know what I'm saying and very simply the analog stick on any console controller has nowhere near the sheer amount of possible values and inputs and the sheer just Elegance like a lightsaber of a well calibrated Optical mouse.
Scott: a mouse even a trackball even the wiimote right even though it's not even the wiimote It's not as good as a mouse are so far and above an analog stick in terms of you know being able to point at a spot on the screen or Just precision pointing.
Scott: It doesn't do it.
Scott: That's not what it does.
Scott: I mean if you want to control moving around Yeah, it can do that pretty well because an analog stick is good for moving around in a 3d universe But aiming in a 3d universe it is basically Worthless,
Rym: I mean
Scott: they've come up with ways to make it better, you know playing Halo with an Xbox 360 controller It's probably as good as it is as good as it's gonna get as well.
Scott: They figured out just how to calibrate that stick to make it I guess playable.
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: also a lot of those games tend to either use some sort of auto aiming or aim helping or They'll make it easier to target things or precision shooting doesn't matter or things like that.
Rym: But even then I can't look around as quickly and naturally in those games as I can with a mouse.
Scott: Yeah, I mean try to turn around as much as I like Metroid Prime, you know.
Scott: And I would say it's not actually an FPS even though it kind of is.
Scott: but it's it's not the same.
Rym: It's an FPA or an FPE.
Scott: Yeah, it's something like that.
Scott: You can't really turn around quickly.
Scott: It just doesn't happen now And it's the reason they have a lock on and an auto aim on that game and all the other games like.
Rym: I really look forward to the day where Xbox Live is set up to where I can play Halo whatever on my computer with my Windows Vista against all those kids with Xboxes because I I really
Scott: think that
Rym: an Above-average player with a keyboard and mouse will cream even an expert player with the best Console setup that isn't a keyboard and mouse.
Scott: He'll ever be able to get over any time over the average over time I believe will show that keyboard and mouse players will have a huge advantage because they have the ability to Just turn.
Scott: just the ability.
Scott: the fact that they can turn around quickly.
Scott: I mean the fastest thing about how fast you can turn around with the gamepad.
Scott: as fast as the game goes Pushing the analog stick all the way to the right right at the left beckonquake - I had a button I could hit.
Rym: that did A perfect 180 that I used often.
Scott: but with my mouse I can always move the mouse farther I can always pull it faster I can always Do more with the mouse.
Scott: with the analog stick the most you can do is push it all the way in one direction And that's the end of the line.
Scott: You can't make it go any faster than that and the least you can do with the analog stick is Move it as little as you can.
Scott: with the mouse I can Exactly move it at any Movement of my arm.
Scott: I can like reach all the way across the desk and plus since I control the sensitivity The higher I crank the sensitivity the more I can do.
Scott: Whereas with the analog stick it just you're limited because you can only move it in so many ways And that's that's why a mouse is better than analog stick for FPS.
Rym: I defy anyone to argue against that.
Rym: I'm dead serious.
Rym: We've had this argument with a few people before and Invariably no one has actually defended the position beyond the final argument.
Rym: They've always given up.
Scott: my anecdotal experience has been that people who?
Scott: Began FPSing with you know consoles and halo or maybe goldeneye and never really participated in the quake counter-strike FPS golden age days are the people who play with the game pads and You know maybe they don't even know how to use mouse and keyboard.
Scott: and the people who are mouse and keyboard are People.
Scott: anyone who's ever done mouse and keyboard and played some FPS is on PCs for real Agrees with us pretty much.
Scott: I've never found anyone who was like a PC FPS or using mouse and keyboard saying that game pads are better.
Scott: You know no one has ever could.
Scott: I've never seen anyone convert in that direction But I have seen gamepad people convert to the PC direction in terms of what is the better FPS control mechanism.
Rym: I think that's really all we have to say about this.
Rym: If you thought this was boring you don't care about.
Rym: FPS is well You might want to suggest more shows because this was in the forum.
Rym: someone very specifically asked for it.
Scott: Yep, we're gonna have a pretty exciting show next week actually.
Rym: Oh actually yes.
Rym: We are oh, man I'm kind of looking forward to it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at Frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front road crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.