Rym: It'd be Wednesday September 19th, and this be GeekNights.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm scatter and tonight.
Rym: We'd be talking about the piracy.
Scott: Let's do this Alright people.
Scott: I know that a long time ago.
Scott: We promised like double time that we would never advertise on GeekNights or Sell ads on GeekNights.
Scott: I guess I just redundant.
Scott: there's get sponsors for GeekNights or anything like that.
Scott: but Eventually you know.
Scott: I guess you know like if someone came and offered us like a billion dollars We wouldn't be able to refuse.
Rym: Scott is the one.
Rym: this was his idea, and he accepted it.
Rym: So I'm just gonna let him tell you what is going on.
Scott: So I guess I don't know.
Scott: should we dilly-dally or like beat around the bush, or you should get right to it.
Rym: Think you know.
Rym: we always say you know everyone has a price.
Rym: There's a point at which you can't refuse.
Rym: I mean think about it.
Rym: say someone said hey, would you punch your mom for five bucks?
Rym: No how about fifty five hundred?
Scott: Thousand fifty million, and then your mom would say hit me.
Scott: So even you know.
Scott: no matter how much you make a promise and how much you know you're the type of person who will never Break promises.
Scott: there is always some set of conditions in the world.
Scott: You know who know you?
Scott: they you might not even be able to conceive of them.
Scott: But there might be like this incredibly rare Circumstance of events where you will go back on your promise.
Scott: granted
Rym: for me to go back on my word would often take some Sort of I don't know promise of supernatural powers
Scott: something like that maybe
Rym: wings
Scott: but anyway, we we have gone back on our word in a way and I am simultaneously
Rym: pleased
Scott: but also Ashamed to announce that this episode of GeekNights is sponsored by the letter.
Rym: That's enough of that.
Rym: we learned our lesson last year.
Scott: Goddamn, what lesson did you be learning last year?
Rym: Talking like a bad pirate for more than about 20 seconds via mighty painful.
Scott: I heard it also be painful for the listeners.
Rym: ears, right?
Rym: Peg ear it however be talked like a pirate day One of our most sacred holiday.
Rym: it honestly it is one of the few holidays I actually celebrate.
Rym: I really do celebrate it and there aren't many.
Rym: I don't celebrate Christmas I I celebrate Thanksgiving in that I end up going to people's houses and having part.
Rym: But I don't celebrate it as a holiday and I know for a long time.
Rym: It's pretty much that International Day of Slayer, which I may or may not ever be able to celebrate again And yell at the sky day,
Scott: yeah, but I mean, you know it back in the day You'd have holidays and you'd celebrate the holiday, you know nowadays I guess there are people out there who do celebrate the holidays, but there are most holidays.
Scott: I mean, I might do something be like, you know, it's a holiday there Therefore my mom's having a dinner at her house.
Scott: So I go to it, but I don't actually actively celebrate the holiday.
Scott: Holiday one holiday to holiday three and holiday four Chinese food.
Rym: Yeah, it only happens on Christmas and then you set off the alarm in the house.
Rym: Yeah, but then the police come.
Scott: But it's not like I'm actively celebrating the holiday for what the holiday is Except.
Scott: well, the thing is I don't think about presidents on Presidents Day.
Rym: I think who?
Rym: four-day weekend.
Rym: Yeah, exactly.
Rym: I think the thing is that a long time ago when a lot of these holidays were celebrated more fervently It was that the holiday itself was an important part of culture and was celebrated.
Rym: And I think this is generally true more and more of our generation and the you know So-called internet generation that those holidays don't mean much to us other than especially those fake card company holidays Mother's Day.
Scott: Fuck you not fuck mothers, but fuck you Mother's Day.
Scott: I'm no I'm done buying cards.
Rym: if anyone didn't realize the thing is and my family at least as Accepted this because when they realized after many years that it wasn't just me forgetting It was just that I refused to buy trite gifts for any holiday.
Scott: if I buy a gift It's I'm not gonna spend five dollars and a piece of cardboard for you and I'm not gonna buy you a gift Just because it's a certain day of the year.
Scott: I'll buy you a gift if I see something that I think you would.
Rym: what I was saying is just that these holidays used to Have cultural meaning but our generation at least many of us in it or at least myself and Scott and many of our friends Holidays that are that's not part of our culture anymore.
Rym: My culture is much more related to things on the internet and talking like a pirate.
Rym: so holidays like International Day of Slayer are part of me and I celebrate them because I celebrate Slayer and all that it stands for Yep.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: However, I didn't celebrate International Day of Slayer the way it was supposed to be celebrated because I probably would have been fired and Arrested.
Scott: Yeah, it's always difficult that some of these geeky holidays, you know, I guess it's like anything like, you know Those people who say oh, it's my religion to like smoke weed all day.
Scott: It's 420.
Scott: Yeah, well, it sort of doesn't work if you actually have to go and interact with the world.
Rym: I mean, I had to meet a client today if I had said I be the communication specialist in stalling.
Rym: you switches Over with the executives.
Scott: No, I don't think so either, you know, so your options are you know to either take the day off or not celebrate your holiday to the fullest.
Rym: I Celebrate it in that I'm excited about it all day, even if I don't get to do much about it during the day.
Scott: I I spoke like a pirate when I went to the GameStop today.
Rym: I always will well one I'll always do it.
Rym: whenever I'm I see a person who I think might be cool.
Scott: It's not employees.
Rym: It's definitely a test.
Rym: Hey, remember when we were in with the best GameStop ever?
Scott: Yeah, it was so in an Otakon in you know, there's like this mall attached to the hotel that we stay in.
Rym: We really crappy mall - yeah and before we went to Wildwood myself Scott and Pete went to this mall because Scott decided he needed shoes.
Rym: So he wanted her on the mall.
Rym: He didn't find his shoes and then couldn't find a purse to match him.
Scott: enough with this stupidity There's a GameStop in the mall and the game stuff.
Rym: I went to this GameStop while Scott was looking for shoes.
Scott: I was at the GameStop also.
Rym: You couldn't find shoes with the right here.
Scott: They had The GameStop had two of the coolest GameStop employees ever.
Scott: they actually knew games and cared and they were cool.
Rym: Yep, cuz at first I mean it was normal GameStop banner and I was like whatever and the girl was kind of snarky.
Rym: But at the same time she expressed she said kind of like.
Rym: I forget what game but a really shitty game was awesome.
Rym: And I look and I think huh should I interact with this person?
Rym: Yes, I should.
Rym: What are you talking about?
Rym: That game's crap.
Rym: She's like, huh?
Rym: You're right blah blah blah.
Rym: I was being snarky.
Rym: Check it out.
Rym: How snarky I am.
Rym: No, I was.
Rym: I was paraphrasing the meaning.
Rym: she said something else but the meaning of her words was check out how snarky I am.
Scott: Yeah anyway We're not gonna talk like a pirate the whole show because last year people complained.
Scott: Well, I can my throat would complain even though my throat is like twice rims throat.
Rym: Yeah Well, the thing is we're getting.
Rym: we're getting better at this our voices.
Rym: I mean Otakon.
Rym: despite doing four shows I didn't lose my voice Me either but it was.
Scott: I was quite tired and I'm actually kind of tired now.
Scott: I mean, I think I need some extra because we stayed up all night playing a game that may or may not have come out One extra hour.
Rym: Yeah, but you also stayed up the previous night waiting for the game.
Scott: I think so not much though longer than you should have.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, anyway, it is anime manga comic day in addition to being a dishing addition to being talked like a pirate day.
Rym: So speaking of pirates, you might have heard of this anime called one piece.
Rym: Ah now one piece, uh I don't want to get into how I feel about one piece that the concept the style the aesthetics the characters the story Everything about this show is awesome.
Rym: And it's so up my alley.
Rym: I could cry Yeah, but the actual show is just crap.
Scott: The manga is also Like.
Scott: I read.
Scott: I have 11 volumes of the manga.
Scott: I own them right and like cuz I read like the first couple volumes.
Scott: they were awesome.
Scott: and then Like it got to a point where I realized that like, okay The last two volumes are just the same fight and it didn't stop.
Scott: and then it got back to awesome.
Scott: And then there was like two volumes of a fight and then eventually like in volumes 9 10 11 They fight the fish man, and they're just fighting the fish man for like three volumes and nothing happens.
Scott: and I'm like, what the hell?
Rym: It's one of those just shown in fighting shows that goes on forever.
Scott: But then in volume 11 like they get back to business and it's awesome.
Scott: And I'm like if only they cut out the fighting parts and made them like, you know Like just ten pages maybe of like there's a fight who wins and they just stuck with.
Scott: you know The way they're doing stuff for all the plot stuff.
Scott: It'd be like one of the best manga ever out by like 200 volumes of it.
Scott: but of course there would only be like 50 volumes because there's 150 volumes of Punch kick bite who knows what and I can't deal with that.
Rym: But aside from that the issue here is very simply that many of you may or may not have seen the English adaptation of one piece What is notoriously horrendous?
Rym: I believe there's a relevant VG cats about it.
Rym: that pretty much sums it up for you, but it awful might be a word terrible Disgusting Vomit a shis.
Rym: it's absolutely horrid.
Rym: I mean, I generally don't like a lot of dubs, but this one stands out for being particularly bad.
Scott: Particularly even more bad is the the hip-hop ish opening song.
Scott: They replaced the actual opening song.
Rym: man Why can't it be like Italy they have?
Scott: like the Italian opener to one piece is better than the Japanese.
Scott: open.
Rym: It's like the best opener to any anime ever.
Scott: I wouldn't go that far.
Rym: name a better one.
Rym: I really like the master Keaton opener, but try gun openers pretty cool.
Rym: It's okay the I like the song But the opener itself isn't great.
Rym: Okay good song and Open like an opener as a whole.
Rym: watching the one piece under seed has really awesome opening.
Rym: all right Yeah, I got to give you that Gundam seed head this way just pumping me the fuck off.
Rym: it sure did all right anyway, so Funimation, I don't know if we've talked about this or not is read dubbing one piece.
Scott: Well, what happened was that there the other people are putting out one piece, and then they stopped.
Scott: and good Yeah, then these people picked up one piece And they're putting out the volumes of one piece on DVD from where the other people left off.
Scott: But they're doing the dub better, and I guess they're doing it uncut.
Scott: ish all right.
Scott: And I forget what the status was if they're going to re-release the older Volumes to like make up for the ones the other people screwed up or not.
Rym: I could have looked that up.
Scott: I just didn't care because I don't really Actually really old news that the fact that they're redoing it.
Rym: the news is you if you live anywhere near Atlanta Or if you can wait, I don't know 24 hours for someone to upload whatever thing they film from it.
Rym: They're going to premiere the new dub at anime weekend, Atlanta, which I believe is this weekend.
Scott: Oh, I know a bunch of people who be there.
Scott: yeah Anime world order and all those people a bunch of other anime podcasters that aren't GeekNights.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: it's weird.
Rym: I there was a time when I would have gone to like any anime convention like just about it.
Rym: Atlanta is not that far away, but we got stuff doing this weekend.
Scott: Well.
Rym: It's more.
Rym: It's more than that.
Rym: It's that I can't we do so much stuff now with GeekNights that I just I can't justify going to a spike.
Rym: uber Con is probably the smallest con I could justify taking the time to go to.
Scott: well It's a gaming.
Rym: I can justify going to a lot smaller gaming con than anime con, but like the smallest anime Con I could really go to now is katsu con.
Scott: Yeah, maybe But in you know this like this weekend is going to be a crazy weekend of geekery.
Scott: There's all sorts of crazy geeky.
Rym: Yeah, because I'm doing the pregame for my first burning wheel game the first burning wheel campaign Our group has ever run.
Rym: that happens to be possibly about pirates.
Rym: Yeah, not right away, but eventually and we're also playing D&D and a bunch of other stuff, but also here I'm going to quote from anime news network the episodes which feature voice actress Colleen Clink beard clinking beard.
Scott: she was the girl on the way right in our match game.
Rym: Oh no no no I just I point out is talk like a pirate day and That's quite a pirate surname there.
Scott: Oh, oh it is you're right.
Scott: Yes thinking beer.
Rym: However dispelled on animators network as clink beard they did it.
Scott: did they do that on purpose for pirate day?
Scott: Or is that a mess up?
Rym: You know I'm not going to disparage anime news network because they're the only Useful press we get.
Rym: so I'll just leave it at that
Scott: all right, so my main man Kazuo Koike
Rym: known for various things that we may or may not have talked about Otakon and maybe not he's
Scott: known for lone wolf and cub believe it had gotten
Rym: in trouble for possibly
Scott: He started a new company.
Scott: the company is called Kazuo Koike Gekiga Sonjuku company limited and what this company is going to do is They're going to teach mangaka and other manga type creators about copyright and Intellectual property because a lot of them don't know and you know.
Scott: so this is going to be like hey Manga people now you can learn if people are ripping you off, and you can sue them and whatnot.
Scott: and I guess Kazuo Koike You know is sort of like.
Scott: I guess try to.
Scott: I guess he feels that like manga people He knows that manga people are getting scans lated and all this sort of business.
Scott: And he knows that a lot more manga people are making a lot of money by selling their manga to the u.s.
Scott: So he's trying to educate them into you know knowing their rights to intellectual property, so they don't get ripped off.
Rym: I mean, it's hard to say what the true motivation or result of this is going to be.
Scott: oh, yeah I have no idea, but that's what it seems like to me, and it's apparently this is an extension of his You know manga artist training program Which has been around for a long time and like a lot of famous mangaka have graduated from Kazuo Koike's manga training program.
Rym: like Rumiko Takahashi and other people's see I don't know how much piracy in America among English speakers would affect manga Because I don't think that the Japanese are going to be reading the English Scanslations of the manga in their country especially in manga so cheap.
Scott: no But I think that say if something gets like heavily pirated over here like that You know it might not be you know harder to license So you get less money for it seems to be.
Rym: there's something is heavily pirated over here.
Rym: that just is a signal that hey This is super popular.
Scott: I know, but you know who knows what?
Rym: those jetties are great.
Scott: They always they think backwards when it comes.
Rym: as far as we know they always license things based on Pay us a giant pile of money, and then do whatever you want in America.
Rym: Yeah, so it wouldn't really affect them unless the American company was unwilling to pay.
Scott: and well We know the Kazuo Koike must think that mangaka are clueless when it comes to Intellectual property and he's gonna edumacate them.
Rym: We'll see what you prevent piracy.
Rym: I things of the day.
Rym: I've stumbled upon this randomly when I was setting up a way.
Rym: if we're gonna go to uber con in any official capacity if we're Just gonna go and play games Sadly are things that they have nothing to do with pirates.
Rym: No not at all because that that's totally lame.
Rym: what I'm gonna Find?
Rym: a video of a pirate.
Rym: Maybe that one from That weird show with the girl with pink hair.
Scott: That's what I was just about to say.
Rym: yeah, no lazy town I'm not gonna do anything like that, but I stumbled upon this while I was looking into uber con and Apparently uber con.
Rym: I don't know if this is official or what, but I think it is.
Rym: it is a promo for the convention itself.
Scott: Oh, and it's not a bad idea.
Scott: you want people to come to your convention.
Scott: put a video on YouTube like hey look at our Convention it's all cool.
Scott: Well.
Rym: I've never seen anything like this before.
Rym: I don't know if other cons do it and I know like Otakon or something like that wouldn't do it because Otakon Doesn't really want more people to show up until the hotel expansion is built
Scott: And even then they only want enough people to show up extra to fill that hotel.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it's tough because like the new remember what happened at the New York Comic Con when they advertised heavily.
Scott: Yeah They advertised on television bad move for a geek convention.
Scott: cuz now everyone and their mother shows up And you don't have room for them.
Scott: well
Rym: I mean the real issue is that one New York City has more people in it than a lot of countries and
Scott: more geeks than A lot of places
Rym: yes, and two it's very easy to get to the Javits from anywhere in the downstate area Especially for one day, but more to the point advertising in mainstream media in any capacity for any kind of geeky con I Honestly think does super super well, and I think anime world order touched on this a while ago.
Rym: But you realize that people like us who are you know we're geeky and we're into geeky things like we watch anime Or we read comics, but we're also on the internet, and we talk about it And we consume media related to but not directly coming from our interests.
Rym: Yeah, we're actively geeky.
Scott: I mean I don't just play video games You know, but I also go out and I read blogs about video games, and I forum about video games.
Scott: We're podcast about video game.
Scott: We're
Rym: on the radar and all of you are on the radar too because you listen to things like this The majority of anime fans the majority of comic fans the majority of manga fans
Scott: The vast majority like 90% don't
Rym: even know that Conventions exist or at most they know there's a local con that they go to every year, and that's it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean most video game people.
Scott: they they might read a video game magazine Maybe and they kind of go to their game stop every once in a while And they see what's on the shelf and they see if there's anything they like and all that stuff that like.
Scott: we see that You know we say oh, it's just hype blah blah blah blah blah.
Scott: That's all they get.
Scott: is that hype?
Rym: if they even get that and that more importantly They're not on the radar in the sense that they don't talk about their video games on the internet.
Rym: So the internet and all the press around geekery tends to become kind of a an echo chamber where?
Rym: We see the news that we're interested in and the news agencies and the news people and I guess people like us Talk about the news that we think we're all interested in and those people are just totally out of that loop.
Scott: Think about this right.
Scott: here is an example.
Scott: Team Fortress 2 right just came with the beta and everything.
Rym: Most video game people have no clue, dude I was playing fortress forever and when I brought up Team Fortress 2 hardly anyone knew what it was.
Scott: Yep, I mean there was like one guy who was like yeah, it's coming out whoo.
Rym: But anyway a promo like this I think is actually a great idea especially for a con that can and wants to expand.
Rym: I mean say you didn't know anything about gaming and you didn't know that they're like you play games.
Rym: So you didn't know there was a gaming con or you didn't know what they were about and you saw this hot shit.
Rym: I want to go to that.
Scott: Yeah I mean what's better advertisement for a convention than videos of the convention on YouTube?
Scott: people can see what actually goes on there and If that's something they would like they'd be like, oh man.
Scott: Look there's something going on at that place.
Scott: I want to go to that place also.
Rym: this promo in particular is very well done and it is an exact Indication of what uber con is like.
Rym: to the point cuz.
Rym: I've been going for a number of years.
Scott: I watched it and I was like, oh, I'm an uber con.
Scott: Oh wait.
Scott: No, I'm not.
Rym: I mean I went for.
Rym: yeah, I went for a while but before Scott even when I would have you had one time before I Went.
Rym: yeah, that was a long time before it was one time.
Scott: Yeah, you went to one more uber con than me.
Rym: Yes, I did.
Rym: And you know what all our other friends have only been to one uber con.
Rym: Yeah, it's true I played more Lou Crane than you.
Rym: Oh, no But The con is the same every year like it's the same people.
Rym: There's the.
Rym: if you watch this video like we're watching it and it's like all right all that guy.
Rym: I know that guy.
Rym: I know those kids.
Rym: I played a game with that guy.
Rym: that is katsu and Alex our friends.
Scott: Yeah, this video has our friends playing guitar hero in it.
Scott: It's pretty cool.
Scott: We didn't even expect that.
Scott: and then oh look there They are okay.
Rym: Yeah, but the thing is I thought back and every uber con I've ever been to I see the same people the same vendors the Same everything.
Scott: it was even one guy that I always saw at uber con and I saw him at kinetic con and I was like Do I know you from somewhere?
Scott: He's like probably uber cause.
Scott: the only con I go to this is the first non uber con con I've been to and I'm like, oh man, I seen you.
Rym: Yep So uber con is kind of like this close-knit family of gamers in Jersey, North Jersey.
Rym: If you're a gamer totally check out uber con, it's awesome and we'll be there Alright.
Scott: check this thing of the day already.
Scott: This made me laugh a lot.
Rym: You know the lol cats and the pursuant lol rats.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Well It was bound to happen if it was obvious if you thought about it.
Scott: lol thulu kathulu photography cheeseburger.
Scott: I Has color it from beyond space.
Rym: I think my favorite one is cat like tike it typing Detected and it's kathulu trying to type kathulu for talking.
Scott: I made you a fish god cult, but I eat it it.
Scott: I'm off your coast mutating your village.
Rym: I was actually laughing out loud when I read because I've seen like the one or two of these every now and then but a Bunch of them together.
Rym: It's kind of like a bunch of evil artifacts all in one room.
Rym: It's just it.
Rym: the power of the south then overwhelms is greater than the individual part.
Scott: It's like when a guy detects magic and there's like a magic rod and he goes Magic rod and a guy detects magic in like the magic throne room and he goes blind.
Scott: your sanity has flavor nom nom nom.
Rym: So back to piracy.
Rym: we're gonna talk about piracy and copyright and all that business and how it relates to the anime industry because anime is really this weird gray area and there's still there.
Rym: there hasn't really been a consensus as to how to deal with it and It's changed so much even in the past few years that I mean remember when we got to school like when we got to RIT the idea of digital fansubs online was still unheard of.
Rym: and when I downloaded the eskaflowne Fansub and burned it to a CD and brought it to club People freaked out and half the club was like you're a dirty pirate and half the club was like I see the future Yep, like.
Scott: I didn't even really understand what was going on at first like digital.
Rym: What I don't guess.
Rym: I mean I had 40 or 50 VHS tapes that were fansubs of things that I'd gotten from fansubbers from either mailing them VHS's or from buying them for like $2 each.
Scott: and then someone had a CD-ROM that had the eskaflowne in the movie and I Was like what?
Rym: Yeah, I don't get it.
Rym: and for me the CD-ROM I made because I downloaded it from a website Yep, and I thought wait a minute.
Rym: What if more Japanese shows that I can't get ahold of are on the internet?
Scott: Well, really this to me this is the issue here right?
Scott: you look at something like music piracy, right?
Scott: Well, I guess music piracy of music from the record labels, right?
Scott: You're in the country where these things are available.
Scott: They are making these things available to you.
Scott: They're in the store.
Scott: You can buy them.
Scott: the original one It's.
Scott: it's not like.
Scott: it's inaccessible, you know, and the only reason the pirate it is just did not pay.
Scott: You know cuz you don't you don't want to pay for it.
Scott: It's right there.
Scott: There it is.
Scott: It's not like some other place.
Scott: gets it first and then you get it later.
Scott: It's not like you know.
Scott: It's in a different language and you need to translate it.
Scott: It's just if you pirate it, you're you're just.
Scott: you're avoiding paying for it Which you know.
Scott: when I was in high school in college, I was all about pirating things, you know video games music Whatever because I had a lot of free time and not a lot of money.
Scott: So even you know moral quandaries aside and of course all this is illegal I Felt it was in my best interest to pirate things because I had plenty of time to go and dig around Peer-to-peer networks to get the music and not enough money to buy it.
Scott: So pirating got me more stuff and I was spending time I didn't care about and saving money, which I didn't care about.
Rym: see the thing is though It's weird how I always treated anime differently.
Rym: I mean I pirated music like Constantly possibly maybe not deniability here since I'm talking to an audience But I may or may not have downloaded many many many many many gigabytes of music from American labels foreign labels Whatever and I fired in movies maybe and all those things, but I never.
Rym: well, it's funny I never I would say I never pirated anime, but I did download fan subs and I guess the difference in my mind and aligns a lot of anime fans Especially back then was that a lot of that anime was not available in English period.
Scott: yeah I mean legally.
Scott: there is no question all.
Scott: it's all illegal.
Scott: It's all illegal.
Scott: There is no question about it.
Scott: No dispute, whatever.
Scott: but morally like You know it's like morally.
Scott: I sort of justified myself pirating music because the evil record companies.
Scott: They're overpriced.
Rym: I didn't justify it at all.
Rym: I thought I'm totally stealing this because technology lets me I also did that too.
Rym: I never even once said to myself what I'm doing is right.
Rym: I thought man.
Rym: This is totally awesome.
Rym: He's totally illegal.
Scott: Like I guess more of the time I would justify pirating software.
Scott: like you know yeah This is they can't possibly expect me to pay $800 for the software.
Scott: I absolutely need to do these things.
Rym: You know I never did that either when I pirated software.
Scott: I thought goddamn I just stole 800 bucks, but when it came to anime you know the moral justification was this is a Japanese thing.
Scott: It's not gonna be available over here.
Scott: It's like it.
Scott: There's no way that I can ever see this in my language without breaking the law.
Scott: It is a work of art that is inaccessible to me.
Scott: It's like if you went into the museum and someone put a piece of cloth over the painting And I'm just lifting up the cloth.
Scott: what what's so bad about that?
Rym: you know but Obviously technology in the last five to ten years has changed things dramatically and also because of interest in anime spawned largely from these original fan subs and whatever.
Rym: Anime is super popular in the US and most anime That's I mean most anime period gets released in English legally, and you can just go buy a DVD.
Scott: Yeah, I mean a lot of people have even been like oh, this is never getting released over here And then it does it's.
Scott: you know it might not be a good release.
Scott: It might be an overpriced release bandai visual, but it comes out.
Scott: I mean they're putting out crazy shit.
Scott: the only stuff that really isn't getting released is like super old Obscure stuff like if it's old, but it's got any measure of popularity.
Scott: It's coming out.
Rym: Sazai-san's not getting released.
Scott: No Sazai-san is something That's not gonna get released.
Scott: You know, but I mean isn't crayon Shin-chan is on like Cartoon Network Like you know they got.
Scott: go lion Which is what Voltron was in Japanese is gonna be coming out.
Scott: All this stuff that we said this will never ever ever be in released in the US legally.
Scott: It's coming now.
Rym: You know this is the point where a normal show.
Rym: We just we talked about the history and we talked about you know well at the gray area this and here the blah blah blah blah and we're gonna skip all that and just get right to How we feel about it today as it stands.
Rym: forget the past forget the rationales in the past Forget but fan subs brought the industry up.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: Here's how we look at it right now.
Scott: Well right now the way I look at it is this right if there's an anime that is Super duper old right and the odds of it coming out in the US are super super low for example Space runaway idaeon right that's not coming out here, man It's just not it.
Rym: or if it does it'll come out a long time for now and we'd probably just buy it.
Scott: or a legend the galactic heroes.
Scott: Right that show yeah, but these shows people are fansubbing them and rightly so.
Scott: they are making an old work of art that I That while yes, it's all illegal but if I had my way and I think a lot of people agree that's so old it should be in the public domain and There's no way any person who doesn't speak Japanese and doesn't want to spend a lot of money to buy DVDs from a foreign land which is also sort of illegal to buy region 2 DVDs and play them in the US.
Rym: I mean it varies from country to country and all these things.
Rym: but Region law I won't get into it.
Scott: No.
Scott: But like it is illegal to say buy a Japanese DDR machine to bring it to the US and play it Yep, and it was the music is licensed Yeah.
Scott: And it's similarly illegal to say buy a legend of the galactic heroes region 2 DVD from Japan and watch it in the US.
Scott: So you could probably do it legally if you paid certain tariffs basically illegal for you to experience This work of art in a way that you can understand.
Rym: Oh, I thought I'm forget the legal argument.
Rym: if it is or is not actually legal because of that I have no problem, right?
Scott: I have no moral quandary with Downloading a fansub of that show and watching it even though it's illegal.
Rym: Well, I was just gonna say regarding region 2 DVDs.
Rym: Ah The fact that DVDs are so expensive in Japan pretty much precludes me from ever buying a Japanese DVD no matter what.
Scott: Nope, pretty much unless they decide to go with reasonable pricing which also extends to Bandai visuals releases.
Scott: Yes, it does which I might.
Rym: I'll be honest.
Rym: I might just pirate them.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: Maybe the price is just too much.
Scott: The price is just too much.
Scott: I'm.
Scott: probably what I'm gonna do is Netflix them or
Rym: if Netflix even bothers to get
Scott: I'm gonna wait an incredibly long amount of time like a couple years and then they'll have to bring the prices down because all these retailers who just were stupid and bought them will Have all these extra copies lying around and they can't get rid of them and they'll be in a discount bin one day.
Rym: But anyway, here is the way I like right now in terms of fansubs and all that.
Rym: I look at it pretty simply.
Rym: I want to watch what's on in Japan right now, like I was watching on TV.
Rym: So what we do is I download, you know, the fansubs of shows that are coming out right now.
Rym: You know episode 1 episode 2 episode 3 and watch them and see if I like them.
Rym: if a show is really good I'll probably just keep watching it as it comes out in Japan until it finishes and then I'll be done with it if I don't super like it and Or I just don't watch it even though I did like it and eventually once it's released once it comes out in the u.s.
Scott: Which is taking less and less time then at that point.
Rym: I have absolutely zero justification for fansubs.
Rym: I'll delete him if I've got him.
Rym: I won't even think about watching him and I'll just Netflix the DVDs.
Rym: notice.
Rym: I didn't say bye.
Scott: Yep I will buy the DVDs if it is a show that I know I'm gonna watch more than once because it's awesome.
Scott: And if it's in like a reasonably priced thin pack box set of some sort, I'm not buying individual DVDs anymore.
Scott: I'm not buying huge DVD boxes.
Scott: forget that I don't have space on my shelf And that's a price.
Scott: I'm not willing to pay when I could go with Netflix.
Rym: Yeah, Netflix, honestly Netflix is the sole reason I stopped buying anime, right?
Scott: But if you sell me your 26 episode show for 40 bucks and a little tiny box, I'll totally buy that.
Rym: Well, the thing is a lot of anime they're not like so great that I would like go out and spend money to see.
Scott: It's got to be a good show.
Rym:  no No What I'm saying is what I would do is that kind of show if it were available on TV in the u.s Like it is in Japan.
Rym: I would probably have a TV in cable and just watch that anime.
Scott: Well, a lot of the shows are on TV in the u.s.
Scott: But the thing is I don't have a TV.
Rym: Well, no, they're not.
Rym: they're on TV far after I was wanting to see them.
Rym: Oh, but now I'm talking like right now a show this out right now in Japan.
Rym: I would just watch it on TV as it's on in America as it's on in Japan in America if that was available to me.
Scott: Yeah, see sort of the other.
Rym: the thing is is well, but you know I say I'll watch it on TV.
Rym: when I say watch anything on TV That means I would also own a TiVo and I would watch it whenever I wanted blocking out or skipping all the commercials.
Rym: now Funny.
Rym: so if it were legal like say why was watching one piece in the u.s.
Rym: On Cartoon Network or whatever?
Rym: Alright, I would use a TiVo right?
Rym: I would watch it whenever I wanted and I would skip the commercials.
Rym: So effectively I've gotten the same thing that I would have gotten if I'd watch the fan sub.
Scott: Well, the thing is is is the way Advertising works.
Scott: I don't want to start talking about this But the TV network if you TiVo it even though you block the ad when I say Number goes up by one and they can tell the advertiser that one more person is watching even though they can get more money.
Rym: But the thing is I didn't actually watch the ad.
Scott: I does it.
Scott: Yeah, but that doesn't matter all but plus two.
Rym: when I say TiVo I mean, you know myth TV.
Rym: Yes, I wouldn't pay for a TiVo.
Scott: No, I wouldn't pay for TiVo either.
Scott: But yeah, that's you know the.
Scott: if you TiVo did or myth TV'd it the The TV company would still get money from the advertiser, but they'd be scamming the advertiser, but that's what anyone who's Sells ads is doing anyway.
Rym: Well, the point I'm trying to make is I'm making a purely functional argument that functionally and I'm not using this is not a justification argument It's just.
Rym: I note it as interesting.
Rym: watching a fan sub of a show that's on TV in Japan as it comes out is Pretty much the same as Watching the show as it comes out legally through legal means but not watching the commercials.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: So functionally there's no difference between the two.
Rym: but legally and some would argue morally there is and I find that interesting.
Scott: Yeah, the other thing is that I pretty much refuse morally speaking to buy something sight unseen.
Scott: I mean you wouldn't buy anything without seeing it at least some of it first, you know You wouldn't buy a car without looking at it.
Scott: Someone has like a car under a sheet.
Scott: Do you want this car?
Scott: ten bucks?
Scott: Like I don't know what they could be a piece of poop under that sheet.
Scott: What do I know?
Scott: you always you got to see something before you pay money?
Rym: That's either a really big piece of poop or you're really credulous.
Scott: Yeah, who knows?
Scott: It could be a piece of poop in the car on the seat.
Scott: I'll smear it in who knows.
Scott: Anyway, so the way things work now is that sure?
Scott: some anime series are on American television be it Cartoon Network or something else.
Scott: Some movies are actually in the theaters and I go to see those.
Scott: you actually the Miyazakis and the the Satoshi Kans and whatnot.
Scott: But a lot of the anime especially the ones that I'm interested in are not on television in the u.s.
Scott: I don't have a television.
Scott: I'm not gonna get television or pay for cable because it's not worth it to me.
Scott: and The only way for me to see these shows is Netflix which I'll do or buy DVDs and I'm you know the Netflix queue is well, you know sort of cheap is limited and DVDs are expensive.
Scott: and I'm not gonna Netflix or get something on DVD if I haven't seen it now.
Scott: if I was in Japan I'd be able to see it for free on television and block ads with the TiVo.
Scott: But in the u.s.
Scott: I can't do that and there's a fan sub.
Rym: except in the u.s.
Rym: I can with fan subs exactly.
Scott: So I go and I get the fans up and I that's my ice You know, I'm gonna see it to decide if it's worth watching anymore.
Scott: It's it's my moral.
Scott: I guess I feel it's my moral right to see something before I go in with any sort of amount of money for it.
Scott: Yeah, of course up is the only way for me to do that.
Rym: the exception to that I guess would be movies as opposed to TV shows.
Rym: Oh, yeah, because I don't see the sixth sense before I go to the theater to see the sixth sense.
Rym: No, but I guess I have the sixth sense.
Scott: But that's the other thing is like I usually don't see an anime movie and let until it actually comes out in the u.s.
Rym: Well, the thing is partly because we live in downstate New York.
Rym: if an anime movie comes out in the u.s There's a good chance.
Rym: It'll be in the theater and we just go see it in the theater exactly, which is awesome.
Scott: And also if it you know The movies tend to come out in the u.s.
Scott: And there tend to be trailers that I can see on the internet for free legally.
Scott: Also, you know while a lot of the anime companies now are getting wise they're like selling downloads of their shows and they're putting some Free episodes up.
Scott: they're putting them up way after the.
Scott: you know Japanese have it on their television.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Now we know there are reasons for this.
Rym: a lot of people speculate.
Scott: I just can't do it any faster.
Rym: Well, no a lot of people speculate that the reasons many shows are released far later than they I guess technically could have been because There's some fansubbers who do a bang up freaking job right away or pretty quickly.
Rym: There's also some fansubbers who totally suck, but I'm not gonna talk about that I don't even care who fans up something.
Rym: But it seems like in a lot of cases the Japanese company will put some sort of stipulation like yeah You can license our show but you can't release it until x-date because we're afraid of Re-importation because American DVDs cost less than half what Japanese DVDs cause.
Scott: and I say to that that the I actually I'm not even joking Or you know hyperbole in here.
Scott: I think the Japanese companies that are selling DVDs are Highway robbing the Japanese people.
Scott: the prices they charge for DVDs are Criminal.
Scott: it's really criminal.
Scott: a DVD cost less than like a dollar to print.
Scott: Alright the show, you know, you made your a ton of money for that show on.
Scott: you know TV with your advertisements and whatnot You.
Scott: you can sell the DVDs for like 20 bucks.
Scott: I bet I'll you know the same price we sell them for here.
Scott: Yeah I bet a whole bunch of people will buy them who don't normally buy things because you charge so much freaking money for them.
Rym: I mean we.
Rym: part of it was just that they kind of have a monopoly on the market Partly due to all this region locking crap that's around.
Rym: and I mean it's hard to say how the Japanese Economy and market would deal with cheaper DVDs and whatever.
Rym: but the point is regardless of the reasons and regardless of what would happen if they lowered them the prices are way too high and Obviously the Japanese people know this because the Japanese companies are super afraid of competition from their u.s.
Scott: Licenses and capitalism you lose.
Rym: But to really simplify it here's how I go about it very very simply if a show has not been released in the u.s Yet I'll watch the fan subs.
Rym: if it's been released in the US and it's a show that I want to see again and show To other people I'll buy it a whole box set immediately as soon as
Scott: long as there is a box set that you can buy And it's not like individual DVDs for 30 bucks each.
Rym: yeah, if it's a show that I don't want to own and there aren't many shows I want to own I'll Netflix it and that'll be the end of it.
Rym: and The only other thing I can say is that if there's a bootleg pirated copy fuck whoever's selling it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the only thing that's really changed in terms of myself Is that you know back in the day if there was a show that you know was available in the u.s.
Scott: On DVD that I wanted to own and watch again and again I couldn't afford it and I had plenty of free time and no money.
Scott: So I would actually you know download it in lieu of purchasing it.
Scott: But it's not like if I downloaded it.
Scott: I wouldn't purchase it.
Scott: It was.
Scott: I couldn't purchase it even if I didn't download it.
Scott: so they weren't really losing money.
Scott: And now that time is more valuable to me than money.
Scott: I'll buy it if I want it and So they're getting all the money from me that they were ever gonna get whether or not fan subs existed.
Scott: In fact, they're getting more money from me because if I wasn't able to see the fan sub and know I wanted the show I wouldn't have bought anything.
Rym: But I do want to take a moment to talk a little bit about actual pirates as in the people who sell People
Scott: who are on boats with rocket launchers to hold up your boat or
Rym: the people who sell you know Chinese bootleg copies of anime or whatever For actual money for a profit
Scott: or the people who take fan subs off the internet burn them the CDs and sell them
Rym: Yeah, or in particular in the mall.
Rym: here I mean we have a cool anime store in the mall and we have another mall that's not as crappy.
Rym: and in that mall There's another anime store and the anime store in the mall sells straight-up bootlegs.
Scott: Yeah, not even joking like yeah, these are bootleg right here in the mall We're selling them.
Rym: and the thing I want to say cuz I remember anime world order talked about this up in depth.
Rym: And if actually if you want to learn about the anime bootlegging quote-unquote industry Search for the anime world order episode about that because they go into very interesting detail and it's actually talking about mafias and stuff.
Rym: The only point with I disagree with them on.
Rym: And while I don't disagree with them when it comes to like posters and wall scrolls and all those things even CDs But when it comes to anime DVDs There is no excuse.
Rym: There is no way you could see a bootleg anime DVD and not know immediately that that's a bootleg.
Rym: They're always packaged really weird.
Scott: The colors are always weird the colors are faded and the packaging is not like DVD packaging you see in Best Buy.
Scott: I mean, you're always getting a whole bunch of episodes and like very few discs.
Scott: It'll be like season one through three of Naruto for 50 bucks.
Scott: There is no way that is not a bootleg.
Scott: It's obvious.
Rym: people Chinese writing all over the bag will notice that the cheap DVD they see from the guy at on the street is Weird looking compared to the one they saw in Best Buy.
Rym: There was a lot more money.
Rym: I know it's not like.
Rym: they say oh, it's cheap.
Rym: I'll buy it.
Rym: Haha pirate.
Rym: It's they really don't know.
Rym: and if that's true I think you've got problems because it's not that hard to tell.
Rym: Yeah, I can say with certainty that I've never been fooled.
Scott: I've never ever been fooled by a bootleg DVD.
Scott: They're obvious Super obvious when a DVD is not profession.
Scott: I think the part of the problem though is that people sort of they might not realize that You know, they're the even this big.
Scott: this thing exists the bootlegging, you know, it's like they see a DVD for sale.
Scott: It's a DVD for sale what they don't know it, you know
Rym: I could see that I guess outside of urban areas But in like in New York City if you go anywhere You're gonna run into some Chinese woman at some point who says DVD want DVD DVD and if you can make eye contact with her She'll open her coat and she has a bunch of Super shady looking.
Rym: they usually just
Scott: have my sheet on the side for like
Rym: four bucks Yep,
Scott: and I think people who buy those I think most of them know they're bootlegging like hey getting move your Jeep Whatever, you know that they really don't you know,
Rym: I mean if someone knows it's a bootleg.
Rym: I still think you're a crappy person for buying the bootleg, but as long as you're not lying to yourself I don't hate you.
Scott: Well, I think the problem is is even if they're not lying to themselves like yeah buying a bootleg They don't really have in their mind like what that really means down the line.
Scott: They're just like yeah, this is Technically shady whatever it does They don't actually understand, you know like the whole like what's behind that DVD and how you know this bootleg came to be and and the whole market behind it ever.
Scott: they don't understand or even think about those things.
Scott: and I think if they did they might think twice before buying the bootleg DVD or Not who knows?
Rym: Yeah, but it just it frightens me that so many that there is such a market for bootlegs because it's not like they're Well done like that.
Rym: I like those old sewn May CDs, which I got burned by those a couple of times.
Rym: Yeah, well not really burned by them because honestly the sewn May CDs were super high quality and a lot of times They were better than the actual CD.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you just take the actual CD you copy it perfectly like they're perfect.
Rym: But the DVDs like they're so obviously bootlegs.
Rym: You'd have to be really dense to not realize that this DVD is there's something wrong with it that there's something shady going on Yeah, and I think a lot of people who say oh I got burned Yeah, I didn't realize it was a bootleg are just lying to cover for the fact that they bought a bootleg.
Scott: Yep, and You know if you're gonna buy bootleg what that's?
Scott: the other thing that's because the fan subs exist.
Scott: It sort of makes the bootleg stupid.
Scott: It's like you're either gonna if you're trying to save money just get the stupid fans up.
Scott: At least you're not giving money to some bootleg scum guy, you know.
Scott: And if you're not trying to save money and you're gonna buy it buy the real deal.
Scott: It's better You're gonna get more of your money.
Scott: Why would you settle for some piece of shit bootleg?
Scott: if you're willing to pay for something buy something?
Scott: That's actually quality Don't?
Scott: yeah?
Scott: shit.
Scott: I mean remember that you can get better.
Scott: you can get better than shit for free.
Rym: You got Johnson bought that planet s bootleg and it was the fat.
Rym: basically it was okay for two episodes and Then the fan subs degenerated into literally gibberish.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it's like you can get better than shit for free and you can get amazed.
Scott: You know a really really awesome copy for money.
Scott: Why would you ever pay money less money than the awesome copy for worse than the free one?
Scott: It makes no sense I think even regardless of the harm that bootlegs cause.
Scott: you're only making a stupid decision for yourself When you buy a bootleg because you could get better with a fan sub and if you're willing to pay money You can get better for your money.
Rym: All right on that note I wish you all a yaring talk like a pirate day, even though it's almost over.
Rym: Oh, hey, I gotta get back to playing some Team Fortress 2 or I'm gonna boss.
Scott: actually I kind of want to play Metroid more.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.