Scott: It's Tuesday October 2nd.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We discuss the burning wheel.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: I beat that new Metroid game a few days ago.
Scott: Oh, did you yeah?
Rym: So um how was it?
Scott: it was the Metroid game?
Scott: What I don't know really it's it's weird like it's a fun game.
Scott: I played it I beat it, but this really does not much to say.
Rym: I mean well Imagine part of that because I remember you were showing Emily the end of Super Metroid And how it was such a better ending then.
Scott: Super Metroid is one of the best game endings that ever was.
Rym: I think it is Too because I remember just well.
Rym: I don't want to spoil it in case there's anyone out here who hasn't played that game, but yeah.
Scott: But I mean the end of the new Metroid is isn't really a spoiler, but it's like you beat the bad guys You win the end.
Scott: I mean, maybe I could have gotten a better ending with a hundred percent completion But I got over 75% completion and when I when I finally got the 75% completion the game popped up a message that said Congratulations, you're gonna get a better game ending than usual because you got 75%.
Scott: huh better, but not best.
Rym: They got to have some carrot for the hundred percenters.
Scott: They must have some carrot out there, but I don't know if I'm gonna go for that carrot.
Scott: You know it's really not that hard.
Scott: I was looking like around the around the game And I don't think it would be too difficult to get a hundred percent complete When you could just look on YouTube.
Scott: yeah, I really wouldn't be worth it by looking YouTube.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: there's the whole idea of better endings for getting a larger percentage of arbitrary secrets or arbitrary things.
Rym: I just I lost patience with that like eight years ago.
Scott: Yes, if you want to do different endings the size just the end your only option is chrono trigger method Which is depending on how you beat the game?
Rym: Yeah, it has to be some sort of or Bioshock rational decision you make as opposed to just oh You got 49 of the BAF my dad's.
Rym: you're gonna get the ending where Dracula's hand comes up.
Rym: Oh Yeah, you know I never legitimately got anything But the worst ending in Castlevania 2 despite how many times you got any ending.
Scott: Castlevania 2. it's not worth playing that long.
Scott: It's awesome.
Scott: I don't know what that says me and that says angry.
Scott: video game.
Rym: nerd Castlevania 2 in my opinion sucks is the best Castlevania before Symphony of the night?
Scott: Because symphony Castlevania for the SNES super Castlevania is really good But it's like the best Castlevania before Symphony tonight.
Rym: Castlevania 2 was just so good.
Rym: No Not as good as I do.
Scott: No, you're just wrong.
Rym: Zelda - there was a good you tell me Mario - is better Mario 3 No, but it's better than Mario 1.
Scott: you suck.
Rym: I like Mario 1 I think Mario -.
Scott: oh I think the lost levels are on the virtual console.
Scott: now I'm gonna go check it all hot cuz.
Scott: I have them on the Game Boy Color But that's kind of hard to play with my Diaz.
Rym: see that's how they get us.
Scott: I know that's how they get us plus I don't know it.
Rym: I'm not gonna buy every virtual console game because I do feel like it's kind of a ripoff to buy them all.
Rym: but There's some games where I feel like.
Rym: that is now the definitive version.
Rym: It's just so perfect like Mario 1 on the Wii is amazing.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's better than Mario 1 and anywhere else Especially if it's the original lost levels and not that kind of re graphic crap.
Scott: remake Yep, so to make up for the fact that the the match the new Wii.
Scott: Metroid Corruption was a good game overall, but not too exciting in any particular way.
Scott: once it's finished Playing Super Metroid virtual console Yeah, I noticed that when I came home a much better game than pretty much every other game ever.
Scott: It's like if you look at like the top best games ever at least single-player games.
Scott: It's like Half-Life Half-Life 2 Super Metroid Some people say Bioshock maybe System Shock 2 maybe.
Scott: yeah, I've not barely played it so far But I've played it more than zero which is what how much I played it a few weeks ago.
Scott: Yeah, oh well see a Super Metroid.
Scott: Play that.
Rym: so in the news And I mean there's probably legitimate or interesting news out there in regards to the 50 games and the board game I can't.
Scott: well halo 3 whatever.
Scott: I can't find.
Rym: I think we already said that halo 3 came out and What else could I say other than that it came out?
Rym: And I believe a lot of people are getting the ring of death probably because they're suddenly using their x-boxes again.
Scott: My boss actually has an Xbox.
Scott: he used it to play the Gears of War and now he's gonna use it to play halo 3.
Scott: Wow ever used it.
Rym: Otherwise see honestly find an Xbox.
Rym: I probably would just be playing Carcassonne.
Scott: Yeah, that live arcade is pretty much all of you do.
Scott: I'm playing Uno with the webcam Carcassonne.
Rym: if they ever set it up like if they said alright Xbox Live Arcade is now available on Vista.
Rym: I would upgrade That second.
Rym: maybe I would teleport into a best buy.
Scott: that's how much it was.
Rym: I'd be willing to pay almost as much as an Xbox.
Scott: people are actually starting to be pretty hard on Vista like Listen to the most recent twit.
Scott: I know I know and they were talking like They were talking that like they were treating Vista like Windows ME.
Scott: See, it's pretty harsh.
Rym: Did they have anything legitimate?
Rym: because I mean this is not great.
Rym: I'm not gonna say it's pretty much there.
Scott: One of the guys on the show wrote a really good article and I didn't read the article so I don't know.
Rym: I mean basically the only reason I use Windows anyway is for gaming.
Rym: So if gaming goes to Vista, I'm going to Vista.
Rym: if gaming skips Vista I'm skipping Vista.
Scott: basically the thing is right now.
Scott: if you want DirectX 10 you need Vista but in terms of most games in general what people seem to say is that the performance is worse on Vista and Vista doesn't really do anything that Windows XP doesn't do.
Rym: Well, one thing it does very well is not be fully patched and ready and tested.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, I guess right but I gotta talk about this.
Rym: I'm not gonna talk about it much.
Rym: It's kind of like when the Wii name was announced.
Rym: it ever went.
Scott: Oh my god It made Wii jokes and now everyone calls it Wii and doesn't even think about revolution.
Rym: I know I tried so hard.
Rym: I remember when it came out.
Rym: I was like, no one's gonna call it the physical plant capstone.
Scott: I'm calling it the Phoenix Firebird Fire something.
Rym: yeah, I'm gonna call it the revolution because that would seem so cool, you know the revolution the Nintendo Revolution Wii.
Rym: it's the Wii.
Rym: it's over.
Scott: Anyway, so Nintendo you fought the good fight.
Rym: I thought you thought you second you fought the fight not as long as me.
Rym: So apparently and this is all over the news.
Rym: This shouldn't be news to anyone Nintendo is going to be packaging and giving away with all the new systems or all the new controllers a Big rubber condom for the wiimotes.
Scott: Yep, I mean first they made the strap then they made a better strap and a better strap and a better strap.
Scott: first They made the strap and now they in the best possible strap, I guess with also a Wii condom No remote condom.
Rym: What bothers me is that?
Rym: Anyone could find fault with the original strap.
Rym: Do you understand the sheer?
Rym: Misuse you would have to apply yourself to to break that strap.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: No, it's impossible for an intelligent human being to let go of a wiimote.
Rym: Yep, let alone break that strap.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Obviously they weren't wearing the strap first of all.
Rym: Yeah, but remember a lot of people claim that yeah the strap broke even though I believe most of those people were lying.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But yeah, a lot of people are talking, you know, why would Nintendo do this?
Rym: or it looks dumb or it look.
Rym: It doesn't matter.
Rym: most people aren't gonna use this.
Rym: you know, why Nintendo is releasing this?
Rym: I'm gonna let you all in on a little secret that you may or may not realize.
Rym: This is nothing more than Nintendo saying see we did our due diligence And now you can't sue us if you break your big-screen TV, and yeah, yeah.
Scott: Well, I think a lot of that stuff about you know, people break in wiim.
Scott: You know their TVs at their wiimotes early on was a lot of.
Scott: it was greatly over exaggerated But regardless it created sort of a PR problem for Nintendo and Nintendo is very smart and they realize that the number one Most important thing to making money is not having a good product not having anything else.
Scott: The number one most important thing to making a lot of money in big business is public relations.
Scott: So they said hey is the most important thing if we have bad public relations?
Scott: You know and there's bad stories about us in the news.
Scott: We're done.
Scott: So they did everything they possibly could.
Scott: they don't care How much money it costs to fix that and they did fix that and now they're going.
Rym: ah Money, I have seen some people make the comment that it looks like I mean It would make the wiimote a little bit thicker feeling.
Rym: if you have big hands or you feel like the remotes flimsy It might just make it feel better in your hand.
Scott: It might.
Scott: I could see that we can get them.
Scott: They're free.
Scott: You want to get them?
Rym: I figure we should get them.
Rym: if something is free, you know tragedy the Commons.
Rym: Let's go right in there.
Scott: All right I'll go fill out the thing and get him for free because I never.
Scott: I'm still using the original straps from the because we got The Wii day one.
Scott: so I have the original straps.
Scott: We can get the new ones.
Rym: I've never put the strap around my wrist.
Scott: I always use the strip.
Rym: I just don't.
Rym: if I ever own my own wiimote Which I will once they make a special wiimote so I can be all cool.
Scott: I don't know if they're ever gonna.
Rym: someday they will you know, they will and I'll get some black or pink wiimote.
Rym: I'm not gonna put the strap on it.
Rym: I'm a rebel.
Scott: Yeah, one day you're gonna be playing WarioWare or something in there.
Rym: Oh, yeah, cuz I'm ever gonna play WarioWare for the fucking Wii again.
Rym: That was the best game ever.
Scott: Everybody come out with another one.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what?
Rym: They're probably.
Rym: I mean remember WarioWare for the GameCube was such a fluke and they don't understand why it was a good game.
Rym: I'm not convinced that Nintendo will ever realize why that WarioWare was a good game.
Scott: I just think they don't think about and they don't care.
Rym: Hence, I highly doubt that I will ever play a WarioWare game again Except WarioWare for the GameCube, which for a long time was the best game on the Wii.
Scott: All right So, you know Gabe Newell He's like one of the co-founders of valve.
Rym: I've heard the name.
Rym: I don't really pay attention.
Scott: Yeah, he's like the valve guy, you know, he's pretty famous, you know, he's responsible for all those awesome valve games.
Scott: There was a pretty big interview with him.
Scott: Of course, they're gonna be many interviews with him in the coming times because you know Orange box like biggest game has you know hard it is to not make every Tuesday be about Team Fortress 2?
Scott: I know right and I'm pre.
Scott: I'm pre downloading a portal right now and They ask him a bunch of questions about various things here and there, you know He kind of looks.
Scott: actually I've never seen a picture of him before but this interview has a picture of him, huh?
Scott: He looks like Newman Really?
Scott: Yeah, kinda huh only with different color hair, huh?
Scott: But anyway, one of the questions they ask him is they ask him how come he's not making games for OS X?
Scott: and first of All I'm pissed.
Scott: They didn't ask about Linux ass But you know that is true.
Scott: Why isn't all the?
Scott: why isn't steam on OS X?
Scott: that would totally rock the house.
Scott: I would buy a Mac probably.
Rym: Yeah, I'm gonna get cuz I didn't read this article at all.
Rym: I'm gonna guess.
Rym: the answer is Not.
Rym: many people have max and the kinds of people who have max and not the kinds of people are gonna play steam games.
Scott: not Even close, huh?
Scott: So he's talked.
Scott: they valve has been in talks with Apple before right and they said hey We're thinking about making games for the Mac.
Scott: We want to move all our stuff over there and Apple, you know, whenever they've talked to Apple He said is according to him right?
Scott: He says well, you wanted to read the paragraph.
Rym: I didn't read anything All right.
Scott: I'll read the paragraph.
Rym: I go for it.
Scott: This is this is a direct quote from Gabe Newell via this interview.
Scott: Alright we tried to have a conversation with Apple for several years and they never seemed to dot dot dot.
Scott: Well, we have this pattern with Apple.
Scott: where we meet with them people there go.
Scott: Wow gaming is incredibly important.
Scott: We should do something with gaming and then we'll say Okay, here are three things you could do to make that better.
Scott: and then they say, okay and then we never see them again.
Scott: and then a year later a new group of people show up who apparently have no idea.
Scott: the Last group of people were there and never followed through on anything.
Scott: So they seem to think that they want to do gaming But there's never any follow-through and any of the things that they say they're gonna do.
Scott: That makes it hard to be excited about doing games for their platforms, huh?
Scott: So you like he's probably like, you know There's the Apple people come to talk to the valve people and the valve people are like, okay We'll make games for your system.
Scott: You need to you know implement this sort of thing, you know in the in the OS.
Scott: So it's easier for us to program the games and you need to implement some sort of joystick Handling because OS X is no joystick handling whatsoever.
Rym: That is that's probably my biggest complaint is that if I want to use an emulator on a Mac I gotta pay someone for something that should just be working automatically in the system.
Scott: Yep, and they're like they're probably telling them, you know all the things that they need in OS X to make game development feasible and profitable in a reasonable amount of time.
Scott: and The people they talk to were like, yeah, that sounds great because they're thinking yeah games on OS X people switch over from Windows They'll be awesome and they're right and then they probably go back and Steve Jobs is like what the fuck you talking about?
Scott: Yeah, but they're not doing that shit and it.
Scott: they just don't do it and no one pushes them to do it and they don't think about it.
Scott: and people say Steve Jobs hates games and there's no evidence of that, but I believe it.
Rym: I It's a common practice.
Scott: if you don't want something done is OS X basically has nothing in it to support game developers or game players and You kind of need.
Rym: I just can't imagine why.
Rym: because there are a lot of people like me.
Scott: people are using Bootcamp to put windows on their power books to play world.
Rym: well World of Warcraft runs on the Mac but if I other games besides the world the only reason I didn't just use that Mac that I bought as a Computer for me was that I couldn't podcast on it.
Rym: if I weren't a podcaster you can bet your ass I'd be using a Mac if I could play steam games on it.
Rym: Yep Then I get a DM which is like the best I am client in the world.
Scott: Yeah, it sure is.
Scott: I mean kop I've been using is the second best but adm is just so hot.
Scott: adm is hot.
Scott: But well, you know the Mac it's like, you know, it.
Scott: it does stuff and for people who don't do things It doesn't do it's great.
Scott: Don't do what Donnie don't when you do something like play team fortress 2 or if you do something like Program things.
Scott: Well, I guess he it does that but it doesn't.
Scott: you know, it's not as comfortable as yes podcast It's your podcast.
Scott: The Mac is no good and it's like, you know for the general everyday tasks It's just fine.
Scott: But then again, so is Ubuntu.
Scott: So why spend the extra money on the Mac?
Rym: Yeah, I mean I like Macs, but I look at how much it costs to get a Mac.
Rym: That's as fast as my current PC.
Rym: It's crazy.
Scott: Yep, and it doesn't do things that but less expensive computers do.
Rym: well it does.
Scott: if I use boot camp I guess which means you got to pay for windows.
Rym: Anyway, well pay is one word One word.
Scott: Yes pay is a word.
Scott: But yeah, I think that was pretty interesting because it's sort of not quite.
Scott: I mean, it's not some sort of unobvious surprise that that's that.
Scott: That's what he would say, but it's not what immediately you would think is, you know Why are there no games on the Mac?
Scott: Well because Mac people don't play games because no it's because The Apple people just don't put the stuff in OS X that that people need to make games.
Scott: I mean you could start arguments about well Blizzard gets their games on the Mac, you know, blah blah blah.
Scott: I think that's just cuz.
Scott: Blizzard makes a lot fewer games.
Scott: They're not making steam.
Scott: They're just making games and They spend a lot of time on their games.
Scott: and their games are like they make a few really big games.
Scott: So they could push they can get them on the Mac, but valve makes more games and they're mostly DirectX games Plus.
Rym: think about how many more people play World of Warcraft than any other game I know.
Scott: I know part of that could be because the Macness.
Rym: Now I think part of that is just because a lot of people just have this need to play a game like that and of Those games while I think those games like I think I've outgrown that kind of game and I personally find those games really dumb World of Warcraft is the best one far away.
Rym: Yes better than any game like that has ever been.
Scott: also Like the graphics in World of Warcraft.
Scott: It's it's not like an FPS.
Scott: We have some advanced graphical engine.
Scott: They're pretty standard 3d graphics.
Scott: You know, it does.
Scott: you could run World of Warcraft on really crap computers relatively speaking.
Scott: We can't run Half-Life 2 2 on a semi crap.
Rym: I was shocked barely runs on my computer Exactly.
Rym: Actually, I got it to run great after I turned off a lot of the.
Rym: I can't while I like the eye candy.
Rym: The game was unplayable and once I turned it off the game played great to beat it.
Rym: yet I've played maybe two hours of Bioshock.
Scott: I heard it's only like a ten hour game or so.
Rym: remember I got Bioshock.
Rym: I started playing it.
Rym: It was awesome.
Rym: I killed the doctor I started moving on and then Team Fortress 2 came out.
Scott: How many doctors did you kill then?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Fuck those doctors.
Rym: I think I'm the only person.
Rym: despite that penny arcade.
Rym: I think I'm the only person who actually shoots the doctor.
Scott: I try to shoot the doctor, but it seems like late.
Scott: like the past two days I've been trying to shoot the doctor right?
Scott: He fucking turns invincible every time.
Scott: Oh fuck you.
Scott: What's with your timing you doctor?
Rym: Before we get on to the things today.
Rym: I just remembered something happened in Team Fortress 2 that I Got.
Scott: I'm talking about this game.
Rym: I got to get this out because this is so brilliant and I Enjoyed this thoroughly.
Rym: So, you know most servers in Team Fortress 2 have the voice chat like shared between teams.
Rym: Everyone can hear everyone.
Scott: some of them do.
Scott: Yeah Like you and that I hate that.
Rym: but most of the ones I play on are that way.
Rym: No, a lot of people don't realize it.
Rym: So I'm on one server and this one guy keeps talking to his team.
Rym: He's like, alright, I'm a scout.
Rym: I'm gonna go in.
Rym: Alright, we're setting up a century in their sewer Don't don't bla bla bla.
Rym: and we're just listening for a while.
Rym: And finally someone on his team is like, ah, dude, they can all hear you STFU.
Rym: It's alright.
Rym: I Laugh at that and I keep playing.
Rym: and then you know four or five games go by and there's a lot of turnover the people and then I think a minute and I start doing the same thing for a little while be your lion.
Rym: Well, I'm not lying.
Rym: at first I'm just kind of say I'm acting like I don't know and I'm a sniper and I'm fighting against these two other snipers that are really fucking good and having trouble with them.
Rym: And it's this really close, you know across the team the two fort.
Rym: and then I just say oh man, I'm up here I'm just I'm just guys.
Rym: as a sniper I'm gonna take out this other sniper and then we can all rush and the sniper shot each other and both snipers turn and look At each other and start like maneuvering and shooting and I just picked them both off.
Scott: nice It's very nice.
Rym: I was so proud of.
Scott: that is the way that you do the Sun Tzu And see how I threw that in there.
Scott: cuz you know the soldier.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: That was quite good Things of the day.
Rym: so check this.
Rym: this guy or guys.
Rym: I didn't really read the article because I don't care why they did it.
Rym: It was some sort of art project and I all I care about is what they did.
Rym: Apparently they got away with it for a long time.
Rym: These dudes went up dressed as workmen and I guess one of them stood there with a clipboard or something because you know a clipboard Makes anything look legitimate.
Rym: you could walk into any company with a clipboard and just walk out with just about anything you want.
Scott: So that's the ultimate hacking right there.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So have we talked about social engineering?
Scott: I think so at some level.
Rym: regardless.
Rym: if you ever need to get away with something shady carry a clipboard.
Rym: You'll probably get away.
Rym: but that's beside the point.
Scott: name badge name tag Yep, especially if it's fancy looking and the logo on your name tag matches logo on your clipboard papers your set.
Rym: Oh if you have a letterhead, oh man Yeah, and some sort of scribbly signature at the bottom of a complicated looking requisition form They just make it in Microsoft Word.
Rym: Yeah with really small print and it could be a lorem ipsum.
Rym: They're not gonna read it Yep.
Rym: Anyway, so these guys built an apartment out of cinder blocks and fully furnished it Inside of the parking lot of a mall.
Rym: Oh man and proceeded to live in it.
Rym: It didn't have running water.
Rym: So they had to use the mall bathrooms and I guess they went somewhere to shower.
Rym: But they had power in a PlayStation 2 and just a full furniture.
Rym: Oh my god, and I just think that's so cool because that's always been a tiny fantasy of mine especially when I was younger just a Setting up a tree for it, but not in a tree but somewhere awesome like in the middle of someone else's house.
Scott: Yeah, it's it.
Scott: secret compartments and secret places are like way cool.
Rym: Yeah, if I ever build a house you can bet your ass there's gonna be a secret passage.
Scott: Oh secret passages.
Rym: Oh, yeah, secret room.
Rym: No you walk out.
Rym: All right, so our house right you're gonna walk into it.
Rym: You open the front door.
Rym: There's a foyer and that's it.
Scott: You have to open the skull and take the key out.
Rym: I Wouldn't want to live in Shadowgate.
Rym: That's not a happy place.
Scott: Our house is like a hundred doors and a sphinx.
Rym: Every one of them is dead and a lake of fire and a sphere behind every door is death and a lawsuit.
Rym: Oh That's that's all I got to say about this.
Rym: this is just cool.
Scott: Okay, so BB spot if you if you don't know BB spot is a funny nerd Kind of satire site that makes up funny fake news stories and stuff like that.
Rym: It also used to be a very good source of Thing of the day type things before.
Rym: sites like Fark and dig really just took over for that.
Scott: Yep So they put up today a should I stop playing this game?
Scott: Matrix for Mary a decision matrix for married folks.
Rym: right decision matrix is otherwise known as an expert system.
Scott: Yep It's basically a series of questions and you answer them Yes or no And you eventually you keep it points you with arrows to what question you should answer next and eventually it leaves you with an answer To your cut to your situation.
Rym: It's basically a decision-making system.
Rym: It's very useful in a corporate setting if you want to say have employees execute a process and do make decisions But you don't want them to have any discretion.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right, so you wanted.
Scott: do you want to do this?
Rym: All right, I'll do it.
Scott: All right, pretend you're married.
Rym: All right, I'm married.
Scott: Okay, should you stop playing the game?
Scott: That is the question.
Rym: No, no, no, wait.
Scott: Okay, so hit the first quote.
Scott: That is the main question.
Scott: Oh, it doesn't matter what game.
Rym: we can just make up a game or pretend pretend whatever you want.
Rym: All right I'm playing a Custer's revenge.
Rym: No, no cat house blues.
Scott: All right is the spouse home?
Scott: Yes, is the spouse asleep?
Scott: Sure, is there work in the morning?
Scott: Yeah, you have any sick days left.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Keep playing.
Rym: You know what that sort of decision matrix is the kind of loop that is going on in my head all the time.
Scott: You want to do another one?
Scott: All right.
Scott: Should I start?
Scott: should you stop playing?
Scott: is the spouse home?
Rym: Let's say no.
Scott: Why are you asking for what?
Rym: if I work tomorrow it doesn't matter.
Rym: See the only thing is I I will say this and I'm not.
Rym: that is a little bit sexy.
Rym: Well, I guess not sexist because it's a spouse it doesn't die But at the same time you shouldn't be marrying someone who disrespects your hobbies.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: We've talked about that many a time.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Dave Riley is perhaps the expert on this subject.
Scott: Dave Riley is Definitely our brother in arms when it comes to the topic at hand.
Rym: Yes It's not bros before hoes.
Rym: It's hoes should be bros.
Scott: So you're gay Right, so anyway There you go forum that that's your fill for the day.
Rym: You know someday they're gonna wonder if we do this on purpose or not.
Rym: and sometimes yes sometimes no We swing both ways.
Scott: Oh That was obviously yes on purpose, okay, right.
Rym: so way back we interviewed a man named Luke crane.
Scott: He is the designer and primary author of the burning wheel Tabletop role-playing game system.
Rym: The man is a tiny god and I highly recommend you listen to Scott's interview with him.
Rym: I say Scott because back then we didn't know so much about audio and I was kind of drunk.
Rym: So Scott conducted the inner very drunk.
Rym: that drunk pretty drunk now.
Scott: But the thing was we're gonna drive home.
Rym: Of course not.
Rym: but well partly because of that fucking blizzard I was different.
Rym: that was the time before I was but I was sitting there dealing with the fact that Luke crane for the life Of him cannot use a microphone.
Scott: Well, the man gestures a lot and moves around a lot and he's very energetic.
Scott: So a microphone on a stand sitting in front of him was not gonna.
Rym: I felt like I would had to just stand behind him holding the microphone in his.
Scott: he needs a boom guy or a lavalier?
Rym: Yes, he does.
Rym: But anyway aura or a boundary that guy.
Rym: There's a lot of insight to be had about role-playing and what is good about role-playing and why people really role-play.
Rym: and you know We talked a while ago about you know, whining gamers.
Rym: now a lot of times They don't understand the games they whine about.
Rym: as a result the suggestions they make a Luke crane is an example of the opposite of that.
Rym: He knows more about role-playing than most people and he's put a lot more thought of it into it than most people have.
Rym: and as a
Scott: Lot of help from other people who've also put a lot of yes
Rym: I believe he even used the words, you know standing on the shoulders of Giants Yeah
Scott: But
Rym: the guy if you listen to him and the way he's you'll probably end up having a lot more fun playing games like Dungeons & Dragons or any role-playing game because you'll start to kind of think about What you like about role-playing and what you don't like and how you can get rid of the things you don't like and just do The things you like.
Scott: and despite us being total Luke crane fanboys and playing with you know in his games at conventions And talking to him and interviewing him and buying his books and reading his books We never actually played that much burning wheel and he would always tell us just play it just play it and I'd be like It's.
Scott: it seems hard like it's a daunting task to try to play it.
Scott: You know and I don't feel like it'll be right and I like I'll mess it up and cuz we were.
Rym: so I mean the way he runs burning wheel is amazing.
Rym: and if you ever Ever at a convention a gaming convention where Luke crane is there or even anyone named Luke crane?
Rym: Cuz even if it's not him, you got to take that chance.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Just sign up for whatever event He's running and see what happens.
Rym: I guarantee you'll have a good time
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: but we took all his other advice and we tried all those games He talked about and we read about him and we do, you know, we everything he said we thought about Except the final piece of advice which was just fucking play it.
Scott: That's all in my game.
Scott: You bought my game.
Scott: Why aren't you playing my game?
Rym: Yeah, don't think about it.
Scott: D&D even though he loved his game.
Scott: I'm it was sort of like it felt sort of like this communism thing.
Scott: We're on paper.
Scott: I loved it, but I didn't feel like I could make it happen.
Scott: So I didn't do it.
Scott: I just kept playing D&D.
Rym: It also didn't help that we have capitalism.
Rym: We have a large gaming group and the majority of the people in our group aren't even that well versed in Dungeons & Dragons.
Rym: So switching them to burning wheel didn't seem like it would be easy.
Scott: No, it definitely seemed like it was gonna be hard.
Rym: granted The answer is it is really hard, but we'll get to that.
Scott: It was really hard for us.
Scott: No, not for us, but but it was difficult and there were some hurdles to jump over.
Rym: but a lot of you who listen to that interviewer here is talk every now and then about burning wheel and especially many of you who have been participants in the various forum arguments about burning wheel and Especially after we did that show on why we really don't like Dungeons & Dragons anymore.
Scott: Oh, I remember that.
Scott: wow that Why it sort of makes this show feel redundant in a way.
Rym: Well, yeah, because I think this will be more anecdotes.
Rym: It's real-world experience.
Rym: Yeah, like the previous show was the theory like here's why we think we like burning wheel.
Rym: now.
Rym: It's now that we forced ourselves to play.
Scott: We haven't played it that much though We've played it like one or two times but we put a lot of thought into it.
Rym: and also because we're converting a D&D game over we've Discovered all the things that work and don't work and we've.
Rym: we learned a lot of things and I guess we'll just get right.
Scott: Yeah, we've begun to learn.
Scott: we haven't learned the whole yet No, but we have learned more than before but not the fullness.
Scott: we have not grok it Not grokking the fullness.
Rym: Yeah, we'll need to share some water with all of you later, but But we took the plunge and you've all been asking.
Rym: so here it is.
Rym: we have tried to convert our Dungeons & Dragons campaign to burning wheel partly because I Took the initiative and said all right fuckers I'm running my burning wheel game the one I've been talking about for like a year.
Rym: You know the Horatio Hornblower ships captain blah blah blah awesome.
Rym: And then you know about to play D&D and we're all talking about burning wheel.
Rym: and Eventually, the consensus was reached fuck D&D it sucks and we hate it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So we said, all right What are we gonna do?
Rym: and Alex our DM said, you know what burn your characters?
Scott: We're switching tomorrow and we spent basically two days figuring the game out and sitting around making characters and Discussing and talking and moving and shaking without even playing.
Scott: we just spent like two days Pretty much all day most of the day working on it.
Rym: now before we get into all the things that happen I don't want this to be an advice show But this I have one piece of advice and this is critical because several people in our group of friends did not take this advice And as a result had a lot of trouble.
Rym: if you want to play burning wheel and you own the burning wheel book This goes for any tabletop RPG.
Rym: I highly recommend that you read the book Read it Carefully.
Scott: when
Rym: I say read it I mean read it as in if you read it and it says the Exponent is the number of dice you roll when making a test and then two minutes later You don't know what it means when I ask you what the exponent is for your perception skill.
Scott: Well stat Yeah, I guess what I say is don't just read it like don't just you know process the words.
Rym: Don't read it like you're actually in college.
Scott: actually read it and study it and understand what you read.
Rym: You must grok it.
Scott: You must think of it like a reading comprehension test.
Scott: if you can't pass a quiz about what you just read And you only really have to read the first 75 pages of the main book.
Scott: That's all you have to read.
Rym: That's a good idea for my burning wheel game.
Rym: I'm just gonna make a quiz and if you pass the quiz you're in the game.
Scott: I could pass the quiz.
Rym: I know you can pass the quiz maybe unless you ask hard questions.
Rym: I'm not gonna out fight.
Scott: Actually, I follow the questions are from the first 75 pages.
Scott: then I can answer them.
Rym: Anyway, so we jumped in and we learned right away that burning wheel is not the.
Rym: I mean it can be high fantasy but it's not the high fantasy like D&D.
Rym: and that Presented a problem for some people who didn't quite get like.
Rym: what makes burning wheel great?
Rym: because their characters and D&D wise We're super badass at everything and they could kill.
Scott: They're there.
Scott: you know the character was like I have Superpowers and I can shoot lightning and chop things in half with one swoosh of an axe and I have badass Super armor and I can't be hard.
Rym: like my character I was a bard right and because you know a lot of stuff is not enumerated in D&D.
Rym: It's just character history.
Rym: So my character was super badass at fighting and he was also super badass at diplomacy.
Rym: And he was basically super badass at everything but magic.
Rym: and that really goes against the spirit of burning wheel Which is you know, if your character is bad at some things.
Scott: Well, what it is is in D&D when you make a character, it's mostly about What your character the power of your character the power level, you know, like it's over 9,000 Exactly.
Scott: Whereas in burning wheel Character creation is not about your power level as much.
Scott: It's about you know the the kind of person they are and and what they think about things and and what they're like to talk to and What how they would react in different situations.
Scott: not about?
Scott: Can they chop down a tree in two swings or three swings and how hard are they to kill?
Scott: I mean, it's about that too, but much less.
Rym: I think that the real issue is that in D&D almost all of the character creation you do is two parts.
Rym: One part is making the D&D numbers character for fighting and the other part is writing a couple of pages of backstory.
Scott: It isn't even required for D&D.
Scott: It doesn't say any barely says anything about that in the book at all.
Rym: I mean granted as always people will say yeah, but you could just do that.
Rym: Anyway, I mean a good role player can deal with any system and that's true.
Rym: I guess that the real point we want to make is that after having played burning wheel some more and really just jumped into it Head first and drowned in the deep end.
Rym: It's not so much that burning wheel is a superior system while I will make the argument separately in another show that burning wheel is A superior system to Dungeons & Dragons in terms of conflict resolution and in terms of combat because I hate D&D combat I think it's crap, but that's totally beside the point.
Rym: What makes burning wheel great is something that a lot of role-playing systems could do very well.
Rym: The way burning wheel is structured is such that it encourages a certain style of role-playing.
Rym: It kind of pushes you in a direction that you can go in that direction in D&D or GURPS or White Wolf or any game.
Rym: But burning wheel is set up to make it so easy to go in that direction that you'll go that way without even trying.
Scott: Yeah, it's like in D&D.
Scott: if you want to have like this intense role-playing experience D&D gives you a blank slate as far as role-playing is concerned, you know, there's no rules about role-playing.
Scott: Rope is you know, you can say whatever you want and do whatever you want As long as you don't try to do something that you you know that involves using your powers or your physicalness.
Scott: So it's totally a blank slate.
Scott: So if you're like a master, you know fiction writer and you're everyone else is a master fiction writer actor Lara, you know improv person.
Scott: It's gonna go great no matter what the hell system you use.
Scott: cuz everyone will know really cool things to do and say Yeah, the story be off.
Rym: I mean, I played some great D&D in high school and it was just.
Rym: we were all in first person as our characters Role-playing with each other.
Scott: it worked out great, but but it's a blank slate.
Scott: So if someone isn't an amazing actor like me, you know It's hard to think of something interesting or awesome given infinite possibility.
Scott: we always talk about games and how You know it.
Scott: if a game where you can just do whatever you want is not interesting You need to have constraints and then the creativity flows in figuring out how to do the most.
Scott: considering the constraints It's like hacking, you know How to get the most out of something.
Scott: that only does a little.
Rym: look at this game.
Rym: We have a. there's a game called nanofictionary, which we had reviewed.
Rym: we have to because that game is amazing.
Scott: Oh, we gotta talk.
Scott: We should have talked about that today.
Scott: nanofictionary.
Rym: Yeah, we'll talk about it sometime is a week.
Rym: There's a collaborative storytelling game and you could just get a bunch of friends sit around in a circle and take turns telling stories.
Rym: That's what D&D is like when it comes to role-playing.
Rym: but by playing nanofictionary now, you're putting all these rules.
Rym: You're forcing yourself to go in directions.
Rym: You might not have expected.
Rym: you're forcing yourself to think about things You might not have thought about and those limitations often make it more interesting make the stories beyond.
Rym: it's like you sort of Out-creative yourself because you're limited and as a result, you can't do exactly what you want and you're forced to think in a different way.
Scott: Yeah, give it a blank slate.
Scott: The only thing you're gonna write down is what comes to mind.
Scott: but if you put some like Mile markers if someone else or if you put mile markers down on the ground or get some mile markers from a book and lay Them out and then you start thinking Guided by these markers you're gonna go in a direction that you would never have thought of given a blank slate.
Scott: and that direction because burning wheel is designed so well is Towards interestingness and entertainment for the people sitting around the table.
Rym: and the style of play.
Rym: I mean, I think because we have we know we've always talked up to this point about burning wheel and very vague and Style of play roleplay this and this the important thing.
Rym: We haven't talked a lot about the nitty-gritty or exactly what or why and After playing a little bit of burning wheel and mostly after talking about what little burning wheel we played incessantly for several days very specifically the style of play the burning wheel kind of encourages is this idea that Your character believes something and your character wants to fight for that belief.
Rym: and that's what all good role-playing is.
Rym: if your character doesn't want Anything why are they even in this game?
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I'm a cleric I worship this God and I can cast flame strike and heal people but it's all.
Scott: I'm with this party and there's a bad guy But it's like do I want the bad guy dead?
Scott: Do I even care?
Scott: Why do I care?
Scott: These are questions that D&D does not force you to answer and sometimes you just accept You know, yes as the default answer and go along with it.
Scott: But if any cat, let's see playing D&D right.
Scott: and what if the cleric decides?
Rym: You know I don't really care about this bad guy that everything or this dungeon that we're all crawling in or that happen when we were playing The the sigil game where we were single where we were all, you know, the society esoteric or whatever.
Rym: That was really cool.
Rym: Yeah But my character wasn't stupid and the thing every all the rest of the people in the game were doing their characters Was something that was stupid as far as my character was concerned.
Rym: so he didn't want anything to do with it and Effectively that forced that character out of the game because there was no point for that character to be there.
Scott: Imagine if there's a fighter a black mage a white mage and a thief All right, and they all.
Scott: they're all together.
Scott: They're all friends from some previous experience and the black and then the.
Scott: you know, the fighter gets pissed off at this Guy across town and he's like, let's go kick this guy's ass.
Scott: He stole all my money.
Scott: What if the other people are just like?
Scott: I don't care about your money?
Scott: Well now it's what kind of game do you have?
Scott: you have a game that's uninteresting the fighters pissed.
Scott: He goes across town to fight a guy.
Scott: the other three people are sitting around going whatever.
Scott: now this can be.
Scott: how is that interesting?
Rym: this can be avoided in D&D by either railroading or Forcing it or you have to do it actively as a player you have to suspend.
Scott: It's a blank slate.
Scott: players do whatever they want.
Rym: So you basically if you're if you have an interesting character that you sometimes have to make your character do something That your character wouldn't like.
Rym: it goes against what you wrote your character as just because otherwise the game breaks and There's no real game mechanic to avoid that.
Rym: Yeah, I mean you can't avoid it.
Rym: I'm not gonna say it's impossible But the game doesn't really encourage it.
Rym: and this the number one insight we had when in burning wheel Was why the duel of wits is important and I'm gonna take credit for this because I take credit for this.
Rym: Well Scott and I were.
Rym: we kind of came to it together.
Rym: Scott and I were sitting we were talking about burning wheel and what we liked about it what was going on and Eventually, we kind of hit on this idea that the duel of wits which we already think is like one of the core things of Burning wheel.
Scott: it's pretty fun to do a duel of wits.
Scott: first of all, it's social conflict.
Rym: It is a way to roleplay and constrain social conflict in such a way that The better role player will not automatically win an argument and if I can't it's more about the character than the player.
Rym: But yet the player still enjoys it and it's
Scott: it's really being a better role player does help Yes,
Rym: but it's really fun and it it's great and it kind of takes away the D&D problem of Combat is the only thing that matters on your character sheet because else is just roleplay.
Scott: Well because think about it What is the point?
Scott: we could just sit around and tell a story together?
Scott: the point of having a tabletop role-playing system with dice and such is to put constraints on the story and To resolve conflicts.
Scott: as in if I think the story should go left and Rym thinks the story should go, right?
Scott: You know, I think the monster should die and the DM thinks the monster should eat us all.
Scott: We need to resolve that conflict in deciding where the story should go and we use dice and numbers on paper in order to decide Which direction the story will go and we collectively agree that whatever the dice and the numbers on the paper Say is where the story will take us and then we will continue telling the story from there.
Rym: now And now.
Rym: you could say oh well You could just do that collaboratively and you could but you could.
Rym: luke rain actually says in the book that you should never let that happen because by forcing yourselves to always use concrete arbitrary sometimes just Resolution mechanics for conflict it forces the story to go in directions that you might not anticipate And as a result, it almost always makes the game more interesting.
Scott: So what the duel of wits does right is in D&D one character want things they should go left the other things They should go right.
Scott: What do you do now?
Scott: They can split up they can fight each other.
Scott: They how you can't change anyone's mind.
Scott: I mean, how are you gonna change their mind?
Rym: You can only change their mind through role-playing but that That level of role-playing is beyond a lot of people and to and even if you'd like to say the best role-player in the world.
Scott: The other guy just refuses and he says I'm going right no matter what.
Scott: well now the game splits up and the game is much less interesting and less fun.
Rym: or if you like if you really can't come Up with a reason for your character to go along with it Your only option is your character just goes off to fight for what they believe in or you just railroad yourself into their plot And that it kind of betrays what your character believes.
Rym: in burning wheel the duel of wits works.
Rym: Thus two characters want something.
Rym: Let's say we're in a boat and my character says We have to get back to the capital because the spies are gonna assassinate the king and we have to stop it.
Rym: But your character says screw that we've got this magic Baphomet dad that we have to get.
Rym: Otherwise the world's gonna end.
Rym: and we both disagree and are.
Rym: both of our characters believe Strongly in these things and neither one will compromise in burning wheel.
Rym: We have a duel of wits where Metagame you step aside and say alright my character wants X your character wants Y. our beliefs won't change.
Rym: But unless we want them to yeah But whoever wins this conflict this fight this verbal fight gets what they want.
Rym: So I agree that if I lose this argument will go with you with the stupid Baphomet dad to save the world.
Rym: But if you lose you're coming with me on the real mission to save the king.
Scott: You don't have to like it, you know, you know, you're still in character.
Scott: Your character doesn't change but you you have compromised you have agreed to go along with it And it makes the game a lot more interesting because now you have people, you know in D&D.
Scott: It's Everyone agrees and goes along with it and is happy.
Scott: now You've got someone who's going along with it, but they're pissed off and you start getting these sort of like.
Scott: You know emotions and and things going on that make the role-playing interesting.
Scott: They give you something to roleplay about and not just you know Role-playing based on the situation but in between the characters and and what's going on and it allows because this is a problem.
Rym: We had we tried to adapt some burning wheel mechanics into D&D And what we found was that whenever we did that the end the D&D game just devolved into characters fighting with each other incessantly over major things and the game went nowhere because every fight was some gigantic thing.
Scott: and I guess you know in burning wheel and D&D you can always settle it with physical You know a battle of some sort.
Scott: but in D&D that's sort of all you've got.
Scott: but in burning wheel You don't resort to that unless it's you know prudent because it's really dangerous.
Scott: Yeah, and if you don't if your character doesn't want to die, they're probably not gonna do that.
Scott: Or if your character's weak, which most of them are you're not gonna do that unless it you really you know means it to you.
Rym: But by adding this there's now there's a game mechanic to back it up.
Rym: It's you lost.
Rym: the rule of the game is your character goes along with this But he's pissed and he still believes what he believed.
Scott: or you know It believes that ever you wanted to believe.
Scott: but the point is that what you want to believe it carries it keeps the game Interesting.
Scott: It keeps the people the characters in the game together.
Scott: It gives them a logical reason to be together at all times.
Scott: People are do if anyone's doing anything.
Scott: They know why they're doing it.
Scott: There's a reason for everything that you're doing.
Scott: You're never saying why am I doing this?
Scott: And if you do say why are you doing this?
Scott: we figure the answer out right away, right we back it up with rules in the game and The result may not be that you can.
Scott: you know, I mean some people might look at this and say something like oh Well that puts some sort of role-playing Restriction on what you can role play.
Rym: That's the point.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: The point is is that restriction makes it more interesting.
Scott: It allows it, you know.
Scott: putting a restriction on the creativity makes it flow more.
Scott: It's like it's you know, it's.
Scott: it's like a plugged up tube and you squeeze the tube a little so It can't flow as quickly.
Scott: but now you squeezed a bunch of goop out.
Rym: It's the same thing with character creation.
Rym: I mean think of this in D&D third edition.
Rym: I'm making a character.
Rym: if I put two skill points versus three or four or five into diplomacy as opposed to musical instrument or Stealth or whatever that is such a minor effect on gameplay and it just it doesn't matter.
Rym: I don't have to give anything up to get what I want in burning wheel Choosing to put one point into like, you know, my fighting skill versus into my thinking skill is huge.
Rym: I have to give up a lot to get what I want.
Rym: The character creation in burning wheel forces you to think about to distill your character into what is important.
Rym: I mean, I wrote my character.
Rym: I'll use the example in this game.
Rym: We're converting guys.
Rym: He's a effectively a Roman and you know I wrote the character and he's the son the adopted son of a really important senator and his family's very wealthy and blah da da Da and he's a bard so he's good with the sword and he's a chronicler and blah blah blah And I didn't.
Rym: I could just write all this stuff and some of it was interesting and some of it wasn't and a lot of It didn't really matter in the game in Burning wheel.
Rym: when I remade the character I had to follow the life paths and the rules of making a care.
Scott: making a character in burning wheel is Really fun because when you make the character you basically choose their life paths.
Scott: you say he started out born in the city and then he became an apprentice and then he was Outcast because he was a thief and now he's a loan shark.
Rym: you could write a novel or make a webcomic where you didn't do anything really creative other than Burn a bunch of characters in burning wheel Roll the dice to see who wins what conflicts and then write out the exchanges that those conflicts caused.
Rym: You can do that make up.
Rym: you could make a pretty damn good novel pretty quickly like that.
Rym: But by making Gaius this character in burning wheel I was forced to think about what is important.
Rym: Is it important that he's wealthy or it is important that he's good with the sword?
Rym: because I can only pick one?
Rym: It is important that he knows this senator.
Scott: It's not like D&D.
Scott: Everyone's level 5.
Scott: Everyone has the same amount of money.
Scott: Yeah, even the pauper at level 5 has this much money.
Scott: Like I can still have night at level 5 has the same amount of.
Rym: I can still have all those things in my character history.
Rym: I could be the son of this important senator or not and it doesn't matter in burning wheel.
Rym: But if I spend the points at character creation to say no, he's I'm not just his son I'm his fucking son.
Rym: What I'm saying is that is important to me.
Rym: I chose to give up other things.
Rym: my character could have to say to the DM and the other players and to myself that That is what is important about my character.
Rym: That is what my character is.
Scott: Yeah, and if you put something about your character and you don't spend any points on it, right?
Scott: It's just it's just something about your character in the backstory.
Scott: That's fine But it doesn't actually mean anything in the game.
Scott: But if you spend points on it You are saying that will matter in the game.
Scott: and if it if there's ever a point in the game Where something will matter that you did spend points on like let's say I spend some points to say that my character has Is missing an eye.
Scott: right if I just say my character has an eyepatch, that's just flavor text.
Scott: It doesn't do anything.
Rym: You might have a whole four-page story about how your betrayed lover stabbed you in the eye after blah blah blah But whatever.
Rym: no one cares about that.
Scott: But if you spend a point and say I am missing an eye and I have an eyepatch and that's on your character sheet It suddenly matters.
Scott: and if any point in the game It would ever matter you point at your character sheet and you say look everyone it says right here I spent points and it says I am missing a fucking eye and it matters and it makes a difference in the game.
Scott: your Backstory in D&D Really doesn't make a difference in the game.
Scott: You can write whatever you want your backstory.
Scott: I mean, let's say I make a level 5 monk.
Scott: I could write a backstory that was like I was king of the world I was a god.
Scott: then I died and I came back and I was a present and then I was this and then I was that I was isn't it?
Scott: obviously now I'm a Fifth-level monk.
Rym: all those problems can be mitigated by like people are gonna say and argue, you know Good role-playing and forcing yourselves to stay on track.
Rym: And I'm not saying that you can't play D&D and make it just as dramatic and just as interesting just as awesome.
Scott: It can be done because I've done it.
Rym: I did it a lot.
Scott: It has been done quite often throughout the history of the world.
Scott: However, it is not easy and it requires people who are really trying very hard and burning wheel makes it easy.
Scott: the psychology of the system Moves people to do things that are more interesting and better role-playing Without having to think about it a lot without having to have a lot of acting skill without trying very hard.
Scott: It's almost as if like it psychologically makes people better role players times 10 if they just try a little bit.
Rym: Yep, it is the start.
Rym: I think we can end this with an example because this is one Scott and I talked about An example of how a scenario is run typically in D&D Versus how the same thing would be run in burning wheel.
Rym: and a lot of this isn't even so much game mechanics It's just in the burning wheel book.
Rym: Lou Crane says things like do it this way handle it this way that came up.
Rym: Well, don't make it end make it complicated.
Rym: Yep I think the scenario was our party.
Rym: a bunch of people think think like ancient Romans and a bunch of a whole bunch of people with a bunch of varied interests are trying to get back to the capital of a nation to deal with a whole bunch of bullshit.
Rym: That just happened and we're in a ship that's barely afloat and we have to stop somewhere.
Rym: so we stopped there and it's gonna take like four days to fix the ship.
Rym: and we're stuck here for these four days and While we're there.
Rym: Oh, look the fort was attacked by a monster, huh?
Rym: Should we stay and help these people stop that monster or should we go on our way?
Rym: And that was the base conflict.
Rym: now the D&D way this was handled was alright.
Rym: We're here for four days There's a monster you say.
Rym: well Obviously it being D&D.
Rym: we'd better go deal with that.
Rym: And obviously the best way to deal with it is to roll a bunch of gather informations to find out where the monster is.
Rym: Roll a bunch of knowledges to find out if we know how to fight it figure out where it is role play talking to the villagers and whatever.
Rym: Trek down there because obviously the monster is gonna be there fight it have a long fight on a grid win or lose But if you lose the game's over because everyone died.
Scott: Most likely or most of the people died and it's very hard to raise dead.
Rym: Most of them Yeah, come back and then oh look the complication because you were down there fighting the ship is gone and now you're stranded here.
Scott: Yep, now that worked.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: The problem was there are many problems.
Scott: The first problem is that what if you fail to gather information checks now, you know nothing about the monster?
Scott: So what do you do?
Scott: We don't know anything.
Scott: Oh, the monster just gets what.
Scott: what do you do?
Scott: It's up.
Scott: the DM pretty much just feeds you the information because it's the characters interacting with the setting and that's it.
Scott: That's all you have to play with.
Scott: and if the DM doesn't feed it to you.
Scott: You got nothing.
Rym: the characters can interact with each other, but it doesn't matter.
Rym: We have nothing else to do while we're here because the ship's laid up.
Rym: So we're kind of railroaded onto this path, which is you know, typical D&D and it can work but it takes a lot of effort.
Rym: I say take the same scenario and apply all the I guess loot crane.
Rym: Make it complicated make it interesting.
Rym: Don't make it a dead end.
Rym: All right, so we get here instead of just saying Alright, the ship's gonna be laid up.
Rym: Here's a subplot or here's an interesting plot.
Rym: That's gonna be here immediately think at any juncture as the dungeon master.
Rym: What conflict can I introduce here?
Rym: What can I do to make this interesting?
Rym: So don't just say oh you're stuck here for four days.
Rym: There's a thing you can investigate.
Rym: It should be.
Scott: you're here.
Rym: The ship's ready to go right away Like skip that skip the interesting part.
Rym: Are you gonna stay and help?
Rym: are you gonna get right back on your way now?
Rym: you suddenly have a Conflict between the players because obviously some of them are gonna want to stay and help and some of them are gonna want to gonna Want to get back to the plot even better.
Scott: Look you the characters have beliefs that are written on their character sheet, right?
Scott: so the DM looks and let's say one character has a belief that says Demons are the worst thing ever and another character We should kill them all.
Scott: and another character has a belief that says Avoid dangerous situations because you're weak, right?
Scott: So you make a demon come now.
Scott: suddenly these two characters are at odds.
Scott: One of them says we must go kill this demon and you all have to come help me.
Scott: And the other one is like I ain't going anywhere near that dangerous thing.
Scott: And now there's some interesting role-playing going on between the players not between the players in the DM But in between the players of the game and they start doing interesting things with each other.
Rym: Yep And you know in D&D your role of knowledge check and it's usually you find out what you needed to know where you don't find It out or something like that.
Scott: All right here here pretend here ready?
Scott: I'm gonna give you a thing to role-play you ready?
Scott: Okay Rym.
Scott: You're a kung fu master Yep, and there's a monster over there.
Scott: Go role-play.
Rym: All right, I punch it.
Scott: Yeah now, how about this?
Scott: you believe?
Scott: that monsters are awesome and Okay one over there.
Rym: I don't go punch it I'm just.
Scott: you know, it's like it because you have a was the best example I was.
Scott: I couldn't think of one but when you have sort of like a belief to play on You know you it in your mind what to do it.
Scott: It's like, you know what to do.
Scott: It's like aha I'm gonna do this.
Rym: What do I want?
Rym: and while you'll say yeah, but your character can believe things in D&D Yeah, that's true But the constraints of burning wheel or that you have three beliefs your character might believe a lot of things and might have a lot Stuff going on.
Scott: you have three beliefs on paper So they matter.
Rym: you crystallize it.
Rym: you think what are the three most important things to my character in the world?
Rym: That is what I'm going to care about.
Rym: That is what is going to matter in this game.
Rym: And at the same time the dungeon master looks to everyone's beliefs and says that is what the players want to matter.
Rym: I'm going to make those things matter at every point I can Yep, and I can be done in D&D.
Rym: I know we keep saying this but it's so much easier.
Scott: Any role-playing system yeah, GURPS, White Wolf, LARP's 7C, L5R.
Rym: Oh L5R is a good setting.
Rym: not a great game, but a good setting.
Rym: inspectors, lacuna Anything yeah But just the idea is in D&D the way it tends to go just cuz.
Rym: the way the system is and you can only get around this with good role-playing Is basically you roll the dice to succeed or fail at a task and generally a lot of times if you succeed the plot Continues.
Rym: if you fail the plot stops until you eventually succeed or you find an alternate route Or it just delays.
Scott: you like you failed you get hit by a trap.
Scott: you lose some life.
Rym: Continue or you failed at the gather information.
Rym: You don't find much from the villagers.
Rym: Well shit fine.
Rym: I search around the village.
Rym: you fail.
Rym: well shit fine.
Rym: I send my familiar out scouting.
Rym: you fail.
Rym: well shit fine.
Rym: send dry on the mayor.
Rym: Success.
Scott: the mayor is the demon.
Scott: go get him.
Scott: yeah.
Scott: meanwhile in burning wheel it would be roll.
Scott: You fail.
Scott: let it ride.
Scott: now that you are not getting information.
Rym: Think about that.
Rym: that matters.
Rym: in burning wheel the way It's set up the what it encourages is if you roll the dice if you succeed you continue along the path that your character has Selected.
Rym: you succeed at what you do.
Scott: if you roll the dice you and you get what you need succeeds.
Scott: You say what happens.
Scott: you base.
Scott: I say I want this and the DM.
Scott: the DM says well you have to test this.
Scott: make this test And I take that test.
Scott: I test my character and my character passes the test.
Scott: I say what happens.
Scott: I won my dice.
Scott: say I get to say what happens now right in In D&D.
Rym: if they fail that right whatever you're delayed in burning wheel.
Rym: a Failure does not mean the plot stops.
Rym: a failure does not mean you have to find another way around this obstacle.
Rym: a Failure means it just got complicated or it just got interesting.
Rym: There's alright.
Scott: There's a good example goes in a different direction.
Rym: There's a really good example in the burning wheel book of a character who says like he's running away from some guards And he's gotten away and his intent is I want to pick this lock before the guards come to get away.
Rym: if he succeeds What he is narrating continues to happen.
Rym: basically every time you succeed you get to narrate a little bit of the story and no one Can say otherwise.
Scott: you succeeded.
Scott: dice say you get dice say you win.
Rym: now if he fails you could say well You don't get the door open all right.
Rym: That's a D&D way.
Rym: you fail now You can't get the door open.
Rym: you could take 20 I guess but then the guards will come or you could go another way or blah blah blah blah.
Rym: The example in burning wheel in the book is all right.
Rym: you could do yeah He doesn't open the door, but he didn't say open the door.
Rym: He said open the door before the guards.
Scott: that's what he wanted.
Scott: so if he succeed He would get what he wanted.
Scott: if he doesn't succeed by the rules.
Scott: He doesn't get what he wants something else happens.
Rym: So either all right He still gets the door open just as the guards arrived.
Rym: so now you've got drama and conflict right there.
Scott: Oh, man, or he opens the door.
Rym: this guards on the other side.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: There's all sorts of directions.
Rym: You can go failing in D&D a lot of times unless you really roleplay your ass around it Or you have a really good DM Who takes care of it stops you in your tracks until you eventually succeed and continue in a burning wheel style even if you're not Playing burning wheel.
Rym: if you just take Luke cranes advice anytime you fail it should add a complication.
Rym: It should make it interesting.
Rym: I'm trying to find out.
Scott: I'm going around the games the story always goes forward.
Scott: it Just might not always go forward towards the positive obvious ending.
Scott: it goes forward in Some direction might not be a direction that you were thinking of.
Scott: yeah And if the game mechanic forces you to move the stories in directions that no one thinks of I'm going around the docks Looking for some sailors to get on my ship, and I just roll.
Scott: really bad all your.
Scott: all you're thinking is I'm gonna get sailors on my ship.
Scott: That's all you're thinking.
Scott: I fuck up.
Rym: I don't find sailors.
Rym: I find cultists pretending to be sailors off fuck.
Scott: or even better you find sailors, but one of them is evil The fuck you.
Rym: I don't find sailors.
Rym: I find out that the some old sailor that I pissed off back in the day is looking for me.
Scott: Oh, I gotta watch out now.
Rym: yep All right, I think we've gone long enough.
Rym: the gist is I need to eat something by jumping into burning wheel like we did.
Scott: We've realized that the only way to play burning wheel is to just jump right the hell into it and play it Even if you mess it up a whole bunch Or you don't get everything right and you have a hard time with it.
Rym: It doesn't matter just keep trying keep playing Even with the fact that half the people around the table didn't know how to do basic things in the game and didn't understand it Never even finish their characters or anything The gay.
Rym: as soon as a duel of wits happened You could tell the excitement was in the air because our D&D group was suddenly cheering and clapping and You'd see moments where someone says something like well blah blah blah.
Scott: Maybe we should let the people actually be gant to care about what was happening as opposed to just Going along with what they expected to happen.
Rym: I can't really say something that was going to and the whole D&D table would go.
Rym: Oh you sure man Something's gonna happen now and in D&D that didn't happen.
Scott: so on in D&D only the expected ever happened.
Rym: Yep, and the expected was either we succeed and continue or we fail and wait because
Scott: the only things that can happen are things that You thought of whereas you're never forced to think of something that you wouldn't have thought of because and you just wouldn't thought of it Bernie
Rym: wheel excels in that it forces you in directions You didn't expect.
Rym: I don't think we can say that more times in more ways than we've already said it.
Scott: I can say I'm hungry more time.
Rym: So let's go get some Chinese soup or something.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.