Scott: It's Wednesday November 14th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: tonight We discuss the x-men.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well, I came home today, and I was greeted by a gigantic GeekNights canvas banner the fur.
Rym: well vinyl like canvas.
Rym: I wanted canvas, but it costs a lot more money.
Scott: Yeah canvas plus You know can be damaged much more easily than vinyl.
Scott: I mean even if we spill like though the Thomas Jefferson's red wine Port on to our canvas you know vinyl banner.
Scott: It'll just pour right off Drop it on the canvas banner.
Scott: We have to buy a new one and you know what one drop of that wine If it was real and not fake could pay for a hundred of those banners.
Rym: So the most expensive ones were like the silk, but they I mean they look crazy good And they're like this matte finish, but silk screening.
Rym: Yeah, we don't need that.
Rym: But yeah for any of you go to the New York anime festival You're gonna see a lot of the early parts of swag and stuff because we've actually
Scott: We're halfway to the swag like we have this list of swag and we're sort of working towards getting all of it.
Scott: But the most important swags are also the hardest to you know build up.
Scott: But we're basically gonna build up this mountain of swag and then like dole it out slowly over time and once that swag machine Is turning it won't stop?
Scott: It's just a very big gear.
Scott: so you know it takes a lot of energy before you get it rotating.
Scott: and but once it's rotating It you know inertia, and yeah,
Rym: and I can say this in the near future and why I'm saying near future I mean next week or two maybe maybe three We're not gonna have t-shirts for sale or anything But we're probably gonna have our first t-shirt design available for you to look at and tell us if you actually want to buy it.
Rym: Yeah, I really like the direction.
Rym: It's going so far.
Scott: So it's gonna be hard for us to set up an actual like web store.
Scott: Because if any if you've never actually tried to set up like an online store and not just a crap I have a press not just cafe press like an actual one.
Scott: Let me tell you every you know free program that does that sucks balls And it really sucks is because a lot of them are designed for people who are like really doing it like full-on And we're only kind of sort of doing it.
Scott: You know we're not making like a full online store.
Scott: I don't need tracking of massive inventory or tax stuff.
Scott: I kind of need tech stuff, but I don't need the application to do it for me.
Scott: And and these things that just have way more features than I ever need.
Rym: But yeah, I think for now once we actually have this stuff We'll probably just sell them at cons at price just until we figure out how we're gonna deal with all that.
Rym: yep So the moral of that is if you want to see the early linger the early bits of swag that are coming out You might want to come to the New York anime festival, and we're also doing a bunch of cool events there, but whatever.
Rym: well We're doing the match game.
Rym: We're doing another match game.
Rym: We're doing our famous or Infamous Gekiga panel, and it's modified.
Rym: It's a somewhat less Rapedastic and more informative and actually about Gekiga.
Scott: Yeah, and play it helps that I have now You know decided that I will use the word Gekiga more freely based on a book.
Rym: I read oh really yes.
Rym: Well, maybe we'll talk about that at the panel.
Rym: Maybe it's gonna be a good time.
Rym: We're gonna record it.
Rym: I don't know if we'll put it on the air.
Scott: who knows maybe not.
Rym: you'll have to come and see it live.
Scott: When is the New York anime fest?
Rym: it is December 7th 8th and 9th at the Jacob Javits Convention Center in New York City?
Rym: We'll be there the whole time.
Rym: We'll have a table.
Rym: You can't miss us.
Rym: also, don't miss it we have Dave at least and possibly Joel from Dave and Joel's fast karate.
Rym: for the gentleman They're going to be our well I don't want to say personal staff, but they're basically attached to us, and we'll be using them for various things.
Scott: Did they know this?
Rym: oh?
Rym: Yeah?
Scott: I made it quite clear all right, and we'll see how that goes.
Rym: and the well I'm paying for his badge indirectly indirectly Plus uh it turns out that at least one member of anime world order possibly two will be there though the second one is wishy-washy Very wishy-washy and the ninja consultants are gonna be there.
Rym: well.
Scott: They live right there.
Scott: Well.
Rym: They better be there.
Rym: I mean God There's an anime con within an hour of your house, and you don't even least go for one day.
Rym: You got a problem unless you hate anime.
Scott: I guess yeah, yeah.
Rym: But then again you can go to Otakon hating anime and not knowing what it is and still have a great time.
Scott: Yeah, you got it.
Scott: Well.
Scott: I guess it's hard to go to PAX not like in games, but Yeah, I guess if you were a griefer yeah, do you want me to try tell the French toast story?
Rym: I guess you could.
Scott: it's kind of a sad story.
Rym: It is sad.
Rym: I feel bad for you like I really do this.
Scott: Oh, so my work right in.
Scott: only every Wednesday the office buys food for everybody and it's usually 90% of the time.
Scott: 99% of the time it's the same like basket full of bagels and Cream cheese and like a stack of regular cheese or whatever.
Scott: and they just put it on this counter and everyone goes over on their Own time and grabs a bagel on Wednesday morning right and then by Wednesday by Thursday They're all hard as rocks.
Scott: They throw them out Because no one knows what is it.
Scott: black bag is and I think I'm gonna start bringing ziploc bags to sort of bring bagels Over to Thursday and get people pissed off at me, but anyway curse him with his clever ingenuity So far in the time I've been working there, which is almost a year.
Scott: Maybe like six to eight months something like that.
Scott: Yeah, some some like eight months.
Scott: They have twice Ordered food specially where they the one person who's job it is to deal with this.
Scott: Well send everyone an email with a menu.
Scott: you read the menu and you reply with what you want, right?
Scott: So last week they she sent out an email and she's like order stuff.
Scott: We're gonna get good food this week instead of bagels.
Scott: and I was like woohoo.
Scott: So look to the menu and I said French toast Okay, and then I got an email the next day that was like yeah guys where we're not gonna do it cuz not enough people Replied in time.
Scott: We're just get bagels this week and we'll do the food next week.
Scott: Ah So it's next week now now is next week, right?
Scott: so yesterday there was an email in the morning that said hey order stuff and I'm like, oh, yeah, right ordering stuff.
Scott: and I said I'll do it in a few minutes and then I forgot completely.
Scott: Oh man, and this morning I go into work I'm expecting bagels cuz I totally forgot And co-worker walks by is like hey Scott your order food.
Scott: I'm like shit forgot to order food.
Scott: Damn it Oh, well, and then I tried to eat one of my yogurts that I bought at the grocery But at the bodega and bodega bodega.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Meanwhile the bodegas and Soho are not cheap.
Scott: The yogurt was a dollar whereas yogurt and ShopRite is 33 cents.
Rym: What a yogurt.
Scott: Yeah, it's bullshit But anyway, there were no spoons.
Scott: So I have to bring a spoon to work tomorrow to eat my yogurt.
Scott: So I'm gonna go.
Scott: I didn't get my food.
Scott: yeah, that sucks right but then make it worse right.
Scott: I walk over there a little later to where the food was and This is French toast sitting there.
Scott: It's a styrofoam thing.
Scott: It says French toast on it.
Scott: Just sitting there.
Rym: I guess the French toast unlike the cake was not a lie.
Scott: It was all.
Scott: it was all alone sitting there all alone and I was just like, oh, it's cold now I'm not gonna eat it.
Scott: I'm just gonna let it sit there.
Rym: That's like the saddest story I've ever heard.
Scott: it was pretty sad.
Scott: They still ordered my French toast, even though I forgot to reorder it and then I didn't eat it cuz I had no one told me No one said anything.
Rym: so that the French toast when they walked by and they're thinking that bastard We made sure he got his toast.
Rym: He didn't even eat it.
Scott: bad, man.
Scott: Meanwhile later in the day Apparently some people noticed that there was a French toast sitting there and I think someone ate it.
Rym: Well, duh if I'm walking through my office and I just see unattended French toast I walked by an hour later and it's still there.
Rym: I'm eating it.
Scott: It was actually even better.
Scott: It was a closed a styrofoam container that said French toast.
Rym: now actually today Someone walked by and said hey, there's uh, some food left over from something over there.
Rym: No, it's I ignore it.
Rym: and ten minutes later.
Rym: I walk over there and the leftover food was super fancy sushi Uh-huh, so I ate enough to make myself feel a little sick and then I went back to work, uh-huh My story is not sad.
Scott: No My story is sad is the sad tale of the French toast that went uneaten by me But I should I could have eaten it that morning If I just know and if someone would open their mouth.
Scott: and so that's twice in eight months that my work has ordered special food on Wednesday instead of just the bagels that normally get.
Scott: and Twice I've had a problem but the story of the other time is not interesting.
Rym: So well speaking of sad news though This is probably only sad depending in a not in a oh my god I'm gonna cry sense but more in a wow good god sense So you might know this company called mythware.
Rym: now if you don't they make all those kind of tacky Black bags with like a square picture of an anime character on the front or a nerve logo or something.
Scott: Yeah, you know when you go to anime convention the dealers room There's that one company that has like all these messenger bags all sorts different anime logos on them.
Rym: That's mythware.
Scott: That's them.
Rym: They license pretty much every property they can and they make those.
Scott: I mean, we've talked like those nerve bags.
Rym: We've talked before about how in general.
Rym: I mean, actually I think the nerve bags are pretty cool, but alright That's the best bag.
Scott: They've got a lot of them.
Rym: The flcl one's really good, too Okay, but a lot of them are just like most American fan stuff is really kind of tacky.
Rym: It's always like the black t-shirt with either just the text on it or like the square picture of the red dragon breathing fire.
Rym: Yep, and like Emily got me a Japanese ghost in the shell shirt And it's I. I feel weird using this word to describe this but I think it's app.
Rym: It's a classy shirt.
Scott: It's pretty class.
Rym: I'd like Japanese people get it and Americans don't but I it doesn't matter because the stuff sells.
Rym: but anyway mythware Didn't go out of business at least not officially or anything.
Rym: They didn't blow anything up.
Scott: They just they didn't file for bankruptcy at some court.
Rym: They just Disappeared.
Rym: they're gone.
Rym: They just suddenly stopped answering their phone.
Rym: They're their websites down.
Rym: No one can get a hold of them.
Rym: right.
Rym: stuff was like, ah, alright fine.
Rym: We hereby rescind all licenses to you.
Rym: and Yeah, what the hell dudes?
Scott: Well, you know people sometimes businesses just sort of disappear, you know That often doesn't happen that often but I've seen it happen quite a few times in my life.
Scott: usually.
Scott: Usually though it involves shady business.
Rym: This wasn't a shady business.
Rym: Now what I do want to say a lot of people I mean you could take this.
Rym: Anyway, I saw one comment on the internet that was basically.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: Oh my god I really wanted a nerve bag, but I can never afford one and now I'll never get one.
Rym: This is the worst thing ever.
Rym: Ah But I could care less.
Rym: I mean, oh no, I can't buy semi-tacky black bags with anime characters on him anymore.
Rym: Oh, I think this is a symptom of the general.
Rym: I don't know Non-professional miss of the American anime industry as a whole.
Rym: I mean one.
Scott: I do agree.
Scott: There is too much.
Rym: the fact that right stuff was licensing all their stuff through this company that just disappeared and obviously was not the most together act to begin with and The fact that this sort of thing can happen.
Rym: I feel like I Don't know.
Rym: the industry is just not run the way it should be and it's run by a lot of people who probably don't have A lot of business.
Scott: This is what happens when you get fans running things as opposed to business professionals.
Scott: I mean not, you know, a lot of people would say oh business professionals would fuck over the fans They do all these are.
Scott: well You know.
Scott: It's sort of like.
Scott: you need someone who is it was a fan and respects the actual thing That they're the business that they're doing and knows about the business but also has business sense and is a professional.
Scott: for example look at say I'm just gonna pick any random car company right to the people at the head of that car company.
Scott: Are they really like car nuts who really like they watch top gear and they really love cars?
Scott: Maybe some of them but most of them are just CEOs who care about stock markets and business and all that stuff and as a result Car companies not so appealing to the the people who really like cars.
Scott: But on the other hand if you had say Joe for the local mechanics like being the president of Ford, right?
Scott: He loves hot rods Ford isn't gonna make too much money and it's gonna be sort of shoddy.
Scott: So you got to find someone who's got both.
Scott: like the guys who run Google They know about internet and technology and whatnot and they respect it, but they also have business sense and they're mad monies.
Rym: So if you wanted any of this mythware stuff buy it from wherever you can get it because Even if they reappear come back online or anything to quote right stuff.
Rym: Additionally all license agreements between mythware and right stuff.
Rym: concerning right stuff Those omi entertainment properties are considered canceled effective immediately.
Scott: Uh, do they have like they guess that'll a there might be if I guess if this company comes back if that revoking of license Is not allowed under the contract.
Scott: There might be some.
Rym: I have a feeling.
Rym: I have a feeling though that the company that disappears is not gonna win a lawsuit though In breach of contract Stuff is fulfilling as many of the orders for this stuff that they already had as they can until they run out.
Scott: All right so Marvel Comics, right if you want to read him you cannot is three ways to read them, right?
Scott: Three ways to read Marvel Comics legally ready way number one.
Scott: Well, actually four ways therefore.
Scott: four To read Marvel Comics legally as of last week.
Scott: way number one you could buy paper Monthly comic books in the comic book store, which is crap - you can buy trade paperbacks.
Scott: That is the preferred method by Scott.
Scott: Three you could doubt I guess non-legal way You can fire at them from the Internet's get a bit torrent full of every Marvel comic every week Yeah, and the fourth legal the fourth.
Scott: the fourth way which is also a legal way is to buy those DVDs that are like.
Scott: You know, uh, you know every like 400 issues of spider-man on DVDs and PDF format buy me in a box.
Scott: Now Marvel Comics has added one more legal way to read Marvel Comics on their website.
Scott: Basically, they made this sort of comic reading application of sorts That lets you like read panel by panel or zoom in and all this stuff.
Scott: And is it a good application?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I haven't tried it But it's it's sort of like it's not you know, like it's pretty DRM dump, you know You can't like get the comics and stuff and you have to pay money.
Scott: They're giving out like freeze through.
Scott: certain comics are available as like free samples.
Scott: You can check it out and I'm probably check it out later.
Scott: See if it works on Linux lol, but If you go to the website They have like you can now what read the comics digitally and they're gonna let you pay more money to get access to a whole Shit ton of comics digitally like.
Scott: if you actually pay the money, it's really I don't know How much money it is because I didn't look into this too much.
Scott: But you can read for example the first hundred issues of Amazing Spider-Man the first hundred issues of Fantastic Four The initial 66 issues of Uncanny X-Men the first 50 issues the Avengers more and more etc, etc.
Scott: etc.
Scott: and new stuff too, you know, so you agreed runaways on there apparently and even though I own that All kinds of stuff.
Scott: So if you want to read if you've never read these comics and you like Superhero underwear perfect comics and you want to read a whole bunch of them on the cheap This really isn't too bad If you don't mind doing it in front of the computer with this Marvel comics.
Rym: That's the thing I'd really have to be able to put it on.
Rym: if I owned one an e-reader or something or wouldn't be worth it?
Scott: I'm sure.
Scott: I guess if you might be able to if it I think it's web-based.
Scott: So maybe you could do it on an iPhone or something I don't know or not like a tablet PC.
Rym: But most people would have like, you know an e-reader if they're gonna be reading any sort of e-thing Yep, and if it doesn't work on an e-reader I Wall, it's a step in the right direction at the same time.
Rym: It's not a step in the right right direction Exactly.
Scott: It's sort of like someone on our Forum today posted some like Wi-Fi radio playing device.
Scott: It is a step in the right direction, but it wasn't over the line to where it actually becomes a useful realistic thing.
Scott: It was sort of like yeah half-assed almost halfway there kind of deal.
Scott: So this is sort of a halfway kind of deal.
Scott: It's like yeah, we recognize that comics on paper is the old way and comics digitally is the new way.
Scott: Here's a sort of crappy digital comic thing, but that's sort of okay.
Scott: So I'm gonna check it out later.
Scott: the free sample part see how it is that there is definitely one thing I think it's definitely in color which is an advantage compared.
Scott: I buy the big black books like the big, you know essential whatever right which is.
Scott: I recommend them.
Scott: Actually, you can get like a shit ton of comics that are old for like 15 bucks.
Scott: You can get like 30 issues of like the Fantastic Four.
Rym: Yeah, if you like that stuff and you have like a train commute or something Well, there you go and like one big black and white newsprint book.
Scott: You know those big black ones you see on the shelf in the the bookstore, right?
Scott: But they're not in color.
Scott: So if this is in color, it might actually be a better deal.
Scott: I got it.
Scott: I look into it.
Rym: Well, we've been debating if I should still say things of the day.
Rym: So I guess I kind of said it but do you want me to keep saying it?
Rym: Do you care?
Rym: I'm curious.
Rym: Anyway, I mean people must care.
Rym: someone asked on questions week why I always say it and the answer was I just do though Scott just now refused to say it.
Rym: So, I don't know.
Rym: Anyway things of the day things of the day things of the day.
Scott: Shut up in 2007 I'm just not gonna do the show.
Rym: Alright, go on.
Scott: It shows over.
Scott: All right in 2007 this professor in France named Brigitte Koyoma.
Scott: Richard do I I guess?
Scott: if she must be part Japanese part French I guess good judging by her last name or maybe she just married a Japanese guy.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: she Wrote, oh, she's a University of Tokyo professor, but she was in she was French.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: Okay I don't really understand that but that's not the point.
Scott: Anyway, she wrote this book 1,000 years of manga and The book covers the history of the manga all the way from wall paintings and Japanese temples all the way up to Naruto's.
Rym: and such is this book in English or at least for all.
Scott: say it's a 240 it's a 240 page hardcover book and in February of 2008 is the French publisher fla marion viva la wah will Release an English translation of this book and I will buy it.
Rym: good I because if you didn't I was going to up.
Rym: we were talking about be $49.95 because for some reason lately we've been talking about coffee table books a lot and then you know I made the analogy of coffee table games.
Rym: and if ever there were a coffee table book that would go well in this house.
Scott: It is that I don't know.
Scott: There's that other one that's written by that Jason.
Scott: What's his which I also want that cover.
Scott: It's basically a book that contains a synopsis and like a you know The information on every manga published in the US since he wrote it.
Rym: I imagine once we build the geekhouse mark - you know our manor house somewhere with our millions Well in the reading room, we'll have a selection.
Scott: Yeah, I have noticed though There's this increased trend of people writing like academic books or at least publishing in English academic books about Manga and anime and Japanese culture stuff.
Rym: It's not like they could ignore it because it's it kind of swept America pretty quickly Kinda, but it's like, you know, there's some other you don't see.
Scott: I guess you see some academic books about video games and stuff And you know, but it it just seems like there's a really a bigger market for the academic books about the animes and the mangas.
Scott: Then there is for the other nerdy things.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I mean I have seen several academic works on video game.
Rym: Most of them are studies trying to figure out if they cause violence or not.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm saying there seems to be a lot of them, you know and meant for the people who enjoy them You know and I think that's good because I like those things.
Scott: I think it's pretty cool to learn.
Scott: You know sort of like the the the in-depth information about what you're reading.
Scott: instead of just getting you know The thing you did the surface you got to go deep guy with your shovels.
Rym: So what?
Rym: Oh, oh, man I said go deep.
Rym: I realize now that I could have used that as a really good segue into my thing of the day.
Scott: tough shit go deeper.
Rym: The path before you has been prepared.
Rym: All right anyway This is kind of a cop-out but my rationale super cop-out.
Rym: my rationale is thus I'm done with using anything that's on the front page of dig.
Rym: I'm not just gonna be Instead of things of the day for a long time and we've been breaking from it when we can.
Rym: it always seems to turn into Dig video of the day.
Scott: Yeah, it does turn into dig video of the day And I I don't know.
Rym: do you guys watch every dig video?
Rym: That's good Like we do or do you not?
Rym: do you want us to keep doing that?
Rym: Do you want us to be your filter or can you feel to yourselves?
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: but that aside I Realized that I'd never directly linked to this and if I did I couldn't find it and I way back We did a show with the esteemed Jeff to Tarik about anime music videos And I think I mentioned this is in my opinion one of the best overall anime music videos ever made.
Rym: So thus I'm linking you to the YouTube version of night owl productions.
Rym: Hit me baby one more time.
Scott: It's rooms favorite anime music video.
Rym: Now the thing is the reason I like it so much is that one.
Rym: I think it's Expertly timed and expertly done.
Rym: The only real thing you can say bad about it is that was done obviously with old VHS copies of utenna and there's artifacting galore.
Rym: but in terms of the timing and the technicalness of it that aside I think it's almost perfect and there's one little bit of humor that I think the guy or whoever did it just Discovered.
Rym: he could put Rose all over the screen and decided to make a joke about a penis.
Scott: It's actually.
Scott: I think what's so great about this video is that it's sort of complex and that on the surface It is humorous like lol Yeah, but in reality if you've seen utenna and you watch this video a few times Suddenly it's not humorous as much anymore.
Scott: It's sort of like whoa.
Rym: Yeah In general, I'm a huge fan and I know Scott is to have anything that has like.
Rym: the more level something has the better.
Rym: Like an onion is the best thing in the world to us.
Scott: I guess I guess gotta be a bigger onion.
Rym: Well, there was the onion prince But just the I like it when something can work on a superficial level level in that, you know I've never seen the thing.
Rym: This is referencing.
Rym: I have no idea what it is.
Rym: I'm seeing this in and of itself and it is enjoyable and hilarious and anime clubs that screen It will have people yelling and screaming because it is really funny And really stupid and weird.
Rym: it just.
Rym: but like Scott said have you seen the show?
Rym: it's Really well done and kind of Disturbing and it just brings back all these memories of the show and you just kind of at the end You'll tell you know The people who have seen utenna all the way through and the people who haven't People who haven't are laughing going what the fuck is up with those cars.
Rym: That was great And at the end they laugh because it's kind of a funny scene it ends on.
Rym: But if you've seen the show those people are just kind of sitting there going.
Rym: Oh, man That show was great.
Rym: Yeah, so this is it watch it.
Rym: Enjoy it.
Rym: if you don't like it Well, uh, yeah die in a fire and such All right, I guess you can introduce this topic since you uh Partook of this more than I have.
Scott: well, I guess I guess I know more about it.
Scott: But we're today.
Rym: we're gonna talk about the x-men Aka the uncanny x-men x-factor gonna talk about expect how about x-force?
Rym: Nope How about the ridges the x-men?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Is there any other x-men we should talk about?
Scott: There's plenty.
Scott: Excalibur expo See that's that's happens.
Scott: You're from the 90s.
Scott: We're both you know, mostly I mean we were born in 82, but you know Our real culture came from the late 80s early 90s, you know towards the middle of the 90s.
Scott: So that was you know, all those different exes were definitely Artifacts of the early 90s and that such that is the x-men we know best.
Rym: I mean I can tell my story of x-men because it's much shorter than Scott's but I can't say that we're definitely Let me start telling like the history I guess in a very short way.
Scott: Okay, so yeah, it's Stanley back in the day wrote comics about things in bold You're right.
Scott: So he wrote on he wrote X. It was just x-men.
Scott: It wasn't uncanny x-men.
Scott: yet, right?
Scott: It was just x-men and I think he wrote 66 issues if I'm not mistaken or something along those lines right, and then they reprinted him for a while and then so they kept making more numbers of x-men.
Scott: like the number kept going up but they were all reprints.
Scott: and eventually then John Byrne and I forget his name They took over.
Scott: They took over x-men Claremont Claremont and burn and that that's the x-men that everyone knows and loves is like You know the dark Phoenix and the the days of future past.
Scott: and then all that God loves man kills.
Scott: That was all Claremont and burn.
Scott: So when you hear someone talking about burn x-men or Claremont burn x-men they're talking about the real x-men at least what most people consider to be the real deal.
Scott: x-men.
Scott: and that went on.
Scott: and then like they changed the name to uncanny x-men and what you know, and stuff like that.
Scott: and then they kept going.
Scott: and Then I guess in the early 90s when we were kids they came out with Adjective lists x-men and all those other x-books and then it went crazy and I don't understand.
Scott: don't ask me what's doing with x-men today.
Rym: X men I read was when phalanx appeared.
Scott: I Didn't.
Scott: that was after I stopped reading.
Rym: Yeah, but remember I didn't start until all right.
Scott: So I started with adjective list x-men number one.
Scott: However, the first time I ever encountered the x-men right was like someone else had like a coloring book of x-men and I got it From them and I didn't know what the fuck the x-men were.
Scott: I was like what the hell's this coloring book and I never drew in it.
Scott: And then sort of around the same time like I started reading x-men comics starting with adjective lists x-men number one and then Also watching x-men cartoon on Fox.
Rym: Oh, we'll get to that.
Scott: I saw the first x-men live-action movie.
Scott: that was recent But I did not like it.
Rym: my uh My first experience is my parents especially my mom and her brother my uncle were actually really into comics as kids.
Rym: And actually my uncle has I think almost all of the Fantastic Four Like from one on cuz he just read it.
Rym: but hmm and there's all they have all these old comics everywhere And they also have a bunch of mad magazines, but that's beside the point.
Rym: So they didn't really understand why I was just not into comics.
Rym: I didn't know about him didn't care about him at zero interest.
Scott: I like I knew about comic books that I was just completely disinterested.
Scott: what I knew together?
Rym: I knew that there were this thing that all the kids in school were really into and I just thought it was stupid.
Scott: See, here's the thing is I I knew about comic books like I would see like, you know Stereotypical like every day.
Scott: I watched Dennis the Menace cartoon on TV and he'd have like a comic book, right?
Scott: And I knew kids read comics just like I knew kids skateboarded.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing is All right, but no one I knew skateboarded or read comics.
Scott: and eventually a kid who lived down the street for me He was reading comics.
Scott: So I read some of them and that's when I started reading them because someone else is like, ah Yeah, I got to read him without having to pay for him.
Rym: Opened in the mall and then the business exploded my mom went out and tried to get me into comics.
Rym: So she bought me this x-men board game.
Rym: I think you all remember it.
Rym: there's the one that came with all those great plastic figures.
Rym: and Alright, I got this x-men game and it came with an x-men comic and I'm looking through it and the comic was alright.
Rym: There's this blue guy and this guy with a with oh my god He's got laser beams coming out of his eyes, huh?
Scott: The best guy that no one else likes with me.
Rym: I'm indifferent to him.
Rym: Alright and Between that and the x-men TV series that box cartoon the best x-men ever my only x-men That is.
Scott: that is video that is worth watching.
Rym: I got into it and then I went and got back issues of the executioner song.
Rym: I don't know why like someone told me to get into that and I read that and It was okay.
Rym: I liked it.
Rym: I don't remember much about what happened except at the end professor X could walk but then he couldn't again for some reason.
Scott: Yeah, I believe that if I remember correctly That's where there was like some horrible virus that killed mutants and there was yeah, it looked like cable.
Scott: that wasn't cable.
Scott: Yeah, and I time travel cable.
Scott: I know cable was.
Scott: my man was a Cable.
Rym: why cable was awesome.
Scott: Yeah Cuz that was like, you know that 90s stuff that people want to forget about.
Rym: remember our era of x-men is like Cyclops and storm and Wolverine and cable and Bishop and all well just like.
Scott: just to the little comics history here Right in the early 90s is when comics exploded.
Scott: That's when their comic book stores everywhere and you know the death of Superman and all this business going on with.
Scott: you know foil Covers and image comics and all this stuff that comics exploded and people were trying to make money off of them and the comic book guy sort of stuff like was all over the place and you know.
Scott: And what happened was is people are making a lot of what most people think it's you know I mean most of the comics that are making.
Scott: those days were pretty bad and it was pretty much just a rush on money and collecting and Speculating and printing way too many comics.
Scott: and you know people paying way too much money for a comic with a foil cover.
Rym: I remember when a Cyclops and Jean Grey got married.
Scott: Yeah, I have that in my room.
Rym: I I do.
Rym: I also own it.
Rym: I have two copies of it because don't ask me why.
Scott: yeah that's what I'm talking about that kind of stuff and people nowadays look on that time as like a dark age in a way and that happened to be the age of us reading comics because of the year in which we happen to be born
Rym: except I did other than the executioner's song and Sporadic because the thing is at that point I was like, all right, I can dig this I'm gonna try to get into this.
Rym: and then every like x-men I got didn't follow from the last one.
Rym: And then I someone was like, oh you got to read this and this and this and this and I said what what the fuck?
Rym: God, never mind.
Rym: Just forget it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yeah, so let me do a little Synopsis of what x-men is about in case someone doesn't know what x-men is about.
Scott: So you have this world of people a lot like the real world.
Scott: and but in this world some people are Mutants and it does, you know, sometimes it means they're horrible monsters like the beast or something But most of the time they look like every other person.
Rym: I submit that the blue-haired beast is a lot less horrible and ugly looking than the human looking beasts the original human looking.
Scott: It was just kind of weird.
Scott: Well, have you seen the cat beast?
Scott: No, I'll show it to you later Uh-huh.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of people have changed the design of the beast over the years in different comics.
Scott: But anyway, they you know and some people they're just they're born randomly just genetic mutation They're they're mutants, which means there's something weird about them.
Scott: And sometimes usually they get a superpower, you know Sometimes the superpowers kind of useless but sometimes it's more useful.
Scott: like you could be like Wolverine who can heal crazily making him almost invincible and Also have claws and also be a badass and also Unrelated to all that has an adamantium skeleton.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: He was that wasn't because of a mutation as far as I know Yeah, which I keep changing that story ripped out of him by magneto But yet he could still use his bone claws.
Scott: and yeah, that was a big reveal.
Scott: and then you have other people like Cyclops who has eye lasers or Colossus who can just make armor or Professor X.
Rym: he was a telepath something that Colossus was gay I don't know like there was a news article or something.
Scott: It wasn't even love.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know either I don't read them anymore.
Scott: So what do I know?
Rym: I only like Colossus because in the game and the power was basically not the X-Men arcade game Colossus best character Yeah, his power was knock everyone down and he was bigger than everyone else.
Rym: Yeah, that's all that matter.
Scott: Cyclops is the second best because you could stay far away from the bad guys and still hit them.
Rym: and also nothing moves the blob Cyclops Who moves him easily?
Rym: easily.
Scott: so Yeah, so that in the X-Men you had this world where there's mutants.
Scott: Some people are mutants some people aren't and the mutants are treated poorly much like African Americans are treated poorly in the US.
Scott: and it was such a blatant obvious metaphor and that that was what they were trying to Write was like look is discrimination.
Scott: Let's make a comic about discrimination using the mutants to symbolize.
Rym: You know all the minorities of all that have ever been discriminated against and in a stroke of kind of genius You know the X-Men are gonna form and there's all these characters but the leader of the X-Men Professor X. they decided to make him a handicapped and there was a people had a big deal about that when the comic was when we you know, we saw this and because People didn't expect in some kind of superhero comic that there'd be a man in a wheelchair who is kind of the main superhero.
Scott: Yeah, he's wicked powerful in his brain, but his legs don't work.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time he's probably the most powerful.
Scott: Maybe some magneto and Jean Grey, but that says Yeah, so the story is is that basically the mutants were discriminated against but Professor X was a powerful mutant Who was also very popular and was you know in with the government.
Scott: He was a famous professor.
Scott: So he says I'm gonna make a school in Salem, New York, which is sort of a real place that I kind of need.
Scott: Yeah And he gonna build a mansion there and it's gonna be a school for gifted youngsters.
Scott: and basically all these young kids who are mutants and their parents don't want to deal with them will bring them to the school and dump them there and he will raise them and teach them to control their powers and Raise them to be good people and
Rym: then give them spandex make them superhero underwear perverts and send them around fighting evil.
Scott: Yeah, sort of.
Scott: but that wasn't part of the original plan.
Scott: I don't think but it happened anyway, because Because magneto Professor X's colleague.
Scott: He had a different idea because Professor X is always saying mutants and humans could live in peace together.
Scott: We don't have to keep fighting.
Rym: and magneto partly because he was You know concentration camp action messed him up.
Scott: Yeah, because he is a mad Jew action.
Rym: He well, he was a mad Jew who had you had him right the magneto the mutant Jew.
Scott: He was in the concentration camp.
Rym: Whatever his power had nothing to do with Judaism.
Rym: His power was to control metal.
Scott: hence magneto he's basically like he is the a Sentient magnet that is in basically as infinite magnet power or all new Incredibly ludicrously high magnet power.
Scott: and he decided like he could slow down the spin of the earth like in one comic.
Scott: He just shut electricity off on the entire earth.
Rym: he pretty much decided that.
Rym: one humans will eventually fight to destroy mutants because they fear them to.
Rym: mutants are superior and Should use that power to control the world and make it better.
Rym: and three The easiest way to make the world better in the end is to get rid of all the humans all humans.
Rym: You want to kill all the humans?
Scott: Hey hot mama wanna kill all humans.
Rym: Hey hot Scott You want to say the exact same thing?
Scott: I just said but uh steal my joke Which I stole from Futurama, of course Okay, of course.
Scott: That's if anyone doesn't know that's the story of the x-men.
Scott: Any more details of fighting?
Rym: rogue has some emotional issues.
Rym: Cyclops is all cocky.
Scott: There's a whole bunch of characters.
Rym: Is our saber-tooth?
Rym: is the fucking man?
Scott: the whole thing sort of just plays out like most Marvel comics of the day like a soap Opera, you know, it's.
Scott: there's some status quo.
Scott: You know if these people are good and these people are bad.
Scott: and you know time after time crazy stuff happens.
Scott: So, you know.
Scott: so no someone's a villain someone else is doing something crazy over there something over here crazy stuffs happening Randomly.
Rym: we're all getting into our sr-71 blackbird and going into space but oh shit something happens.
Scott: Yeah and crazy stuff happens.
Scott: and then return to the status quo and then crazy stuff happens.
Scott: return to the sesco.
Scott: great and that's That's all the x-men is really.
Scott: So what else you want to say about the x-men?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: the only x-men I actually liked was the Fox cartoon Because it was just the right thing for me at that age and I think it was in General less melodramatic and better written than most x-men comics.
Scott: Yeah, I definitely.
Scott: but I think that the x-men cartoon if watched today, I'm not so sure it would hold up.
Rym: I mean, there are a few other so not bitch that I think would in particular.
Rym: I mean none of that.
Rym: Okay I Hope you know what we're referring to Anis Charles You can find it on your own your big boys and girls But there's a few episodes like the one where they go into rogues backstory.
Rym: I think that was handled very well in the cartoon.
Scott: I don't remember any of it.
Scott: All I remember is that I was the one cartoon that I watched every single week without missing it for a long time And then I eventually missed one.
Rym: very few cartoons had that power over me ever in my life.
Rym: Especially that was the only one up for me.
Rym: It was that and Mask m dot a dot s dot K. It was better than transformers.
Rym: You can all fuck off and whatever.
Scott: What do you know?
Rym: not counting the transformers movie?
Scott: which one I Think that is obvious.
Scott: I know but there's two now.
Scott: so you guys let's see.
Rym: There's one that made me cry and there's one that had far more Humans in it than it needed and far less robots than it should have had.
Scott: but you didn't see that.
Rym: second because I know better all right, and The Zelda cartoon.
Rym: I mean, I like the Mario show Super Mario Brothers Super Show despite the fact that in retrospect That was one of the worst cartoons ever made not as bad as the link cartoon.
Rym: The link cartoon is so much better than that.
Rym: No, it's not as the only problem with it.
Rym: As Emily pointed out it exemplifies the 80s child because you know, there's like the 90s child, which is Zack Morris.
Rym: I'm too cool for school.
Rym: Check me out.
Rym: Oh, man.
Rym: I'm so cool.
Rym: Got spiky hair.
Rym: Bart Simpson was kind of a part of that Too.
Scott: yeah, it was the 80s child was.
Rym: well, excuse me.
Rym: I'm a snotty little blah.
Rym: You're not the boss of me.
Scott: Yeah problem child.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, you know problem child was a pretty terrible movie But it's got nothing on the worst movie ever made which is Clifford.
Rym: I believe it involves Martin Short playing a ten-year-old boy.
Rym: I'll leave it at that.
Scott: I never saw or heard of that.
Rym: It is the worst movie ever made.
Rym: I will stand by that statement to the grave.
Scott: Even worse than mono sands of fate.
Rym: mono sands of fate is kind of awesome because it went around Full circle and became awesome.
Scott: even worse than the worst anime there is.
Rym: at least I can get it.
Rym: There is no enjoyment to be had, you know, some things are so bad that they become awesome.
Rym: This is so bad, but not that bad.
Rym: it's just bad enough to be completely without redeeming qualities.
Rym: But yet it uh, it's one of the few movies ever just said fuck it and turn it off and never saw how it ended.
Scott: Alright, so we decided to show an x-men.
Scott: you were failing to find more to say about them because there's not that much to say.
Rym: I don't like it that much.
Scott: It's the thing is it's weird.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I like The characters and x-men.
Scott: most of the characters anyway some more than others of all the.
Scott: and when I was a kid I read and enjoyed x-men.
Scott: and the x-men I read as a kid I now know is pretty bad right compared to like, you know now I can buy those big black books.
Rym: I think one thing is the x-men.
Scott: we read the character designs of all the superhero Underwear pervert stuff and those are the costumes that the underwear pervert fans hate the most of the ones that we had.
Rym: but yet those Underwear perverts not counting like watchmen or all the I don't know more erudite superhero things.
Rym: I like those character designs.
Rym: I don't know why.
Rym: they're not like the super muscley crap.
Rym: We see sometimes and they're not So spandexy and stupid compared to later ones and they're not so lame compared to earlier ones.
Rym: I I kind of like that aesthetic.
Scott: Yeah, I like.
Scott: I still identified the x-men.
Scott: when I think about x-men I always think about those, you know, adjectivists.
Scott: x-men number one Fox cartoon costumes.
Rym: that Doesn't wear a stupid helmet.
Rym: He wears cool sunglasses Yep, or the Geordie LaForge kind of thing and he has his hair's always out.
Scott: Well, he wears.
Scott: he wears the the wide visor thing when he's gonna be in battle But he wears the red sunglasses the Ruby sunglasses when he's just walking around.
Rym: He never just rips the Ruby sunglasses off like oh man, you know someone well Someone always takes them off his face.
Scott: Then he goes what the fuck did you do be always always all cool?
Rym: He's just kind of like glances over him like No, you see what I did.
Scott: That's more like what Superman does when he's using his heat vision, but he's Clark Kent right now And he's like I need to use heat vision while I'm Clark Kent.
Rym: Anyway, see I really I do like an angel was a total wuss Turned into Archangel who was badass, but sad.
Scott: Yeah, actually, I like the villains in x-men a lot more than I like apocalypse my man.
Scott: It's all about Magneto and mr.
Scott: Sinister sinister.
Scott: I mean, he's just so sinister Sinister no, but in general I like the x-men.
Scott: I like the characters in the x-men.
Scott: I have nostalgia for it and I did enjoy it reading it when I was a kid and all and I. I read some older x-men comics now and some aspects of those are still enjoyable, but some are still kind of hard to get through because they're so old and corny.
Scott: and It's kind of sad that nowadays it's impossible for me to really read x-men or find any ex new x-men that I can enjoy because it's like it's all.
Scott: the x-men comics are so like Convoluted and twisted and like the x-men that I knew and loved or no longer.
Scott: the x-men, you know It's they're all different people and there's all these extra characters in there.
Scott: and this crazy stuff happened And in order for me to figure it out I'd have to read like years and years and years worth of these comics of varying quality and it's It's and and what I would eventually get to.
Scott: you know, even if I understood the new stuff It's not really what I want and it's kind of sad that there was like this this thing and now it's not there anymore.
Scott: It's like this void almost of.
Scott: there's a thing I could enjoy but no one's making it right.
Scott: I don't know There's that ultimate x-men, but I don't know really know what to think about that ultimate stuff.
Scott: It's sort of sort of weird.
Rym: I've pretty much given up.
Rym: I'm gonna stick to reading that one Batman comic.
Rym: I didn't read yet and Yeah, that's pretty much it at this point.
Scott: But in general if you have never read x-men comics or maybe you know You don't think you've read like the important x-men comics go to the store and you know the big black books I haven't said mentioned for the third time this episode.
Scott: get a copy of essential X-men number two not essential uncanny x-men number two.
Scott: That's the Stan Lee stuff.
Scott: essential x-men number two is the Claremont burns stuff and that one big black book Has all the x-men comics that you need to read in your entire life.
Scott: So get that black book and it's like between 10 and 20 dollars.
Scott: You can probably get it on Amazon pretty cheap.
Scott: I'll even look it up while I'm talking.
Scott: and That is all the x-men you need to read.
Scott: and I do recommend that anyone who cares about comics should probably read it.
Scott: I mean, it's got all those important kind of stories and this is a bit of corniness But not as much corniness as some older comics, you know, and it's it's good stuff.
Scott: And then you'll see.
Scott: you know The x-men and why?
Scott: if you don't understand why people like the x-men now if you read this I think you will understand why people enjoyed the x-men back in the day.
Scott: Oh, it's $12 on Amazon.
Scott: In fact, it's $11 and 55 cents.
Scott: Come on.
Scott: You got to buy that.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.