Rym: Welcome all of you new listeners from ConnectiCon and Otakon.
Rym: Before we get any further, I just want to point out that this is not a normal episode of GeekNights.
Scott: No, it is not.
Scott: It is nothing like our normal episodes, and you can listen to this if you want.
Scott: It's probably going to be entertaining in some small way, but you should not judge our show based upon this episode.
Rym: Or even pretty much anything you hear this week, because in fact, we're out of town.
Rym: Con season's over for us until December.
Rym: So we're relaxing and planning the future of GeekNights in Wildwood, New Jersey.
Scott: And we recorded a bunch of little things in advance, or acquired them in advance, and we are playing them for you this week via the magic of computers.
Rym: And the internet.
Scott: So these are recorded at least a week ago, and you're just listening to them now, so don't judge us on these.
Rym: Yes, if you want to hear what GeekNights is really about, just go to the website www.frontrowcrew.com Which you should have already been to.
Rym: They might have just gone to iTunes, it's hard to say.
Rym: But listen to any episode, any one that does not have the word "special" in the title, because "special" is code.
Rym: speak at GeekNights for "Rym and Scott are out of town and too lazy to do a
Rym: show.".
Scott: And while you're at it, try to pick an episode with a topic you care about.
Rym: Yeah, and just real quick, I'll let you know that GeekNights is actually four different late night shows.
Rym: Monday nights are science, technology, computing, all that sort of stuff, Linuxes, Ubuntu's.
Rym: Tuesdays are gaming, so like German board games, or I guess we don't want to offend that nerdy guy from Connecticut, so tactical euro based games.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, and video games and all that stuff.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, the one you probably care about the most, and manga and comics and all that.
Rym: And Thursdays are pretty much just whatever else we want to talk about, kind of the op-ed, Rants and Raves.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, today we're just gonna talk about a little tiny thing and get this over with.
Scott: So, I was looking around the room for something to talk about, and I said, "Hey, Rims got a mouse there.
Scott: Let's talk about computer
Scott: mice.".
Rym: See, Scott and I differ on mice in one way, though we also agree on another thing very much, and I'm just gonna get this straight out.
Scott: Okay, well first of all, mice that are not USB suck.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Second of all, mice that are not optical suck.
Rym: Third, tracked balls are awesome for very specific things like Rampart, or if you have carpal tunnel, they otherwise suck.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: People who talk about tracked balls like they're so much better, it's like, "Whatever, dude.
Scott: You got a
Scott: problem.".
Rym: They're not as bad as those Dvorak people.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Tablets are okay as a pointing device, but they're not mice, so they don't count.
Rym: Now, the real big thing I want to get out there is that you pretty much should be using your mouse at the highest sensitivity you can bear, because one, that'll prevent carpal tunnel as far as I can see, because you're not moving your wrist hardly at all.
Rym: I mean, I flick my fingers, just my fingers, a half an inch, and I can cover my entire screen pretty much.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Mouse sensitivity is basically if the mouse says I moved an inch, then that moves the arrow on the screen a certain distance on the monitor.
Scott: If you have low sensitivity, then moving the mouse an inch will move the arrow on the screen an inch, which means you have to pick up the mouse and move the mouse around a whole lot in order to move the arrow on the screen around a whole lot.
Rym: Also, if you got to move it slowly like that, you're going to be turning your wrist and twisting your wrist and moving your wrist.
Scott: And you're going to be using your whole arm to move that.
Rym: You shouldn't be moving your wrist when you're using a mouse.
Rym: You're going to hurt yourself if you keep doing that.
Scott: If you turn your sensitivity way, way up, right?
Scott: Sure.
Scott: At first, it might feel like the mouse is out of control, because you move it even a little bit and the arrow flies all over the place.
Scott: out of control.
Scott: You can't aim at anything, but...
Rym: Increase it gradually and you'll get used to it.
Scott: If you practice with it, you can just use your thumb and your pinky to move the mouse in millimeters.
Rym: And yet you still have the fine control due to things like acceleration.
Scott: Yes, you have precision control over the arrow on the screen while barely moving your hand at all.
Scott: And that's the way I say it should be.
Scott: And you should learn to do that.
Rym: But anyway, we're not going to talk about that.
Rym: You don't need a lecture from us on that topic.
Rym: You need a lecture from us on a bunch of other topics.
Rym: So there's only one kind of mouse that I will use and I can't stand any other mouse.
Rym: Mice have to be the standard mouse size or smaller.
Rym: And they got to have two buttons and a scroll wheel in the middle.
Rym: And nothing else.
Scott: I need a mouse with more buttons and I need a mouse with wireless.
Scott: And I need a mouse with the fanciness and the comfort of the hand.
Rym: See, the problem is a lot of cheaper wireless mice.
Rym: There's a tiny delay that just bothers me.
Scott: That's a cheap wireless mouse.
Scott: You got to get a high quality wireless mouse or it's not worth it.
Rym: See, now I don't mind the thumb button so much or even the pinky button, but...
Scott: The pinky button is no good.
Rym: I think the real problem for me is that any mouse that has all these things, it's like all modern fancy mice have this big hump in them, especially the wireless mice.
Rym: They stick the batteries in there.
Rym: And I don't like the palm of my hand to touch my mouse.
Rym: It really bothers me.
Scott: Oh, I don't know why it bothers you.
Scott: I like the mouse.
Rym: I touch my mouse at any given time with all my fingers, like the tips of all my fingers and no other part of my body ever touches the mouse.
Scott: See, I like the mouse to feel like a glove on the bottom of my hand.
Scott: Like if they made a mouse like finger grooves.
Scott: No, that's bad.
Rym: Because if the mouse is touching the palm of your hand, you cannot prevent yourself from moving your wrist back and forth at least a little.
Scott: Yeah, I can.
Rym: How?
Scott: It just slides on my hand.
Rym: I'm not seeing it.
Scott: I don't know what your problem is.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think you use mice weird.
Scott: I mean, I don't know.
Scott: I think you use mice weird.
Rym: I use mice in the most possible, awesome way you could use them.
Scott: No, no.
Scott: But anyway, I have the Logitech MX1000 and I think it's a pretty awesome mouse.
Rym: I have these... Well, there used to be back in the day, there were like two Logitech mice that were optical.
Rym: There was the normal one and the slightly fancier one.
Rym: And I bought the slightly fancier one.
Scott: Let's talk a little bit here.
Scott: My original mouse that I had... Well, okay.
Scott: I first had an IBM whatever, right?
Scott: And I had like a Mac mouse with one button.
Scott: That doesn't count.
Scott: The first mouse I bought was a three button, no wheel, Logitech Wingman gaming mouse.
Scott: It was a wired USB mouse with a ball, but the ball was like double sized for precision gaming.
Scott: And that was the height of mouse technology in those days.
Scott: It was such the height of technology.
Scott: That the mouse cost $50 and came with a free game.
Scott: That was awesome.
Scott: Then I moved on to Logitech optical mice, two buttons and a wheel.
Scott: And then I moved on to the MX1000 that I have today.
Rym: I've been using the same mouse since 1999.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: And I'm still using it right now.
Scott: I think you bought a new version of the same one, right?
Rym: No, I bought a new keyboard.
Scott: I thought you bought the same mouse just again.
Rym: No, I actually, what I did do, I don't remember that.
Rym: I remember buying the same mouse to use on another computer.
Scott: I think you bought that.
Scott: I think that isn't the same mouse, but it's the same model.
Rym: I'm not sure because it's pretty beat up.
Rym: I don't remember buying a new one, but I might've even forgotten.
Rym: But yeah, I do remember that I use the same keyboard from like 1996 up until my junior year of RIT where one day while I was playing tribes, it just stopped.
Scott: Well, the reason I liked the MX1000.
Rym: No, it wasn't even tribes.
Rym: It was like Counter-Strike.
Scott: The reason I like the MX1000 is first of all, you can just charge it in a cradle instead of batteries, which is nice.
Rym: I hate batteries.
Rym: At least I don't like batteries.
Scott: If I'm going to get a wireless mouse, it better not have batteries.
Scott: Well, actually the wireless mouse that goes to my laptop has batteries, but that's obvious.
Scott: That's different.
Scott: Two, you can move the scroll wheel left and right for some horizontal scrolling action, which you can actually get used to.
Scott: It's pretty nice.
Scott: Third, it has these extra buttons on it, but the extra buttons aren't clumsy and they actually click solidly.
Scott: And when I'm playing an FPS, I can actually get a lot of extra functionality out of them.
Scott: And some of them are, you know, I can push some of them simultaneous with other buttons.
Scott: So like I can use, you know, a button on the keyboard to say jump.
Scott: Normally I can move that to the mouse.
Scott: And now I've got an extra keyboard button within reach and I can do a lot more FPS controlling with moving my hand around the keyboard a lot less.
Scott: I keep my hand in the same spot and I can do a lot more things.
Rym: See, now I think this might be why we have different tastes in mice and why I don't need the extra buttons.
Rym: The way I set my hands on the keyboard, I have never in all the FPS I've ever played, not had a key ready to go.
Rym: And I actually, I can do all the things I need to do simultaneously as it is.
Scott: So in some FPS is, you know, I can do that even if I have, you know, a one button mouse because I just need the one button to shoot and I've got buttons for everything else, you know, on the keyboard.
Scott: But some FPSs are really complicated and sometimes I want buttons to do crazy things.
Scott: And sometimes it's not an option without extra buttons on the mouse or moving my hand around.
Scott: Like FPS, especially FPS with inventories with full of items.
Rym: Yeah, but even then I think part of that is that you put your hand over by the arrow keys.
Scott: No, I put it by the WASD.
Rym: Oh, the WASD.
Rym: But there's plenty of buttons there.
Rym: What's wrong with you?
Scott: I need more buttons.
Rym: There's plenty of buttons.
Rym: I've never run out of buttons.
Scott: The other thing is that a lot of the buttons I would like to use are, you know, too far away from the WASD or they screw up because gaming is in Windows.
Scott: Like the window key fucks everything up and the alt key fucks everything up.
Rym: Alt doesn't.
Rym: I don't have any problems with that.
Scott: I do.
Scott: I have problems pushing alt in.
Rym: I use alt to duck.
Rym: I've used alt to duck for as long as there's been ducking in FPSs.
Scott: I use a lot more keyboard shortcuts than you and a lot of them are global keyboard shortcuts.
Scott: So I can't use those buttons in FPSs.
Rym: But you play FPSs in Windows.
Rym: Why would you have those shortcuts in Windows?
Rym: You never use Windows.
Scott: I use Launchy in Windows.
Rym: Yeah?
Scott: Yeah, so I can't push like alt and space at the same time and stuff like that.
Scott: And you'd be surprised that actually comes up.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I don't have Launchy on my PC at home.
Rym: I only have it on the PC at work because I only boot into Windows to play FPSs.
Rym: I never run anything but Steam.
Scott: I use Launchy to launch my FPSs.
Rym: But I just, Steam starts when I boot.
Rym: Basically, Windows is not Windows.
Rym: Windows is just Steam.
Rym: When I boot, Steam starts.
Rym: And that's it.
Scott: Even so, I need lots of buttons.
Scott: Especially, like if I'm playing Tribes 2, I need lots of buttons.
Scott: And I like to put some buttons on the mouse.
Scott: I put jump and duck on the mouse.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I put move forward on the mouse and shoot.
Scott: Oh god.
Scott: I put move forward on W.
Rym: See, move forward, I use the same setup.
Scott: And then like, that's the other thing.
Scott: I use like Q to go fast.
Scott: And then like Tab to walk slow.
Scott: And then control.
Rym: Remember, control is like path lock.
Rym: We need to do a show on the setups we use in FPSs.
Scott: I think we do.
Rym: Because I really want to talk about the merits of mine.
Rym: I've got a pretty good system.
Scott: But think about that though.
Scott: FPS is the most important factor in deciding what mouse we buy.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: It was always that way.
Scott: Because without FPSs, I can use a two button scrollie wheel and I'm done.
Rym: Before FPSs, I didn't even notice what kind of mouse I had.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But yeah, computer mice.
Scott: Optical is important.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: This wasn't the best episode.
Rym: No, it wasn't.
Rym: What do you want?
Rym: We're on the beach.
Rym: In fact, we're probably playing a video game at the beach right now on our DSs.
Scott: And those DSs don't have mice.