Rym: It's Wednesday February 14th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We talk about what we like in an anime convention.
Scott: It's a total cop-out.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: Well we just spent the last hour digging our cars out of our driveway.
Scott: Yeah, the snow finally stopped, and I happen to notice as soon as it happened.
Scott: I just looked out because I've been looking out the window like every hour You know and I'm like whoa no snow, so he ran outside.
Scott: I was wearing two pairs of pants and zero underwears when I ran outside and Unshoveled the car.
Rym: see now very serendipitously Emily had helped me rearrange one of my closets that she could store a bunch of stuff in it temporarily and During all of that we pulled out two giant cardboard boxes full of as far as I can tell garbage.
Rym: however however now that I had to go outside and shovel a foot of snow off of my car and off the driveway and Realize that in one of those boxes was none other than my ski pants that I have not worn since the last time I went skiing
Scott: Wow, that's that's a long time.
Scott: It's like a decade.
Scott: I put on my boots that I didn't wear at all this year.
Scott: I haven't worn them since last year and last year.
Scott: I only warm a few times.
Scott: I'll probably buy new ones the next time like if it snows before like in December next year I'll buy new ones, but yeah boots crazy, so we two pants now.
Rym: the best part is we spent You know all this time digging out the car so that we could then Walk to the Chinese place right next to our house to get some Chinese food.
Scott: yep And it's good though because now we don't have to shovel the cars out.
Scott: tomorrow morning when we have to go to a convention We'll just be able to throw our shit in the car and go.
Rym: yeah speaking of which This weekend we're going to be in Washington DC at the Omni Shore Motel.
Rym: start Yeah, we'll be there like tomorrow night Thursday night for Katsucon one of our at least one of my favorite anime convention.
Rym: Scott's never been to it before so we can't say it's his favorite yet, but no I'm pretty sure it's gonna be a good convention.
Scott: It's one of the top ten conventions in the United States in terms of attendance.
Rym: Yeah, at least anime conventions and the previous two years have been great.
Scott: Yeah, and we're going and we're gonna do a bunch of awesome stuff there.
Rym: Yep, and if nothing else We're doing our famous anime match game Which if any of you went to sita khan which there weren't many of you there, then you've seen most of the questions I'm gonna ask because I'm lazy, but I'm gonna reuse most of them because it's a tone.
Scott: Yeah, so few people who were at sita khan will also be at Katsucon.
Scott: Let's see you me Corbin.
Rym: yeah, so great.
Rym: I'll send the con chair of sita khan.
Scott: Yeah, so yeah, we can reuse the same question.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: Corbin wasn't actually there for all of the match game because he had khan business to attend.
Scott: ha ha awesome.
Rym: However, this will put us in a bind because if oda khan asks us to do the anime match game Then we're gonna have to come up with all new material.
Scott: I have to write new material which is oda khan and Katsucon have the same Attendees mostly.
Rym: there's also the problem that I haven't written new material for this since pretty much the second time we ran it.
Scott: Well, I just came up with a new one like a few minutes ago.
Rym: Yeah, mostly to make fun of one of our celebrity panelists.
Scott: Well, you know what?
Scott: If people want to help us write the anime match game of the future.
Scott: All you got to do is make a little thread on the forums and you have to say stuff like.
Scott: I mean a lot of These we've covered but it's got to be stuff like a funny anime.
Rym: Yeah, you see scary and I write all the flavor text.
Rym: We don't need that.
Rym: I could write flavor text all day long.
Rym: what we need are the actual distill down questions like name.
Rym: a sad Anime.
Rym: an anime that made you cry.
Rym: an anime that fucked with your head an anime.
Rym: That was bad.
Scott: Yeah, I just came up with on a few minutes ago was an anime.
Rym: No one can pronounce the name of ha ha way to reveal our one trump card.
Scott: I know right?
Rym: Yeah, luckily I don't think any rit anime people will be at Katsucon either so we can get away with totally reusing old material.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Yeah, but Katsucon is gonna be great.
Rym: Check us out in the video game room where we will be guests.
Rym: slash staff 24/7 give or take for the entire con.
Scott: Oh, this is gonna be great.
Scott: Also, I need to go to sleep.
Rym: There's a good chance if you're there tomorrow night, you'll see us in the lobby playing German board games Or DS.
Rym: Yeah, or just talking something like that, you know talking the thing we do every day a lot Right.
Rym: So in the news, I just want to bring this up not so much because it's happening again But because I don't think a lot of anime fans really know about this.
Rym: But Japan one of their primary exports to the world is Culture and entertainment and it's not like this is just some way it is.
Rym: But it's actually the fact that the Japanese government works very hard to make this reality Promotes this sort of thing and it's definitely part of Japan's kind of grand plan.
Scott: I mean think about Japan is a little tiny island, you know, and they mostly buy stuff from other people.
Scott: Well, they got to give stuff, you know somehow to give away or else economics don't work.
Scott: So the only stuff they really have to give away is Brains, you know things that they can do with their brains.
Scott: They design awesome stuff.
Scott: They invent awesome stuff.
Scott: They make really efficient factories.
Scott: So they buy raw materials and then put stuff together and sell that and they also create arts and entertainment.
Rym: So on February 9th, the Japanese government announced their second five-year plan For the promotion of Japanese culture as I have just stolen almost verbatim from the anime news network.
Scott: Yep, the I guess the other five-year plan it just finished.
Rym: Well, we know how well five-year plans tend to go.
Rym: Lol, I just I don't really have much to say about this other than that one.
Rym: It's smart on Japan's part - Part of this seems to come out of the fact that anime and manga have as far as Japan can tell or is concerned It's doing really well in America and in other parts of the world and they realize that Exporting it is a good thing and they want to increase this or possibly With other aspects of Japanese pop culture.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you think about it this way, right?
Scott: Japan is just one country pretty, you know, it's an important country in the world.
Scott: It's Western and modern and has a lot of people but it's not very big.
Scott: It's not more important than France or Britain or any of those other countries.
Rym: Well, I don't know.
Rym: you could argue about France maybe in the last 10 to 15 years Yeah,
Scott: but I mean if you look at the mind share that Japan has worldwide, you know in terms of arts and entertainment and culture It seems a lot bigger, especially in geek type communities than like say Spain
Rym: God.
Rym: Well, look at us, you know me and Scott I'd say that a good 60 to 70 percent of our total entertainment comes from Japan.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty crazy.
Scott: So obviously their five-year plans are working and if other countries were smart they would Copy what Japan is doing.
Scott: I mean, you know France makes a lot of art Italy makes a lot of art Greece makes art.
Scott: How come they don't export that stuff?
Rym: now the question just becomes is Japanese pop culture doing so well in the world because they're working to promote it or is it because of some inherent aspect of Japanese pop culture?
Scott: that is a good question that I do not know the answer to.
Rym: yes And I hope that we will get some interesting feedback about that in the forums because I don't really know.
Scott: I think we need to talk to someone who's very smart and knows the answer already.
Rym: Yes, and hopefully no one who will beg the question.
Scott: Oh Anyway All right.
Scott: I got two Anime iTunes related news's.
Scott: first of all and a US anime company has made a little store on iTunes, can you guess what company it is?
Rym: Not really.
Rym: No.
Scott: Well, I thought it was gonna be Viz because Viz has those rights to Death Note.
Scott: Yeah, so it makes sense for Viz to open up a store on iTunes and start selling anime, but it's not Viz.
Scott: No, it's not it's it's Funimation.
Rym: Funimation.
Scott: you say yep If you go on iTunes in the United States iTunes store Remember you can change what iTunes store you're in by going to the bottom and choosing a country.
Scott: you can buy all 24 episodes of desert punk all 26 episodes of samurai 7 and 20 out of 24 episodes of speedgrapher.
Scott: I guess the final four episodes of speedgrapher aren't out yet.
Scott: All three of these are gonzo shows great.
Rym: Yeah, well no that's fine cuz you don't need to buy the end just buy the first two and stop.
Scott: Well, I guess when the final speedgrapher DVD comes out, I assume those four episodes will go up on iTunes.
Scott: They're all you know.
Scott: in the standard iPod video h.264 format I assume they look pretty good because it's not hard to make Anime look good.
Scott: and you know digital video formats if you know how to set all the encoding options properly.
Scott: But one interesting thing is you know, this is Funimation.
Scott: They operate pretty much in the US in terms of distributing anime.
Scott: So unless you have a United States billing address, you can't actually buy any of this stuff.
Rym: great.
Scott: And also, you know, it's got the usual Apple DRM encumbrings double great.
Rym: Yeah, maybe it's just me but in terms of how I consume anime and acquire anime in general There are only two ways.
Rym: I want to get it either I want it as it's coming out in Japan in which case I would pay for that But I can't pay for that.
Rym: So I watch the fan subs instead.
Rym: and then if I didn't want to watch it as it came out episode by episode I don't really care when I see it and I'll just get the DVDs from Netflix.
Scott: Yeah, if I don't if I'm not watching a show as it comes out in Japan, you know with subtitles exactly as it is I want to watch the whole thing at once.
Scott: I want the whole thing real quick like in a box set.
Scott: I don't want to get one DVD at a time every month or two.
Scott: Yeah, it's either got to be an episode a week Or it's got to be the whole show for Netflix or in a box set.
Rym: God I remember back in high school, but our D&D group, you know Ken was buying Escaflowne every month when it came out and every time we said let's watch one episode a week.
Rym: That way we'll finish it and then the next week the next tape will come out and we won't have these binges and then these Horrible withdrawals.
Rym: Yeah, and every beginning of the month we'd watch the first episode we'd sit there We'd pause it like alright We're gonna stop watching and then we'd unpause it and watch the rest of the tape.
Scott: That reminds me of the time when I bought the Matt cross box set and then I watched one episode every day.
Scott: That was good times.
Rym: I remember that because I come home and I'd watch about half of them with you.
Rym: Yeah, I watched all my favorite episodes at least.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, I got another iTunes related anime news.
Scott: It's sort of a combo news, right?
Scott: Apparently the big-time pros are gonna come down and compete with the likes of you and me and Anime world order and Dave and Joel and all those other anime podcasters.
Scott: There's going to be a new anime Podcast video show called anime TV.
Scott: What a creative name, huh?
Rym: Who's doing this?
Scott: Oh, it's going to be.
Scott: It's gonna premiere February 15th.
Scott: That's tomorrow at 8 p.m.
Scott: Pacific on iTunes YouTube forever blip TV v social and go anime TV comm.
Scott: so they just had they have an RSS Feed and they put it up.
Rym: All right, so it's all video.
Scott: Yeah, and It's a free podcast anime review show with a cast of die-hard anime fans who know their stuff.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: Do they say who is on it?
Scott: Well, it doesn't it.
Scott: The only thing it says is that Johnny Young Bosch is the host.
Scott: Ah It is produced by bang zoom entertainment who I've never heard of and it has actual sponsors.
Scott: you ready for the sponsors?
Rym: Let me guess all the American anime companies not a one.
Scott: The sponsors are as follows glyco Wait, wait, wait, wait, right.
Scott: There's more Cal Pico.
Scott: I never heard of them.
Scott: Me either.
Scott: Fiji water.
Scott: What hook-ups?
Scott: I don't know who they are either.
Scott: Kellogg's pop-tarts.
Scott: Ah Palm tea.
Rym: All right, that's good.
Rym: I like that stuff Sacco.
Scott: What the hell.
Scott: Sacco birdhouse.
Scott: I don't know birdhouse is either.
Scott: You can get a sneak peek of the set at some URL Whatever.
Scott: And their first show they're gonna review.
Scott: Hari.
Rym: All right, I don't know.
Rym: this has the all the trappings of Commercial products.
Scott: is definitely feels like someone's trying to move into our game But they're gonna be at all pros.
Scott: styling and not a good job.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I I'm not gonna disparage it cuz I've hung out with Johnny before and he's a cool guy Yeah, but I get the feeling that this is going to be a lot like g4 TV in terms of how relevant it is to that actual.
Scott: that's the feeling I'm getting.
Scott: it's like, you know, the way g4 TV reviews a video game is the way that This show is gonna review an anime.
Scott: I'm pretty sure I might even watch the first episode tomorrow.
Scott: I mean, it's free, right?
Scott: I just had to deal with these sponsors ads.
Rym: When are you gonna watch it?
Rym: We're gonna be at Katsu Kan.
Scott: Oh, I'll watch it when we get back from Katsu Kan.
Rym: Yeah, cuz we also have Monday off work.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: it's a streaming video.
Scott: It's a. it's a video podcast Yeah, but yeah, that's gonna be on iTunes and everything.
Scott: So I figured a combo news.
Rym: Yeah, I'm curious to see what this will be.
Rym: I'm as leery of it as I tend to be leery of just about anything in the world.
Rym: So don't take that.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there is already an anime video podcast that I think is really good.
Scott: We're just anime podcast net which is I guess they pronounce it right pawn.
Scott: That's the way they pronounce their show but they they don't seem to make shows too often.
Scott: But like when there's a convention in the Northeast area They usually do video interviews with all the Japanese guests and then they put those up.
Scott: So I imagine maybe after Katsu Kan me if they're there, maybe they'll put up some shows or something.
Rym: Hey, maybe we'll get them on our show and interview him.
Scott: Yeah, maybe.
Rym: yeah, I mean, we'll have all our stuff set up.
Scott: They're pretty smart people.
Scott: what you know, it's considering they speak fluent Japanese to talk to these guests.
Scott: It's actually pretty cool because the video podcast they interview the Japanese guest in Japanese and they have subtitles.
Scott: Ooh, it's much better that way because whenever you interview a Japanese guest you have the translator there.
Scott: It's all annoying because it takes twice as long to hear the interview Because they say stuff in Japanese and then you hear the person in English afterwards.
Rym: No There's a very easy way around that and most podcasters who record stuff at cons and most press people who aren't professional Just don't do it that way because they don't know how whatever.
Rym: but if we interview any Japanese guests with the translator It might suck for us to do it.
Scott: But you take the Japanese person's voice and make it quiet and put the translators voice over it.
Rym: Yeah, you do the BBC thing or the NPR thing.
Scott: The thing is a lot of people don't do that, especially.
Scott: Yeah, I know that's why I remember I would listen to interviews from e3 with Nintendo people and you.
Scott: they would just give you a video of What went on in the interview room and you like ah this takes forever.
Rym: See, that's why we had GeekNights here.
Rym: wouldn't do that.
Scott: No, he wouldn't.
Rym: All right Things of the day.
Rym: OMG, so there's this show called balls of steel.
Rym: don't care where it came from or anything.
Rym: but they did this bit and this bit involves getting a bunch of people who are recognized experts in various fields and Tricking them into thinking that they're on a quiz show where they'll be quizzed about their expertise.
Scott: Oh, so that's like bringing me on a show and asking me about computer stuff.
Rym: Yeah, something like that.
Rym: and Now they got these experts on and they ask him a few softball questions like one guy was an expert on and Frank and You know that sort of thing.
Rym: so they asked the first few questions.
Rym: the guy gets him right obviously and then they ask a question and The guy answers obviously correctly.
Rym: and they the buzzer goes and they say sorry that was incorrect the correct answer was blah.
Rym: and they start off where they're only kind of slightly off and By the end they start doing just absolutely crazy like so stupidly wrong.
Rym: You want to cry a Rym?
Scott: Name a popular robot anime series directed by Hideaki Anno.
Rym: Oh, I don't know.
Rym: that would have to be a Shinseki Evangelion.
Scott: I'm sorry.
Scott: It's wrong.
Scott: It's actually Robot fighter.
Scott: go go go see now.
Rym: This is a lot like that except It's funny and the questions are well done.
Rym: Yeah, but no the end Frank guy starts getting a little perturbed.
Rym: It is just.
Rym: it's a good watch and that's really all I can say about it because I haven't even watched it.
Rym: I can't see anything because some of the times when they ask a question like you can see a situation where?
Rym: You know the answer to a question But you're not like because they said you're wrong and you're being recorded now.
Rym: You're thinking wait a minute Am I sure?
Rym: am I sure?
Rym: and it's almost like I might be worth it.
Rym: Just let it go because you don't want to look like a total tool.
Scott: if I was in a game show I wouldn't call him on it right there, and then unless I was a hundred percent sure and If I you know and even if I wasn't a hundred percent sure I would go and look it up immediately after the show And then call him on it
Rym: though when I was in quiz bowl in high school And you know the varsity quiz bowl team which I got a letter for.
Rym: that says a lot about how my high school was.
Rym: yeah But a lot of times quiz bowl because they're just run by college punks.
Rym: usually They'd have just incorrect questions Or they'd screw something up, and we would call him on it immediately loudly even if we weren't sure.
Rym: sometimes We'd challenge things where we had no idea what the answer was just to win on a technicality.
Scott: Well there is an advantage in that real game shows at least the United States Are governed by so many laws that if they mess up you can totally get them.
Scott: Yeah It's like so if you get all the questions right on Jeopardy and Alex Trebek just keeps telling you you're wrong And you don't get any money on the show and at the end of the show they say sorry you lose.
Scott: if You actually were right then the game show authorities.
Scott: I guess will come and make sure you win.
Rym: Anyway, this is worth a watch.
Rym: So are you continuing your thing of the day theme week?
Scott: I am and Basically what I got here.
Scott: I went around that looked I found a bunch of videos.
Scott: I was because there was so much awesome jazz action on YouTube.
Scott: I didn't know which one to pick.
Rym: Did you find any videos of Buddy Rich drumming?
Scott: I didn't even try.
Rym: that's something on the side Totally outside of all this.
Rym: you ever get a chance.
Rym: try to find a video of Buddy Rich.
Rym: actually you know the drums Yeah, the hitting instruments.
Rym: No no cuz he does something cool anyway.
Scott: anyway What I found that was pretty cool.
Scott: if you remember my thing of the day for Monday the Dave Brubeck Quartet playing take 5. yeah, I can the ancient times I found another video of the Dave Brubeck Quartet playing take 5 in the 70s really in color and It's pretty cool to see the same guys only Way older playing the same exact thing.
Rym: I had a friend who saw Maynard Ferguson playing when he was quite old Yeah, and frail old man could still really jam.
Scott: I actually read some stuff about the Dave Brubeck Quartet on the wikipedia's and That saxophone guy is dead.
Scott: he died like in the late 70s I think but Dave Brubeck is alive, and it's always been his quartet And I guess they still play in places, and they're pretty awesome.
Rym: jazz musicians live forever Yeah, except that saxophone guy.
Scott: Obviously well, I think he might have died of smoking.
Rym: I'm not sure yeah, because jazz players never smoke or drink.
Rym: nah Yeah, yeah alright, so We kind of wanted to cop out so we could get this show done and pack up all the equipment for katsu kans.
Scott: Yeah, we're in a rush to do this show.
Scott: We don't really care about it.
Scott: that much so.
Rym: Well also we you know we really want to review tank police dominion tank police.
Scott: we do We.
Rym: the only reason we put it off now is that like initial D or utana?
Rym: It's one of those shows that we don't want to do half acidly.
Rym: And I have to get a lot of examples of the audio from the sub and the dub because the differences between them and The good things they did and the bad things they did are very important to the understanding of the wonderfulness That is dominion tank police.
Scott: that is too true.
Rym: I fucking love that anime, but anyway tonight since we're going to an anime con And we realized what I don't think we've ever actually talked about this.
Rym: Now we've talked about.
Rym: we did a whole series on how to go to anime cons.
Rym: We've talked about how to run anime cons.
Rym: We've talked about being guests at anime cons.
Rym: We've talked about how to do panels at anime cons.
Rym: We've reviewed anime cons.
Rym: We've never talked about what we personally like in anime cons like what we're actually looking for.
Scott: yeah Well, I think this show is gonna have quite a bit of overlap with the how to run anime cons Because when we tell you how to run an anime con we're basically gonna say hey do the stuff we like?
Scott: Yeah, yeah pretty much, but I do think there is you know definitely something.
Scott: There's definitely not exactly the same show because there are things you have to do to run an anime con these days and make it Successful that we may not necessarily be fans of or care about yep.
Scott: in other words the perfect anime con That is designed only for Scott Reuben is Nothing like a successful anime con with 20,000 people at it.
Rym: Yeah So I don't expect anime con chairs to take what we are saying and try to turn that into a con.
Scott: because well No, please do that.
Scott: It'll be the con just for me.
Scott: It'll be great.
Rym: It would basically be Rym aka hedonism bot surrounded by cadres of cat girls voice actors Yoko Kanno playing a piano.
Scott: Sounds good to me except replace the Rym with the Scott and the cat girls with the non cat girls.
Rym: see it'd be a lot like cinecon actually because you know that video game pianist and Entertainment system and the set the concert late at night.
Rym: Basically we were sitting like in the middle during the practice like it was a private concert for the two of us that we were.
Rym: Yeah, all right, but first.
Rym: I mean I guess the most important question is just why do we go to anime cons?
Scott: for fun The same reason we had to take the guest stage.
Rym: No, I mean our first anime con ever.
Rym: we went for very different reasons than why we go to anime cons.
Rym: now We're in college we're freshmen.
Rym: we I mean we'd all we Freshman.
Rym: I didn't even fully grasp the concept of an anime can either and I remember our friend Luke one day It was like hey, let's all go to Ohio con.
Rym: Where is it?
Rym: We asked, Ohio He said and then like oh I get it.
Scott: Yeah, it's a pun.
Rym: so we go to the website.
Rym: It lists like oh, they've got some guests.
Rym: They've got some events listed a video game room.
Rym: It's in a hotel.
Rym: It's in Ohio and I know we're really not sure what to expect.
Rym: I mean I'd been to gaming cons.
Rym: I've been going to gaming cons for a long time.
Scott: Yeah, I've been to a gaming con or two.
Scott: mostly.
Scott: I went to a magic tournament.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, pretty much just like a gaming con only with one game.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We got we should do a Sean magic someday.
Scott: Oh, God all that money money the way Magic the gathering.
Scott: no sorry it's money.
Rym: the wasting all right, so I knew what a gaming con was.
Rym: you go to play games.
Rym: I was like what at an anime con.
Rym: Do you go to watch anime?
Rym: that seems stupid.
Rym: yeah, man?
Scott: I could watch anime on my own or a gaming con.
Scott: you can see the purpose.
Scott: It's like aha.
Scott: I can't play this game unless there's someone else there.
Scott: playing with people I don't know is actually interesting as opposed to playing with people I play with every day now.
Rym: Then I could have seen the you know going to an anime con to watch anime because back then especially in high school a lot Of anime was hard to come by.
Scott: that is true, but you see yes, I did.
Scott: it's hard to come by.
Rym: yes Yeah, I didn't mean to like.
Rym: that was an unintentional poorly executed pun.
Scott: all right, so Let's just go to the con and forget this episode.
Rym: Let's power through.
Rym: we can do this all right, so Power through what I had something I was gonna say our back on track.
Rym: I'm not gonna edit this at all I'm just putting it up as it comes.
Rym: okay, but we were at RIT already.
Rym: Oh my God We were members of the biggest anime club in the country.
Rym: they had every anime We could ever want to see in a library that we could check tapes out of for free.
Scott: that was true.
Rym: so you know like why should we go to this anime con?
Rym: and The the people who are older and wiser than us who were I'd lived a lot longer than us and seen a lot more anime Who were kind of spearheading our going to this con?
Rym: Kind of sat us down and explained what an anime con was and the way they explained it was basically all right.
Rym: so you go to a hotel and You're surrounded by nothing, but anime fans most of whom are Girls your age who are as geeky as you and are dressed up like cat girls and anime characters And I was like you know that's nice and all.
Scott: it's obvious why that's nice, but I had been to many youth group conventions in my high school days, which is you know all sorts of Exactly your age girls and in a hotel for a whole weekend, so I was like been there done that what else he got for me?
Rym: Yeah, and then they basically said oh, yeah, and everyone gets laid at anime cons all the time not true Yeah, not the same thing.
Scott: They said about the youth group cons.
Scott: That's the same.
Scott: while there was much laying going on Not everyone gets laid.
Rym: you know I'm gonna quote now.
Rym: This is not me speaking.
Rym: This is the disembodied spirit of the average RIT student speaking.
Rym: ah That's what they said about college.
Rym: Ah But no and you know.
Rym: they said oh well There's video game tournaments, and there's art people with art alley and blah blah blah.
Rym: I kept explaining you know all this stuff that goes on And I still really wasn't sure to what to expect.
Rym: so just all crammed into cars and drove to Ohio Which yeah.
Rym: now the problem is we went to a shit anime con that we did, Ohio con 2.0 was shitty.
Scott: I don't know about Ohio con now, but Ohio con 2 was ass.
Rym: It was still to this day the worst con I've ever been to.
Scott: Yeah, I guess.
Rym: so I can't think there have been cons that were close But they never quite reached that level of.
Rym: not only was it bad But I'd paid for a badge And I didn't even need a badge because they didn't have any security.
Scott: we played settlers with a midget whore And that we played settlers of Catan with a midget whore and that is not an exaggeration at all.
Rym: That is the cold raw truth, and not not only was that not the only midget We encountered, but it was not the only whore we encountered.
Scott: we could have played settlers of Catan with the transvestite transsexual sailor Neptune.
Scott: What's the blue one?
Scott: Oh is the blue one Neptune?
Scott: did I get it right?
Rym: you you asshole?
Rym: I forgot about that.
Rym: I seriously didn't remember that until just now.
Rym: oh That was the worst con ever.
Rym: yeah, it was yeah, but anyway What makes a con bad for us is real easy.
Rym: if the con is unorganized at all if I go in and it's not immediately Obvious where I can get a badge Where all the stuff is or at least where I can find out where all the stuff is if I don't see staffers Periodically if there's no one checking my badge which means I didn't need to buy one to get in
Scott: Yeah, that'll piss me off.
Scott: if I don't need my badge to actually get in and I bought one Girl, I could have snuck into this con you better check it if you make me buy it.
Rym: yeah I mean, I I don't think I saw I don't think half the people at that, Ohio can't even had badges.
Scott: I know they definitely stopped checking them.
Scott: It's rich.
Scott: only the video game room checked.
Scott: And you know what.
Scott: that video game room was weak And it was the only thing going on there that video game room was not as well equipped as our house.
Scott: No no it's not God.
Rym: hey, so yeah, I mean we basically number one.
Rym: We want a con that is organized so that we don't have to worry about anything.
Rym: if we want to do an event We just look on the schedule show up at the event and the event will happen.
Scott: yep, and you know even the smallest bit of Disorganization can bother us.
Scott: I mean when we went to Kinetic Con and they didn't have five dollar bills when they were charging what?
Scott: $35 for a bad yeah, and they knew everyone in the world would have 20s And they didn't take credit cards, then you should know that you should have five dollar bills.
Rym: not having them girl Yeah, and they seem kind of angry at us that we were standing there You know waiting for our badges and not getting out of line and then yet There's nothing we could have done to rectify this situation.
Rym: we both had $20 bills.
Rym: even if we pooled our efforts they didn't have any $10 bills either.
Rym: Nope of course, then I wonder how would how is everyone?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't care that con is past.
Rym: We'll cover Kinetic Con next time yep, but I mean we went to the Oricon next which made us realize What cons are all about.
Rym: and for this day forth or from that day forth every con we go to we go primarily?
Rym: Because our culture the culture that we are part of could be described generally as geeks Mm-hmm.
Rym: and while we get along fine with non geeks Yeah, if you're with people who are like-minded and with similar interests you can generally have a better time.
Scott: Yeah, I mean out on the street I might see some.
Scott: you know there's a bunch of normal people, but I can't really like just spontaneously You know have a discussion with anyone in a restaurant about an anime or a video game or anything.
Scott: I mean someone might look like a gamer But I'd have to go and meet them and find out what they're interested in.
Scott: and you know It's not easy to just have fun out with random people at a conventions.
Scott: You know special an anime convention People ever.
Scott: everyone there likes the same shit.
Scott: You could just immediately like whip out a DS and say who wants to play some Mario Kart and ten people be like me me Me yep, or I remember when we went to Otakon after the Leroy Jenkins thing had appeared.
Rym: We're just out of the blue.
Rym: We were walking to the con and I think one of us just yell Leroy Leroy and half the con yelled Jenkins right back.
Rym: And then there was a tiny ruckus.
Rym: Yep It's very fun to be surrounded by like-minded people and we have friends that we only know from conventions.
Rym: And yet we're very good friends with them.
Rym: We see them every year at at least one con.
Rym: We're good friends forever.
Rym: and yet we know him only because we went to these anime cons.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it would be one thing.
Scott: if you know all the like-minded people lived in the same place Then a convention wouldn't really be necessary.
Scott: You know like if our culture was not geek culture, but popular culture.
Scott: What do we need a convention for?
Rym: Yeah, just everyone.
Scott: everyone is interested in the same stuff.
Scott: if you like sports and TV shows and reality shows go to a bar.
Scott: There's people there.
Scott: It's like a little convention every night But if you like geeky stuff you have to you know, you can't go to a bar.
Scott: There's no geek bar.
Scott: Oh, yes.
Scott: There's a few geek bars in the world, but not many.
Scott: Yeah You live in like San Francisco or like Toronto has that one Linux bar and maybe a couple other places But that's it.
Rym: Well like in Rochester of several times we decided to try and check out the nightlife of Rochester.
Rym: we went to a bunch of dance clubs over the years and Most of them sucked but that was mostly because Rochester's nightlife is pretty much non-existent.
Rym: Yeah, but - even when we found clubs that had people in them The music was just not music we cared about.
Rym: it wasn't even like good techno or good mod.
Rym: It was just nothing.
Scott: Yep I mean the only place you could really go for entertainment on a consistent regular basis was the gaming store Which wasn't open at night.
Scott: it was open during the day and there would always be gamers there.
Rym: so now we go to a con and they've got the rave or the dance or whatever.
Rym: and Not only is it usually good music or at least good enough music usually.
Scott: yeah, I'm cons are no good Oda kana.
Rym: God.
Rym: actually Katsucon has as far as all the cons.
Rym: I've been to some of the best dances ever.
Scott: Yeah, well, we'll see when we go there.
Rym: Yep, especially since last time or two times ago.
Rym: They had 80s night Which made me feel very much at home.
Scott: It doesn't make me happy.
Rym: Yeah, mr.
Scott: Never heard of karma chameleon But supposed to know what the crap is.
Rym: and also the front row crew was formed at this point and you know It's modified change grown slightly over the years.
Rym: But even back then there was something about getting the whole crew together going to a foreign land like Chicago or Baltimore and Setting up our little encampment and then venturing out to recruit new people or to attack.
Scott: Yeah, depending It's mostly just a social a unique social experience.
Scott: That is the number one reason for a convention of any kind of any geek convention to exist.
Rym: So so I guess aside from that to not beat around the bush anymore in terms of the con itself.
Rym: So we can also end this episode and I can pack all my stuff together.
Scott: Yeah, I gotta go pack some clothes and my toiletries and shit.
Rym: Yep Yep, but in terms of the con itself the material of the con our perfect con generally is large.
Rym: my large I mean at least 5,000 people.
Scott: Yeah, if there aren't enough people there I mean sure with a maybe a thousand people you can have some fun.
Scott: But eventually you walk around the con and you keep seeing the same faces that you've seen already.
Scott: The same cosplay walks by again.
Scott: Yeah You know a con like that with so few people only needs to last one day just because or it needs to have so much Quality programming which is not easy.
Rym: So because not all programming appeals to all people plus smaller constant have less programming anyway, that's exasperating the problem.
Scott: Yes so if you're gonna have a Exacerbated you need a lot of people so that I can keep meeting new people.
Scott: the percentage of cool?
Scott: Well, the percentage of cool people will probably be the same at any con.
Scott: the total number of cool people will be greater at a Bigger con.
Rym: Yes And that is key because it seems to me that in anime cons and gaming cons and all this All the cool people at a con tend to kind of form into one or two globs like all the cool people keep running into Each other and eventually like there's this giant mass of interconnected cool people totally separate from the seething teaming masses of
Scott: fat fans.
Scott: Well everyone at a convention is not.
Scott: everyone at a convention is sociable.
Scott: the thing is there are enough sociable people that their awesomeness can occur and There's a critical mass, you know, it's like let's say I'm just making up numbers 15% of people at a convention are cool.
Scott: Well, if the convention is a hundred people, it's 15 cool people.
Scott: The convention is a thousand people.
Scott: That's a hundred and fifty cool people.
Scott: if the convention is 10,000 people That's you know, yes, you get the idea.
Rym: Yep, and also aside from all that con has to be organized.
Rym: con has to be in a convenient location.
Rym: by convenient I mean a major freaking city.
Scott: Yeah, well the thing is it's got to be near a lot of hotels But It also has to be in a nice Convention center of some sort or a nice hotel.
Rym: the con has to be on an interstate or I'm probably not gonna come to it.
Scott: Yeah It has to be easy to get to but it doesn't necessarily have to be in a big city.
Scott: if there was somehow a really nice hotel Just outside of a big city as long as it was easy to get to it would be cool.
Rym: And in terms of programming I don't know what we want in terms of panels is barely achievable by the masses as far as I can tell.
Scott: Yeah, we want professional freaking amazing presentations at every turn like, you know listen to like the Byzantine twelve emperors rulers podcast, right and You're basically listening to an amazing lecture where someone who's a genius Informs you about these amazing things that you've never heard before.
Rym: Yeah and it's so ludicrously interesting that that you can't believe or listen to a stand-up comedian who has Well put together jokes and he's just telling to you in rapid succession.
Scott: Yep, or You're going and you hear like two or three people who are like super important people in the industry who know their shit like like the back of their hand and They have a discussion and you're like a fly on the wall during this amazing discussion of all this interesting shit that you know people hardly ever talk about.
Scott: that's the kind of panel you have to have.
Scott: any other panel is Completely uninteresting.
Rym: I've seen maybe Eleven good panels in my entire life.
Scott: I don't know how many maybe three.
Rym: Well, I've been to more cons.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, yeah, and let's see.
Rym: I want a video game room to exist and I don't really care beyond that.
Rym: I used to worry about playing DDR cons, but now I can play DDR whenever I want.
Scott: Yeah, if you have a game room, you're only really gonna get me in there
Rym: if we're guests at the game room
Scott: or if the game room has some sort of games that I really can't play anywhere else that I really want to play and that there's not gonna be a Way for me to play them in the future.
Rym: Yeah, last concert gone had that retro arcade, which was most fantastic.
Scott: Yeah, I mean like back in the day dance dance revolution not easy to find a machine at the you in the u.s At the time.
Scott: not easy or cheap to get the home version at the time, you know.
Scott: So if a convention had the game available to play that was way cool And you would totally wait in line to play.
Scott: now I could go and there's three machines and Wildwood and I have pads in my house.
Scott: so who cares?
Rym: terms of showings?
Rym: all I want is Horribly violent.
Rym: East Asian low-budget cinema prefer preferably live-action.
Scott: I agree That is the only thing I also want because if it's anime It's gonna be on DVD or fansub.
Scott: I can watch it.
Scott: if it's live-action air Asian cinema.
Scott: It's probably rare.
Scott: it's not easy to get it in the u.s.
Scott: Especially if it's unedited and subtitled and I've probably never heard of it and wouldn't know how to find it.
Scott: Your convention needs to have someone who knows about that shit can go out and find it can get it and then show it.
Rym: The only other thing I could see now now that I think about it is what if I can't like, you know Oh to con is that like the giant showing room?
Rym: What if they showed something like a door you die?
Rym: So sassen just as a super big showing.
Rym: So now you have the opportunity to watch something like that with a gigantic crowd.
Scott: I'll be awesome.
Scott: I totally go.
Rym: Yeah, maybe I'll try to propose something like that.
Scott: That would be so cool.
Scott: Yeah, the other thing convention I like it.
Scott: conventions is certain kinds of guests I like and certain kinds of guests I don't like.
Scott: like it doesn't matter if it's someone cool or someone not it matters if it's someone who will Entertain me at the convention.
Scott: For example, you might get Let's see.
Scott: Let's try to think of someone like here.
Scott: Rintaro Was that anime next right?
Scott: and we saw him at that panel where barely anyone was at?
Rym: And I don't know why no one was at that panel, yeah, but anyway Rintaro was way cool.
Scott: Hey, you know, he's a way cool guy.
Scott: He's way awesome makes awesome stuff and his panel was okay But his presence wouldn't get me to a convention because what's he gonna do there?
Scott: He's gonna talk in Japanese about some stuff.
Scott: He's made that I've seen.
Rym: I mean granted that panel could have been a lot better.
Rym: It could have been a lot if the moderator had actually screened the questions from the audience at all.
Rym: yeah, cuz half those questions were just I Expound for five minutes about how erudite I am when it comes to anime and I want to impress Rintaro.
Rym: And now I finish this long Rambling rant with a totally inane stupid question.
Scott: the whole separate GeekNights episode is how to ask a question at a panel that he's Always got feeding you up.
Rym: God.
Scott: We hate everyone No, but let's say you get someone like like muck.
Scott: muck was at Otakon, right?
Scott: They're just a myspace j-rock band.
Scott: there's really.
Scott: that's the truth, but you know what.
Scott: I Didn't go to the con for them, but I went to their whole concert and it was still awesome.
Rym: It was a great hard concert.
Scott: Yeah Cuz I mean someone who's putting on a concert is able to provide me with like Oh hours of entertainment at a convention Whereas someone much more awesome than muck like Rintaro is not really an entertaining guy.
Scott: I mean Maybe if I was staff or if I was another guest at the con and I was gonna spend a lot of time hanging out With Rintaro behind the scenes at the con then his presence would you know make me see
Rym: see now That's why you should be staff and an amazement with me.
Scott: Yeah, that amaze me.
Scott: if it wasn't so far away and I wasn't starting this new job I probably would.
Rym: yeah cuz an amazement honestly has some of the best guests especially considering how large how small the con is.
Rym: Relative to other cons They get some guests that you really wouldn't expect and being staff is so awesome to hang out with those people at all.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, but yeah, generally a musical act I care about a lot and like the Laraku concert at Otakon a few years ago It was abso-fucking-lutely amazing.
Scott: Yeah, it has to be.
Scott: your guests have to provide Entertainment in order to make me happy.
Scott: It can't be someone who's gonna sit there and go like, you know, like oh We've got a voice actor.
Scott: I'm like voice actors.
Scott: don't entertain people.
Scott: All they do is say some things in their characters voices and make a few fangirls go Except the one god, I forget his name now, but I really like him.
Rym: He played a bunch of stuff in Urusayatsura But he was at an amazement and he put on an amazing freaking panel about how to voice act.
Rym: That was absolutely awesome.
Scott: Oh, see, that's good.
Scott: You know, it's it.
Scott: the thing is if you You know just having them there isn't enough.
Scott: you have to find some way to make them entertain.
Scott: You know for most cases avoid that voice actor is not gonna entertain that much but you can get them to.
Scott: You know, like if you bring an artist right and you just have the artist give a panel, you know Whatever, you know what they drew whatever.
Scott: but then anime artists to like do some sort of art competition.
Rym: well I was about to say anime central did iron guest every time I went and They take like two famous artists like two of their guests Give them a topic and they do iron chef.
Rym: only they both had to draw the topic in a half hour And then like they had the judges panel vote on it and they had a camera on both of their hands showing him as they drew And the guy went back and forth the interview and it moves super double awesome.
Scott: Yeah, you've got to make Something that entertains me for me to go to it because if there's nothing entertaining going on in the programming I'm gonna walk around to the dealer's room and the artist alley and the hallways and wherever and if I don't find anything to do I'm gonna be bored.
Scott: I'm not gonna be happy in a perfect world.
Rym: Who would we want?
Rym: his guess?
Rym: I mean, I would love to see.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I mean we have a sake.
Scott: that sounds like a good guess to me.
Scott: Yeah, who is that amazing voice actor guy?
Scott: who does?
Rym: Oh the guy who plays everything art koyasu.
Scott: Yeah, we talked about him last week.
Rym: Yeah, the guy Takahashi Rios, okay, and toga.
Scott: Yeah that guy.
Scott: Yeah, hotohori, uh bring Osamu testicle back from the dead.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, let's just bring him.
Rym: Anyway roll him in.
Scott: Yep Miyazaki bring him in on.
Rym: I imagine you'd have interesting things to say.
Scott: Yeah, who else would have awesome stuff?
Rym: There's always the old joke for a near kinesia.
Scott: He would have something to say.
Scott: say far say far but I've something to say.
Rym: but like back when we were first going to cons the jet like the Rumor that came every year about every big con.
Rym: Was that to mix or Megumi?
Rym: Hi, ashi bar?
Rym: We're gonna be the guests and it never happened.
Scott: No, I didn't.
Scott: I think Megumi was at an old anime expo or something though Something like that.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I like her but I like Ayumi Hamasaki and Maya Sakamoto a lot more.
Rym: see if we're talking about can do I don't sing.
Scott: really bring something to a con is bring an Interesting guest like like.
Scott: there's that con that Admiral order went to in Florida somewhere that had the space ghost guys.
Scott: a guest yeah, or get Lionel or Yeah, the guy who does Lionel not Lionel Lionel I know not the trains but like a voice actor of Lionel on Thundercats or the office prime voice actor or or you know What you know who I'd like to see Ikuhara cuz.
Rym: I just want to watch him be creepy all weekend.
Rym: Yeah, that'd be great.
Rym: I'd love to talk to Ikuhara.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it's like people keep bringing over like character designer for some show and it's like nobody cares.
Scott: Nobody knows this guy why even paying for him to come you could have got.
Scott: you know You can get rid of five of those guests and get someone who's actually entertaining.
Rym: Yeah cosplay I don't care about as long as it's there Cuz one.
Rym: it means that all the cosplayers will come and I like to look at their costumes and it always adds something to The con to all.
Rym: those people are not removed from the convention for four hours so I can run around and make mischief.
Scott: Yeah, I mean a con without a cosplay at this point.
Scott: I mean, I know a lot of the Grumpy anime podcasters there.
Scott: They really wish they could make a con like that.
Scott: The problem is a con like that.
Scott: So few people would come, you know compared to another con and It just there wouldn't be stuff happening.
Scott: It would just be like people sitting around going.
Rym: Hey Hey, I think we're just gonna stop here because I mean we could talk about dealers room and artists alley But I think I can sum it up very briefly in terms of both of those.
Rym: We just want Otakon because no con comes even close to Otakon when it comes to an amazing artists alley.
Scott: I want a dealers room that has stuff for sale.
Scott: that is out of the ordinary Stuff that I can't find anywhere else.
Scott: if I walk around the dealers room and I see stuff that I've seen everywhere else I don't care.
Rym: anime next actually had a really freaking good dealers.
Scott: Yeah, it was surprisingly good.
Scott: I walked around.
Scott: then I was like, huh?
Scott: Look at all this shit.
Rym: I didn't expect this but with anime central being a close-up a distant second Otakon is the only con where I actually really enjoyed the artist alley and artists alley is really all about.
Scott: You know quantity and quality.
Scott: I mean the more artists there are the more likely.
Rym: and war.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if there's five artists sitting there, I'm gonna go there once and that's it.
Scott: If there's you know a hundred artists I'm gonna spend a lot of time in there because I want to check out every single artist that's going down and you know Get sketches and commissions and buy things
Rym: Yeah, and of course last I like to go to cons that pay us to be guests.
Scott: Yeah, that sounds right.
Scott: Yeah If your con is free or cheap that is pleasant.
Scott: It's also if it's close to my house Yeah, it's nice to if I don't to go very far or if you pay for transportation in a plane.
Rym: I love how the small teleporter of all the cons.
Rym: We've been comped into the one that gave us the most was the smallest.
Scott: Yeah, it's true.
Rym: oh well That's it.
Rym: We'll see you all at katsu con which is gonna be super awesome this weekend.
Rym: We may or may not have an episode tomorrow night Depending if we finish our special in time or if we just go to bed.
Scott: this episode is totally a cop-out Yep.
Rym: Uh, yeah, we'll see you soon.
Scott: Whoo I'm tired.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.