Rym: It's Monday June 18.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we talk about my new computer.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I was all set to talk about how I got to leave work early because the power went out in Yonkers probably because it was the first hot day and Everyone's air conditioning was on, but
Scott: I'll tell you there's nothing people love more in New York in the tri-state area than blackouts.
Scott: We love black out.
Rym: Oh, yeah, cuz nothing bad ever happens during a blackout.
Rym: No siree.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: It's awesome Everyone gets to go home Everyone has a big laugh.
Scott: It's a nice change of pace.
Scott: It makes the day exciting.
Scott: It's way cool.
Rym: Yeah, actually I remember during the big Northeast power outage the biggest problem.
Rym: I mean I got home from work just fine, and I just sit in my house, and I think all right This is gonna be fun.
Rym: I directed traffic for a while started getting dark and went home And then I went to eat and I realized that I didn't have any food except food that needed cooking.
Rym: that's fine.
Rym: I got a gas stove, and I turn it on and I realized that Oh Electric ignition yeah, even with a gas stove you could light it with like a lighter.
Rym: Oh, yeah a lighter or a match or something, but there weren't any in the house.
Scott: Well, you can go to the store and get some.
Rym: oh, yeah, so uh I went to the store and They were all closed because they didn't have any electricity gas stations open.
Rym: uh gas station wouldn't sell anything Because they didn't have any electricity to run their stuff.
Rym: They would not take money They would not sell things.
Scott: there are some places that are that will stay open in a blackout.
Rym: I couldn't find any and after an hour.
Rym: I went back home I opened a can of cold ravioli, and I ate it and then I went to sleep.
Rym: They wouldn't even sell me anything at all.
Rym: I walked into the gas station And I was like at least maybe this is why looting is so rampant.
Rym: uh Yeah, because I really needed to buy that 42 inch gas plasma.
Rym: Just as the power went out Exactly, but uh no.
Rym: I'm not gonna talk about that because a little while ago.
Rym: I almost burned the house down.
Scott: Why why did you almost burn the house down?
Rym: Well you see we have a lot of computers in our house too many.
Rym: We have more computers than we have need for at this point Which is great because I love that but fortunately I think someone out there might need a computer.
Scott: We should get rid of one.
Rym: well see the thing is I've realized now that there's a law in the universe that states that if Rym and Scott have too many computers Catastrophe will befall one of them in short order thus restoring balance to the force.
Scott: well I would argue that catastrophe had already befallen this computer Probably twice two or three times at least.
Rym: The long story short is we had one computer called Jameson because it was a mother board.
Scott: it had a $20 motherboard.
Rym: It was in a case that was basically cursed in many ways.
Rym: It caught.
Scott: we replaced everything in that case except the case and the power supply and it caused the same problem With two different computers, so uh we used it as our Skype box.
Rym: I kept it next to my computer because you can't easily record Skype and Linux And I have the nice mixer.
Rym: so I especially when my old computer was slow I just have this little box here and it would take care of the Skype and we could do whatever we wanted to do get people on interview them.
Rym: and I had my new computer.
Rym: so I cleaned up my room redid my desk put it all back together and today in the AC since I got home from work really early.
Rym: I decided to plug good old Jameson back in and set him back up at the Skype box Now that my cables were all nice and cable tied.
Rym: so I stick him down there I plug him in I turn him on I plug him into my monitor And I look and sure enough it notices that the disc hasn't been fished in a while And it was mounted a bunch of times because I kept using that USB thing.
Rym: so it starts fisking the disc and I go downstairs.
Rym: An hour later Scott comes home all right.
Rym: Let's go get a p.o.
Rym: Box.
Rym: We need a p.o.
Rym: Box and all that business.
Rym: So we head out and just before we're about to actually leave I run up to my room to get my wallet, and I open the door to my room Which is sealed shut you know air conditioning, and I smell burning.
Rym: I smell electrical fire Awesome, and I'm very well acquainted with the smell.
Rym: due to some incidents that IBM back in the day.
Scott: I'm very well acquainted the smell with many computers that set on fire.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So I'm frantically going around the room looking for whatever is on fire trying to determine if this is an emergency yet or not?
Rym: And I'm half debating running downstairs and just hitting the breaker before I come back up.
Rym: Eventually I tracked down the smell to the computer area And I think oh no no no and I moved my mouse and my computer's fine Huh, so I hit the source button on the LCD and Jameson's not working so well anymore.
Scott: I wonder maybe that $20 motherboard has something to do with it?
Scott: Oh, maybe maybe that proceed power supply in case has something to do with it.
Rym: now I was particularly worried because on Jameson's hard drive is the entirety of the archives of GeekNights Awesome because Jameson was the backup.
Rym: So uh I go down there and sure enough the smell of burning is overpowering and the case is hot to the touch.
Rym: So I unplug it and I kind of push it out of the room.
Rym: Good plan yeah, so it's sitting downstairs.
Rym: I plugged it in a couple more times now that in a safe condition Somewhat safe.
Rym: Scott left the room every time I did it to see what was wrong.
Rym: I think it's the power supply.
Scott: Yeah, I would if I had to plug it in I would have done it outside But the extension cord from far away see the thing is.
Rym: I knew it wasn't going to explode or anything It could have.
Scott: not really don't?
Scott: we could add some capacitors going pop pop pop.
Rym: I've had that before it's day.
Rym: I'm not that dangerous pretty dangerous.
Rym: Not really plus the top like to avoid it.
Rym: They wouldn't have gotten me.
Rym: That's I wasn't too worried.
Scott: I need safety goggles before I'll get close.
Rym: Yeah, suffice to say that computer is now two dead and between that and my old computer shows are.
Rym: I think we've got to pull All the relevant parts and make one computer out of them again, I think we do.
Rym: maybe it's time I don't think the motherboard survived.
Rym: That's just my guess.
Scott: Yeah, I think yeah We'll probably just make a new egg order for because I'm gonna get another hard drive and RAM for my computer.
Rym: I'll probably get a couple more hard drives to make some sort of Linux raid and then we'll buy a case for whatever We could.
Rym: yeah, I'll buy a. probably I'll buy the second cheapest case on new egg.
Scott: That's still a bad case.
Rym: Hey, it's not the cheapest case.
Rym: Cardboard box full of razor blades get a good one for like $40.
Scott: That'll be actually good $40.
Rym: That's more than twice what I spent on that computer.
Scott: It doesn't matter Computers broken.
Rym: so the motherboard my $40.
Scott: It would be working and it would have never had a problem.
Rym: So, uh, yeah now despite the fact that is really hot out all my windows are open to dissipate the smell of burning.
Rym: well
Scott: also Because the windows might as well be open if the air conditioner is off and we turn the air conditioner off when we do the Show because it makes a lot of noise and I sit right in front of it And that means doing GeekNights in the summer.
Rym: It's hella hot hella hot It's not usually the room is like 70 when we start doing the show and it only gets up to about 76 by the time We're done.
Scott: I know I'm pretty high.
Scott: I got this laptop on my lap and such.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: You know why you're hot cuz the air conditioning is not on Yeah, and I'm sitting in this squishy chair and yeah Yeah.
Scott: But so I think in the summer the shows are gonna go Faster.
Scott: just out of I want to go into my air-conditioned room.
Rym: Well after the burning smell is gone from the room I'm definitely going to re-equip the air conditioning.
Scott: good idea.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So what do you got in the news?
Scott: This isn't so much a news because uh, there were some tech news is but I didn't really care.
Scott: Is this?
Scott: I don't know if this isn't even tech at all, but I don't know.
Scott: I liked it Basically that some guy started a blog called unexpected truths.
Scott: It was he put up one article in April and one in June and this is his second article the one from June 16th and it got dug.
Scott: so I noticed it and It's not correct.
Scott: Basically this base like I can just argue against it with one point and defeat it but it is partially correct.
Scott: Basically, this guy makes an argument and he says that if you have a really hard standardized test right like stupidly hard Then it's actually less meaningful.
Scott: and this is his logic right.
Scott: his logic is this let's say I'm Scott and I know One thing about I don't know.
Scott: pick a topic.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: think about I don't know living podcasting Aerospace engineering, right?
Rym: Let's go with quantum physics.
Scott: All right quant.
Scott: I know one thing about quantum physics, right.
Scott: then you bring in another guy who's a quantum physicist and he knows I don't know five times as much as I do about quantum physics, but what happens when you multiply by zero?
Scott: Yeah, okay Anyway, all right enough snipping.
Scott: Yes, so then you give us a test right and the test has you know 100 questions, right?
Scott: Let's say I know enough to get 10 questions, right and he knows enough to get 50 questions, right?
Scott: Since it's so hard that 50 of the questions are just so hard that we can't neither of us know them then basically half the test is guessing.
Scott: so a harder test like that where the knowledgeable person is Equally difficult has to guess also makes it better for me as the dumber person and that the ideal test Would be one where if you were knowledgeable you could get them All right, and if you weren't knowledgeable you would get them all wrong.
Rym: Well, you see it depends because that really seems to rely on the fact that it's a limited number of multiple choice question.
Scott: Yes, he does say this only counts in a multiple choice test where you only count the correct answers.
Rym: Yeah, and also a lot of tests mitigate that by.
Rym: you can choose not to answer a question But if you do choose to answer it you lose points if you get it wrong.
Scott: Yeah That's the SAT used to work out of.
Scott: it still works that I don't know the SAT works anymore.
Rym: I never even took it.
Scott: Yes, but the basically the argument I mean this does sort of make sense though I mean, it's not a hundred percent correct because I could just say um, you can't really quantify human knowledge in that way.
Scott: I mean obviously sure the quantum physicist doesn't know them all but he can make educated guesses on a lot of them and eliminate Multiple choices on.
Scott: you know many of them which I could not do and therefore his odds of getting a better score better than mine.
Rym: It's such plus I can relate when I was in high school in 10th grade when I took out AP biology.
Rym: It was a class of like 11 people.
Rym: It was this little seminar class.
Rym: We're basically free to do whatever we wanted and the tests were Incredibly difficult.
Rym: the tests were designed for someone who already had a degree in biology or saw, you know The relevant field.
Rym: so we're talking about genetics.
Rym: then it was that super hard about genetics and the class average was always around 30%.
Rym: yep, and all it really did was force everyone to like you really had to strive for a lot more than you actually needed to Because by the end of the class we were averaging around 50%.
Rym: So when we went to take the actual AP test We were so used to these basically hammer-you-in-the-face questions that we all got fives on the test like that.
Rym: Ah But then again, that means that doesn't mean that the tests we took in the class were really a useful measure of intelligence because it was generally a useful measure of Intelligent guessing like Scott was saying.
Scott: Yes, but regardless they While his Argument is not 100% correct.
Scott: I do think that you know incredibly Stupidly difficult tests are sort of not good at measuring intelligence.
Rym: Anyway, at least to a point Yeah, but I would make the opposite argument that you don't want to test especially if you're trying to differentiate between people of varying skill That has too low of a cap because then you can't differentiate between people who are very intelligent.
Scott: That's why what I would do if I was making a test two rounds, no, no, oh two rounds is okay.
Scott: I would make the first question right the easiest possible question, right?
Scott: And I would make the last question the hardest possible question And that way you would basically everyone would start failing at a certain point along the way and maybe I would shut randomize them You know instead of doing them in order.
Scott: but basically when I did the grading I could Shuffle them and look at them from easy to hard and then just look at your score is like a line with maybe some holes In it.
Scott: if you messed up on a few problems and then you could really see okay, that guy's a friggin genius.
Scott: He got all the ones near the end.
Scott: Okay That guy only made it a third of the way through instead of having this test where half the questions are Impossible and basic, you know like that where it's pretty useless.
Rym: Well, actually another example just from my high school in AP physics.
Rym: The way he did it was there'd always be ten questions on a test But you had a very short amount of time to actually do the test and you weren't expected to complete them all.
Rym: they were Multiple choice.
Rym: each one was a very complex, you know physics problem Yeah, and there were ten and you could choose which ones to just do whichever ones you can.
Rym: that way he made that so difficult and not enough time.
Rym: to where the loadout of the scores.
Rym: the way the scores were disseminated at the end very much reflected how Proficient everyone was in the class.
Rym: It was a very good measure.
Rym: I think yeah, like I was so at one time I got six right and I was like crazy.
Rym: There's this one kid who got eight once like four years before we got there.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Oh Yeah, I just thought it was pretty interesting and this does look like a blog to me.
Scott: That's pretty much trying to become popular and I don't know.
Scott: he wrote two things.
Rym: I didn't read the first thing he wrote but maybe he is taking these strategy that I used to take posting on slashdot.
Scott: Maybe it's just a blogspot blog from some guy.
Scott: So whatever a link to it.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: See, you know lately I found that whenever a blog talks about something like that or whenever they bring up a topic or a question I never bother reading the blog because I see the question on dig if it was an interesting question And I just read the dig comments and I probably get more out of it.
Scott: See actually that would.
Scott: that would have bitten me in this case because on dig the headline was the fallacy of hard tests And I thought it was gonna be about how the tests aren't really
Rym: hard,
Scott: you know Like oh everyone says this is so hard to test but it's not and you can actually just pass the tests and blood or bullshit.
Scott: And then I read it and that's not what it was about.
Rym: Nah So a while ago we talked about a judge who didn't really know what a website was.
Scott: Oh The lady in Connecticut.
Rym: Alright, so arguments aside from that.
Rym: No, no, no, not that.
Scott: Oh the other one the Irish English one.
Rym: Well, this is the other other one.
Rym: okay, so I'm just gonna read the slash dot bit here because I think it says it all in an impressive example of the gap of understanding between legal officials and technology.
Rym: US magistrate some woman found that a computer servers RAM or Random access memory if you will if I may is a tangible document that can be stored and must be turned over in a lawsuit.
Scott: Now there he can have it now.
Rym: think about this for a minute.
Scott: This judge is basically saying that you have to turn over the contents of your RAM Because there's evidence contents of the RAM or the actual RAM because it is possible to copy the data that is presently in the RAM To like a CD or something or DVD.
Rym: That is equally useless because the the data in the RAM is transient and I highly doubt that the court Proceeding is taking place at a time where whatever data they wanted is still in RAM.
Scott: I know that but it is possible to Take a snapshot of the current data in RAM if that is useful plus while I didn't.
Scott: for example you could but potentially set up a computer or with a service that logs to a space in RAM and Maybe it doesn't log that much.
Scott: or maybe you have so much RAM that you can hold on to those logs and thus a snapshot Of that RAM would be something you might want to put in Possible.
Rym: I couldn't read the article because it was slash dotted and I didn't want to really search for it.
Rym: All right, but it seems that the judge really doesn't understand and think so I think that's obvious that they can get the data that they want from the RAM.
Rym: They're mad because torrents by according to them doesn't keep records.
Rym: So I guess the judge must have found out about RAM and said well Wouldn't the data be in there because it has to be in there at some point not understanding that it's not there anymore.
Scott: Well, all I can say is where the hell were the expert witnesses, you know, I wonder that more and more every day.
Scott: Maybe there aren't any expert witnesses.
Rym: Well when it comes to computers Because I ran into the situation today there aren't.
Scott: I would love the job of expert witness flying around the country going to courts getting Asked today at work.
Rym: It's not that I realize this is a problem.
Rym: It's more that I ran into this problem again.
Rym: But it seems like almost every IT problem in the corporate world comes down to a very simple problem.
Rym: You have a customer and you have the technologists.
Rym: the customer wants X, but they don't know about technology But they want some sort of technology to do their job.
Rym: the technologists know how to make technology But they don't know anything about the customer or the customers job.
Rym: So the customer says say I want to be able to print these documents and the tech guy says fine And he gives them a printer but it might not be the mark kind of printer.
Rym: The tech guy will often solve the wrong problem because the customer doesn't understand the technology enough to know what to ask for and there don't seem to be any people out there or at least very few of them who are capable of Talking to the customer talking to the technologist figuring out what needs to be done and writing it down.
Scott: Well, you see that's actually they taught us in school to do that.
Rym: Oh They taught us to.
Scott: the problem is not that we're incapable of doing that like if I go To someone's business and I take a look at it for a little while maybe hang out for an hour.
Scott: So see how they are their business process.
Scott: I know figure out what they need.
Scott: I'm not I understand business enough.
Scott: The problem is is that in the actual business world while we were taught to do that in school No one else does know how to do it.
Scott: people just don't do it.
Scott: They think you go and a customer just comes up and says something and it's like wait I want to talk to you about this and figure out what you need.
Scott: Just give me something.
Scott: this I'm like, no You're not gonna be happy.
Scott: All right, I'll give it to you.
Scott: But if you complain you got you can't say anything you promised me right now on paper.
Rym: Maybe that's cuz the kind of companies you work for but it's the opposite with me In the like IBM and these other companies where you know There's a customer and they want something big from the company or they want some big technology thing And they need something to do their job and they know what they want But the technology is just aren't willing to listen or figure out what they need.
Scott: I think those technologists I think that's a problem that people have realized and The older technologists who have gone to school or much older than we are in their 30s and 40s didn't learn this.
Scott: Yeah and then they began teaching it once they realized it was a problem because I'm basically the now because The older people are still the old way.
Scott: There's we're not doing it even though we know how.
Rym: yeah because I'm now I'm basically the fireman.
Rym: I go around the company putting out the fires when they start and the fires are always always always Customer got what they didn't want because no one bothered to listen to them.
Rym: But when it comes to these I mean, I mean there are.
Scott: there are many cases I will not deny you tech people out there of incredibly stupid customers Can't deal with.
Rym: however, the easy answer is what you want is not feasible and all and of course the tech guy is never stupid.
Rym: But I think the best answer to this sort of thing is to take the RAM chips and bring them into court and hand them To the judge.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I also think that is the best way to do it.
Scott: now.
Rym: It does remind me back when Scott and I were younger and more full of vim and vigor.
Rym: We were trying to figure out how we could Like how we could mess with computer forensics people and we realized that if you wanted to commit some sort of piracy Internet crime.
Rym: Oh, this is a great plan the best way to go about it, and I'm really surprised No one has done this yet, or if they have it hasn't been publicized.
Rym: So we're basically gonna tell you all and I'm not saying you should do this.
Scott: In fact, I'm going to say on the record This is one of those things where it's okay to put bomb instructions on the internet But it's not okay to might make bombs or blow them up.
Scott: Yes This is what we're about to tell you.
Rym: we're trusting you guys because I?
Scott: well I think the main reason is no Seriously go and actually do this because then we will get insane publicity when the news finds out.
Scott: they learned how to do it From some podcast.
Rym: Yeah, but yet don't actually do it.
Rym: So I can't get sued exactly.
Rym: You see how that works.
Rym: Yes, but all that aside we realized that if you wanted to give data to people or put data out there of any kind that is illicit or Insightful or in any way would want to be stopped by the man or your government or whoever.
Rym: This is probably a great idea for dissidents in China.
Rym: Yep, what you do is you take laptops particularly you got to buy second-hand laptops with cash But that's not hard to do with wireless cards cheap-ass ones.
Rym: now You get a big old battery and stick it to the thing.
Scott: or if you can or you find somewhere where there's an outlet in Public like if you open up the bottom of a street lamp, there's usually an outlet in there Yep, or you can wire in and get power if you're smart.
Rym: It's not that hard to do Yep.
Rym: So what you do is you take this little laptop with its wireless card and no hard drive no hard drive No fingerprints, obviously all that stuff.
Rym: You took the serial numbers off.
Rym: Not that that matters Yep, so you run whatever.
Rym: you make sure it's within sight of an access point.
Rym: So it'll get on the internet.
Rym: somehow you make a live CD.
Rym: Yeah, a live CD that contains an operating system designed solely to do whatever it is you want to do.
Rym: Maybe you take a not big CD.
Scott: you put an Apache on it, whatever But you don't let it actually you don't set it to automatically do whatever it's gonna do on boot because then by Examining the CD they can figure you out.
Rym: Now what you do is you boot this CD yep, and the CD now loads what it's doing into RAM.
Scott: then you perform the critical steps via the keyboard and All everything is in the RAM.
Scott: you close the lid and as soon as you close the lid You have it rigged in such a way that opening the lid or turning it off or rebooting it or opening The CD drive will just turn the computer off and furthermore you remove the CD.
Rym: Just in case though if you wanted to do it optimally the CD is just a straight-up Live CD with nothing on it because you guys say you did everything with a flash drive and then you take the flash drive away.
Scott: So basically everything that's illicit that's going on is in the RAM of that computer and no one can figure out where the computer came from or who's doing it or anything.
Scott: and the most they can do is just Pick up the computer.
Scott: and as soon as they pick up the computer and if they try to do any sort of research on it Whatsoever forensics, they're not gonna find shit now.
Rym: even better a lot of pcs.
Rym: It's pretty trivial to set up a PC that if it's jostled it'll turn off or do something.
Rym: Yep That's one step further.
Scott: The thing is if it's a laptop like sitting on the street outside of a like Cafe using the free wireless then it's probably gonna.
Scott: well no cuz you jostled on its own.
Rym: Yeah, but someone's gonna steal it anyway, yeah But in that case that's for like the quick spy handoff where you leave the laptop there Like you're sitting at the Starbucks.
Rym: make sure you're wearing a hat.
Rym: No one can see your face on the cameras to leave it there.
Rym: Someone walks by gets the data wirelessly while he's walking.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: See the problem with this plan, right?
Scott: There's only one problem with it.
Scott: And that is that it's very uneconomical to get all these laptops.
Rym: Well, there is another way but the the way.
Scott: that's why everyone does things via Windows.
Scott: zombies, right?
Scott: But the zombies have to start somewhere and starting them from one of these anonymous laptops is a great way to go Especially if it started with a cron job that takes place like three weeks after you left the thing there.
Scott: Well, then you have to bet that it's gonna sit there for three weeks.
Scott: Yeah, it's a. hide it pretty well now if you're gonna has to have a three week battery.
Rym: Yeah now if you wanted to host a whole bunch of data or something big You rent an apartment with cash in a shady part of town and you get internet stolen from your neighbor Which is not that hard to do usually.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And then you just have a server and you have the server rigged up the same way.
Rym: live CD Maybe a gigantic amount of RAM to hold the data.
Rym: They should need that much because I can't imagine how much data it would be.
Rym: you can get a lot of RAM and you rigged The house up.
Rym: So if any entrance to the house is open, it cuts the power to the computer.
Scott: Nice.
Rym: Yeah Yeah Imagine the forensics guy trying to explain that to the judge.
Rym: There was nothing in the computer.
Rym: your honor What do you mean?
Rym: we see clearly that it was serving the battle plans to the Death Star?
Scott: Yeah But there was nothing in it.
Scott: What do you mean?
Rym: Nothing?
Rym: Nothing.
Rym: many both inside trying to get that Things of the day again, I'll be real brief.
Rym: I don't have a lot to say about this other than that.
Rym: I think it's really neat now.
Rym: Sculpture is one thing.
Rym: you make a sculpture to look like something.
Rym: Maybe it's some abstract thing.
Rym: Maybe it's a big naked guy.
Scott: I was gonna do that.
Rym: You were gonna do that joke.
Rym: Well, I guess I already did it.
Rym: It's done.
Rym: It's taken naked.
Rym: Greek guy is already out there in the open.
Rym: There's nothing you can do about him.
Rym: All right, all right, but and that's well and good.
Rym: But what if instead of the sculpture being the art the shadow the sculpture cast worthy art now?
Rym: You might say Rym.
Rym: That's so like Avant-garde nouveau whatever term crap modern garbage art.
Rym: That's not anything interesting.
Rym: Now what if you made Something a physical object that didn't in and of itself look like anything?
Rym: In fact, it looks like a pile of trash.
Rym: but if you shine a light on it in a certain way the shadow it casts is Nothing like the object and in fact is a work of art.
Scott: That's pretty cool.
Rym: That's pretty cool.
Rym: That's what this is.
Rym: That's all I have to say about that.
Scott: All right, my thing of the day is a Simple astronomy picture.
Scott: Well, actually it is a conglomeration of many astronomy pictures.
Scott: You see you look up at the Sun, right?
Scott: And you know that if it's noon The Sun is directly overhead and you have no shadow.
Scott: and if it's early in the day The Sun is in the east.
Scott: it was later in the day.
Scott: The Sun is in the West.
Scott: You know that in the summer the Sun takes longer to go across because the earth tilts and in the winter It takes less time to go across.
Scott: and all that business, right?
Scott: well, what if you had a camera pointed at the sky and the camera didn't move?
Scott: and Like every day you had the camera take a picture of the sky at say 10
Scott: a.m.?
Scott: Just pick a time, right?
Scott: You can see all the different places in the sky where the Sun will be at 10 a.m Every day around the year and it sort of makes this like eight like this figure eight or like the infinity.
Scott: It's kind of angular, you know.
Scott: and like one day the Sun will be really low at 10 a.m.
Scott: and then the other end of the year the Sun will be Really high at 10 a.m.
Scott: And the shape that it creates in the sky is called the Analemma and here is a picture of the Analemma and They list the dates when the pictures are taken and everything and it's pretty cool and you learn something new.
Rym: So it's been long enough and it's finally up.
Rym: So I guess it's time to talk a little about my new computer.
Scott: Oh, it's a cop-out episode.
Rym: I think yeah a little bit.
Rym: We actually put it in the schedule a while ago and we ended up you put it in the schedule.
Rym: Yeah, well you agreed to it.
Scott: I just I didn't agree outright.
Scott: I just did not object.
Rym: Well, the main reason we put it in originally was all right.
Rym: I got a new computer.
Rym: we should talk about new hardware or whatever and You might notice that it's been quite some time since I got that new computer and we're doing this episode.
Rym: The computer is just now working as it should be.
Scott: Alright, well, let's talk about what parts you got for that computer.
Rym: Alright, well, of course the only relevant parts.
Rym: well, I got a core to duo e 6600 which I still believe is the absolute perfect price point in terms of diminishing returns.
Rym: dollar per unit.
Scott: performance Yes If you have a lot of money like a pile of money Go out and get the faster one because this is not the fastest one available.
Scott: if you can afford it There's better ones, but if you're gonna save money, but you still need if you're gonna just save money You don't care about performance that much.
Scott: you can get like the core non two duos and like the core one duos and for real.
Scott: But if you are looking to get performance and the money saving at the same time, this is still the best spot.
Scott: I still I can't believe I turn my back on AMD.
Rym: AMD has been with me for a long time and I never thought that Intel would have a better chip or a cheaper chip because Intel was always just so ludicrously expensive and not that much faster.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I wavered back and forth.
Scott: I mean originally I got Intel because AMD was nothing in those days.
Rym: Well, yeah back in like the k3 days.
Scott: Yeah, this is like before even the k2 days.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well the k6 like 1999 yeah, and then AMD just came out and really caught were faster and cheaper bitches and I was like, oh, yeah It wasn't just a little bit cheaper.
Rym: It was like $300 cheaper and twice as fast.
Scott: Yeah, and that was AMD for the win.
Scott: and then I was stuck with AMD cuz they maintain their cheapness and their competitiveness.
Scott: But then and Intel also sort of went down the tubes with their Pentium 4. it was not good.
Scott: But then luckily this one R&D team at Intel Basically bailed them out.
Scott: and the story is like some Israeli R&D team invented the core.
Scott: do the core Basically, and then they core solo the core duo, etc, etc.
Scott: And now AMD not keeping up they're trying to do their 64-bit thing.
Scott: But that's not working out so well because the 64-bit OS is they're not so hot.
Rym: Yeah I mean god, I tried to use Ubuntu.
Rym: Well, I'll get to that.
Rym: That's a whole other adventure gonna get to that We'll get to that.
Scott: All right, but there's one constant even though Intel and AMD may change Nvidia is always the wind.
Rym: Yep, but luckily I mean the thing that really pushed it over.
Rym: because Literally the day before I bought my computer on Newegg.
Rym: There was a gigantic sale on AMD processors.
Rym: They were so cheap.
Rym: ah and I still just couldn't rationalize it because the core 2 seems like it has so much future potential.
Rym: and If it comes to it in the future I actually looked and I could overclock this thing like four years from now to keep this computer going a while.
Scott: I don't think that's going to be necessary, but it is that much better.
Rym: Yes, because and it uses practically no power compared to the AMD.
Scott: I think that's another major factor is that AMD sort of just kept increasing the horsepower Over time and didn't increase the price very much and that helped out in those days.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And also I really got to say Installing the Intel chip the core 2 duo compared to other CPUs I've installed was a dream.
Rym: It just went in so wonderfully.
Scott: Yeah, and there's a new mechanism that's sort of complicated and foreign.
Scott: Yeah, it works.
Rym: No, the pins don't go in holes anymore.
Rym: The pin just go up against these pads and it's really nice.
Rym: There's no longer is the fear of fucking up my motherboard or fucking up my processor.
Scott: Yeah, well, I mean it is sort of strange.
Scott: if you've done a lot of you know, old-school socket CPU So much better, but it does work.
Scott: It's not some BS.
Rym: I mean, it's not as easy as a slot but the slot had too many drawbacks.
Scott: So slot is no good.
Rym: Yeah, and also I got to say the stock default heatsink cooling mechanism that comes with the core 2 is Absolutely silent.
Rym: It does not make noise as far as I can tell.
Scott: that's good.
Rym: It's beautiful.
Rym: It goes on like that.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it's so easy.
Rym: It comes with the thermal paste on it.
Rym: There's no reason to replace it.
Rym: I can't praise Intel highly enough for the core 2 duo.
Rym: I'm so incredibly happy with it.
Rym: anyway, yeah and motherboard wise I actually had a lot of consternation because it seems like This generation of motherboards had a lot of trouble with Linux back in a lot of trouble regardless of Linux.
Rym: Well, yeah, but Linux in particular.
Scott: Yes, also Linux.
Rym: I ended up going with the a bit a b9 Pro partly because one it has ten serial ATAs Which is more than you're gonna use but two.
Rym: it had three different serial ATA controllers And I figured that no matter what problems there are with Linux at least one of those bad basses is gonna work.
Rym: I don't know why I said bad basses.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know how it's gonna make a noise of a fish But I really didn't.
Rym: I wasn't gonna say badasses.
Rym: I don't know what I was gonna say.
Rym: I don't know where basses came from.
Rym: bad boys the bad boys badasses.
Rym: I guess they got merged together.
Rym: I guess the bad basses of computer science.
Rym: bad boys asses bad, but asses.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, and Yeah, it turned out that there were quite a few problems with the a bit a b9 Pro the least of which was that my computer didn't boot when I first got it at all and I couldn't believe that the awesome and tech power supply I had bought that had way more power than I need for this motherboard and all my components Wasn't a problem.
Rym: there's no way.
Scott: it wasn't actually the problem what it was.
Scott: Well, it was a nation problem.
Scott: Yes, it affect because the whether you know it or not pretty much any power supply you buy these days, right?
Scott: And it's been true for many years like since the year 2001 2000. even right is that?
Scott: computer power supplies are very smart.
Scott: if you try to get a computer power supply to give you more electricity that it is capable of Giving you it will say no and turn off that way.
Scott: It doesn't explode or anything.
Scott: That is good.
Scott: It's a smart power supply Newer even like super new power supplies.
Scott: ones that you get say today what they do.
Scott: They have a newer feature if you don't ask for enough power They will turn off.
Scott: because if you're not asking for enough power Then something might be wrong because the computer asks for a whole bunch of power when you turn it on.
Rym: Yep, now it appears.
Rym: from what I've read and researched though I haven't verified this experimentally because I'm not the type to sit there with a voltimeter and mess with it.
Scott: Yeah, but it from what I've seen and all the evidence.
Scott: I think this is 90% the case.
Rym: Yes, though There is another issue that will also get to.
Rym: yeah But it seems like the a b9 and a lot of other modern motherboards Staged the activation of components in such a way as to not suddenly overburden the power supply.
Scott: So instead of turning on everything in your computer at once it turns on one bit over here then a bit over there then a bit Turns in the CPU then the memory then this and that and the result of that is you don't ask the power supply for enough Power.
Scott: so the power supply starts turning on your computer and then it turns off.
Rym: Yep No, I mean that's the guess I've seen.
Rym: I can't again.
Rym: I can't prove it.
Rym: that just and the reason I say that is the one a lot of other people have said that on the Internet and - I could get the power supply to power up longer and better and work a little bit more But still not actually work.
Scott: if I loaded it down with more stuff Yeah The more stuff we plugged into the power supply it would spin the fan for like a second longer and then the computer would turn On.
Rym: it was kind of weird.
Scott: He would have plugged in enough things He would have turned on all the way but that wouldn't have been worth.
Scott: it would have been worth.
Rym: So basically I ended up buying this like the crappiest power supply you can imagine Because it was the only power supply they had really at Best Buy.
Scott: Yeah, and he had to run to the Best Buy instead of waiting to buy a nice one on Newegg.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I. well I couldn't wait any longer and This crap power supply works perfectly.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Now the other issue is that the antac is all fancy.
Rym: It has three rails of 12-volt and each.
Scott: well I'm not gonna talk about the rails suffice to say in.
Rym: it does look like while the antac power supplies are really nice They can't provide enough power over to any single 12-volt rail long enough to fully power up my system.
Scott: Yep, I'm not gonna get into the thing about the rails But I learned that I'll say expensive antac power supply wouldn't work.
Rym: much crappier off-brand Disgusting looking power supply in a shady box worked perfectly.
Rym: I'm still talking to antac support.
Rym: I kept the thing around but mainly because I really want antac to give me a better power supply to make up for this because the antac power supply is Much quieter and quieter.
Rym: It's silent.
Rym: The part my computer is utterly silent except for the power supply.
Scott: silent mostly thanks to its antac case.
Rym: Yes, but my case is really hot.
Rym: I love this case so much.
Rym: The only thing better was the same case where the are the panel sagging.
Rym: now the panels aren't sagging yet But according to the internet within a month or two the panels, you know The cold steel rolled panels are gonna start sagging.
Rym: roll, I guess.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I said cold steel rolled.
Rym: I said the right words in the wrong order.
Rym: Yep But yeah, I worked all that out.
Rym: computer wouldn't brood a little bit.
Rym: I had to fiddle with the RAM timings to get it to go.
Rym: That's just because.
Rym: Get this it seems like all the nice motherboards can't handle that fancy gamer.
Rym: Super fast low cast latency RAM.
Rym: I also learned that based on the benchmarks that super low latency Twice as much money.
Rym: low voltage RAM Isn't faster at all.
Rym: No benchmark demonstrated any performance benefit whatsoever to using that so-called better RAM.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of a lot of stuff in computers especially, you know the overclocking gamer computer market is a lot like the audiophile market where they charge you a whole bunch of extra Money for you know something that may not actually benefit you or doesn't actually cost them extra money to make.
Scott: Yeah Monster tables.
Rym: back in the day I actually did a lot of research and looked at benchmarks and spent the extra money to buy lower cast latency RAM because the performance Benchmarks did show a not well not dramatic definitely measurable performance difference.
Rym: And also the price difference wasn't that great.
Rym: Nowadays, the price difference is ludicrous and there's no performance benefit at all Huh?
Rym: Yeah, fine.
Scott: Also, whatever Rams gonna work the best and get as much of it as you can.
Scott: now It does matter like if your computer can handle DDR 800.
Scott: Oh, yeah You don't want to get DDR six.
Rym: the RAM speed matters crazily.
Rym: the cast latency and the strobe latency don't matter at all.
Scott: So make sure you get the right speed.
Scott: So if your computer gets DDR 800 get DDR 800 but just get as much as you can and don't worry about anything else except the speed and type of the RAM and The amount of it in the price.
Rym: what took me off guard was the fact that I used to always buy RAM from a few Very very specific manufacturers.
Rym: I pretty much bought Corsair or Crucial.
Rym: I used to buy Viking way back in the day.
Scott: Yeah, Corsair makes pretty cool RAM plus pirates.
Rym: Yeah the thing is those Rams were very expensive compared to the RAM ended up buying and The RAM ended buying was like OCZ whatever.
Rym: Yeah, and it looks all ricey and it's got this red heat spreaders on.
Rym: It's all fancy, but it was also really cheap and you know what it works perfectly.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, it's either gonna work or it's not gonna and pretty much the only qualms I have about buying like off-brand stuff from Newegg Is that I know that probably the vast majority of that off-brand stuff works but I am taking a risk that it won't work and thus taking a risk of suffering a pain in the ass.
Scott: and I know That while there might be like a 90% chance of that off-brand stuff working There's a 99% chance of the brand name stuff working and sometimes I am willing to pay that more money just for that Peace-of-mind and that this is gonna work.
Rym: Yep, and I know it's not gonna be the problem But I ended up spending a hundred bucks to get two gigabytes of DDR 800.
Rym: It was G skill not OCZ.
Rym: Okay, whatever Yeah, it doesn't matter.
Rym: I'd never heard of them before.
Rym: They're somewhat new.
Rym: They definitely cater to.
Scott: they're not that off-brand There's just like.
Rym: no they just cater to a demographic.
Rym: That is not me.
Rym: Yep Yeah, but the hardware aside I got it all together and Installed windows.
Rym: Oh, yeah at the video card That's probably important because that was the that was the component that I spent the most time thinking about.
Rym: Yeah, because basically I want a game But I'm not willing to spend the four hundred dollars on a video card that I spent back in the day on the video card I was using up until now.
Scott: usually buy a $300 video.
Rym: Okay Well The other thing is I realized that not many games have come out since half-life 2 that I really need to play other than possibly supreme commander and I Wasn't willing to spend the money to get a computer that would play that well.
Scott: yet Yep And the games that you do want to play in the future like Team Fortress 2 are basically half-life 2. so Hey, you just need to play half-life 2. and you know what my computer with a GeForce FX 5900 5900 place half-life 2.
Rym: well enough what I ended up going with was the pretty much one not the topest of the line But near the top of the pack of the 7000 series.
Rym: I got a 7900 GS Yep, with 256 megabytes of RAM.
Scott: Well, the reason I think the logic was you don't want to buy ATI.
Scott: Oh first, let me say something.
Scott: people don't seem to realize this.
Rym: don't buy ATI.
Scott: Not only that, but I want it.
Scott: people still don't understand.
Scott: ATI makes chips to go on video cards, right?
Scott: They also make the video cards.
Scott: You cannot get as far as I know an ATI chip that is not on an ATI video card.
Rym: I don't actually know because I've never that's the way it was.
Scott: I'm not sure if it's still that way, but I'm pretty sure it is still that way.
Rym: I've never given ATI my business and every time I've had to use an ATI card has ended in misery.
Scott: I'm pretty sure.
Scott: the only way to get ATI chips is with eight video cards manufactured by ATI.
Rym: It's not that way with Nvidia.
Rym: In fact, you can't just buy an Nvidia video card.
Scott: no Nvidia only makes chips and they sell those chips to people who then make video cards with those chips on them.
Rym: and And Well, it used to matter back in the day because there were some people who made they took those chips and they made more solid More reliable video cards, but nowadays ignore the manufacturer of your video card.
Rym: Just look at what Nvidia chip it is how much RAM it has and all that business.
Scott: Oh, it does appear that that situation with ATI has changed slightly.
Scott: There are some other brands of video card manufacturer that make video cards with ATI chips on them But they all appear to be far inferior to the ATI product.
Rym: but I just bought some brand of video card.
Rym: it didn't matter because it was a g4 7900 GS and It's stupidly fast for all the games.
Rym: I'm going to play and I think my plan is I got a high-end DirectX 9 card because no games need DirectX 10 yet and I don't have Vista or anything and you're mostly gonna be using Linux.
Scott: So, what do you care?
Rym: So I'm pretty much gonna wait until there is a game that uses DirectX 10 that I need to be able to play well
Scott: and And that
Rym: will not play well enough on my current video card
Scott: and that you're willing to pay for that and a copy of Vista In order to play.
Rym: yeah, however at that time.
Rym: I probably will be willing to pay.
Scott: maybe maybe it depends.
Scott: It's got to be a damn good pretty much.
Rym: I'm holding out on DirectX 10 for a while.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there are.
Scott: I think there's a new line of g-forces That's out very very recently like days ago or maybe possibly a few days in the future maybe even today or tomorrow.
Scott: That is like the bargain end of the DirectX 10 cards.
Scott: They're like $100 or so.
Scott: So those might be worth looking into but I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, and video works.
Scott: ATI doesn't.
Scott: here's an example of a and video working at ATI not working for anyone out there.
Scott: No OS on a computer no operating system whatsoever, right?
Scott: We have an ATI video card.
Scott: It has an S video out hole.
Scott: we connect that as video out with an S video cable to our television and we turn the computer On.
Scott: we don't see anything on the screen at all.
Scott: There's no operating system.
Scott: It has nothing to do with Linux or Windows or anything, but nothing shows up on the screen.
Scott: We can't get the video output to work in Linux either.
Scott: Okay, so we replace it with an in video card All right, which we connect the S video out to the television Without Even before the operating system has a chance to go.
Scott: the display is already on the television working properly.
Scott: Nvidia's good ATI is not.
Scott: I don't care if the ATI card at the present time happens to be a little faster For a little less money.
Scott: It sucks.
Scott: It's just not worth that slight Performance increase in your Windows games to suffer the hassle of everything else.
Scott: ATI sucks at All right, so now Rym had all the parts for his computer, yep, and he had everything together Yep, and I installed Windows and I immediately installed steam after getting all my windows updates and it worked just fine.
Rym: And then I played Counter-Strike for like three hours.
Scott: Haven't played Counter-Strike in years.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: I'm not as good as I used to be but I Put in some noobs and I'm getting it back and after about an hour of icy world I got my headshot AK skills back.
Rym: Oh, no s or my death from above Mac 10 attack Which I did like four times to the same guy earlier today.
Scott: Someone set up us the bar.
Rym: so then I go to install Ubuntu and install all these other OS's to play with them and I'm not gonna go into the details.
Rym: We had a few problems with the audio getting everything set up and we resolved all that.
Rym: It turned out that my computer would crash and well not really crash, but it would freeze Hard permanently with nothing in any of the system logs.
Rym: No way to solve it sort of cutting the power and it would do this whenever I opened Firefox or Audacity.
Scott: Yeah, it happened pretty much all the time sort of randomly.
Scott: I mean you could sometimes link it to times when you were doing things with high.
Rym: I could I could.
Rym: well the thing is I could very specifically recreate the freeze whenever I wanted.
Rym: All I had to do is open Audacity have more than three tracks and try to play any selection from them.
Rym: Try to export away from Audacity.
Rym: try to import more than like seven tracks.
Rym: Like it would always freeze.
Rym: But this wasn't an Audacity problem.
Scott: No, no, because probably made the problem happen with a bunch of programs you never use.
Rym: Well, I tried and I couldn't with any.
Rym: I open office couldn't do it.
Rym: I opened a bunch of different things.
Rym: The only other thing that could do it is if I opened a bunch of tabs with flash in Firefox.
Rym: Uh-huh, and those are the only two things but nothing else would do it.
Rym: All right, uh, I tried a bunch of different OS's.
Rym: I thought maybe I had some kernel support problems.
Rym: So I tried to get a newer Debian.
Rym: the stable Debian won't install.
Rym: Well, it has an old ass old kernel.
Rym: the testing Debian won't install because it has a bug that doesn't work with my hardware.
Rym: Well,
Scott: yes, basically the situation was is that the newest version of the Linux kernel probably would have worked great but it the only way to get that newer version of the kernel was to use Gentoo and some horribly pain because There aren't any Linux distributions that come with the very newest kernel.
Scott: so the only way to get it is to use a distribution like Gentoo which where you build everything from source and you would Get the newest kernel or to build the kernel by hand.
Scott: Basically, if you wanted that new kernel that made the computer work, right?
Scott: It would have been a pain in the ass.
Scott: Meanwhile all the Linux distributions out there that aren't a pain in the ass Didn't have the newest kernel and while some of them might have booted and been stable They didn't support all of the hardware in the fancy new computer.
Scott: So old kernel.
Rym: I basically tried all those flavors of Linux I'd never tried before.
Rym: I have a pile of installation and live CDs laying next to me.
Rym: I was fiddling left and right.
Rym: the crashes were happening in most of them.
Rym: I was breaking down and I was gonna just fucking install Gentoo.
Rym: as much as I hate Gentoo I use Gentoo for the longest time and while I respect it, it's not worth the problems that had causes.
Scott: Yep, I discovered in the meantime a new Linux distribution We have yet to try on this computer called Sabayon.
Scott: S-A-B-A-Y-O-N.
Rym: Well, we shouldn't really talk about it.
Rym: We'll do a show on it.
Scott: I just want to say that it's basically It's a live CD or a live DVD that you basically push a few buttons and it installs Gentoo without the hassle and once it's installed, it's basically Gentoo without the effort.
Scott: Of course You need the effort once it's installed that Gentoo requires but not the installation effort.
Scott: The problem with it that I found so far is that it installs so much Software and most of it you don't want.
Scott: and one of the beautiful things about Gentoo is that you only have to have the software You want and no other software.
Rym: but beside that I was running out of things to do and I decided that the last ditch is to Force myself to upgrade the BIOS because that might.
Rym: there might be a bug where Linux couldn't deal with it properly But Windows could because Windows is tolerant or whatever.
Rym: and if I update the BIOS everything will be fine.
Rym: And let me tell you Updating an a bit BIOS is not the pleasure It used to be because the utility that used to be on the a bit website that would let you just from Windows update your BIOS They stopped supporting and got rid of because they didn't trust it anymore or something.
Scott: I don't know what the hell the deal is back in the day when everyone had a floppy drive, right?
Scott: It was easy to update your BIOS because everyone had a floppy drive.
Scott: You just make a BIOS boot floppy you put it in you turn the computer on your BIOS is updated done.
Scott: Now people don't have floppy drives anymore and a bit saw this problem coming and they made a program that you run in Windows.
Scott: It's an exe program.
Scott: You would run it.
Scott: It would update your BIOS.
Scott: Then you'd restart your computer.
Scott: It worked on my computer that I have now.
Scott: I've used it many times.
Scott: There was wasn't a problem with it at least on my a bit and f7s on rims new computer.
Scott: We went to the a bit website looked up his motherboard.
Scott: The only way to update the BIOS on this new motherboard was with a floppy disk and we could tell that he didn't have the newest Version.
Rym: so we needed to update it and it was very difficult to do So yep And I still haven't done it yet due to the fact that I have three floppy drives sitting to the right of me.
Rym: Two of them function one of them does not.
Rym: independent of that it took a while to get my motherboard to Recognize a floppy and deal with it and then that's because you didn't choose the right BIOS options to turn.
Rym: No, because even when I did that then I plug the cable in upside down because floppies don't have the nice tab.
Scott: Your fault and not the fault of the computer not working with floppy drive.
Rym: Well, also there were three different areas.
Rym: I do enable all three to make the floppy drive work.
Scott: Well, you disabled them all.
Scott: they weren't enabled by default.
Scott: You just turn them off and then you had to turn them.
Rym: actually know some of they were disabled by default Because the floppy and the parallel ATA and all that stuff like the PCI are this legacy crap.
Rym: That's on the motherboard in case you need it.
Rym: They don't expect you to use it.
Rym: Yeah, but so I finally get that resolved.
Rym: that didn't take long It's just I had to plug it all in.
Rym: Uh We don't have a single functioning floppy disk.
Rym: None of them worked.
Scott: Well, I think I found one that might work.
Scott: Yeah, but I haven't tried a few and they didn't work.
Rym: Yeah One of them seemed like it was working.
Rym: then tried to boot it and it wouldn't work.
Rym: and I'm trying to figure out man Is the floppy still not working then?
Rym: I just discovered that it didn't actually write the data to the floppy.
Rym: It just said it did.
Rym: the floppy didn't even spin.
Rym: as far as I can.
Scott: Yeah, we've got a lot of floppy disks that we haven't used in years and I'm not sure how many of them are good.
Rym: The one floppy that was good because it happened to be laying out.
Rym: I rearranged all my games.
Rym: I have this nine of the installation for quest for glory for That disk worked fine, but there's no way in hell.
Rym: I was gonna use that disk.
Scott: Well, you could just copy the data off of it.
Rym: I didn't want to.
Rym: I don't want to risk that disk In any capacity.
Scott: don't risk that did.
Rym: don't risk that disk.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, you lost my stack of CD ours.
Rym: I don't know where that stack CD ours.
Scott: way I think I'm gonna go buy like a tiny package of floppy disks and some CD ours.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway I just want to point out that for some reason that there was no technical reason that we could not make a boot CD Rom and then do the BIOS from that.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I would had to make a custom CD run that had the bios on it.
Scott: Yes, it seems like they're like in Windows.
Scott: if you want to make a bootable DOS floppy disk There's just a button that does that in Windows Linux nothing.
Scott: there's no button that I can see to make a bootable DOS bootable DOS keep mind you not just bootable CD rock.
Rym: well there is but the thing is what I would have had to do is create such a thing on my computer.
Rym: There's various means to do it that are not trivial and while I could have done them It wasn't worth the effort as opposed to just
Scott: me to like install Nero and then do a bunch of crap and
Rym: or I could have like gotten free DOS put it on a CD and made it a bootable CD and put all the
Scott: Files on it, but that's not as trustworthy as using the windows.
Rym: However floppy in my last-ditch effort I tried doing the thing that as in the past almost always made a screwed up Linux machine where you couldn't get anything else Go and work.
Rym: I turned off a CPI and a pic and now my computer is working perfectly.
Scott: Yeah, I remember there are some problems in the past with a pic and instability in the kernel.
Scott: Yeah I'm getting the feeling now that if the problems are still existing or if they come back up from the dead.
Scott: Everytime new motherboards come out They should really just rewrite that whole module in the kernel.
Rym: It is definitely a problem with Linux because I want to do point out that Windows works like a champ.
Scott: Yep I think it's probably something that would work in 2621.
Scott: The problem is Ubuntu which is the only easy to use in good distribution for us is 2620. so we and it's very difficult for us to get the newer kernel.
Rym: You know, it's not that it's difficult It's that it's not worth the effort.
Rym: Yeah, that's basically what I'm saying Except I was more difficult or more.
Rym: I was willing to put far more effort into solving the solution by another means.
Scott: yes, and a CPI is the thing that Controls like when your computer goes to sleep and hibernates and and that's always been a problem in Linux.
Scott: Yeah, I mean Linux is doing a lot better job of that.
Scott: But it's basically that stuff is really undocumented and it's different with every single computer and no one follows the rules.
Scott: So, you know with some computers it just works perfectly and other computers.
Scott: It doesn't work at all.
Scott: So it depends, you know some people like on my laptop It kind of works but sometimes a little buggy, but it won't screw me, but I guess I'm rims Motherboard it just it's so incompatible that it crashes.
Rym: now What I did is I just disabled them all in one fell swoop and the computer works.
Rym: I might whenever I feel like it try using each one at a time to figure out if it's both of them or if it's just One of them.
Scott: seemed like a pig to me because that's very similar to the problem I had with my parents computer in the past and a pic.
Scott: basically there was this crazy problem right where if you had a Ubuntu I think the one before dapper or maybe dapper.
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: I think the one before dapper and you had an motherboard with an Nvidia integrated graphics processor an onboard Nvidia card that you were using and you had didn't have your RAM and dual in dual channel mode and You had the IO a pic on.
Rym: I remember when Scott described this to me.
Rym: Oh, I I couldn't.
Rym: I couldn't believe that he had the patience to solve it because I would have just said you know what?
Rym: It doesn't work and gone home because it.
Rym: why wouldn't I don't like trouble if you had all those things in combination?
Scott: Then the computer would sort of freeze randomly similar to the way it was freezing for Rym.
Scott: if you bought a new video card and use that instead of the integrated graphics processor problem went away.
Scott: if you got another stick of Ram and dual channel mode turn on problem went away.
Scott: if you turn the IO a pic off problem went away.
Scott: use a newer version Of Ubuntu problem went away.
Scott: So that shows you the see people are gonna use.
Scott: probably what we've said now to say Oh Linux blah and well yet kinda Linux blah.
Scott: new hardware.
Scott: the thing is.
Scott: Think about that problem.
Scott: that is such an obscure problem And it only happens on the newest of awesomest hardware.
Scott: unless your hardware is like the bleeding edge craziness Linux is gonna work.
Scott: fine is not a problem for you.
Rym: plus I do note that the problem is solved and I can use the computer now.
Rym: and the thing is I'm so fickle I Was ready to just dump two windows in a second.
Rym: I'd be like screw it.
Rym: I'll just use windows, but The only reason I didn't do that and I kept trying to make Linux work was that the one program that I really need Resound does not exist anywhere else, and I could have built it in Sigmund or done a VMware.
Rym: You know what.
Rym: I can't get it to build in Linux.
Scott: Yeah, I can but only unlike Gentoo's.
Rym: Yeah, only on Gentoo.
Rym: I'll try it on Ubuntu.
Scott: No no no that's something that people need to understand.
Scott: Is that if you want to build?
Scott: Like Linux software from source code like by hand it'll most of the time work on most distributions But only gen 2 and distributions like it seem to have the pure GCC.
Scott: that will.
Scott: all that will work 99% of the time.
Scott: like Ubuntu will only successfully build software like 90% of the time because it's not pure.
Rym: but I realize I don't want to talk about this very long, but Resound is Pretty much the perfect podcasting solution.
Scott: for as far as what choices are currently available?
Scott: Well, no, I mean you could make something more perfect.
Rym: Well.
Rym: Yes, you could but it doesn't presently exist.
Rym: I looked around and I tried a whole bunch of audio applications and on my windows I pirated a whole bunch of things just to try them all out.
Rym: Just to try them out.
Rym: I was actually willing to purchase them.
Rym: however I discovered that almost every audio program out there when it comes to single track wave editing now Multitrack those programs are all really nice, and they're a lot better than audacity.
Rym: I tell you what and But what they don't have is they lack certain critical Functionality that I really need to do GeekNights or to do the other things I do with audio And I wonder why they're not there.
Scott: It's like are we the only people in the entire world who use these functions?
Rym: that can't possibly be true and a lot of them Will have the functions, but not to the level of control that I want.
Rym: I mean I want to control the raw math of whatever I'm doing and while there are ways to do that with Nyquist things and Plugins it's already all there in Resound.
Rym: and also while the interface of Resound is really old-looking The way you interface with the audio is something that I haven't seen in any other program and maybe it's just that people don't have to edit the volume of audio this quickly like I do but I Haven't found anything better.
Rym: It's not a matter of oh, I'm not used to it.
Rym: It's a matter of it takes fewer clicks to do the things I need to do in Resound than in any other program.
Scott: Yeah, it's like other programs can do what we do.
Scott: however even if you're the Grandmaster It will take you like an hour more to do it with that other program simply by the sheer number of clicks and processing time.
Rym: Also, and here's the funny bit I'll end it on this because because Audacity crashed and now you know whatever Resound didn't crash.
Rym: it crashed on its own, but that's just because it's Resound and I we resolved that with Jack.
Rym: But I had Resound and that was the only program I could use to make the show.
Rym: So I had to make the whole show in a single track editor Which totally sucks.
Rym: as a result I had to get creative and I learned that I and I made it and I'm still tweaking it.
Rym: But I was able to make a script in Resound that will make Process and do the entire show from start to finish and create an mp3 when it's done.
Scott: Wow, so basically all you do is you edit out the coughs and the stuff I spend because you can't have a computer.
Scott: do that It computer in this.
Rym: as an AI I could but it would be very difficult and prone to error.
Scott: It would be much easier to just do it by hand every night.
Scott: Yeah, and you just do that and that takes how many minutes just to cut the things out?
Scott: You know click click push a button click.
Rym: it takes about one second for ten minutes of audio at this point to do that.
Scott: Yeah, and then you push a single button and the show is produced.
Scott: No other audio application is capable of this even the incredibly expensive $1,000 professional ones.
Scott: they can do it, but there's so much less efficient in the user interface.
Scott: Meanwhile this free open source one that's kind of got this junky interface That's ugly and blah.
Scott: it does it in one button.
Rym: part of the problem It's just that those expensive programs do what they do very well.
Scott: And if you were using them for the purposes for which they are intended like making music in a music studio Or you work in a radio studio, or there's a live concert And you they're great work in the sound.
Rym: when I took digital audio at RIT And we use Pro Tools Pro Tools was the motherfucking bomb when it came to do.
Rym: it was great.
Rym: I loved it.
Rym: We recorded everything multi-track in the studio, and I could just move stuff around.
Rym: it was great.
Rym: And while it was slow and somewhat inefficient to edit things compared to resound Well or even audacity in some cases I didn't need to do it quickly because you're not editing like but it but it but it but a bit.
Rym: when you're making music You're editing it slowly.
Rym: you're checking to make sure things work.
Rym: You're doing things very precisely And it's just none of those things are efficient for the fast and loose Edit an hour of audio and throw it up on the air ten minutes later thing that we do.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if we made a podcast once a week or once a month or less often than four days a week right then We could probably go out and get one of those digital mixers And it would record both of us on two separate tracks And we could edit ourselves individually and mix it together, and it would be this you know double awesome professional job.
Scott: But when you do it at four days a week You don't have time for that.
Scott: you need something more efficient, and I really think that if someone made an audio application that incorporated the powerful Multitrack features of say Pro Tools or audition with the single fat the single track post-production editing efficiency of resound that you could make Amazing audio and even less time that has ever been done before.
Rym: And on that note I think we're done because I smell tofu downstairs And I want to turn my AC back on now that my room doesn't smell like burning.
Scott: and also I'm one day I'm gonna make a podcasting application.
Scott: that is perfect.
Rym: basically We just need to take the interface and the power of resound and write a program that does that.
Scott: well.
Scott: basically I just replace I take the code of resound that does the audio part and replace the rest.
Rym: yeah pretty much.
Rym: Yeah, maybe we could add it all to that Joe kosher which has promise, but it's currently useless.
Scott: Yeah, you know open source.
Scott: That's what the point is.
Rym: yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.