Scott: It's Wednesday December 19th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: tonight We review Essex County volumes 1 & 2 by Jeff Lemire.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Oh Snap Rym has new glasses.
Rym: Okay, that's that's all I got.
Rym: that's what happened to me today.
Rym: I don't know what you did, but I got glasses.
Scott: I went to work.
Scott: I did work.
Scott: I came home.
Rym: see I can say one thing.
Rym: over the weekend I thought oh man.
Rym: I'm gonna go get glasses.
Rym: There's gonna be that blizzard.
Rym: I'll go to the mall even though it's near Christmas You know Xmas when generally my policy is to not go within 10 miles of a mall until like January 10th.
Rym: But there's a blizzard.
Rym: so I figure all right.
Rym: I'll go up the road There'll be no one at the mall, and I can get some glasses and go to the GameStop.
Rym: Maybe play some DDR and Sure enough.
Rym: I was the only human being in that mall who was not a worker.
Rym: yep And the doctors who were supposed to give the eye exams also didn't bother to show up Would you probably not if I was a doctor.
Rym: so there you go, so I went back home pretty much soundly defeated.
Rym: Then I learned something today.
Rym: I tried to go get glasses like a pearl vision or lens crafters the place I've gone my whole life, and it was kind of a pain.
Rym: You know I'll come back in an hour make an appointment.
Rym: It'll take forever blah blah blah Insurance.
Rym: So I just said screw it I just went to this place right next to my work in New York and like 42nd Street And I was like I need glasses, and I walked out an hour later with two pairs of brand new glasses.
Scott: Yep, that's the thing about New York.
Scott: You know back in the day They used to be customer service you'd go into a store and people would help you.
Scott: You know with whatever you needed they would talk to you, and they'd be like selling to you like salesmen.
Scott: You know attending to your needs, and you know you know fanning you with fern leaves Putting grapes in your mouth.
Scott: You know in order to get you to give them money.
Rym: Yeah, you know what.
Scott: now you only get that in the big cities in the in the fancy stores or the semi fancy store.
Rym: I had two salespeople standing there handing me.
Rym: They don't even let me look at the glasses.
Rym: They'd hand me one and that I'd put it on me and then they'd tell me how they thought it looked and then they'd show it to me and I'm dead at it at it done and They didn't even pull the.
Rym: the more expensive ones are clearly superior because they handed me this Armani thing.
Rym: It's like it was like a thousand dollars just for this frame And they put it on me, and I'm like I don't know cuz I don't know I don't know fashion so much.
Rym: I look at glasses, and I can't really tell if they look good or not on me, so I need to ask other people And they're like no those don't look good on you at all, and I didn't get the stupid crazy expensive Armani's.
Scott: yeah Yeah, that's how it goes.
Scott: and that's I think what is the only advantage now that retail brick-and-mortar retail has over the internet.
Scott: because pretty much if I'm going to buy something at retail and It's not I'm not gonna get that great customer cervix experience.
Scott: I might as well buy it online like I want a great customer cervix cervix.
Scott: But you know if I go to say millennium games right even though the games cost more there than they do on the Internet's Someone's gonna be there to talk to me about games And they're gonna tell me what games came out recently which ones they think are cool And which ones they think are not cool, and if I think a game is cool They're gonna tell me about the game.
Scott: begin to know something about the game on the internet.
Scott: You know I have to go and I have to search for the game, and it's it's almost as good But not quite as good and the price is lowered.
Scott: so if I go to say normal Joe Schmoe's game shop Joe Schmoe just sits behind the counter reading the newspaper.
Scott: I'm not gonna do that.
Scott: fuck that.
Scott: it's either the good customer service in the brick-and-mortar or the The Internet's.
Rym: yeah And I kind of realized after I did this that I haven't really gone to Stores other than food stores in a long time and in fact we tried to order our groceries online And we live a little bit too far from New York City to get that service.
Scott: yep But yeah the only place to get decent customer service these days that I found is specialty or Semi specialty shops at minimum and mostly in New York City.
Scott: I mean every time I've ever bought something in a place in New York City that wasn't a chain or franchise place.
Scott: There's been excellent customer service in the old-fashioned way.
Rym: now I'm sure you know Chicago and LA have the same deal, but we're in New York, so we talk about New York.
Scott: Yeah I don't know how those other cities are.
Scott: the problem is I've been to too many cities like Hartford, Connecticut Where there are no stores.
Scott: well, it's just big office buildings from the ground up to oh god.
Rym: I love Connecticut.
Rym: That's what I mean.
Rym: I really really love Connecticut because the first time I went I realized that it's just a really fun laid-back con.
Rym: yeah, but We tried to walk out of that con to get some food.
Scott: Because all that's in Hartford, Connecticut is first of all government buildings This is the capital city of Connecticut, but also office buildings for companies, but unlike, New York City Where let's say I own an office building and my company's in it right the bottom of that office building is gonna be all Stores and things like
Rym: every.
Rym: you know the building comes down.
Rym: It's a big skyscraper, and then the whole bottom floor It's just storefronts.
Scott: Yeah, I mean Empire State Building.
Scott: even the whole thing is storefronts except for the one spot That's the entrance to the Empire State Building.
Rym: Yeah, my building the Lincoln building has like these tiny little entrances in the four corners, and then just stores.
Rym: yep, but Go to Hartford and every skyscraper just comes all the way down to the street no doors No windows nothing just a wall, and then the door to the building and then a wall.
Rym: It was kind of like walking in a big empty building that didn't have a roof.
Scott: yep So there's too many cities like that.
Scott: so those cities don't have the customer.
Rym: Chicago's not like that.
Rym: I've been to Chicago a few times.
Rym: It's more like New York.
Scott: Yeah, I imagine Vancouver to be sort of similar.
Rym: Philly can't be like that.
Rym: I hear tell that Philly's pretty cool.
Scott: Yeah, Philly's got stores all right all right.
Rym: I'll go first so I don't have quite as much time to Poke around on the internet at my new job like I used to at say IBM, so I often find out about the news I don't know.
Rym: five sometimes seven minutes after other people do.
Scott: how do you get by?
Scott: You know what?
Scott: if something happens that you like you know needs to happen in the next seven minutes like what?
Scott: Big buy something for a dollar.
Scott: you got seven minutes, then it'll be a thousand dollars.
Rym: I highly doubt that'll happen in two.
Scott: if it does I knew I will products gonna release.
Scott: you got to run and wait in line.
Rym: If it does I have people like you who go omg omg in my Google chat anyway.
Rym: So uh I'm sitting there at work and Emily messaged me, and she says something to the effect of Satoshi khan is doing Batman to which I said that is probably going to be the second best Batman ever done.
Scott: Well, I mean I heard back in the day You know when paprika was was newish that Satoshi khan's next thing was gonna be some sort of thing for the younger audience.
Scott: I was thinking uh you know.
Scott: so when she said he was doing a Batman I was like ah a Batman movie makes sense.
Scott: the kids can enjoy the Batman movie You know but it's certain court seemed kind of weird to me that he's making a Batman movie when?
Scott: There's a bat a live-action Batman coming out kind of soon ish, and I think there's a trailer now Yep, plus.
Rym: I mean the deal is that basically they're making you know this new Batman movie from Christopher Nolan's Batman As was kind of expected.
Rym: and uh they were gonna make some sort of Batman and matrix to go before it.
Scott: ah Batman a matrix.
Rym: so uh it sounds good to me six animated shorts that are going to be called Batman Gotham night.
Rym: Now the director that was named was somewhat Bruce Timm for the whole project, but according to sources here Satoshi khan is going to be the director of at least one of these segments.
Scott: ah So it is gonna be the Batman a matrix.
Rym: yep There's gonna be six of them, and it looks like the people they've got on board.
Rym: I mean Satoshi khan might only be doing one But I'm still really excited about this because they've got madhouse studio 4c in production IG, so they're all gonna be great.
Scott: see I Really, I think this is a good trend because you know wait you think about it.
Scott: if someone wants to make say a collection of Shorts right or a collection of animated shorts especially and sell them for money in the u.s.. That's kind of hard You know trying to sell something like memories You know in the u.s.. Not easy, which is sad because I like things like that a lot right but if you attach them somehow to some existing popular property like like the Topically or you know a timely fashion like is an a matrix like the matrix just came out.
Scott: Hey If we make we can make an anthology of animated things on a disk and sell it now because we just attach the matrix name To it and put it out with the regular matrix and people will buy it and they did and Doing the same thing with Batman.
Scott: I don't think you can go wrong And I hope they continue to do this for things that come out because I like Anthologies now.
Rym: I hope you all know who Satoshi khan is.
Rym: I mean we don't just Constantly talk about how awesome we think this man is but he was the director of you know no How awesome he is.
Rym: I'm not sure I know how awesome Satoshi khan is.
Rym: He directed on.
Rym: let's see perfect blue.
Rym: paranoid agent paprika millennium actress Tokyo godfathers.
Rym: yes, that's the one I always forget.
Scott: That's the best one.
Scott: it is.
Rym: no it isn't.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: Actually, I think perfect blue is my favorite.
Scott: I think paranoid agent for glue one So I don't remember, but paranoid agent.
Rym: I think is the best.
Scott: I gotta tell you freak is the prettiest.
Rym: Tokyo godfathers is the funniest.
Scott: If you haven't seen plenty of actors Oh godfathers, or if you haven't seen anything's brought by Satoshi khan go get Tokyo godfathers on DVD now Because it's a holiday movie.
Rym: actually watch it.
Rym: if you're some geeky kid out there and you're gonna be with your family over the holiday and You want to geekify them a little bit, but kind of with a sucker punch.
Rym: Bring Tokyo godfathers because it's an acclaimed movie.
Rym: You can probably convince your family to watch it.
Scott: Holiday movie.
Scott: it is definitely a Christmassy movie a very very much.
Rym: So I think we showed it as the Christmas showing at RIT anime.
Scott: I like how the movie especially and I got a record to do a show about Tokyo godfathers.
Rym: We will but not tonight.
Scott: Did we do one in the past?
Rym: Maybe I don't know if we did listen to that if we didn't remind us and we'll do it all right, but yeah It's.
Scott: it's one of those good holiday movies where that's it happens to take place that all the events take place around the holiday season But there's no actual.
Scott: it doesn't actually deal with like any holidays directly.
Rym: Yeah, it's not like the Tokyo godfathers kidnapped Santa.
Rym: Yeah, it's up to you.
Scott: It's just in the holiday spirits and the holiday times.
Rym: It's also I guess I would call it one of those feel-good movies.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, it's sad.
Rym: It's poignant.
Rym: It's very much a Satoshi khan film don't get us wrong, but it's very.
Rym: it's one of his more light-hearted works.
Scott: yeah, all right, so When you want to find lyrics to musics well, what do you do?
Rym: I used to go to Sailor Bacon.
Scott: Well, that's for you know, anime musics I never cared about.
Rym: I never looked up lyrics to any other song ever except once I looked up the lyrics to stairway Cuz I couldn't hear what the hell they were saying and I wondered uh, can't believe you don't know lyrics to stairway?
Rym: I know the lyrics now when I was a kid.
Rym: I wasn't sure what a bustle in a hedgerow was.
Scott: There's a bustle in your hedgerow.
Scott: Don't be All right, it's just exactly, all right, so Yeah used to go to the Sailor Bacon.
Scott: But you know those people.
Scott: they protect their lyrics like with the copyrights and they're really anal about it.
Scott: cuz you know They want you to buy the album which is the lyrics printed in the little cover and sometimes lyrics I've been printed in there, you know?
Scott: or the worst thing I remember I got a Nirvana album way back or they want you to buy the sheet music That is the lyrics on it so that your band can cover it.
Rym: Well, the thing is actually what bothers me about the whole situation in general is that I can derive It's not like I'm recreating the whole work, but I can derive information about the word just because I'm a human being.
Rym: I can listen I can hear the words.
Rym: How come I can't transcribe them.
Rym: Yeah, it's kind of like how tablatures should be equally legal and free.
Rym: I mean if I listen to a song and figure out your chord progression, there's only so many chord progressions.
Rym: There aren't that many.
Rym: It's not like.
Rym: I can't figure it out.
Rym: You can't copyright a chord progression.
Scott: Yep All right, and copyright only prevents the copying.
Scott: I mean, it's one thing.
Scott: if I go to the store and buy your sheet music and photocopy it All right It's another thing entirely.
Scott: if I listen Figure out the notes on my own and then tell my friend what I found out and then play it.
Rym: That's I guess we need some DRM in music.
Rym: make it so you can't hear the notes.
Rym: Ah, cuz then this won't be a problem anymore.
Scott: Good call.
Scott: anyway Japan has actually found a solution to this problem that I think is high quality.
Scott: Oh, they have a website Annie Kashi JP and you can go to this website and you can search for artist song title anime series tie-in program or any phrase within lyrics and You can find lyrics to anime musics.
Scott: if you type in the word Gundam It gives you a list of a hundred and sixty six songs that you can get the lyrics to on the site.
Rym: Now, is it just in Japanese?
Rym: Do they have the Romani?
Rym: Do they have the English translations?
Scott: I'm gonna go right now because it doesn't say because what I need for karaoke, okay It's a Japanese.
Rym: so far I can't read hiragana that quickly.
Scott: So far, it's in Japanese great.
Rym: So I guess it's back to Sailor Bacon.
Scott: for me if Sailor Bacon still exists.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: Hold on I'm gonna I'm gonna try.
Rym: I'm sure the spirit of Sailor Bacon lives on Regardless of whether or not the actual site that may or may not have been run by a man Named Sailor Bacon who may or may not have dressed up as a sailor sky.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it's in Japanese, but Regardless it is fully authorized by the Japanese Society for the rights of authors composers and publishers Which is the the people who you know manage the lyrics whatever.
Scott: so it's totally legal and this is exactly What they need to do in the US.
Scott: you want people to stop doing illegal?
Scott: Technically illegal things and you want to sort of put some control on it.
Scott: Then you have to offer something that is better.
Scott: You have to.
Scott: you know, it's possible to compete with bit torrents or you know, crappy lyrics fan-made lyric sites.
Scott: you just put up a quality lyric site.
Scott: that's yours and people will go to that one instead and Japan did that in.
Scott: the US should follow suit if they're smart.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: if you kind of a short episode since you know The holidays are coming up and we're all exhausted and I really want to be rested.
Rym: So when the new mixer comes tomorrow, I can sit here in my room for the next four hours going Testing.
Scott: you mean you're gonna.
Rym: I'm gonna fiddle about.
Rym: I'm gonna fiddle about with knobs for like eight hours.
Scott: Yeah Rym likes to fiddle the knobs.
Rym: Hey, the thing is when I first got my mixer, it only doesn't have so many knobs.
Rym: It has like 15 knobs.
Scott: How many knobs do you need?
Rym: there are like 70 knobs.
Rym: I can mess with on this new given knob fetish.
Rym: I like knobs.
Scott: Well, we have it people.
Rym: so My thing of the day in fact involves a knob great.
Rym: so I'm using this partly because I Don't know I have mixed feelings about this thing today because it's one of those top ten lists and It's done in a very kind of pedestrian radio void like and number ten is It's a screw attack one, right?
Scott: Yeah screw attack.
Scott: They do all theirs in the same style.
Rym: So yeah, I just I don't like that style.
Rym: It's kind of this old-world thing.
Scott: Yeah, sometimes their top ten lists are good and sometimes not so good.
Rym: Well this one Starts out strong.
Rym: The number ten is arguably one of the funniest ones.
Rym: Yep, and then pretty much like eight through three are Patently unfunny and then it suddenly gets funny at the end except number one wasn't so no number one wasn't so great But a couple of the other ones.
Rym: Yeah It's basically a Christmas themed the top ten hose.
Rym: get it Santa Claus ho ho in video games.
Scott: Yet I could have thought of ten better hoes.
Rym: Let me tell ya I definitely could have but watch it to the end because I think number two right around there There's a pretty good payoff and the first one they give you.
Rym: I don't know why I never noticed that.
Rym: I don't know why I never thought of that because I've seen all sorts of times where people like a website of check out these Unfortunate screenshots from video games, but never saw this one before.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: I mean I think game I've never even seen before.
Rym: you've never seen that game before not really.
Rym: I mean, I've seen the glory holes in total recall.
Rym: Oh the glory holes, but this one was news to me.
Rym: Okay
Scott: so I go to some other forums not many pretty much to one or two and One of them is the is the forums for the comic geek speak podcast where there's a lot of comic nerds who I you know They're well, I might disagree with them about many comic things because they're mostly underwear pervert fans across the board mostly not all of them You know, they're they're cool people in their forms.
Scott: Okay, I think it helps that and I don't go to all the threads.
Scott: I go to very few of the threads.
Rym: see my Scott and I have kind of different circles here.
Rym: Like I meet some of these people at comms like the comic geek speak people.
Rym: I meet a few of them and Every one of them I've ever met has been really cool and I remember they wanted to shake my hand when I finally read Frank Miller's Batman.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, the Dark Knight Returns not that other one that they.
Rym: they had a look of horror lot of.
Scott: there's a lot of Batman's that Frank Miller has written.
Rym: Yeah, and when I said I read Frank Miller's Batman They looked at me with this look of horror and they're like you Dark Knight Returns, right?
Scott: Yeah, because lately he's been second.
Scott: Okay anyway So one guy his name on that forum is dad Zorro.
Scott: All right, so him and his wife You know, they would go to the comic shop.
Scott: I guess with the kids, you know, nice little fit comic family and The guys at the comic shop are apparently really nice to their kids and they appreciated that.
Scott: So they made some gingerbread cookies to give to the guys at the comic book store.
Scott: But then they took some food, you know the frosting of different colors that you can just sort of decorate food with.
Scott: you know I guess you get at the cake decorating section of the.
Scott: you know the store there and They decorated these gingerbread man's to look like superheroes and some of them were done by the kids obviously.
Scott: So they don't look that high-quality But you can recognize which hero they are anyway.
Scott: and some were done by the mom or the dad and they're pretty high quality.
Scott: So you can look at those and they're high quality.
Scott: and yeah little underwear perfect gingerbread man's they're really cute and awesome.
Rym: I think Scott's favorite one was the Hulk.
Scott: There's that there's two Hulk ones There's the there's the first Hulk one though the one that is done by the parent obviously is Super cute and high quality.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I really like that Iron Man.
Scott: I don't know why I don't like Iron Man.
Rym: I don't know why you don't like Iron Man.
Scott: I don't like Iron Man.
Scott: He sucks.
Scott: It's a stupid character even before recent events of Iron Man.
Rym: good song though.
Scott: Yeah, that's completely unrelated.
Scott: There's also two different Batman's this, you know The black and gray Batman and there's the blue Batman.
Rym: the blue Batman is.
Rym: I mean that Batman is my favorite Batman.
Scott: The blue Batman is is high quality also.
Scott: But yeah, check these out.
Scott: They're pretty cool.
Scott: These people are pretty cool.
Scott: You should do similar things.
Scott: maybe anime character.
Scott: You know gingerbread.
Rym: Well, we had some up.
Rym: Well one awesome person actually make a cornucopia for us.
Scott: Yeah for Scott one person made a cornucopia.
Scott: They were awesome.
Scott: Everyone else sucks I don't know.
Rym: or maybe we're thinking about making some cookies because actually Emily's going out of town.
Rym: I think everyone is going out of town to do what Xmas stuff?
Rym: Except us.
Rym: Scott and I always celebrate a Jewish Christmas.
Scott: I'm the Jew and rims the honorary Jew.
Rym: Yeah, so we maybe go to a movie get some Chinese food and we're probably gonna sit in the house recording like maybe My parents sent me a link to a YouTube.
Scott: that was pretty crappy, but it was a Jew kid You know, he was pretty actually good at singing in music.
Scott: But you know, he made a little music.
Scott: No, he made a little music video about you know a Jew going to eat Chinese food and watch movies on Christmas.
Scott: So maybe I'll make that my thing today tomorrow, even though it's not that great.
Rym: It's still relevant Yeah, but if you guys can think of some gingerbread cookies, we should make.
Scott: yeah We generally I'm trying to because a lot of other people with podcasts and other internet creative people.
Rym: You want to be like those other people?
Scott: No, no But they seem to be very much more successful in getting their community to create more things.
Rym: I think the problem one is that we tend to not follow through on sending the prizes We're supposed to send.
Rym: we've got a growing list of we don't need prizes.
Scott: I mean like these comic guys.
Scott: right every month or so they say alright everyone We're gonna start a thread a fan art thread.
Scott: everyone draw animals and people just draw animals like crazy.
Scott: Let's say alright guys, we're done drawing animals.
Scott: draw guys with capes and they'll draw guys with capes.
Rym: I think number two we very rarely will explicitly say do X for us and then follow up by reminding people and Make a specific thread in the forum that we look at and maintain and then we talk about on the show.
Scott: Yeah, I generally don't.
Scott: in general I know we're not gonna, you know, follow through on any of that business, but I want to stir up more creativity among the listeners.
Scott: So stir stir stir.
Scott: do make things stir stir stir.
Rym: so I'll tell you this if anyone gives us a good idea for something to make out of gingerbread and To make at all make make foods that are geeky.
Rym: You know what people are gonna say.
Rym: They're gonna say make a podcast.
Rym: Yeah more podcast Videocast.
Scott: Oh, well, you want to get into the main bit here?
Rym: Yeah, well if you want your videocast hold out till Katsucon and I'll tell you more later.
Scott: Okay, right?
Rym: So in some strange turn of events, I don't know how this is happening, but it's kind of a miracle.
Rym: lately I've been reading a lot of comic books.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It's like wait a minute.
Scott: There's someone at the door.
Scott: Let me go see who it is.
Rym: It's not opportunity.
Scott: No, no, it's death.
Scott: No up.
Scott: It's Satan.
Scott: He says he needs to borrow your blankets.
Rym: Oh Joke about how hell freezes over.
Rym: that was that was clever.
Rym: That was new media.
Scott: Wait, wait, something just bumped into the window here.
Scott: Let me go see what it was.
Rym: Oh flying pig.
Rym: It's still good.
Scott: I hear oh my it is indeed a swine with wings.
Rym: Yes See ya I could have gone one step further cuz now.
Rym: I used to live in Michigan.
Rym: Yeah, there is a town called hell in Michigan.
Rym: And yeah, it's real cold there right now, but probably it's been cold there for a long time All right, so I read among other things like Frank Miller's Batman Dark Knight Returns these two comics There's gonna be more but it's
Scott: gonna be one more
Rym: Called uh, it's Essex County by Jeff Lemire.
Scott: He's Canadian.
Scott: I think I think The impression I get the impression he's a Canadian dude, I.
Rym: the reason I get that impression is that there.
Rym: Well suffice to say I will talk about this.
Rym: But the second one is about hockey.
Rym: The first one has hockey in it.
Rym: The second one is a hockey story in the sense that I don't think a human being could write us a story That involves hockey so true to the spirit of the people who like hockey who is not either Canadian or from Northern, Michigan Mm-hmm.
Scott: Well, at least they had to be above the Messier line.
Rym: Yeah minimum, but this is very very very inside.
Scott: Yes, okay to give you to give you an introduction to these comics.
Scott: Remember, we're only reviewing volumes one and two out of three because the third one's not out yet Or at least I don't have it yet.
Scott: And the back, you know every book lately on the back They will tell you like what genres the book is in and that helps the bookstores You know shelve the books properly.
Scott: on the back of this book.
Scott: It's his farm life Slash hockey slash graphic novels.
Scott: that sums it up.
Rym: Farm life hockey graphic novels.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Alright, so let's talk about volume one first.
Scott: Alright, volume one is.
Scott: Give me a quick summary of the story.
Scott: as a young kid He lives on a farm in Essex County Canada, which is the area in between New York and Michigan.
Rym: Yeah, I actually have been through a lot of that area a lot.
Rym: I used to drive between RIT and Detroit on a regular basis.
Scott: It's Hicksville, but it's Canada.
Rym: Yeah, and This kid in fact that highway where the there's an there's a car accident in the second volume.
Rym: I've been on that highway.
Rym: It's a super dangerous highway.
Rym: There's car exits like that all the time.
Scott: so the kid likes the superheroes and he wears the mask in the cape and he likes the comic books and he likes the hockey because You know what Canadian doesn't and he lives with his uncle in the middle of nowhere on a boring farm.
Scott: And he kind of hates his uncle.
Scott: and I feel bad for the uncle.
Scott: cuz the uncle is not such a bad uncle He's just doing the best he can, you know, given the circumstances.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time It's definitely not that kind of real hate It's more the the hate of an adolescent who is living with any adults.
Rym: Yeah Cuz you know kids tend to be really kind of dickish to adults and they just I guess they don't think about it until they Get older.
Rym: then they go.
Rym: Ah, why'd I act that way when I was a kid?
Scott: Yep, and You know, so you have There's a good scene to show the kind of hate that's going on where the kid walks in and the uncles like hey the games On you want to watch the kids like no kid goes upstairs watches the hockey game.
Scott: That's that's the kind of hate We're talking about here.
Scott: So the kid meets this guy who is a little slow.
Scott: ish that he's a weird guy and he's sort of mysterious who works at the gas station and apparently the guy used to be a hockey player.
Rym: or You know that the reason they bond is that the kids really into these comic books and the guy is Also kind into comic books.
Rym: So he cuts the kid a deal and gives him a comic book.
Rym: He couldn't afford.
Scott: Yep And you know it it's it's good stuff.
Scott: You know what goes on here and it's very it's sort of slice of life.
Scott: You know in that same sort of feeling that goes on the tone of the book is very Slice of life.
Scott: like here are people living their lives.
Scott: Here's stuff that happens, but it's not a slice It's.
Scott: it's what is this kid's life?
Scott: straight through you know from one point in time to another point in time and it shows the character development of this one kid mostly as he as he learns something and grows as a person a bit and It also sort of introduces you to the uncle and to the hockey playing guy who also live in the town and you know things About them which come into play in volume 2.
Rym: now It's pretty good.
Rym: It's not the best thing I've ever read though The first volume I kind of was left with this sense of I didn't get much out of it.
Rym: Like I see.
Rym: I see what they were going with it.
Rym: I see what they did.
Rym: I see what the intent was I I get it.
Rym: I just didn't really feel a lot.
Scott: Yeah for me the first volume it like it does some clever stuff and it's going in the right direction But I don't think it comes on strong enough.
Scott: It feels kind of like.
Scott: you know, they came up with an idea and they did it But they could have done it like more powerfully.
Scott: It's like yep.
Scott: There it is.
Rym: But then again that might just be because it's the first one.
Rym: There's a little.
Scott: there could be an intentional setup like that.
Rym: because the thing is there's a thin thread linking the first one in the second one even though they're effectively completely separate.
Rym: and if you wanted to and Actually, if you're not sure if you'll like this stuff, I'd recommend just reading the second one for all.
Scott: but how much is the second?
Scott: One cost there.
Scott: look in the back 15 bucks.
Scott: Yeah, the first one's 10 bucks.
Rym: I think it's worth it.
Rym: The second one is far superior.
Scott: The second one is far superior.
Rym: I mean granted when the third one comes out, we'll know if you have to have read the first one.
Scott: Yep Well, I do think that there is much that is added to the second one.
Scott: if you did read the first one Because when I was reading the second one like I was noted, you know I because I had read the first one I knew things and I kept trying to connect him and that sort of changed the way In which I read the second one.
Rym: Well, yeah, but you're trying to figure out who that guy is.
Rym: because you're it starts you're like, oh, it's that guy then Wait a minute.
Rym: He doesn't look quite the same.
Rym: Huh?
Rym: Huh and then you figure out who that guy was.
Rym: you'll know when you read it and That was good.
Scott: But yeah, the second one the second volume is a story of some other people who happen to also be in Essex County But it mostly tells the story of just a few of them and their professional or semi-professional hockey playing careers.
Rym: Well see if the first one's about this kid and the guys living with and the weird guy at the store.
Rym: The second one is about two brothers who are hockey players and like the minor league whatevers, but it's told entirely from the perspective of one of the two brothers and It's told as a flashback reminiscence of this old deaf dumb Barely able to stand or think going senile and dying man Just kind of recounting his life to himself because no one else cares.
Scott: Actually the thing about it is like early on.
Scott: it shows you this is you know There's an old decrepit man who's you know?
Scott: Angry at the world and he's gonna probably gonna die within the you know, not too long because he's so old Sitting on his porch or whatever, you know.
Scott: last and living that is the final days Tell you reminiscing about his life and what went wrong and what weren't right.
Scott: and as he read he goes you know flashes back and you sort of forget that it was the this old man for it.
Scott: and you're just paying attention because the Flashback is like this whole story and then it goes back to the old man.
Rym: You're just like box but what it does and I thought this was very interesting Flashes back in little bits and little chunks and there's a lot of narration of him.
Rym: Just thinking like I did this.
Rym: I did this why did I do this?
Rym: and as it goes on the flashbacks are longer and I guess the lucid moments or the the present moments are shorter as the flashbacks recount his whole life eventually getting up to the point where now he's an old man and I don't know.
Rym: the effect is really really immersive despite the art which we'll get to know that the arts it serves its purpose.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's it's a different it's a different style.
Scott: but yes, the The thing I like about the second volume so much is that it's this guy the guy's story itself Has like everything that makes a story awesome.
Scott: It's got like, you know, the awesome hockey playing drama, but not the drama of actually the games of hockey.
Scott: But you know the sort of like that sideline drama, you know the in the locker room drama going on and it seemed it's so Human.
Scott: the Description of the people's feelings.
Rym: That's a good way to describe it.
Rym: I mean the let.
Rym: the dialogue is all very organic and realistic and it's you feel like you're reading an Actual account of someone's real life.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: this is how people do.
Scott: it's not you know, melodramatic or you know Sensationalized or anything like that.
Scott: It's very.
Scott: this is how it goes down with people.
Scott: It's very real like yeah That that's how you could.
Scott: you could imagine that if this is biographical or autobiographical even even though it's It's completely fictional.
Scott: It says that Allah is a fictional story.
Scott: Taking place the tales from the farm is the first in a trilogy of graphic novels set in a fictionalized version of Lameer's Hometown of Essex County, Ontario.
Scott: So the guy who wrote this he's writing about his town.
Scott: So the setting is real.
Scott: front is the setting is autobiographical But the characters are made up and the stories made up.
Rym: now in terms of the art.
Rym: The art is very Very minimalist and very sketchy and very inconsistent.
Scott: Yeah, it's well, it's not so much inconsistent.
Scott: I mean you can always tell you know, unlike a lot of other very stylized, you know arts and comics You can always recognize which characters are which right after.
Rym: well, let me put it this way You know, sometimes you watch an anime or read a comic and you see a character and you recognize them But they're a little off-model.
Rym: it happens every now and then and like ghost in the shell even good anime They get off-model and sometimes they do it so badly that you're not quite sure which character it is.
Scott: Is it a new character?
Scott: Is it that character you just saw in the last page here?
Rym: The style is such that you can always tell who someone is mostly by the shape of their nose.
Rym: Yeah, but the noses are very important in terms of going off-model.
Rym: There's really no model to go off of.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's very.
Scott: it's a very sketchy kind of.
Scott: I Really don't know how to what to compare it to Sorta a on flux II.
Scott: not really now It's very.
Rym: it's very sloppy but purposefully so.
Rym: yeah.
Scott: And he actually changes up the style at certain times like, you know There's parts where it sort of gets a little bit watercolor II and hazy During this flashback scene and there's another.
Scott: there's a bunch of pages in the first volume That where the kid drew a comic book and you're reading the comic book that the kid drew.
Rym: Oh, that was awful.
Rym: It's good, but it looks a lot like the kinds of things you see kids draw.
Scott: it looks a lot like the kind of things that I drew when I was drawing comic books and I was yeah aid and That's what makes it so real.
Scott: It's it's actually better than the comics.
Scott: I drew it But it looks literally like some he drew like, you know with a pen some like yeah He must have had a fifth grader draw a comic book and then scanned it in because that's what it looks like.
Rym: One thing I can say though.
Rym: That was a little it was that thing at first but then you get used to it.
Rym: It's almost like every character is a caricature in that there's really no perspective at all.
Rym: you characters are always facing you pretty much no matter where they're facing and everyone's kind of standing like straight up and odd angles and There's really no sort of consistency in the scenes in terms of where things are placed, but none of that really matters.
Scott: No, it really doesn't at all.
Rym: It's kind of like you look at it.
Rym: you think wow This is badly drawn.
Rym: But then you start reading it and the story is so strong and the art serves its purpose So well that you'll just completely forget and lose track of that and just suddenly you'll finish the story.
Scott: a nice touch I thought with the printing of the book is that on the inside of the back cover it shows the back of a tops Hockey card.
Scott: because I have I have some cards from that series of hockey cards, you know like baseball cards But with hockey players on them where it's got like this skate and all the statistics are in the state.
Scott: But Instead of you know having you know, the statistics in the state It's got like, you know, Jeff Lemire's information in inside this, you know, it looks like the back of a card But it's it's cool.
Rym: I like that But I mean, I don't know what else.
Rym: what else I can have to say?
Rym: I don't want to spoil anything at all because you know these are.
Rym: each one of these is basically a standalone story that you can just read and I feel like you should just read it.
Rym: I do recommend these.
Scott: this is definitely High quality high brow sort of non-underwear pervert Canadian comics Available from top shelf productions.
Scott: everything they make is highbrow and awesome.
Rym: Now if you're not sure if you like this, I really I personally recommend that you just pick up Essex County vol 2 ghost stories.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: I mean you will miss out on some things in vol 2 because you did not read vol 1 but you'll still get it and you'll know if you like it or not and you can always go and get vol 1 then read Vol 2 again and to get the correct experience, I guess and it's only gonna be three volumes So you're just you know one away from the finishing the whole deal.
Rym: Yep, and I gotta say at the end of ghost stories pages 218 and 219.
Rym: Let me see those pages.
Rym: That was when that happened.
Rym: Oh I didn't cry But I that really got to me because these the stories are really sad.
Rym: don't come into this expecting It's gonna be some happy fun slice of life.
Scott: No, remember these are people on a farm With drama and shitty lives, you know sad things happen.
Scott: There isn't many happy times for these people.
Scott: It's people, you know Recounting their their days and in a boring ass crap town.
Rym: Well thing is they recounted in a very realistic way like well in especially in ghost stories.
Rym: It's just an old man kind of having his entire life flash before his eyes and he remembers the good and the bad and it kind of.
Rym: It kind of follows the way memory goes where the the big moments and the important Conversations and the things that mattered stand out and as a result he remembers them more and all the Everything in between.
Rym: that isn't really good or really bad.
Rym: Just kind of faded into the background of memory.
Rym: So it's very much like a trip through someone's mind.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: There's even points it where you know, cuz it's the guy, you know Recounting his stuff.
Scott: There's some stuff.
Scott: He just doesn't remember it.
Scott: He's like, yeah, this is all I remember from that.
Scott: Oh Is there anything else to say about this?
Rym: Not really?
Scott: No, what kind of person would like this you think?
Rym: Honestly anyone who likes hockey I'm serious not just you know, like oh, I'm a hockey fan blah.
Rym: But they're you know, those people who are hockey people, especially if they live north of the Messier line.
Rym: If you like hockey, you'll really like ghost.
Scott: Yeah, whether you like comics or not but even if you don't like hockey if you like sort of really sort of mellow and Not heartwarming but Poignant I've been saying that word a lot There's not many other words sort of like, you know sort of like it's.
Scott: it's not sad like, you know balling all over the place but it's sort of like calmly said like It's just this vaguely Hurtful.
Rym: just that person like you see this person recounting the mistakes They made in their past and you know, it's a mistake and they know it was a mistake But it already happened.
Rym: and all they can do is tell you what happened because of that mistake.
Scott: Yep, and it's it just it sort of just goes down.
Scott: if you like that kind of thing and you like comics These are worth reading very much.
Scott: So and you top shelf doesn't print stuff.
Scott: That's not good.
Rym: Yep There's another part that really got me where the old man he's going through his things because he can't sleep and he he finds a book of photographs and newspaper clippings and letters from his brother and They pretty much just give you that entire photo book in the comic and you can just read through it and it's just the newspaper clippings and the actual letters and well actual in terms of the story and these actual photographs and They're really kind of sad and touching especially knowing what's going on in the story.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty rough, you know and you sort of get the same feeling when you read that that the old man would get when he takes it out and looks At it and it's sort of like wow That's good Comicking when you can do.
Rym: this comic does a very good job of getting you to really empathize with the main character the old man Whichever character they want you to empathize with at any moment in time.
Rym: You're pretty much in this one.
Rym: You follow.
Scott: the old man is volume two.
Scott: You're pretty much the old man the whole time.
Scott: Yeah in volume one.
Rym: I felt bad for everyone.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: Yeah, there's a thing about volume one is a slight ambiguity, but I want to spoil it.
Scott: So I'll ask you after.
Rym: but uh Yeah, oh, I know you're getting that.
Rym: Yeah, I wasn't sure either.
Rym: Yeah, okay I really don't know.
Rym: I think the third one is gonna wrap that up because I don't know what happened.
Scott: Well, I don't think I I don't know anyway, yeah, I don't want to spoil it.
Rym: Maybe we'll talk about probably talk about it again Once the third one comes out at least to you know.
Rym: Say if the first one mattered or if it tied together or what the end result was.
Rym: We're not gonna do some sort of final thoughts.
Rym: this is what this symbolized and this is what I thought about when that happened, but I Really think this is a good book to read and especially I think that ghost stories is a good gift to get for I'm not gonna say this in a stereotypical way But an older person because it's definitely you know someone looking back at their life and I could see how someone who has lived a very long life would read this and
Scott: Get it.
Scott: Yeah, this is not a bad comic to get some older maybe anti comic minded people to accept a comic as a Respectable form of artistic expression nothing else.
Rym: get this comic for your dad.
Scott: Yeah, sure or your mom.
Rym: Yeah All right, I know it was a little bit of a short episode.
Rym: but what do you want?
Rym: we're tired tired.
Scott: There isn't really that much to say without spoiling it and we want to do a review and not a plot synopsis.
Rym: tomorrow We'll be good because we're gonna our things of the day might turn into the whole show.
Rym: Oh Great that.
Rym: yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front road crew comm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.