Rym: It's Thursday, February 8th.
Rym: I'm Rym and I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about professionalism.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Well today I woke up and When I got myself together at around I don't know nine.
Scott: I did my usual business.
Scott: I took the 1050 train to the city.
Scott: I got to the city like noonish.
Scott: I Went in I saw the new office, which is all fancy And I said all right now that I've seen your new office, and it's all fancy.
Scott: I quit I'm out.
Rym: So how'd they take it?
Scott: they were just kind of like oh well you know Good luck.
Scott: Where are you working all right?
Scott: We still like you come back if you want.
Scott: Yeah, and that was it all right.
Rym: They make you sign any non-competes or anything.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I think I signed a non-compete when I got there.
Rym: ah See I would.
Rym: I don't think I would have taken a job that made me sign something like that in the first place.
Scott: Well, it wasn't a bad non-compete.
Scott: It wasn't like.
Scott: you know is one kind of non-compete that says let's say you're a plumber right and you work for someone plumbing There's a non-compete that says you can't plumb for anyone else.
Scott: It's like great.
Scott: Well now my only skill I'm not allowed to use anywhere, but here this non-compete was pretty much I couldn't work for a competing company, so I'm working for a company that provides small business services.
Scott: Well, I was until today, so I couldn't go work at another company that provides small business services.
Rym: Yeah, I just generally really don't feel comfortable signing agreements like that.
Scott: when it got in regards to my employment I generally don't like you know signing a lot of kinds of agreements, and I'm hoping at the new place I'm not gonna have to sign so much bullshit.
Scott: I'm getting the feeling I won't because it's a private company and not a public company.
Scott: So they're not beholden to shareholders.
Scott: So they don't make you sign shit that you know they don't care about because who's who's gonna complain?
Rym: I just remember was funny that when I left IBM They made me sign a lot more stuff than when I got hired by IBM.
Scott: Yeah, all I had to do was I had to sign a thing that says yes They told me all these things like you know.
Scott: yes, I was informed that I can't talk about patents.
Scott: Yes, I was informed that I can't reveal trade secrets.
Scott: Yes, you know.
Scott: and then I had to say yes I gave back all this equipment.
Scott: Yes, okay, and then they were like They were like ten questions, and I could answer yes or no, and it was like you know Do you think you were managed well?
Scott: Do you think you know?
Scott: Was your job rewarding?
Scott: Etc etc, and I was just like yes, no, maybe you know CS.
Scott: Yes most of them were yes actually Except the rewarding was no Not rewarding job.
Scott: Well.
Rym: I mean honestly.
Rym: I don't think I've ever had a rewarding job at least in terms of my career advancement Or my degree or the stuff.
Scott: I know or I'm good at and it's not not rewarding in money.
Scott: I mean the job I had until today.
Scott: the money was enough.
Scott: You know the people there.
Scott: They weren't the.
Scott: you know they weren't like my best friends, but they were all cool.
Scott: I couldn't.
Scott: you know you it'd be tough to ask for better.
Scott: You know considering all these people who complain about their evil boss.
Scott: Yeah, my boss Didn't.
Scott: I didn't do work for a whole year, and he didn't say anything.
Scott: That's you know.
Scott: and when I go to see him in the city.
Scott: He's always like hey What's going on happy to see me and all that.
Scott: yeah, so yeah, they're not bad people It's just.
Scott: I was tired of sitting in the middle of nowhere doing nothing.
Scott: Yeah, I made that clear I gave back my laptop after erasing it and That's that.
Rym: yep well I guess now I better get a new job to keep up with the Joneses since now you make more money than me.
Scott: Yes, I do.
Scott: I have a 35% more money than I used to be making at my new job Which I who knows when I'm gonna start it probably a few weeks.
Rym: Yeah, well plus your company apparently is paying for your two weeks, but you don't have to work.
Scott: Yeah I'm getting paid at my current job until the 15th, and I'm also getting paid for any vacation days.
Scott: I did not use and my insurances and my benefits last until the end of the month and Then this Cobra which can allow me to use them even longer if I need to because who knows at the new job usually Like your new benefits don't kick in for 90 days or some crap like that.
Scott: So I might have to use the Cobra to go to the dentist or something.
Rym: yeah Well actually my the job.
Rym: I got my benefits kicked in in me almost immediately like within two weeks.
Scott: Bing yeah at the car at the job that I just quit from the benefits didn't kick in was it 30 days?
Scott: six It was a while.
Rym: Yeah, well technically the company.
Rym: I'm working for now, too.
Rym: They originally you know you don't start a crewing vacation for the first 90 days.
Scott: Oh, I hate that,
Rym: but I basically said I'm gonna take a bunch of vacation This month when I start with you, and then I'm gonna take a bunch of more vacation two months later, and they said well We'll just start a crew in your vacation now, and I said that's fine
Scott: all right.
Scott: Yeah other also because I just gave back my laptop to its Technical owners.
Rym: now Scott's got this.
Rym: I have to go buy one.
Rym: Scott's got some dead tree with some words printed on it that he's staring at in front of his microphone.
Rym: boom.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, hey at least he got the boom now, so now you can use that extra hand to hold that piece of paper.
Scott: Yeah, you know like the microphone boom.
Scott: I was like yeah, I don't need no stinking microphone stand You know whatever.
Scott: and then I was like all right, you know whatever we'll get one at RadioShack.
Scott: It was like 30-something bucks for the stand and the boom stick and this is my boom stick boom stick.
Scott: And you know I didn't realize this when I got it But the huge advantage of having the microphone on some sort of stand or boom is that both of my hands are free.
Scott: when?
Scott: Podcasting up until yesterday I was podcasting with one hand on the microphone So now when I get a new laptop I can type on it and podcast at the same time.
Rym: Yeah Though I will see if you actually get that laptop in any reasonable span.
Rym: as we've discovered there aren't actually any easy ways to buy Good laptops anywhere.
Scott: Yeah, check this shit, right?
Scott: I want to get.
Scott: I looked I did research and I want decided I want this x60.
Scott: I'm still like this information.
Scott: I want to know to decide between the ThinkPad x60 and the x60 s but besides that on The Lenovo website I can get the x60 for like $1,800 and it comes with a core 2 duo and one and a half gigs of RAM and the better battery and all this stuff.
Scott: right if I buy that same thing for Newegg with half a gig of RAM so one-third the RAM and You know everything else.
Scott: note the small battery.
Scott: It's $2,200 from Newegg the place that's supposed to be discounted.
Scott: What the hell.
Scott: it makes no sense.
Rym: I don't know when it comes to anything like that.
Rym: if I can I try to just buy direct and I pay whatever the company That makes it would want me to pay.
Scott: I think I'm just gonna have to cave in.
Scott: I'll buy it from the Lenovo website and wait two weeks for the descended to me.
Rym: So anyway in the news people in our forums posted this we're talking about it, but CNN had this kind of skewed.
Rym: Oh No, the atheist segment not too long ago Great and the funny thing is the internet responded in kind.
Rym: now I've noticed over time that dig is very much generally pro atheist.
Rym: you can see that in any religion thread where generally atheist comments get dug way the hell up and Religious comments get dug away the hell down.
Scott: Yeah Well, I mean when you have a site that's editorial like most sites were prior to dig actually coming out and saying yeah We're actually gonna do that crazy idea.
Scott: Everyone's been yelling about for ten years since slashdot started.
Scott: You know stuff that was super controversial like that or super one-sided would always kind of go and You know, it wouldn't get posted.
Scott: you wouldn't post a story on the front page of slashdot that was like there's no God but on dig, you know, there is a democracy there of some kind.
Scott: however, it may be swayed by Networks of people and Scheming.
Scott: well, it's not that.
Rym: it's just that there's a lot of atheists on dig And I think it's starting to come out that the internet as a whole has a lot.
Rym: I mean before like atheists weren't really prominent like they were just there.
Rym: you didn't know if someone was an atheist didn't care.
Rym: but More and more inflammatory things happen and dig reacts and you realize that the majority of the people there are atheists.
Scott: Well Atheists tend to be smart people So smart people the Internet's.
Rym: anyway.
Rym: CNN did this thing and immediately there was a story on dig about it and it got a crazy number of digs and comments and the very first comment with a crazy number of up digs was basically a link to the CNN feedback thing and Apparently everyone on dig followed it because all the people who were on this segment Got all sorts of thousands and thousands and thousands of rather displeased emails and CNN got crazy complaints.
Rym: Now we don't know if CNN had planned this already or if they're just reacting or what but apparently tonight as we're doing GeekNights Richard Dawkins is going to be on CNN.
Scott: Oh, that's a funny coincidence.
Scott: You have there now.
Rym: someone in the forum suggested that maybe CNN did this on purpose and there's no way Anyone at CNN is that smart?
Rym: No, they didn't plan this.
Rym: I imagine that there's a guy in charge of programming for whatever that night and he's sitting there and his aid comes in.
Rym: and Sir, we got a million complaints about that atheist thing.
Rym: What atheists think that thing we did Crap, we better do the opposite side of that thing.
Rym: get that Richard Dickens guy I keep hearing about in the news.
Rym: He wrote some book.
Scott: Uh-huh Yeah, it just.
Scott: it pleases me to see that now the opinion of the Internet is starting to have some sort of effect like people Who are in the old media are starting to get it a little bit like the tiniest bit of getting it.
Scott: They don't have it by far but they're starting to get it.
Rym: There's that newspaper guy who said yeah, you know what?
Rym: We might not be printed in for top five years I don't care.
Rym: and there was snakes on a plane which would never have happened without the Internet.
Rym: while it was bad At least they noticed that the Internet was there and they tried.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, whatever It's like we got the hook like it's starting to stab the tongue But we haven't hooked him and reeled him in yet when they're in my boat and I'm cooking him.
Rym: Then we'll be all set and then we'll see the juggernaut.
Rym: live-action movies.
Scott: Okay That movie be such a bitch.
Scott: Okay alright, so I Don't know.
Scott: we've talked about this before on the show But it's it's well known probably among most of our longer time listeners that we are Skeptical of things.
Rym: God Scott is skeptical of me.
Rym: when I come home and I tell him something like I had pizza for lunch Like what kind of pizza you didn't have a pizza?
Scott: Well, it's mostly I'll be skeptical and Rym exaggerate something like.
Scott: he'll say I had the best pizza today.
Scott: I'm like, no, there's no way you had the best pizza today.
Rym: No, cuz I had the best pizza.
Rym: I had that day that day whatever.
Scott: anyway, one thing that we are skeptical of is The belief that there are aliens Visiting us.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: There we go Cuz you know Carl Sagan and all that.
Rym: it is totally within the realm that there is life out there somewhere in the billions and billions there probably is.
Scott: the odds are that out in the universe there is some sort of life other than human beings on some other Planet or maybe in between the planets or on a Sun or on a moon.
Rym: good odds that there's intelligent life out there.
Rym: however based on all we know about the laws of physics and based on the fact that By and large the only people who claim to see UFOs are idiots of delusional and or drunken people or people who really have no credibility anyway, and also the fact that Despite the fact that we've got you know cameras everywhere now everyone has cameras high definition this and that.
Rym: and yet How come there really aren't any more UFO pictures?
Scott: Well, there are but all of them are incredibly blurry Or incredibly over.
Rym: there's the string.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, I would believe it.
Scott: actually I kind of want to believe in aliens and stuff, but the evidence is so flimsy Good God when I was a little kid.
Rym: It's like.
Scott: it's like if It's almost as if like a three-year-old kid like pulls a prank to get his mom To believe that his brother did something bad.
Scott: It's that much of a sham job yet all these people believe it.
Rym: you mean like my little brother when he would punch himself in the arm until he got a bruise and then yell for our Mother and she'd come in.
Rym: he'd yell.
Rym: He hit me and ah, ah The the absolute outrage that I would feel because there was nothing I could do.
Rym: I mean I try to explain.
Rym: no he was hitting himself.
Rym: He was hitting himself.
Rym: I didn't do it.
Rym: There's no way any parents gonna believe that right?
Scott: So anyone who believes that there are gray men from Mars walking around and that Roswell was something other than a military project of some sort You're a nut job.
Rym: According to us see when I was a little and according to psychologists and psychiatrists when I was a little kid I kind of believe.
Scott: oh, I totally believe like when I was in middle school Watch all those shows like I read.
Scott: I totally watched all the same show.
Rym: I read Fate magazine and I watch.
Rym: I read a hundred and I watched unsolved mysteries.
Scott: my first website That I ever made had like a little section like ooh, they're aliens.
Rym: OMG what you're.
Rym: by the time I knew how to make a website.
Rym: I was well past that.
Scott: No, it was in my second website that section disappeared.
Rym: When did you make your first website?
Rym: Cuz that was must have been late middle school high school at the early.
Scott: I think it was like 1995 or six.
Rym: All right.
Scott: All right, and then I got made a new website in 97 98.
Rym: I stopped believing there were aliens and pretty much fifth or sixth grade when I started reading real newspapers And I kind of really didn't start believing in the aliens until like seventh or eighth grades.
Rym: Oh, I believe when I was a little little kid cuz I'd watch I'd watch unsolved mysteries and they'd be like so scared to watch Unsolved mysteries a little.
Scott: it wasn't until middle school and I was brave enough to watch unsolved mysteries that I believed See you were probably smarter.
Rym: I was more like Bill Cosby as a kid.
Rym: right watch the unsolved mysteries and I Wouldn't be afraid of it and I'd be fine.
Rym: My parents really you're gonna have nightmares.
Rym: You're gonna come crying You're gonna like no mom.
Scott: Unsolved mysteries is a scary show for a little kids.
Scott: But I was like there's one that was all about George Washington's ghost.
Rym: Oh, yeah It didn't bother me at all.
Rym: Mm-hmm until you know, it's time to leave grandma's house, you know I'm sitting at grandma's house and there's the Grandma's house also cuz my grandma yeah But there was this giant window that went out to the like the back carport and this other giant window.
Rym: There are a lot of dark places.
Rym: my grandma's house cuz the house was gigantic and they didn't leave all the lights on.
Rym: So normally I'd be watching the show.
Rym: I'd be like, yeah And then after like the second child murderer mystery is talked about I keep thinking I see someone lurking outside But I'd be too afraid to act like.
Rym: I saw it cuz then they'd know I knew and then they'd get me.
Scott: I'm just glad that shows off the air Show the UFO and I'd swear.
Rym: one time we're going home from my grandma's house and I swear in the car next to us I saw the dude from the unsolved mysteries driving and he looked at me and I was like, oh crap.
Rym: And I told my mom and she told me to be quiet.
Rym: I'm so afraid you so my home and get me.
Rym: so my news cares about your news.
Scott: So apparently The are the military of Chile the country Chile in South America, Chile, Chile.
Scott: the military there Believes in UFOs and aliens and shit.
Rym: that doesn't surprise.
Scott: there was an international Ufology Convent conference of some sort and these big-name guys from the Chilean military came and did Presentations and stuff and they yeah, it was kind of crazy.
Scott: Here at the conference was retired official Armando Valdez who is noted for his involvement in one of Chile's first documented UFO abductions which became known as the Valdez case 77 wait Minute Valdez along with five members of an army patrol saw two bright objects descending from the sky.
Scott: They set out.
Scott: Oh Valdez set out alone to investigate.
Scott: according to the men simply vanished.
Scott: 15 minutes later They said he reappeared tried to speak and passed out.
Scott: The date on his watch had been advanced five days and he had a mini head about a week's growth of beard.
Rym: You know what now?
Rym: normally I'd say there's prior rational explanation but I'd go one step further and say that these guys just made that bullshit up to cover for something they were doing my Either that or they were all doing drugs.
Rym: No, it wasn't drug.
Rym: I'm almost certain that they made it up to cover up them not doing their job.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: Either way, maybe I mean, I don't understand the rationale.
Rym: some of these people like if I actually saw An alien like if an alien came into my window and I saw one I'd tell everyone be like, yeah, but What would it take?
Rym: you can't?
Rym: I mean who would make that up?
Rym: who would sit down and I'm gonna act like aliens abducted me because that I think.
Scott: another problem is that you make up a story like this and you tell it to yourself and You tell it to your friends and you tell it to people so many times you end up believing it yourself that that's what really Happened.
Scott: because you you know that happened to me.
Rym: who tells it in the first place.
Scott: I don't know man.
Rym: I mean, that's the logical leap there.
Rym: I can understand believe in your own lie Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, I'm just gonna say People are still crazy about these UFOs cuz I it is died down in recent years.
Scott: the craziness about UFOs.
Rym: it was much stronger in the 90s and Well, the 90s were that magical era where the internet existed, but it wasn't that widely available.
Rym: So there were still that.
Rym: check out this picture of a UFO.
Rym: No one's debunked this.
Rym: check out this magazine that has all this evidence and you didn't have an internet to just go Obviously refute it.
Rym: So you'd say oh a scientific paper.
Scott: I have to believe that I remember one time I sent in like a Freedom of Information Act request for like Information about Roswell and stuff really?
Scott: Yeah, I might still have it somewhere.
Scott: what what they sent back?
Scott: It was just a bunch of papers with stuff blacked out.
Scott: It wasn't very interesting or didn't?
Scott: nor did it make sense.
Rym: see nowadays they'll send you a redacted PDF where you can just take the black bars away cuz they Remember that story.
Rym: Oh, yeah, that was funny Things of the day.
Rym: I now have to conclude my awesome rims.
Rym: Hitler was born to be alive theme week.
Scott: Oh Shit, I wonder what Scott's theme is gonna be next week.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Scott gave me a preview and I'm not.
Scott: I don't know if I'm.
Scott: I haven't sold on that theme yet.
Rym: See, I'm not Totally worried.
Rym: I'm not thinking like Scott's gonna steamroller me.
Rym: But at the same time, I don't know if you can top.
Rym: Hitler was born to be alive week.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: See the thing is while your theme itself in essence is high quality the actual things of the day Selected to support your theme while the first one of course embodied your theme entirely I don't know if all your things of the day are as Great as the idea that your theme project.
Rym: Well, the thing is the first thing.
Rym: I mean anyone who hasn't listened to the rest of this week should look at all of my Things of the day this week.
Rym: The first one was probably my favorite.
Rym: It's what spawned at all that music video set to Hitler singing born to be alive.
Rym: That was boring.
Rym: But the thing is the the Hitler needs a car.
Rym: that isn't a rice car thing.
Rym: I think was incredibly hilarious.
Scott: It was definitely the funny.
Scott: I don't know if it was incredibly hilarious.
Rym: it was the funny and the fact that we found that video of that kid dancing in that whatever thing to that other techno remix of That was all.
Scott: I enjoyed that one a lot.
Scott: just cuz I like this.
Rym: Yeah, I think the theme it wasn't so much the theme.
Rym: Hitler was born to be alive.
Rym: It was that by choosing the theme from that first thing of the day I ended up finding these weird funny things of the day that I never would have found otherwise Unless I was searching for this one weird thing.
Scott: So rather than just accept what normally comes through the pipeline on dig as being popular and everyone's already seen it you Pick something and you search for that something and then you find the best stuff that comes up for that search.
Rym: now I remember I used to do that in the early days of Google video once the top of hon But you would always just search for puned or cool or funny or cat.
Rym: Yeah, and then one day I thought you know What.
Rym: I wonder how I could find something awesome That no one else has already seen or something that just isn't in the internet presence right now.
Rym: so I searched for the word British and I found a bunch of funny stuff and I searched for a couple other random words and Found funny things.
Rym: In fact back when penny arcade used to have the awesome archive search that they since totally gimped I remember sometimes I type a random word in and it would give me a semi random sampling of penny arcades to read Yeah, those are the good days now books.
Scott: Yep Which are scary once you look inside it's certain pieces.
Rym: Oh, I was reading Oh the third penny arcade book has references to when the Xbox came out and I thought that wasn't that long ago was it?
Scott: It's only it's the third penny arcade book, right?
Scott: So the third year of penny arcade the Xbox one came out and you know what year.
Scott: that was 2002.
Rym: you know what made me feel even older.
Rym: we're gonna do a show on this as soon as I convinced Scott to watch it.
Rym: But I got a copy of this thing that I saw in 1993 on TV called wild palms, which was the science fiction kind of awesome made-for-tv movie in two parts and I just realized now that I finally after all these years got a hold of it again.
Rym: I want to see now if what I think of it is the same as what my 11 year old self thought of it.
Scott: Mmm, but we will find out next.
Rym: it turns out that it's set in the year 2007 totally out of the blue which made me at least it's no crystalis God But yeah, at least anytime I think I'm feeling a little old.
Rym: I remember that old man Scott Johnson will always be older than us But anyway, I had a bunch of candidates for how to finish off.
Rym: Hitler was born to be alive week.
Rym: I have this.
Rym: there was this funny animation of Hitler singing in his bunker and There was this stupid rat music video to Hitler and all this stuff.
Rym: There was also and I realized that what I should do is I should you know, like a firework show Where they have you know little firework little firework and then they shoot a whole bunch off at once as the finale.
Rym: So what I got here are all the straight-up music videos to this song that are not jokes.
Rym: these are actual music videos or Things that are what music videos were before MTV came, you know, just a video of the band playing of this song various techno remixes Perhaps my favorite other than the original.
Rym: let's talk about him in order.
Rym: There's the original the original video by Patrick Hernandez.
Rym: There are about 40 as far as I can tell different performances of him doing this song and I don't think he ever did another song Ever that he was a one-hit wonder.
Scott: I'm sure that he had an album.
Scott: I'm sure we could get that album.
Rym: He also everything else in the album is probably crap doesn't look the way you think he would look.
Rym: He's kind of scary.
Rym: He has this weird kind of dance that all the videos of him.
Rym: He does the same dance with this cane.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: Looks like a child malaise.
Rym: You don't realize how weird he says the word Bart until you listen to this song a bunch of times and then you see the shape of his mouth when he says it.
Rym: and Also, it's just he's kind of weird.
Scott: I don't know why it was a one-hit wonder.
Scott: people, you know, the song was good enough that they would tolerate it.
Scott: But everything else you're just like get the hell out of here.
Rym: So then there's this punk rock metal band.
Rym: Oh, I didn't listen to enough of them to figure out what genre they're actually in But they covered this song and I think what stands out the most.
Rym: aside from the fact that you know Bands like, you know the guar style of band.
Rym: They have their face.
Rym: when they're playing that like Kind of face, you know that the scowl the whatever they're doing.
Scott: Yeah, most most metal bands have a face.
Rym: These guys have a diarrhea face.
Rym: Now more importantly what stood out more than anything was the fact that the guy has a base in the shape of a coffin.
Scott: That obviously I'm pretty sure he made it himself.
Rym: It's so lame and It's so tacky.
Rym: They're terrible.
Rym: Now the worst thing is if you watch this video look at the YouTube comments.
Rym: the comments aren't.
Rym: what the fuck is this band?
Rym: This is scary.
Rym: The comments are yeah, that was from the coffin era of this band.
Scott: Wow If my band has a coffin era Just shoot me.
Rym: that could be awesome me in a cough.
Rym: That could be awesome.
Rym: However, this band not so much.
Scott: Imagine if like the second season of utensil was the coffin saga.
Rym: it pretty much was I know but I'm saying If they called it that you know what I wouldn't be surprised.
Rym: There are people who do because half of it is certain people talking to each other.
Rym: Well coffins are being wheeled away in the background.
Rym: In fact, the the stock footage that they play during the elevator thing before the duel I know but wouldn't it be so much tackier than the black rose saga, which it is named.
Scott: That's all I'm saying.
Scott: It's tacky.
Scott: The name is tacky itself.
Rym: Yeah, but then there's cars.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Anyway, I got a thing of the day, too.
Rym: Oh, do you?
Scott: yes, I don't know if I used it as a thing of the day even though I'm pretty sure I did.
Scott: there was a video of a Little midget kid in India.
Rym: Yeah, you say midget.
Rym: now Scott was like, oh Rym you remember this and I'm like.
Rym: I don't remember any video of an Indian guy dancing and Scott's like, yeah, I said it was a kid.
Rym: Yes, like he's this Indian kid dancing.
Rym: no, it's an Indian midget who happened to be a child at the time dancing Back when then you didn't know he was a midget.
Scott: yet cuz he was still a kid.
Rym: No, we knew he was a midget.
Scott: We knew.
Scott: I thought he was just a small kid.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Yeah No, it was obviously a midget.
Scott: Anyway, it's a midget kid and is a video of him dancing and it was all over the internet cuz he danced.
Scott: really well For a little midget kid, you know what that's like.
Rym: It's like if say one of our friends was killed by an apple a long time ago And instead of saying hey remember when so-and-so was killed by that Apple you said hey remember that Apple.
Rym: Anyway, okay.
Scott: Anyway someone as You know using the power of the internet, I guess Discovered what happened to this midget kid?
Scott: Ooh He's now a midget choreographer in Bollywood and there's a video of him Teaching someone this dance.
Scott: to do that They're gonna do in like a movie or a TV show or a commercial or whatever.
Rym: They're doing well good on him.
Rym: I'm glad he made something of himself.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: I think it's pretty cool that you can go on the internet and see a video like oh my god There used to be this midget kid who danced really awesomely in India And now you can see that that midget kid is a midget choreographer in India and the world is one.
Rym: That is in fact the power of the internet.
Scott: I You know, it also does awesome dancing.
Scott: I always loved watching people dance.
Scott: Yeah Yeah
Rym: If only I could get a hold of all the news like that whenever I wanted if only I had some sort of overlay Where I could see someone and like put a bookmark on him and then two years later Just hit the button and see what they've done.
Scott: Yeah I know if I was in some sort of lame story where there was a genie and I couldn't wish for all the really cool Smart wishes
Rym: you mean like more wishes and all the powers of a genie without any of the constraints
Scott: or being a wizard or anything Like that.
Scott: if I couldn't do any cool wishes and I had to do a lame wish I would definitely wish for dancing skills.
Rym: You know those can be had with practice books and cool people telling you how to dance.
Scott: I don't have the right DNA.
Rym: See that's why we go to anime cons.
Rym: is there we can be cool?
Scott: I do not and I have some rhythms.
Scott: I have more rhythms than most people.
Scott: I mean I can play DDR and I don't mess up.
Scott: see what I do not have enough rhythms to.
Scott: You know achieve the net.
Rym: what I've learned in my years of dancing both at real clubs and at concerts and at anime cons of varying levels of nerdliness is that Unless you are somehow broken you can put forth a minimal dancing effort.
Rym: That is well above being ridiculed.
Scott: You can definitely get above the ridicule level.
Scott: I believe I'm above the ridicule.
Rym: Oh, yes, we both.
Scott: in fact, however, I am NOT at the level of I could get a job Dancing for a DJ come.
Scott: no, no I could make a video on YouTube of me dancing and people would think it was cool or I don't know.
Scott: Numa that's not the same thing.
Scott: I want you got to have people respect for the dancing and not for your fatness.
Rym: I know I am at least at the level.
Rym: I'm not at the level where at any reasonable dance or dancing item I could actually be in the center of one of those circles and having people actually care.
Scott: I don't want to get like be the center of attention.
Scott: That's that's above my goal.
Scott: my goal is to just you know, my dancing should get some level of Positive attention because it is pleasant to look upon me while I dance.
Scott: My face brings some pleasure to people to look upon it as opposed to just yeah, looky mighty Yes My favorite thing all I want out of dances.
Rym: if I'm dancing and someone else is dancing we make eye contact.
Rym: If they give me that nod of I approve of the fact that you exist in her dancing and I return that nod.
Rym: That's all I want.
Rym: That nod of.
Rym: huh, we're dancing ain't it great.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's the level I'm at now.
Scott: I want one step more course.
Scott: I remember mind being the ultimate breakdancing God or anything, but I'm just you can't beat that kid.
Scott: No can't beat that kid.
Rym: All right, but I do remember at a katsu kana while ago I was dancing with a friend of mine.
Rym: You know hanging out.
Rym: There's a bunch of funny starters about that.
Rym: We will tell him at katsu kana maybe but you know where he's dancing really well, and I'm thinking to myself wow He must actually know how to dance.
Rym: someone must have taught him god damn Halfway through 80s night.
Rym: He leans over and says hey Rym am I dancing?
Rym: Okay?
Rym: I don't know if I know how to dance and I think I look stupid And I'm just like dude.
Scott: that is.
Scott: the problem is that many people have the natural rhythm, but no one ever tells you Hey, you're dancing.
Scott: Well or anything like that, especially not Guys, if you're a guy well unless you're gay or something or you're just you know, not homophobic like us.
Scott: Well, I mean you'd have to ask like I wouldn't just say hey Rym you're dancing real.
Scott: Because then Rym would say you know how I know you're gay.
Rym: Yeah, I would but however You know how.
Rym: I know you're gay is not an accusation of gayness.
Rym: It is merely an acknowledgement.
Scott: I know, but I would still seek to avoid receiving that.
Scott: you know what I'm saying.
Rym: I know you like to avoid receiving, but Exactly all right.
Scott: What are we talking about today in our main bits?
Scott: professionalism Professionally Professionalism professionalism as opposed to amateurism.
Rym: well no you see we actually way back We did a show on.
Rym: either either we did a show or we said we were gonna do a show.
Scott: We don't remember.
Scott: That's how many shows we've done.
Scott: I have to tell us cuz we have no clue.
Rym: God return independent to go good though They're like.
Rym: did we talk about that?
Rym: I don't know whatever.
Rym: let's talk.
Scott: Yes, you've done three shows on why you should be allowed to smoke weed, but you won't.
Scott: it's do something else guys.
Rym: But anyway we I'm just gonna assume we did one.
Rym: we did a show on how to do a good panel at an anime con or any kind Of con.
Rym: did we?
Rym: or we said we were gonna do it?
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: regardless during the planning of that we decided that the idea of professionalism is Worthy of a separate show in and of itself beyond that.
Rym: so here.
Rym: We are talking about professionalism.
Scott: Well, I think the reason that the professionalism is kind of important Is that it's sort of the foundation of most of our how to not suck shows.
Scott: It's like if you follow if you don't suck at being professional, then you will not suck at many other things.
Rym: yep.
Rym: So before we continue as Scott was alluding to we really have to take care of the fact that we're not talking about this other totally different dichotomy of amateur versus professional which basically comes down to Paid to do it versus doing it for free or something along those lines.
Rym: that seems to be the demarcation most people make.
Scott: yeah We're not talking about official professionalism.
Scott: We're not talking about the difference between NFL and NCAA where one's a pro sport in one's college sports.
Scott: We're not talking about the difference between how the Olympics only used to allow amateur athletes, and now it allows professional.
Rym: Yeah, in fact if you want it if you want to get where we're using the word professionalism We are am an amateur podcast that is done professionally.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: We are professional amateur.
Scott: We're using the other definition of professional.
Rym: now I guess we start this with the story because I remember way back RIT anime club.
Rym: You know we were I was just I was on the eboard.
Rym: I had just gotten in by Fiat.
Rym: I wasn't elected.
Rym: I was one of those like those presidents who never actually got elected.
Rym: They just got appointed and then they were good enough that no one ever bothered to run against him since then because I never ran in my first two elections, but anyway I get on this board and you know we have some conflict with this other club.
Rym: that's causing trouble.
Rym: and We make the argument that well, they're just not being professional about this.
Rym: it had to do with a certain convention Mm-hmm, and you know we say to the you know the head of clubs Who's mediating this dispute that work?
Rym: They're not handling themselves in a professional manner?
Rym: We can't work with them.
Rym: and his response was this is a club in a school.
Rym: You shouldn't be professional about it.
Rym: There's no reason to be professional about it.
Rym: and that statement bothered me a lot.
Scott: that would bother me as well a great deal.
Rym: You see all professionalism means without getting into specifics is handling yourself in a generally intelligent receptive Responsible manner respectful.
Rym: Yes, that's it.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: respectable and respectful.
Rym: It goes both ways mostly the respectable.
Rym: So to use you know the anime examples since we always tend to fall back on anime.
Rym: It seems to be one of our primary geekeries now.
Rym: We devote a whole night to it.
Rym: Panels at cons a Professional panel or a panel that is run in a professional manner is a good panel I'd say our panel, but I'll go with the OC remixes panel as an example.
Scott: No, they were very professional with their panel now.
Rym: What does that mean?
Rym: They came in they had a plan.
Rym: they had all their stuff ready to go.
Rym: They knew what they were gonna talk about that all their props ready.
Rym: everyone involved in the panel knew their role.
Rym: They started on time or as on time as you could start.
Rym: They finished on time and they put together a well-run presentation.
Rym: They handled all eventualities in a professional manner.
Scott: yeah while they are not professionals They are not an actual you know.
Scott: whereas say the ATV panel those people are professionals.
Scott: you know they do things in a professional way because They have their company.
Scott: think that's the way they do things.
Scott: if you do things in that way whether you're actually Quote professionals or not you know in the paid fashion you are doing things in a good way.
Scott: There's a reason that professionals do things that way.
Scott: It's not because you know well all of a sudden when there's money and companies involved you have to do things a certain way.
Scott: But really you shouldn't do it that way.
Scott: you know That's just the way you have to do it.
Scott: if you're being paid money now That's the way you're supposed to do things and doing it the other way is because you suck.
Rym: So let's take an example from what was a really bad panel at Otakon.
Rym: there was that old-school anime panel.
Scott: I did did I go to that one.
Rym: Yeah, we went to it, and we bitched about it, and then we left.
Scott: That was in a transfer.
Scott: Oh wasn't that Transformers panel Was panel before the old?
Scott: I don't even remember whatever.
Scott: you know.
Scott: it was the one with space ghost.
Rym: yes Yes, the crap panel now.
Rym: This was a panel with four dudes.
Rym: Maybe there's a girl there.
Rym: But these people didn't have a plan.
Rym: they didn't have any sort of preparation.
Rym: they started late They went long they floundered they obviously had not actually thought this through at all and as a result They put together a piss-poor presentation.
Scott: yet They came up there.
Scott: all right this guy You know did his space ghost joke for like a few minutes and everyone I was just rolling my eyes.
Scott: And then they sat up there, and they were like hey guys.
Scott: Yeah, we're supposed to do What old-school anime panel or something yeah?
Scott: We're just four guys up here saying stuff.
Scott: we put together this short video.
Scott: that was the only preparation we did.
Scott: let's watch it.
Scott: and If people scream when they see their favorite anime on this on the you know the video as is done at anime conventions Yeah, or any.
Scott: and then when it was over You know they just let people in the crowd yell out questions, and then they just kind of answered him in their haphazard Dorky way.
Scott: and then when their time was eventually up they were shoved out.
Scott: and that was it.
Rym: yep I mean professionalism like we said it just comes down to not being dumb and planning ahead and Trying.
Scott: yeah, you don't try you will suck.
Rym: now the scary thing is I you know I've worked for IBM, and I've worked for the company I work for now, and I work for mostly very large companies.
Rym: And you'd think you know corporate America big business the big iron the real deal that everyone in an Organization like that who is an actual you know really like.
Rym: not like the janitors and all that But the actual like the meat and potatoes and the managers and the executives.
Rym: managers the executives the technologists the Researchers the scientists all the people who do the things that make that company work.
Rym: you'd think you'd assume that they would all conduct themselves in a professional manner.
Rym: and I have found in my years of working for various corporations and being in corporate America that by and large Very few people have the sheer ability to put forth even the facade of professionalism.
Scott: Yeah something that always bothers me.
Scott: I think it really stands out in corporate like in the company email.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the company always send an email to anyone in my company right whether it's you know like the closest co-worker I just have to tell them you know hi How you doing, or what's the status of something even if it's real short?
Scott: I write you know dear so-and-so.
Scott: Yeah, thanks me You know I write it like it's a letter and I write check it for spelling and I put more than there.
Scott: I don't just shoot off a quick email in ten seconds.
Scott: I just can't bring myself to do that.
Scott: I have to check it.
Scott: the grammar has to be right.
Scott: I have to write out the entire words I have to put a little heading and a signature and the salutation and everything.
Scott: yep That's the way it has to be done.
Rym: Yep, now.
Rym: I mean depending if I'm I mean I can send a quick email in my private life to Scott.
Scott: Yeah, there's no problem with that now.
Rym: and I but like GeekNights stuff, too If I respond to any email especially in a corporation I do the same thing as Scott.
Rym: you know my email is basically as far as I'm concerned a corporate memo Fully exemplifying everything that I am as a professional.
Rym: it reflects on me Just like I wouldn't wear a pair of black sweatpants and a stained Coffee shirt to a job interview or to a meeting with a client.
Rym: I'm not gonna put that persona In my corporate communications.
Scott: It's like if someone sent me an email like okay.
Scott: Thanks.
Scott: Bye.
Scott: Oh my god Right you did that work for me.
Scott: I would say I would not respect that person.
Scott: I think wow that person is a doofus.
Rym: that person obviously is not a professional.
Scott: yes So I wouldn't want anyone else to think of me in that way that I'm thinking.
Scott: you know I not in a corporate environment most of the time I don't give a shit what people think about me But when I want something from someone or if it's a person at a company And I'm dealing with them in a professional manner And I need to get an upper hand in some dealings.
Scott: Then I need to make them think that I'm professional and to look upon me You know to look up at me instead of down and therefore it is beneficial to write things in professional manner.
Rym: in fact That seems to be pretty much the most overall important thing of being professional.
Rym: a professionalism really just entails not taking things personally.
Rym: It's like you have your personal self.
Rym: You're you.
Scott: you're the real you and the real me is like whatever dude fuck you.
Rym: Yeah, but when you're being professional It's like a court etiquette.
Rym: when you're in front of the king or whatever you're doing you put forth not so much a lie It's not like a fake mask.
Rym: It's just I am putting forth this persona.
Rym: That is my professional persona because I am trying to conduct business with you in the most efficient manner possible.
Rym: I want you to think highly of me, and I hope that I will think highly of you.
Rym: I'm putting forth the effort that I would expect you to put forth on whatever work You're doing for me and vice-versa.
Scott: Yeah, what I'm acting professional obviously that's not my true inner self But I don't really think of it as lying because I do think that some forms of pretending to be someone else are lying.
Scott: but When you're acting professional you're not going up to someone and saying haha.
Scott: I'm not actually a doofus.
Scott: I'm a professional guy.
Scott: That's not what you're doing.
Scott: what you're saying is look I might.
Scott: you know my true attitude might be completely different from what you're seeing now But I have the ability and the intelligence to act in a manner that is presentable and respectful and therefore I am worthy of respect no matter what my true opinions and ideals and attitude are.
Rym: see you can conduct yourself in a professional Manner and still totally suck.
Rym: that is nothing to do with it, but true.
Rym: But if someone is unable now unwilling is another thing.
Rym: But if someone is unable to put forth that persona if someone is unable to check I mean if you misplace a preposition in an email that even a professional email That's not the biggest deal, but if you forget to capitalize the letter I multiple times in order
Scott: to say What's what's your favorite?
Scott: Please advice please advice with an s?
Rym: ah or even please advise But they use it in the entirely wrong.
Rym: what just anything like that?
Rym: obviously it shows that While you are dealing with me in a professional manner you are not willing to put forth the trivial effort required to be professional about it.
Rym: Now if you're not willing to do that.
Rym: What else are you not willing to do for me?
Rym: Where what else are you going to fuck up?
Scott: It's a. it's a wonder like so many people like.
Scott: they want things and They don't get them and they wonder why.
Scott: and the answer a lot of times is you didn't you're not professional You're not acting like a professional.
Scott: You know it's sort of like.
Scott: you know is the old saying like if you act like You know you're worth a million bucks, then eventually you'll have a million bucks.
Scott: Yeah, that's not so true, but there's something to it.
Scott: You know if you go up.
Scott: You know to say a Rock star or someone you want them to give you an autograph.
Scott: if you just go You're just a raving fan, and they don't care, but if you go up and they go hi.
Scott: How are you doing?
Scott: My name is blah blah blah such-and-such you know and you act professional you can get their attention and get shit You want because you don't you stick out, and you're not a doofus.
Scott: You're obviously Somewhat intelligent because you can do that.
Rym: yeah, I mean we get into most cons.
Rym: We go to now free and we do all this stuff.
Rym: I mean I remember there's another podcast that I'm not going to mention because I don't like this podcast.
Rym: But they were complaining last year that basically yeah, Otakon didn't give us a panel, but meanwhile us GeekNights We got a panel like that like hey Podcasting panel.
Rym: they said go nuts Yep, and it really comes down to the only reason we get all these things.
Rym: aside from our vastly superior skill talent Intellect charisma and the fact that we are gods among men.
Scott: yeah walking up We can't demonstrate any of those amazing things to the people that we want to give us a panel.
Scott: They don't know that we're geniuses, and we can't convince them Right.
Scott: the only way for us to get a pet them to give us a panel is By acting like pros and pretending to be pros.
Rym: I mean working staff and stuff for various kinds.
Rym: I've seen the kind of proposals that Cons get for panels and they usually along the lines of One giant paragraph.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I want to run a panel about Blah blah and it'll be awesome, and I need some people to help me with it.
Rym: and and and crap.
Rym: There's just this crap like barely legible barely understandable raving of a fan.
Scott: They put less effort into it than they put into like an instant message.
Rym: and yet when we send a proposal like I sent our Proposals this year for what we want to do at Otakon to the panels coordinator I wrote a three-page document describing in exact detail The panels were willing to do and all that they will entail The other things we'd be willing to do if they asked that we could provide more detail upon Everything we need everything we would provide and then an entire resume of all the things we've done in the past all the things we Plan to do the things we're doing this year.
Rym: I sent links to recordings of panels that are similar that we've done in the past.
Rym: Oh Yeah, and when it I guess that's what real I mean everything we do.
Rym: it sounds silly but everything we do if it's worth doing It's worth doing professionally.
Rym: if we write if we decide that we're going to go to Greece We're actually thinking about going to Greece.
Rym: You know how everyone knows we're gay.
Rym: Yeah sometime like maybe in the fall We're not sure when.
Rym: we're just kind of a long-term plan to go on a big vacation to the whole Greco-Roman area Mm-hmm, and you would not believe the absolute level of planning that we're going to put into this.
Rym: if we actually do it Yeah, we put that same level of planning into what we're going to eat for dinner or when we're going to go to the mall.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Now we might not plan it ahead.
Rym: We might plan things at the spur of the moment.
Rym: I mean, it's not like we regiment our lives out say we're at a con and we decide hey, we're gonna do blah We just do it.
Rym: But while we're doing it the whole time, we're planning we're planning ahead.
Rym: We're coming up with contingency plans.
Rym: We're handling it in a professional manner.
Rym: So I guess if you want to get the things you want in the world Whenever you think something's worth getting.
Rym: if you actually want something Try to approach it in a professional manner meaning in all of your communications Be careful about what you say, you know, actually look at what you wrote for more than a second spell check it Make sure it's got at least decent grammar.
Rym: Make sure it gets the point across.
Scott: when you talk to people, you know Present yourself stand up straight walk up to them, you know, shake their hand, you know say things like hi I'm so-and-so and then you know, give them a professional pitch.
Scott: don't use words like like like, you know like like man I'm totally gonna do this shit for you.
Rym: I got it.
Rym: shit man shit.
Scott: Yeah, I was wondering if I could do this panel for you.
Scott: I have X You know credentials such-and-such.
Scott: Here's my business card.
Rym: if someone sends you communication Actually read it and respond in kind with the information.
Rym: They actually asked for.
Rym: you know, how often promptly See, this is the worst thing in all my jobs.
Rym: it seems like most people in the corporate where I get these garbage emails from people and they don't even ask me for anything and Then a month later, they're like, hey do that thing and I'm like what thing?
Rym: Oh the thing I asked you to do and I say well when did you ask me to do that?
Rym: Oh in this email and I quote the email back at him usually copying their manager where in this email Did you ask me for anything?
Rym: And the saddest thing is that I got a manager who's actually really smart in my current company and I usually copy him on stuff And he actually sent me a reply back kind of BCC saying that was a really good memo And I didn't know what to say to that.
Rym: I mean at one point.
Scott: it was like a really good memo.
Scott: every memo should be like that.
Scott: And if I was a boss of a company and every memo what?
Scott: if you said one unprofessional memo?
Scott: You would be out the door on your ass so fast.
Rym: Well first I'd sit you down and ask so what why did you send?
Scott: Oh, yeah, I'd make sure to humiliate you before I put you out on the curb.
Rym: I did that once at IBM.
Rym: I just I was dealing with this guy, and he was a total.
Rym: the guy wasn't the brightest guy And he was in this other department and everyone in my department knew that he was not the best guy.
Rym: Eventually he sends me this terrible long correspondence.
Rym: It looked like a fifth grader wrote it so I responded you know with the exact same request for information that I had made I don't know 10 or 11 times in the past and you know I copied in the email all the times I had asked and all the answers he'd given that didn't answer it and Furthermore I corrected all of the spelling or grammar in his emails to me in my reply.
Rym: Yeah, I left IBM not too long after that.
Rym: I never really found I don't think he even noticed.
Rym: to be perfectly honest.
Scott: no I think there's another component to acting professionally that we haven't touched on and that is Confidence.
Scott: like I went to a job interview.
Scott: You know I quit my job today, and I have a new job already.
Scott: when I went to the job interview You know back in the day when I went to job interviews I was you know just like a nervous kid whatever like oh god am I gonna get hired?
Scott: Went to this job interview, and I conducted myself in a professional manager manner Mr.. Manager yes with no nervousness at all.
Scott: I was just you know hey hello.
Scott: How are you?
Scott: Yes, that would be terrific Etc etc.
Scott: and I got the job without any like that day.
Scott: They're like yes, you have the job and It's why?
Scott: because I was incredibly confident, and I was just like yeah, you're gonna hire me.
Scott: That's right That's what you're gonna.
Scott: Do because I mean look how smooth I am that's right.
Scott: I mean you know if you don't have that frame of mind then even if you try to act professionally You're gonna be kind of slow and off the mark and it'll come off as like What's wrong with this guy?
Scott: It has to be so natural.
Scott: It's really you know there's something to it.
Rym: Yep, I mean if you don't have the confidence in yourself to do something Why would you ever expect other people to have confidence in you to do that thing?
Rym: And on that note I guess we're done.
Rym: Stay tuned next week when we'll have a short week as we're going to Katsucon to in a professional manner help run the video game room.
Rym: oh one last thing professionalism Honesty yeah, I mean if someone that's probably the biggest thing.
Rym: if you make a mistake At a job like say you mess something up Most people kind of try to hide it or try to pass off the blame.
Rym: You've got to just be upfront.
Rym: be like as soon as you realize you made a mistake you send the memo out to whoever Cares saying the following mistake was made by me.
Rym: Here's what I will do to rectify it.
Scott: Is there anyone that we can think of like a public figure who is just ridiculously professional ah?
Rym: Well, we don't know a lot about their personal communication.
Rym: I mean Elliot spitzer acts professionally, but I don't know how he acts internally.
Scott: I want to have like a. what would so-and-so do?
Rym: what would Barack Obama do if you were here?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: He'd probably smile with his gigantic teeth.
Scott: God that man You know if he ever gets like more popular.
Scott: they start making political cartoons with him his teeth and those things are just gonna be Like so huge.
Rym: yeah, the thing is the political cartoonists will be it because they want to caricature him And that's the obvious caricature, but they don't want to appear racist.
Scott: Yeah, it does big teeth.
Scott: I know, but it does nothing to do with race I know, but it'll be a fine line.
Rym: And I think a lot of political cartoonists are gonna try Teddy Roosevelt with big teeth also.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, all right That's off-topic.
Scott: I think we're done.
Rym: But yeah be Professional in all you do or at least all you do that you care about and that you want other people to care about.
Rym: you Can do things unprofessionally.
Rym: just don't expect other people to respect those things or care about those things or ask you to ever do them For them.
Scott: again, yeah, and when you're posting on our forums keep that in mind.
Rym: yeah, mr.. Period has been busy lately.
Rym: I really know what he's been up to but Even if he isn't that active we'll get another moderator to fix some of you people who haven't been so professional lately.
Rym: yes
Scott: I'm letting you know we're letting some of you off the hook because We're letting some of you off the hook because you know you're from foreign countries And your English might not be your first language,
Rym: and that's understandable, but a lot of you We know that you spoke English first.
Rym: We know that you can spell words.
Rym: Yes, well least we hope.
Scott: well.
Scott: spelling isn't the problem.
Scott: now that this spell checker and Firefox do as a spell checker It's mostly.
Scott: you know things like run-on sentences Yeah, or not?
Rym: putting line breaks between large blocks of text yeah, all right, whatever.
Scott: We're done.
Scott: Yep Three times we're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various random And tomfoolery.
Scott: you can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row.
Scott: crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.