Scott: It's Monday February 5th, I'm Scott and I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we discuss the IT professionals toolbox.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: You know, we were actually somewhat productive this weekend.
Scott: We were productive this weekend, but now I'm all.
Rym: How come we got plenty of sleep?
Rym: Well, you got plenty of sleep last night.
Scott: I stayed up playing civilization - again I did but I ate very off schedule today, which kind of messed me up.
Scott: And also I you know, I got this tough job switching situation Trouble to go through.
Scott: as soon as that's all over.
Scott: I'll be all set.
Rym: Uh-huh Mm-hmm.
Rym: Yeah, but we did a lot of work on the DVD which will be coming out sooner than you might expect But not as soon as you might hope.
Rym: Yeah, more importantly.
Rym: We also finally have decided to make some promo CDs Which you'll only be able to get if you come to katsu-kan.
Scott: Yes, there'll be katsu-kan exclusive promotional CDs So if you come to katsu-kan you get one.
Scott: if you don't come to katsu-kan, you don't get one.
Rym: Well, they are technically exclusive.
Rym: That is correct.
Rym: It is not a lie.
Scott: And we're gonna do that at every convention for now on probably.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it doesn't take as much effort Basically, we just record an opening bit and then we stick a random episode of GeekNights on after it And then we got to burn a whole mess of CDs.
Rym: Yes, and let's take stock of the burners we have in this house.
Rym: We have my plex tor 820 scuzzy from before CD RW's were commonly available.
Rym: That doesn't even work properly anymore.
Scott: It's so useless.
Scott: It effectively doesn't count.
Rym: I can't make it work in Linux.
Rym: that scuzzy card is just too busted and old.
Scott: I met you could it just be hard?
Scott: It wouldn't be worth it.
Rym: I couldn't.
Rym: with the token effort.
Rym: I was willing to put forth.
Scott: I said wouldn't be easy.
Scott: We've got a plex tor 8 for 32, which is my first burner.
Scott: I paid $150 for it in 1999 or 2000.
Scott: I forget probably 99 and Yeah It's it's not in a computer.
Scott: I've got it.
Scott: See I got this thing I bought which is pretty handy.
Scott: We're actually gonna talk about this today in our in our episode.
Scott: It allows you to take any IDE drive that you have be it a CD ROM or a hard drive or anything and Turn it into a USB drive.
Scott: So we have the CD burner attached to a $20 crap computer With this device and it's effectively an external CD ROM.
Rym: after we finish the show I'm going to attempt to actually burn something over this link.
Rym: I imagine it'll work.
Rym: It did.
Scott: I tested it yesterday.
Scott: It worked.
Rym: Yeah, well, we'll see if it works on the $20 motherboard.
Scott: That's a good question.
Scott: I did test it with a Windows and Nero.
Rym: see normally I wouldn't be Larry at all.
Rym: I mean a motherboards a motherboard but this goddamn motherboard 20 bucks to get what you pay for you got exactly that.
Scott: it works.
Rym: We're lucky it works.
Rym: It didn't work at first.
Scott: anyone out there who's poor in the poor house and you are willing to suffer with a computer that kind of works.
Scott: $20 motherboards the way to go All right.
Scott: What else?
Scott: Oh, I've got a burner in my computer.
Scott: That's a very.
Scott: it's a relatively new Plex store.
Scott: The thing is I bought it and I was like who is my first DVD burner, but I never had to burn a DVD with it.
Scott: I just bought a DVD burner and I burned many CDs with it and work just fine.
Scott: and about many months after buying it I tried to burn a DVD and it didn't work.
Scott: It's the only unreliable Plex store.
Scott: I've ever seen in my entire life And I could that flex stores have a really good warranty.
Scott: I'm just too lazy to send it in to get it fixed.
Scott: So it's just a CD burner.
Rym: Last and least we bought a brand new light scribe DVD drive to make people a $30 light on CD-burner and it works amazingly.
Scott: Yeah compared to the hundreds of dollars.
Scott: I paid for that flex store That doesn't work.
Rym: The thing is.
Rym: back in the day a Plex store was the gold standard.
Rym: I mean you guys might not remember kinda is.
Rym: it doesn't matter anymore at all.
Scott: It doesn't matter though I wouldn't buy one anymore.
Rym: So it's not really the gold standard because silver works just fine.
Rym: So don't even bother.
Scott: if I was a super professional I would buy one.
Rym: I wouldn't there's no reason to uh.
Rym: But yeah back in the day way back For some of you might be too young to remember that CD burners didn't work.
Scott: Yeah, you would buy a burner and the more money you spent the less often it would screw up.
Scott: It's like you would buy a $50 burner All right But oh it's only gonna actually work 30% of the time.
Rym: you'd have to decide based on how much CDs cost and how much your time is worth how expensive a burner You're going to buy and how many?
Rym: Coasters were willing to put up with and the thing was the only burner that could work all the time Was the Plex store and the Plex store cost a lot more money than anything else.
Scott: That's why I paid a total of probably more than three hundred dollars for two Plex stores and Rym has one, too Yep.
Rym: And I went above and beyond because I decided I would like to be able to burn things while I do other things on my computer Which back then you really couldn't do even with a Plex store.
Rym: if your computer didn't have a lot of RAM Which most computers didn't you couldn't play quake?
Rym: You couldn't have more than one or two ie windows open.
Rym: It would just mess up your CD or with the Plex store would be all fancy and slow down the burn so it wouldn't mess Up.
Scott: Yeah, it depends on which Plex store you had.
Scott: They added more technology to them over the years.
Rym: So I being a fancy lad who knew a little bit of our computers a little bit I decided that scuzzy was the way to go.
Rym: So I got a scuzzy card and a scuzzy burner and let me tell you I could burn CDs at 8x While I played quake.
Scott: that was good.
Rym: I was very pleased with that.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, oh well nowadays it doesn't matter just get a burner for 30 bucks.
Scott: they all work perfectly.
Scott: they burn everything.
Scott: It's like dual layer is not even a big deal anymore.
Scott: You just burn whatever you want.
Scott: the big deal in the future is gonna be the HD DVD and the blu-ray burners Which I don't really care so much.
Scott: Well, I'd like one read them even if you make them.
Rym: I'd really like to have something like that just to back up GeekNights considering.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I agree Considering that GeekNights won't fit on anything.
Rym: We have other than a hard drive or a veritable pile of DVDs.
Scott: Yes, however Distributing I mean if we distributed data blu-ray discs or data HD HD DVD discs.
Scott: No one could use them.
Scott: That's why we have to put out a DVD set.
Rym: Yeah, but internally if I could buy for a reasonable price an HD DVD or a blu-ray burner I probably would.
Scott: yeah that the price is gonna go down.
Scott: I'm gonna start looking into it.
Scott: Here's the problem.
Scott: in six to twelve months.
Scott: You'll be able to get them for less than $200, but here's the problem.
Rym: There are other formats on the horizon already that are so much better.
Rym: There's really no real like the technology is moving so fast that Moving to blu-ray and HD DVD doesn't seem like it even really matters because the next generation is gonna be even better.
Scott: also, you always have to count in the Price of you know getting a NAS with a raid 5 and a whole bunch of hard drives or something like that.
Rym: Yeah, those aren't always the best option because those let you have live backups But they don't really let you unless you really want to be fancy have the you know Definitive back.
Rym: You know more for enterprise stuff than us.
Rym: But say you want to back up a file regularly as opposed to just having a backup of the most current file.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, I know what you're saying.
Rym: All right.
Rym: It's not a thing.
Rym: Most people care about Nope in the news now.
Rym: This shouldn't really be news to anyone out there, but the AP wire had a story I'm looking to it on the Guardian, but it doesn't really matter.
Rym: No one's writing checks anymore.
Scott: Oh Gee, that's a big surprise.
Scott: I haven't written a check.
Scott: I don't write checks other than for rent.
Scott: Oh, we gotta pay rent.
Rym: You have to pay rent.
Scott: Oh, it's the fifth.
Scott: I'll pay it.
Rym: Yeah, okay, but no checks really aren't being used anymore.
Rym: Checks are being used primarily by very old people The primary uses of checks now seem to be nothing more than paying a few utilities.
Rym: But even then a lot of people are doing it online or through their bank or through other services.
Scott: I pay absolutely every bill and do all of my money management via ATMs the Internet and the only thing I have to do with the check is rent.
Scott: nothing else requires a check.
Rym: Well even better most people old people especially who use checks on a regular basis for you know Grocery store transactions and whatnot are paying their bills don't seem to realize that checks don't really float anymore And they're not processed mechanically anymore.
Rym: Usually they're converted into an electronic format and then build just like a direct checking thing.
Rym: Yep, and this is really starting to screw a lot of old people who are used to the fact that if you write a check It won't actually hit your account for another several days, so you can kind of float money and live on the edge.
Scott: Yeah, I never even thought about that.
Scott: You know I've always got actually been kind of pissed when I used to write checks way back in the day before I had you Know any other possible way of paying for certain things like I would buy stuff on the internet And then mail a check and then get the stuff.
Rym: Wow see luckily my was a long time.
Scott: My parents got me a credit card when I was 16, so I've just pretty much always had a credit card Yeah, but no when I used to do that I was kind of pissed that it took so long like I wanted.
Scott: the second that you know the check was brought to the bank.
Scott: I wanted that to be registered so I could go online and see that the money was taken out.
Scott: And if it took three days, I was kind of pissed.
Scott: so the fact that it's quicker now is better for me.
Rym: Yeah, I definitely never floated checks usually because I didn't want to risk it.
Rym: I mean I had a bank that if you overdrafted they gave you like a $40 per day fee.
Scott: Oh Yeah, yeah, I just think checks are kind of silly and outdated, and we should stop using them all together.
Rym: well No, they're still used for a lot of things.
Rym: I mean large purchases are often done with cashiers checks.
Scott: I'm talking about personal checks only obviously cashiers checks and money orders and all those sorts of personal checks.
Scott: Oh, you don't have a place a lot for charity donations.
Rym: If you give money to a charity you want to give it in a verifiable way And checks are the easiest and best way to do that.
Rym: plus most charities aren't equipped to take credit cards Then your charity sucks.
Rym: Well.
Scott: No because the charity can take PayPal or something.
Rym: No, because PayPal and credit cards have one major thing in common.
Rym: They skim off the top.
Scott: that is true.
Scott: However, I think there really needs to be some sort of law that says if someone is a legitimate charity that you can't skim off The top when they take credit card donations and such because that's actually a pretty annoying problem.
Scott: a charity will get like $10,000 of donations from people and only get like $8,000 because the credit card company charges of money, and it's really annoying.
Rym: yeah Maybe some credit card companies do that or maybe there's some loopholes We don't know about.
Rym: maybe there's.
Scott: all I'm saying is if it's not true It should be true.
Scott: No If I donate five dollars to a charity with a credit card on PayPal The charity should get the entirety of that five dollars and PayPal and the credit card company get nothing.
Rym: now what I what I actually Get from this news is that it must be a slow news day because the AP wire is running this and this article doesn't really have Anything of note in it.
Scott: I mean everything I said like a recent occurrence to trigger this news not something that's old.
Scott: It's usually.
Scott: that's what happened.
Rym: No nothing's happened.
Rym: in fact a lot of the data in this article is from 2003 Oh, but the article was posted today.
Rym: You've said oh, I like ten times today.
Scott: Yeah, I guess cuz my stomach is I?
Scott: Okay, okay, I told you I ate lunch when I got home from work at 4 and then ate I don't know my stomach hurts.
Rym: They don't say oh, I say it doesn't hurt.
Scott: It's just kind of.
Rym: I'm not saying that you're saying stuff, but I'm pointing out specifically that you're saying.
Rym: Oh, hey.
Scott: Oh, hey, oh What the dyslexic rabbi say?
Rym: what did he say?
Scott: yo?
Rym: All right, but yeah this article.
Rym: the only interesting thing here, and it surprises me Immensely that apparently the part of the government that handles processing checks on a national level you know through the Federal Reserve and all that is cutting back on all of the Offices that do that.
Scott: wait a minute.
Scott: Did you just say a government agency is cutting back the government?
Scott: Someone's here at the door.
Scott: Let me go see who it is.
Rym: Alright, whatever.
Rym: You're doing is lame.
Scott: Just made sure it's Satan.
Scott: He needs a he needs a winter coat.
Rym: Yeah, that was really late.
Rym: is that that was absolutely?
Rym: oh my god you say.
Rym: But yeah, the government is actually shutting down a lot of these processing centers and by 2008 18 of the 45 that exists now Will remain Awesome, well, maybe even though You know the credit cards are skimming off the top.
Scott: Maybe I'll get some tax money back is not Because I'm not paying for all those people that handle all these checks.
Rym: I have a feeling that for every dollar We're saving from this there's something going on in certain parts of sand coated areas of the world that might be preventing us from getting Any money back.
Scott: yeah, that's you know surprisingly.
Scott: That's not the biggest money sink, but it is pretty sucky.
Rym: Well, it is because a lot of those graphs you look at and you point out a lot about you know Oh look how much Social Security and all those take.
Scott: yeah, well those Social Security is sort of outside of the budget.
Rym: It's a different thing entirely yeah, but those graphs aren't the best.
Scott: no It's still because the problem is no one really knows because the budget is just so big and complicated.
Scott: I mean didn't like Bush just submit a budget to Congress that was like well No, it's not point.
Scott: six trillion dollars people know very much.
Rym: It's just the issue of it's very easy to make a graph Regarding the budget and percentages or gross amounts to prove whatever you want to prove about the government being efficient or inefficient or whatever.
Scott: Yep, that's true all right.
Scott: so my news.
Scott: You know the electric slide.
Rym: Yeah, it's a generally mediocre dance Dance move.
Rym: from before I was cognizant of the fact that dancing existed in the world.
Scott: you gotta be It's electric.
Rym: I remember in fifth grade our teacher for whatever reason taught us the hustle the electric slide and Something else and that's good for you.
Scott: in second grade.
Scott: They taught a square dancing even better.
Rym: I remember it science Olympiad at the regional tournament right.
Rym: they taught us this dance.
Rym: They called it the Mexican hustle, and you know we all thought it was cool.
Rym: We all did it and years and years later that Macarena Craze that went across the United States part of that craze were you?
Scott: yes I was.
Scott: I have a Macarena mix CD.
Scott: It has like 16 Macarena's.
Rym: No, I vaguely remember you telling me that I think I'd blocked it out of my mind like in Phoenix right with those chains.
Scott: I got it for free from Columbia's.
Scott: I didn't pay for it.
Rym: Did you choose it however?
Rym: Yes, no no I gotta ask because For this one case despite the fact that I'm a geek.
Rym: I think I was ahead of the pop-culture curve.
Rym: I learned the Macarena.
Rym: did the Macarena love the Macarena got sick of the Macarena and decided it was stupid before the Macarena even existed.
Scott: and It hit me like I got in right at the beginning like a week before it was on the television, and then I got out two months later.
Scott: The thing is that was the period of my life like I was around 13 years old.
Scott: ish All right, so they're like a million bar mitzvahs to go to and you danced it at every single one.
Rym: I see there's nothing like that in white bread suburban culture.
Rym: The only time I ever went dancing is when some friend of the family got married.
Scott: Okay, so anyway the electric slide.
Scott: some guy Kyle Matulius right whatever he's a. he's an engineer at Linden lab.
Scott: Oh, maybe he's an engineer at Second Life.
Scott: Anyway, he received a DMCA takedown notice about a video Daddy shot at a convention showing three people doing the electric slide.
Scott: apparently some guy copyrighted the electric slide and He's sending DMCA takedown notices to every person on YouTube with the electric.
Scott: wait a minute now.
Rym: specifically he copyrighted it.
Rym: It says copyright not patent.
Scott: yep You can copyright the choreography for dances and then enforce the copyright against anyone who publicly publicly performs the dance.
Scott: So says Jason Schultz attorney for the EFF.
Rym: What I would point out to the world in this issue here Is that according to copyright statute unless it's different specifically for choreography?
Rym: Once you create something or do something it's automatically copyrighted.
Scott: Yeah, and other radically is illegal to move.
Scott: I could interpret no because that would have expired already.
Scott: Okay
Rym: However, it is illegal to do what I'm doing right now because I know no one has ever done this before In the exact way that I'm doing it and if anyone does this I'm suing your ass
Scott: Yeah, and the other thing is this guy also made some complaints about people doing the dance poorly.
Scott: Well, if they're doing it poorly, they're not doing it the exact same way that you've copyrighted doing Yeah, that's a slightly modified it.
Scott: Well, no because they're not allowed to remix the dance.
Scott: But if you do that, how do you know that jumping up and down and just you know?
Scott: Waving your hand isn't a remix of the electric.
Rym: are you sure this isn't some sort of fake news?
Scott: This is definitely a real news.
Scott: It's on CNET and it's from a staff writer at CNET.
Scott: Wow, and a lot of people are even sued some daytime talk show the Ellen DeGeneres show.
Rym: Did he win?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: He's trying.
Scott: he's basically saying wait a minute.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: Has he won a single lawsuit?
Scott: No, all he's doing is sending DMCA takedown notices, right?
Rym: Oh, that's nothing.
Rym: Yeah, I mean as far as I'm concerned There's so many stories on FARC, you know Someone's suing someone over blah and the fact of the matter is you can sue anyone for anything at any time.
Rym: The real question is is he going to win?
Rym: and I don't know but I'm gonna bet.
Rym: no.
Scott: Anyway, he's sending out the DMCA takedown notices and we'll see what comes of that.
Scott: You know, it's it's nothing.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is you can copyright a dance, which is kind of interesting.
Scott: I didn't realize you could do that.
Rym: Well, we'd better copyright the dance that we do for the mamalayo.
Scott: Maybe we should yeah, and then anyone who puts videos of it on YouTube is gonna get fun Unless the original creator of the dance finds out.
Scott: Yeah The thing that bothers me is it says here Richard silver filed the copyright for electric slide in 2004. the electric slide was created in 76.
Scott: What the hell?
Rym: Huh?
Rym: Something doesn't add up.
Scott: How does that work?
Rym: I got a question.
Rym: How old is this guy?
Rym: I have no idea because if he didn't create it and he just filed the copyright Then it's bullshit.
Scott: Supposedly.
Scott: He's the creator.
Scott: That's what it Supposedly and I mean the only place I've seen it actually say he was the creator.
Scott: It said the quote creator of the electric slide.
Rym: Let's try to track him down and talk to him.
Scott: All right, it's all you go for it.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I think it'll be hilarious.
Rym: I'd like to talk to this guy if nothing else.
Rym: I wish the internet would send him DVD upon DVD of videos of themselves doing the electric slide and or other dances.
Scott: We should Do the electric slide like everywhere instead of walking.
Rym: that might be a little difficult.
Rym: I mean we used to skip all over the place.
Scott: I actually kind of forget how to do the electric slide.
Scott: I mean, I remember some parts.
Scott: you slide clap and turn to the side Alright, whatever.
Rym: I remember the Macarena better.
Scott: Yeah, I do God You know, it's.
Scott: I think it's time for a new dance craze, yeah, you know what the the hurry.
Scott: That's a Japanese dance craze.
Scott: I think it's time for another American dance.
Rym: I don't think it can happen anymore.
Rym: I mean most dance clubs these days tend to play like house crap at least the ones around here.
Scott: No, the thing is the dance craze is like the Macarena.
Scott: We're never in clubs.
Scott: It's all about weddings and bar mitzvahs.
Rym: Yeah, you know what like that?
Rym: weddings and bar mitzvahs?
Rym: now don't see.
Rym: I mean the last wedding I went to the only silly dance.
Rym: They did it all other than you know, the hustle which gets played ever.
Scott: We got the chicken dance.
Scott: We got the hustle we get the like.
Scott: here's the slide.
Scott: We got the Macarena.
Scott: We got that cotton.
Rym: Here's the thing they did cotton-eyed Joe right?
Rym: I remember this.
Rym: at the last two weddings I went to.
Rym: No one knew how to actually dance it.
Rym: They just danced.
Rym: Ah played the hustle.
Rym: No one knew how to do the hustle.
Rym: My mom knows how to do the but no one at this wedding did the.
Scott: I've always wanted to learn how to do the hustle But I learned it when I was a kid.
Scott: I know I keep forgetting.
Rym: I remember about half of it.
Scott: We should get a video that tells us how to do it.
Rym: I'm sure there is one probably on YouTube probably violating the copyright of the guy who created it.
Rym: Ooh Yeah, all right, yeah you people out there wonder why we're always so pissed off about copyright laws because things like this happen.
Rym: I mean, it's one thing to argue that artists should get credit for their work and compensation or whatever.
Rym: But when something like this happens, that's that's another straw on this camel's back.
Scott: Hamels backs been broken for a long time.
Rym: So I got new camel two humps Things of the day and I gotta say I'm throwing down when it comes to things of the day this week.
Scott: What are you throwing down?
Rym: Well, uh one thing led to another and I've decided that I have an interesting theme this week a theme that I don't think Scott will be able to top and I give Scott until next week to come up with a theme.
Scott: So we're gonna sort of had this dueling Theme.
Scott: thing of the day is for this week all of rims things of the day will have a theme and my things that they'll Be normal next week.
Scott: all my things today will have a theme.
Rym: see I was debating if I should make it a kind of thing Where I'll do the four things the day and then over the weekend.
Rym: people can guess what the theme was But I think I'm is so obvious.
Rym: Kinda the theme isn't quite as obvious as you'd think you might think.
Rym: it's obvious from day one.
Rym: Day two is probably gonna throw you for a loop day three is gonna bring you back around and day four You're probably gonna cry.
Rym: Okay, right now you see before way back We did a theme week on things of the day and it was hockey fight week.
Rym: That was well and good because there are more than eight hockey fights in the world.
Rym: But if we try to do any kind of unified thing today theme week We realized that now we have to find eight related things of the day that are all at least above the line.
Scott: Oh, it's not easy unless it's something, you know already existing.
Rym: So thus I'll tell you the story of how I came upon this because I've come upon it twice.
Scott: I was watching I think Random Family Guy episodes and clips on YouTube and YouTube has that handy feature when you're done watching a video It says hey check these out.
Rym: So I was just surfing through them by clicking on the recommendations and after Family Guy it eventually took me to a Spanish Family Guy.
Rym: Toma Toma Toma Toma Toma Toma Toma Toma Toma Toma Toma Toma Toma Toma Toma Toma Toma Toma.
Rym: And then in the bottom, right I see a picture of Hitler and I think Hitler a. How is this related?
Rym: So I click on it and It was the short version of my thing of the day and I thought it was Entrancing and hilarious.
Rym: Forgot about it, totally forgot about it, this was weeks ago.
Rym: Fast forward to this weekend.
Rym: I'm sitting around, I'm watching random space ghosts on YouTube.
Scott: Oi!
Rym: One thing leads to another, and I end up watching Monty Python instead.
Scott: Why would you watch Monty Python on YouTube when you have every DVD of it?
Rym: 'Cause it happened to be recommended to me, and it was a sketch I liked.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: And then I noticed that the recommended sketch is one of my favorite sketches, one that I've used at the thing of the day before, Mr.
Rym: Hiltter.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: Hiltter?
Rym: So I click on it, and sure enough, related to this video, was uh, the same video I had seen before, except this time it was the full version.
Scott: Oak snaps.
Rym: Thus, my thing of the day, and my theme, are one and the same.
Rym: They're Adolf Hitler, born to be alive.
Scott: I think that's all you gotta say about that.
Rym: I think that's all I have to say about that.
Rym: I'll warn you, this is one of those videos that if you watch it, one, the song is going to get stuck in your head.
Rym: Two, you're gonna get the video stuck in your head.
Rym: And three, you're really gonna start thinking about this video in weird--.
Rym: I mean, if you listen to this and watch it more than a few times, it's almost like you forget what Hitler really did, and you only remember him saying, "Born... born to be
Rym: alive.".
Scott: Yeah, we learned that this song was a one-hit wonder from before our time.
Scott: God, this is-- In case you're wondering.
Rym: This guy, Patrick Hernandez, did a bunch of disco music, I guess, and this is apparently the only song he ever did that anyone remembered.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: And someone decided to make a Hitler music video to it.
Scott: Why they chose this song, I don't know.
Scott: You could've made a Hitler video to all sorts of songs.
Rym: Why they chose Hitler, but though I gotta say, the voice acting-- Well, the voice sync between the guy, Patrick Hernandez, and Hitler is really well done, considering the quality of the footage.
Scott: It's about as well done as it could be, considering the circumstances.
Rym: I particularly like the use of horns.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's a good one.
Rym: And the use of Nazi youth.
Scott: Yeah, too much Nazi youth going on.
Rym: Alright, so now that my awesome thing of the day is out there, I can sit back and drink brandy.
Rym: What have you got?
Scott: Alright, well, there's a story on some dude's-- I guess it's his blog, I'm not sure, that made the rounds.
Scott: And it's pretty short, so I'm just gonna read the whole thing.
Scott: He says, "Well, my father heard about Vista coming on the
Scott: news.".
Scott: For anyone who doesn't know, Vista came out last week.
Scott: "Since he was interested in getting it, he asked me to obtain it and install it on his computer, and he would give some cash in return.
Scott: I told him I was gonna do that, but instead, I installed
Scott: Ubuntu."
Scott: Ubuntu!
Scott: "Later, when it came home from work, I showed him his new Vista install, complete with the latest office and Solitaire.
Scott: It's been a few days since that, and now he says Bill Gates is better than Steve Jobs and brags about how OS X on my iMac is obsolete compared to Vista on his
Scott: PC.".
Rym: So, when's this guy gonna let him in on the secret?
Scott: "I will continue with the prank for some weeks, after which, I'll tell him the truth and give him back his
Scott: money.".
Rym: Wow.
Rym: I don't know what to say other than, I don't think Microsoft's inherent old-school monopoly or the preference people seem to have for Windows is as strong as everyone thinks it is.
Scott: Well, I think it just shows the power of branding and, you know, ideas.
Scott: It's like people go, "Ah, a new
Scott: Windows!".
Scott: You know, they don't actually know about their computing or think about it.
Scott: And it just, you know, this is just circumstantial evidence here.
Scott: But I truly do believe that Linux is better for a lot of people if they would just accept it.
Scott: And if you, you know, the thing is, because you say to them, "You're gonna use Linux instead of Windows.
Scott: That's a change and they're afraid of it and they don't want to go for
Scott: it.".
Scott: But if there's no change for them to be afraid of and you give it to them, it is better for them.
Scott: They just don't know it.
Scott: And they'll like it if they would give it a try and be more open-minded and get rid of their misconceptions about what Linux is or, you know, lose their fear of the unknown and change.
Rym: Yeah, the only thing is, like some people, I'd love to give it to my parents, but they have a lot of old Windows weird proprietary programs that they really like to use and don't exist in Linux.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The other thing is my parents, they browse the web.
Scott: They browse the web.
Scott: They do email, instant messaging.
Scott: All that normal stuff that everyone does, email, web browsing, instant messaging, watching videos, photo management, all that sort of stuff.
Scott: Linux, perfect, no problems.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: Especially Ubuntu.
Scott: Ubuntu.
Scott: You know, what the hell.
Scott: This guy also has a funny Photoshop here of a Windows Vista Ultimate box, only he replaced the Windows logo with the Ubuntu logo.
Scott: It's kind of nice.
Scott: So yeah, if anyone out there is thinking about getting Vista, I tried it out for five seconds in the store, and it looked like Windows to me with a big bar on the side and some fancy graphics.
Rym: All right, a bar on the side, eh?
Scott: Yeah, you can put widgets in it and stuff.
Rym: I don't know about that.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure you could probably make it go away, but yeah, that's what Vista is.
Scott: And, you know, if XP is no longer supported and you're tired of it, before you try out Vista, you're going to erase your hard drive anyway.
Scott: Why not try Ubuntu first?
Scott: It won't hurt you.
Scott: It's free, free.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Right, so we're both computer professionals.
Rym: I'm an IT professional and Scott's a CS professional, and we carry around with us in various situations a number of tools of the trade.
Rym: I mean, if you see a plumber and he's going to do some plumbing, he brings plumber's equipment with him.
Rym: A carpenter brings carpenter's equipment.
Scott: So you might be asking, "You know, carpenter's got his hammer and nails, plumber's got his
Scott: wrench.".
Rym: What on earth do computer people have as the tools of their trade?
Rym: I mean, it's not quite as clear cut as a lot of people might think it is.
Scott: No, it is not.
Scott: I mean, a monkey wrench really doesn't help you with a computer.
Scott: Neither does a hammer and nails.
Rym: Hammer and nails might.
Scott: Hardly ever, though.
Scott: It's not a common tool.
Rym: If you need to destroy a hard drive in a hurry.
Scott: You know, we don't need chainsaws.
Scott: All the standard tools you see at Home Depot, you know, power drills, not too useful for computer guys.
Rym: However, Dremel, incredibly useful.
Scott: Well, for hacking or modding, yes.
Scott: But for normal computer use, not so much.
Rym: Also as a low-powered electronic screwdriver.
Scott: Yeah, I think an electric screwdriver is better than a Dremel.
Rym: Yeah, but we're geeks.
Rym: We want to have the most functionality for the least money.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: So obviously we're going to have the Dremel.
Scott: Electric screwdrivers can be had for pretty cheap if you don't want the best one, though.
Rym: We always want the best one.
Scott: No, you don't.
Rym: Oh, no, you always want the second best one.
Scott: That brings us to the first tool every computer guy ever needs.
Scott: The Phillips screwdriver.
Rym: Yeah, always.
Scott: The standard sized Phillips screwdriver is a computer guy's best friend.
Scott: I mean, I just keep buying more of them because I can't have enough.
Scott: See, I got like five.
Rym: But actually, ever since I started working at this new company, I have, see, we'll talk differently because there's the, you know, what you have around the house versus what you bring if you know you're going to be fussing with someone's computer versus what I carry around as a professional in my professional life.
Rym: And the three very different sets.
Scott: They are very different.
Rym: In my professional life, I was given a tool set that includes a very nice, very sturdy manual ratcheting screwdriver that has ratcheting is good, has about 20 different heads for it.
Rym: Every different size of screwdriver ever, including the hex bits, the hex bits with the holes in them and the proprietary HP bit.
Scott: Ooh, a proprietary HP bit.
Rym: Yes, for working on HP racks.
Scott: Ooh, if you could only get the Nintendo bit, that's the big one.
Rym: Actually, you know what?
Scott: Or do you have the Tri-Wing?
Scott: That's also a good bit to have.
Rym: I probably, you know what?
Rym: I haven't even gone through a quarter of these things yet because I don't need them all in my day-to-day work.
Scott: The Nintendo bit's actually called GameBit.
Scott: It actually has a name.
Scott: I think it also opens old Macs, like Mac Pluses and Mac 512Ks.
Rym: I'm fairly certain I have enough stuff in my toolkit to open any Nintendo thing.
Rym: Perhaps, perhaps.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, you need a Phillips screwdriver.
Scott: I prefer this most standard basic one you can get, but anyone will do.
Scott: If you like ratcheting, ratcheting's great.
Scott: Magnetism, magnetism is great.
Rym: Yeah, one thing.
Rym: A lot of people worry about using magnetic screwdrivers around computers.
Rym: You're really not gonna hurt anything.
Scott: Not with a magnetic screwdriver, anyway.
Rym: I mean, hard drives are pretty resilient now.
Rym: You'd have to put a magnet on it, Yeah, you would have to take a strong magnet, like a neodymium.
Scott: Well, maybe not a neodymium, but a neodymium would screw it up for sure and put it on your hard drive to screw it up, or on your CRT monitor.
Rym: But aside from hard drives, nothing else is gonna get hurt at all by a magnet.
Scott: As long as it's off.
Scott: You don't wanna mess around with your computer when it's on.
Rym: Well, you shouldn't be messing around with your computer anyway if it's on.
Rym: Now, here's one way, however, that you can screw up a computer with a magnet.
Rym: Take a magnet and affix it to the end of a power drill.
Rym: Turn it on and allow the magnet to spin.
Scott: Yes, that will screw up the computer for sure.
Rym: But yeah, a magnetic screwdriver is not going to hurt your computer.
Rym: I really don't worry about that.
Scott: It's actually very useful for when, if you're having to drop a screw onto the motherboard, you can pick it up with the magnetic screwdriver.
Rym: Or you just won't drop it in the first place 'cause it stuck to your screwdriver.
Scott: Oh, that too.
Scott: Another good thing, a lot of computer screws.
Scott: There seems to be this one screw.
Scott: It's not the only screw you'll ever find in a computer, but it's very common that not only is it Phillips, but also you can sometimes use a normal flathead screwdriver on it if you suck.
Scott: But it also is sort of hex-shaped around the Phillips hole.
Scott: And you can use this other sort of screwdriver.
Scott: It's not enough.
Scott: I really want to call it a screwdriver.
Rym: You mean a socket wrench?
Scott: It's not really a socket wrench, no.
Rym: It's a socket.
Rym: It's just a small one.
Rym: It's the same mechanism as a socket wrench.
Scott: Yeah, it basically has a hexagon hole in the end of it.
Rym: Yes, it's a small socket.
Scott: Anyway, they're very useful.
Scott: And I actually, whenever I have the opportunity to use one, I often do because I can screw things tighter and more easily than with a Phillips, and there's no worry about stripping any weak screws or anything like that.
Rym: Well, what I actually use those for a lot was, at one point at IBM, we were on a very shoestring budget, and I had to put hundreds and hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of data-less Linux clients out there.
Rym: Now, we had hundreds and hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of old computers.
Rym: They're pretty fast, but they weren't being used for anything.
Rym: So we decided we could use these as the Linux clients, you know, image all the hard drives.
Rym: I had a script that would change everything so they'd all be unique, whatever.
Rym: Not going to get into the details there.
Rym: And it turned out that due to a long series of events that goes back to some sort of corporate espionage between China and Japan a long time ago, a good half of the motherboards on these things had exploded capacitors.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: Now, we didn't have any budget, and I really needed to finish this project.
Rym: So I sat down and replaced hundreds of motherboards.
Rym: And in order to do this quickly, I came up with a process.
Rym: And the fastest way to unscrew and screw those motherboards back into those cases was with a socket.
Rym: At a power socket, it sets the right speed.
Rym: I just went vzzzip, vzzzip, all in a row.
Scott: All right, so after the screwdriver, the obvious need tool.
Scott: Oh, and your hands and your eyes, those are very important tools also.
Rym: Yeah, now, there's the static strap that you don't really need.
Rym: A lot of people use those because they're paranoid, and...
Scott: It helps.
Scott: If you are paranoid, it is guaranteed.
Rym: A much better way is just to hold on to something that will ground you.
Scott: Yeah, don't wear wool socks and a sweater and roll around on the wool carpet and then work on your computer.
Rym: Yeah, don't work on your computer if it's frigidly cold or really, really, really dry out unless you have to.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Just avoid any possible chance of creating static electricity.
Scott: You know, hold on to something metal.
Scott: Hold on to your computer's case.
Scott: Hope it's a metal case.
Scott: If it's a plastic case, that's not going to help you.
Rym: But we're not really talking about it.
Rym: We're talking more about the tools you bring.
Rym: But if you don't know how to deal with grounding yourself properly, you can get one of those wrist straps.
Rym: They work alright.
Rym: The key is, you actually have to click them on to something grounded.
Rym: Don't just click them to something metal.
Rym: That's not going to do anything.
Scott: I mean, just wearing the wrist strap isn't going to help you.
Scott: It has this little, you know, wire with an alligator clip.
Rym: No, but I saw a guy working on a computer once at a company that I won't name.
Rym: And he was working on it, and he had a wrist strap on.
Rym: And the little alligator clip coming out of the wire on it was clipped to the case of the computer he was working on.
Rym: Now, the computer was not plugged in and was not grounded in any way.
Scott: Not so good.
Scott: You generally click it to, like, I don't know.
Scott: Well, you know what's always grounded?
Scott: Supposedly, those screws right in the middle of a power outlet that hold the thing on, those go right into the grounding.
Rym: Yeah, I actually made a little thing where I could stick it into the third hole on a grounded power outlet.
Scott: That's a good way, too.
Rym: And I always grounded myself that way if I was working on anything sensitive.
Scott: Be careful not to kill yourself, though, when going near the outlet.
Rym: Yeah, it'd be pretty hard for me.
Rym: In fact, I couldn't physically stick that thing in the wrong hole.
Scott: No, you couldn't, because you were smart.
Scott: But an idiot could very easily kill himself playing around with power outlets.
Rym: Not with that mechanism, because it's wide and fat.
Rym: It won't even go into the normal holes.
Rym: You would have to sit there, filing the edges down enough to shove it into that hole.
Scott: Anyway...
Rym: It would take you about 15 minutes to kill yourself.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, so a grounding method of some sort could be a useful tool for a computer guy.
Rym: Well, you see a lot of those kits that people sell, like, "Oh, a computer, whatever
Rym: kit.".
Rym: Don't bother with anything like that.
Scott: Yeah, I bought the cheapest one from Radio Shack.
Scott: I think it's still available, but the only tools in there that I needed were the screwdriver, the hex bit, and two other bits.
Scott: One of them was sort of this grabber.
Rym: And... The grabber's useless.
Scott: The grabber is useful occasionally.
Rym: I've never needed to use the grabber.
Rym: Any time I've dropped something where the grabber might be useful, I could either just reach it on my own, or I could tilt the computer slightly and it would roll to safety.
Rym: Also, the grabber very easily can scratch things.
Scott: That's only if you suck with the grabber.
Rym: But why bother with the grabber?
Rym: The grabber's useless.
Scott: I've used the grabber many times when anything else would have failed.
Scott: What would have failed?
Scott: I drop screws a lot.
Scott: A lot.
Rym: Well, you should get a magnetic screwdriver instead.
Scott: I should, I should.
Scott: But, anyway, yeah, if you drop screws, they make these little grabbers where you push a button on the top, and these three little metal guys come out, sort of like a claw, a little tiny claw.
Scott: that's exactly the right size for you.
Rym: I'll warn you right now, don't think, "Hey, and grab yourself with it.
Rym: That
Rym: hurts.".
Scott: It does kind of hurt.
Scott: A lot.
Scott: Yeah, 'cause they're pointed little metal guys.
Scott: But, you know, it's the perfect size for grabbing a screw.
Scott: So let's say you drop a screw, and the screw is in between the video card and the CPU and a capacitor, and you're like, "Ugh, God, how am I gonna get that out of
Scott: there?".
Scott: The grabber goes "whoop" and pulls it right out.
Rym: Yeah, or your magnetic screwdriver.
Scott: It depends.
Scott: But, yeah, it's a handy tool to have when working with screws that can fall into tight places that you need to retrieve.
Scott: 'Cause you can't leave the screw there.
Scott: That's no good.
Rym: But those kits come with a bunch of other crap.
Rym: Like, a lot of times, they'll come with a continuity tester.
Rym: that's never going to be useful to you.
Scott: I didn't even get one of those.
Rym: They'll come with two specialized tools.
Rym: One of which exists solely to remove ICs from breadboards.
Scott: And you will never need to do that.
Scott: They also have another tool that puts ICs in breadboards.
Scott: Yes, you will- There's a chip pusher and a chip ripper.
Rym: That was the other thing I was gonna mention.
Rym: You don't need them.
Scott: You will never- You needed them a hundred years ago.
Rym: You know what you need them for today?
Rym: And even then, usually you don't.
Rym: If you screw up your BIOS so royally that you can't even recover it, which is hard to do because- A lot of BIOSes aren't even on those kind of ICs anymore.
Rym: Yeah, but most BIOSes now come with an unrideable recovery sector.
Rym: you can boot from in an emergency.
Rym: With a jumper or something.
Scott: You never gonna need to replace a BIOS chip, trust me.
Scott: It's so rare.
Rym: But my motherboard right there, I could replace it.
Rym: So if I screwed up the BIOS, I could probably order a BIOS chip.
Scott: You know, I never used the chip pusher, the one that puts the ICs on the boards, but I did on occasion use the chip ripper because it was really good for ripping jumpers off.
Rym: I am the pusher robot.
Scott: It was really good at grabbing jumpers off of things.
Rym: See, here's the thing.
Rym: I have a nice jumper grabber.
Scott: Oh, well that's a tool that you need, is some sort of jumper grabber.
Rym: I recommend needle nose pliers.
Rym: They work just as well.
Scott: Needle nose pliers I think are the best, as long as they are needly enough.
Scott: I've tried to use needle nose pliers that were less needly, didn't work.
Rym: Of course the thing is, jumpers are fast becoming obsolete.
Rym: I mean, back in the day, you had to switch like 10 jumpers on your motherboard to make it even boot.
Scott: That $20 motherboard had a lot of jumpers.
Rym: It did, but nowadays, most hard drives don't need to set any jumpers, because cable select or serial ATA...
Scott: Yeah, serial ATA doesn't need jumpers anymore.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: Contrary to popular belief, non-serial ATA hasn't need jumpers for a long time.
Rym: Cable select just works.
Scott: Yeah, cable select usually works, but I still like to set the jumpers.
Scott: I like to.
Rym: You know, I used to, and I unset them all when I started moving hard drives around between all the computers in my room.
Rym: Because I kept making them master slave, and it just wasn't worth it.
Rym: So I just pulled all the jumpers out, they were all cable select, worked like a charm.
Rym: Hey, awesome.
Rym: Also, my old RAID thing that I never really got working from way back in the day, wouldn't work unless everything was set to cable select.
Scott: Whoa, crazy.
Rym: I never really figured out why, and I didn't really care.
Scott: Yeah, I just wouldn't ask the question.
Rym: Really important.
Rym: We talked about you need the Phillips head screwdriver, even though most things have thumb screws.
Rym: You still need that screwdriver, believe me.
Scott: Yeah, I've had thumb screws that just won't come out, and I need to put a Phillips screwdriver into the thumb screw to get it off.
Rym: Independent of that, you need a flathead screwdriver, but you need a special one.
Rym: You need a flathead that is effectively just a mini crowbar.
Rym: Needs to be really durable, really solid, yet small.
Rym: And the reason is, with modern socket processors, usually there's this weird mechanism that holds the heat sink on.
Scott: Oh, I didn't even think of that.
Scott: You're smart.
Rym: Because at IBM, I encountered that, because my computer is so old that I had a slot A in there for the longest time.
Scott: Yeah, when you install the heat sink on a socket processor -- Well, this is how to install a processor on a motherboard, a modern processor, right?
Scott: First, there's a little lever on the motherboard.
Scott: You pull the lever out and up.
Scott: That's easy enough, right?
Scott: You can do it with your hand.
Scott: Then you drop the chip into the slot.
Scott: That's pretty easy, because there's only like four possible ways it can go.
Rym: And it'll only actually go in one of those ways.
Scott: Yeah, if you have to push the CPU down, you just screwed up your CPU.
Rym: Yeah, you just set it on there and wait for it to fall in.
Scott: And it falls into the holes.
Rym: It usually lines up.
Rym: There'll be one clipped corner, and line the clipped corner with the clipped corner on the socket.
Scott: Yeah, it's not hard.
Scott: Then you put the lever down.
Scott: Now the CPU is installed, but you need to put a heat sink on top of it.
Scott: Well, the heat sink is a big block of metal, and it has this metal clamp that kind of swings back and forth.
Scott: What, the clamps?
Scott: Yeah, the clamps.
Scott: And sometimes they have fancy clamps.
Scott: Sometimes they have really simple clamps.
Scott: The way the clamp works is the plastic socket that the CPU just went into, on two sides of it, will have these hooks.
Scott: And you take the metal thing on the heat sink.
Scott: Well, first you rest the heat sink on the CPU in the correct orientation.
Scott: Then the metal thing that swings back and forth, you put it under the hooks on one side.
Scott: You can do that with your hand.
Scott: It's easy.
Scott: But now you have to get the other side of this metal thing under the hooks on the other side, which requires a lot of pushing.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of people are really afraid, you know, how fragile their processors are.
Rym: But you'd be surprised how much force is actually used to hold a heat sink directly against that thing.
Scott: It is very important that the heat sink does not fall off.
Rym: Therefore, this clamp is very-- It's that it has to be perfectly tight and sealed effectively.
Rym: Yes, and-- I mean, it's not going to fall off.
Scott: And the equipment is made to withstand the amount of force required to install the heat sink.
Scott: Don't worry.
Rym: Now, keep in mind, it's taken to withstand normal, gradual force.
Rym: Don't hit it with a hammer.
Scott: No, don't do that.
Rym: But the thing is, to get it in there, there's a slot for a flathead screwdriver.
Rym: If you use a cheap screwdriver, especially if you try to use one of those little black ones, you know, the little, like, eyeglass screwdrivers, even though they fit in there just fine, you'll just bend it right in half.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You need to get a nice, sturdy flathead screwdriver, stick it into there, and then you will be able to easily, with a little bit of practice, push that metal clamp under those hooks and have your heat sink installed properly.
Scott: So if you're ever doing heat sinks on or off, you need that flathead screwdriver, because you also needed to get the heat sinks off to push it down under the hooks and then out.
Rym: Now, other than things like extra screws and all that, there's really, in a basic level, nothing else.
Rym: you need to work with computers.
Scott: No, I mean, you could do 99% of computing tasks with those tools and your hands.
Rym: However, let's say that you also are going to be doing some troubleshooting, or, you know, these are just things you should also just always keep around your house to mess with computers.
Rym: Not so much tools, but just useful bits.
Rym: First and foremost, and I can't recommend this enough, get a power supply tester.
Rym: They're real cheap.
Rym: You plug them into a power supply, you turn them on, they trick the power supply into thinking that a motherboard is plugged in, and they allow you to power up a power supply.
Rym: 90% of the time, if you can power up a power supply, the power supply is good, and now you know that the problem is something with your expensive motherboard as opposed to your cheap power supply.
Scott: The reason that you need a power supply tester, but you don't need a specific tester for anything else, is because power supply problems are usually a little trickier to diagnose than other problems.
Rym: You know, I mean, let's say I-- No, no, really, these things by default only test if a power supply is dead.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Because if the power supply is dead, then-- Well, if the computer doesn't turn on.
Rym: All right, any number of things could be wrong.
Rym: So the first thing you should test is the power supply because most of the time, that's the problem.
Scott: Yeah, we learned that lesson the hard way in the year 2001.
Rym: Yeah, partly because power requirements for PCs had gone up quite a bit suddenly, and we didn't keep track of that.
Scott: Nope, no one told us.
Rym: We were trying to use 200 and 300 watt power supplies on 400 and 450 watt computers.
Scott: Yeah, it didn't turn out so well.
Rym: But the thing is, power supplies-- I mean, you might wonder, how does the computer know to turn the power supply on?
Rym: Because the power supply turns on independent.
Rym: It turns on.
Scott: I mean, the power button that you push to turn your computer on is connected to the motherboard.
Scott: The motherboard is connected to the power supply.
Scott: So turning on the power supply, the motherboard has to do something.
Rym: Yeah, basically, it shorts out two of the pins on that connector.
Rym: you shove into the motherboard, especially the old standard ATX power supply connector.
Scott: Yeah, the old ATX connector said 20 pins.
Scott: The new ones have 24, which sucks.
Scott: No one told me about that either.
Rym: You might think, why can't I just short those pins out and test it?
Rym: And the answer is, the power supply is smarter than you.
Rym: If it doesn't notice a load on the wire itself out there, it won't turn on.
Rym: So power supply testers are a thing that you stick onto the wire, you turn it on, and not only does it short those things out, but it has a bunch of resistors, and it puts a load on the power supply.
Rym: Now, you can't turn these things on for more than, I don't know, 10 or 15 seconds, so they start heating up.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much just a tester.
Scott: Click, it's working, click.
Rym: Now, you can use these also, if you're more adventurous, with a voltimeter to see if the power supply is actually good, but they're also fancy power supplies.
Rym: In general, you really don't need to, because nine times out of ten, if the power supply is dead, it's just not going to turn on at all.
Scott: Yeah, power supplies these days are really smart, and they have a lot of logic and things in them.
Scott: So if you hook up too much stuff to a power supply, and it's not going to be able to power everything, it just won't turn on.
Rym: Also, if it will turn on but is giving bad voltage, you can go to your BIOS and look at the voltage coming in.
Rym: The motherboard knows, and the motherboard can tell you if it's bad.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right, what other tools are--.
Scott: Oh, number one, if you're working with, let's say, some IDE hard drives, you want to have some extra cables.
Scott: If you're working with SATA hard drives, you want extra SATA cables.
Scott: Any sort of little wire that's going to be inside the computer, pretty good idea to have some sort of backup.
Scott: Get some extra Ethernet cables, video cables, USB cables.
Scott: All kinds of cables are useful to have.
Scott: You never know when the cable's the problem.
Scott: Or, "Oh, I need to hook up something extra, but I don't have the cable to do
Scott: it.".
Rym: Yep, it's always good to have a power supply adapter splitter just in case you need one more device.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Of course, you don't want to use too many of those.
Scott: Nope, nope.
Scott: An extra CPU fan.
Scott: Now, you might be thinking, "Ah, CPU fan, they're kind of
Scott: expensive.".
Scott: Well, usually you buy one CPU, it comes with one fan, how are you supposed to get an extra one?
Scott: Let me tell you, many times an extra CPU fan has come in handy.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: How often do you go to fix someone's computer and it was just a problem of they never cleaned their computer, their CPU fan full of dust, now it doesn't work?
Rym: Of course, very important, always carry around the can of air.
Rym: Oh, you forget the can of air.
Rym: Look, it's right there, it's in my closet.
Scott: Yeah, can of air is, I think it's up there with the Phillips screwdriver, we shouldn't have forgotten it this long.
Rym: No, because I don't bring it everywhere, I only bring it if I know I'm going to clean a computer.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: If I don't know I'm cleaning your computer and I come to help you and your computer needs cleaning, that's the end of our day.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I'm not cleaning a computer.
Scott: That is a common problem.
Rym: But the easiest way to clean out a computer is just to take it outside and spray all the relevant bits with compressed air.
Rym: Now, make sure you use a can of compressed air.
Rym: Don't use a compressor.
Rym: Compressors can make static electricity.
Scott: That is correct.
Rym: You want to use cans of compressed air.
Rym: Don't try to be clever.
Scott: Yeah, and while you go to the store and those cans of air that you see at Staples or whatever are kind of expensive, just deal with it.
Scott: You're not going to get them cheaper anywhere else.
Rym: Yeah, really.
Rym: I mean, if you try really hard you can save a couple bucks.
Rym: Just keep a can of air around.
Rym: They actually last quite a while.
Scott: And they are really useful.
Scott: Really useful.
Rym: Actually, you always want to have two cans of air because I'm not going to get into the physics here.
Rym: You guys should know this stuff since most of you have gone through at least high school.
Rym: If you have a can of compressed air and you use it for more than a trivial amount of time, it starts to get cold.
Rym: The colder it gets, the less effective it's going to be until it warms up again.
Rym: However, you don't want to just warm it up with a heater because then it'll explode.
Rym: And you'll kill yourself.
Scott: So what you basically need to do-- That's a YouTube video.
Scott: Throw a can of compressed air into a fire.
Rym: That's a bad idea.
Scott: That's a great YouTube.
Rym: But you've got to have two.
Rym: So you use one.
Rym: And the moment it starts getting really cold in your hands, you set it aside, let it warm up while you use the second one.
Rym: And you switch off between the two.
Rym: Otherwise, you're going to waste a lot of your air at a much lower pressure and not get your money's worth.
Scott: That is correct.
Scott: And sometimes a lot of people, they're dumb, and they use one and it starts getting cold and it stops squirting out air.
Scott: They think it's done even though they only used it for five seconds.
Scott: I've seen that happen a lot.
Rym: Also, if you want to have fun, you can turn it upside down, and now you basically have a liquid death ray.
Scott: Don't do that unless you know what you're doing.
Scott: It's dangerous.
Rym: Yeah, it's also really fun.
Scott: And dangerous.
Rym: Yeah, don't try this at home, kids.
Rym: But yeah, also, you need to carry around things like, I don't know, an Ubuntu CD.
Scott: Yeah, not everything that you need for tools is hardware.
Scott: There's a lot of software stuff that can be really even more handy.
Rym: Yep, we don't really need to go into all of them, especially not specifics because it changes a lot.
Scott: The only specific one I want to mention is the OPH crack CD.
Scott: I've never used it myself, but from everything I hear, supposedly, you can just use this CD to break into a Windows machine if the password is messed up.
Rym: I have actually broken into dozens of Windows machines as a part of my job at IBM and at RIT.
Rym: I didn't use that, though.
Rym: I used a boot disk called a Stroomy that did the same thing.
Rym: Basically, there are four different ways to hack Windows passwords.
Rym: I don't know if these work on Vista, but they work on XP, they work on 2000, they work on NT.
Rym: 98's a whole different bag.
Rym: Don't even worry.
Scott: The thing is, you will probably run into a Windows machine that you can't log into as administrator or someone forgot a password, and these CDs are really handy.
Scott: Some of them might take a while to break the password.
Scott: Some of them don't take any time at all.
Rym: No, they don't break the password.
Rym: That's not what they do.
Scott: Some of them do.
Rym: No, you can try to break the password.
Rym: That's going to take forever.
Rym: It's generally a losing proposition and you don't want to do it.
Rym: The best way to do it, I forget what the tool is, but on the Stroomy thing, you can find it.
Rym: Maybe I'll post in the forums.
Rym: But what you do is you use a hash function and you can basically change someone's password to whatever you want.
Rym: You can't get their password.
Rym: The only problem here is that if they have encrypted volumes, you won't be able to access them unless you figure out their password.
Rym: However, if they left any data non-encrypted, especially if they're not the brightest user, you can usually find hints as to what their password actually is.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: But, yeah.
Rym: Also, I always carry around a DBAN disk.
Rym: DBAN is pretty much my favorite nuke a hard drive in a hurry disk.
Scott: My favorite is, oh, DBAN, Derek's Boot and Nuke.
Scott: I was like, I use a different one, Derek's Boot and Nuke.
Scott: And then I was like, wait a minute, DBAN is Derek's Boot and Nuke.
Rym: Yeah, every company I've ever left, I always DBAN my hard drive whenever I quit.
Rym: I'm done.
Rym: Here's my blank computer.
Scott: Yep, Derek's Boot and Nuke is basically the CD that you boot off of it, and it will completely erase whatever hard drives you tell it to.
Scott: Not just erase, but super erase, so that there is basically no mathematical possibility of recovering the data off of that hard drive ever.
Rym: It has various Department of Defense standards in it, all sorts of different things you can do.
Rym: It's highly effective, it's very fast, it's very good.
Scott: It will make a hard drive, the entire hard drive, full of zeros or full of ones or whatever, and no way to figure out what those zeros or ones used to be in any point in time.
Rym: Yep, and of course, if you're working on, you know, Muggles PCs, it's a good idea to have a Windows 2000 and a Windows XP CD, just in case.
Scott: Ubuntu CDs, Knopik CDs, those are very useful.
Rym: Just have a CD binder full of stuff, flash drives full of stuff.
Scott: Yep, the most useful thing about a live CD, really, is just, you know, if their computer's broken, and you need to go on the internet to find some answers, the live CD's gonna be your only way unless they have two computers.
Scott: You know, a laptop is also a really good idea.
Scott: If someone has a computer that's not working, or maybe an internet connection that's not working, get a laptop with some Wi-Fi or some, you know, cell phone type wireless with some Evdu and a PCMCIA card, and that way, no matter what someone's situation is, you have a working computer that you can use to revive the other not working computer.
Scott: It's very hard to fix a broken computer when you don't have a working computer to help you out.
Rym: Yep, or not even a working computer, but at least a set of all the parts of a computer that are known good.
Rym: That way, you can play the process of elimination game where, "Well, I can't make that hard drive work.
Rym: Let me see if this hard drive works.
Rym: Oh, it does!
Rym: Mister, your hard drive's
Rym: broken.".
Rym: Or, "Oh, it doesn't.
Rym: Maybe something else is
Rym: wrong.".
Scott: You know what else is really useful?
Scott: A mouse and a keyboard.
Rym: Yes, now, we fucked up once.
Scott: We fucked up a couple times.
Rym: Make sure that you bring along a USB mouse and keyboard and-- A PS/2 adapter.
Rym: Yes, because we went to Citicon with our Mac, and we were all happy, and we had this cheap keyboard and mouse that we just brought with us.
Rym: We get there, and we're about to set up our podcasting rig, and I go behind the Mac, and I just go,
Rym: "Huh.".
Rym: And I go to Scott and say, "Scott, here, plug this
Rym: keyboard.".
Rym: And he's like, "What?
Rym: Why?".
Rym: And he goes down, and he goes,
Rym: "Huh.".
Rym: The Mac doesn't have a PS/2 port, anyway.
Scott: And we had a PS/2 keyboard.
Rym: I could cry.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So get a USB keyboard and USB mouse.
Scott: You can get really cheap ones.
Scott: And get the little-- the green adapters that turn USB into PS/2.
Scott: They're super cheap and common.
Scott: I have, like, a sack of them.
Rym: Or the purple one.
Scott: Oh, the purple one.
Scott: Ooh, yeah.
Scott: That's for the keyboard.
Rym: Not that it matters.
Scott: The green one's for the mouse.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Now, I guess-- I mean, we've talked a bit here, but before we end, we are professionals, so maybe you'd like to hear-- I won't go into a lot of detail-- but the kind of stuff I carry around in the course of my daily duties at my job.
Rym: 'Cause I carry around a very specialized set of equipment far above and beyond anything the vast majority of you would ever need.
Rym: And in fact, I don't need most of this stuff in any of my non-work life ever.
Rym: Of course, I carry everything we just talked about.
Rym: I have this gigantic briefcase.
Rym: It's like-- God.
Rym: It's like a foot and a quarter wide and two feet wide the other way and two feet tall.
Rym: It's this massive, heavy thing.
Rym: I carry around, like, a 1-meter, a 2-meter, and a 4-meter fiber cable with various connectors on the end.
Rym: I carry around, like, four different lengths of Ethernet cable and a couple of crimpers and some crossover cables and all that stuff.
Scott: Oh, those are real useful, you know, to just--.
Scott: Hey, crap, I need another Ethernet cable.
Scott: 'cause someone wants me to hook up a router and they don't have an extra.
Scott: Make one.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Or a recent incident.
Rym: Oh, we're hooking up two active devices, yet none of us have a crossover cable.
Rym: Why isn't this working?
Rym: Help us, Rym.
Rym: Help us.
Rym: Ha ha ha.
Scott: I will just make one.
Scott: What's the colors again?
Scott: Bring a little guide.
Rym: White, orange, orange, white, green, blue, white, blue, green, white, and brown, brown is a B connector.
Scott: Yeah, if you can't remember the colors, like, Rym can remember the colors, bring a little piece of paper.
Rym: Don't worry about knowing those things.
Rym: Just print out a little thing and carry it on you.
Scott: That's what I said.
Rym: Yeah, because I know it 'cause I do it a lot, but you don't need to know it.
Rym: And if I didn't have the job I have, I wouldn't know it.
Scott: Have we had to look it up how many times at RIT?
Rym: God.
Scott: Every day?
Rym: In fact, I don't even need to know it at my current job.
Rym: I needed to know it at IBM.
Rym: I don't need to know it here because here we just buy cables.
Scott: Oh, that's no good.
Rym: Eh, pros and cons.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But yeah, I carry around a full set of tools.
Rym: Now, when I say a full set of tools, I mean ranging from socket wrenches to hammers to power, everything, you know, for building server racks and putting together routers and UPSs and batteries.
Scott: Oh, that reminds me.
Scott: You know, you need cable ties.
Scott: Cable ties are real useful.
Rym: Now, if you can afford it, this sounds silly, but they're actually expensive, your best bet is always Velcro.
Scott: Velcro cable ties are like the sexiest cable ties you can get.
Rym: They're solid gold.
Scott: Especially if you're even sexier, you can get multicolored labeling Velcro cable ties.
Rym: Yeah, now I carry around approximately 50 to 100 feet of Velcro with me at all times.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: It might be in the trunk of my car or in one of my other duty bags, but I have it available 'cause that stuff's handy.
Rym: I also carry around some very interesting things.
Rym: I carry around a fluke, which is basically a super, super, super cable tester.
Rym: It also is a toner, so I can figure out where a cable goes.
Rym: I carry around two different labelers.
Rym: I mean, it doesn't matter so much in your house.
Rym: You know, you don't need to label-- You could use the cheap labeler from Staples.
Scott: That's like 20 bucks.
Rym: Yeah, but even then, you don't need to label your computer my computer.
Rym: You know it's your computer.
Rym: You know which computer it is.
Rym: You don't suddenly forget, "Oh, is this my computer sitting on my desk with my porn on
Rym: it?".
Scott: Yeah, you don't suddenly forget, "Hey, which video cable coming out of my computer is the video
Scott: cable?".
Scott: Let me label it video cable.
Rym: Yep, so I carry around a normal, you know, actually a normal Circuit City whatever brother labeler.
Rym: And I label the fronts of servers and switches and whatever.
Rym: But that's whatever.
Rym: That's nothing.
Rym: I also carry around a Brady labeler.
Rym: Now, this thing was like 500 bucks.
Rym: It's good God, but it looks like a heavy duty piece of equipment.
Rym: It's like super awesome construction yellow with shock mounts.
Rym: It takes these gigantic cartridges of all different kinds of labels.
Rym: You know if you look in like a plumber's closet or like at a gas station, like a power station or some kind of industry thing.
Rym: You see those gigantic like fancy labels on like gas pipes and oxygen pipes and all that.
Rym: This is the machine, pretty much the only one that people use to make those things.
Scott: So that's what it is.
Rym: Yeah, and I have all the different kinds of labels.
Rym: I have ones that will resist acid, ones that will go outside, whatever.
Rym: Very cool are the ones that I use on, like say I'm doing a...
Scott: Do you ever use the ones that resist acid?
Rym: No, I just have them because I have a bunch of cartridges.
Scott: One day you're going to have to label a computer in an acid bath.
Scott: You're going to use those.
Rym: Actually that would have been handy at IBM.
Scott: Oh man, scary.
Rym: Yeah, IBM was actually a scary place to work sometimes.
Rym: I mean I'd be next... There was a vat of a fucking deadly chemical.
Rym: Like touches me, I'm dead.
Rym: Cancer.
Rym: There was a vat bigger than our house, full of it.
Rym: And there were like these double walls and this retaining pool around it in case it broke or something.
Scott: At least you got some safety there so you'd be able to run away if something happened.
Rym: But just every day if I went into that part of the factory I'd walk by it.
Rym: I'd always just kind of look at it like...
Scott: I would also go... I would walk fast.
Rym: Of course then there were the Tachikomas and I'd totally forget and play with them.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No really, we had these little robots but...
Scott: Yeah, they weren't Tachikomas.
Rym: No, but they were as close to a Tachikoma as we've gotten in this world.
Scott: I think there's better out there, but anyway.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Alright, but this labeler will also make self-laminating cable labels.
Rym: So say you got a switch or a router with like a thousand cables coming out of it.
Rym: They're all labeled with this fancy little labeler that makes these awesome little self-laminating wrap around a cable.
Rym: Everything's repeated, perfect label.
Scott: So some guy comes along and he goes "hehehehe" and he unplugs every cable from the router.
Scott: And the cables go like to another room somewhere and there's no way to tell which cable goes to which computer somewhere else.
Scott: They're all labeled so you can just pick them up and put them back in the switch and you're all good.
Rym: Yep, or more likely if I'm fixing a problem that got caused somehow and I'm unplugging a bunch of stuff in order to diagnose it.
Rym: And then now I'm done and I gotta plug all that stuff back in.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, it's real easy to unplug something and not know where to put it.
Scott: Hey, I'm here standing holding 50 blue cables.
Scott: I don't know where they go, I can't pull them out, I can't possibly find the other end.
Scott: There is no way to do that, it would take hours.
Scott: When they have to go back in the right holes on this box.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Oh gee, there are 25 times 25 possible combinations.
Rym: And of course, last and not least, other than, you know, I carry a bunch of weird stuff around.
Rym: Like a tile puller to pull tiles up in a data center, raised floor and all that.
Rym: But I've got this little metal bit that I got from someone who got it from one of the HP contractors who came in and installed a server rack one time.
Rym: I don't know if anyone out there has ever worked with modern server racks.
Rym: But essentially they're these little square bits that you put screws into.
Rym: And you stick these bits at the rack elevations where you want to install your servers.
Rym: It's a pain in the ass to install these things in anything.
Rym: And you basically have to sit there crying trying to use a pair of pliers to manhandle the thing in.
Rym: I have this little bent piece of metal.
Rym: And with that, I can put a hundred of them in in the time it'll take someone with a pair of pliers to put one in.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: And if you ever, ever end up working with any HP person who is building a rack for you, ask them if you can have one of their little thingies.
Rym: And they'll know exactly what you're talking about and they'll give you one.
Scott: Ooh, handy trick.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Who else makes rack mount stuff that you might need to ask for a different metal thingy?
Rym: Actually, IBM, pretty much racks are standard.
Rym: IBM uses a different metal thing that's far more complicated, but serves the same purpose.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I've never actually mounted anything in a rack, even though I've... Well, no, I've mounted ATX mid-towers in racks.
Rym: See, it's weird.
Rym: Like, we've... Scott's... I've mostly worked... In fact, I've only ever worked at monolithic, gigantic companies.
Rym: And Scott's only worked at very small companies.
Rym: And we both make the same amount of money.
Rym: It's just totally different work environments.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Like, you'll write code for a server.
Rym: And I'll have to install, like, a hundred UPS's.
Scott: Haha.
Rym: That sucked.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That really sucked.
Scott: How much did it suck?
Rym: You know how much a UPS weighs?
Scott: Oh, that reminds me of something else you need to bring with you.
Scott: A freakin' power strip.
Scott: Good God.
Rym: Yes!
Rym: Bring a power strip with you everywhere you go for the rest of your life.
Rym: Even if it's a shitty two dollar one.
Scott: Bring it.
Rym: Yeah, you will never have enough power outlets unless you build a house that has nothing but power outlets.
Scott: Yeah, you'll go to someone's house, you'll be like, "Oh yeah, can you do something to my
Scott: computer?".
Scott: "Oh yeah,
Scott: sure.".
Scott: "Oh look, there's enough outlets, but you have these giant AC adapters and I can only use three outlets.
Scott: I wish I had another power
Scott: strip.".
Rym: God, there was that one year, way back, we all went to the shore with our friend Scott Johnson and his family's awesome beach house.
Rym: So we're all hanging out there.
Rym: We're all geeks.
Rym: We all bring, like, three or four things each that need to be recharged.
Scott: I had an iPod, a cell phone, a DS, and a laptop.
Scott: And I brought a power strip.
Rym: So multiply that by everyone in the crew who was there.
Rym: And there aren't enough outlets on that island for all of us.
Scott: Let alone- I brought a power strip for me.
Rym: I brought a power strip for me.
Scott: And people who didn't, it sucked for them.
Rym: Yeah, you generally want to bring a power strip everywhere you go.
Scott: Lots of cell phone power swapping going on.
Scott: People who had the same cell phone kind of benefited.
Scott: And, you know, everyone has a DS and the DS chargers are all the same.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Oh, except people with DS lights.
Scott: I think is different, isn't it?
Scott: Or is it?
Rym: I don't even know.
Scott: I'll get one one day.
Rym: I'd assume it is, just because Nintendo's that way.
Scott: I don't know, I think they actually changed it on this one.
Scott: I'm not sure.
Rym: No, I mean, I'd assume it is different.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: That's where I was going.
Scott: Well, the SP and the DS have the same one.
Scott: But the micro has a different one.
Scott: And I don't even think the light is the same as the micro.
Scott: We gotta check on that.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: I don't even know.
Scott: Someone will tell us.
Rym: 'Cause the thing is, Nintendo's got me by the balls.
Rym: And if I want their product, I'll just buy it and take it like a man.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh well.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's been a DS flood, but that's not what we're gonna talk about.
Rym: God, I still, as much as cool as the Wii is, I've played the DS more still.
Scott: At least right now I am.
Scott: There's been like three DS games in rapid, four DS games in rapid succession.
Rym: Alright, on that note, I gotta solve the mystery of who shot that guy.
Scott: And I have to go hit a lot of monsters with swords.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology, Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs, Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says "Send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial Share-A-Like 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it, as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.