Scott: It's Wednesday October 31st.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: We review Apollo's song.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So driving home from the train station to the house and the traffic's going a little slow, and then I remember all right Trick-or-treating type people.
Rym: Oh snap Halloween.
Scott: Yeah, so I see you know some costumes like.
Scott: you know this.
Scott: I think there was a cat a little girl dressed as a witch Some girl wearing something I don't even know right.
Scott: and then I see this guy dressed up as the tin man.
Scott: You know from Wizard of Oz he's got two friends That aren't dressed up at all, and I'm like what the hell's up with that.
Scott: They're not dressed up as anything.
Scott: I'm like how does that work?
Scott: and is the?
Scott: it's only one guy getting candy.
Scott: the other two guys are just coming with them to Make fun of them.
Rym: cuz you know there's a lot of those punk kids.
Rym: You'll just show up at your house not dressed up and say trick-or-treat.
Scott: Yeah, and I'll say yeah trick see ya.
Rym: Yeah, of course knowing kids these days if I just burned down the house Maybe
Scott: but you know they look like three just average punk kids and only one was dressed up as the tin man And the others were nothing and nothing and I was like what the hell's going on.
Scott: Then I got closer, and I realized their costume was much more clever than I had Anticipated from afar in my car.
Rym: Oh really.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: What was it like?
Rym: the living statue from hot fuzz?
Rym: and no some hoodies.
Scott: No, living statue my fuzz looks nothing like the tin man.
Scott: I don't know man is just Gold man At all.
Rym: the tin man is not gold he's tin I know but close enough not even close especially in the fading light as you're driving home.
Scott: Maybe with your eyesight?
Rym: Yeah, anyway anyway.
Scott: He was not just up as a tin man.
Scott: He was dressed up as a keg and his two friends were just up his college party dudes.
Rym: I see what they did there.
Rym: It's still a cop-out.
Scott: It is a cop-out, but I am a fan of the cop-out costume because they think about it, right There are a million costumes out there that you can do that don't actually require any sort of out of the ordinary clothing.
Scott: for example Dress up as your favorite character from your favorite live-action TV sitcom.
Scott: You're wearing normal clothes most of the time.
Rym: those costumes suck.
Scott: dress up that like I could die could go shave right now.
Scott: Put on blue jeans a white t-shirt and put my coat back on and it could be like hey I'm the Fonz just don't have to do anything.
Scott: and I like those kind of costumes because it's like yeah No one's respecting the people who don't have weird character design.
Rym: But that's that's only one step away from just saying I'm dressed up as a serial killer.
Rym: they look just like you and me.
Scott: Oh, that's a good one.
Scott: I like that.
Rym: I'd stolen from the Addams Family.
Scott: I didn't know that never saw that movie.
Scott: I did.
Scott: I just don't remember that joke.
Rym: Huh?
Rym: All right.
Scott: I actually do you ever see the second Addams Family where they're at summer camp?
Rym: No, yeah, don't okay.
Rym: It can't be as bad as Earnest Rides Again, I never saw Earnest Rides Again.
Scott: I saw Earnest Goes to Jail and Earnest Earnest Goes to Camp.
Scott: Earnest Christmas.
Rym: No, no Earnest Goes to Camp.
Scott: I might have seen Earnest Goes to Camp if I did.
Scott: I don't remember it.
Rym: That's the Earnest movie.
Rym: All right, if there's any an Earnest movie to see it's that one.
Scott: None of them.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: But yeah anyway, it is indeed Halloween today as we record this and as we release this even though if not as you listen Which means if you did not know It's a day in America where kids dress up in costumes and go around stealing candy from unsuspecting people.
Scott: Oh, I guess foreigners might need to know that some of you.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, the first episode of GeekNights That was not a beta alpha episode.
Scott: the first actual episode that we put on public places for people to listen to Was put out on Halloween in 2005.
Rym: yeah, even though actually the first episode was uploaded on November 1st.
Rym: for November 1st, yep, and then like a week later I was going through audio stuff and I realized that the episode we'd done on the 31st because remember we Podcasted just for ourselves for a while to make sure we could do this and that it wouldn't be stupid.
Rym: I listened to it and we said something funny and I thought you know what?
Rym: I think this is good enough.
Rym: So I retroactively put it up.
Scott: So whenever you want Episode season 3 of GeekNights has or will soon begin.
Scott: also, I noticed I did a count of.
Scott: You know according to our WordPress I do.
Rym: I did a count and then you followed up later because you were dubious.
Scott: Yeah I didn't.
Scott: I used the SQLs and I looked at the database and I counted the number of database entries for Episodes that are in the podcast category and I just looked at the wordpress at the number of episodes.
Scott: There are 399 or 400. so depending also on your particular taste This or maybe the next or the previous episode of GeekNights is the 400th episode.
Rym: Wow, we've done give or take about 400 hours of podcasting.
Scott: So we're doing about 200 episodes a year because we've done two years and we've done 400 episodes.
Rym: seems to work out that way.
Rym: Yep, so at 50 weeks for episodes 200 now I think we originally had a bunch of plans for season 3 that you probably wouldn't have liked but we're kind of putting those on Hold because everything's going great.
Scott: Yeah, we missed you know, let's see.
Scott: So we're missing about two eight podcasts a year.
Scott: We miss.
Scott: that's not bad.
Rym: It's better than most podcasts.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you're only missing eight a year.
Scott: Most podcasts do eight a year.
Scott: So take that.
Rym: But yeah season 3 is gonna be a lot like season 2 because we never bothered to change the music or anything and people seem To like it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean maybe we'll change things but that'll mostly come season 4. obvious We'll change the show if things outside of the show change, you know, like if we get stupidly popular new websites, you know as stuff.
Scott: we're just gonna keep trying to move forward as much as we can and stuff will change organically as opposed to arbitrarily changing because the season changes even though I kind of like the idea.
Rym: originally the plan was that every season we were gonna change the Opener and the closer and the thing of the day music.
Scott: I didn't we say like a few months ago that we were gonna start only doing two episodes a week.
Rym: Well, I don't think we actually said that.
Rym: but our plan a while ago was to give ourselves a breather and to I guess prove To some naysayers that the show would be ten times better if we had the time to just like do it and not have to Do it every night.
Rym: We thought well every other week like one week will be Monday Wednesday the next to be Tuesday Thursday and the next to be one Day Wednesday again, and we might do that someday if we need a break or if we're working on stuff.
Rym: But we're not gonna do that now because we're on a roll here.
Scott: Yeah, I don't even do that right.
Scott: this second You know, I guess a few months ago I felt like doing it and I said oh I'll do it later and then it.
Scott: now it's later and I don't feel like doing It.
Rym: so plus after those questions episode.
Rym: We've got a good week and a half of extra content if we need it.
Scott: Yeah, we do that.
Scott: the questions episodes.
Scott: I think are what we needed.
Scott: I think if we didn't do those we would have needed to do some two day a week business for at least a while.
Scott: All right, so it's a Wednesday episode.
Scott: We were thinking about doing like, you know scary anime or something, but we did.
Rym: well We realized you know Looking at what anime is out there that would be considered horror either by the Japanese or by the Americans and by either Accounting.
Rym: there aren't that many Mm-hmm.
Rym: Also we haven't.
Rym: I mean, I guess I could talk about take the x-train because that was scary but not in a wasn't scary.
Rym: it was scary in the sense that someone somewhere wrote that and Convinced someone else to pay the money to have it animated and then someone else Convinced us at the RIT anime club.
Rym: That would be a good idea.
Scott: to show that to other people by that account then MD guys This is the second scariest anime ever.
Rym: MD guys is the second everything everything ever Not the second best anything.
Rym: I think it's the second best worst podcast podcast anime ever perhaps Perhaps?
Rym: no take the x-train is bad don't watch it.
Rym: But there's not a lot of horror and things that were called horror didn't work so well or didn't really fit like Vampire hunter.
Rym: D is not horror.
Rym: It just happens to have a vampire in it.
Scott: Yep All right, so we're just gonna do a normal episode for you.
Scott: cuz whatever this there's nothing real.
Scott: What are we gonna talk about?
Scott: That's scary.
Scott: We got nothing boo.
Scott: Oh We're not really scared by anything either.
Scott: it's like even like the the movie that scares you the most in your whole life.
Scott: I watch it and I'm just like whatever.
Rym: Well, that's cuz you're sad godless couch fuck.
Rym: That words been coming back into our lives I used to.
Scott: I was more scared of scary things when I was a kid who hadn't yet watched scary things and I was like Like.
Scott: I was afraid to watch alien because I heard it was so scary and it looked scary when I saw pictures of it.
Scott: I saw the box in the store in the box in the store was scary.
Scott: then I actually watched it.
Scott: I was like, alright, nothing scary anymore.
Rym: I guess part I mean I grew up reading Stephen King books when I was really really young and watching slasher films because my mom's Really into horror.
Rym: so I went through a period when I was young where there were scary movies That scared the ever-living crap out of me.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I was scared of that with the boogity man, mr Boogie, you know, that's the worst cuz that fits into anime.
Rym: You know a lot of people say that when they were young and they watched Prodigy a co They didn't get that.
Rym: it was a comedy and they kind of took it at face value.
Rym: Yeah when I was a kid and I saw mr.
Scott: Boogity that was that was scary.
Rym: I took it at face value.
Scott: I took it at face value when I was a kid.
Scott: I was scared.
Scott: I was so scared, but I've watched it a few years ago Beetlejuice - Beetlejuice didn't scare me as a kid, but it was scary.
Scott: I didn't realize it was a comedy.
Scott: I thought it was just sort of a freaky movie.
Rym: It was scary, especially as a kid.
Scott: some of it some of it.
Rym: Yeah, not as scary as mr.
Scott: Boogity, which really Boogity really scared me even the sequel bother.
Scott: No, remember we're talking like Elementary school like kindergarten action here.
Scott: Yeah, but I was like in middle school.
Scott: Mr Boogity was no longer the bane of my existence
Rym: But I do find it interesting how we can see something like there are things that you expect to be taken on one level But through the eyes of a child in the case of mr Boogity goddamn or through the eyes of just someone who doesn't know about anime in the case of project a co You can almost take it in this innocent level.
Rym: That's totally different from what I guess an experienced watcher would get.
Scott: Yep All right, let's just get on with news and stuff.
Rym: Well, there is something scary on the internet and that is the collective output of all the webcomic people out there.
Rym: now I don't mean the web comics and I don't mean the good web comics.
Rym: I just mean kind of the blogosphere equivalent of web comic people.
Scott: So you mean pretty much every webcomic guy out there combined like the not any individual webcomic person Even though some of them would count but the the collective sum of like the vocal webcomic sort of community.
Rym: Yeah, I even go one step further and say that this is this is the average webcomic or if you don't include I Guess the webcomic artists that are big and famous and popular big players like penny arcade and PvP and such.
Rym: yeah, even some smaller ones that are like friends of ours did or pretty just the average webcomic is about as good as the average blog.
Rym: that's just because that's the way it is and the average webcomic and the average blog Probably don't deserve an article on Wikipedia.
Rym: Wikipedia is not.
Rym: well I'll get into that.
Rym: the story here Is that supposedly a bunch of webcomic artists are all in a tizzy in an uproar because Wikipedia had the sheer?
Rym: Audacity to delete the completely fanciful and entirely non useful articles that they had written about themselves.
Scott: Well, I think the problem here the main point of contention is Wikipedia is notoriety policy, which They're basically saying, you know, there's some people out there who say Wikipedia shouldn't have a notoriety policy.
Scott: Let anyone make an article about anything no matter how insignificant and then we'll eventually have articles about everything.
Rym: Well, the thing is the notoriety policy Actually does something very specific because everyone involved in the stupid argument forgets one thing The primary rule of Wikipedia is that there is no unverifiable or original research Period.
Rym: end of story.
Rym: if you can't find Something even somewhat legitimate somewhere else out there to cite and then paraphrase that then it doesn't belong in Wikipedia.
Scott: No, wait, but it.
Scott: but if I make a webcomic and I write my own article about it.
Rym: That's I am the primary source, but that doesn't work because that's self-referential.
Rym: You have to have a source other than yourself.
Scott: So what if someone interviews me and then writes a Wikipedia article?
Rym: if someone interviews you and they themselves are also Noteworthy then.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Ah So you need someone who is already on Wikipedia's or like an invite-only system.
Rym: Well, it's more like and it's not just one things.
Rym: even if you just have one source A lot of articles did get deleted because there's no point in having him on Wikipedia.
Rym: I mean if you're some blogger and you have a hundred readers Having a Wikipedia article is just a waste of everyone's time
Scott: and it's sort of like, you know The people are editing Wikipedia and I have to monitor your shit, you know, no one wants to look at your show.
Rym: I think the real issue is that most of the articles about very small things like that are written by the people who do them
Scott: and the only reason they have these articles is because they think that they're somehow gonna increase their Popularity through Wikipedia like they're gonna use it as marketing which it is not for that's like saying yeah I'm gonna get an article about me in a cyclopedia Britannica.
Scott: So then people I'll be more popular that way.
Rym: Yeah, but remember Wikipedia is like this tertiary source.
Rym: You're supposed to go to Wikipedia and from there everything you find on Wikipedia should have a verifiable reference somewhere else somewhere It's semi-legitimate and there are very an argument as to what constitutes legitimate and there are different sets of rules for different articles.
Rym: but I don't think any set of these regulations would make me think that a wet some small webcomic that's read by a few hundred People deserves a Wikipedia.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I'm with you.
Scott: these small webcomics definitely do not deserve Wikipedia articles.
Scott: They're not notoriety They do not have any sort of notoriety.
Rym: But if Pluto is a planet then all those other little small things floating around are just as much planets.
Scott: Yeah, the but I do think that the Wikipedia, you know Notoriety policy is slightly subjective and could be fine-tuned, but I do think it should exist and is necessary.
Rym: Well the only problem we've ever run into it and it was kind of funny because after that there is this parsec award thing and anime world order Had a article written about them in Wikipedia and we also had an article written about us in Wikipedia at about the same time by the same person looks like they wrote a bunch of articles and Theirs immediately got deleted and ours didn't and the criteria that made us quote unquote noteworthy as opposed to them were flimsy at best.
Rym: Uh-huh, and I found the whole situation kind of hilarious.
Scott: Yeah, I just really don't care.
Scott: It doesn't I don't care.
Rym: I guess what really bothers me is that this guy who's he writes some webcomics, honestly I'm not just saying this but I've never heard of this guy or his webcomic.
Rym: But he was saying that people should stop donating to Wikipedia until they correct this problem.
Scott: Yeah, I pretty much every time Wikipedia puts that thing up there.
Scott: I donate something.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's just pocket change.
Rym: Yeah, but I don't know I guess anyone who's outraged about this think about it for a second.
Rym: If there's nothing about a webcomic other than the webcomic and their webcomic friends and maybe like an article on ain't it cool news?
Rym: That's not terribly know worthy.
Rym: Now say you were published in a newspaper or say you won some prestigious award like Fred G Lay.
Rym: Fred G Lay Remember that you don't remember the reference to you.
Scott: What's Fred G Lay?
Rym: me Fred G Lay.
Rym: It's a major award.
Rym: Okay Italian, uh-huh Wow Christmas story when he wins the major award.
Scott: Yeah, I only saw.
Scott: I've never seen the whole movie really.
Scott: No It's always just like on on Christmas and I see parts pretty much.
Scott: the only thing I know about Christmas story is to shoot your Eye out kid.
Rym: You've never seen one of the funniest movies ever made in English.
Scott: It's not that funny.
Scott: Yes it is.
Rym: I'm gonna have to ask our listeners to chime in cuz that movie.
Rym: the only way that movie is not funny is if you've already Seen it a thousand times that movie is gold now.
Scott: Anyway, you're not human and whatever.
Rym: All right, non-human.
Rym: What news do you have?
Scott: Speaking of webcomic not a human.
Scott: webcomics, you know for the most part until now have mostly been the domain of.
Scott: you know Sort of like, you know people know people on the street, you know some guys some anime artists someone.
Scott: they make a webcomic They make their own website.
Scott: The you know some penny arcade guys.
Scott: they make a website they put up their own webcomic.
Scott: There isn't sort of any unified webcomic place.
Scott: Well, they're well there was key spot, which was I'm pretty sure let me see if it's still.
Rym: they were really big and a lot of people got their start there Keen spot.
Scott: the website says still the best damn comics on the web.
Scott: I beg to differ.
Rym: a lot of comics are there.
Rym: a lot of fairly big comics are still there.
Scott: Yep there's a you know United whatever.
Scott: that syndication places.
Scott: that syndicates all the comic strips and they put all the Newspaper comic strips on their website like you comics calm.
Scott: But other than that, you know Most like Marvel and DC really or anyone like that has not ventured into the webcomic realm so much.
Scott: even the indie people have not ventured into the webcomic realm.
Scott: you don't see image or dark horse or Top shelf.
Scott: they're not making webcomics until now.
Scott: DC.
Scott: they announced they were gonna do this a while ago, but it today it launched zuda comics.
Scott: calm, right?
Scott: Zuda comics calm and this website.
Scott: the way it works is.
Scott: They have one webcomic right now.
Scott: That is a ongoing webcomic called by you right and you can go there and read this comic.
Scott: They also have ten other comics that are not ongoing comics.
Scott: they are current competitors and you can vote for these current competitors and there are ten come competing comics and if you like them you can vote for them and Whichever one wins will become the second ongoing comic.
Scott: And then there will be ten more competitors and the way this sort of works is you can actually submit comics.
Scott: But there's all these sorts of agreements And I'm not a lawyer and I didn't read.
Scott: the contracts are on the website for you to read and I did not read them In full.
Scott: but the impression I get from you know Glancing through them is that you make one comic for them for a limited amount of time and they own that comic that you make For them, but they pay you a good amount of money and they don't own you.
Scott: so you can do other things.
Scott: You know, they only own the one thing you're doing for them.
Rym: Well, if that's the case to be honest if you're someone with you know, moderate skill That's a great way to get a start.
Rym: make it Like say you have your a story in your B story Write your B story for them make some money and then use that to publish your a story on your own.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if your art is good and you think your comic is gonna get voted up you go submit it.
Scott: if they vote For it, you know, it'll be number one.
Scott: You'll probably get at some nice monies and you'll get your comic all over this and you have a big thing for your resume.
Scott: You probably have a probably an easy time of getting a job at least at an indie comic publisher with an ongoing real comic on Paper, you know, it's.
Scott: it's really not so bad as far as I can tell on the surface.
Scott: And if you're looking to read some webcomics, this ain't a bad place to go either.
Rym: You know, it's been a long time since I found a new webcomic to read.
Scott: Yeah I haven't read any of them, but I'm gonna try all these out and I'm gonna.
Scott: every time that someone wins the contest I'll you know, I'll come back and take another look.
Rym: cuz seriously what I mean.
Rym: Wondermark is the latest comic We found and that was a while ago.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So yeah, if you're looking for webcomics ZUDA comics.com It's actually run by DC even though the DC logo is not anywhere on the way.
Scott: Oh, it's odd.
Scott: This is DC Comics in the bottom right?
Rym: I guess the real question is are they Wikipedia worthy?
Scott: I think that ZUDA Comics itself might be Wikipedia worthy, but I do not know about any Comics on ZUDA Comics.
Scott: They might just you know, note them on the ZUDA Comics page in Wikipedia.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: so this might seem like a cop-out but you know Like we've always said GeekNights is not really news But commentary.
Rym: and I have some commentary here because way back we did a couple of things of the day about the angry video game And how hilarious we found him.
Rym: and of course he had promised for a while now that on Halloween There would be a special episode and sure enough today.
Rym: He reviewed the Michael Myers game Halloween for the Atari 2600.
Rym: But you can watch that.
Rym: I'll link to that as my thing of the day, but I got to say Especially now that we have zero punctuation.
Rym: The angry video game nerd is starting to slip a little bit.
Scott: I think his problem is that he still does his excellent video game reviews in his classic sense But he's sort of doing every review is the same as every other one just like oh look how crappy this game is.
Scott: It's a piece of shit.
Rym: Well, the reason for that is that he's been doing Atari games.
Scott: I know I with the last good one he did was the Silver Surfer, which is amazing.
Scott: He just spent the whole episode Doing what he's good at reviewing the Silver Surfer and how terrible it is and saying quotable things like, you know The difficulty is legendary.
Rym: I think his problem now is that he's try in the in the Ramah Sharma.
Rym: He is trying to do too much with it.
Rym: When you try to do too much with it, I get the point He is trying to do too much of it.
Rym: You are correct because much like the previous one half the video was just some sort of live-action moderately funny Video and the other half of it was the hilarious him reviewing these games.
Scott: Yes, but I mean he reviewed three games in the latest one right in addition to the corny live-action bit.
Rym: I think the problem is with Atari games.
Rym: There isn't more than about 35 40 seconds worth of review no matter how in-depth you go.
Scott: Yep especially Atari games where it's just do the same thing over and over again get higher score because there were better.
Rym: most of them there Were better Atari games.
Scott: like you could do a review of an adventure that would take more than 30 40 seconds.
Rym: Not really because there's only one or two jokes.
Rym: There's a big duck.
Rym: Nothing makes sense.
Scott: Somebody get this freaking duck away from me.
Scott: Haha.
Rym: Oh clever.
Rym: I see what you did there.
Rym: Yeah But I don't know.
Rym: I feel like he's slipping and I hope I think his main strength was that he used to do NES games or you know Sega games that had all this nostalgia.
Rym: and There's not so much nostalgia for these very rare Atari guys.
Scott: Well the rare ones no No, there's not really much nostalgia for rare games.
Scott: See the one exception for say et it which he's been teasing for a while.
Rym: Well, remember when he did all those Swedish sex games for the Atari.
Scott: That was a good one.
Rym: That was great Cuz.
Rym: he just did a bunch of yes good nice one.
Rym: I don't know if he doesn't get back to where he is.
Rym: I think the zero punctuation is gonna be my new thing.
Scott: well, I think another thing is the Angry video game.
Scott: nerd makes releases sporadically.
Scott: you can't trust him, you know.
Scott: But yeah, I think the zero punctuation guy.
Scott: I think he's weekly.
Scott: I got a look.
Scott: but I'm pretty sure he's weekly and I'm pretty sure he's getting paid money by the escapist.
Rym: Oh, he'd better be I think so.
Rym: So we should get him on the show.
Scott: Oh, he's awesome.
Scott: He might talk too fast.
Rym: I have a filter for that.
Scott: Yeah the filter make him talking too fast.
Rym: Be like that micro machines guy.
Scott: You know, it took me a day after I discovered him to realize he was called zero punctuation because he talks so fast.
Rym: That's kind of like when you came to me one day and you're like I get it Beatles.
Rym: it's spelled with an a like beat.
Rym: Yeah instead of an e like bug.
Scott: How's that?
Scott: I Never realized the pun before Right.
Rym: So what do you got for me?
Scott: Oh, so, you know, I I like to Meet, you know get in conversations with you know, middle-aged or older people people much older than myself.
Scott: I especially Scott Johnson You know, especially at nerd conventions, you know I try to question them out to ask what you know geekiness was like in the olden days and it always.
Scott: you know comics is one of the older geekeries and You know, I always end up asking him what kind of comics they read and without Exception they all read uncle Scrooge every last one of.
Rym: as we learned from our foreign listeners when we asked about comics Uncle Scrooge is pretty much the best and most popular comic in the world.
Scott: Uncle Scrooge Donald Duck all that stuff I mean freakin I think in you know in in northern Europe in general, you know, Sweden Norway It's oh you mean the concentrated cool part of the world.
Scott: Yeah As far as I can tell in that part of the world like more people subscribe To Donald Duck and Uncle Scrooge comics and subscribe to the newspaper.
Scott: so Regardless uncle Scrooge is awesome.
Scott: If you have not read an uncle Scrooge comic Well, first of all, if you liked DuckTales DuckTales was incredibly faithful to uncle Scrooge comics.
Scott: So if you like that, you'll like uncle Scrooge comics.
Scott: You should go buy some.
Rym: you should also watch tailspin But that's beside the.
Scott: all Disney afternoon was sort of the same deal.
Scott: If you like one you like them all you know.
Scott: And I recommend you get this book called the life and times of Scrooge McDuck by Don Rosa.
Scott: You can get that book and if you like it, you should get the life and times of Scrooge McDuck companion by Don Rosa.
Scott: There's also.
Scott: I have two volumes of Carl Barks greatest DuckTales stories which is the original comics the DuckTales episodes are based on and those are also awesome because that's what Don Rosa based his thing off.
Scott: and Regardless read uncle Scrooge comics.
Scott: They're awesome.
Rym: All right.
Scott: So what's my thing of the day?
Scott: Yeah, my thing of the day is this guy from Northern Europe no less who made a scale model of the money bin as Laid out in the comics down to the finest detail.
Rym: It's a pretty impressive.
Scott: I mean you've seen models that impress, you know, you see someone make a really cool Gundam or someone makes like You know a six-foot tall Gundam or something like that or some garage kid that just blows you away.
Scott: There's all kinds of.
Scott: you know, some guy makes the Death Star model.
Scott: that's way cool.
Scott: This is one of the coolest models I ever seen.
Scott: this is this is hot shit and it all comes apart.
Scott: But and it's it's perfect in every way.
Scott: It's pretty much here.
Scott: This is the money bin only Smaller than the real money bin, but it's exactly right.
Rym: Well, you know for all we know Scrooge McDuck is just you know an inch and a half tall.
Scott: It could be that whole world model the model being in Northern Europe is not too far from Scotland, but I don't think.
Scott: But I don't think Duckburg is actually in Scotland.
Scott: It is actually, you know in the United States somewhere, but whatever
Rym: Right, so we were inspired to do this partly because I finished the comic but also because uh some friend podcasters reviewed it not too long ago and I Kind of think that they missed the point of this entire manga
Scott: Oh rims doing a challenging.
Rym: I think I am doing a challenging thing.
Rym: I think that someone out there who reviewed Apollo's song by Osamu Tezuka not too long ago Missed the boat in one critical regard in that being loveless people.
Rym: They decided that it was about how horrible love is and I really have to take issue with that.
Scott: Yeah, first of all, I want to say another reason we're reviewing this right now is because Mu mw, you know mu by Osamu Tezuka is just become available from vertical comics Which is a vertical ink which is the same people who published this Apollo song volume.
Rym: You should probably buy that.
Scott: if I buy that my copy should be coming in the mail in a week or so.
Scott: And they also just announced that they have license for America all of the blackjack manga Which is.
Scott: you should buy that also and this is you know It's sort of like.
Scott: hey if we review this and we get you to like this Then it'll get you to buy these other things.
Scott: maybe that are if you like one.
Scott: if you like Tezuka you're gonna from vertical You're gonna like the other Tezuka from vertical, you know.
Rym: The one thing I can't disagree with is that when those other people reviewed this they talked about how special the opening Chapter of Apollo's song was and I must say it is quite Fantastic.
Scott: Yeah He has something like that.
Rym: I was rather impressed.
Scott: Tezuka is not being too subtle here.
Scott: I mean, I I read this only once and I pretty quickly and it was you know more than a month ago.
Scott: So I don't remember all the details.
Scott: the Rym is gonna remember because he read it all like a couple weeks ago.
Scott: But yeah, there's no way you'll forget the opening bit.
Scott: God do you want to describe it?
Rym: Well, Imagine if you took the battle for dominance that semen under sperm undergo when they're fighting the way toward an egg in order to fertilize it and you anthropomorphize that and you replace the semen with cavemen.
Scott: well anthropomorphizing.
Scott: Well anthro replies sort of animal I guess.
Rym: no it don't realize.
Rym: that means to make human.
Rym: Ah Okay, fine Hahaha Sure Whatever what Rym said it's the same as say you talk to your computer you get mad at your computer and you your computer's mad At you.
Rym: it is not really mad at you.
Rym: You're just making that up.
Rym: You're projecting your humanity onto the computer.
Rym: It's just a cold lifeless thing.
Rym: What are you crazy?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: All right, it has no feelings.
Scott: No, it is much better Alright, so after that opening bit which is sort of metaphorical and very important I might add and important that this I'll give you the Literal what what the rest of this is as opposed to the metaphorical right?
Scott: So you have this guy Shogo and Shogo is not the greatest dude.
Scott: Basically, he lived a life of you know badness.
Scott: His mom was what like a dirty whore doing all kinds of guys and you know, it's not really clear if she was a prostitute or simply a loose woman.
Scott: either way She was doing lots of guys who were not his dad.
Scott: He didn't really have a dad.
Rym: They were all his dad.
Rym: I mean, that's the bearded dad.
Rym: That's the fat dad.
Scott: Uh, yeah, right Yeah, none of them were his real dad.
Scott: None of them were like a father to him.
Scott: He didn't have a father figure in his life in the classic sense
Rym: And in addition his mother was kind of abusive and
Scott: by quite quite abuse by
Rym: kind of I mean Extremely
Scott: abusive
Rym: beat him with a broomstick in such a way to have basically conditioned him to hate all love.
Scott: Yeah, and you know cuz pretty much anytime he encountered love in his life.
Scott: It was brought with pain.
Scott: So as a result, this is a man who kind of even a man he's not even like.
Scott: he's young.
Scott: he's young He's maybe adolescent.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, effectively freaks out every time he encounters anyone in love or anyone showing effect.
Scott: He'll even like walk down the street and if like he sees two birds like cuddling he'll freak out and like he'll kill the birds.
Scott: He's also abusive to animals in general.
Scott: Well, that's the.
Rym: that's the start I mean, he's basically abusive and torturing toward animals.
Scott: So they arrest him and take him to a mental institution and the mental institution is very Classic mental institution, you know, the was that Classic at mental institution.
Scott: Okay, sort of like one flew over the cuckoo's nest style.
Rym: Yeah, I mean their their immediate treatment is well.
Rym: Well electro shock the hate out of him as we all know works wonderfully.
Scott: Oh, it works perfectly.
Scott: every time turns nutty people into perfect.
Rym: gentlemen now This is where the comic I guess really begins because during this electroshock therapy He has a vision.
Scott: I have a vision.
Rym: I Have a vision of a manga.
Rym: that's kind of depressing perhaps.
Rym: basically, he's entreated upon by what I guess you could call a goddess or a god some sort of deity a statue something and He is told that he is going to be punished for his crimes against love by forevermore repeating the cycle of Falling in love with someone or having someone fall in love with him and then one of the two of them or both of them Dying in some horrible way before they can consummate their love or truly be happy.
Scott: Well now the structure of the rest of the manga follows directly from that vision He had.
Scott: basically it alternates between the quote real world or the present world Which is the world in which he is Shogo Chikashi.
Scott: I think his last name is Shogo something Shogo and you know, he's in the mental institution and where he goes from there immediately without you know And it's just direct right?
Scott: so every other chapter is him in that you know default world and every other chapter where it is sort of You know Tezuka likes to do this a lot where he'll have sort of like the same Characters in like some other setting, you know, it's not really the same characters exactly.
Scott: It's like reincarnations of those characters and it's sort of like, you know Imagine if you go to see a play and you know It's like the and you see the play and an acting troupe puts on the play then, you know The next week and it's the same acting troupe putting on a different play.
Scott: so it sort of alternates to these other plays other stories of you know falling in love and then Dying horribly and never actually getting to live out your wonderful love and tragedy.
Scott: But with the same actors.
Rym: it gets confusing at first just because you feel like The world you were presented with was a lie.
Rym: and there's all this stuff.
Rym: and it's once you get back to the the original.
Rym: You know, he is Shogo again after the first interlude you started.
Rym: I guess it grounds it and it makes more sense from that point forward.
Scott: Yeah, it's like it goes from the mental hospital.
Scott: And then I think it's like World War one or two.
Scott: It's a war in Germany.
Rym: It's a World War two.
Rym: is it because they're rounding up Jews in box.
Scott: Okay, cuz I didn't.
Scott: I haven't read it recently.
Scott: I'm just flipping through it to try to remember.
Scott: so I didn't remember it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well the chapters are I'm looking at Wikipedia here D Blumen und delete.
Scott: Oh, I got the carrot.
Rym: Yeah flowers and the corpse.
Rym: Shogo has a vision of Nazi era Germany And of course falls in love with one of the girls who was in the boxcar.
Rym: He is transporting it.
Rym: It ends in tragedy.
Scott: No, I wonder what kind of tragedy?
Rym: and it goes on from there and I guess it.
Rym: what I could think what Tezuka was doing is Each of these stories while they might seem out there and some people remark that Maybe he was just kind of using up extra stories that he had to fill this out.
Rym: and that may have been true.
Rym: but each one kind of puts forth a Situation.
Rym: it's kind of like a moral dilemma.
Rym: You know when you're trying to argue with someone about morals and you always set up the.
Rym: well What if there was a car and it was gonna go off a cliff?
Rym: You could save the people by shoving a fat man in the way But then the fat man would die.
Rym: and you kind of set up a specific situation to test a very specific Moral idea and have a nation about it.
Scott: and then you set up multiple moral dilemmas and you get the person to decide one way on one and one way on the Other and you say haha.
Scott: Look you have an internal moral contradiction.
Scott: You're not consistent.
Rym: Well, that's not what I usually do but now that can be fun that it that is fun.
Scott: But
Rym: this kind of does that at each one of these lives he lives and I do like how about halfway through each one You completely forget about his real life and you care a lot more about this fake
Scott: life Especially when reading the Queen Sigma chapter that that whole chapter was like a whole it when I was reading that I Kind of forgot it wasn't like a chapter of Phoenix almost and then I go back and I'm like, oh right nutty guy I was in the present.
Scott: I was very surprised when the the Queen Sigma part ends and then he's back in the real world again Cuz Queen Sigma like could have stood on its own as an awesome sort of future manga about love and tragedy.
Scott: Well, I think they all kind of stand on their own except for one I guess the one problem last one which sort of requires, you know, the two the one that's two before that And the one that's two before that.
Rym: Well, I guess that could be counted as one together.
Rym: Okay?
Rym: Yeah now again, we're avoiding spoilers.
Rym: I'll say this if you think we've spoiled anything Seriously, don't worry because this thing.
Scott: All right, this book right is.
Scott: how many freaking pages 541 pages.
Scott: this is one
Rym: of those situations where How they get there and is a lot more important than what they do when they get there And the journey is a lot more than the end and even if you know how it ends That's really not going to affect it too much.
Scott: And I mean if you if you understand anything about literature at all You could see how it's gonna end right from the get-go.
Scott: as soon as that statue says, you know You're gonna fall in love and then have tragedy all the time.
Scott: and then you read a short story Where there's love and tragedy and you then you go back to the main story.
Scott: Then you're another story of legend love and tragedy.
Scott: I wonder how the main story is gonna end.
Rym: Well, the thing that really struck me was that I was told by this comic right away that it will always end in tragedy And yet I never saw it coming.
Scott: No, I think the thing was is that while it always ended in tragedy They mix it up.
Scott: It's not like the same Romeo and Juliet tragedy every time it's a little different.
Scott: You know, sometimes they die this way or sometimes dead unexpectedly or you know You don't know the timing of it.
Scott: because you have this giant volume in front of you You don't know where each chapter begins and ends.
Rym: Well, I think it's also just that.
Rym: I think this is one of Tezuka's Brilliances.
Rym: is that even though you it's a foregone conclusion what's going to happen?
Rym: Hope is dangled in front of you and you always feel like there's a way out.
Scott: Oh constantly I was.
Rym: just how about it gets?
Rym: you always think it'll be okay.
Rym: They'll make it this time.
Rym: The one
Scott: thing
Rym: they
Scott: were one thing that carried me through this book is I was always holding on to this Hope no matter which chapter it was that the insane guy was gonna become a good Person in the end and everything was gonna be okay, and he was gonna be uninsane.
Scott: because they keep.
Scott: you know He keeps making progress and he keeps moving forward.
Scott: and you know, he sees things.
Scott: He doesn't completely change his ways, but he's getting better.
Scott: and I'm like at the end.
Scott: He's gonna get better He's gonna learn a lesson from all these different things.
Scott: Well,
Rym: especially the fact that this when he's in these alternate visions he doesn't have any memory of who he was and Notice that when he doesn't have the memories of his abusive relationship with his mother and his you know bad childhood He is a pretty normal person who makes I mean, he's still himself.
Rym: It's just without those memories.
Scott: He's kind of an ass He's not like.
Rym: no he is an ass But I think he would have been an ass even if his mother hadn't beaten him with a broomstick Repeatedly and denied him the true knowledge of love.
Scott: Yeah, but well, he says he's written by Tezuka.
Rym: Yeah, but even then despite being an ass I mean, he's still he.
Rym: it doesn't have this problem except in the real world when he has this bad upbringing kind of holding him back, yep, and This is where I really took issue with I don't know.
Rym: Daryl Sarad and Gerald wrath called the Clarissa when they talked about this.
Rym: Oh, man.
Rym: Oh, there was a spoiler Just because you know, they they talk about how.
Rym: Well, I'm not gonna talk about what they said but basically I think that Apollo's song is an Incredibly strong testament to the power of love and the importance of love and a lot of people read this especially with the opening scene and the closing scene which kind of comes full circle and I don't think it's a spoiler to say that you'll see the parallels of how it was all a cycle in the end.
Rym: and the Very opening scene has much in common with the very ending scene.
Rym: But I guess there's this idea that if you read it kind of superficially love is bad or love is this thing that is thrust upon us by biology and as a result were forced to live this cursed existence or love is just a biological thing to force us to breed and continue existing or anything like that.
Rym: and we know we talk about testing to set up all these moral dilemmas.
Rym: and Very specifically the Queen Sigma segment is set up in my opinion to show that all along the way You could always use the excuse of oh well biology forced them to this that one specifically says that that's not true.
Rym: And I think that's where the true moral of this work comes out.
Rym: because remember well I guess remember if you've read it or not.
Rym: But I'm gonna make a minor spoiler here.
Rym: Queen Sigma and all these Synthians do not have Genitals and do not engage in sex ever.
Rym: They have no need of sex to reproduce at all and they make that clear Continuously throughout that chapter.
Rym: Yep, and yet love still blooms.
Scott: Yeah, Queen Sigma is all like crazy in love with this guy Even though like she can't control herself even and he's like, ah get away from me you crazy bitch.
Rym: And I guess the real moral of this I mean without the Queen Sigma segment You could easily say that Tezuka's writing was basically saying that love is this horrible biological impulse that leads off into tragedy that we have no power over but with that segment and with that one Simple thing that one dilemma set up where it shows that biology is not the only factor.
Rym: I think what it's saying is that no matter how bad it gets love always blooms.
Rym: that love is the most powerful force ever.
Scott: Even says so much at the end of the book.
Scott: He says between man and woman male and female.
Rym: without that love the history of the human race would have ended long ago And you could say oh, well, yes, obviously because without that they wouldn't have made babies.
Rym: There's a lot more to it than that and I guess you have to really read this work Fully and kind of think about it or else to come away with a really superficial understanding of it.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Also If you read like what Tezuka had to say about it, you know, he was really sorry It was this was written in a day That was very like student movement kind of times, you know in Japan mostly and there was a lot of It's sort of a sex education kind of thing.
Scott: in a way and I think you know from that Perspective Tezuka was trying to say and he wasn't teaching you how to do it this, you know in the cold Scientific way, but he was sort of saying, you know, you know sex and love should kind of go together.
Scott: You don't you don't want just sex without the love.
Scott: or you know love with you know And love without the sex is also sort of not so good.
Rym: Well, I don't know.
Rym: if he's saying that too much then you say I think all he's saying is that love doesn't conquer all and that love will not allow you by in and of itself to survive or to Create or to beat your the odds and win.
Rym: but love is more important than winning.
Rym: Mmm, and cuz that happens every time.
Rym: all these stories are kind of.
Rym: they say look at this love bloomed Anyway, and it got snuffed out.
Rym: but people always held on to love before they held on to anything else.
Rym: and then the without Queen Sigma that would have been lost.
Rym: on the fact that It goes beyond that and says that love has nothing to do with biology in the long run.
Scott: Yep, and also in a way he's saying, you know If if without if without love things will end then if things are still going on then love must still be there somewhere.
Rym: So, I don't know what else more we can say.
Rym: I mean, I don't want to spoil how each one of these segments ends other than the obvious.
Scott: Yep We could talk about how it relates to the you know, legends of Apollo, but that's kind of very specific thing in the story.
Rym: Yeah, I almost feel like it'd be out of place.
Scott: I recommend though if you read this because I didn't know that any stories about you know The mythology of Apollo before reading this and it's incredibly relevant Can do what he was doing.
Scott: does it Apollo song?
Rym: for a reason Doesn't it lay it near the end?
Rym: pretty much re-relate that one story of Apollo.
Scott: I think it does pretty explicitly.
Scott: I know I didn't know the story of Apollo said you realize what it was doing.
Rym: Well Apollo did many things but yeah many things.
Scott: but just go read, you know on the internet It should be easy to find stories of you know, Greek mythology and stuff.
Scott: Just read you know about Apollo read like a synopsis read about Apollo and the Laurel Yeah, and then read this book and you'll go A lot more than you would otherwise.
Rym: I guess a lot of people review this and say that and I'm not talking about anyone in particular.
Rym: seriously now Just that they people don't look upon.
Rym: This is one of Tezuka stronger works and a lot of people much prefer many of his other works.
Rym: so they say that this one's depressing or on Tezuka or not characteristic of his writing and I Really think that those people just didn't get it and that it's actually not a pessimistic work at all.
Scott: No, this is a this is a terrific work And if you know any other thing is it compared to Tezuka's other works?
Scott: I actually you know while it may not be representative of his greater body of work in many ways You know I like it more because it lacks a lot of though It doesn't have as many random comedic panels and it doesn't have you know A lot of those other things that Tezuka works have that it sort of make them You know less serious like even ode to kira hito Which is the most similar to this.
Scott: one had a lot of those random silly panels all over the place.
Rym: also human tempera.
Scott: Yeah, human tempera and this had some of that, you know, it's never gonna be completely devoid But it was really lacking and it was sort of like, you know You read Phoenix and your is the serious parts.
Scott: There's not so serious parts It's it's like just the serious part sort of like in Buddha, which was mostly just serious parts.
Scott: but this I think is the greatest percentage of just seriousness.
Scott: and Because I read those other manga, you know of Tezuka's mostly for the serious side and the corny jokes are okay once in a while But most of the time I ignore them.
Scott: So this was really up my alley.
Scott: And if you like the serious side of Tezuka stuff this is also up your alley
Rym: and I guess what I could say is that our opinion that this is an optimistic work and that it is very much in line with what Tezuka tends to write about and That other people may have misinterpreted it.
Rym: We I could cite countless examples from the work and so could Scott probably if he thought about it Even though he hasn't read it in a while, but I just read it again.
Rym: I'd be like, ah, yeah The only reason or not is that I don't want to spoil those things because those are much closer to the story and they'd kind Of ruin it for you.
Rym: Yeah, I guess the Queen Sigma I mean the fact that she doesn't have genitals is probably the strongest piece of evidence But there's a lot more when her face changes at one point and that's actually a really powerful scene.
Scott: Yep, if you've actually if you've read brave new world.
Scott: that chapter will also make a lot of sense more to you.
Rym: Yes, it will All right.
Scott: So yeah, do we want to say anything else?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I hope you're all enjoying your Halloween.
Rym: sadly It's more difficult for us to enjoy Halloween now that we're not in a college campus.
Rym: Halloween is on a Wednesday.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's okay.
Scott: So Oh Samu Tezuka Apollo's song it's 1995 from vertical incorporated.
Rym: it's well worth it.
Scott: You should be able to get it on Amazon probably for less than 1995 Which is the cover prep.
Rym: and seriously don't listen to what everyone else says about it.
Rym: Just read it and if you disagree with us tell us I wouldn't.
Scott: I would not recommend this as your first Tezuka though.
Scott: Ah first Tezuka, I'd say read Phoenix Yeah Read a Phoenix or a Buddha or something like that and then read this just.
Scott: you know You want to be familiar with Tezuka before you read this one that you do.
Rym: After all, where else would a woman have just randomly built a cage in which she sleeps just in case There's a crazy love killer around?
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.