Rym: It's Tuesday November 20th 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are hype for PAX Unplugged.
Rym: It's coming up, and it's the second one ever.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So one of the things I have to do in the course of my job because I'm like a business manager owner type these days like a product manager is I gotta like go to team dinners like take a bunch of people out to Stuff and like hang out with all you know the people who actually build.
Rym: because I don't build anything I just decide what to build and how to build it and when to build it.
Rym: the easy part to it.
Rym: It's surprising how hard that part is sometimes.
Rym: But so I'm at one of these things and I got a team that pretty cool.
Rym: They're all like really gamer e. so we're talking about like game stuff And it's fun.
Rym: and then at one point someone's like one of my one of my like senior engineers It was real good says something like yeah, I really love Classic console gaming.
Scott: uh-huh is he gonna say some PlayStation game?
Rym: PlayStation 2 I picked up used GameCube Mm-hmm.
Rym: so already like I'm already feeling old like you can see like Rym's feeling of age Escalates rapidly at this point, and I got the original Smash Brothers for it.
Rym: That was the first one right.
Rym: there couldn't have been one before that.
Rym: yeah, yeah this conversation just made me feel Incredibly old.
Scott: so on the internet today, so in these in the Nintendo switch subreddit Everyone's of course like Metroid Prime 4 when's it coming?
Scott: when's it coming?
Scott: right, but people have basically been based on no information whatsoever.
Scott: Right have basically been in assuming praying begging that Nintendo will re-release all the old Metroid Prime 1 2 3 Which they already did on the Wii.
Scott: there was a Metroid Prime trilogy re-release disc But they're hoping for Metroid Prime re-release HD.
Scott: They really want this for some reason and I'm like you could probably for less than the cost.
Scott: even if they put that out It'll be like 60 bucks for less than the cost of that.
Scott: you could probably go get an old Wii or GameCube and the original discs or that trilogy disc for the Wii.
Scott: Why the fuck do you need this re-released for the switch although?
Scott: I must say again.
Scott: It is really stupid.
Scott: if I was the CEO of Nintendo Every single game ever published by Nintendo would be in the e-shop Or there would be some sort of Netflix subscription, and you would just get them all the end
Rym: Yeah, I feel like
Scott: because it's like yeah, you could just go get it, but that's sort of a pain in the ass.
Rym: Yeah, the Nintendo service the problem is Nintendo is incapable of like working In anything other than the Nintendo silo is the problem.
Rym: like they have they're set in their ways.
Rym: nothing will ever fix that.
Rym: It's just.
Scott: I was just buying it.
Rym: But I'm increasingly like I've gone to board game nights with like my engineers and co-workers.
Rym: And the thing is these people are not that much younger than me like they're in their late 20s.
Rym: And yet the gulf of like knowledge of the history of games among people who are deeply invested in games is Terrifying to me partly because we got that when we got to RIT.
Scott: I grew up with the NES and slightly Atari 2600.
Rym: I grew up with Atari 2600, 7800, all 16-bit and then even into the.
Scott: you know the end of high school.
Scott: There was the N64 and such right and then the PlayStation 2 came out while we were in college, so then Even though I was only in school for you know already in the second third year of RIT People that were only one or two years younger came in and they grew up with PlayStation.
Scott: they somehow did not see.
Scott: How did they skip where I saw some Atari 2600?
Scott: How did someone two years younger than me miss ten years?
Scott: Plus of games?
Rym: now that would be fine like I'm not gonna be.
Rym: the old man is like ah kids They don't know shit cuz over.
Scott: someone who's like feel that That's wrong for someone who's ten years younger than me.
Scott: I assume that anything older than PlayStation 3.
Scott: They don't know.
Rym: yep But what bothers me?
Rym: I guess what bothers me isn't so much that Like people younger than me don't know the things I know.
Rym: cuz that's expected.
Rym: like that's how the world works.
Rym: time advances.
Rym: What I didn't expect is how rapidly the memory hole like Devours these things because I know a lot about gaming from before the era I played games and yet most people I encounter Literally know nothing about the era before they started gaming even if they are deeply invested in the hobby.
Scott: Well, I think the thing is even people who even just current knowledge.
Scott: right.
Scott: there seems to be this huge gap between People who read the internet and people who just do a thing.
Rym: well It's weird.
Scott: like there's someone there are people who will go to the store.
Scott: They'll go to GameStop.
Scott: They'll buy games They'll take them home and play them and they'll play a lot of games and spend all day playing games and never read a Single video game website or magazine and thus they know nothing.
Scott: and whereas I grew up reading Video game magazines basically just ads for video games video game websites So I knew things.
Rym: as I seek out information about things, but the internet II people I meet who are a little younger than us.
Rym: they seek out information about new things But they have never like looked into the shroud of the past like they were did.
Rym: I overheard some co-workers last week Debating what the first Final Fantasy game was because they weren't sure Final Fantasy one Weren't.
Rym: but they weren't sure because like you just went over there.
Scott: Can they just Google what was the first Final Fantasy game?
Scott: because that's like.
Scott: what happens to me is I don't spend time like Let me go learn about the past.
Scott: I just if I happen to have a question.
Scott: Yeah, I google it and Slowly over time.
Scott: I remember where to Google to get a thing and also the old one.
Scott: when I remember the actual information I just remember where I saw the information.
Rym: when I google something like that the generally there's one of two results either There's an answer and now I know or there isn't a clear answer in which case I just found something amazing that I wanted to like track down and figure out.
Scott: you go set the Final Fantasy people straight.
Rym: Yeah, I literally like stepped into the conference room.
Rym: It was like hi none of you know me.
Rym: the first Final Fantasy was Final Fantasy one And it came out on the Nintendo entertainment system in the Famicom, and I walked away before they could react And I just left them in the room.
Scott: and why don't you be like?
Scott: I grew up playing that game.
Scott: I sold it back to Funko.
Rym: No, no what I actually said?
Rym: the words I said were like I hate you guys don't know me but what I said was in my professional expertise And I started to just explain to them the history of Final Fantasy and then I left and it was pretty funny.
Rym: But uh yeah, there is some interesting news.
Rym: so most of you don't seem to follow the world chess Championships.
Scott: no cuz chess is hella boring.
Scott: I would rather watch many sports that I hate and call boring than watch chess which I respect chess players more than some of the athletes Like.
Scott: I hate fucking curling right and I respect people who play chess more than I respect people who curl I but I would rather watch the curling.
Scott: I'd rather watch curling than I hate fucking.
Rym: I'd rather watch curling than chess.
Rym: I would rather watch chess than soccer.
Scott: It depends I.
Rym: so I don't watch the chess live cuz I don't care that much No but I had.
Rym: I do follow chess because I like to look at the results of games and Step back through.
Rym: cuz you get you know this stuff.
Rym: like there's a million chess websites We can look and see like what the fuck happened in this game.
Scott: with commentary I don't.
Scott: I pay attention to the developments in the chess world Slightly about as much as I pay attention to developments in the go world or the counter-strike world.
Scott: yep, right?
Scott: Where's like?
Scott: ah there's a. there's a thing happening, but like I don't follow it.
Rym: So I'm gonna set the stage here.
Rym: the thing that's been happening for the last decade or more Is that and we did.
Rym: the funny thing is the reason I'm bringing this up is that I've been saying this in lectures and publicly and professionally for like a goddamn decade and I I am being proven right and I'm very happy about this but It happens to me all the time.
Rym: Yeah and I'm.
Rym: this one is interesting though because math people are backing up my like.
Rym: I Like I didn't know the math and I just made a lot of assumptions about the math and the math is backing me up.
Scott: But basically you know, it's like guessing about P versus anything.
Rym: Yeah So here's the deal chess.
Rym: Humans are not competitive in chess and haven't been for a long time.
Rym: No Even shitty a eyes are better than any human can possibly be at chess.
Scott: usually when people Commentate chess like I was the one chess I did watch a few years ago the last time I paid slightly more attention the commentators are basically the computer would figure out the move and while they were the best move and while they were waiting for Then they would have the computer generate like other possible moves that would also be good yeah, and like top five moves from the computer and then while the person is still thinking on their turn and then they would use The computer's best moves as you know aid in discussing what move the person was going to make.
Rym: Yep So basically humans like cannot compete in chess against even shitty a eyes.
Rym: So human chess as in terms of strategy has diverged a lot from what the a eyes do because that space is still going.
Rym: It's AI versus AI and the chess that they play is fucking weird as shit, right?
Scott: But the a lot of people I think at one I don't know.
Scott: This is a while ago years ago that I read that this was happening, but that people were basically learning from the AI.
Scott: That's part two intentionally trying to play like them as much as they could.
Rym: so Humans who are trying to be good at chess are studying what the AI's are doing.
Scott: But right this year.
Scott: That's many-year-old news.
Rym: Yeah, so the Predicted outcome of this is that like the attractors in chess?
Rym: Like if you play randomly what is gonna be the result of your actions over time and like skilled players and all this?
Rym: but chess probably devolves into a draw in long and play.
Rym: and My evidence for that is not the current math because I don't know it like I'm not a mathematician that ship sailed But because as I studied chess to write GeekNights panels and just my own amusement It seems like most of the rules changes to chess in modern history have been to handle Increasingly complex situations that ended.
Rym: draws like draws are the answers right of chess game.
Scott: the only way to fix this is to change the rules of chess itself so that a draw cannot happen and the happen because that would be nothing like chess.
Rym: it really looks like Players can force a draw pretty much if they want to which is the endgame of checkers.
Rym: Mm-hmm checkers is proven.
Rym: chess It's not proven seems likely.
Rym: so humans can study a eyes but they can basically study what the eyes are doing to be able to take a game where they might lose and Guarantee that they'll draw the game to move on to the next game.
Scott: I wonder right so so far checkers.
Rym: We've proven There's a soft proof.
Rym: There's not a hard proof.
Rym: They have not explored every game stage chess looks like it.
Scott: Yes, I wonder is are there any out there any perfect information?
Scott: Games that we've proven like oh, it's a win or a law or anything like that.
Scott: So that way there's a bunch.
Scott: Okay, otherwise, they'd be like whoa, maybe all games like this Yeah are draws and we could maybe make a higher level rule.
Scott: So I guess not go.
Rym: I don't think has a draw state at the end.
Rym: Checkers definitely both players.
Scott: Oh, we don't know it's way too far out.
Scott: We probably won't live to see.
Rym: the problem with chess Is that the endgame can get into all these loops where the game will be a draw and there's a like.
Scott: You move your dude back and forth there move my king back and forth.
Scott: I love that.
Rym: so you can tell.
Scott: an elegant provision putting a rule for OSHA like OSHI.
Rym: Yeah So they did.
Rym: chess has a ton of rules like OSHI to ensure that loops don't happen where a game that's entering a loop state Is a guaranteed draw?
Rym: And I think the only thing human players will be able to do in the future is if they're losing force a draw.
Rym: So the world chess championships that are going right now have had eight crazy epic games that have all ended in draws Mmm, and they can only have four more games that I will bet money will end in draws and after that They're gonna go into sudden death Which will probably end in draws.
Scott: so chess people probably mad at me for this and it's probably hella wrong, right?
Scott: Yeah, I want to say it anyway, cuz that's how I do.
Scott: So I just gonna admit that it's hella wrong to begin with.
Scott: right but usually in my experience my very weak experience playing chess Right, which doesn't even rise to the level of high school.
Scott: I'm like Not even high school chess club level right?
Scott: It's lower level than that.
Scott: It's nerd who knows how to play chess.
Rym: We should play a game of chess against each other.
Scott: Yeah, I won.
Rym: Yeah, you did.
Rym: we should play one now and livestream it.
Scott: The point is is that at my level of I know how to play chess and that's about it.
Scott: Most of the draw stalemate end states involve one player moving their king back and forth So it can't be killed and the other player moving and attacking peas back and forth into it like check You can't kill me check.
Scott: You can't kill me.
Scott: All right, that's the thing that I have seen personally the most common State event now, I do know that you probably didn't know all the rules for draws.
Scott: I have no idea what the rules are, but that's the complex than you think.
Scott: I'm sure they are.
Scott: But I'm saying is that that's the most common state that I see and that's definitely a draw right?
Scott: Yeah, and but in that situation It's like well the other player who's doing who's moving me say Queen back and forth Also has their King like hiding out in the back somewhere, right?
Scott: You know, otherwise they would have lost already, right?
Scott: Why don't we define?
Scott: The rules of chess to be like, well look You're the one who's moving your fucking King back and forth.
Scott: try not to die And I'm the one who's moving my attacking piece back and forth try to kill.
Scott: Therefore we're gonna define this not as a draw but as I fucking win because you're the one who's hiding and I'm the one who's attacking King back and forth.
Rym: doesn't really happen the way you have experienced it in real.
Scott: I'm sure it doesn't.
Scott: I press Why I preface this by saying I'm probably stupid.
Scott: Please correct me people who know more than me, which is anyone who's played in each s. But we could define we could just by definition just change the rules of chess to define some of the stalemate states Where the person who is more defensively positioned in the stalemate loses.
Scott: So here's the problem.
Scott: is the rule so that no, it's not a stalemate.
Scott: Here's the problems because you're on defense.
Rym: Here's the simplest problem with that because I don't want to get it like this.
Rym: I don't want to make the show about this.
Rym: Yeah, the simplest problem is white already has an advantage.
Rym: Yep, if you codify those rules you probably turn chess into a white wins game.
Scott: I mean checkers is a first player wins game.
Rym: So no checkers is a force.
Scott: I'm a tic-tac-toe.
Scott: I said checkers.
Scott: Yeah, brain had a picture of tic-tac-toe.
Rym: That's fine but basically the end result of this is I think the game of chess by the nature of its fundamental rules is Going to be a guaranteed draw game for humans forever.
Rym: good And I said boring game that it'll be a guaranteed draw game for the AI's.
Scott: all you people who play chess and are stupid Hella smart and I respect you for being fucking awesome at games.
Scott: Come play real games with us and not stupid fucking chess.
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: You know the go come play some.
Scott: you know, they go people gathering and blow the doors off right.
Rym: come play with us and go Right, even though you know, we'll have a similar problem in the sense You need to play.
Scott: go come play fucking settlers and kick the shit out of everyone except when the dice go poorly.
Scott: Yeah, come play fucking netrunner come play.
Scott: Well, you know Some playing your boring ass chess.
Rym: the thing about nerd games and we talk about this a lot in our panels Is that come play 1846 if you play trains if you play nerd games?
Rym: Like we play them and you treat them seriously like chess the entire Tournament scene devolves within a year or so and the game is solved and you move on to another game.
Scott: Come play NFL.
Scott: come be an NFL football coach.
Rym: I think the future will be The kind like that's what chess is.
Rym: a sport will probably die out in popular like even like chess circles in the long run.
Rym: But I think you're gonna see a class of players of games who are the professional board like abstract board gamers that move from game to game to game and when they saw the game To the point of the AI's are better than them and they have like draw state or whatever.
Rym: They move on to another game or they do like triathlons of What I try to do, but I get no respect for it.
Scott: If I play a boring game like chess, then I get respect, but if I play my nerdy games get no respect.
Rym: The next game is on November 21st, I'm going to on November 22nd see what happened in that game.
Rym: I practically guarantee games 9 10 11 and 12 are gonna be draws and then we're gonna go into the Kind of ridiculous and hilarious over time that chest overtime should just be the default mode.
Rym: It's basically just speed chess, right?
Scott: Speed chess should be the only chess because if people are playing so perfectly that they can push a draw given all the time to Figure out their moves just give them like 10 seconds per move.
Scott: fucking deal with it.
Scott: You miss a move you lose immediately.
Scott: Fuck dude.
Rym: You know what the endgame is gonna be like.
Rym: It's basically you get like four minutes total.
Scott: And right if we can't test who can make if we both players are equally good at making decisions given a minute We'll see who's equally good at making decisions given five seconds.
Rym: You know, here's the tiebreaker.
Rym: You just they go to another table.
Rym: You got to play.
Rym: go against each other now.
Rym: Good luck.
Rym: Have fun.
Scott: I hope you know the rules.
Scott: just just boxing.
Scott: Let's go.
Rym: Okay Just boxing is literally what was just suggested in the fall in the chat.
Scott: Just like this is a good sport I'm like, yes.
Rym: So in some other news before we get into the bigger news about this about these kinds of games We're gonna do a whole show on this game probably as soon as we play it some more.
Rym: So key Forge has a problem if you're not aware and the problem is talk about this already I don't think so.
Rym: Okay, but really briefly there are unfortunately named decks.
Rym: Mm-hmm and The.
Rym: basically if you get an unfortunately named deck they filtered out all the bad words.
Scott: But there could still theoretically be combinations of normal perfectly normal words that result in bad words.
Rym: now honestly 99% of the ones that I've seen that are designated bad are in my opinion fucking hilarious.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and I would pay extra for those decks because they're not tournament legal.
Scott: What they're doing is if you have a deck that is banned which you can find out by scanning it into the app Yep, because its name is bad.
Scott: They will give you two decks.
Scott: You just return the bad one.
Rym: Hell no Like.
Scott: but if you're not the erect wang of the forest Playing in tournaments, which I won't then you don't give a shit if your deck is banned or not.
Scott: So if the name is hilarious and not offensive to you Why get the two free decks?
Scott: if you got the one awesome hilarious day I want like the the flying boner min of erectile Cove or whatever is gonna come out I would much rather have that deck than the two you're gonna send me with boring names.
Rym: Yep And I'm sure there'll be a point in the future where unfortunately named decks will be worth above market price to collectors.
Scott: There's already some Stores who are opening the decks like the retailers are buying the game wholesale Opening the decks
Rym: sort
Scott: of guessing by looking at the deck list like how you know strong the deck is competitively and then Selling them at like an adjusted price that they just randomly decide.
Scott: Yeah, like I think this deck is gonna kick some fucking ass.
Scott: I'll try out to see if I can sell it opened for like 70 bucks instead of the normal cover price.
Scott: If the name was funny enough like yeah, no, they're not doing it based on the name They're doing it based on the card list which faces outwards.
Rym: Yeah that I wouldn't care about.
Rym: but if the name were funny enough that alone would be enough for me to pay extra.
Scott: Yeah, I think You know.
Scott: on the one hand it's like well, I guess you can do that.
Scott: But on the other hand, it would be kind of awesome to see the publisher just be like, well We're not selling any products to your store anymore.
Scott: Fuck off.
Rym: Yeah, I I'm ambivalent on that issue.
Scott: Yeah, that's sort of like whatever.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see what they do.
Scott: cuz I'm.
Rym: I don't like game retailers Game but there's some news for the other game that we haven't talked about a lot yet on GeekNights.
Scott: artifacts All right.
Scott: So artifact if you don't know is valves.
Scott: entry into the card game world is the first new valve game since Dota 2 and as we've said Looks really fun Looks great.
Scott: It is also designed by Richard Garfield just like key forges and it is a competitive Collectible card game and it's based on dota.
Scott: But actually that's kind of good because it's sort of like hey, there's like three boards.
Scott: You're managing.
Scott: It's really complex.
Scott: It looks like a really fun game.
Rym: I got a little bit of Colonel Blotto going on.
Scott: Yeah, I was really hyped to actually play this game until I found out how they were selling the cards.
Scott: We talked about this in GeekNights before.
Scott: I'm pretty sure They're going to sell you.
Scott: you can get in on the game for 20 bucks Which gets you like a starter set full of stuff which like old magic when I was a kid.
Rym: Yeah, 20 bucks would get me like a starter deck in a couple boos, right?
Scott: If you want to buy more cards cost $2 a pack, which is slightly more than Hearthstone cards.
Scott: Yep The only other way to get more cards is to play the competitive like drafting mode, right?
Scott: But where you like have to use tickets to play in a draft and then if you do well in the draft you could then somehow earn more free drafts and More free draft tickets and also some cards, right?
Scott: Or you can buy cards on the secondary market because you can sell cards on the steam marketplace.
Scott: So many copies of a card you can sell them for money.
Scott: that that already.
Scott: and then people can buy cards for money.
Scott: Specific cards that nonsense.
Rym: Well, what is wrong with you?
Scott: So basically I as soon as I saw this news about how the game we monetize is it nope not touching it all not even Gonna bother playing it.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: Nope, because even Hearthstone is sort of like.
Scott: well You pay a few hundred dollars a year and you have all the Hearthstone cards.
Scott: Yeah, it's a lot of money but it's and it's.
Scott: it's worse than say the netrunner model because the amount of money you have to pay to guarantee getting all the Cards is variable.
Rym: Artifact looks fun enough.
Rym: I'd pay a hundred bucks a year to just get like all the cards.
Scott: Well, I would pay like but if it was if they could just say hey, you're gonna get all the cards I would pay the $20 to get in.
Scott: and if I played it a lot and Kept playing it and got way into it and stopped playing other card games because I was playing artifact all the time Then I would I would pay a monthly fee Like 10 15 bucks a month if I just had every artifact card ever and I could play all I wanted.
Rym: Chris Rymer points out In the chat, which I was gonna say in a little bit This is basically the bullshit business model of Magic the Gathering online.
Rym: We all know how well that did.
Scott: Well MTG Arena Which is a magic online thing has the same business model as Hearthstone.
Scott: basically only it's magic cards and it's a worst game.
Scott: but yeah, it's like.
Scott: Now what's the news?
Scott: is that basically the thing that I figured out months ago?
Scott: So I didn't bother with artifact.
Scott: the artifact open beta opened up.
Scott: Yeah, because it was a closed beta all these people got in and realized Oh, the only way I can fucking do anything is either spend money to get cards or Get draft tickets, which cost a dollar each because you buy them in packs of five or five bucks.
Scott: Otherwise, I'm just stuck with the same cards.
Scott: I got for my 20 bucks and I never get any other more cards ever.
Scott: I don't get a single extra card without spending money.
Scott: It's like going to an arcade where you put a dollar in the machine and you play and you better win three games.
Rym: Meanwhile at least Key Forge.
Rym: I can buy a bunch of decks and just play and I'm good to go.
Scott: Yeah, well, it's a card.
Scott: when you get cardboard for your money.
Scott: Yeah, right I guess we'll last.
Scott: you could play Key Forge forever even a hundred years from now.
Scott: I mean your cardboard doesn't disintegrate.
Scott: There's a.
Rym: there is a world where I could praise valve for trying to do a different monetization model But the reality is one.
Scott: they picked the worst possible one.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: well, they really wanted to use their marketplace.
Rym: Yeah, but the marketplace is the fucking problem, right?
Rym: That is the my whining.
Rym: a real money marketplace is like the like.
Rym: that is the most harm You can make.
Scott: I feel like we should monetization my shitty generic magic clone card game Just like all the rest.
Scott: not even bother trying to make a new or interesting game.
Rym: Just like Billy and the snake man, too Yeah, just make a game.
Scott: just like hearthstone.
Scott: just like magic just like all the other card games.
Scott: you put out dudes and they fight.
Scott: Just you know mix it up a tiny amount make it slightly unique and just do the business model of you pay a flat fee And have all the cards and that's the only difference between us and the competition.
Rym: Oh Wow, I just looked up Billy versus the snake man.
Rym: Okay, I Guess it's still around.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Anyway, I'm not gonna follow that thread any further because it's time for Things of the day.
Scott: what he got All right.
Scott: So when I was a kid and I was stuck home from school for whatever reason at 11 a.m Eastern time would be the price is right now and watch that shit no matter what cuz.
Scott: it was really great and headless.
Rym: It's like a fantastic game show.
Scott: lots of old people commercials But really great show really entertaining worth your hour while you eat lunch.
Scott: feel good to in between playing video games.
Scott: The current host drew Carey not as good as Bob Barker.
Scott: Apparently it's been 11 fucking years.
Rym: Next you're gonna tell me Craig Kilborn doesn't host the Daily Show anymore, but Still a great show.
Scott: still really hasn't changed fundamentally all that much since 1970 whatever.
Scott: The only problem is I don't know what anything fucking costs anymore Depends what they put on there, but the problem with the price is right is everything is always MSR P's.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like you're gonna say the price you pay at the store.
Scott: That's way under the actual MSRP.
Scott: Yeah, they use on the price Or anyway, one of the best parts of the price is right is when they spin the wheel twice of the show.
Scott: Does he who gets in the showcase but showcase showdown, but you can also just win money on the fucking wheel You get a dollar.
Scott: I saw a lot of people get a dollar on this wheel.
Scott: It's basically like a one out of what 20 something It's like.
Scott: it's like a one.
Scott: it is only like 20 something.
Scott: slots on there right zero five ten twenty.
Scott: Yeah, it's like twenty one and twenty shot of getting a dollar on there.
Scott: and you know with two spins You can add up to a dollar and win that way also, right?
Scott: So You got to get.
Scott: imagine this show has been played five times a week For how many decades?
Rym: Yep, so the odds are You can think of.
Scott: eventually there's gonna be a situation where all the contestants get a dollar.
Scott: Well, this was a special.
Scott: not only did that happen.
Scott: Obviously everyone got a dollar.
Scott: This is a special event for the show's anniversary Drew Carey's anniversary or whatever some kind of special event where you could win even more money on the wheel.
Scott: and Boy, did they win even more money on the wheel in some, you know crazy luck event Which was again guaranteed to happen because the show's on five days a week with two wheel spinning events per day With six people spinning this 30 times.
Scott: people get to play this wheel spinning game every week forever.
Scott: So it's gonna happen eventually and it did so.
Scott: there you go.
Scott: You can see it happen.
Scott: I still we were talking about before the show, but it's funny that it happened during the special extra prize time.
Rym: I just I've wanted my whole life to spin that goddamn way.
Scott: It looks like it's kind of heavy right like it has some heft to it But also that it has like, you know It's a well lubricated wheel that keeps going once you get it going with some inertia.
Rym: I remember as a kid I watched an episode where this big dude pulls it down and it just kept spinning and spinning and spinning.
Scott: The point is I just I just really I just I don't care about winning.
Scott: I don't need to be on the show even though that would be fun.
Scott: also, right, you know.
Scott: But the only reason I haven't actually haven't been like.
Scott: if this was in New York and not, California I probably would have gone to be in the audience plenty of time.
Scott: Hell, yeah But I just want to feel what it feels like to spin the wheel, you know Just let me have a spin just so I can get a feel for it.
Rym: They should bring the wheel Comic-con.
Scott: Yeah, I don't care if like you give me money or I'll even give you like a dollar.
Scott: Just let me feel what it feels like to spin the wheel.
Rym: I love the fact that even to this day they basically have Drew Carey using a weird like long stick microphone.
Scott: Well, that's the style exactly.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: The show doesn't change but doesn't need to.
Rym: so my thing of the day is It's more of a science II thing.
Rym: But a lot of people have green laser pens or green lasers because green lasers are really cool.
Scott: And you know green is the best color.
Rym: Yeah green is the best color.
Rym: but y'all know one don't shine lasers in your eye not even red ones.
Scott: and two green laser pens are Known to be particularly dangerous much higher frequency than red and blue.
Scott: Well, not necessarily blue but much higher frequency than red.
Rym: So a Lot of people because independent of this you can buy a lot of stuff on Amazon these days Anyway, so you can just get.
Scott: well you could buy like wood-burning lasers You could buy using craving lasers or all kinds of stuff.
Rym: So the problem here and this video does a really good job of explaining it and it's like really detailed and they show examples and Everything.
Rym: but here's the deal.
Rym: green laser pens aren't just dangerous because it's green and because it's higher power.
Scott: They're extra dangerous because you can see the same way He's not.
Scott: ultraviolet ultraviolet rays are way dangerous because they're high frequency But like low frequency infrared waves aren't gonna hurt you bootleg crap.
Rym: Oh green lasers generate the green color in a way It also generates a ton of in for a red radiation.
Scott: infrared is just heat.
Rym: Yeah, I hurt you which will burn the hell out of your eye.
Scott: Oh, yeah burn Yeah, but it won't cancer you like an ultraviolet or gamma ray or something, but it'll.
Rym: basically it'll blind you way bad.
Scott: Yeah, so even the red laser will blind you way bad.
Scott: It's well-made.
Rym: red lasers and blue lasers tend to not have this additional danger of the umbrellas.
Scott: There's higher frequency than the green laser.
Scott: Wouldn't that burn your eye?
Rym: Oh, they don't dead.
Rym: They don't have that infrared.
Scott: the problem Don't point any laser at any human's eye unless they're a Nazi in which case hold them down.
Scott: Yeah point lasers at both eyes.
Rym: But the problem basically is that the apparent danger of green lasers is way less than the actual danger Because if you buy a cheap green laser the odds are it generates the laser in a way that also generates tons of super dangerous infrared radiation and This the lens that would block that radiation is definitely bootleg and counterfeit Mmm, and this video shows like how to test your green laser pen to see if it's actually outputting a shit ton of infrared radiation.
Scott: You just pointed at your hand and if it feels warm, it's not not enough.
Rym: Watch the video.
Rym: It's pretty good.
Rym: Okay, every question you've had is answered by this video and it's a good video.
Rym: The video is very good goes into great.
Scott: I was watching it.
Scott: You know if you have questions while you're watching a video and the video that answers the questions that say I was watching a cooking Video today, so I was making chilaquiles and I was like and I was like, where's the egg?
Scott: And then he's like, oh I'm gonna fry an egg and I'm like, hello.
Scott: I said two seconds I'm like, whoa, he still hasn't gotten any egg in there.
Scott: He's like a fry egg now.
Rym: So in the meta moment the booklet book is the space Odyssey.
Rym: we'll read it soon.
Rym: we've been busy.
Rym: Yeah PAX Unplugged we'll talk about in a minute because our whole shows about PAX Unplugged.
Rym: but Suffice it to say we will be there live doing two events learn and win Puerto Rico and the 40 tabletop games.
Rym: You must play advanced mode.
Rym: So we'll be there doing two pretty good panels.
Rym: Otherwise, we're just gonna be in tabletop playing games going to panels doing stuff.
Rym: It's gonna be fun time.
Rym: Yep Other meta we Got our first PAX South panel.
Rym: I'm gonna do the official announcement.
Scott: like that was fast.
Scott: We got any MAGFest mag fizzes before packs out.
Rym: Uh, yeah, we had.
Rym: we're doing between four and six mag fest panel too many.
Scott: Yeah You gotta play games you can.
Rym: you only have to be on for it most.
Rym: I might be on more without you because I know You tend to not want to be honest many.
Scott: I want to get in and play free games and go to your kid.
Rym: You will not have to do personally more than four panels Day, I got you think it so at mag fest.
Rym: We're gonna do a bunch of panels There's still like the schedules not live yet, obviously TVD, but we will be there.
Rym: but it PAX South.
Rym: We are going to be doing at least a brand new panel.
Rym: Not rare game mechanics, at least not yet.
Rym: That's not on the schedule yet.
Rym: Then we were probably doing that one at mag fest, but a new one.
Rym: We haven't talked about at all Nostalgia versus game design.
Rym: Okay, you can guess it what that one's gonna be about and you're probably wrong.
Rym: We're gonna make a lot of fun of MOBAs along the way and we're gonna talk about how wind jammers isn't actually that good.
Scott: But anyway wind jammers out on the switch now.
Rym: Yeah, so wind jammers - we'll see how wind jammers - ends up being.
Scott: no It's out.
Rym: Yeah, I've played it.
Rym: I've touched it.
Scott: I think is it?
Scott: there is definitely a some wind jammers in the e-shop.
Scott: I haven't bought.
Rym: So Yeah PAX Unplugged.
Rym: we feel Deserves some hype because we've talked we've done GeekNights for so long over a decade.
Scott: It's sold out yet.
Scott: No, nope that can you are any days sold out?
Rym: Nope, we have done such a big convention center and we're using way more space than we did last year.
Scott: This is like in a major area here, right?
Scott: How could you know?
Scott: the east and west are sold out right.
Scott: south sort of gets really close to sold out.
Rym: almost.
Scott: Yep, right, but we can we vote in Philly which for all its awfulness.
Scott: maybe people, you know realized awful Philly was yeah But you know as a lot of people living near it and it's like how cut this is a pecs.
Rym: you can just go Aren't you going?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So one we've talked a lot like.
Rym: if you want to find our advice I'm like how to go to a con how to go to pack like.
Rym: we've talked about that shit for 13 plus years.
Rym: But I feel like it's worth it because we haven't done that kind of stuff in a while.
Rym: We feel like we did it.
Rym: I feel like it's worth it to hype up PAX Unplugged and to sort of approach it Like it's a new convention and talk about like it in that sense.
Rym: So let's dive right in first.
Rym: PAX Unplugged is a pecs.
Rym: It has all the accoutrement of our regular packs like a compile of it compared to PAX East or PAX West.
Scott: The only thing that is not at PAX Unplugged are video games and video game companies.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It has Concert Megathon.
Scott: it's got acquisitions incorporated.
Rym: It has an expo hall.
Scott: It has a concert.
Scott: I think it does so.
Rym: at least it has main events But generally instead of concert.
Rym: so far the main events have been like at a regular packs in main theater You'll see like acquisitions incorporated or like the C team like that kind of stuff.
Rym: That'll be the main event during the concert slot at PAX Unplugged.
Scott: It's got a keynote which this year So last year the keynote at PAX Unplugged was not very good.
Scott: It was like the CEO of watsy and like it was pretty lame.
Scott: apparently the CEO of watsy is like a marketing guy and he was not the greatest public speaker.
Scott: and Yeah, it was.
Scott: it was disappointing Especially CEO of watsy.
Scott: Well again, they went down to the watsy hole.
Scott: But this time it is Jeremy Crawford the lead rules designer of D&D and the game's managing editor.
Scott: So in effect the person who is the boss of D&D at the current time game wise You know in terms of like, you know The actual game rules and stuff in the game as opposed to say someone who's managing like, you know marketing of D&D, right?
Scott: Yeah, but so hopefully having an actual game person and not a marketing person to make this much more interesting.
Scott: But I still can't deny I'm disappointed that it's another watsy person and another Dude, why can't they go?
Rym: Is yeah, right that's who should I call where to come and talk about like fucking weird.
Scott: Yeah, I should be the first person.
Scott: that should have been the first one, right?
Scott: But yeah, it's like I wish they would get people from these smaller more indie table towel community Someone who's broadly famous like the very least you think they would have had the what's-his-name.
Scott: who did the the Thornwood game for them?
Scott: Whatever Thorn watch game?
Rym: or yeah, really?
Rym: We need to get like mordenkainen.
Scott: But it's like you just get anyone who's from the you know, the not watsy.
Scott: There's other you know, even another tabletop game company or even a bad one, right?
Scott: It's like there's a guy who run Rio Grande games with that with the the cowboy hat.
Scott: What's his name?
Rym: Oh, yeah, someone like that Just basically someone who can tell a bunch of war stories about the game industry.
Rym: that isn't just like marketing for D&D.
Scott: It's like it'd be so easy, but it's like oh they're just going on the watsy hole a second time.
Scott: So next year you better get a non watsy person.
Rym: Yep I would recommend if you're going to PAX Unplugged.
Scott: I'm still going to this keynote.
Rym: Yeah, I go to the keynote every packs.
Rym: I will do this forever.
Rym: So the person who's in charge of D&D right now in general while the like a lot of the more recent keynotes haven't been that great.
Rym: The majority of the keynotes I've been to have been great.
Rym: It's just I've been going to a lot of taxes.
Scott: Did you see?
Scott: the D&D just came out with a box set that is.
Scott: I assume it's three books Which I assume must be players handbook DMS guide monster manual.
Scott: Yeah, I assume those are the three books.
Scott: I don't know about the other choice They would be but for the new it's obviously for whatever.
Scott: the newest edition is fifth edition, right?
Scott: But they were really nice looking books and a really nice box and I was like man if I played D&D right now.
Scott: Totally buy that dude.
Rym: I see I see those books and I just feel like I need to buy them anyway.
Scott: It's a way.
Scott: nice looking box of books
Rym: Also like as much as I look
Scott: it up look for like D&D But as
Rym: much as I like my indie RPGs with all my d6 is my bag of d6 is Every now and then I have my dice back out and I see my d8s and my d20s And part of my brain is like Rym.
Rym: play some fucking D&D.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: You must if you feel it.
Scott: It's happening alright, so the next thing it PAX Unplugged.
Scott: that needs hyping is The key Forge which you talked about a little bit.
Scott: Yeah, but basically they're going all out with this game.
Scott: There's gonna be like non-stop tournament events.
Scott: There's gonna be people selling it people demoing it Right, like they're going all in on this game, which is a game We are obviously somewhat excited for.
Scott: so we will definitely be making at least one stop over in the key Forge zone To see what's up probably to just buy the damn game because I order an Amazon and it keeps getting delayed.
Scott: So I might cancel that order and just buy it.
Scott: It unplugged.
Rym: I doubt I will engage in the tournament scene or serious.
Scott: No, no, bye-bye go over there.
Scott: I mean literally go Like.
Rym: I feel like a bunch of us are gonna play a lot of key for I learned from my netrunner days.
Scott: I am NOT going to competitively play any fantasy flight games game.
Scott: I am only going to.
Scott: just because this one particular game happens to be published by them, but is not designed by anyone there I'm gonna buy one copy of it and play it with people.
Scott: I know according to the rules.
Scott: We know are right.
Rym: Well having played like a little bit like having interacted with the game at PAX West I feel it scratches the itch that has been unscratched since I stopped playing magic in middle school.
Rym: Like that ish has been itching like.
Rym: I'm not gonna pretend I haven't been feeling that ish.
Scott: You should have scratched it with some netrunner.
Rym: Nah, the netrunner didn't scratch it.
Scott: All right, it didn't.
Scott: Much better game probably better game.
Rym: Yeah, it is an objectively better game, but it didn't scratch that itch.
Rym: I'm still not a hundred percent sure why It has to be cardboard or doesn't scratch it, okay Nah So I feel like that.
Rym: we're gonna do that a lot also.
Rym: The tournament scene like the general like tabletop tournaments tournament scene at PAX unplugged is way better than the tabletop Tournament scene at regular PAX is because it is a primary part of PAX unplugged, right?
Scott: So regular PAX is.
Scott: there are tabletop tournaments and quite a few.
Scott: they're very substantial but at PAX unplugged It's like it's not a part of the tabletop department.
Scott: It's its own department the tournament department and it is big-time Big yep, and also a thing to be aware of.
Rym: there is a small number of events at PAX unplugged.
Rym: You have to sign up for an advance but they are almost entirely either games where you have to do prep in advance like make a Character to bring or make an army of miniatures and bring
Scott: it
Rym: Or they are tournaments that need a large number of players where they cannot organize the tournament
Scott: at.
Scott: They have these like mega tournaments.
Scott: What did they actually call them like the PAX championship series or something like that?
Scott: Yeah, it's like these giant enormous tournaments and in order to I don't know if you have to register for them in advance But you can register for them in advance And that is simply because they can't have all that met.
Scott: They have tons and tons of seats for these tournaments, and they could not possibly register everyone on you know on site.
Rym: Yep, so this it's.
Rym: it's a good thing like I as much as I philosophically am opposed to any pre-convention signups for anything.
Rym: there are Limited cases of tabletop where it actually makes perfect sense, and I feel like unplugged doing it right.
Rym: So if you want to play like the game where you bring a giant army Check and see if that's something you can sign up for in advance.
Scott: But yeah most tournaments at PAX the way it works is you show up the day of you don't can't go a day ahead Of time.
Scott: right because most some people have one day badges.
Scott: It won't be fair to them and at 10 a.m When pack starts you go to the signup area and you put your name on the sheet if it's not full.
Scott: and now you're in That tournament.
Scott: you show up at the time you play in the tournament you try to win.
Scott: if you win you get a PAX medal Congratulations.
Scott: some tournaments which are might be run by non packs.
Scott: They might be run by vendors or something like that in which case there may be prizes or who-knows-what Or there may be other entry fees But those are not run directly by enforcers.
Scott: the main tournaments that are on the schedule unless otherwise noted on there are run by Enforcers and they don't cost anything to enter other than signing up on the piece of paper.
Rym: So the omega-thon at PAX is always like a big deal and it's fun.
Rym: like if I'm free I will watch omega-thon rounds because they're really entertaining.
Rym: yeah But the omega-thon at PAX unplugged they're still like working out exactly what kinds of games.
Rym: They're still like figuring stuff out.
Scott: But I want to point out wonder if they will use my tumbling dice suggestion.
Rym: tumbling die If X custom tumbling dice if you see tumbling.
Scott: if you see tumbling dice in the final round of the omega-thon You just know that was all me.
Scott: I suggested that one and it was heard by people who are unplugged.
Rym: But what I will say is that it is a full-on omega-thon just like any other packs.
Rym: It's worth seeing these rounds, but especially the omega-thon finale.
Rym: We'll talk about that at the end of our little hype show.
Rym: but round four of the omega-thon at PAX Unplugged on Friday is blockus.
Rym: Blockus is a game of goddamn skill Blockus.
Rym: I'm really.
Rym: I might like go watch this round like this.
Scott: I am personally extremely good at blockus.
Rym: I too am extremely good at blockus Scott, and I have both studied Classic opening moves and opening strategies to blockus.
Scott: I usually beat you a blockus though When was the last time we played blockus?
Scott: I can remember the last time I played bot blockus.
Scott: was that a recent packs?
Scott: I can't remember the last time I lost.
Rym: oh so the other problem is four player blockus Joey Jojo Shabbat who could fuck it up?
Rym: for me mm-hmm two-player.
Rym: blockus is a game of such pure anger.
Rym: But this omega-thon is gonna be pretty off the hook.
Scott: You got a problem.
Scott: So let's.
Scott: I want to talk about some panels I saw on the schedule that look really hype.
Scott: so the first one is CEO panel discussions publishing trends and avoiding mistakes.
Scott: right the panelists are Stephen MacArthur a game lawyer from the MacArthur law firm.
Scott: That's a guy's job game on young lawyer.
Scott: Tim fowers the CEO of fowers games.
Scott: Patrick leader owner a creator director of me.
Rym: Stephen MacArthur all right.
Scott: well Are you sure I've met him the director of leader games?
Scott: Which is publishes like a root and all that biz right.
Scott: and Scott Gaeta?
Scott: Sorry if I mispronounce your name.
Scott: other Scott the president and publisher of renegade game studios Which I've heard of but don't know which games they make.
Scott: but that panel looks hella interesting.
Scott: that is at Saturday at 10 a.m I'll probably be there And while Rym talks about something I will scroll down until I see the next awesome panel.
Rym: So what's cool?
Rym: Is that a lot of the panels that involve publishers in general impacts unplug?
Rym: They lean a little more toward the kinds of panels.
Rym: I tend to go to it PAX dev because the thing is PAX dev is interesting and that Most of the people who want to go to pack like who want to engage in the industry stuff like this our tabletop.
Rym: so It's hard for people who are in the tabletop industry to get out to PAX dev because it's really expensive a lot of the tabletop Industries in the East Coast, so I'm seeing a lot of these kinds of panels at pecs unplug that I normally would see it a dev like this CEO panel, and I think that'll be really interesting.
Rym: in general I feel like the panel's game at unplugged will be more Specialized to the attendance of pecs unplug because there's a lot more overlap between the people who play Tabletop games and the people who make and publish them than there is in video games.
Scott: so Saturday at 1 there is a FFG Key Forge creating the world's first unique deck game panel, but I'm even though I just talked about hype.
Scott: We were for Key Forge.
Scott: I'm kind of meh on this panel.
Scott: Maybe I'll go.
Scott: maybe I won't because Richard Garfield the designer of Key Forge is not on the panel.
Scott: Well, probably not at PAX Unplugged either, and it's mostly FFG people And also it's probably mostly gonna be marketing for their game, and maybe not too much good info I don't know.
Scott: Maybe I'll watch that one on Twitch afterwards.
Scott: if it's on Twitch, maybe Mmm.
Scott: That's a maybe panel, so here's the.
Rym: here's how you handle this.
Rym: like to be in Pike hype for packs.
Rym: Especially a lot of people go to PAX Unplugged because it's kind of in Philly and easy to get to never been to a pecs before.
Rym: here is the absolute best way to decide what panels to go to download the guidebook app on your smartphone or whatever.
Rym: and Thursday or Wednesday like before you go to the con or maybe Friday morning while you're waiting for the keynote to start.
Rym: Just go through the schedule.
Rym: start on Friday scroll all the way down go through Saturday go through Sunday Click on any panel where the title looks even remotely interesting.
Scott: Oh, here's a panel.
Scott: Saturday It's all the good panels.
Scott: on Saturday Saturday at 6 executive women in tabletop.
Scott: There are six women.
Scott: Right Heather O'Neill Elaine chase cat Tobin Julie.
Scott: I'm not gonna talk about all their jobs are cuz just gonna take too long.
Scott: It's a mouthful.
Scott: But it's like.
Scott: these are like six CEOs CEOs Vps of global brand strategy for game companies.
Scott: how come?
Scott: none of them is doing the keynote.
Scott: Why are they on this panel?
Scott: Instead I mean well they should be on this panel and also do the keynote, but hey go to that panel.
Rym: Yeah, very good, so here's one.
Rym: This is a workshop.
Rym: It's a master class in the owlbear.
Rym: it is two hours and Everyone's going to learn how to paint a fucking amazing owlbear together, but if I can't even paint like fucking anything like.
Rym: not even It's intended for painters of all skill levels.
Rym: Okay, you're and we'll focus on painting feathers and fur.
Rym: oh shit This is gonna go all the way to dry brushing and inking.
Rym: I kind of want to go to.
Rym: how long is it?
Rym: two hours?
Scott: You think you can get me to paint an amazing owlbear.
Rym: in two hours you will paint.
Rym: I think you know what's gonna happen.
Rym: you're gonna paint.
Scott: It's gonna paint a bear like it's gonna look like that.
Scott: What's that famous one where the Jesus looks all messed up?
Rym: you were going to paint the best possible owlbear you could paint.
Rym: That is what will happen.
Scott: Maybe I should go to this.
Scott: it cost money.
Rym: Uh no, I think there's gonna be so last year to register for it on Friday at 9 a.m Cuz it's gonna fill up obviously But that's the kind of shit that happens at PAX Unplugged.
Rym: that cannot happen at any other pack.
Scott: so at every packs I've ever been to that I can remember Reaper miniatures has had a little paint and take booth Right you basically walk up and for free they give you a mini.
Scott: There's like two choices like wizard and some space marine And you take one and you go and they just sit down and there's like a few paints And you paint it and I painted space marine.
Scott: finally was it.
Scott: I think was packed south.
Scott: I did this space marine.
Scott: I finally did it last year at PAX South.
Rym: Yeah, I think so I'd pay.
Rym: the problem is we go to so many packs as they.
Scott: It was packed south last year after all the years.
Scott: I wanted to do it.
Scott: I finally did it and that made me so hype.
Scott: I was like oh, man I totally want to like you know not play any minis miniature games like Warhammer But like buy a tiny amount of paint and a tiny amount of minis and paint a few when I'm bored.
Scott: So I bought the most basic starter set.
Scott: that's got like a skeleton in it.
Rym: cuz skeletons skeletons are going to paint.
Rym: It's all about inking like.
Rym: inking is what makes a skeleton look good,
Scott: and I have yet to open Mostly because I it's not that I haven't had a free weekend It's that I haven't I have to find like some sort of material to cover my very expensive tiny table So I don't get paint on it.
Rym: So but basically the way to handle this like I said look through the schedule click on Every panel where the title looks even like minimally interesting and read the description look at the people and if you and Think to yourself answer this one question if I had nothing better to do would I go see this?
Rym: the answer is yes Just add it to your scheduling guidebook And then when you're at the con don't worry about going to all those panels.
Rym: like you're gonna have your short list of like the three Things y'all really want to go.
Rym: see but feel all the right just like like everything Adam all to your schedule.
Rym: Anytime you're bored just look at your guidebook and see hey What panel is on like next that I said I might want to go to?
Rym: and if you're bored?
Rym: And it's there just go to it.
Rym: that is like the best way to maximize your packs because anytime you get downtime You've got like a guaranteed backup thing to go.
Scott: do speaking of thorn watch guy, which I remembered his name Mike Selinger.
Scott: Yeah, right, and I said he should do the keynote, but here he is doing a panel Sunday Called.
Scott: this sounds like a panel.
Scott: I would do.
Scott: this is a puzzle.
Scott: This is a game He's gonna talk about.
Scott: what's a puzzle and what's a game what the difference is?
Rym: I have said I have.
Rym: not only have I seen him give basically that talk at PAX dev multiple times like a talk like it like he's Good talks.
Rym: They're good panels, but - I Had a long conversation where he drunkenly explained this in detail to me.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: It'll be a good panel.
Scott: I'm sure it will be.
Rym: yeah cuz we uh Think about this.
Rym: a lot of these panels are the kinds of things that you'll hear us arguing about in panels.
Rym: Just people smarter than us who are deeper in the industry will argue about it with more information than we have.
Scott: Also, I just want to point out you know if you are the kind of person Which is a lot of people who really want to play some RPGs.
Scott: usually a lot of people are like hey I want to play D&D, but I never played a D&D before.
Scott: right pack some plugs Is probably the place for you to go.
Scott: it's gonna be a lot more accessible than one of those tiny RPG cons in the you know like that's you know usually like a uber con or something if that still exists.
Scott: And it's probably gonna be a lot less crowded than trying to play D&D like a PAX East.
Scott: yeah Yeah, this basically if you look at the schedule.
Scott: There's like D&D Adventurers League Pathfinder Society all this stuff is basically happening Constantly even other RPGs that are lesser-known that you might be more interested in.
Scott: yeah all over the fuck is.
Scott: I see some Star Wars RPG.
Scott: if you want to get your RPG on the danger room LARP by mystic realms whatever the hell that is sound Maybe it's based on the x-men danger room.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I just want to point out Sunday morning if you want to win a PAX tournament guys there is a 16 player single elimination.
Rym: Connect for tournament.
Rym: oh, baby Or is a sold fucking game.
Scott: if you go you can.
Scott: you can start right now?
Scott: Go online and learn how to be perfect at connect for it won't take you very long.
Scott: Practice it a few times against your friends.
Scott: yep practice by playing it online against an AI.
Rym: learn the backups.
Rym: learn the Guaranteed strat and learn the backup strat if you're the wrong player right and then basically you will Probably face in the final someone else who did the same thing yep, and then it'll come down to do you go first or second?
Scott: Yep, but anyway, that's that's an easy easy win of a PAX medal yep But there's.
Rym: this is a good schedule like it.
Rym: There's good stuff in here.
Scott: I also want to point out again also if none of those RPGs are interesting to you Or maybe they're not at a good time on your schedule.
Scott: RPGs games on demand is gonna be there.
Scott: what this is if you don't know what they're at many Pax's as well as other conventions is a little booth or an area.
Scott: you go there with your friends or maybe you meet up with some strangers there who knows?
Scott: and There's RPGs there.
Scott: there are GM's just waiting for players and as soon as I did this one year at PAX West I GM like three or four RPGs in the games on demand area.
Scott: Oh, and you just wait when I was a GM.
Scott: I just went there I waited I put up these little cards, and it was like a menu.
Scott: players came up They looked at the menu And they were like they wanted to play an RPG right then there and now as soon as there were enough people I brought them over to a table.
Scott: I ran a one-shot RPG session.
Scott: I set them on their way and even though I thought only maybe one and a half of those sessions was good I got excellent feedback in all the sessions, so if you want to play RPG Telling you PAX Unplugged you cannot miss.
Scott: This is your chance.
Scott: all those you're like oh, man I never get to play RPG.
Scott: I watch RPG on Twitch.
Scott: I watch acquisitions incorporated, but I got no friends.
Scott: Yeah, I can't.
Scott: I have friends But I can't get them together because they're all busy.
Rym: all the people who are obsessed with the C team are Here in the same building with you.
Scott: you can go to PAX Unplugged for three days And if you really want to you could probably play two or three RPG a day if you really dedicated all your time to that and nothing else.
Scott: and that is not a bad way to spend the PAX Unplugged yep.
Rym: So in terms of to like LFG like all packs is have like a looking for game area and tabletop PAX Unplugged has a fucking looking for game area.
Rym: like if you want to no matter what weird like Train game nonsense you want to play.
Rym: if you LFG it unplugged You're all practically guaranteed to find other people who will play this game with you.
Scott: and even if those people are That guy it's packs, so they're not allowed to be that guy.
Scott: yep You can always get some enforcers and be like yo We got a that guy over here And they'll get taken care of.
Scott: you can be rest assured.
Scott: the worst you'll have to deal with is slightly.
Scott: And let me tell you wants to play shit geek but won't be bad because it's PAX Unplugged.
Rym: is the tabletop focused one?
Rym: the Enforcers at PAX Unplugged even more so than other packs is are on top of that guy Like they are crack.
Rym: They're a crack team to make sure that guy doesn't.
Rym: that guy all over you Let's see there's a kids room in a family room like Sunday is a kids day like you can bring your kid if they're under 12 For free on Sunday.
Rym: Oh, baby, and there is a big area because pax's are Family-friendly.
Rym: if you're a family that says fuck casually like that's how pax is like it's family-friendly.
Rym: But it has to be this like cool dad that lets the kids say fuck when they're not at school.
Rym: There is a specifically
Scott: I think there was a dad who had like it let his kid that they're listening to GeekNights in the car And he was like he's like yeah I just got to tell my kid not to say words that you're saying and I'm like I don't think you've learned the lesson of GeekNights.
Scott: You should have a cool kid who says fuck like he's from, New York But the kid who's smart enough to not say fuck in front of his middle school teacher or to say fuck you middle school teacher Just a fucking word.
Rym: But there is a family room that has miniature painting and games and is the fuck like the fuck free zone.
Rym: So like pegs unplugged is more family and kid friendly than a general packs.
Rym: that is like worth noting.
Rym: It's kind of a. it's a cool thing.
Rym: I'm glad they do it.
Rym: The pain like all the pack stuff like the pin trading is there's just there.
Rym: Tabletop is so big.
Rym: there's like oh, so if you haven't been to a packs recently There's a new thing in tabletop called first look mm-hmm Started at last PAX Unplugged But it has reappeared at every packs all year and it'll be at every packs forever.
Scott: first Look.
Rym: the deal if you don't know is it's not like regular tabletop where there's like an area where everyone plays Carcassonne Not an area where you play whatever.
Scott: it's an area where there are games already set up with the rules sitting there and Enforcers who have tried to spend as much time as they could learning the rules so that they could teach anyone who walks up.
Rym: So you can go into this area see a game that is not out yet or not out.
Scott: We had expert enforcers go to S in BGG con and all these other board game events that are conveniently scheduled right before PAX Unplugged To collect the newest and hottest board games that are unavailable still in the United States or hard to obtain.
Scott: Bring them here to teach them to you, so you can have the first look at them.
Rym: It's really great and amazing to just sit down at some brand new game and have an enforcer Expertly teach you and a bunch of other people how to play it and then be available answer questions While you play it and when you're done playing it walk away from the table and the game is set up for the next group
Scott: of people.
Scott: the only thing I can tell you though is that the first look area at PAX Unplugged as hard as there's a line is Very crowded because a lot of people.
Scott: so the real secret.
Scott: you got to go to the first look area.
Scott: I packed south and literally any other packs, but PAX South it is the least crowded.
Rym: Yeah PAX South is like the Secret packs on.
Rym: you'll
Scott: get the same exact first look area and the same exact tabletop library that was at PAX Unplugged But they'll be fucking like almost no one else playing games there But the same enforcers learning and teaching the same games the same everything and now you can play those games Just to your heart's content without having to wait whereas it PAX Unplugged.
Scott: you'd be like oh, man I really want to play that that meeple circus that was in the first look last year.
Scott: right yep.
Scott: And meanwhile someone's playing it.
Scott: so you walk away and come back someone else is playing it walk away coming someone's playing it PAX Unplugged.
Scott: It's just sitting there waiting for you to come and enjoy the circus.
Rym: and one last thing that's interesting about PAX Unplugged Is that you know Mike and Jerry are both like around and other packs is kind of equally and they hide and whatever.
Rym: But if your PAX Unplugged is kind of like the Jerry attacks Like Mike will be doing like a storm watch stuff and Jerry's just like wandering around all the time like playing games with people.
Rym: He's more accessible than he is at other packs is.
Rym: so if your jam is to like be adjacent to that dude while you play a game like unplugged is the one to go to if you care about that sort of thing.
Rym: and last and least If you are a fan of us already You don't need to go to our 40 tabletop games You must play panel because one it's gonna be on YouTube and two it's 80% the same as the one that's already on YouTube.
Rym: We're doing it at PAX Unplugged because one it's gonna be a live streaming.
Rym: because that kind of panel like gaming comms that aren't packs don't really have good panels and tabletop gaming comms that aren't packs Really don't have the concept of panels by and large.
Rym: so we're doing this for people who aren't you.
Rym: But it's probably worth going to our learning when.
Rym: Puerto Rico if you don't know how to play Puerto Rico Because we're literally gonna be in the room for a couple hours like helping you all play Puerto Rico Like not just the panel even if you just watch it on YouTube It's not the same.
Rym: if you're in the room You can like ask us what to do in a situation right there and we'll be like Pick the captain because it'll totally fuck over that guy and this guy is not gonna beat you Etc.
Rym: like that kind of stuff will happen.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And if you see us like, you know what other packs is people like, oh, hey, I want to play.
Scott: Oh, yeah, this packs of bug just really soon.
Scott: We should probably work on that parent Rico panel.
Rym: I'm gonna finish it this like over Thanksgiving.
Rym: cuz I'm not going.
Rym: I'm not doing shit for Thanksgiving.
Rym: I'm staying home.
Rym: Okay, so I'm going to like finish the panel on Thursday.
Scott: You don't want to go to New Jersey.
Rym: I could do you wanna.
Rym: I could do that?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: See if it's a. if it's possible.
Rym: see if it's possible.
Rym: Emily we're gonna like a film screening but this in the morning.
Rym: So it wouldn't really impact us.
Rym: We have no plans.
Scott: Hmm.
Rym: This is uh, this is my like don't go anywhere for the holidays here.
Rym: So I'm just I'm making no plans.
Rym: I'm just relaxing.
Scott: The thing is if you go to New Jersey And we take the train there and then I don't know if a car will be big enough to put Everyone in to take us to yeah The the destination
Rym: might just have to get me to Q Gardens and I'll deal with the.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm working on Friday to save vacation day.
Scott: So oh, I'm Going back.
Scott: It's nothing you have to get home somehow.
Scott: Yeah Cuz I'm just gonna go back to Connecticut because I'm not working.
Rym: Yeah, we'll figure it out.
Rym: worst case.
Rym: We'll just stay home.
Rym: I'll finish the panel.
Rym: Mmm I had to figure out.
Rym: cuz I have like the three-player strategies I had to do a little bit of work to figure out the right advice for five-player Puerto Rico.
Scott: I mean, I'm just mostly gonna focus on the advice.
Scott: That's good.
Scott: No matter how many players you have Use the captain when everyone else has to dump all their barrels in the ocean.
Rym: Here's an example.
Rym: like three-player Puerto Rico never buy a fucking warehouse.
Rym: Like what a waste of goddamn doubloons.
Rym: Yeah, five-player Puerto Rico that small warehouse is real good.
Scott: Yep, small warehouse plus war main the main strategy is you want to take have to take as few actions as possible, right?
Scott: Like if I have to go mayor and then a bunch of nothing happens and then I have to go Alright now I'll do build it right.
Scott: It's like, you know, if I do well, I guess we build her.
Rym: then mayor You want everyone you want to line it up?
Scott: So everyone else is taking the actions you need in the order you need so that on your turn You're like you're getting turns ahead of other people.
Rym: Yep, like race for the galaxy You can't just be going Craft x2 craft x2.
Rym: you want to go x2 x2 x2 and trick some other schmuck into going craft craft craft.
Rym: Yep So yeah, this is a fun panel.
Rym: This is gonna be real like not everything is gonna make it to YouTube from that one.
Rym: If you're a fan of GeekNights, like seriously go to our Puerto Rico and skip our 40 tabletop games.
Scott: Thanks unplugged.
Rym: Yeah PAX Unplugged like go and Unlike other packs is we're literally just gonna be in tabletop like the entire time except for
Scott: the
Rym: whole Yeah, but we're gonna be in like tabletop free play the whole time except for the keynote the Q&A the omegathon finale And maybe a couple of panels.
Rym: We're just gonna be in like table top replay playing fucking games.
Rym: It's gonna be amazing.
Rym: Mmm, this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Rym: music can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights.
Rym: Ah Alan Joyce Craig Oliver Heidi McNicholas shimmering ruby obelisk hanging in the sky kashar Thomas and my stady comm link.
Rym: Eiji J Beds go to lonely.
Rym: Roberto Kingsley cat Shawn Yeager, Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando mr.
Rym: Strong distraction for to one creations Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Shervin von Horl Rory Rochelle, Monta, Nona super boy sailor Vista Don sh like Joshua Joe star Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan parent rope and Lander Finn all caps one exclamation mark Chris midkiff Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: We.
Rym: uh, if you didn't notice when you watch the live stream we recorded the show yesterday because Scott had a thing tonight today And it's the holidays.
Rym: So there won't be a regular GeekNights on Thursday but there will be a ribbon Emily special.
Rym: so stay tuned for that.
Rym: and now I leave you with Let's knock them back.
Scott: I could use a hand.
Rym: I'm going to Engage In the game I Play to win TV engaging.