Rym: It's Thursday March 1st 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights' tonight.
Rym: camp of the summer and band variety.
Scott: Isn't band camp also in the Sun?
Rym: Yeah, but band camp.
Rym: would you say that summer camp and band camp aren't the same thing?
Scott: Not only they have many similarities very few though.
Rym: And also they have separate Wikipedia pages.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: so as you know, cuz I talk about it a lot one of my main hobbies is skiing and The ski season also known is almost dying.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, Scott I still posit to you that what actually causes more serious injuries and deaths skiing or Biking.
Scott: there's a lot more biking going on.
Rym: Oh, no, I mean I'm saying even per capita Skings.
Scott: pretty safe If you had everyone in the world ski and then everyone in the world bike With equivalent levels of skill.
Rym: I mean skiing is a high-skill thing.
Rym: Most people who do it become reasonably skilled or they don't do it like.
Scott: how much biking goes on around the world?
Rym: Yes, how many people die biking in New York City on a annual basis?
Scott: less than 20?
Rym: Yeah Yeah, how many people die skiing at Hunter Mountain on an annual basis?
Scott: one mountain?
Rym: Yeah That mountains where all the New Yorkers go.
Rym: There's a ton of people there.
Rym: So as best I can tell there have been I think four deaths there in the last several years.
Scott: That's a lot For such a small number of people.
Rym: but compared to how many runs they do and also so I looked into those I was looking up some stats today for research for Emily.
Rym: of those four deaths in the last several years One of them was the lady who just fell off the ski lift like basically just fell off a building to the ground.
Scott: Don't go ski lifts are dangerous.
Scott: Don't get on them.
Rym: No, they're not dangerous.
Rym: It's actually a mystery how she fell off Because you you can't fall off a ski lift unless you want to fall off a ski lift or you make a Really really ridiculous and terrible mistake.
Scott: a lot of them seem really precarious except for the kind where it's like just a sky car Where there's like a ball that's called a gondola.
Scott: Yeah Those are safe, but the ones that just like a bench that comes up behind you they could just like knock you over.
Rym: Well, it knocks you over.
Rym: that's not gonna kill you.
Rym: It's just funny.
Scott: You could also get on to it and then just like lean forward and fall off There's a bar that comes down in front of you just like in a roller coaster Howdy, but at the bar like it's it's like that doesn't seem of some moving.
Rym: you reach up and you pull the bar.
Scott: It's not hard a moving bench.
Rym: That doesn't sound all right.
Rym: Here's the here's Rym.
Rym: skiing aside You want to talk about the things that are dangerous and skiing that are.
Scott: and that thing?
Scott: I'm pointing out is that the lift is the least dangerous thing there and it's still a death trap.
Scott: The least dangerous part is still a death trap.
Scott: people are feeling it.
Rym: But yet there are three other kinds of things that will take you up the mountain tree.
Scott: Oh a rope that moves.
Rym: Yeah, they're moving rope.
Rym: The funniest thing is the things I'm about to describe to you tend to only be used on beginner hills yet They are also the most dangerous and hardest to use.
Scott: Yeah, the moving rope.
Rym: It's called a toe rope.
Rym: It's literally just a rope that's just spinning around spinning at high speed.
Scott: It's like two pulleys and a rope.
Rym: and here's how it works.
Rym: You grab the rope and hold the rope And it just goes through your hands and you don't move at all and it burns your hand burns your hand.
Rym: You have to grab it real tight and then you try to hold on to a real tight.
Scott: Does it have knots in it to help you?
Scott: No, I thought has knots.
Scott: No, fuck you.
Rym: The toe rope sucks.
Rym: Okay worse than the toe rope is something called a magic carpet.
Rym: What it's a conveyor belt.
Rym: ski onto it and just And you're just.
Scott: that seems like it'll just kill you when you fall down.
Scott: Well because those and you'll bump into everyone behind you.
Rym: so those are only used in two circumstances.
Rym: one You're all.
Rym: you're basically on this can uphill conveyor belt It seems like be okay for going flat but going up they go up but they go up like The bunny hill that kids learn to ski on.
Rym: that's only like 30 feet.
Scott: I guess you have to face sideways that you get them straight up.
Scott: Wouldn't you start sliding backwards?
Rym: No, it's like rubber.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: He's not gonna slide on.
Scott: that got snow on it.
Rym: No, it's doesn't this snow.
Rym: No, it's not always snowing 24/7 in the mountain.
Scott: Well, I guess you can't use it when it is snowing.
Rym: You can cuz it's moving and the snow will melt on it cuz it slippery piece of rubber is wet.
Rym: skis don't move.
Rym: the reason skis move on snow is Because they have a special material on the bottom filled with wax and the pressure of it on the snow actually melts this very thin Layer of water due to pressure and that's what allows you to ski.
Rym: if you can't make that happen your ski just sits there.
Rym: Mm-hmm anyway The magic carpet is a nightmare machine that traumatizes children.
Scott: Yes Obviously, I don't even need to see it to know.
Rym: there is a hybrid thing where there'll be a magic carpet with a rope.
Rym: No, that leads to a faster magic carpet.
Rym: That magic carpet is moving at the same speed as a ski lift.
Scott: that doesn't slow down And it basically just swings in Slow magic carpet because you can't possibly start moving on.
Rym: the fast one takes you to a fast Switch.
Rym: it just pushes you on to a fast one And then the fast one is moving at the same speed of a ski lift chair.
Scott: that doesn't slow down not going anywhere near That.
Scott: yeah Those fucking suck as a ski and I put a rope next to it like an escalator has a handle that moves next to it.
Rym: Cuz that'll people will just mess that it's not moving at the same speed as the carpet.
Rym: But there's something else called a t-bar.
Rym: Imagine like a truck flying trapeze.
Rym: You just got a fucking grab and hold on to for dear life.
Scott: You mean you mean a death draft?
Rym: Yeah, those things are the worst.
Scott: grab on to get to the top let go.
Rym: Last time used a tee up toe rope was a pine knob in Michigan when I was a kid and last time I used a T-bar was once at Loon Mountain.
Scott: I can't.
Scott: it can't be legal Has to be phased out right as Bretton wood.
Rym: No, they exist.
Rym: They exist for morons in places that I don't want to go anyway.
Rym: The ski season just ended abruptly because it got like it's like 60 degrees right now here.
Scott: It's like 50 something.
Rym: It's 57 according to my phone.
Scott: It's cold.
Rym: 57 is not cold.
Scott: It's 54.
Scott: You're just old and it's cold.
Rym: It got real warm like crazy warm and there's a crazy warm for the for February.
Scott: I guess it's like it's slightly less cold.
Rym: It was warmer than this like two weeks ago.
Rym: That was weird.
Scott: It's one coat less cold.
Scott: It's still need a coat and head.
Rym: Ah someone in the chat pointed out the J bar.
Rym: I even fucking talking J bar.
Rym: There are other bars That are even worse than the T bar bar is basically mechanism to hurt people who think they want to ski.
Rym: I feel like there's a trap to reduce the number of people skiing.
Scott: You should be better, you know how to stay safe.
Scott: be a person like me who knows they don't want to ski.
Rym: So I went on that ski trip in New Hampshire and then suddenly it was late spring and everything melted like everywhere in the Northeast.
Rym: So I thought my ski season was over.
Rym: I got a notification Because there's this giant storm bearing down on the East Coast right now in New York and Massachusetts is gonna be torrential rain Up at hunter mountain.
Rym: It's gonna be like two feet of snow.
Rym: So I'm skiing on Saturday.
Rym: I'm getting like one more day on real snow.
Rym: It's gonna be amazing.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So yeah, that's what I got.
Rym: That was my opening bit because you forgot what yours was.
Rym: I remembered Oh, is it something good?
Rym: No, no.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Let's get right to the news.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: What was my news?
Scott: Oh, so it's not super newsy and actually it's this great article that is somehow been locked by a password but I got an archived version of it and this person did a statistical sampling of Apple map versus Google map versus ways to figure out which one is the best.
Scott: it wasn't like some enormous enormous Sample covering a large amount of terrain and a large amount of uses, but it was pretty significantly.
Scott: You know, I mean not.
Scott: maybe not statistically significant But it's like one person did all their trips switching up between the three and measuring them all based on various things And basically the conclusion they came to matches up with my anecdotal experience.
Scott: So I'm inclined to believe it.
Scott: And the the summer detail dr is if you want to get to do your destination most quickly use Google Maps.
Scott: if you want an accurate prediction from your Navigation app to help you arrive on time use Apple map.
Scott: and if thinking you'll get to your destination Quickly helps to ease your commuter anxiety use Waze which tells you you're gonna get there sooner than you're actually gonna get.
Rym: that Does Waze even still exist?
Rym: cuz isn't that data just in Google Maps now, right?
Scott: So I don't think so.
Scott: a lot of people I know are like oh my god Waze is so much better because it gives you This info about things.
Rym: but Google gives me the same info.
Scott: Well, no, it gives you info about additional things like it'll tell you if there's a speed trap or about that I'm saying is like it gives you this this extra detailed info about stuff that is kind of not necessary.
Scott: Google just constantly tells you which way to go and that's all you need to know.
Rym: Well, no But Google also tells you some of the ways in for they included was things like it gives you the ETA when you'll arrive Based on current conditions on your entire route.
Rym: it warns you about issues and whenever there is an alternate route It shows it and gives you the option to switching to it and tells you what it'll what it'll do to your ETA.
Rym: Yep, and I have found cuz I'm I'm basically the driver for the crew when we go to places.
Rym: now because I rent the car cuz it's none of us own cars live in the city and I have found that over the last couple years Google directions at least have been like Shockingly accurate down to the minute.
Rym: I'll arrive at a place and every time they tell me to go away that my Knowledge of driving in New York City tells me is wrong Like for example heading north like going up to Albany or something very often.
Rym: It'll say yeah go into Manhattan Take go across Manhattan to New Jersey and then go north.
Rym: I used to balk at that.
Rym: now I just trust it and it has never steered me wrong.
Scott: Whatever weird road Google Maps says to go on.
Scott: I just do it without question and it's always right and it always gets me where I need to go as much as my Every time that happens.
Scott: I remember the days of the mid-2000s when we all fix we would use MapQuest and print it out Because we didn't have some smartphones and one of us if I was driving Scott was sitting next to me Literally like telling me where to go.
Scott: Google Maps came out and it wasn't as good as MapQuest.
Scott: It was garbage for directions.
Scott: Yeah, and we kept using MapQuest until eventually Google Maps became good sometime around like the iPhone time.
Scott: I think the smartphones really gave them the data they needed.
Rym: Yeah to not suck cuz you guys you don't.
Rym: you don't understand if you're young what it was like to drive Like driving to Otakon.
Scott: I mean there was MapQuest, you know 2000s.
Scott: imagine trying to drive somewhere that you've never been before.
Scott: and like 1988 you go to AAA Triptych which was basically manual.
Scott: MapQuest printed out a custom map just for you.
Scott: It was a member.
Scott: It was a little book of paper and you would flip it page by page and you would highlight where you've been so far Based on you.
Scott: look at this the strip.
Scott: you look outside you see what road you just passed You know how far to highlight and you turn the page as you go And once you finish the whole book and you've highlighted the whole road you've reached your destination.
Rym: So to give you an example of what this was like when Scott and I and many of our friends You drive to like Otakon.
Scott: The book was a narrow vertical book.
Scott: If you went off course at all You needed to plot a big map and the road atlas that you kept in your car in case you fucked up Where the fuck you were.
Scott: or ask for directions from a human being or buy a map at a gas station.
Rym: I have so many.
Rym: we could probably do a Thursday show on road trips Just like I remember situations where I'd be driving and I'm like Scott we're gonna run out of gas in like 20 miles.
Rym: The simple question of is there a way to get gas before we run out of gas Was an existential question.
Rym: and then the follow-up question of we got gas.
Rym: Where the fuck are we and how do we get back on the freeway?
Rym: That'll take us to Baltimore.
Rym: Mm-hmm I wrote my god the idea that I were on the way home from Baltimore.
Rym: Yeah that though Yeah That was the one where I turned off the AC because I was worried we're gonna run out of gas And it was on e.
Scott: we got off to go to a gas station.
Rym: It was closed.
Scott: the guy was in the gas station, but waved us away.
Scott: We got back in the highway and got somehow miraculously to the next gas station while still on.
Rym: We were at that point where the car was literally running on fumes like it was on e. it said e if I had turned The engine off.
Scott: I think I was driving.
Rym: I we were taking turns I forget.
Rym: all I know is if we had turned the engine off not confident.
Rym: We could have restarted the engine.
Rym: Nope Cuz.
Rym: when we refilled the tank cuz I know that car held 14 gallons of gas we put in like 13.8 gallons Like we filled it up all the way.
Scott: Then we were just fine.
Rym: So If you haven't noticed that my news is sort of a minor call to action.
Rym: but Politics is kind of fucked up in the US right now.
Rym: So if you don't live in the US this really doesn't apply to you But a common problem a pretty apparently even if you don't live in the US you can still influence our politics with your money.
Scott: So, please send it.
Rym: Oh, yeah, if you want to do the reverse Russia like help us out.
Scott: Apparently it's okay.
Rym: but anyway The specific thing I want to talk about is that especially if you're like urban living nerd a lot of the people listen to GeekNights.
Rym: a lot of our friends like us in particular as Invested as we are in politics Literally every election I can vote in is a landslide for the best possible outcome already.
Rym: Yeah, like if I call my senator like I call actually look all my representatives at every level.
Scott: All right, except for president are Democrats of awesomeness and I went and I checked.
Scott: I'm like are any of them like the not good kind?
Scott: because there are.
Scott: so And I know hunt they're all like if there was votes for like universal health care.
Scott: They would vote.
Scott: Yes tomorrow.
Scott: Yep, like my state's every single one of them even my city council person.
Scott: So it's like there's no point in getting involved in my local anything.
Rym: I called my state senator to be like, yeah, New York State universal health care and the response I got was I fucking Co-sponsored that.
Rym: that's my bill.
Rym: Yeah, so yes, I am for it.
Rym: so if you were one of those people who feels like you live in a place where you can't influence things.
Rym: a Good friend of ours is trying to change that and I've been talking to him a bit and I wanted to kind of.
Scott: I want To point you out some way somehow we can influence elections in other parts of the United States.
Scott: So how can we do this?
Rym: So in particular, I'll give you a very specific example, Texas.
Scott: Mm-hmm Text.
Scott: we none of.
Scott: I don't think I know people who live there.
Rym: Yeah, but I know a bunch of people live there.
Rym: We know someone who moved there specifically to try to organize political activism in Texas because While Texas seems to be a very red for non?
Rym: u.s scenes red means bad state in the u.s.
Scott: Only.
Scott: but thing is even in places like the big cities like Dallas San Antonio all blue Cities are still not places that are red.
Scott: Yeah, even in Texas.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: So the interesting thing is that Texas Actually could very easily flip much more Democrat in the United States.
Rym: They're because voter turnout in most of Texas is actually really low It's true and the elections are closer than a lot of you realize.
Scott: that's very so.
Rym: the idea Is that if you do are not the kind of person who just has money?
Rym: Because if you have money you can literally just like send money to Texas Democrats.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but most of you can't do that.
Rym: And also I would argue that if you don't have a lot of money that is not how you should be spending your money.
Scott: Let's spend it on food.
Rym: Yeah, so You feel strongly about politics in the u.s.
Rym: And you want to try to make a difference?
Rym: I'm gonna link to you to a bunch of websites that are trying to organize people like that.
Rym: people who live in blue states Live in cities don't have money to donate but have time to donate.
Scott: get to go to Texas.
Rym: No, you can do they.
Rym: basically they could.
Rym: these are sites that are legit like I check these out.
Rym: that will.
Rym: If you want to donate your time instead of your money to help do things like let this dude beat Ted Cruz.
Rym: So he's just out of government and fucked.
Rym: it's achievable.
Scott: So what do you do?
Scott: Do you like call people in Texas on the phone?
Rym: So basically they'll let you can do.
Rym: set up your time and you can do like all the phone calls and data entry and all The work that needs to be done to try to help the Democrats win these elections in this red state If you don't live there and without having to donate money.
Scott: because again Scott's evil hacker brain immediately says go sign up for this and Do a bad job.
Scott: Scott's evil hacker brain also says go sign up for the opponent's system doing the same thing and do a bad job on purpose.
Rym: That may be true that may be possible But this kind of Activision sort of my broader point I'm gonna talk this more in future episodes is that in general in the u.s.
Rym: most people think that if they can't donate a lot of money, they can't do anything and And So few people actually do this kind of work That the idea of gaming this system doesn't seem to really exist yet like if ten GeekNights listeners sign up for this.
Scott: Hello, is this Rym House?
Scott: Please vote for Vlad in next election.
Rym: Cobra stan is best Cobra stan forever.
Scott: I'm calling from local party in New York, please vote.
Rym: Stephen AI see through anything.
Rym: So anyway, I'm gonna link you to a bunch of these things.
Rym: if you care about this stuff Please vote and you want.
Rym: if you want to try to influence politics doing stuff like this Has way more impact than the piddly amount of money you could part with.
Rym: we should call Russians.
Scott: Hello.
Scott: Is this comrade?
Scott: Please vote against Putin in the next election.
Rym: Yep, but specifically I am NOT American.
Rym: Texas you in your blue city can do things and some of these some of the things they need are things like Help translate things from English to Spanish Answer emails help with social media shoot and edit video.
Rym: Like.
Rym: if you want to make campaign ads for them, they will hook you up with the things you need to do that.
Rym: Mmm, this is the kind of stuff that nerds can fucking do if they don't have money make.
Scott: Yeah, if you're someone who's making funny YouTube videos, you can make funny campaign ads.
Rym: Yeah, like they'll hook you up with someone like if they need a video shot like it's not hard to make fun of Bad politicians that they're running.
Rym: Yes I mean like one of the.
Rym: you can rip their ass holes open real easily with your internet comedy skills And you if you feel like this doesn't like you feel like this is a Sisyphusian task.
Rym: The dude who's trying to kick Ted Cruz who is an evil shithead in the US out of the government.
Rym: He's neck and neck in the polls in Texas like This is possible.
Rym: So that is my funny videos.
Rym: gonna tip this I mean The elections were so close in a lot of these districts that something like that literally could mm-hmm.
Rym: And you know that we're we're not.
Rym: we're the opposite of optimists.
Rym: Shall we say it's got an eye.
Rym: you might be referred to as cynical.
Rym: I'm pretty I'm pretty invested in this actually being possible And I think my funny videos gonna do it.
Scott: But I hope that motivates you to make the funny video anyway, so I can laugh.
Rym: But check these things out.
Rym: This is the kind of stuff you can do that isn't just.
Scott: you should be all saying I'll show you Scott.
Scott: It's like yeah show me Go ahead.
Rym: but anyway things of the day.
Rym: So I have a specific moratorium for myself.
Rym: I will never much like the old Jack Thompson thing.
Rym: my thing of the day will never be related to steamed hams Ever again unless a steamed hams thing occurs.
Rym: that is so transcendentally better than anything that has ever come before Which I feel like is impossible.
Rym: however I found a steamed hams that was one of those technical memes, and it was something like every time someone says the word ham Generation loss occurs mm-hmm, and I realized that a lot of modern nerds have no idea what the word Generation loss means or the term generation loss
Scott: mm-hmm.
Rym: Generation loss is a concept from the analog days where if you make a cop if you have an analog thing And you make a copy of it it will introduce defects Artifacts.
Rym: if you keep making copies of copies.
Rym: that's what happens when your fourth generation copy of the key to your dorm room doesn't work anymore.
Rym: or the The VHS tape that was a seventh generation of a fan sub is literally unwatchable.
Rym: or the literal entire plot of the movie multiplicity.
Rym: This video will explain to you in detail with examples What generation loss in the analog world was as it takes you through a VHS tape that is copied again and again And again, and it goes into some detail of the kinds of things that occur.
Rym: I can say that I have watched like literally watched entire movies that were fourth generation Lost copies.
Rym: I've watched movies to that level of quality.
Rym: once you get to about Generation 18 That's what the porn channels look like if you had cable in an era.
Rym: that is also by God also It shows you.
Scott: people in those days really you know Underestimated the quality that these media could exhibit because they rarely had first-generation stuff.
Scott: Yeah, first generation VHS is actually pretty damn good.
Rym: Yeah, in fact it is better than digital video was until like.
Rym: But the only other point I got is that this is analog and this is fascinating and you should watch this video to the end.
Rym: It's only like seven minutes long.
Rym: It's just really well done.
Rym: The same thing happens with lossy digital media.
Rym: take a JPEG rotate it 90 degrees a hundred times and your JPEGs fucked Mm-hmm.
Rym: So your thing of the day was the song you made.
Scott: All right, so Google?
Scott: It was a while ago.
Scott: Google had like a Google Doodle that let you sort of like be a DJ And it's pretty cool.
Scott: They've had a lot of actually Google doodles that involve music creation right where you could have a simple and limited interface and make music with it.
Scott: But today they actually released a site.
Scott: What's the name of the site?
Rym: song maker song maker dot Google or whatever music lab dot Chrome experiments dot-com slash song maker?
Rym: right Network slash block.
Scott: so it's basically Like a Mario Paint kind of situation, you know.
Scott: And it was pretty easy and you can make a song with it and I made a song that wasn't unlistenable.
Rym: Yeah, it's interesting as you know as someone who's studied music formally for At this point because it's been so long not much of my life, but not a majority of my life.
Rym: at this point Your music is indeed listenable, but also by the technical definition naive and uninteresting.
Rym: Naive in the sense that I can clearly see what you were going for.
Rym: But because you lack the like knowledge of chord structure or like knowledge of melodic structure It's interesting to see the choices you made.
Scott: or I just did something really quick.
Rym: Yeah with no not much effort Yeah, but at the same time it's it's.
Rym: you're right.
Rym: It's not unlistenable.
Scott: you did Okay, anyway, but you the point is you can use this to a you can make a lot of music with it and combine it together.
Scott: you can even use your microphone to get some samples in there and You can save and share links to the music with other people and then they can load up the little music that you made and Such and such and that makes it pretty cool.
Scott: I think it's weird.
Scott: It's like it's so simple even almost less than Mario Paint actually.
Scott: But yet you could definitely get real stuff done with this, you know what and actually it sounds pretty good.
Scott: the audio The total ad hoc contest I make a visit they have there doesn't sound bad.
Rym: I'll make a forum thread and we'll do a mini contest over like the next month or so.
Rym: Whoever makes the best song in here they judge.
Scott: No, no, here's how we should do it.
Scott: All right, if your song is better than mine you win.
Scott: So almost everyone's a winner and your song is worse than mine.
Scott: shame It's almost no one should have shame.
Rym: All right Mine should be like the second worst, but I'll make a forum thread specifically for this.
Rym: I think we can have some fun in the forum with it in the better moment.
Rym: You should join the GeekNights forums.
Rym: pretty fucking awesome in there reduced.
Rym: We talked.
Rym: there's a lot of people.
Rym: There's a lot of.
Rym: there is too much activity in that forum.
Rym: It's kind of.
Rym: I'm still shocked at how much many people use our forum.
Scott: Community dot front row crew comm it's worth your time more than watching our.
Scott: we're listening to GeekNights.
Scott: A lot of people go to that forum and don't listen to you guys.
Rym: They're smart Yeah, and that actually I think the majority of the people in there.
Rym: don't lose the GeekNights smart people In the rest of the meta moment the GeekNights book club.
Rym: I'm gonna update this Today or tomorrow because we did read the fifth seasons done.
Rym: You can listen to the episode.
Rym: We have a GeekNights book club.
Rym: You should read those books.
Scott: We've done a ton of books over the last 13 years, even though we're really slow to do each one somehow they've added up.
Rym: I am Rapidly burning through Emily Wilson's translation of the Odyssey, which is the current book up book club book.
Scott: Oh, no, I'm reading some spider-man come because it's oh no this translation.
Scott: And I really good if you've never started it, but then I read comics instead.
Rym: if you've never read the Odyssey You'll get into it just like you would a novel I think just the way it's translated.
Rym: and if you read the Odyssey in high school And you kind of vaguely remember what happened probably because of the way it was written.
Rym: It was kind of obtuse.
Rym: this translation.
Rym: It's very much like Athena's dragging this kid around making him do stuff and like the humor and the jokes and the references and it just.
Rym: it Feels like a more natural narrative and if you had trouble like enjoying it in high school I feel like you may actually find enjoyment in it reading this translation.
Rym: I'm very impressed so far.
Rym: But a tiny aside if you're gonna read the Odyssey in our book club Read the introduction.
Rym: It's long.
Rym: You should read it.
Rym: If you don't read the intro That's all I read so far.
Rym: You're doing yourself a grave disservice because the introduction is Fascinating and very informative and very interesting in a shockingly short period of time from now.
Scott: It will be Pax East 2018. oh my god is a Fourth-day Pax.
Scott: the first four-day East Pax.
Scott: Thursday Friday Saturday Sunday Saturday Sunday sold out but fry Thursday no Friday and Saturday are sold out.
Rym: Thursday and Sunday are not sold out which you can't Just go on.
Rym: Thursday or Sunday if you are anywhere near Boston if you want to do an expanding brain meme.
Rym: Friday and Saturday being sold out is the baby's first because Actually Friday Thursday and Sunday the first day and the last day of any given packs are the most powerful days.
Rym: Yep the first day of packs has keynote Q&A and it's a full day that goes till midnight and the last Apparently won't be very crowded and it's still a full packs as full as all the other days.
Rym: Yeah like getting the expo is no content difference between Thursday and Friday and Saturday at PAX other than what happens to be on the Yep and Sunday while it's shorter It has the omega-thon finale the closing ceremony of packs and shit's not that crowded.
Rym: You can see all the stuff you want to see.
Scott: I think Thursday is really the strongest day.
Scott: I don't know why it's not sold out.
Rym: Anyway, I think it's cuz most people want to go to packs for the whole weekend.
Scott: I think it's cuz you got expo help people and you got local people.
Rym: Also, a lot of people can take days off work for cons.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: Look at magfest.
Rym: people buy a four-day badge.
Rym: They only show up Saturday Sunday.
Scott: Yeah night point is we're doing a panel there.
Scott: It's not a. It's not a good time.
Rym: Sunday, April 8th 10 30 a.m.
Rym: The 40 tabletop games.
Scott: You must play man the mad time but a good panel.
Rym: The thing is we didn't.
Rym: yeah We did a trial run of this panel that we kind of threw together at the last second at magfest.
Rym: Not only did it completely fill the room, but I really liked it Right.
Scott: So the thing with this panel is it's a clickbait title.
Scott: You think it has clickbait content just like a BuzzFeed list of like good best board games, but actually As GeekNights does we bait and switch and what actually we do is it go down the list of games?
Scott: but what we're actually doing is exploring like 40 concepts of games and mechanics and Discussing those right and that is you know, you can get a wide view of the varied ways in which board games work.
Rym: Yep So we'll be there.
Rym: It's gonna be awesome.
Scott: The panel will be good Probably be on YouTube at some point and you won't have to play 40 board games to find out we played them for you.
Rym: Frankly you don't want to play all those games.
Rym: some of those games aren't even that good or we didn't like them.
Rym: No, but they illustrate an important point.
Rym: Yes, and I'm changing the list.
Scott: I thought we'd there's no reason not to change it every time.
Rym: Oh, yeah, so easy, especially because I made that list over the course of an hour Like at magfest like trying to make the panel be ready.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So the last thing is there's a lot of PC games right now It's PC game season.
Scott: Oh, yeah, so there's gonna be a lot of streaming on Twitch and YouTube.
Scott: so make sure to go to my YouTube which is just my username or twitch which is also my username or Rym's and we've got lots of streaming going on When we're not GeekNights in.
Scott: so if you're really bored You can watch me get mad at a poorly designed game Or the design flaws of an otherwise good game.
Scott: Well,
Rym: it's there's a debate when we do a Tuesday show between what is a design flaw versus what is the difference between a Game aimed at player mastery versus a game aimed at player exploration of mechanics, which is a Constant struggle for us because the latter is a type of game that we personally tend not to like.
Scott: You want to explore make of Metroid Vania?
Scott: Yeah, but like this board I can actually be exploring the map not the rules.
Rym: like Spirit Island is a board game.
Rym: That is more exploratory than mastery.
Rym: focus Mm-hmm.
Rym: Anyway, that's it.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: I only played it once and I don't remember that much.
Rym: Well, we the whole point of review con is we're gonna do a show on it.
Scott: It's you waited too long.
Rym: I remember specific details about turn I took in that game like things I did in that game.
Rym: that happened.
Rym: How did you forget so much so quickly?
Scott: Because I didn't put it in my brain.
Scott: it's not that important.
Rym: It's the game where the white people are coming in ruining the island.
Rym: I know I know that yeah Yeah, and they got their little houses and we're trying to burn again.
Scott: I remember that the generalness but I don't remember the details.
Rym: You don't remember the powers and like that.
Scott: Anyway, no, I can't remember a single power.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Okay who?
Rym: name anyone?
Rym: Odysseus had sex with?
Scott: Oh Seriously the witch.
Scott: okay, we turned it Frozen two pigs.
Rym: Yeah, what about not Calypso his actual wife, which probably happened?
Scott: What's her name?
Scott: Penelope?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah Those are historic figures.
Scott: They're not remember Specific details from the Odyssey that I haven't read yet.
Scott: guy read.
Scott: Well, I read the pop-up book recently.
Rym: Yeah Oh, yeah the pop-up book.
Rym: Oh That did it.
Scott: So I knew those.
Scott: anyway the main bit the reason who's who's the main character the Odyssey?
Scott: Could it be Telemachus?
Scott: It's like Athena, yeah Polyphemus, it's not like a trick question where the you know, I mean, I don't remember the characters names from Fifth season that we just read.
Rym: uh, I actually forgot most of them to hot The hottest pirate captain to ever be in a media, but I don't know his name.
Rym: I forgot his name.
Rym: Okay, all I know is that he is the.
Rym: he is the most attractive character I think I've ever encountered in written literature.
Rym: I agree.
Rym: Yeah, so summer camp.
Rym: we I Reminded ourselves repeatedly.
Rym: We're gonna do a show on capture the flag, but that's a Tuesday show.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But on a Thursday, there's a whole separate topic around that of camp like summer camp band camp.
Scott: Well, cuz the place I played the most capture the flag was camp.
Scott: Yeah, but it folds right in.
Rym: but I Because as someone who grew up in the Midwest summer camp as Scott envisions it as a lot of kids who lived in New York State and Connecticut and New Jersey and possibly Massachusetts envisioned it is not that common in much of the rest of the country.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't realize that when I was a kid, I thought like is everyone went to camp.
Scott: But apparently that's not.
Scott: I don't know what a lot of the other kids like in my local School in Connecticut.
Scott: I don't know what they did in the summer because like in the summer I'd go to camp and I wouldn't see any of them ever.
Scott: Yep I'm not so much like what were they doing growing up in the Midwest one?
Scott: I never want to ask them.
Rym: I never went to summer camp ever.
Rym: That was the thing.
Rym: that way one my mom asked once like you want to go to a summer camp and I was like why?
Rym: The fuck would I want to leave all my video games and all my friends behind?
Rym: do I hang out with a bunch of kids?
Rym: I don't know far away from home Because our neighborhood just like the things Scott described doing in summer gave her things We just did every night in the neighborhood.
Scott: We didn't have.
Scott: you don't have hundreds of kids in the neighborhood.
Rym: We did.
Rym: Okay, I lived in a dense suburb But cars driving to the neighborhood.
Rym: Yeah, there was woods next to the neighborhood.
Scott: Yeah, you don't have expensive equipment in the stuff in the neighborhood like what we just take our lake.
Rym: a lake full of boats Lake full of but there were lakes full of boats fucking everywhere.
Rym: I lived in Michigan.
Scott: You just walk right up and boat just whenever the fuck dude.
Rym: Yeah, go to like anchor Bay and just get in a boat.
Scott: Did you have to drive there?
Scott: I bike there Like as a summer camp.
Scott: you wake up and walk and just you know your arts and crafts tent You got.
Scott: make a model rocket play D&D.
Rym: Yeah, we all just made model rockets.
Rym: People went to the school and launched them on our own.
Scott: It's like archeries.
Scott: All the shit just going down.
Rym: if we want to do archery went to the YMCA and just did archery.
Scott: They just free archery at the YMCA.
Rym: Yeah, what do you think?
Rym: The YMCA is.
Scott: it's free.
Rym: you pay like a trivial membership.
Rym: It's like cause it costs.
Rym: the cost of the YMCA is basically zero.
Scott: Not summer camp is where it's at.
Rym: but so as a kid interest from my perspective The only kids I ever knew of who went to something that I would call summer camp were Like I can fix little characters on TV.
Rym: Yeah, I can classify them as such.
Rym: Kids on shows and T like TV shows like salute your shorts or movies had summer camp Which always like a family one cuz I yeah the Adams family one cuz I'd never done that kind of thing.
Scott: Uh, so what did you think when you saw that in a movie?
Scott: Like what the for camp Krusty like?
Scott: he's like you watch that like what the fuck's going on.
Rym: The kinds of kids I thought went to summer camp when I was a kid were poor kids.
Rym: No rich kids go because a lot of the summer camps I knew of poor kids can't afford were Specific to poor families and were subsidized.
Rym: and they were like kids who lived in Detroit would come upstate in Michigan and go to a special camp to experience that because they didn't get it living in the city and they Had there's reasons why the state was subsidizing them to go check this out.
Scott: Well, that is part of what camp is is you know, like city people would send their kids out into the woods during the summer Right.
Scott: Yeah, that's part of what it's.
Rym: the second class was all the upper middle-class kids Like their families sent into these really expensive fancy camps way far away even in other states.
Scott: It's other states,
Rym: but the only kids Were either the middle-class kids who didn't have any friends in the neighborhood like they like the kids that like no one was friends with would go off on their own to summer camp or The like upper middle-class kids that none of us ever Interacted with and didn't even go to our schools because I went to the private schools.
Scott: Right, so the camps vary a lot economically speaking, right?
Scott: So you had you know, and I've actually been to a wide Variety of camps economically speaking right.
Scott: so that you know It's not like we're loaded with mad moneys like even when I went to the more expensive camps They would only send me for four out of the eight weeks total because it cost twice as much to go for eight weeks And it cost a lot thousand.
Rym: All I can think is I'm gonna lose four weeks of my idol summertime of playing video games.
Scott: No, you're kidding somebody was the way better than what you could do at home.
Rym: Ah I don't get based on what I did at home as a kid in the summer.
Rym: I don't feel like that's true.
Scott: Anyway, so you could Their summer camps arranged like they got day camps.
Scott: so they were like there were a few years where I just went to like this day camp where the state the school bus would Come and get me at my house Just like it was school.
Scott: take me to the local one of the other local schools Not the one I went to but a different one Right, and then there was a camp there and you could just instead of going to school You just did whatever the fuck you wanted.
Scott: So usually what I would do most of the time all I really remember doing is get there playing basketball for half the day eating lunch then go into a room full of Apple twos
Rym: and
Scott: Play an Oregon Trail or doing some logo programming for the other half of the day.
Scott: But then it would only be like like not even like one and I go home and it was like, alright So that was like the lowest level of any.
Rym: so I went to a bunch of camps like that But those kinds of camps were like.
Rym: I went to a thing called Starbase, which was cheapo space camp.
Rym: Yeah, it was basically so it was Retrospect.
Rym: it was really more like young age military officer recruiting.
Rym: Okay, but because it was run it's at the Air National Guard Bay.
Rym: I grew up next to an Air National Guard base.
Rym: so like can we go there all the time and like fuck around with f-16s and like play in the simulator?
Rym: and like F-16s would literally fly over our houses all the time making noise and trouble.
Scott: that sounds healthy.
Rym: But as one of the things that that that Selfridge Air National Guard base did is they ran this program called Starbase Which was basically all the smart kids from the local schools would get invited And he'd be like a two or three week thing where we'd go every day come home every night.
Rym: That wasn't like a sleepaway thing.
Rym: and we do exercises like.
Rym: you're gonna learn how to do aeronautical navigation.
Rym: You're gonna learn how to like plan a travel mission though in retrospect I realized that the materials they were using like this is my adult brain looking back.
Rym: They taught us what literally World War two bomber navigators did to plan to like navigate Bombing runs.
Rym: Okay, but our runs were framed.
Rym: as we're gonna drop this package off to these people in this city Like it's like thinking back on what we were taught to do in that camp Kind of weird and fucked up but at the same time like we learned a lot of technical skills about aeronautical navigation and Space and it was like mini space camp coupled with military stuff, but they changed it later and actually they Specifically made it.
Rym: only poor kids from the city could go to it and none of us in the local town could go anymore.
Scott: Anyway, so the other kind of can the next level up camp wise which I've been to all these levels of camp, right?
Rym: As as counselor and also as camp which I want to know in the chat Someone said that quote.
Rym: I've never heard such an American thing in this podcast, right?
Scott: Yeah, I guess I was wondering about like do other countries have?
Scott: I didn't feel like other countries had this right?
Rym: So the Wikipedia article implies that yeah, this is a very American and it's also a very Native American Appropriative.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It's like they're like half on a wanna write.
Scott: the nerd camp.
Scott: I went to was camp Watanka.
Scott: There was not a single Native American there Yet it was very Native American themed.
Rym: very quote from the Wikipedia.
Rym: United Kingdom.
Rym: There's a whole section on the United Kingdom for camps.
Rym: quote summer camps are not a main part of childhood in the United Kingdom.
Scott: I think it's an American thing.
Rym: Anyway, I still think it's like a mostly like Northeastern American thing.
Scott: I may be But I mean salute your shorts was screened all over right?
Scott: Yeah, and it's it's in popular culture across the whole country.
Rym: So it was a thing I knew about but it wasn't a thing I would do.
Rym: and the kids I knew who did it Were always the weird outliers anyway, so The next level up was like the day camp.
Scott: That's where you go away in the morning and then you come back home, right?
Rym: My brother did all day and I did a lot of that but it was all under the purview of like Cub Scouts Mmm, but it wasn't the wrong thing.
Scott: Well some of those, you know, I've been to a few day camps right expensive ones and cheap ones, you know and they vary in levels of qualities and and and right.
Scott: some of them are there as just like I have kids and I Work, I'm a working parent.
Scott: I can't leave the kids at home alone all day.
Scott: I will send them to a day camp.
Scott: It's right The day in the summer and then pick them up and then some of them are actually pretty fancy even though they're day camps.
Scott: They just don't let you sleep there and it's slightly cheaper than the sleepaway cam Yeah.
Scott: But they're just as fancy or perhaps sometimes even more fancy because the money that they're not spending on like camping Cabins and food they're spending on like improving their sport fields and improving their activities, right?
Scott: It's like there are a lot of day camps or like the shit is actually way fancier than Sleepaway camps will have because you know, they're charging about the same but the cert, you know, they're budgeting differently.
Scott: And then you got the sleepaway camps which again range in quality based on how expensive they are and you know at the lower levels You've got like sleepaway camp and rusty shacks barely meeting the you know Barely, basically passing inspection and getting.
Rym: that's what camp was like one of the cab I can't like camp crusty one of the cabins next to where I was staying for band camp one year that no one was in Just fucking collapsed in the middle of the night, right?
Scott: and then at the high end you've got luxury camp which is like the cabins or palaces and The food is incredible and basically each kid wakes up in the morning.
Scott: It just does whatever activity they want all fucking day And it's just like, you know living in a woodsy paradise Commune place for eight weeks
Rym: now seems interesting because the only
Scott: tennis courts
Rym: like when I went When I went
Scott: ball
Rym: when I went on camps, it was usually literal camping which is kind of orthogonal to this.
Scott: Yeah, usually literal camping is like a component of sleepaway camp.
Scott: We're like, yeah, you're living in this cabin in a bed most of the time But then you'll be like, oh this week.
Scott: We're gonna go on a hike and camp.
Scott: Yeah, or this week, you know this weekend We'll go do this activity and you know, we did stuff like go to amusement parks Or you know all kinds of stuff.
Rym: But what I the only real camp I did that was sleepaway and in cabins and the kind of thing was band camp Which in the Midwest like a lot of people went to because marching bands were real big there and that was the thing.
Rym: So there were a lot of dedicated like summer camp looking places that were actually just for band camp.
Rym: So like every band would send their band there for like two or four weeks and they just imagine a summer camp like you're thinking But it has like 12 football fields like all over the place and like band shells and Otherwise, the food is awful and the cheapest possible rule you can imagine.
Rym: the facilities are just like dilapidated garbage like pooping in a hole.
Scott: I've had some pooping in a hole.
Rym: Yeah, but band camp was also hyper-structured and very military like literally Someone like some senior plays Reveille on a bugle at dawn.
Scott: We had we had Reveille blow on the PA system every morning.
Rym: Ours was a real trumpet or a bugle and you had to get up at dawn For inspection eat breakfast and then immediately to the field for drills and we literally just worked all day until the Sun went down.
Rym: We need the gruel dinner and then we'd have like two hours of.
Rym: you can do whatever you want time Meaning.
Rym: we'd play like bond in the cabin because old and I yeah Yeah, and then we'd have dinner and a dance.
Rym: every night They'd have like this dance party which I wanted nothing to do with and then the next morning at like 6 a.m We'd wake up and do the whole thing again.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and it was just a grueling Difficult slog that left everyone physically and mentally exhausted by the end of it.
Scott: See summer camp.
Scott: see that if you're a kid that goes to summer camp, it's basically either heaven or hell.
Scott: there's not really a lot of in-between right.
Scott: so if some kids go there and like they're homesick or Like they don't.
Scott: they're just like, you know, they're socially.
Rym: When I was in high school and I went to space Academy Which is like the older kids version of space camp Holy shit did.
Scott: most of the kids who went to that like Freak out and cry and like couldn't deal with me and so friend or they don't get along or they're you know Bullying victims because I mean it's a place with a bunch of kids.
Scott: Yeah, right You're one of those kids.
Scott: then summer camp is like hell.
Scott: it's the worst thing ever.
Scott: Don't send me there again Right, but if you go there and you make friends and you enjoy the activities and you like doing the things that are at summer Camp it's heaven on earth.
Scott: It's like you can ignore society.
Scott: There's no fucking grades not you're basically cut off from the awful world, right?
Scott: You have this awesome culture of everyone getting along kumbaya for eight weeks.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Everything's free.
Scott: You don't gotta worry about fucking money, right?
Scott: Everyone's just having a good time 24/7 You don't get to give a shit and it's the best.
Scott: and if I could go to live in summer camp I totally would but you can't Okay, so it's like that sort of thing and as someone who has counseled and been to summer camp many times I've experienced both the heavens and also the hells equally in different numbers.
Scott: those who I saw here is I guess I can't go forever which I could yell right.
Scott: so the things that GeekNights listeners will find relevant, right?
Scott: One year I went to a day camp.
Scott: This is the second time I had been to this particular day camp.
Scott: The previous time was like a couple years ago And I only kind of got along with the kids who were at this camp who are my age, right?
Scott: They weren't really the nerdiest.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Scott: So I go to this camp is the first day there.
Scott: It's the second time I've ever been to it.
Scott: But the camp and here's the thing is about these camps when they're eight weeks.
Scott: If you're only gonna go for four weeks, you better go for the first four weeks.
Scott: Don't go for the second four weeks.
Scott: You're the new kid.
Scott: so I was the new kid even though I had been there two years ago, whatever.
Scott: And I show up and they've already got like a whole, you know That like the culture has already been established and I'm sort of like man.
Rym: You got to be there first to establish the culture exactly.
Scott: So like I'm sort of an outsider outcast person who's just appeared on this first day, right?
Scott: But you know, that's just the people that are like in my cabin.
Scott: So it's like my day was meh with them right, but what was actually a problem?
Scott: It was a day camp and on the bus to go there There was this one kid who was harassing like.
Scott: he wasn't like targeting me.
Scott: He was targeting everyone on that motherfucking bus like a Nelson Muntz.
Scott: He was like this kid was the Nelson.
Scott: is Nelson That ever Nelson?
Scott: right?
Scott: so bad, right.
Scott: and then we're basically waiting for the bus to go home.
Scott: right, I Attempted to strangle this kid to death.
Scott: people were cheering me on.
Scott: Yeah, I did not succeed.
Scott: He was I guess a little bit larger than me.
Scott: My friend was like, you know, my friend who was with me at the camp.
Scott: He was just a year younger than me.
Scott: So he wasn't like in my cabin or anything, but he rode the bus with me because we live close to each other.
Scott: Well, I think his comment was yeah that kid deserved it.
Scott: But yeah, I don't know if I got kicked out of the camp or quit but I only went to the care for one day that you Didn't go back.
Scott: My mom probably got my money back I imagine because she.
Scott: that's how she is see.
Rym: it's interesting because like the band camp dynamic because it's so structured There really weren't concerns like that.
Rym: because even if there was a piece of shit kid who wanted to bully everyone You're literally busy the entire time and being judged and graded the entire time.
Scott: Yeah, there's.
Scott: no people are there just to have fun So someone ruining the fun is no good.
Scott: And then so here's the other thing GeekNights listeners will care about is the.
Scott: there's a camp I went to two times Sleepway camp.
Scott: It's in Pennsylvania.
Scott: I don't know if it exists.
Scott: I think it still exists.
Scott: It's a nerd camp called camp Watanka and it is science camp.
Scott: specifically.
Scott: It was also only boys, but I think there was another camp.
Scott: That was only girls.
Scott: That was like the sister camp.
Scott: It's W-a-t-o-n-k-a Right.
Scott: I don't know if you can find it anyway But this camp was the nerdiest camps.
Scott: He is things that happened at this camp that made it the greatest, right?
Scott: So first of all, right imagine you take you have to choose to that you choose activities.
Scott: So like you have to choose two activities every two weeks, right?
Scott: So if you're there for eight weeks, you're doing all right.
Scott: You can choose the same ones again, but those are like supposedly beat.
Scott: There's like a short list.
Scott: Those are the educational sciences.
Scott: When you're not scheduled to be at a science you can do any of the activities that they announce on the loudspeaker, right?
Scott: But so the science is.
Scott: for example when I chose chemistry We threw sodium in the lake and had a uranium compound.
Scott: It wasn't pure uranium It's like uranium something I'd and pointed a Geiger counter at it, right?
Scott: And her to go click click click Right.
Scott: when I chose what else did I choose?
Scott: Oh, wait, I chose video and we made a zombie movie.
Scott: That was awful on VHS camcorders.
Scott: I chose Can't even remember what at the house I know in Starbase.
Rym: I chose fighter jet and I got to lick because there's such a kind of thing.
Rym: we got to choose and I literally got to spend like a Couple hours over the course of the summer all told in the actual military f-16 Simulator that they use for training and I got the like 101 training and how to fly an f-16 I chose.
Rym: I never successfully fucking landed that thing.
Rym: I crashed every time.
Scott: I chose computer science.
Scott: twice I learned HTML with Netscape navigator gold Apple Macintosh like LC twos or whatever.
Scott: one of them was better.
Scott: It could switch to DOS and you pressed Apple enter and they played marathon.
Rym: Oh, so, you know, it's funny cuz I also played a lot of SimCity 2000 before I had a computer like I learned see I made a hangman in see - I think this is part of the like the area differences.
Rym: like in the Midwest least where I was the local middle school all Summer like twice a week had a computer club.
Rym: You could just go in and use the computers like and that like we did that like I'd go into the school like every day.
Scott: We had an external hard drive with all the games on it and it was a network.
Scott: So everyone was loading up the games onto their Macs from this one hard drive.
Scott: and the British guy who?
Scott: The visiting, you know counselor?
Scott: right because a lot of camp counselors are from foreign countries.
Scott: They get like temporary summer visas.
Scott: They're a camp counselor easy job.
Scott: for eight weeks you get your room and board you visit the US for basically almost nothing.
Scott: It's a great deal.
Scott: If you are in a foreign country and want to come to the US for a summer that is actually still a great deal.
Rym: You can do probably way better than working like the boardwalk of.
Rym: yes, it's super great.
Scott: I highly recommend it Uh, but anyway, he was like.
Scott: I just always remember he's Australian.
Scott: I was in New Zealand.
Scott: He definitely was Australia or New Zealand.
Scott: Remember, it was definitely not UK guy because I remember him teaching us how to throw a football rugby style And he we couldn't catch it when he threw it.
Scott: It was too hard.
Rym: If you can't place the accent it could have been South Africa.
Scott: No, it was definitely a New Zealand or Australia, but I remember him saying this hard He was so proud of the hard drive that they had.
Scott: Yeah, this hard drive is one gigabyte.
Scott: It was a one gigabyte external magnetic spinning disc that was plugged into the server Mac with like her the SCSI cable.
Rym: Oh my god, beautiful.
Scott: It had sim CD 2000 and all everyone save games on it.
Rym: It was like I remember the first time someone said they copied a CD to their hard drive and I called bullshit.
Rym: Yeah, I was like, there's no hard drive that big.
Scott: we didn't have a CD around there.
Scott: Other things that happened at the summer camp.
Scott: they would always after lunch.
Scott: They would always be go to the cab and have quiet time and you're supposed to write a letter.
Scott: We would play D&D second edition.
Scott: Yeah after Always after dinner at no other time of the day did they offer this activity on the loudspeaker?
Scott: But after dinner it was guaranteed to be adventure games behind the food at the picnic table.
Scott: Adventure games meant one of the following Magic the gathering with the cards you brought to camp.
Scott: Yep It's not like you could get more unless someone mailed you some which I brought my magic cards to.
Rym: most of the camp They wouldn't mail us magic cards.
Scott: That's I'd be like mom mail more magic cards.
Scott: All right, or more D&D or Battle tech.
Scott: those are pretty much the adventure games that would happen after dinner.
Rym: every single fuck Every one of those is truly an adventure.
Scott: Yes, and The other amazing things that would happen at camp?
Scott: because you basically had this humongous area with every sport and lake and pool and Roller hockey and dodgeball basketball and everything that you could possibly imagine is when there were camp wide activities, right?
Scott: They would always be epic and I'll talk about this more.
Scott: on the catch the flag.
Rym: All this is a prelude to get it out of our system.
Scott: on the 4th of July There was no schedule.
Scott: There was only one thing on the schedule and that was Revolution.
Scott: everyone at the whole camp plays capture the flag in the woods all fucking day go the end until it's dark.
Scott: Right shit like that goes down there and that does not happen in your neighborhood.
Scott: Capture the flag ghost in the grave all those kinds of games like bombardier Which would take me a while to explain but it used the entire terrain of the camp.
Scott: Yeah involved trivia and also counselors jumping out at you swinging socks full of flour trying to whack you with them.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, we uh, well we'll save all that.
Rym: but this is think of all of this because I think we've wrapped up this show.
Scott: Yes, the prelude to the next Tuesday episode of GeekNights, which is gonna be about Capture the flag talk come to the forum where we're gonna have a there's a thread for every episode in the forum and Discuss your summer camp experiences and such.
Rym: All right This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Scott: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and my comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights
Scott: are
Rym: Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Rebecca done Heidi McNicholas shimmering ruby obelisk hanging in the sky my state calm Jeremy minor linky G cold guy Amanda - yet Sean Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas brand out captain Shingo Akasi for 2-1 creations.
Rym: No, I never come ever come.
Rym: I wonder why we're here.
Rym: a period Semper Fi come a bitch period Sure, but horrible rare.
Rym: Laval James David White Rochelle, Monta Nona Superboy with a bunch of exclamation points.
Rym: Rym says something funny here sailor Vista Don Shleich Jartavish and Joshua Joe star Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Finn with an exclamation points in all Caps Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: It'll really mess me up if the end of this ever changes from that nice little cage I got of Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn, but yeah, I still working on the production for that new ten episode.
Rym: we're gonna release that as soon as we can and I'll see you guys later, but now I leave you with fun times in Cleveland today Cleveland.
Rym: Come on down to Cleveland town.
Scott: Everyone come and look at both of our buildings.
Rym: buy some food that's prepared near the street.
Scott: Who knows you might even see this guy.
Rym: you should come on down to West 6th Street.
Rym: It's the perfect place.
Rym: if you're a douchebag watch the poor people all wait for buses.
Rym: Who the fuck still uses a payphone?
Rym: Here's the place where they're used to be industry.
Rym: this train is carrying jobs out of Cleveland.
Rym: Cleveland leads the nation and drifters.
Rym: Here's a statue of Moses Cleveland.
Rym: He's the guy who invented Cleveland yeah.