Rym: It's Tuesday, May 22nd 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We're talking about big fish casino.
Scott: You're the fish.
Rym: it's bad news.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So one thing about New York, I love living in the city But if you got a broken toe It's kind of a pain in the ass cuz you do have to walk pretty much everywhere.
Scott: you broke your toe.
Rym: I broke my toe like two weeks ago.
Scott: I'm doing what skiing?
Rym: Uh, yes skiing.
Rym: I tripped over the rapids cage in the middle of the night, uh-huh, pretty bad and The fit.
Rym: but I learned something interesting about broken toes.
Rym: So normally cuz I mean I've broken my toe a bunch of times before.
Rym: that's just the thing that happens.
Rym: I don't know isn't?
Scott: I got thousand pieces.
Rym: I've broken a bunch of my toes over there.
Scott: I have broken no toes and I'm used to it.
Rym: and it's one of those things like what do you do when you break your Toe, how do you even know it's broken and I just hurt You.
Rym: the way I'll describe you would know if you broke your toe.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Well, I haven't broken it.
Rym: Then you definitely have not broken your toe.
Rym: Okay, it's just a hairline fracture but my whole life broken toe unless like the bone is sticking out then you just set it and buddy tape it like tape it to the toe next to it and just suck it up and wait and it'll heal itself and My whole life.
Rym: I always just assume that's what you do unless like something serious happens.
Rym: so this time, you know broke my toe and it was obvious like I broke it.
Rym: and Because I've got insurance I Decided well, maybe I'll go to the doctor because there's just like a clinic I can go to in the basement of my office building.
Rym: It's like a full-on doctor in there.
Rym: So I just went down there and got it checked out and I learned That the advice that you should just tape it up Really only exists in America because our health care system is so shitty that most people can't afford to treat a broken toe the right Mm-hmm, so apparently you should always get it x-rayed even if it's just like a minor broken toe because there is no way to tell just by observing that your toe is broken if it's a hairline fracture that will heal on its own or a hairline fracture that Touches the joint in a way that if you just tape it up You'll probably get arthritis and have problems with that toe 20 years down the road.
Scott: Maybe that's why your toe keeps breaking.
Rym: Uh, no, that is not why my toe keeps breaking.
Rym: adults break their toes Shockingly often in the United States.
Scott: Oh, I will live the rest of my life with no broken toe.
Scott: I would actually.
Rym: I will bet you money that you will break your toe at some point before you die.
Scott: No, I might actually bet on that.
Rym: You want to bet on that?
Scott: I am so not.
Rym: I'll bet you a hundred bucks Right now that you will break your.
Rym: break a toe at least once in the next ten years.
Scott: I gotta research the odds.
Rym: How's it pretty good?
Rym: Because like I said people just tape them up or don't worry about it.
Rym: But yeah The only way to know if your toe is broken in the way That could cause you pretty serious problems way later in life is with an x-ray.
Rym: there's no way to tell otherwise, but because most people in America don't have good insurance or Otherwise can't easily get an x-ray The next best advice is to just tape it up and suck it up because it's probably fine.
Rym: But because I'm a runner and I actually really care about being able to run into my old age I got an x-ray and had it legit checked out and it was the good kind of broken toe.
Rym: So I just taped it up and did the thing.
Rym: but even the doctor was like, yeah You should get it x-rayed because there's no way to know.
Scott: Yes, you should give me money and patronize my doctor business.
Rym: They uh, ah They're like a clinic in the building.
Rym: Like I don't I don't actually give them any money.
Rym: It cost me zero money to have to get this x-ray.
Scott: Yes, it cost you zero money.
Scott: But if you go there someone else gives them money.
Scott: if you don't go there, they would have gotten less money from someone else.
Scott: Oh, yeah true It also cost them not a lot of money to spend a few minutes talking to you.
Rym: but the moral is I think there are a lot of Low-key medical issues in the United States specifically where you should go to the doctor But beyond if you don't have good insurance, you're actually better off not going to the doctor, but there's a small like negative lottery.
Scott: I mean I think it's funny is even if you have insurance is just going to the doctor is a slight pain Compared to say going to the store true.
Scott: So In other places, right?
Scott: It's not necessarily the fact you have to pay for it.
Scott: It's simply that it's just easy to go there.
Scott: You know, there's less dude.
Scott: I have bureaucratic hassle Involved in going there.
Rym: I've always Be painted because of the way insurance works.
Rym: It's always a pain in the ass to go to the doctor for anything other than a physical.
Scott: you think they want it To be less of a pain in the ass.
Scott: even you know.
Scott: You think the for-profit insurance companies would want it to be less of a pain in the ass so that you?
Scott: Oh, I guess no.
Scott: then they would have to pay out.
Scott: Yeah The doctors would want to be less of a pain in the head.
Scott: The moral
Rym: is if you break your toe and you have good insurance Even if you know like I knew that you can just trade it yourself You should probably just go get an x-ray because there's a small chance
Scott: if there's anything wrong with your body You should go see a doctor.
Scott: Yeah a real doctor.
Scott: Yeah Not dr.
Scott: Nick.
Rym: Well, I remember when I cut the tip of my finger off and I tried to go see a doctor.
Rym: then I gave up and went Home and just super glued his shot as a different problem.
Rym: Yeah, but uh, so I got this broken fucking toe And it's a giant pain in the ass to walk around New York City on this thing.
Rym: So I've actually been wearing my bike shoes Because the bike shoes have a steel plate in the bottom.
Rym: They don't bend so they're actually Great for dealing with a broken toe.
Scott: Hmm.
Rym: So I'm just doing the right thing.
Scott: is your Go to like get a boot?
Rym: Yeah, this serves the same purpose as the boot.
Rym: In fact, it does the exact same thing as the boot.
Rym: It seems squishier.
Rym: No, the part the thing about the boot is that it doesn't let the bottom of the foot flex.
Rym: You don't want that toe to fight.
Scott: It's squishy on the top.
Rym: Yeah, my bike shoes are really comfortable.
Rym: They're squishy on the top.
Rym: They're hard on the bottom.
Rym: But anyway in some gaming news The thing that I predicted open the envelope.
Rym: Lisa the thing that I've been talking about a lot Very not a very difficult prediction.
Rym: Yeah, but seems like a lot of hockey.
Scott: It's not like you're fucking Nostradamus up here.
Rym: yeah, I was pretty confident.
Rym: the Vegas Goldenizer do very well and it has come to pass the The new expansion team.
Rym: There's a new team in the NHL for hockey You don't know and that brand new team in their first year made it all the way to the Stanley Cup playoffs.
Rym: They are going to play a series of between four and seven games and they might win the Stanley Cup.
Rym: that is For a lot of people really vexing and I find that really funny.
Rym: I really want them to win the Stanley Cup.
Scott: I don't understand why it's.
Scott: it's like why you know, the only thing embarrassing about it is Nothing.
Scott: It's like I don't have a problem with.
Scott: it's like why they're a team just like every other team.
Scott: They're valid just like.
Scott: I don't see a problem.
Scott: Right?
Scott: The only problem is it's embarrassing for Existing teams especially
Rym: existing teams who have never won the cup
Scott: right teams that have like they've worked all these years Developing players and scouting and doing all this work and they're gonna
Rym: win a cup before the Buffalo Sabres win a cup,
Scott: right?
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, even if they don't win it It's already embarrassing because it's like even if you're just a team in your second year It's like you had another year to work on this.
Scott: Yeah No, it's like if I'm playing netrunner.
Scott: I played since the way beginning people who started playing way after me who didn't you know learn all those cards and they came out Better than me.
Rym: Yeah, like ah, but it seems like it's just a consequence of the the way the draft works Well also dated a modern take on forming a team and the team seems to be.
Scott: there's also no there are no other teams expansion teams formed at the same time to exactly and also they made deals even before the thing started and Most of the rest of the NHL didn't seem to take them super seriously and was not worried about them being good.
Scott: No And there's a bunch of other stuff.
Scott: they didn't get any of the.
Scott: you know, everyone is able to protect players.
Scott: They didn't get any a players.
Scott: They just got all B players and but they got like if you play all Grande and you get second place in every cut in every province.
Rym: They made the team in NAS ice hockey.
Rym: That's all middle dudes Yep, and all middle dudes actually a really good team.
Scott: It's not bad.
Rym: They don't have to have like one worthless fat guy.
Rym: So, uh, yeah pretty excited about this, uh, I'm rooting for the caps in the just to make it.
Scott: No, I'm rooting for the Lightning because there's 15 Rangers, Florida Rangers.
Rym: Yes See, I'm ambivalent cuz.
Rym: on one hand I want those people even though they're on Tampa Bay to win.
Scott: But other than I don't like Tampa Bay What I have nothing against Tampa Bay and I want those people to win and I also want the conditional draft pick to become more Valuable.
Rym: I'm rooting for the caps just because they're losing the series But now that they pushed it to game seven, I don't care that much anymore In every series, I don't care about.
Rym: I root for whoever's currently losing.
Rym: That's all I want.
Rym: I just want everything due to a crazy game seven.
Rym: I Think I think Vegas is gonna win the Stanley Cup.
Rym: I would bet money on it.
Rym: You want to bet money?
Scott: Go you you can bet money.
Rym: No, you want to bet money against me right now?
Rym: No No, you want to bet cash for his lightning?
Rym: No, I'll put 20 bucks on the caps.
Scott: You can go to Vegas and do it.
Rym: I'll put a hundred bucks on Vegas right now.
Scott: go to Vegas.
Scott: You don't want to.
Rym: you don't want that 50.
Scott: No, I'm not talking about Vegas the teams on Vegas the place.
Scott: Go I know I'm talking.
Scott: go there and bet.
Rym: go talking you right now.
Scott: if you're so confident go do it.
Rym: I just want to bet against you.
Rym: I don't want to bet against.
Scott: you could do.
Scott: I'm sure you can do like some sort of fantasy not exactly directly betting on the result You know, yeah on draft kings or whatever,
Rym: but yeah, I just bring this up because Gaming nerds should pay attention to sports nerds because you're all fans of the same thing in the end.
Rym: So there's other big news and there's.
Rym: there's a lot of there's.
Rym: this is actually a much more complicated Story than we even have time.
Scott: There's a lot of details on here and I don't have time.
Scott: if you care about the details go read a hundred articles about them.
Rym: So there's two ways to look at this and I pulled two different articles to link to to give you two different perspectives.
Scott: Well, his is the gist right?
Scott: is that on steam?
Scott: There's a lot of games and there usually aren't a lot of games on steam that are just outright porn.
Scott: they don't allow that.
Scott: Yeah, you got it.
Scott: You got to sell your porn somewhere else.
Scott: It's not steam.
Scott: Yeah, which you know makes sense It's not.
Scott: you can't sell your porn at Barnes Noble.
Scott: You got to buy the porn at the porn shop, right?
Rym: But then again, you can buy a Danielle steel book at the Barnes & Noble sure, but you know, you can buy our Pornography Every definition of the word blockbuster.
Rym: video didn't have porn except apocalypse zero was just on the VHS rack next to like My Little Pony and a Disney movie.
Scott: Yes, but to get actual porn you had to go to the back of video bar.
Rym: Not the front of video, but there was actual porn at the front of video bar.
Rym: It just wasn't obvious that it was porn.
Scott: and but at the back there was real.
Scott: Yeah, straight up for anyway.
Scott: on steam.
Scott: There are a lot of games.
Scott: most of them Happen to be visual novels in a what is Stereotypically called anime style, right?
Scott: Yeah or of Japanese origin that do not necessarily Containment or may contain pornographic material.
Scott: but you know, it's a varying degrees of pornographic, you know Yeah content, but right what constitutes pornographic content for valve and steam?
Rym: What constitutes it in the United States is I don't want to see it But especially with valve and steam they don't actually have clear policies on this stuff.
Rym: how?
Scott: because you can't make it clear policy?
Scott: That's what the policy of the United States is.
Scott: You know when you see.
Rym: but the trouble is a lot of the things that are being classified as pornographic Aren't?
Rym: they just involve LGBT themes?
Scott: also They contain the exact same kind of content that you would see in say Grand Theft Auto which is on steam.
Scott: Yeah, or there's a wolfenstein game where there's like a set of straight-up sex scene.
Scott: It's on steam.
Scott: Yeah, right, but because it happens to be in a anime style and some visual novel It's viewed differently because like oh, it's a hentai.
Scott: But this is just like, you know a sex scene in our rated movies seen differently than you know A sex scene in an anime because then it suddenly becomes a hint.
Rym: there is yet another angle here in terms of what they've actually been cracking down on and how a Lot of this might just end up being.
Scott: and in some of the cases they like for some of the games They're like, oops We said that you know, we didn't think hard enough about who we sent those messages to.
Scott: we're not gonna actually take you off steam.
Rym: Yeah, right, but there is a problem.
Rym: there's a situation basically where Some people are taking Japanese crap.
Rym: Oh visual novels.
Rym: or just making the good ones or making their jet.
Rym: No I'm talking about the crap Oh ones okay, or they're making their own like super crap.
Rym: Oh visual novels and they're just shoveling the shovelware into the steam marketplace as fast as they can.
Rym: We're talking like copy/paste the entire game script into Google Translate and just sticking it out there Maybe without even having the actual rights.
Scott: Well, didn't steam like change it So you can't just get your game on steam automatically.
Scott: You gotta be approved in the first place.
Rym: Yeah, and they got rid of greenlight because greenlight was both good and bad.
Rym: and there's there's a. there's a bunch of crap going On here, but these two articles one of them is titled valves move to censor visual novels undoes its steam direct promises And it's a pretty nuanced take on all this.
Rym: The more popular title line this is from motherboard is it's an anime titty holocaust.
Rym: Steam is cracking down on visual novels.
Scott: So I think what it comes down to is if you're someone who wants to play Visual novels that may or may not have porn in them You're gonna want to get them from somewhere else.
Rym: is not steam which you probably should anyway But also a lot of games that either aren't pornographic or really should not be banned from steam or being caught up in this.
Scott: Yes, there's definitely an unfair, you know Unconsistent application of policy as to what is an unclear policy as to what is and what is not allowed on steam Which is a problem when there's pretty much, you know, it's not they're not monopoly this.
Scott: you know that origins they.
Rym: Amazon doesn't have a monopoly on buying stuff online exactly But they are the.
Scott: they basically run PC gaming and choose what PC games are available and it's a problem that they don't just allow everything.
Scott: so You know, it's sort of like hey But it's like it's the given it's the.
Rym: there's the fine line because at the same time look at the difference between what's in the Apple Store versus what's in Google Play for Android?
Scott: Yeah a bunch of crap.
Rym: Yep So, how do you deal with the crap?
Rym: I like all these.
Scott: all these issues have culminated About what's the perfect right way to do.
Scott: handle everything is but I can tell you the way it's being handled right now is a Problem.
Rym: it is not good and it's especially considering valves undo influence over the platform.
Rym: But as a consumer, I only want to go to one store.
Scott: Yeah, and the main victim here is really Games and other software content that happens to have be perhaps x-rated But also isn't just you know worthless, you know low like porn that has no like You know other value to it, right?
Scott: There could be for example some really highbrow shit that happens to have lots of nakedness and explicit sex scenes in it.
Scott: Yeah That will get cut from steam and there's also a lot of and that's the real.
Scott: the real victim is stuff like that or a lot Of media.
Rym: that isn't even that explicit.
Rym: probably isn't even x-rated maybe not even r-rated but certain Shall we say shitty people will treat anything that involves LGBT themes as Partographic and that is being caught up in here too.
Rym: This really hurts Indies.
Rym: it also really hurts really bad.
Rym: companies really shouldn't be selling their games on Steam and It's just a giant mess.
Scott: and they got it.
Scott: They got to sort their shit out and say this is what's allowed.
Scott: This is what's not allowed.
Rym: I would argue on a higher level.
Rym: valve needs to short sorted shit out because valve increasingly is Not a very good company in my opinion.
Rym: like the steam controller failed They kind of stopped making games.
Scott: for the most all they make dota and they're making a dota card game.
Rym: Yeah What happened to half-life?
Scott: 3 Have a what?
Scott: Numbers go up to 3.
Scott: Yeah, what's half is 2 2 is as high as numbers go To The zombie game - yep numbers only go up to - doesn't know how to count the three To Games.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so when I was a kid in middle school one of the events in the science Olympiad I was always into was the various paper airplane events, but I did it one time.
Scott: I was not good.
Rym: Yeah, I was good and I won medals.
Rym: But the reason for that was that I got this book that was like here are how to make professional quality paper airplane.
Scott: I got also such a book and I chose the coolest looking paper airplane and not the farthest flying.
Scott: But there was no award for coolest looking.
Scott: No, I minded mine basically went And then land on the ground, but the trouble was that.
Rym: but a lot that book made really good paper airplanes And I actually am very good at fault like making paper airplane.
Rym: That's a skill I have.
Scott: I mean, it's not it.
Scott: You can just look it up and do it.
Rym: Oh, no, but I like the craft of it like actually folding it myself.
Scott: I can very quickly be easier than like origami.
Scott: Yeah, anybody can do it if they give you just show.
Rym: well high-quality paper airplanes are very origami adjacent and actually kind of difficult to Execute because slight miss foldings have drastic consequences for them.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: We're right one to account for next time.
Rym: We go to the park.
Rym: Let's both make paper airplane.
Rym: We'll see who goes furthest.
Rym: You can't look online.
Rym: You have to make it right there.
Rym: You get one piece of paper.
Rym: No second chances paper clip Paper clip kind of baby.
Rym: Are you?
Rym: he's bigger paper only no tape.
Rym: No paper clip.
Scott: No paper.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: No scissors.
Scott: What kind of paper can I?
Rym: uh one?
Rym: standard letter hundred pound eight and a left eight by an F by 11 Just one just one.
Scott: No second chances scissor.
Scott: No Ruler.
Rym: though, I'll let you have a ruler.
Scott: Oh, you need a ruler, huh?
Rym: I don't need a ruler.
Rym: I'm allowing you to use a ruler.
Scott: Are you gonna use it?
Rym: No, fuck now.
Rym: I know what I'm doing Mm-hmm.
Rym: I can make a very paper airplane right now.
Rym: They'll kick your ass.
Scott: But anyway, he's gonna look up how to make best paper airplane and copy that design.
Rym: So in the science Olympiad I made the paper airplane design that had the longest hang time because that was the competition that year.
Scott: It was I should have done but they didn't have internet in those Long.
Rym: is the paper airplane going to stay in the air before it touches the ground?
Rym: the number of seconds That's your score.
Rym: and I made an airplane that stayed near a real long time.
Rym: But this other fucking kid is also.
Scott: the throwing technique is the problem.
Rym: Oh, I knew I knew the throwing technique is the book told me and I practiced it.
Scott: I watched it.
Scott: I think we'd think of the day once was like farthest airplane.
Rym: Yeah, you kind of stand down.
Rym: you have this like particular launch.
Rym: So this other fucking kid and I threw mine.
Rym: it hung for a long time.
Rym: I felt really good I was gonna the gold medal.
Rym: he walks up.
Rym: He makes this weird-looking airplane And it wasn't in something from my book and he throws it into the air and it flies across the arena flips over Flies back the other way flips over flies back.
Rym: It was in the air for fucking ever.
Rym: And I was like, how'd you make that?
Rym: He was like, I'm not telling you you wouldn't talk to me.
Rym: This video tells you exactly how to make those kinds of paper airplanes.
Scott: Well, I guess that's the one the video that I'll copy.
Rym: this guy makes the world-record paper airplanes and goes into detail on how to Make paper airplanes.
Scott: I'll just copy exactly what he does in this video.
Rym: Yep, if you do what this guy does in the video and you execute it Well, you can make one hell of a paper airplane.
Rym: And it's interesting because I found videos like this for Pinewood derbies For boxcar all isn't?
Scott: Pinewood derbies want to get a real narrow Without people staying on above.
Rym: No, you want to have slightly off-center wheels only three wheels.
Scott: Oh You put the wheel in the middle in a hole.
Rym: Oh No I'll make my thing of the day.
Rym: So basically all the things that Scott and I and a lot of you are our age did as competitions where we were in school.
Rym: nowadays there is a YouTube video that will tell you how to make a thing in that competition that is world record quality.
Scott: and Does that mean if I go to a Pinewood Derby like the local elementary school that I'm gonna see all Identical cars except for the kid who doesn't and see the one kid who does not use the internet as a different car?
Rym: So basically what you seem to be seeing because I was poking around to try to answer that question is There'll be like three or four kids who watch these YouTube videos and just make it and learn from professor you.
Rym: yes There'll be one kid the kid who actually wins their dad mom or dad watches YouTube and actually does the execution for them because they have adult knowledge of like Execution techniques coupled with YouTube and then every other kid just sucks Like doesn't know how to use YouTube and they just try to do it on their own.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I feel like we should just like people keep talking about like funding for schools and stuff.
Scott: I feel like we can just get rid of all schools private and public and just have professor you only.
Rym: I think the problem is My based on this experience in any given sample size of like a hundred kids five or six will go to professor you.
Rym: One of them will go to professor you with their parents.
Rym: the rest of the kids will fuck around and fail on their own.
Scott: They're gonna fuck around and fail in real school - why should we spend money at school needs to teach them to go to professor?
Rym: And also the problem is if you just teach them to go to professor you Couple of those kids are gonna go to the Nazi professor you and make a Nazi airplane.
Scott: Yeah, you got a first thing you do when you go to professor you is a professor you.
Scott: how do I ask you questions?
Rym: So, you know what?
Rym: Here's the craziest side.
Rym: when the internet was relatively new when I was in sixth grade The Science Olympiad had an event that was literally how to fucking search for stuff on a search engine.
Scott: Yeah And garbage Alta Vista where all right, it was a real event and the girl There's also 404.
Rym: the competition was.
Rym: they gave you a list of like a hundred questions to answer and the only thing you could use Was a computer with access to the internet raising Carta.
Rym: No, you could use a CD-roms, nope, you had a computer with a web browser and unlimited internet access With the caveat that that's what the internet was when I was in sixth grade.
Scott: I mean, I could probably redo really well at that today or back in the day.
Scott: Yeah, you know what?
Scott: I entered.
Scott: that's like my number one skill.
Rym: I uh, I won that event real fucking hard Because kids didn't know how to use Alta Vista and I was like hitting five search engines at the same time Using the and/or not.
Rym: minus porn minus xxx minus titties minus anime titty Holocaust Kids don't know.
Rym: in the old days.
Rym: The only way to find anything was to type minus a billion things.
Rym: So you got a thing of the day?
Scott: Yeah, so sometimes in life There's a thing that like you sort of feel right but you since you're an intelligent person You don't just believe that you're feeling out the truth Like some people do like
Rym: Girl Scout cookies aren't as good as they were when I was a kid.
Rym: like no you when you were A kid you were just addicted to sugar and you didn't know better.
Scott: Sometimes there are things you just feel are true or you just sort of.
Scott: you know, but you you second-guess yourself.
Scott: You're like nah, it's just a feeling I have.
Scott: it's not real right and I've sort of felt that Like, you know recently it's like I go to the store and I buy saran wrap and it kind of sucks and I'm like.
Scott: and I Thought oh, maybe I'm just buying the shitty saran wrap.
Scott: I got to buy the better shit right out cuz like when I worked in food service For example, you get that big roll and it's just fucking awesome And you know it clings so nicely and it works great and then it kind of just stopped working.
Rym: so great.
Scott: But like all the saran wrap I bought at home You know like wouldn't work so well.
Scott: and it's like how often do I buy a new roll?
Scott: not that often because I don't use it so Much because it sucks and then I discovered like this press and seals.
Scott: I bought that instead and it works pretty well.
Rym: So I want to point out this video.
Rym: your thing today was uploaded on May 15th.
Rym: Like it's recent I think we both watched it at the same time because we both saw the thumbnail that was like is Saran wrap worse than it used to be right?
Scott: It's like apparently.
Scott: yes saran wrap is actually worse than it used to be.
Rym: It's even worse than that.
Rym: It's worser than you think it was right.
Scott: So apparently what happened without anyone knowing except for people who really know things and the SciShow YouTube channel Is that saran wrap did used to be fucking awesome.
Scott: It wasn't just me hallucinating.
Scott: who's they used to be?
Rym: we're talking like early 2000s, right?
Scott: Like it would cling really really well and keep things really really fresh.
Scott: And now it doesn't even if you buy the higher fancy brands.
Rym: and it's not just it doesn't cling Well, it literally doesn't even keep you food fresh anymore.
Rym: No, there's no point in using it.
Rym: It's worthless.
Scott: get the press and seal instead.
Scott: So apparently what happened was there were the press the the old saran wrap.
Scott: there was a chemical in it.
Scott: That was no good.
Scott: No, not no good.
Scott: Like it would poison your food.
Scott: Yeah, no good is in when you threw it away to hurt the environment.
Rym: So not even that it was.
Rym: if you threw it away in a context where it was burned or incinerated which is really common It released poison into the atmosphere, which is bad Yeah, so they stopped making that and they made it differently.
Scott: The problem is the one that they make differently now doesn't cling so well.
Scott: So it's like it's a pain in the ass to use it.
Scott: And also it is much more porous and your food doesn't stay as fresh.
Rym: We say much more porous.
Rym: I think I got it up here.
Rym: So old good Clint saran wrap.
Rym: the real deal would let one to five grams of water vapor out of your food a day.
Rym: So it keeps stuff real real good.
Rym: the Let's see.
Scott: Where's the new stuff?
Rym: the new shit lets out an order of magnitude more water Mm-hmm, and it lets in Multiple orders of magnitude more oxygen.
Rym: That's the real problem.
Rym: old saran wrap let in two to sixteen cubic centimeters per day of Oxygen.
Rym: oxygen is the thing that generally makes your food start to go.
Scott: So it's like I stopped using saran wrap.
Scott: I use like these glass lock containers like Tupperwares Yep, and then I use the press and seal also if I have to right and I just stopped using saran wrap.
Scott: But now this proof that like.
Scott: no I wasn't just like that.
Scott: that change in my behavior actually was because of a real thing that happened.
Rym: Yeah, we noticed like the oxygen thing two to six.
Scott: I wonder if I can buy the old.
Scott: Oh, it's banned saran wrap on eBay or something.
Scott: Even restaurants can't use it as far as I can tell saying like by, you know Yes, someone's still got a role.
Scott: yeah, cuz it's gonna throw it away anyway, it's gonna get thrown away anyway.
Scott: I'm not hurting the environment more if I just help use up all the old poison stuff.
Rym: That's a problem though Scott.
Rym: then you're gonna think anytime you wrap something is it sponge worthy?
Rym: That's right.
Rym: But two to sixteen is the oxygen for the old stuff.
Rym: for the new stuff 8,000 it is literally worthless.
Rym: Just throw away your cling wrap.
Rym: It is worthless garbage.
Scott: now I think.
Scott: I think I do have one role that I don't use of the new crap.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna throw it out In the meta moment.
Rym: the GeekNights book club book is home as the Odyssey translated by Emily Wilson.
Rym: I'm reading it.
Rym: You should read it.
Rym: It's awesome.
Rym: More importantly many of you know, we've been doing a side YouTube show There's been on hiatus for a while called GeekNights presents where on one hand only ever presented one thing.
Rym: Nope, GeekNights presents board games is the other one.
Rym: Okay, but I'm doing that one by mining old episodes of GeekNights.
Rym: That where we've reviewed things.
Rym: But there was a lot of reasons why we weren't making more episodes of GeekNights presents utenna Which is a show where we are going deep into the lit crate and analysis of a famous old anime called revolutionary girl utenna.
Rym: That YouTube show is actually shockingly popular.
Rym: The playlist has like 20,000 views and Hey shockingly popular relative to the general popularity of us.
Rym: Okay, like it's one of our more popular things Because People who like this show not a lot of content for them out there.
Rym: There's like.
Rym: there's empty movement.
Scott: It's an anime that was on for X episode like 40 something episodes in 1990 something and then that was it the end.
Scott: But we have a new manga volume coming those.
Rym: Yeah, we haven't have watched it a bunch of times.
Rym: I've been kind of obsessed with this.
Rym: We've been doing this late lit crit show.
Rym: we relaunched it we made a new episode and Already, there's like a like.
Rym: this has more comments than anything I've uploaded in a long time already and I uploaded this like a couple days ago.
Rym: So if you subscribe to our YouTube and then unsubscribe because GeekNights presents utenna was the only thing you cared about It's back baby who is subscribing just for that.
Scott: Hope isn't listening to this podcast.
Rym: Yeah, they're watching the live stream except for not live streaming this.
Scott: I don't think they're doing that either.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, they are pretty much.
Rym: all these comments are like I've been following your YouTube channel for a year waiting for another one of these.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, ignoring all the other videos we put.
Rym: yeah, though seems like a lot of those people started getting into our other stuff.
Rym: So it's kind of working.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, I think that's all we got.
Rym: follow my youtube channel.
Rym: Hello Scott's YouTube channel.
Scott: There's no conventions coming because it's summertime until PAX West on Labor Day weekend.
Scott: But PAX West tickets are gonna be on sale imminently imminently.
Scott: So you alert if you want to go to PAX West and you don't have a means of getting a badge any other way than the Normal way either a save your money and buy one in the secondary market, which you can totally do easily.
Rym: They are more they are overpriced but not as much as you'd expect You're basically paying money to avoid hassle.
Rym: but or still fuck cuz you need a hotel or be Get ready.
Rym: Yep Any day probably this week is our guest.
Scott: Well, hope it doesn't happen.
Scott: Like.
Scott: well, I'm in a meeting.
Rym: Oh my god I have my Twitter alert set like I am like.
Rym: on top of this I got a. I got a bookmark to go straight to it on the on the front page of my cell phone.
Scott: I've got West pack site calm open in a tab so I can reload it.
Rym: I'm trying to every like hour like on the hour.
Rym: I'm trying to be at my desk because it tends to go at it like on the hour Like I like.
Rym: that's the level of how much we care about packs.
Scott: Are we worried about our pet?
Rym: I'm not being accepted No, and also, uh, the the secret if you really care.
Rym: if you go to PAX dev You can just buy a four-day PAX West badge at any time Face value guaranteed, but you have to buy a dev badge which cost a few hundred bucks.
Scott: It's like if our panel doesn't get accepted and I don't buy one.
Scott: What do I do?
Scott: but last time I bought some and then I end up having to deal with the hassle of selling them Cuz I don't use them.
Rym: Yep, but also I could book a hotel right now if I buy a dev badge But you can only book the Westin the dev hotel.
Rym: Yeah, which is a pretty good packs hotel.
Scott: It's not the worst Yeah, but it's no sure.
Rym: Yeah, it's no PAX East Weston.
Rym: It's no PAX West Sheridan.
Rym: It's no Olivet.
Rym: So, yeah be ready all of you out there.
Rym: So we're gonna talk about this big fucking fish casino game.
Scott: So here's the story here, right?
Scott: It's like why the fuck would these smart people even go near this thing?
Rym: So on it's on my cell phone cuz I had to play it and like really look at this thing.
Rym: I am deleting it like within minutes of us finishing this episode.
Scott: Yeah So I what happened was is I saw this article like a month ago like late March or something that this app big fish casino Had been declared illegal in Washington State by like a federal appeals court.
Scott: It's according to Washington State law Not any other state law.
Scott: cuz like there have been similar cases in other states and there's no federal law regarding this.
Scott: So like federal law doesn't apply and I don't understand why a federal court would look at this when it's a state deal.
Scott: But whatever it's not.
Scott: I don't care about the legal issue.
Scott: I care about the fact that wow, there was an app that was declared illegal now
Rym: Before we did a panel and a pax a long time ago talking about kappa gacha cuz Japan banded
Scott: Yeah, so I put a note like hey check this thing out of it at some point, right?
Scott: So at basically like a week ago, I was just laying in bed you know just gonna go to bed and I was poking on my iPad like you do before you go to sleep and And I'm in the App Store and I'm going like look at you know Just see what new games are in there and I see big fish casino and I'm like, that's the illegal
Rym: one.
Scott: So I doubt it was free to download.
Scott: cuz I you know, it's obviously a free-to-play evil casino thing.
Rym: So I downloaded that shit and I've been checking it out and figuring out its deal And it got to the point where he messages me like you got to check the deal.
Scott: I like this for the past week.
Scott: I've been investigating this and this app.
Scott: I mean, there's other apps.
Scott: There's like.
Scott: there's another one that's a different.
Scott: I looked at a couple other casino Things and like this one is a different one.
Scott: That's I think I forgot exactly what it's called.
Scott: It's something else casino and it basically is the exact same slot machines you see in real American casinos only Digitized and you play for them with fake money.
Scott: you play them with fake money.
Scott: But big fish casino is of all of them the most devious most heinous free-to-play app I have ever seen there.
Rym: literally this is a masterpiece of Pavlovian conditioning.
Scott: every single game mechanic that has ever been conceived by humanity to gets a rat-to-poke a Skinner box is all combined together in a giant salad in this one app.
Scott: Everything that casino that real-world casinos have developed and everything that free-to-play app makers have developed I mean Candy Crush compared to this is totally legit and totally moral in every way.
Rym: Yeah, loot boxes.
Rym: I don't even care about loot box.
Scott: Overwatch loot boxes hearthstone packs of cards.
Scott: They have literally nothing on talking heinous evil.
Scott: That is the big fish casino.
Rym: talking about a loot box It is the base like talking about one bullet in World War two.
Scott: Big fish casino is the ultimate bait and all of humanity is the fish.
Rym: I want to point something out.
Rym: You can't win money.
Rym: It's not real gambling.
Rym: I'm gonna read verbatim from their website.
Rym: big fish casino is intended for an adult audience and does not offer real money gambling or an Opportunity to win real money or prizes.
Scott: That is right.
Scott: It is in fact Just like Candy Crush and all the aforementioned things worse than real money gambling.
Scott: if I go to a real casino like the ones in Connecticut or Atlantic City
Rym: like we did we went and gambled in Atlantic City
Scott: to a real fucking casino and I go to a real slot Machine and I put my real cash in that slot machine There is a non-zero chance that real money will come out of that slot machine and I could.
Scott: actually I could.
Scott: The odds are not with me.
Scott: do not do this I don't recommend it but it is possible that you could leave the casino with more money than you went in with Scott and I Did this placing bets once we went to Atlantic City?
Rym: We were like red red red.
Rym: Well, we got some money Fuck this and we just left with the money immediately.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: It is possible an unlikely but possible I think we've had on black.
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: with big fish casino You don't have to put any money in and we have not put even one penny.
Scott: No, you just get a bunch of fake money you get you gamble with fake chips and you win fake chips.
Scott: But you can if you so desire Give them real money in return for more fake chips.
Scott: And as soon as you do this, you will immediately lose Guaranteed 100% chance.
Scott: You will immediately lose all of that real money.
Scott: It's gone forever.
Rym: Remember you don't get it back.
Scott: You can't win real money, but you're.
Scott: that's like if you go to a slot machine in the casino You put in a dollar.
Scott: your dollar is gone.
Scott: You can't win it back.
Scott: Even if seven seven seven shows up on that slot machine.
Scott: No money comes out only fake money.
Rym: Now when we say no money, we're being late.
Rym: There is.
Rym: you cannot get anything.
Rym: No anything at all.
Rym: Nothing can ever come back to you.
Scott: All you get is they will flip bits for you in their database.
Scott: That's all they will do in exchange for real money.
Rym: So on one hand one could argue that how is this different from any other game?
Rym: You're just paying to play this game.
Rym: Sure Like it's you're not.
Scott: this is illegal.
Scott: How come you know, the loop boxes and frankly aren't illegal.
Rym: I think the only reason this is illegal is that it has casino games in it like status.
Scott: Yeah, it is obvious that the only reason that this is it was no
Rym: people don't know better
Scott: Looks like a casino, but if you actually read some of the comments from the the judges and such They actually point out how the they it's not because it looks like a casino.
Scott: It's because they say that the chips you're winning have some sort of value.
Scott: if you run out of the fake chips You can't play the games in the big fish casino.
Scott: unless you just make a new account you get another hundred thousand free chips Yes, but they're like, hey if you run out of the chips, you can't play the games in the big fish casino anymore.
Scott: Therefore they have value.
Scott: Therefore.
Scott: It's gambling.
Scott: You're gambling the ability to play the games more.
Scott: I'm playing the while you're playing the game.
Rym: No, this is not unprecedented.
Rym: this I cuz salty bet which I think is great.
Rym: You can buy more fake money to bet and a lot of people do buy fake money to bet in salty bad salty bet.
Rym: I actually feel for it.
Scott: Yeah, but way back in the day I paid for it one time.
Rym: I went in there though It's still rockin.
Rym: I logged in for like two seconds and immediately there was this floating Goku and someone's like fake Goku and someone else is like that Is the realest Goku I have ever seen.
Scott: and then someone said never bet DBZ.
Rym: Yeah, never bet DBZ.
Rym: always What a what a what a what a Perfect community.
Scott: salty bad salty bet still great.
Rym: Anyway, but anyway One could also argue that this game I say it didn't have the spend more money to get chips thing.
Rym: It is no different than For example, there's no game on the Game Boy the original Game Boy.
Rym: That was just.
Rym: hey, here's a casino bet the fake money The games gives you and when you leave the casino, that's your score or a bunch of money you had.
Rym: There's no fundamental difference between them except this thing is designed to make humans addicted to it and it does it so well that as much as it is easy to look down on someone who Gets addicted to a really shitty game.
Rym: I Is a victim.
Rym: yeah, it is very hard to play.
Scott: I mean, I can't even begin to list all of the evil things this game does would take a long time, right?
Scott: So first right, but I'm gonna try to list a whole bunch of them.
Scott: just you can grasp how many evil Psychological mechanisms have been combined here.
Scott: It's like it seems like what they did is they just looked at every other app and every other casino in the world and all saw the things that they did and just started adding them one by one over the years because this App is years old.
Scott: It's not new And just.
Scott: they're just all combined together all the next to each other, right?
Scott: So here we go.
Scott: So first of all, it does the same thing that real-world slot machines do which is it tells you win when you lost.
Rym: Yeah, so like yo poker does this - it'll give you a payout.
Rym: That's less than what you bet.
Scott: This happens at real-world slot machines - let's say you go to a slot machine you put in a dollar Right and you and you spin the it spins and you win 50 cents.
Scott: It'll say you won 50 cents.
Scott: No, you didn't go lost 50 cents.
Scott: You put the dollar in asshole, right?
Rym: So, you know, you might think I wouldn't be fooled by that.
Rym: I know I lost.
Scott: you think that right but it never tells you lost.
Scott: The only thing it'll do is just be silent which means you lost a dollar asshole.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: and what's even worse is it shows a Total like a tally of like your winnings over time and it's like you're sitting there and in the bottom corner.
Scott: It's like you have won a million dollars today, but you look and you see well I've got a hundred thousand ships and when I started this morning, I had about a hundred thousand ships.
Scott: I didn't win shit today.
Rym: Yep, now analogize this to like an overwatch.
Rym: when you win or lose the game It says victory or defeat but if If you win or lose it doesn't remind you that you lost because the next thing it does is say oh Here's all the points you got because you played right?
Scott: So that's a thing that real-world casinos do.
Scott: this also does right.
Scott: telling you you always telling you you won When you lost to make you feel like you're winning when you're not to keep you spinning or playing whatever game, right?
Scott: Okay, so here's the things that does that that apps do right?
Scott: So it has this weird.
Scott: the biggest thing I think is the social mechanism.
Scott: How do you make a fucking slot machine?
Scott: So, you know, right?
Scott: so you go to the slot machine and it shows you five other people playing the same slot machine and shows you like what they're.
Scott: It's like if they win like flowers and things explode around there.
Scott: You can see.
Scott: you see they're playing too Right and you can chat with them and you can give gifts to them and buy, you know You can spend the chips to buy Drinks for them which so all it does is make like a drink icon appear next to them.
Rym: I chatted with some people just to see today over lunch No one I interacted with past the Turing test, but I do think they were humans.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: No, they're humans Yeah, but they did not.
Rym: these are humans who could not pass the Turing test.
Scott: No Also, there are some of the slot machines have an even more evil social mechanism.
Scott: There's scatter slots, which means as you're spinning the slot machine, you know There's all the icons that are there, you know, whatever they are, right?
Scott: But there's also these scatter icons.
Scott: If three or more scatters appear anywhere on the slot machine doesn't matter what line they're in or anything Then you'll win money.
Scott: You'll win chips.
Scott: Everyone else who happens to be in the same virtual room as you will receive chips when you spin and get scatters and you'll get chips when they spin scatters and People were like saying thank you as if somehow I chose to give them a gift when I happen to randomly get scattered spin Right, and it's sort of like, you know, there's like encouraging, you know group aspect of like, you know The same thing as Wow raids like.
Scott: don't let the team down it, you know.
Scott: It's like everyone.
Scott: you got to keep keep spinning on auto auto spin on max bet So everyone else will scatter to everyone else.
Scott: Come on do it for the team and then some people are leeches doing like the minimum spin just to stay in the room Right and leech off everyone else's scatters and try to make money that way.
Rym: Yep Not just craps word like.
Rym: the social aspect is keeping them together.
Rym: It's also these social Obligations, right?
Scott: Well, it's either way.
Scott: It's it's both.
Scott: both ways are the same pressure either pressure to do that max bet and keep spinning forever for the obligation or Pressure.
Scott: it's either way keeps you playing right or do what you can do to stay in that room and just leech off other people.
Scott: Either way, they're keeping you in there.
Scott: They don't care which one you're doing You know because it's they've already got a hundred percent of your money as they don't care What happens when you actually play the game?
Scott: They just want you to Want to play it more because the more you play the more you're going to need to give them money eventually to keep playing more.
Rym: Yep, think of it.
Rym: They get you addicted to it and eventually you run out of chips.
Scott: It's like going to the arcade and you played x-men, but you didn't beat magneto.
Scott: yet You need to go back to the change machine.
Scott: Yeah, they want you to go to that change machine.
Scott: good.
Scott: They want you to want to beat magneto, right?
Scott: I guess they you know, they want you to get the jackpot or whatever.
Rym: I mean I sat in fed quarters into a Simpsons arcade machine all day once until we beat it.
Scott: Yeah, this is like that only not a good game.
Rym: It's not even a game.
Scott: It's just random.
Rym: You know, you always say not a game not a fucking game.
Rym: these things right?
Rym: There's one game in here So there's other.
Scott: there's other evil things going on.
Scott: So there's not just the chips, right?
Scott: There's also Tickets gold bars and VIP points.
Scott: There's all different currencies, right?
Scott: The VIP points eventually let you get into VIP areas To play VIP games that other people hang out with.
Rym: the people who might be closer to passing the Turing test.
Scott: Play this game only in a virtual room with other people who have played it too much just like you have.
Scott: No get the tickets.
Scott: the tickets can be used to get prizes.
Scott: the gold bars can be used to get gifts for other.
Rym: No, it's got those prizes.
Rym: These are only prizes in the game.
Rym: It's just more bits.
Scott: Yeah, just more bits and pictures and graphics and icons and sometimes chips sometimes other currencies.
Scott: I think like you can like use the tickets to get the VIP points.
Scott: now Now look at this.
Rym: all that stuff combines into the same kind of pressure that you'd get playing old muds.
Rym: Yeah, you want to be really high level to show off to people around you?
Scott: There's also no matter what whether you win or lose as you play you level up.
Scott: There's like this levels.
Scott: you get XP of some and you're always getting levels and whenever you actually get a new level you get VIP points and chips and tickets and tokens and they begins to give you a pile of rewards.
Scott: so you just even if you're losing money You just want to keep playing to get level up because you'll actually win if you.
Scott: if you if you lose as little as possible You'll actually profit in virtual currencies if you manage to level up.
Scott: So like I found the slot machine that was losing the slowest.
Scott: It's like a really low Minimum bid scatter slot that had like pictures.
Scott: So you're basically you're doing forest animals.
Rym: You know what you're doing with you.
Rym: do that Scott.
Rym: you're doing what the old sad people in the casino do.
Rym: They play the penny slots to build up their reward point.
Scott: I was just trying to see like, you know, how often you level up.
Scott: I wanted to see mostly if the if it's like Yeah, if it's like Pokemon go or the leveling up gets harder over time and actually know the leveling up is like a really consistent Rate, it's like you just keep getting levels like, you know out.
Scott: with that auto spin I got levels like every you know, however unit of time I just kept getting them.
Rym: Well, cuz unlike Pokemon go this doesn't even need the illusion of real competition.
Scott: They didn't make the levels harder to get.
Scott: getting from level 1 to 2 was just as easy as getting from level 49 to 50 It wasn't.
Scott: it didn't get you know, they didn't increase the gap size.
Rym: But see this design pattern is again the same thing that's used to trick old people into sitting in front of a penny slot forever Until they die.
Scott: Yep now even worse.
Scott: They've got clubs.
Scott: You can join a club which is like a guild in Wow And you got to contribute money into it.
Scott: and I don't I didn't do this because I you know didn't get enough fake currency to Do this?
Scott: Yeah but you you basically somehow you have to contribute money into it and you have to play enough that the people in the club want You in the club.
Scott: and then somehow there's like you work together on slot machine tournaments.
Scott: I still don't understand how a slot machine tournament works, but they're a thing I think.
Scott: it's like you have a time limit and you spit.
Scott: it's like who can get the luckiest within that time limit and then You get more payout if you're the luckiest out of everyone who's spinning within that time limits.
Scott: like you want to start when the timer starts and spin as much as you can and then One person out of everyone will go.
Rym: I can get 1.65 million chips and that would normally cost $100.
Rym: If I click on this in the next 15 seconds, it'll cost me $4.99.
Scott: Yeah that I didn't.
Scott: obviously that thing keeps popping up all the time.
Scott: It's it's lying to you about the time limit.
Scott: the same way that like when you get those info, you know TV commercials even better.
Scott: It takes all what's in the next 20 minutes to save whatever but actually you can call whenever that's the same thing.
Scott: It's like there's a get it now button.
Rym: There's a tiny X like a pop-up ad.
Rym: That's the only way to close it.
Rym: Yep, I'm gonna bet all my money on red till I till I run out right now go Yeah, put all your money on red.
Scott: Maybe you'll actually win like you could have go Paris lights.
Rym: Let's go in here do it.
Scott: Yeah, like the the amount of things that this app does is like the most endless evil of evils, right?
Scott: And it's just like shocking that like why shouldn't this be illegal?
Scott: Even if it isn't gambling?
Scott: and also why is?
Scott: Why is this seen as less evil than actual gambling like an actual gambling?
Scott: Like I said, you can win real your money back.
Scott: Maybe here.
Scott: It's a hundred percent guaranteed loss.
Scott: This should be illegal.
Scott: more than real gambling should be illegal But yeah, so the thing I want to take away from this right is two things.
Scott: number one In addition slot machines are most of this app, but it also has some other slot equivalent games.
Scott: There's a horse racing one, which is yeah a slot machine that looks like horses basically effectively.
Scott: There's Texas hold them is in here, which is like hey if you want to play Texas hold them with fake money.
Scott: This actually isn't a bad way to do it.
Scott: It's a pretty good UI for that and you can't you know It's.
Scott: that's actually probably, you know worth playing this app compared to doing real hold them with real money.
Scott: Yeah It also had video poker which is just a slot machine that looks different.
Scott: But it also had this game called burn 3 poker imagine Oh as roulette, which is also a slot machine.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah the burn 3 poker once I played it is actually almost a game like this.
Scott: actually decisions you make and It's mostly luck because you basically only have like a few cards to choose from and you keep getting new cards because you burn the other three Called burn 3 but actually is like there's some thought that goes into like where you position the cards.
Rym: It's actually it's.
Rym: it's like a really baby version of battle line or lost cities.
Scott: Yeah, it's like a one-on-one game.
Scott: It pairs you up with someone you put up some money and if you be if you win against the other person you take The pot.
Scott: there's no like raising or anything or any sort of betting mechanic.
Scott: It's literally just put money in the pot play this game against another human being and if you win you take everyone's money.
Scott: Yeah, and I think the house maybe takes a cut and there's almost like there's almost a game there.
Scott: Yeah, it's like a little game.
Scott: It's almost a little game.
Scott: I was surprised it was in there because he got it Foster that competitive element.
Rym: Yeah, craps is not in here Which is interesting because craps is like the most social existing game.
Scott: I'm also you know also the one well It's still favors.
Scott: the house obviously has the best odds for the players if played properly, but yeah true true Crap, when I perhaps is the way to lose your money the slowest at a real casino?
Scott: Yep,
Rym: craps is also probably the most fun game you can play in a casino
Scott: Game where if you lose your money slow enough and you bet low enough It's actually sort of like fun and it's like, you know I don't feel if I play craps with a low enough minimum bid.
Scott: Yeah, some of those tables like $20 minimum bid.
Scott: It's like hell.
Scott: no.
Rym: No, but if it's like what I said 20 cent minimum bid, here we go.
Scott: It's like a dollar.
Scott: It's like it's actually sort of like hey, it's you know, it's almost.
Scott: it's half as fun as putting a dollar in a DDR machine.
Scott: Okay What was I gonna say?
Scott: I forget.
Scott: so oh No, I forgot.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: The moral of all this is that we've there's a fine line because on one hand we're both extremely
Scott: In
Rym: favor of free speech and we think video games are speech but on the
Scott: other hand
Rym: This addictive shit is really evil and it praised very directly on a lot of people
Scott: All human beings
Rym: and yes, like
Scott: I
Rym: Even though I am mostly me.
Rym: I'm very much inoculating.
Rym: It's this kind of shit.
Rym: Like I'm constantly evaluating games.
Rym: I play Even I over lunch like poking around in this game.
Rym: They got it a little bit into it.
Rym: I was like, oh shit.
Rym: No, and I'm actually deleting the app right now.
Scott: Yeah, they this thing they have slot machines of every different visual style and theme.
Scott: So no matter what you're personally like into what your culture is.
Scott: There's actually a slot machine in here for you.
Scott: There's one that's like a dragon's horde that looked pretty cool.
Scott: The pac-man one is obviously the best one, but the minimum is too high.
Scott: So I couldn't play it unless I wanted to lose all my chips.
Scott: Maybe that's what I'll do is I'll just put the pac-man one on max bet and spin it.
Scott: So all my chips are gone then delete it.
Rym: I just uninstalled it.
Rym: It's uninstalling right now.
Scott: Good job.
Scott: But there's also like America one is a Baywatch one.
Scott: There's like, you know, no matter.
Scott: It's cute little animals.
Scott: There's like any you know There's any kind of theme that interests you.
Scott: one of these slot machines will appeal to you visually And you know the music, you know all the same thing.
Scott: a real slot machine does musically and visually attracts you and makes you want to watch it and get hypnotized mesmerized by it and all that stuff Right.
Scott: So the actual takeaway here that the other thing I want to talk about is that I think there's a way That we can use all of these evil mechanics or some of them and apply them to a not evil casino right to some other kind of good game Right and get people to play it.
Scott: Yeah People to do a thing that is good for people to do like vote for Democrats I mean just you know get addicted to a good behavior and not a meaningless behavior.
Scott: Also how much people talk about how much electricity Bitcoin is using?
Scott: how much electricity is people wasting?
Scott: You know that their phones are using on worthless apps like this.
Rym: But it's just.
Rym: it's interesting that I'm actually pretty.
Scott: always got their phone like set to auto spin somewhere Just killing, you know eating off the power grid.
Rym: I'm okay with legal gambling.
Rym: what I'm actually not okay with are these addictive experience, right?
Scott: I think there should be a lot like if there was a law that was like hey If you got a slot machine and someone puts a hundred in and they win 50 It should be forced to say lose 50 on it.
Rym: But where's the line in a game where there there is no actual gambling here?
Rym: Where is the line between?
Rym: this game is good and people keep playing it versus.
Rym: this game is Mechanically addictive and people people keep playing it.
Rym: Where's the line between?
Scott: I think it just has to be honest and in the case of this game The honesty has to be like hey here.
Scott: They should have to tell you for example Here's the amount of money you've given us over real money.
Scott: You've given us over time total, right?
Scott: You're not and it should be like you've lost all this money.
Rym: Well see there's that I think was the real important differences.
Scott: when it says here's the amount of money you won today It should have to show you the net not I think you know the the real line To regulate this.
Rym: you don't regulate games.
Rym: Generally you specifically regulate microtransactions in games Microtransactions.
Rym: if this game had no way for you to give them money directly if it just had ads be as addictive as you Also has that you can watch ads to get more chips.
Rym: Yep, but make it hundred percent.
Scott: I didn't watch any ads to get chips.
Rym: Yeah, if you make an addictive app That's just free speech.
Rym: if you make an addictive app with microtransactions or a non addictive app with microtransactions those Microtransactions should be heavily regulated.
Rym: That is where I feel like the liner.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver, Ellen Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Heidi McNicholas, Shimmering Rubiopoulos, Hanging in the Sky, MyStady.com, Jeremy Miner, Link Eiji, John Baldwin Kelly Snyder, Cold Guy, Amanda Duchette, Shawn Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brandow, Mr.
Rym: Strong Strachan, 421 Creations, No I Never Ever Wonder Why We're Here, Semper Fi, Bitch, Shervin' on Horel, Rory, James David White, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, Capybara Pickle-Cumquat, Sailor Vista, Don Shleich, Jartavishan, Joe Shiro Joe Star, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Copenlander, Finn, Chris Minkiff, Daniel Redman, Shawn Klein, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: No shows for the rest of this week cuz I gotta fly out to Virginia But we'll be resuming like normal next week.
Rym: and now I leave you with.