Rym: It's Tuesday, May 8th, 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Battle tech the video game the new one Not any of the old battle taking 20 80 not the one on the SNES We'll use on that warrior.
Scott: people use years to tell different things apart that have the same name.
Rym: Yeah, I do that in the time.
Scott: When has there ever been like a doom?
Scott: and then the same year also do Call Right, or they might be like doom video game and do board game.
Scott: But yeah, then you can just say what you know.
Rym: Yeah, very rare is doesn't?
Scott: that is not battle tech and battle tech in the same year.
Rym: Yeah so, uh Stanley Cup playoffs are happening and it's still weird to me.
Rym: This is the first time in my entire sentient life that no team I cared about was in the Stanley Cup playoffs.
Rym: Like there were some years where the Red Wings got eliminated in the first round But they were always there and the first year in a long long long long time They were not in the playoffs.
Rym: I think they set a record for most consecutive playoff occurrences in the modern like not original six era because the original six era What four teams made it to the playoffs out of six and it was the same for almost every year But not counting the Challenge Cup era for obvious reasons.
Rym: But just as the Red Wings for the first time didn't make it I'd been living in New York for like a decade and the Rangers are in the play.
Scott: So there was a screenshot someone showed from I guess a shot from one of the games recently.
Scott: Yeah
Rym: I
Scott: probably I think a lightning game and it was like players with most playoff appearances in the past X years and it was just like a little corner graphic and almost everyone on that list was a New York Ranger until very recently,
Rym: so I guess it
Scott: was like.
Rym: Well to your point it's zero cups.
Scott: Yeah, that's why it was most playoff game appearances.
Scott: Yeah going deep got you more on that list.
Rym: I'm uh, I'm very conflicted now because on one hand I just wanted no Pennsylvania team to still be in the playoffs and we have succeeded at this.
Rym: But Pennsylvania is the bottom right corner and they're gone the asshole.
Scott: they put all their stupid balls in the football Yeah, and fuck them, but well, it's it's past.
Rym: and on one hand I don't like Tampa because they have historically been a team that has not teams I care about out of the playoffs, but on the other hand, it's basically the Tampa Rangers.
Scott: at this point It is the 2015 New York Rangers of Florida.
Scott: Yeah, 2015, Florida Rangers.
Rym: And as I forgot until you reminded me Rangers get a conditional draft pick, right?
Scott: So there is a conditional draft pick where if Tampa wins the cup this year, I think or maybe even next year Then the they have a draft pick that already belongs to the Rangers.
Scott: But that draft pick will move from the second round to the first round if Tampa wins.
Scott: And of course if Tampa wins it would be the last pick in the first round.
Scott: But last pick in the first round is still a few pigs better than you know.
Scott: Pick it like close to last pick in the second round.
Rym: Yeah, that's a big move up if Tampa wins So but on the other hand that upper left quadrant of like the Predators and the Jets I don't really watch those teams or know about him.
Rym: I don't really care that much.
Scott: Well, because you know unlike the other sporting leagues, you know It's like you don't see.
Scott: but if you're in the hockey East you don't see the West too much.
Scott: Yeah, you see like the West like one game a year per team.
Rym: But I think in the end I'm still rooting for the Vegas Golden Knights and the reasons are pretty simple one if they win They will be fucking insufferable.
Rym: There'll be an entire year of batting a thousand.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: every Stanley Cup we've been up for came in and taught you Yeah, it's just like when Rym plays a game for the first time and wins.
Scott: I'm undefeated in this game.
Rym: Yeah, my my pro move is to learn a degenerate baby strategy for a first time game and never play it again.
Scott: Well, you can say this if you were you the Golden Knights you would stop playing hockey.
Rym: Yeah, just retire the team like we're done hundred percent Stanley Cups.
Scott: close the arena we built.
Rym: So it'll also.
Rym: it'll anger the most people.
Scott: no doesn't anger me.
Scott: yeah I just think I don't know why people are upset.
Rym: people like Don Cherry will probably be furious.
Rym: Yeah, I think he'd be madder.
Rym: I think he'd be really mad about this.
Scott: who cares?
Scott: so I've been watching They win.
Scott: or like the Jets win, what's the difference, you know, the national predators aren't a very old team.
Scott: What if they win is not what they're allowed, you know, yes But is this so the reason I bring this up?
Rym: cuz I think I kind of when I panels.
Rym: they talked about this.
Rym: I and I've been talking about this a lot lately.
Rym: I think the Vegas Golden Knights are doing so well Specifically because of the structure of the expansion draft.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: This is not a thing you think this is the thing that is.
Rym: Yeah, no, but game did like game design is Tuesday GeekNights.
Scott: So the deal is if you play the expansion draft was structured in such a way and the owner and the GM of the Golden Knights milk it.
Scott: they made deals before the draft even happened to sort everything out.
Scott: Yeah, so that they basically it wasn't an expansion draft because usually when there's an expansion in sports You have multiple teams coming in.
Scott: here is just one team being added.
Scott: Yeah, and they basically wasn't a draft.
Scott: It was a looting.
Scott: they looted all the other team.
Rym: every team could protect like a small number of people.
Rym: So this team this is a hockey team that could not get any superstars But could otherwise get pretty much anyone they wanted and design their team.
Rym: It's like the difference between.
Rym: here's the analogy in dungeons and dragons third and fourth edition.
Rym: If you play a character from level 1 to level 10 You're gonna make a lot of compromises along the way because the sunk cost and situations and everything.
Scott: and you build you this thing Again, you can explain it much simpler than that.
Scott: It's like you're playing El Grande and you know And you can't get first place anywhere.
Scott: You just automatically get second place everywhere You win.
Scott: Yeah at the most points.
Rym: Yep The end.
Rym: but if you make a D&D character level 10 from the beginning you craft that perfect specialty option from the beginning and ignore all the history.
Rym: So I don't see what happens in the hockey's.
Rym: but there is much more important news.
Scott: at least for me This is such isn't the biggest news.
Rym: It is for me because the steam controller is garbage.
Rym: I said it.
Scott: so the steam controller is kind of I mean it has good parts in bed.
Rym: Boy has two good parts the left paddle button the right paddle button.
Scott: But yeah, the steam controller is not the controller of choice.
Scott: I think for pretty much anyone There's a reason why.
Scott: there's a reason why they're in the discount bin.
Rym: There's a reason why my steam controller ran out of battery because there wasn't even a battery in it anymore.
Scott: Xbox controller At least the Xbox 360 controller is still great.
Scott: I haven't used an X bone controller.
Scott: I'm sure it's just fine except the d-pad on it is meh, but otherwise just fine if you don't need the d-pad.
Scott: D-pad is serviceable, but not great.
Scott: Yeah, the PlayStation controller a lot of people love those fart noise.
Scott: The only reason I do not like them is because the d-pad on them while functional has separation.
Scott: I mean, I know that it's still underneath a solid d-pad But it has this plastic cross so that you can't really touch all of that d-pad.
Scott: It's it's effectively like these four separate buttons sort of and it offends my sensibilities Even though it works better than the Xbox one.
Scott: I add is unusable for me.
Rym: Well, that's it.
Scott: It offends our old grog Nardi sensibilities, but the rest of the controller is just fine.
Rym: I have a much more fundamental beef with the PlayStation controller.
Rym: I never really had PlayStations and during the Soul Calibur era Soul Calibur 2 I use the game of cube controller.
Rym: I don't want to use a PlayStation controller.
Scott: controller is basically perfect.
Scott: Yeah, except for the fact that it's kind of weird and doesn't really match well with games that use a normal shape Except for Soul Calibur 2 where it matched better than any other controller because the whole horizontal vertical attack thing Right.
Scott: Anyway, so now you've got the switch pro controller.
Scott: The switch pro controller is basically perfect except it does not have analog buttons on the top.
Scott: and oh, you know The the throttling ones.
Scott: it only has four regular buttons on the.
Rym: but to be fair.
Rym: I haven't played a game.
Scott: Two regular buttons on the top.
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: The point is it doesn't have the throttles like, you know The the analog levers for anything.
Scott: needs that any racing game.
Rym: name a name a game that needs that that you play.
Scott: I place f-zero will come.
Rym: Yeah, well, we'll see what happens if f-zero comes on the switch.
Scott: Mario Kart doesn't have it but it could.
Rym: yeah It could.
Rym: now cuz Mario Kart is a whole different ballgame.
Scott: I'm just saying Mario Kart.
Rym: there There are exactly two settings.
Rym: Your gas is going all the time or you have lost.
Scott: I'm just saying Racing games where you want to have that analog throttle.
Rym: I'm just saying name a racing game you have played I don't know in the last decade f-zero Where did what did you last play f-zero?
Scott: definitely since 2008.
Rym: yeah since 2008.
Scott: Then I played f-zero GX
Rym: Anyway, but this is a big deal for me partly because
Scott: oh, but yeah The news is that steam is now officially supporting the switch pro controller Which means you can now use it with your HDPC and you can get rid of your Xbox controllers that you had just because.
Scott: yeah Yeah, but the thing is the switch pro controller is more expensive.
Scott: I'm not like throwing out my Xbox controllers.
Rym: The other thing you know, it's gonna happen.
Scott: It's annoying to switch.
Scott: It's it's a switch.
Scott: I know I just swap the pro controller between your switch and your PC.
Scott: Yeah, so and buying more of them would be expensive.
Scott: So I'm not gonna probably do this unless like I really need to get
Rym: I am going to buy one more pro controller to plug into my main PC not my HDPC because I play a lot of games here and I don't want to have to keep repairing the Xbox controllers in the other room in here on this PC.
Rym: and I don't want to use the fucking steam controller because I have a very low opinion of it.
Scott: You know what game needs those analog levers that I have played definitely within the last decade.
Scott: Yeah Rocket League Oh, yep, actually the steam controller is the only thing.
Rym: I mean, how does Rocket League work on the switch?
Scott: Not as good.
Scott: Oh Okay, I haven't played Rocket League on the switch.
Scott: I used to actually use the steam controller when I played Rocket League and actually I did too because that was It was like actually good for that the pedal buttons.
Rym: I used for my juking around.
Rym: It was yeah It was.
Scott: it was actually, you know better than slightly better than the Xbox controller in some ways for that one game.
Rym: Yep Man, just steam.
Scott: Why can't someone just make a switch pro controller with some analog levers on it And then it can throw away every other controller and buy five of those?
Rym: Yep, that would be worth the investment and then never buy another controller again, frankly I should just get USB converters or use an old gaming cube controllers.
Scott: I mean the switch pro controller is USB C.
Rym: Oh, yeah but the fact that it's getting official support is a big deal because Actually also I have a USB converter that can take four game controllers at once.
Rym: there was a time in my life when I was Very willing to hack and fiddle with things, but I don't got time for that shit.
Rym: I am too old to like install a special driver to make a weird thing work on my control on my computer.
Rym: Nope so in some other news, I Played two games at pat does then kai khan.
Scott: so it's not news It's a gig.
Rym: It's two gig bites really big bites.
Rym: I'm gonna talk about these two games because they're there is a thread.
Rym: They are both designed by coal.
Rym: Well, where are they?
Scott: Well, you can't even pronounce the person's name.
Rym: Oh, but these are two games That I don't know if you will like but you seem to want to play And They're similar in some regard John made by the same person and an infamous traffic.
Scott: Well, I've heard of the John company.
Rym: So an infamous traffic is the same person and similar concept.
Rym: So the idea of an infamous traffic or both these games are that there is a historical So geo-economic or power structure of some kind like the opium in infamous traffic is about the opium trade.
Scott: Oh great.
Rym: And yeah, these are these games are interesting.
Scott: So it's based on the car the present day.
Rym: Uh, yeah, especially because like I might argue that the area around Lancaster is the Ground zero of the current opioid epidemic.
Scott: It sounds right.
Rym: I will say that jokes about Pennsylvania and Lancaster.
Rym: in the course of playing this game in Lancaster where shall we say abundance?
Rym: Mm-hmm as were people who appeared to be.
Rym: There appeared to be.
Rym: there's a mechanic in this game called opportunity Which basically means are there people who want opium in this area?
Rym: Yes, and I think that there were a lot of opportunities in the area where this convention is.
Rym: But John company and I realized got to know this is about the British East India company Mm-hmm, and if you don't know most people I realized have a middle school social studies knowledge of what the East India Company did.
Rym: Don't really know Both of these.
Scott: I mean, I know what it did.
Scott: I just didn't know the one fact that you just told me which is that the name of it was not I do that East India.
Rym: What did it do?
Scott: Completely controlled all trade between Britain and all these colonies and all these other places and such and such.
Rym: It's actually way more complicated than that.
Rym: it was basically its own Sovereign government mega Corp.
Rym: Yep, and it had its own armies multiple of them So boats that invaded and conquered India on its own not without necessarily having permission to do so.
Rym: but anyway, these games are basically very nuanced and shockingly accurate simulations of How these two things functioned From the perspective of the people who were driving them.
Rym: So you basically in both cases play a shitty white dude in Britain?
Rym: Who has and your victory points what you actually do to win.
Rym: the games are?
Rym: analogous to the actual motivations of those people which came down to Bullshit around social standing and getting your relatives into comfortable positions.
Rym: But as a result So in John company You're basically you're doing things like get someone in your family to be the executive in this part of the East India company Who's responsible for something and all the players get relatives in all these different places And if you have a relative who's like in charge of procurement or in charge of the second presidency army you
Scott: can do
Rym: whatever the fuck you want that you're in charge of that and You all have to work together to make sure the company doesn't just go bankrupt.
Rym: Well simultaneously trying to achieve your goals and basically these games are Some of the most.
Rym: like you I were a teacher in a high school.
Rym: I would make kids play these games to learn about these concepts rather than read a history book.
Rym: That is how high an opinion I have on the history and function of these games.
Rym: However, I do not know if They're necessarily enjoyable.
Rym: Nor do I know if you will like them, but I like them and I would know I don't want to step that back.
Rym: I appreciate them and I want to play them again.
Rym: I am not sure if I like them But I appreciate them and kind of like with quartermaster general.
Rym: I just want to play them again, and I just always want to play them again.
Scott: It's weird How I like quartermaster general, but it doesn't matter because you're a bullshit.
Rym: you are banned from quartermaster.
Scott: I don't know why you guys are against just slightly.
Rym: You're banned from quartermaster general.
Rym: You think we're joking.
Rym: you're banned from this game for life.
Scott: What's your problem?
Rym: because none of us want that.
Scott: why don't you want that?
Rym: because the game as it is is exactly what we want.
Scott: Then why do you want garbage?
Scott: It's it's so close to perfection yet so far.
Rym: This is why I don't know what your opinion will be of John company.
Rym: I don't know if you're gonna feel if you're gonna do the quartermaster general thing or if you're gonna be into it.
Rym: I all I know is that we got to play this game so we can do a show on it And I'm sure we will accomplish this at a coming packs.
Rym: and in case anyone didn't know Scott is legit banned from the game of quartermaster And in perpetuity and you you laugh, but you are bad.
Scott: There's no way that game would just be so good.
Scott: I don't know why you guys are so obstinate about making it already is so good.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: It's like saying you know what we really need to do to fix battle tech.
Rym: No small lasers and no jump jets because they're bullshit and no look-up tables.
Scott: No, it would be bullshit if you had dice that were like all ones with like one six on one of the dice.
Rym: But that's how it feels when you play real battle tech.
Rym: Anyway, no, it's not.
Rym: It's always just miss bad.
Rym: I guess miss glancing.
Rym: blow to center torso.
Scott: battle is 2d 6.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: 2d 6 2d 6 2d 6.
Scott: It's not like, you know a D that always rolls a 1 and then a D with 5 ones and a 6 on it.
Rym: So we got one less little news that isn't really gaming related, but you got to see this shit.
Scott: Why I didn't?
Scott: I was just sending this to you cuz you need to see it.
Rym: Oh, you don't want to talk about it today.
Scott: Is it for Monday?
Rym: All right, we'll save for Monday.
Scott: Monday What the fuck you gonna do?
Rym: Never mind, you don't get to learn about this today.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: So I am a fan of Rube Goldberg machines.
Rym: when I was a kid in middle school in high school I competed in the Zulberg
Scott: machines have probably been things of the day more often than any other category of yep
Rym: But kind of like it's one of those rules where like a steamed hams edit where you can't just Use these things as things of the day Unless there's some unique thing about this
Scott: one.
Scott: I mean, I'm sure there's like a Rube Goldberg community.
Scott: We could make a whole podcast about Rube Goldberg machines only there probably is a tire podcast.
Scott: but
Rym: this Rube Goldberg machine is particularly fascinating because it breaks some of the tropes of Rube Goldberg machines and it also Surprised me at several junctures in terms of how it functioned and it was subtle Kinda like our friend Luke the juggler who makes points about how a juggling routine Can be made funny through intrinsic properties of juggling and good stagecraft.
Rym: There are some extremely well-crafted Visual jokes in this Rube Goldberg machine and I do not even want to spoil them.
Rym: You just need to watch it.
Rym: And all I want to say is keep an eye on that laptop.
Rym: Okay, this Rube Goldberg machine is fantastic.
Rym: It's probably it is on the level of that slow motion Rube Goldberg machine that okay go did in terms of how much I enjoyed.
Scott: Why like the Rube Goldberg the Japanese kids want to tell the story the story?
Rym: Oh, what was that called a balls adventure something something like that.
Rym: I forget what that was.
Rym: Anyway, what do you got?
Scott: Oh, so it's just a tweet, but the tweet had a funny video in it.
Scott: It looks like it's Japanese.
Scott: Of course Basically two dudes in pink bodysuit things.
Scott: They're on some bicycle And this bicycle is interesting and that is a tandem bicycle.
Scott: Yet one of the seats the rear seat is facing Backwards so one person's facing forward and one person's facing backwards and they're riding on this sort of side of the road with a jersey Barrier next to them and on the other side of the jersey barrier is a legit pro bike race happening And the peloton is right there and they're biking ahead of the peloton And I guess one person is watching the race because they're facing back.
Rym: It looks like bikers threw something at them at one point I don't know and the other like this very clueless moment where something gets thrown at them Like people don't seem happy about them being there I don't know.
Scott: But the other the other person is just looking forward and biking and smiling.
Scott: Yeah if you go to the next tweet and reply you can actually see the bicycle up close and how the gearing works to Make this thing possible.
Rym: It's cleverly done.
Scott: It's you know, it's a hack together together mess, but it works.
Rym: So It's it's just.
Rym: they'll just watch it and appreciate it for what it is.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: I like how the the text in the Pretty much as a bunch of W's and then some Japanese moon language In the meta moment.
Rym: the book club book for geek.
Rym: the GeekNights book club If you didn't know we have a book club is Emily Wilson's translation of the Odyssey.
Rym: I assume Scott has read zero More pages of this good assumption.
Rym: All right, we will.
Scott: I'm busy.
Scott: I'm getting new furniture.
Scott: on Saturday I had to take apart all the furniture in my apartment and throw it out.
Rym: I got a bunch of flights coming up cuz I'm going to be not Scott and not geek not just me with Emily at TCAF this weekend in Toronto.
Rym: So one if you're in Toronto and you're gonna be a TCAF.
Scott: What's TCAF?
Rym: It's basically a comic convention similar to like mocha or SPX or Emerald City comic-con.
Rym: A lot of our friends will be there.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: Emerald City comic-con is like a real comic-con.
Rym: It's not an indie show like yeah, but there's a big indie presence there and a lot of the same people go.
Rym: I mean New York comic-con has an indie presence in the artist alley too.
Rym: I specifically left New York comic-con off that.
Scott: Emerald City is you know, no different than like Heroes.
Rym: Emerald City has a way bigger indie presence than you realize.
Scott: So does every other comic-con.
Rym: Yeah, not New York comic-con.
Scott: Even San Diego does.
Scott: you just don't see it in the news about San Diego Because the news about San Diego doesn't cover it.
Scott: Yeah, they have a giant and massive artist alley that has all the indie peoples in it.
Rym: Yeah, not all because a lot of the people I know who go to these things that like a lot There's a lot of indie people.
Scott: Yeah, not all of them go to all the guys.
Rym: But there is a huge huge overlap between ECCC and SPX and TCAF and Though like that Venn diagram is tighter than a lot of the other clusters of conventions.
Rym: but anyway, I'll be there hanging out and otherwise, they'll just be digging around in Toronto for the weekend and This previous weekend I was at Zenkai Con.
Rym: we did three panels.
Rym: So if you were here listening to this or watching the stream because you saw me at Zenkai Con Well, guess what?
Rym: I posted notes and links and stuff If you go to our website A lot of people seem to find the YouTube channel Can't quite make the leap from that channel to the fact that we actually have a website.
Scott: people don't use websites.
Scott: It's 2018 yep, like they just go to.
Scott: you know one place like Twitter only or YouTube only.
Rym: it's extra sad But I started putting links to our YouTube on our flyers instead of our website and it increased the response rate heavily.
Rym: so whatever we have a website and if you go to that website, you can see actually a video of one of the panels I did from a different con way more professional because it's the video for packs and Zenkai Con was super fun and the funniest thing that happened was on the way home.
Rym: there were all these teams who were on the train who went to Zenkai Con from New York City and they were loud and I Overheard their conversation and the conversation was basically these kids go to cons like you and I used to go to cons.
Rym: They go to like every anime con.
Rym: Hmm, and they're pretty they get money from.
Scott: if they're teens.
Rym: Well, they're like teens and a couple of them are like freshmen in college and they go.
Scott: where do they get money from?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: They do.
Rym: the East Coast Con circuit cram 12 people in a hotel room like we used to.
Rym: but the funniest things were one.
Rym: they Someone brought up Otakon and they all started laughing.
Rym: They're like, yeah who even fucking goes to Otakon anymore?
Scott: Otakon moved and changed in.
Scott: such.
Rym: one of them went this year and was like the previous Otakon and they were like Yeah the panels are like way worse than Zenkai Con's panels.
Rym: all the good people don't go anymore and And the convention center is a hole.
Rym: and one of the other ones is like yeah anime boss is like the only anime con worth going to anymore.
Rym: and then they basically were like if you want to see panels Literally go to any con because no con has higher quality panels, but they don't go to gaming cons They only go to anime cons.
Rym: So in the estimation of this large group of teens to summarize Zenkai Con has the exact same level of quality of panels as every major anime con on the Eastern Seaboard.
Rym: I don't know if that is speaking highly of Zenkai Con or speaking lowly of the Eastern Seaboard But that is the information that I have from a large group of teens who are very loud over the course of two and a half hours.
Rym: So I Have always for a very long time because I really enjoyed playing battle tech which we reviewed on GeekNights a long time ago.
Rym: Apparently, I don't remember doing this.
Rym: I really like tabletop battle tech.
Rym: I really like rolling 2d6 over and over again and like this sort of squad based combat in these really fiddly details.
Scott: Well cuz battle tech the pen and paper game.
Scott: We actually did an episode on it super super super long ago Back in the way early days of GeekNights where we lived in Beacon.
Scott: Yeah but pen and paper battle tech is a game where you can get all the joy of a miniatures game where you know on your Turn you move and shoot and you roll dice to determine how much you hit and such.
Rym: but miniatures game.
Rym: in the like it
Scott: is actually Simpler and more comprehensible and you dealing with less units and also giant robots Yeah, and you also get the fun of like custom, you know, instead of customizing like this whole army like Warhammer You you know in each individual unit you're actually just customizing like a couple giant robots and it's pretty easy to do, you know, and It's fun to fill in little bubbles when you get hit right like everything about it is like this sort of.
Scott: It's sort of like this elegant system where you have a complex game That is easier to play than other games that are equally complex.
Scott: Yep Because it's just designed so nicely and that is why battle tech has been around Almost as long as I have lived.
Scott: I think the game was invented in like 1984 or something like that but also it's been around since then and it's still around and it's still big.
Rym: these games edge into wargame territory and Simulatory territory and that they're.
Rym: they're more like simulations and simulations of this fictional galaxy universe whatever you want to call it, but in terms of they're kind of random and not that fair and more like Real-world tactical decision-making.
Rym: like it's not.
Scott: it's not Gundam where these are super-powered robots of like.
Scott: oh we got awesomeness.
Rym: This is more like.
Scott: you know battle tech is slow and dumpy robots.
Rym: They go like that are huge and go kitchen like Situations like oh they busted through my left armor and blew up the ammo for my weapon.
Rym: Now my pilots hurt and Really unluckily.
Rym: I'm in a bad situation.
Scott: That's really the fun of battle tech is the stimulatory things where it's like, alright Well, I got knocked over and now falling down the hill and I took damage in this specific part and that part had ammo in It and there's a chance the ammo explodes.
Scott: it did.
Scott: All right that ammo exploded.
Scott: How much damage does it do this much?
Scott: what happens now?
Scott: Well, it damaged your gyro.
Scott: It's gonna be hard to stand up.
Scott: everything just sort of makes sense in a common sense way without having to have this sort of like Esoteric military knowledge.
Scott: you would have to like, you know have those grog guard war games, which also make sense.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Scott: This just makes sense because you understand a giant robot.
Rym: So I've always enjoyed it, but I don't have time to play that kind of game anymore.
Rym: or space and I have space I don't have time.
Rym: and before you say like mech war whatever those all the not official or mega mech mega mech Those things are intolerable, right?
Scott: There are software versions of the tabletop game Back when I could tolerate pretty intolerable software that are free open source ish and their user interfaces are so bad They're not even worth attempt.
Rym: Even when I had infinite time.
Rym: They were not worth pursuing.
Rym: Nope So battle tech got kick-started Right.
Scott: So actually I first discovered this at a PAX.
Scott: I was walking around and there was a booth and the booth was like battle tech and I'm like Well, this is not the catalyst booth.
Scott: Which catalyst if you don't know is the company that currently licenses and publishes.
Scott: I don't know if they own but they currently publish the pen and paper Miniatures books and stuff for battle tech tabletop.
Scott: Yep, and it was not the catalyst booth But it was a battle tech booth.
Scott: and I said what is this?
Scott: and they said we are making a battle tech video game.
Scott: That is the turn-based You know pen and paper miniature battle tech only a video game.
Scott: and I said shut up and take my monies.
Scott: and then I went With them at another PAX and also played the beta.
Scott: cuz I kick-started at a level where let me play the beta.
Scott: And it was.
Scott: I was so surprised.
Scott: It was legit.
Scott: Like they were actually developing this game.
Scott: It wasn't some scam.
Scott: They were actually making this thing real.
Scott: They were making significant progress very rapidly.
Scott: More importantly they made it right because playing the beta what you saw was Next walk and they torso twerking shooting and torso twist is key anyway, so Now just recently like a week or two ago ish I don't know the big game has been fully released.
Scott: You can now buy whether you kick-started or not.
Scott: I already.
Scott: I just got it because I already kick-started it.
Scott: Yep, you can just go on steam and buy this fucking game.
Scott: It is out and a lot of people are playing it.
Scott: and Great, let's talk about it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So first things.
Rym: first there are two.
Rym: I want to get these out of the way because they're kind of topical like news wise.
Rym: There are two quote-unquote controversies about the game already.
Scott: a lot of it's weird.
Scott: It's like it's there's a lot of controversies, but they're all.
Scott: there's minor.
Scott: It's like there's a lot of minor controversies and no major ones There are.
Rym: there are two that I think are relevant and newsworthy.
Rym: ish one of them The which the people are complaining about.
Rym: it are wrong in my opinion and just don't understand humans or games.
Rym: But their argument is that the game shows some to hit percentages.
Rym: uh-huh, and someone proved that the actual to hit percentages are Narrower than that like the real.
Rym: the numbers they show are slightly fabricated and they actually groom the random number generator to Effectively avoid streaks a little bit.
Scott: I wouldn't just be 2d6.
Rym: It's not just 2d6.
Scott: Why is it not just 2d6?
Rym: So you didn't see this controversy.
Scott: I did see someone saying that the percentages shown were inaccurate.
Rym: They're slightly.
Scott: I did not.
Scott: I did not read the actual numbers in math.
Rym: Yeah The deal here's the real deal from.
Rym: in my semi-professional opinion on this particular issue This happens a lot in games because it turns out if you tell a human they have an n-percent chance to hit something.
Rym: Humans are so bad at math and so bad at statistics and so bad at patterns in this type of environment That if you say an 80% chance to hit and you actually hit 80% of the time They will perceive the 20% of the time they miss as bullshit.
Rym: They will perceive that the numbers are way off.
Rym: I mean it was a perfectly accurate.
Scott: It is bullshit, but that's battle.
Rym: Yeah, but it's not the right kind of bullshit.
Rym: all I'm saying is that when game companies fudge those kinds of numbers they're doing it because Your brain is dumb and they were tricking your brain.
Rym: and as long as you don't try to peel back that onion You'll enjoy games a lot more.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: You're saying is ignorance is bliss?
Rym: in this particular case Yes, and also it's such a my one.
Rym: This is not an e-sport, but I'm playing to win.
Rym: Yeah, so play to win.
Scott: How is it not an e-sport?
Rym: This is not yet a major e-sport where it matters.
Rym: And if it came to pass, I'm gonna be Battletech world champion.
Rym: Watch out Based on our history together.
Rym: There is no chance you will ever be the Battletech champion.
Rym: Why not?
Rym: 18 small lasers and no rear armor.
Scott: That's just what I like.
Scott: if I have to win and the championship is on the line It's just a LRM boat.
Scott: Yeah I got a LRM boat and an SRM boat.
Rym: I was always a fan of mex 2 boat.
Rym: I've always been a fan of mex with no rear armor Like zero rear armor.
Scott: Good luck against my jump jet and then you're dead.
Rym: I'm already backed into a cliff.
Rym: You can't touch me.
Scott: I can just go up on top of the mouth.
Rym: Yeah anyway, anyway, but the other controversy and I controversy I'm making the hardest quotes ever is that shitheads and gum regators are really mad at this game because It has female male and gender neutral pronouns.
Rym: They are the the internet shitstorm around that is Actually pretty big and it's I didn't see any of it.
Rym: It's all shitty people.
Scott: Anyway, well, you don't have to play battle tech.
Scott: They're trying to mass boycott the game, which is great Because that means shitty people be playing battle tech.
Scott: Yeah, only if someone plays battle take that means they good.
Rym: But if you see anyone complaining about that at all.
Scott: And like if you see there is one thing about that that does bother me If you go and it's the character creation screen right up is if you choose he as your pronoun Yeah You get all these photos to choose from that are Stereotypically looking like dudes.
Rym: if you click enough you also get female looking ones like it didn't know.
Scott: if you choose she you get different Ones.
Scott: she's they.
Scott: you get all of them.
Scott: So it's like why can't I choose the she looking one?
Scott: Basically if you choose he or she you get half as many.
Scott: you get half of the choices for your image.
Scott: And if you choose day, you can choose any image you want.
Scott: They should just allowed all images for all products.
Rym: But if you see anyone complaining about these options like for real those people are basically just gummer gators and they're mad.
Scott: I thought.
Scott: I thought the thing you were gonna bring up was that the game if you play single-player Which is what you're playing probably.
Scott: Yeah, is that there's a lot of slowness and time losing in this game.
Scott: There are slow animations There are slow things.
Scott: You got to watch.
Scott: you got to watch FMV's you got.
Scott: it's all this stuff in the game is very Time-consuming and waiting happens for no reason and the game could be sped up a lot.
Scott: And the example I always bring up when people say oh no you want it You can't speed it up is even Pokemon.
Scott: lets you speed it up.
Scott: The children's game.
Scott: lets you turn off animations and do fast text.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So there is no reason that any adult game including you are stone Shouldn't allow you to turn off animations and speed everything up.
Scott: to just let you play without any visual cruft This camera zooming it.
Scott: you can turn off some of it in the options menu And you can do other things by editing some files and stuff.
Scott: But it's like just let me play the battle tech without any of this garbage like zooming in and watching missiles fire.
Scott: No, I want to click fire and just see a number of how much damage was done.
Rym: So counterpoint I Actually very much enjoy the slow ramp.
Rym: I actually in this game partly because battle tech.
Rym: I actually really enjoy These slow animation.
Scott: you enjoyed it one time and then I want to turn it off But I keep enjoying it because it has this interesting bit of tension.
Rym: It simulates for me.
Scott: I don't got time for that.
Scott: I want to hurry.
Rym: I know I agree with you.
Rym: The option should be there but I part of the appeal I had of original classic pen and paper battle tag was Pete shoots a thousand SRMs at me because that's what Pete liked to do.
Rym: I then have to sit here and listen as He rolls 2d6 while Alex or you are looking at a book and say right center torso.
Scott: Oh, that would be fine if it like fired each weapon individually, but I get that experience.
Scott: animation No, it just makes a slow animation.
Rym: like I see the missiles come in and they actually like they'll veer off before they hit and you get that like oh They're gonna miss and a few of them hit.
Rym: You see the PPC fight the PVC scary than me the most because he had no indications.
Scott: Inner sphere garbage.
Scott: the inner PPC is like the best weapon you can get.
Rym: It is inner sphere garbage, but give them time.
Rym: It's like when sip five.
Scott: I don't know why people hate clan stuff.
Scott: so much stuff is bullshit.
Rym: Why it's too.
Rym: It's op and not fun.
Scott: What if everyone just as clan stuff was difference?
Rym: That's that's the same as playing Dungeons & Dragons versus PvP with two level 20 characters.
Rym: wrong with that It ain't fun.
Scott: What's?
Scott: how was that?
Scott: any less fun than fighting to one level one characters?
Rym: It's uh, it's a lot different and a lot less fun.
Scott: Why what's there ever done?
Scott: it was there.
Scott: It's in heavyweight boxing and featherweight boxing.
Rym: They're boxing way more fun to watch.
Scott: Well, who says me?
Scott: All right Well, I don't think this.
Scott: I mean they're both equally.
Scott: they're different, but I think they're.
Rym: you got a reason why in our group No one ever.
Rym: you were the only one who wanted clan ever.
Rym: Why not?
Rym: None of us wanted clan.
Scott: I like heavyweight boxing just it's obviously different but it's like.
Scott: I like it just as much as Most of the clan stuff was.
Scott: the only thing that's bullshit is intersphere verse clan.
Scott: That's obviously stupid.
Rym: Yeah, clan verse clan is a time and place what I know.
Scott: I'm not asking for intersphere verse clan.
Scott: That's dumb.
Scott: I just want to see clan verse clan.
Scott: Let me get my arrow for my ultra aces and whatnot for Gauss rifles.
Scott: my you know, triple strength My embers and you know triple strength wasn't clan that we are PvP.
Rym: I just advanced intersphere.
Scott: I don't know whatever targeting computer is All the good stuff there.
Rym: I saw some screenshots of like gyros and stuff in this game Mmm, I think you can get that in the campaign.
Rym: Anyway, I have not played the game enough yet Like I like.
Scott: yeah, I have not played it enough.
Rym: I played it a lot, but I haven't played it enough Right.
Scott: So here's the thing is like.
Scott: the game like on the one hand is so good and that yes It is tabletop battle tech.
Scott: you take your turns you move your mechs you shoot, you know If you it's.
Scott: the fundamental concepts are all the same.
Scott: we take damage to areas Right areas.
Scott: your arm falls off you can walk up to someone and melee them You can step on a vehicle and it gets destroyed.
Scott: the fact that DFA is there like DFA real easy Like, you know all the weapons, you know work the same.
Scott: you can have someone's spot for your LRM fire You can you know you get a cover if you're in the woods.
Rym: In fact, my only complaint about the game I only like mechanical.
Rym: complaint about this game is that they implemented this hardpoint system and met customization.
Scott: Oh that I don't like.
Scott: that is actually.
Scott: there are many things that they've changed from the actual tabletop rules but a lot of the things they've changed are functionally equivalent or similar enough for like the exact roles and math for like falling over aren't exactly the same but it's effectively the same kind of thing where it's like yeah, if you moved a lot and then you get bumped a lot then your odds Of falling over increase and then you fall over,
Rym: you know, you've moved a lot.
Rym: So you're harder to hit.
Rym: It's a much it's a very in the woods.
Scott: It's harder to hit you.
Rym: It's harder to hit and the game is a really good job of really streamlining the heuristics and indicators and artifacts around that.
Rym: So like the further your guy moves and depending on the things that happen It'll show these little chevrons that show how much evasion you accumulated.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: it's a really intuitive system, right?
Scott: There's not just piloting skill and gunning skill which would used to be just like two numbers.
Scott: Yeah now like four different stats that like grit and something else and like you can Level up your characters and to like get different.
Rym: you never played battle tech as a campaign though.
Scott: That's well.
Scott: No, that's messy mech warrior.
Scott: Yeah the RPG has some of that stuff but battle tech as a campaign is Basically just playing the battle tech tabletop game that we played But linking the missions together and having money.
Scott: now The other thing that is missing and having a store and having a story is.
Rym: there's a deeper level of fiddly mech Customization that is not present and that is the things like what engine did you put in the Mac, right?
Scott: So they don't allow.
Scott: they only allow customizing the mech to the way that mech warrior 2 allowed customizing the mech But actually even more restrictive.
Scott: because what they've done is like Rym was saying they these hard points.
Scott: So usually in mech warrior 2 or in battle tech on pen and paper You could just you have these slots on the Mac.
Scott: You have a lot of them and you can put whatever you want in there that you can fit Without running out of slots or running out of weight.
Scott: in this one the mechs have these hard points.
Scott: So it's like okay.
Scott: on this mech The left torso can hold one missile weapon and the right torso can hold two Ballistic weapons and the arms can hold two lasers.
Scott: each or each Mac has like a different loadout.
Rym: I wouldn't even be that butter about it If it.
Rym: if it was if they were like there were a mix that a lot of hard points It was just the next have so few hard points.
Scott: You basically cannot customize much at all.
Scott: You just need to get a different Mac.
Scott: Yep Also, they're the way the game is structured which is a truth of battle tech.
Scott: But is they tried this?
Scott: I think the hard points were an attempt to solve this problem But didn't solve it.
Scott: is that it's just better to field heavier max?
Scott: Yeah You're better off just putting the four heaviest mechs you can out in the field loaded with the most stuff Yep, and the LRMs are just better.
Rym: like 180 ton Mac can kick the shit out of 250 or 60 ton max usually.
Scott: Yeah, I mean in battle tech the pen and paper your game without the hard points.
Scott: It's like yeah, it's true Every hundred ton Mac may as well be the same as every other hundred ton Mac But I could make a 30 ton Mac.
Rym: That was really fucking dangerous in the right circumstances.
Scott: Sure, you know you look at your mission situation you make the right kind of deal, but that's it.
Rym: This is this is where in the campaign Different tonnages have interesting uses and I actually feel like a light Mac that I set up to be a scout And I've done things.
Rym: but in the in multiplayer, which is my main interest in this battle tech game There aren't.
Rym: there isn't yet like a scenario builder, so it just comes down to what's the tonnage?
Rym: We're gonna play with and we both field lances of appropriate tonnage, and it's and they're like.
Rym: I can't make a scenario.
Rym: There's no like customizer there yet, which in multiplayer can lead to a problem where?
Rym: And when Scott and I played for the first time the same thing that used to happen in our old battle tech days happen.
Rym: We both set up our max in an optimal ambush position And then dickered around for like 20 minutes and neither one of us would commit our forces anywhere.
Rym: Till eventually we were just like fuck it.
Rym: Let's just play the game.
Rym: I Want to be able to build scenarios.
Rym: I want to be able to build like or at least have scenarios that are more interesting for multiplayer.
Scott: So the thing is this game for all its you know.
Scott: hey, I can now play a video game But it's battle tech.
Scott: the turn-based game hooray has lots and lots of these tiny Issues that you can see complained about on the subreddit for this game and many other place.
Rym: But what I would analogize this to actually is when Civ 5 first came out It was real fun for like a month, and then it was tapped out and had a similar Breadth of problems.
Scott: yeah, so this has tons and tons of tiny issues.
Scott: for example some today the one I saw most recently.
Scott: There was a mech standing on top of a building.
Scott: somebody decided Hey Let me destroy this building and they destroyed it.
Scott: the mech was then floating in air And then the mech was then standing on the ground.
Scott: perfectly fine.
Scott: in pen and paper battle tech you take falling damage Which is severe as fuck and holy shit, but in this video game?
Rym: We just like nothing pointed out in the campaign.
Rym: they moved a mech into a spot And then an event happened, and they were hosed.
Rym: they just couldn't continue.
Scott: Yeah, little bugs there was some like there's.
Scott: some missions were like.
Scott: you know vehicles Go too fast.
Scott: there's some like missions where you go in and there's just a million enemies that are super strong And it's like fuck you.
Scott: so you might as well.
Scott: Just run away.
Scott: You know there's like tons of like.
Scott: you know I could go on and on.
Scott: there's just you know the user interface problems.
Scott: We're like you're trying to click on a thing, but actually you've moved your mech by accident.
Rym: It's hard to get the angle of my view just right.
Scott: some you have the camera is not the greatest.
Scott: also the a lot of The maps.
Scott: everything is dark And it's hard to see what's going on.
Scott: the mechs don't look distinct enough because they're sort of blending into the background.
Scott: They're camo you know so it's like it's hard to even see.
Rym: But I just want to be clear.
Rym: the game's still real fun and as a 1.0 like a released game.
Rym: if This if they're able to invest in this game I mean the fact the game actually launched.
Scott: kick-starting games is like usually.
Scott: it's just like they run away with your fucking money.
Rym: if this game gets DLC Over time even in DLC expensive DLC even free clan DLC even just guy like I'm talking like the civilization levels of DLC I Would buy it all.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the thing.
Rym: you'll see that adds like the advanced tech so I can have my Gauss rifle.
Scott: Yeah, my main problem is like I played the single-player and like the campaign.
Scott: There's lots of stuff like you get a manage the mechs in the mech bay.
Rym: It's real fun because it evokes old xcom.
Rym: well.
Scott: It's from mech warrior mercenaries.
Rym: Yeah, you're managing your money, and I really enjoy that because shit sucks your things are always broken down Everyone's always hurt.
Rym: you're like.
Scott: But the thing is there's a lot of fiddly issues like I'm trying to allocate tons of armor on my mech And it's like forty nine point seven seven and it won't let me make it exactly fifty.
Scott: and then I go to start a mission.
Scott: It's like warning you're not using all the tonnage on your mech, and I'm like who's fucking fault is that?
Scott: forty nine point nine nine ton?
Rym: asshole granted right Making mechs repeatedly on pen and paper at similar issues.
Rym: I never had an issue of point oh one tons missing, but I had issues of little fiddly details like that And usually we just ignored them, so it didn't matter.
Scott: But yeah You know there's this Problems like you've got to repair a mech and it cost more on if you do it from one screen on the other screen and Oh, yeah, and you gotta wait.
Scott: You know for the mech to actually repairs That's it.
Rym: There's definitely some problems now in the the economy of how long on the one screen.
Scott: It's like how much of the salvage worked.
Scott: oh like three million space bucks.
Scott: And then you go to the screen to sell it.
Scott: It's like you can't sell it, and then it's like it's not actually worth jack shit.
Rym: It's like what the hell because you got to finish it.
Rym: It's not like stay.
Scott: why can't I sell that if a piece of a mech is worth that much and then when I do finish it The full mech is worth less than the it said the part was worth.
Scott: You know and they got this reputation system Confused
Rym: but also it's sparse in that head like it's fun, but You do end up just hitting play and letting like 40 days go by Because you're waiting for like all your mechs to repair and stuff like
Scott: yeah Why would I do the next mission before my mixer repair?
Rym: yep?
Rym: So the economy of action in the single-player campaign type.
Scott: you're starting everyone There's scarters starting scout dies, so I'm like my starting scout guy didn't die I'm doing died.
Scott: I go to the subreddit and everyone's like Decker.
Scott: He always dies.
Rym: I don't know how they could have him die.
Scott: I like blew through that mission, and then I immediately do well No, I mean he's your scouting guy for like the whole many yeah for the beginning of the game You just keep him around right and then the next mission.
Scott: I did.
Scott: He just got.
Scott: he was perfect.
Scott: perfect health.
Scott: He hadn't been hit yet.
Scott: a mech just walks over to him comes out of the fog and fires like a million.
Scott: He dies instantly, but that is battle tech.
Scott: right, but then I loaded the game so he didn't die.
Scott: But everyone else is like this guy keeps dying.
Rym: I'm playing hardcore in all consequences.
Rym: I never back out of a fight.
Scott: Well.
Scott: I mean why not load a save game?
Scott: Oh, also if you have too many save games the game starts to slow down.
Scott: You have to delete your save games.
Scott: Yeah, so Basically, I got you know I played the single-player until I was like.
Scott: some of the missions are so samey.
Scott: That's where I feel like I don't care about the plot enough to see the rest of it.
Scott: I could watch it on YouTube.
Scott: so now I'm pretty much just only waiting for like people who want to play multiplayer.
Scott: But I feel like that's where the sweet spot is gonna be kind of like Civ 5.
Rym: The sweet spot is multiplayer.
Rym: until there's a DLC that adds something to the game and that as long as they do continue to invest in this game and release Content and improve it then there will definitely be a cycle of play the game with people in multiplayer.
Rym: It starts to get tapped out some content comes in we jump back on the single-player train.
Scott: You know whenever we're in a battle tech mood We can actually play a battle tech now without having to bust.
Rym: so I would say cardboard.
Rym: if you are in the situation We're in where you have fond memories of old pen and paper battle tech But don't have time to play it buy this game The even if you only play the campaign and play it multiplayer a few times It'll scratch that if you're
Scott: expecting the exact same rules.
Scott: This is not that for exam.
Rym: you know like I never 100% knew the rules back then.
Scott: anyway I know I know the rules But how to present?
Scott: for example the biggest rule change is that in paid pen and paper battle tech right everyone moves Then everyone shoots, and you all shoot simultaneously.
Scott: So I get a headshot on Rym.
Scott: He still might get a headshot on me before he dies right whereas in this There's initiatives more like X come so the fast makes go first unless they delay And then the next Mexico and they move shoot move shoot Which is more what you're used to in a turn-based strategy video game.
Scott: right like advance wars.
Scott: move shoot move shoot right.
Scott: so In that sense you could just like destroy a mech before it even gets a chance to do anything if you get lucky right?
Scott: Yeah, which is not the same.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, you go with that on purpose.
Rym: You set up stress.
Scott: It's fine right there's nothing wrong with it.
Scott: I'm just saying if you're expecting it to be exactly the same it is not.
Scott: it is just the same Feel and mostly the same.
Rym: But I would also say if you're gonna get into it for the multiplayer Get in on it now because our crew the front row crew and geek guides forums We're gonna try to get a bunch of multiplayer going as long as the iron is hot.
Scott: The only thing I can say is that like there's all these PC games now.
Scott: It's still PC game season yet the game I still play the most display the fire especially since they got a new character.
Scott: And it's like I played.
Scott: I played the what was the other way into the breach like for a day I really liked into the brain liked it so much.
Scott: It's nothing wrong with it, but then I you know and I played battle tech for like a few days.
Rym: But slay the spire just scratch.
Scott: I just played slay the spire every day.
Rym: I still place play the spy every day at least for now.
Rym: I play this almost like this.
Rym: scratch is a really profound itch, and I'm playing it a lot.
Scott: I just don't play it every day.
Scott: They just play it you know.
Scott: But I feel like once I get doing multiplayer with our friends and it's like if I already played slay the spire that day and I'm bored and I got nothing to do.
Scott: Then I plan to open battle tech.
Rym: so this weekend.
Rym: I'll be in Toronto, but like within a week or two We're gonna get.
Scott: we're gonna schedule some multiplayer games on the discord if anyone wants to play multiplayer battle tech And I'll you know if I'm on steam just like message me or whatever.
Rym: yeah We're gonna make a forum thread about that specifically mm-hmm cuz uh yep.
Rym: So the only people I would say don't buy this game if you don't like turn-based turn-based fiddly Strategy game.
Scott: it's not the most fiddly, but it's but it's really.
Scott: it's slightly fiddly.
Scott: It's in this sweet spot between very.
Scott: it's so fiddly.
Scott: you can't even deal like Europa universalis not even close to that.
Scott: No, it's way even less fiddly even than civilization, but it is more fiddly than advancing.
Rym: I. This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this is what the GeekNights are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Heidi McNicholas shivering Ruby obelisk painting in the sky my steady calm That's my st.
Rym: Ady calm Jeremy minor link a G Kelly Snyder cold guy Amanda douchette Sean Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando, mr Strong distraction for two one creations.
Rym: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Rym: Semper Fi bitch Shervin horrell Rory James David White Rochelle, Montanona Superboy copy bar pickle kumquat sailor Vista Don She like chart option Joe Joe Joe star Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan parent drew open.
Rym: Lander Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Probably no show on Thursday cuz uh flying to Toronto, but now I leave you with.
Media: I Don't want to go to Toronto.
Media: I don't want to go.
Media: all of the blocks are square.
Media: None of the streets are twisted none of the streets are paved with bricks.
Media: There's too many elevators in Toronto not enough stairs in Toronto Nothing upstairs.
Media: all of the food in Toronto is made of edible oil products.
Media: They don't have bagels in Toronto.
Media: They have donuts donuts made of edible oil.
Media: I don't like donuts.
Media: They don't have bagels.
Media: I don't want to go to Toronto.
Media: people don't have faces in Toronto.
Media: They have cigarette ads.
Media: instead they listen to your phone calls.
Media: There's a tower in Toronto that controls people's minds.
Media: It's illegal to possess brightly colored balloons in Toronto.
Media: Illegal the one brightly colored balloons.
Media: all of the children in Toronto must wear suits even the girls Three-piece suits.
Media: the buildings in Toronto have no windows.
Media: I don't want to go.
Media: Everyone lives in subterranean caverns filled with donuts made of edible oil.
Media: nobody goes to the bathroom in Toronto.
Scott: They have a special operation.
Media: They have it removed Surgically.
Media: there's a tax on all wicker goods in Toronto.
Media: There's huge buildings with no windows on streets with no curves and inside you might little girls and suits running around with black Balloons and munching on edible oil products.
Media: the kids don't have names.
Media: They have numbers which are assigned to them at birth.
Media: They're called 387 point seven four hundred and twelve point nine and they all have cigarette ads instead of faces.
Media: I don't want to go to Toronto.
Scott: I don't want to go.
Media: I have plenty of wicker goods.
Media: I don't want to tax on my wicker goods.
Media: I like going to the bathroom.
Media: I don't want to go to the hospital.
Media: I don't want to go to Toronto.
Media: I don't want to go so I have to go to Toronto.
Scott: Do I do?
Rym: I have to go?
Rym: I don't want to go.