Rym: It's Monday February 5th 2018 I'm Rym, I'm hungry and this is GeekNights tonight M.2 and you.
Rym: we're talking about the modern state of storage for computers.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So the other day I was sitting in the living room and I got a halogen torsier the last Halogen bulb in my apartment.
Scott: You don't need that shit.
Scott: get LED people.
Rym: No, because LED bulbs still they are good Like.
Rym: I actually have an LED torsier in this room and it's really good.
Rym: But the torsier I got in the living room one I paid a lot of money for that lamp and two it's really.
Rym: it's like the perfect lamp.
Rym: No, because it doesn't have glass on top.
Rym: the way this one does.
Rym: okay, but I was sitting there and suddenly it just goes.
Rym: Light turns off didn't explode because there's no like giant tempered glass shield on top of it.
Rym: So I go over to it and the light bulb that has had from the beginning just died.
Rym: I look at it and I unlike kids younger than us who will probably not actually know how Analog like light bulbs work.
Rym: I Know how they work and I saw the filament was just broken.
Rym: Mm-hmm I never bought a new light bulb for that and let me tell you if you know if you do.
Rym: I did find one but it's it's shady.
Rym: if you need to buy a Like an Edison screw bulb for anything It's pretty easy to figure out because the only thing you need to know is that is an Edison screw of the normal size.
Rym: And then how many watts?
Scott: in other countries?
Rym: They have this similar same light bulb standard and it's pretty much how many watts does it take?
Rym: if you need any sort of like Modern LED bulb usually like the bulb is not a bulb It's just LEDs that are built into the lamp.
Rym: if it dies you throw away the lamp.
Scott: There are.
Scott: I have LED bulbs in all my land.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: But increasingly modern lamps like this lamp.
Rym: that was not cheap either.
Rym: It the LED is just in it Like the LED is built into the land.
Scott: not seen a lot of those and I wouldn't buy one of those.
Rym: Uh, they're pretty much what you want to buy these days.
Scott: now I want to buy a normal lamp that I can put a bulb into because that way when they switch from LEDs to some new Light technology I can just screw in a different bulb.
Scott: I don't think a new light technology from regular light to compact fluorescent to LED all with the same light lamp.
Rym: I don't think a new technology is on the horizon.
Scott: I think they'll make something to make a tiny Sun that you can screw in the one thing I can say a tiny star.
Rym: So why have I had two CFLs in the living room in those dim lamps?
Rym: I use for like accent lighting and one of them died.
Rym: I didn't get a new one yet But I happen to still have one box of the last four old style Light bulbs that I own just incandescent light.
Rym: I have in good.
Rym: I had a box with three.
Scott: you're gonna last like five minutes.
Scott: It's like we forget like how often those went out.
Scott: They went out all the goddamn time.
Scott: We just are you so used to it, but like it now that we've had come back for us and like LED.
Rym: No, I thought I bought that thing a fucking bulge when I moved into this.
Scott: It's like they never they never die.
Scott: So the idea of like a like a light bulb going out used to be a common occurrence.
Scott: now It's like super super rare.
Rym: Yep, so I didn't throw them away because they were still good, but I wasn't gonna use them.
Rym: So I put the cut the the this old bulb into one of these lamps.
Rym: So one of these lamps are identical lamps has a CFL like a modern one and the other one has an old incandescent bulb.
Rym: All the people who say that they can tell and that the light quality is different or something No one can tell me which one is which.
Scott: no unless they go look at the bulb inside of the fix It's the same thing is like the bottle of expensive wine bottle with the man of Chevy's and it tastes Yeah, it's the same thing.
Rym: However When I try only tell the light the light the white balance, however, I tried putting in white But I tried putting an LED in one of those cuz I was gonna replace the CFL's even though we're still good with LEDs.
Rym: I did that because they just use so much less power.
Rym: The LEDs at least the ones I had which are these like daylight ones that are pretty good white light.
Scott: That's what I have.
Rym: They looked pretty shit in those fixtures and you could tell because the fixtures made him have sort of this greenish greenish character.
Rym: So I find I got to figure out what to do with that.
Rym: There are LEDs I think provide.
Scott: you can just get daylight balance.
Scott: I mean not day instead of the white daylight ones You can get the yellow more yellow.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta get a different balance But there's.
Rym: I gotta figure out if I can completely replace all my remaining CFL's with LEDs.
Rym: I've replaced most of them.
Rym: one in the bedroom It's like this fucking Sun that I plugged into the top of the tertiary.
Scott: It's great But just get a light that the kind of using a driveway and that'll light up your room real good.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: so I think I'm talking years before that I had some xenon bulbs and some fixtures and actually replace those with LEDs because the Expensive LEDs that'll fit in those weird fixtures are way cheaper than an actual xenon bulb.
Rym: but Halogens if you don't know the codes and like what a t3 is or a fucking d15 Good luck buying a halogen bulb.
Rym: But I found the one I needed from a non dodgy place and it was like eight bucks and that is way cheaper.
Rym: Then the kind of LED bulb I would need to use this kind of t3 Connector or this.
Rym: well t3 form factor.
Scott: They're not making too many of those.
Scott: They're not exactly in high demand.
Rym: Yeah, so I'm gonna eventually probably buy a pure LED from the beginning light to replace this halogen but in the interim It was way cheaper to just buy this $8 halogen bulb because this halogen bulb lasted a decade.
Rym: This next one's probably gonna last another decade.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: That is my story.
Rym: So we got any tech news.
Scott: There is tech news, so I guess you know, there's been you know, many net neutrality talks.
Scott: It's not a lot new to say but actually there was something new to say.
Scott: I told a lot Something happened that we sort of thought but we didn't know exactly how it was gonna go down.
Scott: So In the United States, I guess this we got to make this tech talk and not legal talks Context because we do have a lot of non US listeners and we got a It's.
Rym: you got to remember how kind of fucked up the u.s.
Rym: Is from.
Scott: anyway There's a group called the FCC the Federal Communications Commission and they regulate, you know radio signals And cable TV and all sorts of electronic communications things telephones primarily, right?
Scott: And that includes ISPs and Internet's.
Scott: they regulate that as well.
Scott: They make you know, they make the regulations regulatory body.
Scott: It's where if you want like a radio operators license you get it from the FCC.
Scott: Yep, so The FCC, you know against the wishes of everyone except the FCC Undid the previous net neutrality regulations that we put in recently and so now there's back to the way it was before then Which is not good
Rym: because the before then was a time when there really wasn't a modern internet and it wasn't a problem yet.
Rym: And the reason it's now actually becoming a problem.
Rym: Yeah, and we fixed it with legislation.
Scott: so What happened was as we said well, you know on the one hand there's a lot of states out there that disagree And they those states, you know, such as New York want to have the old rules back But states don't have the power to do that.
Scott: The federal government has the power to do that and our federal government is because it is an interstate deal Not a you know.
Scott: radio signals go across state lines.
Scott: Yep telephones make calls across state lines Across state lines and out of the country is kind of broken right now, so we can't fix it there now.
Scott: So some of the smart states found a nice loophole, which is very clever and they said, alright We can't pass some law in our state that says you have to have net neutrality to be an ISP.
Scott: We can't do that.
Scott: But what we can do is we can say this Anyone who wants to have a contract with our state to do some work or something?
Scott: Must be an ISP that adheres to these principles of net neutrality.
Scott: So basically you don't have to be if you're an ISP in New York.
Scott: or what's the other state, Wisconsin?
Rym: There's actually a Law makers in Montana, so it's now up to six states.
Rym: All right, so sit one, California, New York, North Carolina, and so North Carolina, Illinois might be the seventh and eighth I guess.
Scott: okay.
Scott: But anyway, a bunch of states, you know saw this trick and all decided to go in on it.
Scott: and the trick is this You you know can be an ISP and operate in New York and be very unmet neutral and you won't be breaking any laws.
Scott: But if you make a contract with New York State say to provide some service to an office of the state or who knows what Or say to use land that you're gonna run cables in that is leased from the state, right?
Scott: You know you're making a contract with the state Then you either a have to abide by net neutral principles or not have your contract with the state.
Scott: Just void it and the state will pay someone else for that, you know business.
Scott: So yeah, that's a it's a clever move And it's gonna go to court eventually.
Scott: But you know, I guess I haven't seen any unnet neutral activities on my internet yet That I could tell.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is though I haven't had because there was a member.
Rym: there's a period like four years ago where Netflix just wouldn't work that well in New York on Verizon Like that happened for a while, but it seemed to have calmed down.
Scott: Yeah, there's a website You can go to fat.
Scott: I think it's fast.com.
Scott: FAST like speed fast And that is a site that will test your internet speed very very easily and it is run by Netflix.
Rym: No fancy that.
Scott: Yeah, Netflix made this site to test your internet speed And you know sort of like see if anyone is throttling the Netflix, you know
Rym: this does set a sort of I don't say dangers but worrying precedent yet again that an issue in the United States is that Traditionally the only reason any state has wanted to do its own thing So-called states rights has been because of slavery or racism or religion.
Rym: It's always been the bad sides of things.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: States want rights because the federal government would have Regulations that would say don't be evil and it is like what we want to be evil states rights states rights
Rym: but and part of the reason why the other the correct side of the political spectrum didn't really push on those sorts of things is Complicated but they basically never did.
Rym: you very rarely had states being like we're gonna do universal health care.
Rym: Fuck y'all.
Rym: So there's it seems with technology issues in particular.
Rym: States that are on the left side are more and more willing in the United States to do stuff like this and there's a lot of reasons why that are beyond the scope of a Monday episode of GeekNights, but the problem is The main reason why we I have not pushed for this too hard Is that if you let these states that are intelligent do intelligent things like this And you let the states that are have better having problems because they voted in Republicans do the opposite of that.
Rym: You're just gonna increase the divide between people with technology and without with health care and without with computers and without.
Scott: That's gonna bring about the cyber dystopia that I've been waiting for.
Rym: Not great for most people But it's I've been preparing for ever so long I have been to.
Scott: it rewards me because that's what I invested in and counted Huh?
Scott: Well, I'm a selfish person.
Rym: We're deckers and company men.
Rym: We're not.
Rym: we're not like the orcs Shadow run.
Rym: It's a role-playing system where you can play an elf who is also a hacker.
Rym: I dare you to find it.
Rym: Oh and a dragon runs for president.
Rym: I dare you to define a more Rym setting.
Scott: We need the dragon president now more than ever.
Rym: Yeah, I would vote dunkless on let's go.
Rym: So in some other news, uh, this sort of come out that uber and lyft, you know those companies Uber more sucks less than the other one, but they both suck.
Rym: Yeah, not gonna get into why they're evil.
Rym: But let's say uber is evil.
Scott: Do not use them ever.
Scott: use a legit cab or not something else.
Rym: now The hope has been that all those problems are made moot by accessible self-driving car technology Because self-driving cars mean that no one ever needs to take a cab anywhere again ever.
Rym: the car itself does it?
Rym: that also means that maybe for most people individual ownership of cars doesn't even matter anymore.
Rym: and There's a problem that a big part of all the employment in the United States is people driving cars.
Rym: We've talked about all this before.
Scott: truck driver is the number one job in the country.
Scott: in most states It's the number one job and then driver of car Period is like if you employ
Rym: a huge percentage of the middle class You
Scott: eliminated all the jobs where your job is to drive There would be not like that's like a very very perhaps double-digit percent of all jobs in the United States.
Rym: So it appears based on this article and some of the discussion that's been happening in the sphere lately That the company like companies like uber like uber They their endgame is to try to have regulation and urban planning and policies in place To basically ban the private use of self-driving cars Particularly in urban areas where you know the vast majority of people are.
Rym: so I'm actually okay with the principle of you can't own cars anymore.
Rym: cars are Car should.
Rym: in my in my ideal future car is just one more form of mass transit that drives very small numbers of people to destinations that not very many people want to go to and handles like last mile transportation.
Rym: But car should just be one more offering of the government right alongside train boss, etc.
Rym: So I'm okay with not letting people own their stupid cars anymore.
Rym: I'm not okay with private company using that legislation to be the sole owner of said cars to Continue to wage its war on mass transit and modern practice.
Scott: I mean even if they do do that, right and it would be it would be crappy in the short term.
Scott: Yeah, but historically speaking right that you used to have private subway IRT VMT.
Rym: Yeah, that was a terrible idea.
Scott: We had private train terrible idea.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, you know, we still have private plane.
Rym: But yeah, you know what?
Scott: Maybe we shouldn't know but the point is is that over time because they were so terrible They became not so public anymore, right?
Scott: Even if we let uber do this, it's like well, it'll just get nationalized eventually At least to the Amtrak level of nationalization,
Rym: yeah, but I guess from a technology standpoint The the thing self-driving cars are still gonna be crazy disruptive and that this is yet an example of one more way They're gonna be disruptive that a lot of people are not even thinking about whether or not private car ownership even matters and whether or not large conglomerate companies might use legislation ostensibly promoting better technology governance governance to in fact just control and industry as a private contractor.
Rym: So in some other news, we got to talk about this because everyone was talking about it.
Rym: It was kind of a big deal.
Scott: too much news going on.
Rym: Yeah We got.
Rym: let's see how that goes.
Rym: you want to not talk about the Hawaii missile alert.
Scott: It's not that big You know, I feel like it's a. it's a. it's a beaten bush.
Rym: I feel it wasn't.
Rym: it's partly.
Rym: we just didn't do a GeekNights around when it happened.
Rym: But basically if you lived in Hawaii You got a legit notification from the government on your phone that said there's a fucking missile coming.
Rym: This is not a drill and Because of the way the government works that was not corrected for what like 40 minutes too long?
Rym: Yeah, I've 40 seconds might have been too long.
Rym: any number of seconds is too long, but the original story that came out I think the joke I saw on every UX designers Twitter was well I'm making a slide about this in my next TED talk Blamed it on the UI which is of course an awful UI.
Scott: the UI is atrocious the UX is atrocious Yeah, but I mean that's you know Because the only there are very few companies in very few situations where people producing software Right have a culture of valuing designing UI for example Apple.
Scott: obvious, right?
Scott: But most places that produce software do not have a culture appreciation or care for design.
Scott: They just may it works.
Scott: You know, it's just a bunch of text on the screen.
Scott: Don't give a fuck.
Scott: They don't even care or think about it.
Scott: It's not even a matter of like being bad at designing, right?
Scott: It's like they actually don't care or even think about like.
Scott: design is not a step.
Scott: Yep, right It's like.
Rym: but UX user experience goes one step behind just the design of a GUI.
Rym: because yeah, this GUI is awful but the entire Process and procedures around something are also part of the user experience and the process here was bad And the the rules people had to follow were.
Rym: it seems like Everything was bad in this situation.
Rym: So this outcome was basically inevitable and I am shocked.
Rym: It did not happen sooner.
Rym: Yeah I Guess the only point I really got here is that this is not just the story of a poorly designed menu caused a missile alert.
Rym: No, the story here is that?
Rym: GUIs.
Rym: GUIs can prevent.
Rym: our GUIs can mitigate or Minimize the chance of mistakes being made.
Rym: UX design can also mitigate and minimize the chances of these things happening.
Rym: but the story of bad decisions like this is always bigger than you think.
Rym: and don't drill it down to One slide in some UX designers.
Rym: talk at some TEDx that you're gonna see next month.
Scott: I mean, it's just a question if I you know, we know how to design something, right?
Scott: You go to design places and it's like they always talk about how to design things better how to get a topography.
Scott: good It's like.
Scott: but everyone there is someone who already cares about design, right and also they tend to care.
Scott: If you got someone who's painting Warhammer miniatures, right and it's like oh and they're trying to do better at it You can show them techniques like oh, he's had a dry brush.
Scott: Here's how to do that, right?
Scott: Oh, here's how to apply the primer better, right?
Scott: But if there's somebody who literally takes a can of red spray paint goes I'm done and like just doesn't give a fuck.
Scott: It's like how.
Scott: it's like what do you?
Scott: that's what you have most of the time in software production, right?
Scott: And it's not really a problem if someone does that in Warhammer cuz it's like, alright, that's what you like, bro I mean whatever right but it's a problem when you're hurt.
Scott: any missile alert system for Hawaii It doesn't hurt anyone but a badly designed software Even if it is technically speaking in the code bug free the poor design could actually cause bugs.
Scott: Yeah, I cut it pebkek.
Rym: So and you cannot assume that a user is going to follow a procedure.
Rym: do the right thing.
Rym: So a user experience has to take into account all of human failings and mitigate those things like say There's a situation where you have a UX that gates people to prevent Common mistakes from being made.
Rym: like if they try like the if you wanna send a real missile alert You got to click on it.
Rym: Like you got to do a confirmation thing of some kind You also have to assume that someone's going to go one step further and do all of that and then continue to proceed in making Their terrible mistake, so maybe you need a way to undo it a break glass Like you got a thing a lot of steps deeper than even a lot of UX designers do.
Rym: Last and least.
Scott: Oh, yeah, come on.
Scott: There's not tech news round up here.
Rym: This is kind of amazing.
Rym: Best Buy announced that they're no longer going to sell physical CDs.
Scott: They still sell CDs.
Rym: That's the news.
Rym: I am shocked that any big stores sell CDs.
Scott: I'm shocked.
Scott: anyone buys CDs.
Rym: Yeah, I don't own a CD player, I don't think.
Scott: Yeah, I can play one in my In my computer.
Rym: Oh, I still have my Fujitsu lifebook.
Rym: It has an optical drive in it.
Scott: Yeah, I have an optical drive.
Rym: I also have one optical USB drive for emergencies.
Rym: I guess I could play a CD.
Scott: I'm here cleaning up my The Connecticut house this weekend.
Scott: I found two disc men.
Scott: I don't know if they worked or not.
Rym: yeah, didn't care throw them out, but it seems like everyone's moving to streaming and Hardly anyone seems to care about owning music.
Rym: streaming seems to be good enough And I think the whole industry is gonna have to align itself a hundred percent around streaming.
Rym: Well ninety percent around streaming.
Rym: ten percent around collectors that you can milk for a lot of money.
Scott: There is a niche industry Going on like the lossless players There.
Scott: first of all, there are people who are stupid and collect vinyls.
Scott: Yep, right of new things for some reason.
Rym: Okay, whatever you like bro you like music Go be my don't collect CDs though CDs will actually like they wear out like they'll just start flaking and they're dead.
Scott: no, but there are people who are I see this in kpop a lot is they'll produce albums where they have like Photobooks and a big, you know, it won't be in a plastic jewel case It's like a big cardboard thing with all sorts of shit in there.
Scott: Yeah actors crap, right sort of like.
Scott: I used to buy anime DVDs and they would come with plush plushies Underwear and action figures.
Rym: Where is it?
Rym: I still got the eye of Vogler somewhere, right?
Scott: That kind of thing.
Scott: So imagine if albums all came in eye of Vogler.
Scott: that's what kpop is like.
Scott: so you'll buy them if you're a fan of that group and you won't listen to the music on the CD.
Scott: you stream the music or watch it on YouTube right to get views up here to make Popular.
Scott: but you know people buy those to collect them as things just to have things because they're materialistic collecting people who I guess That's not good.
Rym: yep, so It's kind of amazing that this long tail lasted so long as people buy in CDs and Surprised it was worth the shelf space.
Rym: I think it's partly that it takes a long time for retail like big retail Organizations to change anything that they're doing.
Rym: Yeah Cuz I'm sure there's some whole workflow around.
Rym: like CDs get shipped in bulk and then like with comics and things some things can't be Shipped back.
Scott: and I was like about CEO best buy right?
Scott: When was the last time I Scott bought or listened to music on a CD?
Scott: probably sometime in Beacon before when I had the car before.
Rym: it's the last time my car my CD player didn't work in my car at any point.
Scott: We lived before I plug the I've got the thing to plug the iPod into the car.
Scott: I use CDs in the car right as soon as I stopped using CDs period Which is I guess 10 plus years ago 2004 I think is the last time I listened to music from a red book CD, right?
Scott: Something like that.
Scott: That's when they should have stopped selling them.
Scott: as soon as you stop using them like, huh?
Rym: I'm the CEO of Best Buy Because you should stop selling these if you are wealthier you're probably an early adopter.
Rym: I mean my family actually like we Reinvested and saved and bought a CD player in the early days to add to the high-five system.
Rym: Anyone, you know use the CD but tapes continued to be sold and popular for a long time After CDs were introduced and I didn't even know.
Scott: I didn't even know who's still buying DVDs and blu-rays.
Scott: I'd stop selling those.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of people.
Rym: I see them in my Anna Twitter feed.
Scott: Mostly I think they're doing the collectors item biz.
Scott: I don't think they're actually.
Rym: actually.
Rym: a lot of them are buying shows and Then laughing at people later when those shows are taken off a streaming platforms And there's literally nowhere to watch them and the physical media is sold out and you try to pirate them and like they're not even Easily pirated cuz no one gave a shit.
Scott: if no one gives a shit then that's not a show We're not?
Rym: I need to see yeah, but I thought like I thought name a show I is.
Rym: I couldn't find an easy Torrent of my hood sky tie the original you have that I already.
Rym: yet cuz I pirated it and I kept it.
Rym: What if I hadn't kept it?
Rym: and today I was like man, I should really watch my hood sky time.
Rym: Good luck with them.
Rym: Yeah, might be tough But anyway things of the day.
Rym: So this video is called why the metric system matters.
Rym: But what it really is about is it talks about a bunch of different like?
Rym: Measuring and counting systems and a bunch of historical stuff.
Rym: It's a pretty good video goes a little more depth than a lot of you probably encountered before but it explains something That I didn't really know and I realized that no one around me seems to know.
Rym: so Scott American shoe sizes.
Rym: Mm-hmm How the fuck do they work?
Scott: They're just slightly different from the European ones like half half up.
Rym: Europe uses pretty much just metric now number of centimeters There's like no the UK ones were half up from yeah, cuz you just know the US are you.
Rym: but anyway, why?
Rym: What what is a 10 mean?
Rym: and what versus a 10 and a half like?
Rym: what is that system based on?
Scott: Probably they was probably someone's foot and they were like well that foot is X and there's probably something cobblers did and measured with.
Scott: So funny that my thing of the day also involves cobbling.
Rym: oh, yeah because I actually like the American system for purely selfish selfish reasons because my shoe size is Exactly a u.s.
Rym: 10 and a half.
Scott: mine change mine depends on the shoe company.
Scott: It's like if it's a Nike.
Scott: shoe is usually 12, but like some other companies could be 11 11.
Rym: I mean if I buy quality shoes like.
Rym: I don't buy shoes from weird places, but I think I bought.
Scott: I bought some dress shoes.
Rym: My ten and a half is like spot-on.
Rym: it's always different from different company, but That system is actually based on a specific unit of measure Called the barley corn.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: It's how many?
Rym: I guess it's how many barley corns long your foot is.
Rym: Anyway, this video is pretty interesting.
Scott: I'll use barley corns.
Rym: Uh, yeah, it's American shoe sizes much like American acres.
Rym: Seem to be based on some of the oldest units of measure that are still in common use today Because we have these like meta systems that are actually based on these old systems.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Anyway, so what's your shoe related thing?
Scott: So I found out about.
Scott: you know, I've always thought like hey, you know There used to be cobblers about but now there aren't really cobblers Like.
Scott: the only cobbling that goes on these days is like shoe shining replace shoelaces and maybe replace a soul and that's about it.
Scott: I mean I had some Birkenstocks and I wanted to get him fixed and usually in the city It'll be like shoe and watch repair place.
Scott: the cobbler wanted like 80% of the price of new shoes And whatever all-in-one anyway, so I was like you can't really.
Scott: I always thought well You can't really cobble like sneakers the shoes that people actually wear, right?
Scott: It's pretty much just dress shoes and boots and stuff.
Scott: But I would have thought without this video who even cares you buy another whatever the current Nike is and just move on Right, but no There's this kid in Chicago and I think his dad and also his grandpa were cobblers and he is also a cobbler.
Scott: He's the teen cobbler almost like a superhero teen cobbler and he may has a store called fix yo kicks Which is fucking awesome.
Rym: I did not take into account the people who want to keep their old Non leather shoes together.
Scott: sneakers are a big craze for the past.
Scott: You know X years right.
Rym: or if you live in the rest of the country tennis shoes anyway.
Scott: and or kicks Kid in Chicago you bring him like your Jordans for the 90s.
Scott: He'll make them look new even though they're from the 90s or whatever and it's like that's fucking awesome.
Scott: I wish I had that kid.
Scott: Yeah, I hope it's cheaper to bring him.
Scott: You know, I guess you're only bringing shoes to him.
Scott: if they're you know, ultra rare coca beans I would take him cuz.
Rym: I got my Nike like for whatever free running shoes.
Scott: I don't know if you can fix those.
Rym: Yeah, I'd be curious because the new ones are great for running but there was one.
Scott: It'd be cheaper to just buy new ones.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but they're different.
Rym: I wear them for running.
Rym: I wear them out.
Rym: I don't care what they look like.
Rym: But there was one year where they looked really good and I got a pair of those that are not looking so great and you Can't get those anymore.
Rym: If he could make those look good.
Rym: I would pay a reasonable amount of money.
Scott: Mm-hmm Yeah, that's kids.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: Yeah in the meta moment The book club book is Emily Wilson's translation of the Odyssey by Homa Homa But really probably more by Emily Wilson, I'm guessing.
Scott: well, I don't know how much is how much is what?
Rym: well It's a new interpretation.
Scott: Yeah, we'll discuss that when we do the book club.
Rym: Yeah, the previous book club book is it's still on.
Rym: the website was Nk jemisin is the fifth season and I just want to reiterate again If you didn't read that book you should go back and read it because the fifth season and the trilogy it's part of is real fucking good and More and more people around me are reading it because the book club.
Rym: so you should too.
Rym: Otherwise if you saw us at PAX Unplugged the video of our talk is on YouTube.
Rym: if you saw us impact South the video of our talk is on YouTube.
Rym: if you saw us at magfest the video of one of our talks is on YouTube.
Rym: and if you a long time ago saw our judge anime by its cover and anime Boston the video of us doing it At Scott's apartment for the fall 2017 season.
Rym: anime winter 2018.
Rym: Oh, yeah winter 2018.
Rym: This is one older.
Rym: Anyway, it is on YouTube.
Scott: the fall 2017 also is on YouTube.
Rym: That's all of these are on YouTube and you can enjoy them.
Rym: So We haven't actually talked about like how hard drives work in the modern era as far as a consumer would care like Episode and SSDs.
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: pretty sure we did.
Rym: we I'll dig some of that up.
Scott: I mean we can just briefly go over right?
Scott: So when I first built a computer it was ATA.
Scott: You had a ribbon cable and a molex 4-pin connector that went into that hard drive and spinning magnetic platters and read heads That would zip across them.
Scott: Right and that was a hard drive and there was no other kind of hard drive.
Scott: that was it.
Scott: and they were slow and they got faster over time.
Scott: and they changed it from IDE to SAT and SAT was better because it was faster and it didn't use a stupid ribbon cable used a much smaller cable.
Scott: That was way better.
Scott: Yep, and it was cereal in general.
Rym: There's been a move away from at least outside of Tightly controlled environments like on your motherboard with CPUs and everything, but you move to Serial interfaces for connectivity to slower things as opposed to parallel because it's really hard to keep those bits in sync in Parallel unless you can parallelize the workflow which for hard drives until recently you could not do
Scott: anyway.
Scott: So then we had to SAT a and there's also a better power connector.
Scott: not and it was smaller.
Scott: and you can get smaller drives because the connectors are smaller.
Scott: and you know The drives got better and so on.
Scott: and then you know The idea of the SSD was always there.
Scott: people would like get a ton of RAM which meant like 32 megabytes of RAM.
Scott: Yeah, and they would make a RAM drive, right?
Scott: That would only last while the computer was on but they tried to keep the computer on a long time You know or people would get a whole bunch of RAM sticks and put them on a PCI card and make a drive.
Scott: You know out of RAM, you know some way because it's you know, it's solid-state storage meaning You know magnets is not solid-state, right?
Scott: It's it's a chip, you know that we're like an SD card.
Scott: that's solid-state like flash storage.
Scott: All right, if you want to know what's actually happening there.
Scott: It's like you had to go look that up.
Scott: I'm sorry That's not what the show's about.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Also, I can't explain it to ya
Rym: and what's interesting is actually this stuff in general like This the protocols and how things work and like all the details have actually gotten way More complex around PC storage than they were back when I paid attention because I was like Meticulously researching how to build PCs.
Scott: Yep, but eventually we had SSDs But they were crazy expensive and small and they're still more expensive and have less storage.
Scott: You still sometimes need magnet drives if you need a ton of storage like terabytes, but we have the SSDs now They're the size of laptop hard drives.
Scott: They connect to that same SATA.
Scott: It goes up to six gigabits per second You know and that's still.
Scott: we got and it's still great and people still use it But it wasn't fast enough.
Scott: We sorted the SATA couldn't really get any faster even though the SSDs could go faster.
Scott: So on your computer on your motherboard this PCI Express slots and no one's really using those except to hold video cards.
Rym: now It's interesting.
Rym: remember in the old day There was ISA and PCI and AGP and all these slots where you could use a protocol to connect things to your computer.
Rym: Yep, generic things like a card that does USB or a sound card or a video card or a network card.
Rym: Yeah, you're putting a board in your computer that gives you shit.
Scott: But now they slowly added all those things to the CPU and the motherboard and the bridge North bridge the South bridge Whatever.
Scott: So now your motherboard has a sound card.
Scott: You don't put a sound card in there.
Scott: Yeah, your motherboard has like one or two network ports.
Scott: You don't add a network card.
Scott: So like the motherboards even mini ICX ones have like fucking everything on them and no one needed to put cards.
Scott: You know everyone used USB.
Scott: They didn't need a game card to connect.
Scott: their game can tell again USB.
Rym: the big deal with USB is that it was a serial protocol as opposed to a parallel protocol.
Scott: We stopped needing to use those slots.
Scott: So some people got a bunch of video cards.
Scott: Yeah, cuz they had too much money.
Rym: Some people like me have a firewire card or something weird.
Scott: Yeah, but most people put in one video card and had a bunch of empty slots.
Scott: Yeah, so the thing is the way.
Scott: the way the PCI Express works is that it's crazy fast obviously, that's why your video card connects to it, but There's only so much bandwidth there just like anything else this bandwidth.
Scott: You couldn't put a hundred video cards in there.
Scott: They wouldn't be enough, you know bits to go around, right?
Rym: Yep, so now not to get into the details just kind of beyond the scope of this.
Rym: But that's why you'll see like you plug in one video card and it runs at 16 But if you would in two, it's eight and eight.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Anyway, so What they call this is what channels you have so many PCI channels something like that.
Scott: I forget what it is lanes.
Scott: lanes That's what they call it lanes.
Scott: So your motherboard and your CPU have so a limited number of PCI lanes and you can only you know Once you've used those lanes up you can't add any more cards or anything else to use PCI Express Even if you got vacant slots, right?
Scott: So they're like, well, that's faster than SAT a. why don't we go borrow some of them?
Scott: They're lanes.
Scott: so you could get Solid-state drives that plug in the PCI Express slot.
Scott: Yeah, that's kind of silly, but it works and it's really fast.
Rym: So, okay sure and there's all these other ways to do fast storage that are Enterprise only server only way beyond the scope of what we're gonna talk about today, right?
Scott: But what eventually?
Scott: what they currently have the latest and greatest technology is the m.2 slot.
Rym: now, this is important.
Rym: This is kind of why we're doing this show a lot of people Confused thinking because SATA was sort of.
Rym: I mean there were all their form factors for SATA But SATA for all intents and purposes was both the form factor for the cabling and the protocol.
Scott: Yeah up until now It was pretty much.
Scott: you plug stuff in where it fits and it works and you don't have to think about it.
Scott: M2 it makes, you know configuring the PC and the storage a little weird Compared to before and there's like a lot of weird stuff going on that you won't know unless you've been educated because m.2 is Literally just the form factor.
Rym: They basically needed a way.
Rym: the fact that you're like hard drives were pretty big in the old days and the old days They're even bigger.
Rym: but nowadays if it's not a spinning disk It's really just.
Rym: it can be a like.
Rym: look at a micro SD card like storage can be really tiny.
Scott: They have a micro SD cards at like 512 megabytes.
Scott: Yeah, it's like holy shit.
Rym: so it's like it's like smaller than a cornflake, but the Form factor of plugging in like SATA or all these other ways Didn't really make sense.
Rym: to have just like this tiny little chip sticking out of the end.
Scott: You open up your solid-state drive and it's like two and a half inches.
Scott: you look inside.
Scott: There's almost nothing in there.
Rym: Yep, and for most people who aren't building a giant desktop computer because desktops really are not like workstations are not a thing for most People anymore.
Rym: Nope You want you wanted a form factor?
Rym: To be able to just put a hard drive into some small computer in a modern way.
Rym: that made sense.
Scott: Yeah for the way computers are used today It's like other than the power supply in the video card.
Scott: literally the motherboard in the CPU is the whole computer.
Scott: So you could get mini ITX computers and like make really flat cases if you could somehow get rid of that stuff.
Scott: and the hard Drive, you know, even the two and a half inch SSDs We're you know, really gumming up the works in terms of making the flat computer.
Rym: So as a result, my hard drive is smaller than one of my RAM chips and it's just plugged into the light.
Scott: It's like it's like a stick of gum, but slightly bigger maybe like smaller than a bookmark.
Scott: It's small.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So m2 refers to just the physical slot on the motherboard that these things go into.
Scott: right.
Scott: Well, it's which is separate from what it's actually doing.
Scott: so an m2 slot and most motherboards you're gonna buy today can actually work either in SATA mode or PCI Express mode.
Scott: so you plug a thing into it a drive.
Scott: you get an m2 drive and plug it in.
Scott: That drive might be using SATA or it might be using PCI Express.
Rym: This is why you gotta read the manual for your motherboard and the specs.
Scott: if you're buying the drive You might buy a drive that doesn't do PCI Express.
Scott: you plug it in.
Scott: it's only going at SATA speed.
Scott: You might as well just plugged it into the SATA port with the cable.
Scott: It's not really getting anything by being plugged directly into that m2 slot.
Rym: Yep So even even better.
Rym: so a lot of motherboards like they'll advertise like they'll even have multiple m.2 slots like yeah m.2 raid.
Rym: Usually if there's more than one it's because it's just say to using the m.2 form factor.
Scott: No, no, I seen drive motherboards where you can put in two real PCI.
Rym: I have but but I've also seen a lot that pointedly we're not.
Scott: it's gonna be.
Scott: it's gonna be in the cheaper end.
Scott: Right if you get a cheapo motherboard that looks like it has too many m2s for a cheap motherboard then Probably something's up with that.
Scott: You got to read the specs.
Scott: Anyway, there's another thing going on.
Scott: It's tricky which is you plug in an m2 drive and even if it's in PCI Express mode It's linked up to some of the SATA ports.
Scott: So if you also have SATA drives Plugging in something into one of the m2 ports might disable some of the SATA ports that match up with that one.
Scott: Yep, so it's like oh if I plug in something to m2 slot one SATA slots one and two become disabled and you can't plug anything into.
Scott: oh my god.
Rym: I was about to make an analogy but then I realized that kids today probably wouldn't even know what this is.
Rym: but on Network gear in the older days you'd have a bunch of ports.
Rym: You can plug your stuff into like plug computer one computers you computer three, then you had on uplink port.
Rym: That's where you plug the switch or the router or the hub Into your other switch or router or cable modem or whatever like the upstream stuff.
Rym: Usually there was one port.
Rym: like you'd have ports one two and three were like for plugging stuff in.
Rym: Then you'd have port four and the uplink port.
Rym: if you plug something into the uplink port it Cannibalized.
Rym: port four is one or the other not both.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like yeah You have to play it's.
Scott: it's a weird situation.
Scott: It's like you think well, I got ten plugs here, right?
Scott: I can use all ten of them.
Scott: It's like no actually if you use that one, it borrows bandwidth for that one.
Scott: You can't use it.
Scott: You can't use both of these at once.
Scott: Yeah one of the other.
Rym: so my motherboard supports both.
Rym: so I can tell it Hey, I'm gonna put us say to drive in this m2 and then there's one say to port that I just can't use.
Rym: It's got a different color on it.
Rym: Yeah, or I can tell it that's an NVMe PCIe card and it says yes Sir, your Sata port is ready and available.
Scott: Yeah, it's you know you got it.
Scott: you got to make sure you know you're aware of this before you just start plugging stuff in because it'll tell you Like which ports become disabled and stuff like that, right?
Rym: Now.
Rym: What's funny is I gotta remember how old I am because AHCI.
Rym: I Remember that being the new way to do things and then I just noticed I'm looking at the Wikipedia here in addition to supporting Legacy AHCI.
Scott: Yeah, it's NVMe now, right?
Rym: Yeah NVMe.
Rym: I forget what this stands for NVMe Express, okay Non-volatile memory host controller interface to NVM HCIS.
Rym: Yeah the To deal with all that shit.
Rym: This is kind of why this is really interesting.
Rym: Is that Sata and enable PETA like parallel like old IDE with the parallel channels like, you know the big ribbon cable?
Rym: it only had all those channels to try to push a lot of data as fast as possible and More wires was just better back in the old days.
Rym: nowadays.
Rym: One wire is usually better.
Rym: Serialized transactions can generally be scaled better anyway But hard drives could not execute parallel instructions.
Rym: Because there's a spinning platter.
Scott: the needle can read like one spot at a time.
Rym: Maybe Maybe they could be as long as the data was formed the right way.
Rym: They could be writing onto one side of one platter and reading onto part of another platter.
Scott: I don't know that is the inside of a hard drive.
Rym: That is not.
Rym: even if that existed that is not something you could take advantage of or be scalable.
Rym: the reality was that hard drives could effectively just queue up operations, but couldn't have been parallel and early Sata SSDs Were pretty much the same way because even though they were a solid-state drive internally Which theoretically could be engineered to have parallel read and write operations you Wanted it to be compatible with the way hard drives plugged into computers So it just plugged into Sata.
Rym: so even if the drive supported it your computer couldn't support that.
Rym: as far as I can tell NVMe allows for the idea that you have a drive that could have parallel I/O and Take advantage of that right?
Scott: It's like you plug in a drive to Sata and it's like sure You know it you you can.
Scott: it can tell the computer that this is a solid-state drive and not a hard not a magnetic drive.
Scott: The computer the operating system can account for that to a certain extent.
Scott: right treat it slightly differently But it's still speaking the same state of protocol There's only so far it can go to treat it differently Right by plugging it into something different and being like this is definitely not a magnetic drive.
Scott: This is definitely solid-state storage.
Scott: with these capabilities You can take full advantage of those Capabilities and not using a protocol that was designed for a hard drive with a big spinning platter that you know Spun around with a motor yep.
Rym: So NVMe or NVM Express or you'll see.
Rym: people refer to different ways.
Rym: That's the thing if you buy like one of those Intel solid-state drives.
Rym: That's just a PCI card Mm-hmm.
Rym: well PCIe card yeah,
Scott: so another thing you might be confused about is when you're shopping for m2 drives You'll see all these numbers like 2280 and 22 something else and all these numbers like it's like what the hell are all these numbers And like the motherboard will list like four different numbers and the you know.
Scott: But the drive will only have one number and of course common sense you just go.
Scott: okay I'll just make sure the number on the drive matches one of the compatible numbers in the motherboard and you're good to go which is true, but it's important to know what that number means.
Scott: that number is Literally just the size and shape of the m2 drive.
Scott: 22 is the width and the height.
Scott: the length of it is you know?
Rym: The other number 80 every now and then the standard make sense.
Scott: I said 2280 is like those sort of is the normal size for most of them that you're gonna get these days like the Samsung 850s or whatever like the Evo's.
Scott: those are 2280.
Scott: I'm pretty sure.
Scott: now in the old days if you see one.
Scott: That's like 2240. well you know it's a short stubby one.
Rym: now in the old days with like ISA and PCI like the old things you'd plug into computers They didn't really have that much of a tight tolerance.
Rym: And how big the things like there were rules about how big things could actually be.
Rym: but like some video cards would just be Longer.
Rym: you just had to know and take it into account and the tolerances weren't that big as computer cases were big.
Rym: the whole point Of m2 is to be able to build very space efficient computers.
Rym: so the Specifications and the way you refer to these things encoded those sizes Directly like this because people care a lot about how many millimeters wide something.
Scott: well you'll see on the motherboard.
Scott: usually They'll be the m2 connector and then one screw and then another screw.
Scott: so if it allows for the longer one Yeah, right.
Scott: And that's that you you're only gonna put one screw in there and the way you install it is real simple.
Scott: you put in The end with the clips into the into the slot you push it down and get flat against the motherboard Top or some of them go on the bottom of the motherboard Yeah, which is cool, and then you put in the one screw, and you're good to go.
Scott: It's great.
Rym: No, I can slide one into my nose up there if I was separate power connectors.
Scott: No nothing okay.
Scott: now one more thing You got to know is like this is a B business.
Rym: luckily This doesn't like you don't have to worry about it as much because it's kind of like in the old days with AGP Like whether or not you had the tab for the voltages and everything.
Scott: You don't to worry about this too much, but it's also good to know yeah Is that so?
Scott: on the connector part is a little notch and some have the notch on the left B?
Scott: Some have the notch on the right them some have the both not just being M. Yep, so you'll see a drive will be like B. Plus M. That means that on the connector part It's got two notches on it.
Scott: You just got to make sure it fits in your mother part.
Scott: It's probably gonna fit.
Rym: yep I'm pretty sure.
Scott: pretty much all the motherboards have B, and if you buy a modern motherboard from you know aces a asrock Gigabyte whoever right and you buy a Samsung Evo m2 is gonna fit.
Scott: it's gonna be just fine.
Rym: It's sort of interesting that this is the kind of thing where?
Rym: It matters for early adopters because there would be things that only supported certain kinds of yes Like when m2 is brand new everyone is still feeling it out.
Scott: get a little bit now.
Rym: It's standardized you're good to go like AGP there was still there within the old days you could buy video cards that were AGP and try to plug them in your AGP core port and they just wouldn't fit.
Rym: and the assumption was the only people buying AGP video cards in that era were people who knew what they were doing.
Rym: and then later the GP ports just supported every kind of AGP card mm-hmm, so I hope we demystified the deal with m2 Cuz.
Scott: frankly it took me a while to figure it out.
Scott: Yeah, if you have those numbers somewhat recently.
Scott: so if you have an existing computer You're just gonna buy a SATA hard drive or SSD or whatever and stick it in there still making new SSDs that are SATA, and they're still just great and still just fine and still crazy fast.
Scott: There's nothing wrong with those, but if you're building new computers Pretty much if you're gonna cost you a bit more to get an m2 drive.
Scott: So if you can't if you want to save money That's the first place to save money is to get the SSD.
Scott: that's goes SATA instead of m2 because for most Normal people doing normal stuff that difference you won't know your game is gonna load a little slow or whatever.
Rym: But I predict it'll.
Scott: the SSDs are still crazy fast.
Scott: You could save like a hundred to two hundred dollars, but not going m2.
Rym: Oh my HDPC probably got four more years of life just by replacing its old spinning disk with a regular old SSD.
Scott: That is.
Scott: one of the good thing about SATA is that you had your spinning disks hooked up to SATA.
Scott: now You can get an SSD play in the same hole.
Rym: But I think it won't be long until the vast majority of computers if you buy or build one Even if it's still SATA you're gonna put.
Rym: you're gonna have one hard drive is gonna be an m.2.
Rym: Yeah, if you have two hard drives It's just gonna be two m.2s.
Scott: and then the only other kinds of the main limitation is that the biggest m2s are like one Terabyte.
Scott: I think I've seen some two terabyte ones But they cost on our as much as the whole computer.
Scott: like mine a one terabyte m2 is like $1,000.
Scott: It's like fuck.
Scott: no I have a 512 is like it.
Scott: the for the is the price for people who have money and the 256 is for the price of people who have More less money.
Rym: Yep, but that's fine because if you need more space just add SSD That's much cheaper.
Rym: or add a magnetic drive Even if you need a lot of space.
Scott: if you just got like thing about.
Scott: if you got a computer and it's like, okay I'll install windows in the m2.
Scott: I'll install the gate the Applications.
Scott: I use the most on the m2s.
Rym: they load real fast on the games my Adobe apps Whatever my other crap on just a cheap SSD that I played into it.
Scott: But if you got all this stuff you could put it on an SSD and if you even want to save more money It's like okay.
Scott: I got a huge video collection.
Scott: You could put that on a magnetic drive and you wouldn't notice for shit.
Rym: now the fun thing about magnetic drives.
Rym: It's so cheap.
Scott: You can get as well as massive.
Rym: one might as well just buy two and raid them Like why not get an eight terabyte if you got money, but yeah You just get it by one if you don't have more.
Rym: thereby four terabyte spinning discs ain't expensive?
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: you can get a four terabyte like spinning magnetic disc for like less than a hundred bucks Probably way less than that.
Scott: and meanwhile, you know a one term, you know to get four terabytes of m2 Storage is gonna cost you like five thousand.
Scott: Right, you could.
Scott: it's ridiculous the difference in price.
Scott: So yeah, the magnetic drive is not dead yet, right?
Rym: That's why you still the magnetic drive is the place is for if you have Terabytes of data that you want to start.
Scott: people are not storing so much anymore because they use their streaming their music.
Scott: They're streaming their videos and most you know, yeah, maybe you got a photo collection You keep in the cloud on Google Photos and then you know stuff like that.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: well now you're not storing anything But people who are still storing things people are storing photos locally people who are have videos downloaded or making videos usually creators Are gonna be stored right or you know anything like that?
Scott: Yeah, you might need to throw a magnet drive in there to get your storage up or just a NAS but that's still a magnet Drive is just in a different box.
Scott: Yeah the box your computers in.
Rym: so if you're building a computer in the near future You're probably have one hard drive for all your basic stuff.
Scott: now, you know how the m2 goes.
Rym: Yeah, it'll be an m.2.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows.
Rym: sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays Night's is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn hiding the nickel a shimmering ruby obelisk hanging in the sky.
Rym: my state calm.
Rym: Jeremy minor genuine bonafide electrophotics car monorail Cold guy Amanda Duchette Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando captain shinku Agassi.
Rym: 421 creations.
Rym: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Rym: Semper Fi bitch Shervin about horror rarely.
Rym: Val James David White Rochelle, Montanona Superboy Rym says something funny here.
Rym: sailor Vista Don Schleich chart obvious and Jojo Joestar Sam Carter Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open lander Finn Chris mink if Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Han.
Rym: I'm really excited at how steamed ham seems to be like exploding onto the scene everywhere.
Rym: and Yeah, I'm not gonna make a steamed hams cuz I feel like percent percent perfection has already been achieved.
Rym: but anyway now I leave you with.