Rym: It's Wednesday March 21st 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We review Lou over the wall.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Got to do something.
Rym: I only get to do two or three times a year today.
Rym: I wore the work in the snow.
Rym: Yeah, so many people didn't go to work and it was totally fine.
Rym: But I realized all the people who didn't go to work are the people who don't live in the city.
Rym: Basically if you work in the city, but don't live in the city, it sucks and that's it.
Rym: So everyone who lives in the city was just in the office and everyone doesn't live in the city.
Rym: He was working from home pretty much.
Rym: I got to wear my fancy boots.
Scott: Okay, I mean you could wear them whenever you want.
Scott: You don't have to wear them when it's news.
Rym: They're so big and There's.
Rym: they're the most comfortable shoes I own but they're so big and clunky that it's there's very few occasions to ever wear them.
Scott: My pre my boots that I were very expensive and high quality.
Scott: The rubber part just like had cracks in it recently, so I had to get new one.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and then I realized wait, these are so old.
Scott: I had them when I lived in Beacon.
Scott: You can't be too salty about that No, but I bought new ones and the new ones I got I guess were highest rated on Zappos or whatever And they're the kind where there's no laces or anything.
Scott: So at first I ordered the regular size, but they were all slippy.
Scott: So the size smaller and that was better.
Scott: But the inside of them is all like fuzzy and cozy like a slipper you would wear in your house But you would never know when by looking at him.
Scott: Oh, so it's like I'm walking around and my feet are like But everyone you looking at me.
Scott: It looks like I'm wearing a clunky boot.
Rym: I have like a leather boot in insert that is itself as big as an entire boot and I can wear that like a giant comfortable slipper.
Rym: And then inside of the boot is that.
Rym: but then the boot itself is like this monster.
Scott: Mm-hmm Well, they seem very good to keep my feet warm and dry.
Scott: So yeah, no complaint.
Rym: Yeah, the snow is not really a big problem and everyone's kind of freaking out about it, but we don't drive Yeah, we don't go far to work.
Rym: Don't have to shovel.
Scott: No, cuz it seems like Just it is Cold, which is fucking bullshit.
Rym: It'll be warm soon enough, but I might ski this weekend with all this snow.
Scott: I mean this climate change really some false advertising.
Scott: It's supposed to be 90 degrees.
Scott: I burned coal to make it 90 degrees in March and it has not yet to be 90 degrees in March.
Scott: I'm very upset.
Rym: I gotta see how much snow we're getting.
Rym: upstate Cuz.
Rym: actually I think the snow is coming here more than it is up there.
Scott: So just burn more coal this year Rolling your coal.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I gotta get it to be warm.
Scott: It's too cold.
Rym: So you got any anime or animation related news?
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I guess it's not super news.
Scott: This is movie.
Scott: they came out and anime movie.
Scott: They came out like late 2016 and I guess there at least I didn't notice any talking about it.
Scott: But that could just be like it.
Scott: just be me.
Scott: I think I saw this mention.
Scott: I heard it mentioned like one time.
Scott: So this is a movie that's in the sad Hiroshima genre, which is it's a genre a common genre Japanese works of all mediums obviously.
Scott: But yeah, it's called in this corner of the world and the news is that this shit is on Netflix and people didn't even fucking know about that.
Scott: So I plan to go home and watch this on Netflix as soon as I get a chance.
Rym: All right, I guess this will be our next Wednesday show.
Rym: maybe the GeekNights movie club watch this movie.
Rym: We're gonna review it soon.
Scott: But yeah, uh, it's like wow, there's an anime movie That's totally legit that you know showed up on Netflix and I the only reason I know is one person tweeted it.
Scott: one person No one else said a damn thing.
Scott: Yeah, if it wasn't for that one person I wouldn't even know and it wasn't for me.
Scott: You wouldn't even know so speak.
Scott: How did that go under the radar?
Scott: I don't I don't know.
Rym: I I Vaguely was aware of this.
Scott: in the same way There's not many anime movies that figure if any one of them is even screened Anywhere outside of Japan that there'll be like a big explosive, you know news at least in the nerd.
Rym: Yeah or in the very least we'll like find out just the way we do and get tickets and go see it because I usually be In New York, I guess we missed this until now, but we're good.
Rym: But speaking of a tweet If you don't follow Anna Twitter like Mike tool at all Darryl sir, like all those types of people Mike reminded me today of saw of a chapter of my life That was very important to me and people who were fans not just of anime but of East Asian cinema.
Scott: Well any cinema that wasn't United States in.
Rym: so you young kids might not understand.
Rym: but when we went to college It was rare to have a DVD player.
Scott: They were when we got to college freshman year No one none of us owned one.
Scott: There was a cherry.
Scott: we had VHS players.
Scott: It was a DVDs or super news.
Scott: the year 2000, you know.
Scott: DVDs I think came out in the late 90s, but people still.
Scott: they were not widely adopted in 2000.
Scott: They became widely adopted between 2000 2003 for yeah.
Scott: And when we got to RIT the ps2 was brand new freshman year the year 2000 and it had a D. It was a DVD was a DVD player, which was you know.
Scott: nowadays it's like oh, it's a bure pair.
Scott: who cares, right?
Scott: But it's like at that time it was like whoa.
Scott: I need a DVD player anyway and a ps2.
Scott: It's the same deal.
Scott: It's like a huge deal.
Scott: It's like it was a bargain.
Scott: cuz you're getting more important.
Scott: You're getting twofer.
Rym: DVD was like doubly important in that era because an anime VHS box set Tended to cost two to four times more than the exact same show in a DVD box set and DVDs on anime were starting to Come out that year 2000.
Scott: That's when they first started making them for reals.
Rym: So we didn't have any money.
Scott: There was a charity casino night that we went and gambled fake money to attempt to win a ps2.
Scott: We want all air between us and we failed.
Rym: I wonder what would happen across all our different dorm rooms if that would have been a radioactive man number one situation.
Scott: Well, the other people we know bought a ps2 at some point.
Scott: Yeah, he didn't.
Scott: so what we did and our TV was much larger and superior.
Rym: But what we did is the summer between our freshman and sophomore year.
Rym: Was this golden age where DVD players are actually really expensive?
Scott: yeah, they were like three four hundred dollars, but there was a particular brand of.
Rym: I don't want to say they were bootleg, but they were dodgy as fuck.
Scott: This was the year 2001 2002.
Scott: Yeah, not 2000.
Rym: this company called apex.
Scott: You could buy these apex branded DVD play was sort of like Vizio TVs used to be where it's like.
Scott: What the hell is that brand?
Scott: I never seen the TV like Magnet box.
Scott: Yeah, it wasn't that it wasn't like that But it was like this brand.
Scott: you never heard of suddenly producing electronics and selling him at the store.
Rym: So we learned from the early internet while we were at RIT That the apexes were special for two reasons.
Rym: one if you bought one It costs like hundred bucks 60 bucks.
Scott: Sometimes they were.
Scott: they were el cheapo crapo DVD players.
Scott: We're up until that point.
Rym: I think I would circuit city to get one.
Scott: up until that point I had borrowed stolen a DVD player from someone else.
Scott: That was actually a Sony legit one.
Rym: Yeah, that DVD player was a part of.
Scott: that was my.
Scott: that was my best DVD.
Rym: Well, we know for a fact that Scott's owned that DVD players.
Scott: That is correct.
Scott: DVD player belong to Scott.
Rym: Whatever anyone on the show even knows that.
Rym: anyway.
Rym: That's that's somebody.
Rym: if you were a fan of us in like 2005 you might know what we're referring to anyway.
Rym: So I did research and learn that if you buy an apex, not only are they cheap Not only are they shitty But it worked if y'all bought the right one.
Rym: Meaning you had to look at the serial numbers look for particular Combinations of numbers and like you had to look at the box and like figure this out I was at a circuit city.
Scott: Yeah, this was not buying on the internet days.
Scott: This was buying in a store.
Rym: like I went to stores like bigger stores wouldn't carry.
Scott: apex drove a car innocent In the suburbs of the college town to I heard to circuit city in the Best Buy to look at DVD player.
Rym: that's why I didn't even have these things.
Rym: now I heard tell that a circuit city a couple towns over had a bunch of them and They were just in their original boxes on a pallet on the show floor Which is what I needed because I had to look at the serial numbers and the version numbers and the model numbers to get this Particular one that was either region free.
Rym: We'll get back to what that means and why we cared or Was capable of being hacked to become region free.
Rym: So the reason we cared was that if you there were a lot of anime DVDs But more importantly a lot of like weird East Asian cinema DVDs that were not region one Right.
Scott: So even that expensive high-quality Sony player would not play some of it some of the easy one.
Scott: And now some DVDs were unlocked.
Scott: like we'd go to video barn and they would have a bootleg DVD that would work No matter what but but even video barn would flag like some of the movies they had.
Rym: they're like guys.
Rym: This is region to like.
Rym: they put a warning on the box, right?
Scott: It's like you needed to have this hack DVD player to watch any DVD in the world because they were all region locked.
Rym: So I it's funny because my tool tweeted about this I think ever almost everyone from this particular era of anime fandom or East Asian cinema fandom in the u.s Did the same thing about the same shitty apex DVD player because it was region free.
Rym: and then in retrospect We probably only watched like four things that needed the region freeness at any point.
Scott: Yeah, also that DVD player is so crappy had problems like overheating and such.
Scott: so we would like take the lid off.
Rym: Yeah I Burned this DV.
Rym: Well, I burned a CD and I put it in there and I did some stuff to it that hacked the firmware to make it Truly region free.
Scott: eventually we graduated to HD PC and we were still watching DVDs.
Scott: What you do is the HD PC.
Scott: you'd have a piece of software called any DVD.
Scott: Yeah, that would unlock your CD ROM some CD.
Rym: so some DVDs would just play on Computers without much effort and some you had to mess with you make it work.
Rym: I That's this whole era flooded back to me.
Rym: So if you wonder why Anna Twitter is talking about a particular shitty DVD player from the early 2000s, that is why mm-hmm in some other really tiny news.
Rym: Adventure time which I feel like we're gonna have to do a big like even a bus short series on adventure time.
Rym: once it's done done Do something it's good.
Rym: It's ending.
Scott: It is end and ending the end of all of them.
Scott: There are comics.
Scott: I don't know if the comics will end but TV show will end.
Rym: the TV show not.
Scott: they might make.
Scott: who knows if they'll make Anything else?
Scott: I don't know they could be moving.
Scott: who knows what they're gonna do, right?
Scott: It's completely unknown.
Scott: But the actual adventure time TV show the original core real deal is going to have a final episode Five episodes from now.
Rym: there is a teaser trailer up now Hinting at the what the end arc will be.
Scott: I don't know like do they mean five?
Scott: because adventure time is a weird show where one episode is like two tiny ones.
Scott: But usually it's like there'd be a tiny new one and then a tiny old one next to each other.
Scott: So is it gonna be ten tiny episodes or five half-hours like I have no Five 15 minute episodes like how long is that these five episodes gonna be?
Rym: there's so the thing adventure time.
Rym: like I really like Steven Universe, and I like a lot of shows, but I think adventure time is going to Survive and be remembered as one of the most important and influential cartoons in American animation history.
Rym: Mmm, like it's it's had a long enough run and these she's all started with that crap.
Rym: Oh, yeah, that's short that we watched at RIT.
Rym: Who knows when we watched that we watched that at RIT I remember very specifically because we were for like a week.
Rym: We were like algebraic And then we just forgot about it and then later someone was like hey, you know They turned it into a garden network TV show.
Scott: It's real like I didn't realize it like when adventure time had become a TV show Like I was like, I feel like I've seen these characters before.
Scott: Yeah, I was like I didn't quite put it together that oh that weird little one-off short somehow became a legit.
Rym: I didn't even start watching it until several seasons in and I didn't watch it several seasons in either.
Scott: But then I watched every episode up to a point Sometime, I don't remember maybe a couple years ago.
Scott: Yeah, and I was like, alright, it's gonna end.
Scott: Do you say well, I will just stop watching now and when it ends then I will go.
Rym: whoosh you're there's a lot That's happened.
Scott: I'm sure a lot has happened.
Scott: But if I think about adventure time, it's real quick to watch.
Scott: You can just burn through so fast.
Rym: but the the most impressive thing about it and the reason why I put it on such a high pedestal is that the sheer scope of Eames the end styles that it is embraced over its run is Shocking.
Rym: they're like pick any like for random seasons and watch one random episode.
Rym: They're so different You might not even realize they're the same show and yet they are all thematically tied.
Rym: Despite this the scope is breathtaking.
Rym: The fact that it's ending is actually a pretty big deal Mm-hmm, and then Scott will finally watch a bunch of this.
Rym: I don't even know how they're gonna resolve all the Jake stuff that they mean.
Scott: I you know, it's gonna be one of those things and they don't resolve everything which is dope.
Rym: Well what I want what I wonder?
Rym: I don't care if they resolve any details of the story because it's kind of like Evangelion and end of Evangelion if you cared about those details you miss the point.
Rym: It's the same thing.
Rym: what I'm wondering about is how are they going to resolve this?
Rym: cyclical almost hero of time Story around Finn on the meta level.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: There's the.
Rym: the themes are what I want to see.
Scott: We don't have to resolve it.
Rym: You just had to you know, well, I'll put it this way Where are they going to leave the overarching theme of the show?
Rym: Irrespective of the details?
Rym: because they've hinted at a lot of very interesting directions.
Scott: There's not much time left to Solidify that you can only do so much in five episodes.
Scott: However big those five episodes are.
Rym: Yep They could have just kept going forever.
Rym: Finn's been aging at a rate of one year per actual year.
Rym: The show has been produced Like he had his birthday in the show and it lines up like recently.
Rym: so I was kind of hoping they would keep going.
Rym: and when I'm in my 80s like Finn the human is like 70 something and he's just like the show is being animated by 20 year olds for your 80.
Rym: But anyway things of the day what do you got?
Scott: So this is a really kind of simple deal here, but it's a whole lot of fun.
Scott: Even though it's so simple.
Scott: It's a website and This website.
Scott: all you do is put in a URL of an image or upload an image or upload an image and It will take that image and put it on a flag on a flagpole and wave the fuck out of it.
Scott: in 3d the edge.
Scott: Oh, you can choose between Dexter and sinister hoisting yeah, and you can change the flag to be vertical horizontal left right up or down and you can turn the wind on and Off and that's about it.
Scott: And you should definitely put a good goatsey flag up there first.
Rym: You were trying to do.
Scott: how can you resist that as your first option?
Rym: I Feel like goatsey is fading from the public like internet culture and consciousness.
Rym: Yeah probably for the best.
Scott: but the point is if you need to say for example make like a YouTube video or a movie or Some kind of short and in that you want to have a scene of a flag wave I guess I don't know what kind of rights are tied to this.
Rym: I guess I don't have any right.
Scott: pretty sure you could just screen capture The box of the flag waving and scale it up to 1080p and you're good to go.
Rym: Whatever will happen if I zoom it out.
Rym: Look if I zoom in It doesn't.
Rym: it zooms the web page, but not the flag.
Scott: Yeah, that's fine.
Scott: The point is this is pretty cool and fun.
Scott: Yeah is a nice amusement for a short time and also possibly a useful tool.
Rym: So speaking animation you might remember I'm pretty sure we made this thing today a long time ago But IBM made a movie an animation like an actual animated cartoon a short.
Scott: IBM made a lot of stuff.
Rym: There's the Jim Henson IBM Movies and shit, but this was the one that was literally constructed of individual Adams Titled a boy and his Adam.
Rym: Yeah, we talked about it a long time ago.
Rym: I'm confident We did so.
Rym: my thing of the day is not the animation because that's old old news.
Rym: my thing of the day is that I found all these videos that explain in detail how the hell they made an animation with Individual visible Adams.
Scott: Well recently there was that photo of a single Adam, right?
Scott: somebody won like the the science photo of the Year award with.
Rym: so this is Utterly fascinating.
Rym: and these videos are all short.
Rym: They're like two minutes.
Rym: even if you have no attention span.
Rym: you can watch this video and learn a weird story about how IBM made a machine to literally move an individual Adam around so that they could create a stop-motion animation.
Scott: Adams are pretty small So they're good for short attention.
Scott: Yeah You can see a lot of them all at once real easily.
Rym: in the moment the book club book is the Odyssey by Homer.
Scott: So I I loaded that shit up on the kindle on my iPhone.
Rym: I start reading it now.
Scott: basically the Kindle says I'll finish reading in like 12 13 hours.
Scott: So add up poops and train rides and of 13 hours and that's what I'm gonna finish.
Rym: I think we'll do the gig the GeekNights book club on Emily Wilson's translation of the Odyssey.
Rym: a week or two after packs 12 or 13 poop train hours from now you burn through it pretty quick.
Rym: Once you start reading.
Rym: Did you start reading?
Scott: I'm rereading intro because I you know, just yeah Because I read the intro and then I forgot half the intro.
Rym: The intro is actually really good like really interesting I learned.
Scott: I'm obviously going through the intro pretty quick because it's the second reading of the.
Rym: yeah It's kind of.
Rym: it's quite good to reread it if you were fuzzy on the details.
Rym: cuz reading the actual Odyssey and keeping that in Mind is really important But it's it's good.
Rym: Otherwise, uh, if you want to go to our website right now.
Rym: You can see gig guides judge anime by its cover.
Rym: We did review the entire winter season of anime.
Rym: That's on now before it came out.
Scott: Yeah and according to the anime chart the next season of anime is starting in like 15 to 2012 between 12 and 20 days from now, so we're going to review that season very soon.
Scott: Yes, very soon like maybe you know Let's see a week or two.
Rym: But what I need you to do if you're watching this season's anime is go watch our review of this season That we made before we watched any of this anime and leave a comment to tell us if we were right or wrong about any Particular show because if you never tell us we're wrong, we're just gonna assume we're right.
Rym: If you want to see us live well Guess what.
Rym: PAX East is way sooner than you realize Ridiculous soon and we're gonna be there Wednesday Thursday Friday Saturday and Sunday and on Sunday at 10 30 a.m The third worst possible panel slot.
Rym: we are doing the top 40 tabletop games.
Rym: You must play if you want to see that panel live.
Rym: There will be some content for you that will not make it to YouTube, but we're gonna try to do the thing on YouTube.
Rym: So if you show up to this panel think of yourselves as the live studio audience.
Scott: I mean normally I tell people it's PAX you get something better to do.
Rym: don't come and see anything better to do.
Rym: It's Sunday morning.
Scott: Yeah, it's Sunday morning is actually like the time.
Scott: Maybe you could consider coming and frankly maybe if you want to know something better to do But not much not as much as other times of that.
Rym: also unlike other PAX is I like?
Rym: I've realized something with our fans.
Rym: It's real easy for people to find us at all.
Rym: The PAX is except East East is so big and so dense that There are friends we know who go to PAX East who we never bump into in tabletop at any point.
Rym: So if you're trying to find us there you're basically effed.
Rym: so this is the only Guaranteed way to find us at PAX East.
Rym: So, yeah, we went to see at the New York International Children's Film Festival as we do anime movies And one of the movies we saw is loo over the wall.
Scott: This is the like opening of the festival movie, right?
Scott: It was dubbed which I was surprised.
Rym: I didn't know that was good though.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: Yeah, we'll talk about that.
Scott: some of the characters sounded like my little pony characters.
Rym: Yeah, I did not look at who the voice actors were to confirm that but I was so sure that girl was Pinkie Pie pretty quick, maybe.
Scott: So yeah, so this is also made by Masaaki wasa who we talked about recently who did an Adventure Time short.
Scott: Yeah, we talked very easily for Devilman crybaby.
Scott: So it's like, you know this dude.
Scott: It's like wow, he's making tons of crap.
Scott: Yep, it's all over the place.
Rym: if I had to on a really high level I try to pin down what I would think of when I think of Masaaki Yuasa Things that are a little bit weird.
Rym: Yeah, isn't what I would say.
Scott: But what I noticed is he has this distinctive art, you know artistic style as most you know.
Scott: You don't tell just looking at it like it'll go a little flat a little like stretchy Usually usually what the way you can tell it's his.
Scott: the lines of the characters get a little bit wobbly Right almost like they're made with like a wiggly pencil Sort of.
Scott: and like they're like they'll deform a little bit in sort of a Picasso Esque like you take an anime character and then like you don't go full Picasso But you like slightly Picasso it with wiggly outlines.
Scott: Yeah, and that's what the Yuasa style looks like and you can see it in all his animes.
Scott: But what's interesting in Lu over the wall is most of the time?
Scott: The characters are like not drawn in that style or only have very tiny hints of his style showing through like a character.
Scott: We'll have like, you know a slightly elongated neck and you'll notice you know.
Scott: But then in scenes where appropriate where shit gonna you know goes crazy and magical and crazy things happen.
Scott: Then everything like goes like super Yuasa land.
Rym: Yeah, and it happens like that like a song starts and it's crazy crazy crazy in your face, right?
Scott: That's the visual things about this.
Scott: also it's a it's anime movie with a big budget so it looks great in general.
Rym: The only thing I'll say though if you if you think because you like Lu over the wall that you should immediately watch other things He's made like Devilman crybaby Just look at what those things are Before you watch them.
Rym: Yeah, that's what I'm going to say.
Scott: Anyway, so the second thing is I didn't know you might not know this is a musical, right?
Scott: Since it was dubbed we had all replacement music and the replacement music was It was fine.
Scott: It was okay.
Scott: Yeah, but I won.
Scott: I'm curious what the original music was.
Rym: I'll find some clips to watch in Japanese.
Scott: Yeah I wonder I don't know if it was a Situation where the music was the same and they re-sang it or if it was completely new music or not.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I believe Someone in my Twitter feed said it's the same song.
Rym: They just translated and re-sang and they I believe it.
Rym: But the vague story of this we won't spoil anything because it's an anime movie and it's good and it's big-budget.
Rym: You should just go see it.
Rym: Yeah, like if you need the short review just go see it like find a pirate.
Rym: if you have to see this movie It's good.
Rym: You'll enjoy it.
Scott: You'll probably marry in the witch's flower.
Rym: Yeah, this is like.
Rym: This is better than sort of a stranger.
Rym: Yeah It is better than many many most of the anime movies we've reviewed.
Rym: It's really good.
Rym: It's got flaws.
Rym: It's not perfect.
Scott: No, but If I it's not like a paprika.
Rym: But if I had to say like what I like about it the most on an abstract level without getting into details or spoiling anything It moves way faster than you expect it to.
Scott: well I think all Yuasa's work sort of this sort of breakneck pace where things keep moving along crazy fast and seemed disjointed.
Scott: But you can still put them together in your brain like like it'll cut to a C me Things will start happening.
Scott: You're like what.
Scott: did we just skip all that?
Scott: Like I don't understand.
Scott: and then 10 seconds later You just sort of accept it and go along with it and put it together in some way in your brain.
Rym: Yep But like if you want to say like you want a really simple sample of what that can look like watch the adventure time Episode that he did because it is literally like normal adventure time.
Scott: He also did a space dandy hips.
Rym: I think so I don't even I never finished that show.
Rym: I should mmm, but the movie also Covers a lot more ground and a lot more themes than you would expect from the first four minutes of the movie.
Scott: Yeah, I think because of the speed of it that you they fit more into it Even though it's also felt like you'll get to a slightly long, but it didn't feel like it dragged Like.
Scott: it just felt like he kept doing stuff.
Rym: at no point Do you think oh I know where this is going because you're wrong.
Rym: No, I had no idea was good and to you'll get to a plan.
Scott: It would be happy ending because it's a kids movie, but that's about it.
Rym: But it also took a pretty dark swerve that could have continued swerving.
Scott: Oh, yeah, but some of it is it's sort of like, you know It has one of those situations where there are things happening where if you really think about what's happening It's really dark, but it's presented in a way that makes it seem, you know bright for children, right?
Rym: Yep, which is part of the.
Rym: well We'll talk a few spoilers toward the end of this because I have some specific thoughts, but I don't want to ruin Interesting aspects of the movie because the fact that you're gonna have a hard time Figuring out where this movie is going is a big part of how you both how you might enjoy it the first time you watch it.
Rym: There's a lot of music in it and you'll get to a point where someone's dad shows up and you're wondering what that's gonna be Like and then the movie is just like 90 to return for a while.
Rym: It's also subtle in that there's a lot of little things that happen on screen and A lot of little things that happen in the background that if you notice them are really fascinating But you'll probably miss a lot of them right they cram.
Scott: it's weird for your move for an anime movie.
Scott: It feels like he put as many characters in as you'd have in like a TV series, but none of them feel like Flat or useless like I know.
Scott: but the screen time of some of them is short.
Scott: But you still get their idea and they complete their arc even though they're only in there a little bit.
Scott: You can make a hole.
Scott: you can make almost half a Simpsons with the amount of characters.
Rym: there's a million characters who all have a recognizable arc and all have a recognizable and Relatively complex character.
Rym: for how many seconds of screen time they have.
Scott: Yeah, like the grandpa the old lady.
Rym: Yeah There's every one of these characters.
Rym: Yeah, it's like a Simpsons carrot.
Rym: It's like moves the you get about the level of most his lack and season six seven of the Simpsons like he's there.
Rym: There's a character there.
Scott: There's a complete aside.
Scott: There's a. there's a mighty Moses like comic book coming.
Rym: what I feel like I need to read that Go ahead and buy this is like was my favorite Simpsons character for like three seasons.
Scott: Oh the comic book store again I'll be out in like a month or two.
Scott: Now.
Rym: You're thinking of a guy with two knives.
Rym: Oh, yeah But the music that not only is this a musical but it is a story about Characters who make music and characters who are invested in music and the power of music The literal magical power of music.
Scott: like.
Scott: it's not one of those things where like, you know, they talk about the power of music.
Rym: It's like don't make don't don't ever sing songs by the water cuz the fucking mermaids will come.
Rym: get you and it's true That is literally the plot.
Scott: the mermaids like hey I see you got an electric guitar there and then you play music for the mermaids and then they cast a spell and make everyone dance, yep, like Literally happens not some sort of you know, oh metaphorical thing.
Scott: It's like no.
Scott: Yep that straight up magic but The.
Rym: so the movie on a face value tells a really good kids story like for this is a fantastic Movie for a kid to see.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: I mean it was at the children's film.
Rym: Yeah, but it it is perfectly understandable within the bounds of Masaaki Hwasa and And straightforward on a direct face value reading because we talk about that a lot with you Tana and our antenna analysis show how you can something.
Rym: the the mark of good allegory is when you have a show or a movie or a work that Works completely on a face value and works completely on its higher order metaphorical or allegorical level.
Rym: this movie does that very well and The metaphors in the allegory that are addressed are actually pretty complex and some of them are pretty subtle.
Rym: it is very easy to read the simple concept of mermaids as Presented in this movie as a direct metaphor for death and loss or for immigrants.
Rym: Oh, yes, and both of those stories work entirely self consistently and do not conflict with each other.
Rym: or the face value story of.
Rym: there are literal mermaids in this town where For literal specific reasons.
Scott: Yeah, there's also, you know, this all the sub stories Right also have their own sort of like messages and arcs right all the way.
Scott: You know the smallest one being like.
Scott: there's a girl who does the PA system for the town.
Rym: Oh my god, the fact that she had her holes arc and story and the echoing came back at the end, right?
Scott: It's like she's this character You never see except for like near the end when one of the main girl like visits her for like a minute And I but you get her whole deal and she helps in the end and does a thing and this person is maybe in the Movie for a total of like two minutes,
Rym: but my man
Scott: her her story not only matters to the plot And she helps save the day or whatever.
Scott: But you know, she has like this message about like what you should you do with your life and such in meaning and whatnot.
Scott: Like, you know just her thing, you know has another message to to give right?
Scott: It's not like this one big message of the movie with everything contributing.
Scott: It's all these small separate messages that are all delivered separately.
Rym: Yeah, but they all Sort of resonate together to form a wave of like this higher-order metaphor, right?
Scott: They all they all like peak in climax and resolve together, right?
Scott: the big and one of the bigger ones is like You know this battle in the town for like trying to get more tourism money because it's a it's a small town But nothing going on and all the kids want to leave because there's no future there.
Rym: But it also peaks with the literal battle of the the old lady and her allies with spares trying to kill mermaids.
Rym: Yep There's there's a lot going on and I was very impressed with the ability for all those stories and characters to work and not feel Disjointed or distracting or plotting.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I mean, I really like this movie.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like character wise you've got like.
Scott: the main character is just.
Scott: you know, you seem sort of like a Cliche.
Scott: you see an anime a lot.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: He's the Dude, who's boring?
Scott: He's almost like Takumi.
Scott: He's really good at a thing.
Rym: He's just Shinji Takumi.
Rym: Yeah takes Shinji and Takumi mix him together talking me from initial D.
Scott: If you don't know we're talking about Yeah, really bored really good at something but doesn't care also makes but then you know discovers mermaids and is like Oh now he's got a thing going on.
Rym: Yep You know unleashes his driving power or his robot fighting power or whatever music making but he also makes all the same Very poor decisions for dubious reasons, but the reasons make sense in the context of he's a dumb kid, right?
Scott: But all the other characters are all crazy and fun, right?
Scott: So you got this main girl who's sort of wacky.
Rym: Yeah, you got.
Rym: she's like Pinkie Pie.
Scott: You got me got main energetic friend who reminds me of like Skeeter from Doug But his I guess his dad owns the is a shrine as a monk in the shrine or something like that.
Rym: Oh, yes does remind me of Skeeter, right?
Scott: Yeah We talked about the girl with the PA system.
Scott: We got the like dad who's like, you know that the go to school do a good job do something.
Scott: I love your life dad, but that dad was in a rock band.
Scott: It was a hidden past.
Scott: You got grandpa who's making umbrellas, but you don't know why.
Rym: until then you find out why.
Rym: but then that ties into Grandpa's like.
Scott: don't go messing around with their mermaids.
Scott: Grandpa clearly knows something about magic and isn't saying anything.
Rym: grandpa's umbrellas tie into the death metaphor.
Scott: He's a lot like the grandma and witches flower, right?
Scott: Oh, yeah, is that old character who is in on the magic deal, but they have the scenes they're done with it.
Scott: It's part of their past but now the young kid is experiencing it.
Rym: but they always have the scene where they see the evidence of the young kid interfacing with the magic.
Rym: and they always go like Mmm, like the knowing.
Scott: But they let it go because they know they turned out.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yep You obviously have the crazy mermaids.
Rym: the mermaid dad the giant hilarious that mermaid dad is is my second favorite character.
Rym: Yeah is so great.
Scott: You've got the the people who own like the fishing company in the town What you think is the main girls family, but to give you an example of like how?
Rym: Subtle because there's so little screen time for any of these characters to tell one of these stories that the PA system girl That's got mentioned earlier in The very beginning of the movie.
Rym: There's just this disembodied voice coming over loudspeakers Announcing like some mundane crap.
Rym: that's happening in the town.
Rym: It's like the background sound during the panning shots and the establishing shots and it's really annoying and funny Because she says everything like and today today ten here all these echoes.
Rym: the town council Will be meeting will be meeting will be and it's like really drawn out and funny this.
Scott: and it's a running jet It's a running gag.
Scott: every time she makes an announcement, but then that run you don't know.
Scott: You hear them mention the characters name they're like, oh so-and-so is making the announcements.
Rym: you never see this person another characters like Oh, she's back in town.
Rym: Wow, that's sad.
Rym: Yeah, and then not only is her arc important, but the specific issue with the echoing is both important in the Literal plot at the end of the movie and is important to explain her arc and the arc of another character To get so much value out of a
Scott: running running joke about the town being structured in a way.
Scott: There's a fishing village right and we're talking about Lou over the wall.
Rym: This is literal rock wall in the town that casts a shadow over the town almost like the historical Legacy of the town cast the shadow over the future.
Scott: I was like a legend of like the wall keeping mermaids out or something.
Scott: the shadow of the wall is the shrine at the top.
Rym: Is the only reason the mermaids even live here.
Rym: the mermaids are?
Rym: You see where I'm going with this.
Rym: Yeah, the mermaids get burnt by the Sun like vampires yep, but it's almost like the shadow of history is both Informing the town but also holding the town back.
Scott: I mean, oh well is like the easiest metaphor All time right.
Scott: walls and fire are like a two Two go-tos that are so easy.
Scott: It's like the softball is things ever?
Rym: So you should see this movie.
Scott: If you're an anime fan go see this movie kids to see.
Scott: I don't know how you can see it.
Scott: I'm sure it'll be available streaming or star somehow at some point.
Scott: I kind of want to see it subtitled instead of L dub just to see.
Rym: yep I didn't want to get into spoilers at this point because I feel like we just see this movie But I do want to.
Rym: it's not really a spoiler.
Rym: But the only thing that bothered me at all, but it did bother me was that they coded Lou the mermaid pretty young like very young child But simultaneously framed it as almost a sasami situation of technically.
Rym: She's 900 years old.
Rym: but they also coded her relationship with the main character as both childlike wonder big brother like show me the world and Romantic.
Scott: I read it more as a The.
Scott: the girl is like some sort of alien and she doesn't really.
Rym: I did too I know and the movie does go out of its way to make it clear that They that they the mermaids do not understand humans.
Rym: They are these ageless weird beings.
Rym: they are utterly alien, but at the same time she acted like a little kid and then this Much older kid was very much romantically interested in right.
Scott: well imagine of Lou is like a teenager.
Scott: that would have been also
Rym: Now if Lou was also a teenager that would have been more monster girl that would have been more much more, okay
Scott: Mmm, but then you got to start like, you know I think it'd be creepy because like then you start putting boobs on there and shit.
Rym: She could have been a little coated a little older.
Rym: but That's interesting because not really a spoiler again.
Rym: But like I said, the mermaids are very clearly also used as a metaphor for death.
Rym: like there's a scene early on where he takes Lou around and They garner an animal shelter where there's a bunch of dogs.
Rym: It is clear those dogs were going to be put down like that is obvious.
Scott: Yep, so don't to adults.
Rym: Yeah, Lou bust open the wall Turns all the dogs into mermaid dogs.
Scott: The mermaid dog is the best character in.
Rym: the mermaid dog Continues to be an important part of the story all the way to the.
Scott: yes, but the mermaid dog is the best character.
Scott: It's a cute doggie that's super excited but instead of two leggies he's got a little mermaid tail where the plushies.
Scott: I want to see them not without giving spoilers.
Rym: just trust me that there there are many points where the idea of someone becoming a mermaid is very Specifically tied to the idea that that person has died.
Rym: Yep Simultaneously that is reinforced by Lou Saving all the dogs in the shelter by turning them into mermaids.
Rym: During that scene Lou when the main character isn't looking Almost turns him into a mermaid.
Rym: Mm-hmm There is a reading of this that this kid was depressed in contemplating suicide maybe not at the point of actually consciously contemplating it but on that road and That's pretty apparent the way he interacts with everyone and the way other characters are all sort of worried about
Scott: him.
Rym: and because it's Japan Yeah, so that is the tip of the iceberg of the Interesting things to read into this movie.
Scott: Yeah, most of the situations in which the mermaids turn humans into Mermaids, you know killing saving them right our situations in which that human is in dire life-threatening danger And that's why it seems like they're saving them.
Scott: It's like oh, they're gonna die I'll turn them into a mermaid so they don't die.
Scott: or but turning into a mermaid is dying And it's hard to really like.
Rym: I promise we could back the things we're up saying up quite a bit more.
Rym: But just see the movie.
Rym: I don't want to like ruin all these little tiny details.
Rym: You'll you'll get it and it's real good and it's definitely worth seeing.
Scott: it's worth seeing more than any other anime movie I've seen in recent months.
Rym: This is the best anime movie I have seen since.
Rym: What what is the?
Rym: what's the last movie paprika?
Scott: No, you're going that far back.
Rym: What's the movie since paprika that we would say is better than this better than that.
Scott: I need to look at it.
Rym: Yeah, I did it.
Rym: Nothing immediately jumps to mind for an anime movie at least.
Rym: hmm, I Might be able to name an animated movie.
Scott: I like summer was more than this.
Rym: Yeah, I think summer wars was a simpler story.
Rym: Yes, but somewhere this is in the same level of quality as summer wars.
Rym: I'll definitely agree with that.
Scott: It's real close.
Rym: Yeah the in terms of animation It's also summary in war Z and I will say if the only way you can see this in the theater is a dub Dub is totally fine.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: game won't kill you.
Rym: the dub works.
Rym: I don't feel like I'm not seeing it.
Rym: Yeah, but the double the dub did not sound like an anime dub.
Scott: It sounded more like a character who's clearly also voiced by someone who does voice them a little pony.
Rym: Yeah, but that is still didn't sound like an anime dub.
Scott: it sound more like a normal cartoon voiceover I think for the first few minutes cuz I don't watch a lot of dubs the Disjointedness of the voices plus the mouth movement.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, it put me in that dub.
Scott: It gave me that dub feel in my body, but then it went away.
Rym: Yeah, and you know when you watch a typical anime dub that feeling never goes away.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Heidi McNicholas Sherman gruby obelisk hanging in the sky my state calm Jeremy minor link Eiji cold guy Amanda Duchette Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando Mr.
Rym: Strong stretch in four to one creations.
Rym: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Rym: Semper Fi bitch Shervin von Horrell rare Laval James David white Rochelle, Montana super boy Rym's has something funny here sailor Vista dodge like a chart a vision.
Rym: Joe Shiro Joe star Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent or open Lander Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Here's something that'll be stuck in your head for a while.