Rym: It's Wednesday February 21st 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym, I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: devil man crybaby.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I know it's a trope on the last decade plus a GeekNights for us to comment on the weather and say things like warm today, but It's warm today.
Scott: I'm like it's February 2021st.
Rym: and it's what 79 out there right now.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's 79.
Scott: I might be sick.
Rym: My phone says it is 79.
Scott: It might be 69. nice, yeah, but the Yeah, I was wearing t-shirt today walking around No code.
Rym: I went out and took a nap over lunch in the park, but just sucks that it's only a one-day deal.
Scott: It's gonna go back to being cold again at least for a while.
Rym: Yep It was someone pointed out that it was 74 like at lunchtime and tomorrow it's gonna be four to seven Which is still unseasonably warm.
Rym: It's too cold But that is unseasonably warm.
Rym: and yet apparently today broke like all-time records for hot in New York.
Scott: good Let's keep it broken.
Rym: break them all.
Rym: Yep Warming in New York only as much as the weather was not ideal the previous week when I was skin.
Rym: It's done.
Rym: now I look all the mountains are like Steaming.
Rym: it's so hot.
Rym: He's go.
Rym: skiing is basically done for the season based on this.
Scott: Oh good.
Scott: You will not die from skiing in 2017 or early 18 or I could go anyway die in late.
Rym: So there is a thing.
Rym: there's a concept called spring skiing Which is basically you go skiing and like shorts and a t-shirt.
Scott: on what fake snow?
Rym: So they're.
Rym: usually there's such a base layer of snow on the mountain like feet of it that it'll be snowy into April.
Rym: It'll just be wet.
Scott: What are you gonna be mush?
Rym: Yeah, you ski on mush down like the few runs that are left and usually you people have different words for different regions.
Rym: But there's the thing that crazy people do at the end of the season where at the end of the day They'll turn on lights.
Rym: Oh, if it's dark or they'll just do it.
Scott: lights melt the snow more.
Rym: who cares?
Rym: Not more than the Sun.
Scott: I guess not.
Rym: If you have a light that'll melt the snow more than the Sun on a wide area And what you'll do is you'll ski down like the last remaining area and Then there'll be the water at the bottom of the mountain.
Scott: you jump in like a swimming pool.
Rym: The contest is how far can you get over the water before you sink into the water?
Scott: I mean if it's safe water, yeah actually sounds safer than regular skiing because you end in some nice safe water and not in a tree.
Rym: Yeah, it's but you're wearing shorts in the t-shirt instead of all that gear.
Scott: What else?
Scott: what else are you gonna wear to go in water?
Rym: We're bathing suit Yeah, but you're not flying into the water at high spells your water skiing.
Scott: if you fly into the tree at high speed It don't matter what you're wearing.
Scott: Yeah, your winter jacket ain't gonna save your ribbies.
Rym: be good enough to not hit the trees.
Rym: That's what gladeskings all about.
Scott: looks like it hit the tree.
Scott: That's actually Microsoft Golf not ski free.
Rym: So, yeah, uh Got any news.
Scott: I do have a news and I'd say this would be a Tuesday news since it's a gaming news.
Scott: But I associate this particular game much more with the anime community in the gaming community, right?
Rym: I mean we played this game at the Anime anime club at RIT.
Rym: So is the anime club at purview over there?
Scott: There are two main games basically from the college days.
Scott: Right that were the top games and the only reason we don't continue to play these games the exclusion of all else is simply because it's Too difficult right and those games are dance dance revolution and tribes - yep Right battle check is like bringing up the third place.
Scott: Yeah, we could continue to play these games if we really put a lot of effort into it.
Scott: Actually the world shit that we finally got a world champion of DDR from America cuz konami Delivered like the newest best DDR machines to a few places Yeah, and those people like that guy just kept going to like, you know Like the Dave and Busters or whatever where he lives and kept putting quarters in that machine until we're sliding his card in that machine.
Rym: But DDR much like say counter-strike or tribes - is an elegant weapon from a more civilized era.
Rym: Right, it's pretty archaic.
Scott: Yeah, so, you know, I was very very excited like bright more excited Than to see this than I have seen than anything in a very long time.
Rym: now It's worth telling.
Rym: this is exciting in a way that all the other.
Rym: Oh, this is better than DDR games like Para-para or just dance or any of those things.
Rym: Those are not the same kind of thing is that?
Scott: no?
Scott: So I saw videos of this on Twitter and YouTube and I was like, oh my god We.
Scott: I am so glad to be alive in 2017 at the.
Scott: at the konami arcade championships I think they announced this new game called dance rush and this game is basically the current greatest technology of the money and it shows you why the money for whatever evil they are and Konami whatever is still the greatest at making rhythm games over all others because
Rym: unlike this thing is
Scott: increasing is a miracle.
Scott: I can't believe they came up with this.
Scott: I won't.
Scott: if I had money in space I would buy this two of these machines and like get rid of my bed and just put him in the bedroom.
Rym: I mean not to get into.
Rym: I mean, it's not Tuesday so not to go too deep into game stuff, but the reason why we're so obsessed with dance dance revolution over other similar games is That it was a very technical objective and explicit like dancing happened But I'm making a quote motion around it.
Rym: But really it was a game of move your feet to touch these four buttons based on a pattern that we're showing you.
Scott: Yes, and the day just happened to be large buttons under your feet.
Scott: So you have to step on them.
Rym: so the fun of it was that it was a very technically difficult game and Any dancing you could do or style was sort of tempered by the fact that you got to actually perform these motions very?
Rym: explicitly and specifically most dancing games focus more on.
Rym: You can't memorize a pattern and do that pattern perfectly unless you just straight-up dance And even then they tend to be much more subjective and much more restrictive on what you do.
Scott: So this is anyway this new game dance rush.
Scott: instead of this pad with four arrows or pumped case five arrows.
Scott: This is just this big flat surface with a shit ton of lights under it.
Rym: There was the DDR that has six arrows.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Scott: This is just a shit ton of lights and it's just a big flat surface.
Scott: Also, no rail whatsoever, yeah Standing on the dance floor and it's a light-up disco dance floor and it lights up with the rhythm To give you disco power.
Scott: and then the music plays and I saw videos of this.
Scott: There were two kinds of videos.
Scott: I saw people playing this game one kind people actually dancing who knew how to dance and It seemed like they were getting a good score at the game Even though they were actually dancing like you wouldn't think they were playing a game.
Scott: and to Someone who is clearly just trying to hit the arrows or the quote arrows, right?
Scott: Just trying just to do the instructions to get points and not trying to do any style whatsoever.
Scott: And even the person who was only trying to do what was necessary to score points and get a high score at this game Looked like they were dancing Does with less energy than the people who are unskilled and the people who are actually dancing.
Scott: When you play DDR just score points, you do not look like you're dancing.
Scott: You look like you are squatting leaning and stomping rapidly now.
Rym: It is still impressive in its own way.
Scott: Yes so here are some videos showing you how the game works and some people playing it very very well and I want to play this so bad.
Scott: Here the music and also the game has a camera in it and it takes a video of you doing your dance Which I guess encourages you to dance well, and then also adds like these cute little visual effects to the video Yeah Like little sparks jumping out of your feet and shit like that to make it extra fun.
Scott: and you can also see how the dance Floor lights up as you play, you know Because some of those effects are added in post by the video and some of them are actually the dance floor Being the best dance floor ever created in the history of man.
Scott: Too bad, I don't speak Japanese.
Scott: Maybe we can go work at Bimani.
Rym: Yeah, I Only bemoan the fact that the Golden Age of Bimani in arcades in the u.s.
Rym: Died around 2006 mmm, so I don't know where or when we'll have an opportunity to play this.
Rym: Maybe actually magfests.
Rym: DDR machines this year were a pale imitation of even like the last five mag.
Rym: What's really disappointing right is that all the DDR machines they had were these sort of like bullshitty bootleg ones with crazy latency that barely worked.
Scott: but something is really disappointing actually in that in the rhythm game department is that Getting into kpop.
Scott: There's these pump-it-up machines actually have like.
Scott: they're updated with the newest kpop So frequently like and it's like they get the music videos in there and shit.
Scott: and it's like whoa.
Scott: if you like kpops Suddenly all your favorite songs are in this machine, and it's constantly always like a song comes out And it'll be in there right away.
Scott: It's incredible.
Scott: But the arrows that you have to step on are nothing like the actual official choreographies for those songs.
Rym: And that's just well because that's the teardown from that.
Rym: is the pop in music of yeah, just fucking button.
Scott: We're just making giant buttons and subtle little ones.
Rym: hit him with your hand hit the buttons, and we're gonna play these.
Scott: beat mania Retends to look like a DJ console.
Rym: Yeah, oh my god.
Rym: I just want to play this right now.
Rym: This is I feel that feeling because you guys don't understand I can tell.
Scott: just looking at it.
Scott: This is the greatest dancing video game machine that has ever been.
Scott: there was an era as of 2018.
Rym: there was an era Or at one point one of our friends said yo I heard there's a DDR machine at some arcade somewhere.
Rym: We'd get in cars and go there to check it out And it wouldn't be there because there was no way to know short of just driving there and looking.
Rym: yep There was a rumor for like a year that the arcade and campus was gonna get a DDR machine And then one day it got one.
Rym: No it got a broken fucking pump-it-up machine.
Rym: all right Because I remember one of us wrote DDR on a piece of paper and taped it over the side anyway.
Rym: So in a very very brief news Me and Emily will put the show on the patreon because Scott didn't see it.
Rym: But to give the summary the TLDR version of my geek bite for Black Panther.
Rym: It's my second favorite Marvel movie easily.
Rym: It's real good and You should probably see it even if you don't care about Marvel movies.
Rym: I've never seen a Marvel movie.
Rym: never read a comic book.
Rym: don't know who spider-man is because it literally has no Meaningful connection to the Marvel Universe that you need to know to watch it.
Rym: It is just an afrofuturism Extravaganza, and it's real good.
Rym: but anyway things of the day.
Rym: so some of you follow me on Twitter might have noticed that I did start working on that utenna analysis show again because In the period where we weren't working on it.
Rym: Holy shit.
Rym: Do I get a lot of comments and messages on YouTube?
Rym: They're like hey, where's this like?
Rym: is this coming back and those videos actually getting a lot of views?
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: and also when I started pre-production of the next episode.
Rym: The episode that we're gonna do next is the one where nanami turns into a cow.
Rym: Okay, the dona dona dona episode.
Rym: It's probably the second most famous episode among weebs who are trying to tell people about how crazy your tenant gets after the curry episode.
Rym: hmm, it's one of those nanami episodes and Watching it for this analysis and doing the things the dona dona dona song you've probably heard it.
Rym: It's actually a pretty like long-standing kind of famous folk song.
Rym: It's in the show in Japanese, but if you want here is Joan Baez Performing the English version of the dona dona dona song Which is basically in the show about nanami and toga selling her out by way of selling out feminism.
Rym: But anyway, I digress.
Rym: This is a pretty good song.
Scott: Okay, so also speaking of music.
Scott: right recently There was a Twitter thread going down talking about Milli Vanilli and I thought I knew the story of Milli Vanilli and I did know the story of Milli Vanilli.
Scott: everything in That thread was stuff that I already knew except there was a connection between Milli Vanilli and Boney M that I was not aware of.
Scott: all the rest of the story I knew already.
Rym: Scott messaged me this and I had to go confirm cuz I didn't really believe it.
Rym: It just seemed to.
Rym: It seemed like the kind of lie you would tell me to get me excited about.
Scott: so I did not know about this one Connection right between Boney M and Milli Vanilli.
Scott: so you can find that thread on Twitter somewhere if you search for it.
Scott: Maybe Rym will put a link somewhere if he finds it.
Scott: I wasn't gonna put the effort in to find it.
Scott: Anyway, here is my thing of the day, which is related not to Milli Vanilli, but yes to Boney M. Obviously we are fans of Boney M because of the song rah rah Rasputin Specifically because of a Rasputin because of a remix of it.
Scott: in this old internet game There was a flash game called name that beard and when you had to name rest when you had to guess Rasputin's beard They played a remix of Rasputin and I cannot find that remix on the internet anywhere.
Rym: But anyway, I think I found name.
Scott: that being that beard is one of the earliest GeekNights things of the day, by the way So that I'm not gonna link to the flash.
Scott: Someone made a YouTube video of it of them.
Scott: Just playing the It's got no likes.
Rym: I'm the first person to like this video anyway.
Scott: So my thing of the day is this organ this really really old organ the musical kind not the body kind.
Scott: and This organ is a player organ, you know, you feed paper into it with cutouts and that's how it plays music automatically.
Scott: Cuz you know organs got a lot of keyboards.
Scott: It's hard for one person to play all of them at once.
Scott: so you can get a lot better music out of it by controlling Because an organ is special right.
Scott: you can play literally every key at once.
Scott: It's a pipe for every key.
Scott: You can play.
Rym: the whole well depends on how much air capacity behind.
Scott: Yeah, but the point is you can't.
Scott: Ten fingers are not enough to play the organ to its maximum capacity is what I'm saying Right, which is why you can get better music if you feed, you know use some mechanics to control the organ, right?
Scott: This organ is so old that it is old as Actual Rasputin and it is playing the song rah rah Rasputin.
Scott: So he could have Gone and listened to the music from this machine which would later then play a 1970s disco song about himself.
Rym: I Always wonder what someone like that like with the ma with with modern knowledge.
Rym: What were Ross routine think of his legacy of what we think of him?
Rym: I?
Scott: Mean, I'm pretty sure he'd be happy to be thought of at all.
Rym: In The meta moment.
Rym: the book club book is the Odyssey by Homa Translated by Emily Wilson.
Rym: I started reading it.
Scott: I read the introduction of art.
Rym: The introduction part is way good.
Rym: Do not skip the introduction You got.
Scott: when people be reading books, they're always skipping shit.
Scott: The most notorious thing is people read watchman.
Scott: don't read the not comic part.
Scott: Yeah, when you read a book you got to read all the parts.
Scott: You got to read the intro.
Scott: You got to read the four waves of sky.
Scott: we gotta read the epilogue.
Rym: when you read homestuck You got to read all those chat logs.
Scott: That's why I just don't read home.
Scott: Yep When you read a prince of nothing you got to read a glossary, yeah Anything.
Rym: I skipped over all the entries in the glossary that were so and so.
Scott: Man of the crew of the at least had to look at him to skip them.
Scott: Yeah, I had more than a paragraph though got read.
Rym: so and so man of the circumfix a glossary is on the borderline.
Scott: You don't have to read a bibliography.
Scott: You don't have to read an excerpt from another work by the same author.
Scott: That's basically just an ad.
Scott: you don't have to read the Table of contents, although that's not a bad idea.
Scott: Yeah, I guess you should probably read the dedication.
Scott: It'll take you half a second.
Rym: I've seen some long dedications.
Scott: Don't read those Self-aggrandizement, it's usually the sign of a bad book too.
Rym: But the introduction and Emily Wilson's, please don't call me out on that Odyssey is Really really good and you'll miss a bunch of stuff that you wouldn't have thought about if you don't read it.
Scott: Well, I mean cuz you know, it's something that's ancient and studied like, you know in Greek mythologies.
Scott: I don't have Greek mythology knowledge background.
Scott: So that intro is there to help me, you know, read it with the eye of someone who knows at least something.
Scott: Well, it most like you go reading the Odyssey and you're like, what is Troy?
Scott: Then it's probably not gonna be the same.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I'm kind of assuming the average GeekNights listener at least knows that much.
Rym: I'm more focused on.
Scott: I hope you.
Scott: I hope so, but some people don't.
Rym: you gotta at least know about Lega Lamna.
Scott: I love Lega.
Scott: That's my guy.
Rym: but there the context it gives that's important is sort of around why this translation is interesting and Why the concepts that we ascribe to characters in an ancient story may not be Necessarily correct to the way that story might have been read in its time.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: See also Shakespeare and how Shakespeare was actually performed.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Otherwise a bunch of our videos are on YouTube including the judge anime by its cover for the winter season.
Rym: Soon an episode of spring season.
Rym: Yeah soon the spring season as we did the winner one a bit late.
Scott: So, you know the spring one, let's see.
Scott: We're maybe like halfway through the winter season already Maybe like six weeks seven weeks from now.
Scott: We'll do the spring season.
Rym: Yep soon.
Rym: We'll have a new ten I don't know.
Rym: We got a bunch of panels like our panels from magfest panels from back south And now we're gonna be doing at PAX East 2018 on Sunday morning The 40 tabletop games you must play.
Rym: we tried it out at magfest.
Rym: It was a crazy success.
Rym: I'm changing the list.
Scott: you make a clickbait title for a panel.
Scott: They'll accept it.
Rym: get right on Completely filled the room.
Rym: the video.
Rym: people are cheering I guess.
Scott: I guess if you do it at a panel with a clickbait title It becomes a seat bait or a sit bait.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what kind of bait but what if you're on stage a masturbate?
Rym: No, I mean, we're basically just literally.
Rym: the panel is hey, here's 40 games that we thought of.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean, I think the thing is is that rather than you know, you're just doing a list, right?
Scott: It's sort of like.
Scott: what's the point of coming to this panel, right?
Scott: But the point is is that we can use this unlike other people who bait you just to get ad money, right?
Scott: We're basically like, okay We just make a vehicle to get asses and seats and then basically when we talk about the game We learn you something you can teach.
Scott: we can basically each game when we think you know Think about it for a second like oh here is the thing to actually learn quality content about this game.
Scott: Yeah, let's go to the next game.
Scott: Oh, this game has this clever mechanic.
Scott: Let me teach you about it and why it is interesting.
Rym: It's interesting watching the video of us doing the trial.
Scott: It's really less it's you know.
Scott: On the one hand the panel is like here's a list of 40 board games.
Scott: You could you that are really a plus.
Scott: you should play them maybe sort of.
Scott: but really what it is is We're gonna go down this list of 40 board games and it's basically learn 40 lessons about board games from right?
Scott: That's what it really is.
Rym: so yeah, we'll see you at PAX East and Follow us on YouTube and all our stuff.
Rym: We do a lot of stuff.
Scott: You got a lot of stuff going on.
Rym: So we watched an anime.
Rym: Scott watched it all the way through.
Rym: I watched a bunch of the beginning and I'm gonna watch the rest of it.
Rym: Devil man crybaby is making a big splash.
Scott: It already made the splash.
Rym: the splash has done sploosh But in terms of like Anna Twitter and buzz it's one of those shows where it was all over the tweets.
Scott: It was all over everything.
Scott: It was a big big deal and then and now it's still a big deal But no one's talking about it where we've moved on.
Rym: I still see people talking about it a lot in my Twitter.
Scott: So here's a deal right?
Scott: There's a guy named gonna guy.
Rym: Don't know gonna guy is gonna guy made.
Scott: the biggest things he made at least were Mazinger Z Cutie honey and Debbie the man.
Scott: now also other things but those are the big three of going a guy.
Rym: I saw Devil man, at least I like an old OAV.
Rym: I've seen devil man?
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I have seen some amount of devil man and remember the only the vaguest of details.
Rym: It was devil lady - okay But basically I don't really remember it that well because it was literally when I was a kid.
Rym: I rented Everything in blockbuster in the anime section.
Rym: So I saw a lot of shit like Armageddon and doom Megalopolis and devil man was just one of those things and all I remembered from it was it was the guy with the weird Batwing hair who fucking murdered the shit out of people, right?
Scott: Well, I knew it was a dude who was also a devil and he was fighting against actual devils.
Scott: right and there was had freaky going a guy bad guys and was very Sexy and violent as going a guy.
Scott: things are want to do.
Scott: Yeah, right and had the.
Scott: it's sort of like this.
Scott: It's you know, it's sort of like this space in between where you know Cutie honey is like, you know sexy adventuring fighting and Mazinger is not so sexy, but it is very violent and very like.
Scott: well Mazinger Is he is you know, is he devil?
Scott: or you know hero this giant?
Scott: Robot right and devil man is right in between right?
Scott: It's sort of like the combo of the two.
Scott: so devil man crybaby is a New series that is not a continuous Not really a retelling or continuation of devil of the old devil man.
Scott: What it is is a is a ten episodes TV OAV.
Rym: so Oh envy and anime news network actually introduced us to a new term just now and They call it an ONA which is original Netflix anime.
Rym: Okay, so as far as I can tell yeah original net anime.
Rym: Yeah because the deal is You know OAVs.
Scott: well, it's basically a 10 episode OAV that happens to be only distributed online and not on a physical medium.
Rym: So an OAV if you were an anime fan in the early to mid 90s or OVA if you're became an anime fan after that Was the term for anime that basically went direct-to-video as Opposed to being a like aired on network TV or getting a full theatrical release.
Rym: So there was this era where there'd be a lot of like really high production value OAVs that were like short series of anime that were a distinct project.
Rym: and there was another era of really fucking Garbo anime that were like a one episode adaptation of the first ball V's in the United States are like Aladdin to Disney sequels, right?
Scott: They were direct-to-video movies.
Scott: You can get them by buying them.
Scott: I like return to Jafar fight me.
Rym: Uh, you know what?
Rym: I'll go with that.
Rym: I remember that I see.
Rym: I saw that I see you anyway.
Rym: so Devilman crybaby is interesting because if you just go by like what people are Tweeting about it and you don't follow people who like really know about anime and are kind of real about anime You might get a and you don't know anything about going a guy.
Rym: You might have a very different impression about what the show.
Scott: the other thing is that not only did you know about going a guy?
Scott: The other important person here is Masa Masaaki Yuasa.
Scott: So Masaaki Yuasa, you might know him from doing he did an episode of adventure time and what was that first series?
Scott: he did that we that we watched a few episodes of.
Scott: Basically it is you can always tell him a sake Yuasa anime because it's stylistically like Sort of off the wall and really unique.
Scott: It's almost like the Picasso of anime, right?
Scott: It doesn't look like Picasso You know, but it is sort of that unique and sorta, you know craziness but also Okay, it's hard to describe but I mean we're gonna see Lou over the wall on Fridays.
Scott: Yes Yeah on Friday at the start of the New York International Children's Film Festival They're showing Lou over the wall, which is also a Masaaki Yuasa joint.
Scott: Yeah, whether there is other other director Screenplay executive producer for that one.
Scott: Yeah, what else has he done though?
Scott: I'm trying to remember.
Rym: I mean, he's one of those people who does a lot of like key animation credits all over the no Like when he since he started directing he's done stuff.
Scott: What has he done?
Scott: Ah Looking through all I did mind game right my yeah Yeah ping-pong the animation he did we got about that?
Scott: I can't remember but basically he's the hot shit.
Scott: Masaaki Yuasa right now.
Scott: Yeah, and this is like I guess is now like this is now the thing he's known for right?
Scott: It's like from now on when people talk about Masaaki Yuasa, they're gonna probably say Oh, yeah, the guy who did Devilman crybaby Masaaki Yuasa, right?
Rym: So Devilman crybaby You Have to be prepared for a lot of sex violence and sexual violence.
Rym: yes, you also have to be prepared for it to be really weird and really gory and May not immediately make sense.
Rym: Mmm, if you are down with all of those things You should definitely watch Devilman crybaby.
Scott: See it's weird though, right?
Scott: So there are definitely a lot of animes out there.
Scott: They don't make sense.
Scott: Yeah, and there's a lot of anime that are gory and gross And they don't make sense from beginning to end right.
Scott: you watch the whole thing.
Scott: You're like.
Scott: that didn't make any sense.
Scott: That was a nonsensical just mixed up.
Scott: No pacing.
Scott: No plot.
Scott: It was just a bunch of random shit.
Scott: Yeah, but don't man crybaby.
Scott: It's hyperfast like things are happening constantly super fast with not a lot of St.
Rym: Emily most shows will like base them like base their beats in terms of like the Physicality of action or like the reality of the situation like it'll pace itself at some Based on something in the real world or at least the real world of the show or the narrative.
Rym: But don't man crybaby just follows like the beats of the meta story.
Rym: It's trying to tell like it's gonna skip to whatever the next interesting part is Immediately and there's no there is no exposition.
Scott: They crammed a lot in the ten episodes.
Scott: and even though it's going so fast Who's that?
Rym: Oh, why is he got a gun?
Rym: Oh, I guess he's a devil now.
Scott: and even though it's going so fast and show and showing you all not a lot as You like at first it's sort of like you just have all these questions cuz you're showing you seemingly random crap.
Scott: And then like it's suddenly like comes together like as you get to like episode like later in the.
Scott: for now I'm not saying I'll watch it to the end then it comes together.
Scott: No It's like towards the end of episode one two three the pace never slows down and never shows you any more exposition.
Scott: But suddenly these things going crazy fast without stopping really make sense and come together like oh now I know who that character is finally after seeing them the third time.
Scott: Oh now I see that those rapping guys are actually part of the story.
Rym: It wasn't just oh my god those rapping guys, right?
Scott: It's like an episode one.
Scott: these rapping guys show up do this awesome rap out of nowhere And like why are they even on this doc?
Rym: Well, I thought it was Good first and then they like pans down and you see right and it's like what the hell is happening.
Scott: And then like they're there again and they're there again and then they have names and then they're doing stuff and it's like, oh, okay Now that you know, they didn't have a scene where they're like, let's intro the rap guys.
Scott: It's just sort of like they're there we tell you nothing.
Scott: But then soon enough because you've seen them enough now you're used to what their deal is and you know You don't need an explanation, right?
Rym: And it's sort of like that all the thing.
Rym: if something does not need to be explained because it's not relevant this show just ignores it and As a result the pacing is like take it take the maximum pace of ex-escaflowne Which is known for having a ridiculously fast pace and just like quadruple it.
Rym: That's what the show is like.
Rym: Yeah, so.
Rym: But as opposed to say cuz you mentioned, you know Apocalypse zero is a super gross sexually violent fucked up show, but it goes nowhere and says nothing.
Scott: So the show sort of has these two halves Sort of ish kind of like the main character.
Scott: But anyway.
Scott: so the first part is sort of like a more even though it's very sexy and very violent is a Little bit has a little bit of monster of the week action to it right where they'll be like, okay He's devil man and there's demons about.
Scott: and but he since he's devil man He doesn't.
Scott: he's actually against the demons and he's sort of hunting them down a bit, right?
Scott: So in each episode he sort of goes and finds some demons and fights them and shit goes down a little bit, right?
Scott: And the the the overall plot sort of doesn't.
Scott: the big plot doesn't advance too much.
Scott: in those early episodes There is character development that occurs and things move forward but like the big plot doesn't open up right and then I don't know halfway ish through.
Scott: I don't know exactly what episode because I watched them all together.
Scott: So it's a big blur.
Scott: Like the big plot opens up which is sort of like all these demons where the fuck they come from.
Scott: Where is their plan?
Scott: Let's see what the terrible secret of space is.
Rym: and then the very you got that opening sequence that looks like demons coming down On a planet and then it sort of just cuts into the show, right?
Scott: So Rym's only seen with three episodes.
Scott: I saw the beginning and I'm gonna wash it all 11.
Scott: I don't how many there are I think there's only ten anyway, and at the end is basically at the end is like Evangelion.
Scott: basically, right?
Scott: It has an Ava like ending After you know, but it's sort of like.
Scott: at least Ava also had that sort of Robot of the week into the big plot.
Scott: But the difference is that Ava was much more normal in the beginning in like the first, you know Five six eight sort of tricks like a lot of people who say they don't understand it.
Rym: It starts out with a pretty straightforward like there's no straight robot.
Rym: This skips over all the straightforward parts and goes straight to the not straightforward like it starts with the elevator scene in Ava and then just Immediately goes to like end of Evangelion.
Rym: and that's where that's the first episode.
Rym: I like Devilman because it it revokes for me the The weird violent shit that sort of introduced me to anime that I enjoyed.
Rym: Sometimes sometimes I didn't enjoy but it feels crazy and weird and just very different from what I typically consume.
Rym: So I like it for it's you know experimental Animation and you know, yeah And cool characters Flux would do where the camera angles are always like low and weird and then the framing is weird and characters are standing at weird angles.
Scott: the craft of it the mute the sound and Such right?
Scott: That's that's the best part of the show.
Scott: the sex and violence is there if you just like to be shallowly Titillated which is you know, well not bad literally eaten by a tit.
Scott: Sure You know that stuff goes down to this demon fighting and all sorts of stuff like that, right?
Scott: But you know the I can't give it like saying it's like the best a anime because it sort of has this terrible Secret of space big thing going
Rym: on
Scott: but at no point does it like sort of capture my Desire to know what the deal is or like, you know mystify me with its epicness Right, and I think that's actually a consequence of its of its speediness, right?
Scott: It doesn't never.
Scott: it doesn't have time to make me go.
Scott: You know feel the same way about it as I feel about like, you know, ooh, what's under nerve headquarters?
Rym: Yeah Evangelia the whole show you're like, what's that thing on the cross?
Rym: What's going on down there?
Scott: They don't give you any time just to feel like the mysteriousness of like, you know There's no scenes of you know, walking while the cicadas play for 30 seconds, right?
Rym: Like if the first angel comes down in Ava and by the end of the episode there's like 50 Ava's now yeah, so I feel like if you want, you know, this is Probably one of the best animes this year so far.
Scott: Yeah come out this year or last year.
Scott: It's definitely one of the best recent animes, but I don't think it's for everyone.
Scott: I don't For small children.
Rym: I do not know if people who are legit fans of the original Devilman would like it or not What's really great.
Scott: I don't know if you've seen these parts yet Where it actually.
Scott: the original Devilman is an anime and manga that exists in the world.
Rym: The kid keeps logging into his account and seeing the fucked up shit He's looking at but also watches that video, right?
Scott: There's like a kid and the kid is a fan of the old Devilman show and has like toys from the Gona guy old Devilman and like goes, you know, it's not like that.
Scott: So it's like.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: imagine if there was a show called GeekNights and in that show this podcast existed.
Scott: The characters were not me and but they were also making a podcast called.
Rym: So, yeah, it's.
Rym: there's a reason why everyone's talking about it.
Rym: It's a show that is just very different from the sort of typical are.
Scott: Animes like this are not made frequently also, which is why it stands out a lot, right?
Scott: While
Rym: it is evocative of that era of the like Ultraviolet OAV and American anime fandom because there was an era where that was a big part of like anime fandom here It is also much evolved from that format with a modern sensibility and modern artistry that those shows often lacked.
Scott: I mean even you know and even the parts of it that are literally just 90s violent anime.
Scott: it's like well, there aren't really a lot of those these days so I could stand.
Scott: you know You can see if you see some you know genre or era of a medium You know or whatever that nobody is making more of like.
Scott: people are still making disco music But if they weren't you could make a disco song and probably do well, so that's what this is Nobody's making 90s style violent animes so you could do well to make one and so they did.
Rym: I mean the closest thing that came to that that evoking those feelings was actually the Castlevania ONA.
Scott: But it was also a Netflix joint, but this is way better than the Castlevania.
Scott: It was okay, this is like ten times better than that.
Rym: well because this it's one of those things where the creative forces behind it Appear to be given full free rein to go as crazy as they like.
Scott: well they get.
Scott: I guess Netflix Just throws money at ship.
Scott: I don't know what reason and then they just Masaaki you I was just did what the fuck you wanted, but I guess there's a reason why everyone's talking about it.
Rym: if You are okay with hypergory violence and That kind of thing this is probably worth watching.
Rym: This is not the show to show someone to say hey check out this check out.
Rym: What anime is it is well?
Scott: There are a lot of people who are like check out what anime is and that totally worked on them it did.
Scott: if it's that Kind of person here's the thing to show them rather than showing them like ninja.
Rym: If you have a fan of someone you know who you think you could get them into anime with that weird old violent 90s Crap, but that person is the kind of person who won't watch something old.
Rym: This is your way in sure, but yeah, I'm gonna watch the rest of it.
Rym: I'm I'm curious And unlike apocalypse zero I do enjoy this To this day.
Rym: I don't think I enjoyed apocalypse zero.
Scott: fuck up zero has the same craziness, but no you don't enjoy why?
Rym: no You watch it so you know and then you know and you remember that you saw it And that's really the only reason to see it is so you know.
Rym: This is actually pretty good as long as you're okay with the things we talked about because they are all there.
Rym: And if you watch the first half of the first episode and think this isn't as bad as I expected You pretty much got to stop it.
Rym: right.
Rym: then because it's gonna It escalates apart.
Scott: you mean they get the party they get to the nightclub And that's when shit goes down the party starts a little bit Devilish and you think really all right?
Rym: This is what everyone's freaking out about.
Rym: and then you've got about 30 seconds between thinking that and going.
Rym: oh This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Rym: cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website At front row.
Scott: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Rym: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Heidi McNichol a shimmering Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky.
Rym: my state you calm Jeremy monitor link Iji cold guy Amanda Duchette Sean Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando captain Shinku Akasi for two one creations.
Rym: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Rym: So profiled bitch.
Rym: Sure If I'm not horrible James David why Rochelle Montano?
Rym: Superboy Rym says something funny here sailor vista down She likes our jobs.
Rym: and Joe Joe Joe star Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Drew openlander Finn Chris mint give Chris Knox Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: If you wonder why your name isn't being said and you think it should be said it's probably because you Specifically checked the option where you did not want a reward.
Rym: So you're listed down at the bottom here.
Rym: So I'm not reading those names because I'm assuming that was your intention.
Rym: but anyway, stay tuned on the patreon because the Rimly review of Black Panther will be up completely spoiler free.
Rym: but then we're gonna do a separate final thoughts because we realized doing it that Really got a spoiler to talk about the things we want to talk about.
Rym: so stay tuned for that and On that note stay tuned for the utenna episode.
Rym: That is forthcoming and I leave you with Complaining.
Rym: said the farmer who told you a calf to be Why don't you have wings to fly with like the swallow so proud and free?
Scott: Oh They love The whole day through and have the summer's night.
Rym: Cows are easily bound and slaughtered Never knowing the reason why.
Rym: but whoever Treasures freedom like the swallow has learned to fly.
Scott: How the winds are laughing?
Scott: They now Day through and half the summer's night.