Rym: It's Thursday July 5th 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: bike shares and car shares and I guess scooter shares cuz that's the thing.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Yeah, we didn't do a show on Tuesday cuz it rained.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and I guess we don't do shows in the right.
Scott: Well, I was home all day and then I was gonna come down here But it's like it was inconvenient to come down here with any method other than bicycle and which is true I'm not I don't blame you for that and then is raining and it's like.
Scott: well suppose.
Rym: I couldn't help but think of that Seinfeld where Jerry's trying to find out why we won't deliver with the mail cuz it's raining and it's like it was raining Neither rain nor since the first one.
Scott: but on the GeekNights is not the US Postal Service.
Scott: We never made a claim them.
Scott: Whatever will cause it.
Rym: Nor pub G update will keep us from making our appointed podcast.
Rym: But so we didn't do show on Tuesday cuz of that.
Rym: but rest assured the next Tuesday show we're talking about pub G We're gonna go because we're supposed
Scott: to do this episode about the Odyssey Which I said I was gonna read while I was on the beach and I read zero words of it while I was on the Beach
Rym: and while I would like to say come on Scott we were supposed to do the show
Scott: Zero words of it on the beach.
Rym: I read No, I read one or two words.
Rym: cuz I looked at it on my phone and then I decided that was not the time Nor was it the place to read the Odyssey and instead I closed my eyes and took a nap in the Sun.
Rym: The fireworks though yesterday from our rooftop despite all these buildings built in my neighborhood.
Scott: It's really just one building.
Rym: Yeah, well, they built all these other buildings.
Scott: None of them are in the way of the fireworks except the one that's been in the way for like two or three years.
Rym: Yeah, so there's I think there's five Macy's barges or four Macy's for we can see the fireworks from all but one of them.
Scott: Barges one two and four.
Scott: the building blocks.
Rym: barge number three, but it blocks it like a hundred percent.
Rym: It's almost funny.
Rym: It's like it's censored.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Scott: it's pretty much.
Scott: It's like this is black bar over the.
Rym: It's a good time though cuz I went running during the day.
Rym: He's a holiday don't have to work and I forgot that the 4th of July.
Rym: The neighborhood we live in or that I live in especially becomes kind of a problem whenever there's a fireworks.
Scott: Well, remember when they used to be on the Hudson River then it wasn't a problem.
Scott: I think it's time to go back to the Hudson.
Scott: We had East River we when it was Hudson River so many years in a row and I was like, what the fuck?
Scott: Why you know East River?
Scott: then they did East River so many years in a row.
Rym: It's like, all right We can go back now, but well, I guess Jersey still but The East River if you put it where they put them the maximum number of humans can see them.
Rym: They got three boroughs.
Scott: put them where they put them right now the maximum number of New York humans can see them.
Rym: I think that's exactly what I said.
Scott: No, you said maximum number of humans.
Scott: and on the other side, it would just be Jersey human seeing them.
Rym: I'd stand by my point.
Rym: But basically Everyone from the suburbs and everyone from like far out parts of New York Come to our neighborhood to try to watch the fireworks and people who live in New York know the deal.
Rym: So like you show up and cops like check your bag and they don't let you carry alcohol.
Scott: What's that?
Scott: a bort Connecticut license plate?
Scott: turn your ass around.
Scott: Yeah, you ain't parking here.
Rym: But the funny thing is the suburban people because they just I guess there's must be like some set of 10,000 people every year Who cleverly think wait?
Rym: Why don't I just drive to New York and go where the fireworks are gonna be and I'll see him real good and real close.
Scott: Get here at the crack-ass of dawn and stand in a place where they won't let you leave and you can't pee or poop unless You peep in your pants.
Rym: Ah, but more importantly you find out that you're not allowed to park fucking anywhere in our neighborhood If there's fireworks way out and take a train in just like everyone else.
Scott: Yep Actually, if you took Metro north and then a subway you probably right.
Scott: Yeah You'd be as alright as any other New Yorker.
Scott: Li has a stop right there - yeah, I'm sure it's running.
Rym: I think that one only runs on weekdays.
Rym: that aren't holidays though.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: It's a small weird stop.
Rym: It's a connection to the seven like.
Rym: I want to use it to get on the train to go places.
Scott: Where are you gonna go in Long Island?
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: Yeah, I could use it.
Scott: There's there's a there is a LIR our way to get to the LIR for the first time in my life Because we biked to the Jones Beach and then I had to get home.
Rym: I used it to visit Emily from Ronkonkoma.
Scott: Why were you in Ronkonkoma?
Rym: because I drove Lisa to be with her family.
Rym: Okay, and then I took the train into the city for a few days anyway left your car in Ronkonkoma.
Rym: Yeah, okay not taking it in the city.
Rym: But the funniest thing are all these people from out of the city Drive in and they don't know what to do when the cops are like, yeah, every road over here is closed pedestrians only Mm-hmm.
Rym: Oh and you can't park anywhere because no parking during the holiday and I don't know what to do.
Rym: and I witnessed easily half a dozen separate cars of chubby middle-aged suburban white folk Screaming at cops and demanding something to happen.
Rym: while the cops stand there There's a particular New York pose a cop has where they either cross their arms or they have like one hand on their hip and they're Not rolling their eyes.
Rym: They're not actually rolling their eyes Oh, but the eyes of the soul are rolled.
Scott: Well, I think it is.
Scott: if you're a New Yorker, it's sort of like obey and you know that would they live, right?
Scott: Yeah, I look at them.
Scott: I see their eyes going But when a suburb person looks at him, they're not moving.
Rym: Yep, basically what the cops body language?
Rym: I can translate the New York cop body language because that cop body language is I'm waiting until you stop saying words and then I'm gonna say the exact thing I just said to you again and we will repeat this all fucking day.
Scott: cuz I'm getting paid overtime and I'd literally do not care And I may put you in jail if I feel like it.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not too lazy.
Rym: But then they get clever and they think what if I just drive onto Roosevelt Island?
Rym: That's right.
Scott: when I biked home There were many cops there Barrick and they I saw actually a bunch of cars coming off the island.
Scott: So I think they may have let people on but I don't know who but it wasn't.
Scott: it wasn't like, you know a flood, right?
Scott: It's like they let some number of people over.
Scott: Oh, yeah I know what they do because at that moment just after fireworks there was Cars coming and much more than there aren't any other time I've ever gone past.
Rym: so last year I discovered the Roosevelt Island thing and I asked the cop who was standing there because it was like it's 8 a.m.
Rym: I was out for a run and he basically said we don't let anyone on the island in a car unless they can prove they live there.
Rym: or They give the address like an address and a phone number someone on the island and then unless there's a line We'll call that number right then and see if they're lying.
Rym: Mmm, and otherwise, they don't let him on.
Rym: So, yeah 4th of July the fireworks were.
Scott: you give them my phone number and name and then I'll pick out the phone and say Yes, I live on Roosevelt Island.
Scott: Yes, that is my friend delay industries.
Scott: That is my friend.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: My address is blah blah blah.
Scott: Thailand.
Rym: I think I feel like New York cops.
Rym: if you have enough of a hustle They let you get away with it because the vast majority of people have zero hustle.
Rym: if they had hustle They'd be living here.
Scott: I Think I don't think it's that they would be living here.
Scott: I think it's that you you know, there are people with respect game There are people with hustle who don't live here, but there are zero people who live here without us.
Rym: That is true with the possible exception of people who inherited their wealth.
Scott: Well, no, I guess if they inherited their wealth they live here.
Scott: They either get some hustle or they lose all that wealth to guys giving out free CD Every day.
Scott: I'm hustling Every day.
Rym: so in the news, which is if you haven't seen this story, it's tragic Fascinating said there's a lot going on here.
Rym: But in case you're unaware, I guess you can introduce is your news, right?
Scott: Okay, so in Thailand, there's this what's a soccer team, right?
Scott: I think it's yes football team a football team sure Soccer team and their coach.
Scott: they went, you know on a little field trip into this cave system And it's like a touristy cave system.
Scott: You can go explore which is totally mammoth cave in the u.s.
Scott: Yeah, I totally want to go to an awesome cave like that.
Scott: But they ran into a little problem and let me you know.
Scott: Let me explain this problem by telling you a story when me and Rym were in Australia.
Scott: we'll walk it around this island, which is a beach island, but it wasn't in season.
Scott: and We get to we see all these signs that are like can't go here between these hours.
Scott: And basically what happened is during those hours the tide came in and it was impassable Because the water came all the way up covered the whole beach and covered even more of the land.
Scott: So you couldn't walk that way unless you walk through the very thick brush of deadliness And probably poison spiders.
Scott: you had to wait for tide to be low and go out so then you can walk along the beach Right, so they went into this cave system and the tide didn't come in but the monsoons did.
Scott: monsoon came in and the rainy season came in while they were deep in the cave and It.
Scott: basically they can't get out of the cave because it flooded and it won't unplug for months.
Rym: Now no one was like.
Rym: people weren't sure if they were alive like what the deal was.
Scott: They were just missing.
Scott: They were like, oh, but they knew they went in the cave.
Scott: They just didn't know.
Scott: and it was like well, they went in the cave didn't come back.
Rym: Oh shit Yep, so basically the government sent a bunch of military cave divers.
Rym: We'll get back to cave diving Right.
Scott: It's like this is like 12 or 13 people, right?
Scott: Yeah, you could send a big old search party.
Scott: It's worth spending.
Scott: It's not like one missing person.
Scott: Yeah, the u.s.
Rym: Sent 30 experts including 17 members of the Air Force Australian Australia, Japan, China, Myanmar, Laos, all sent people.
Scott: Because all these expert people, you know who are experts at diving and such They don't really have anything better to do on the whole earth right now and they're experts at this.
Rym: So and if they succeed they're gonna save a whole bunch of kids lives, right?
Scott: So basically the Thai Navy SEALs from what I heard Went in and they found them in this tiny little area of the cave way fucking deep completely trapped by water and It's almost impossible to get them out now.
Rym: Part of the reason why the story is interesting is that the divers are there like bringing them food and all the armchair Internet people everywhere.
Rym: There's comments everywhere people talk about it always seem to ask the exact same questions.
Rym: Well, if you die if people dived in why don't they just put like scuba gear on these kids faces and dive them out?
Scott: or these People don't know anything about scuba diving.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So scuba diving is actually a super technical pretty dangerous thing to do.
Scott: That's why I will never do it.
Scott: cave diving is Insanely more deadly than scuba dive Like skydiving would be like scuba diving right and Wing-suiting yeah wing-suiting with no parachute.
Scott: It's like cave diving like.
Rym: it's weird that I know a lot about cave diving because of one specific thing.
Rym: FARC the web One of my favorite internet community other than the front row crew farm community Is obsessed with cave diving because there's a lot of really crazy stories of cave diver.
Scott: thing You do more dangerous.
Scott: the cave diving would be to do cave dive welding Dive into a cave and weld something down there.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, I guess someone dived into this cave to wet to stick this fancy metal sign into the wall.
Scott: I Doubt they welded it down there though I'm pretty sure they didn't dive in the cave to do that because the probably wasn't flooded at them.
Rym: Oh, no this this image is underwater.
Scott: Yeah It's underwater now, but no it's always underwater.
Scott: Okay, it's all.
Rym: this image is a famous sign from a site that kills a lot of cave divers and the sign basically says It's just really good sign with this skeleton, and it's just like prevent your death.
Rym: go no farther.
Rym: And then it's just like there's nothing beyond this sign worth dying for Mmm, which is true because if you go back there, it's just rocks and water.
Rym: yep And dead people yes Like a lot of the famous cave divers who have done skeletons in a with scuba tanks in a praying position yep like.
Rym: But so a lot of famous cave divers have died trying to find and bring out the bodies of Their friends who were also cave divers who died.
Scott: this is how you know something is dangerous.
Scott: Right is when.
Scott: that's why I saw about skiing being dangerous because people who are pros Olympic skiers will severely injure themselves.
Scott: skiing Right that tells you it's dangerous.
Scott: So if you if professionals at a thing hurt themselves doing a thing that is not something that a non-professional Should even go anywhere near.
Scott: so it's like if the fire eater burns his mouth on a torch.
Scott: I should not try to become a fire eater.
Rym: So the reason why they can't just scuba dive these boys out is that it would probably kill every one of them.
Rym: This is cave diving is such a difficult and technical thing.
Scott: They tried pumping the water out, but the water is coming in too fast so that doesn't work.
Scott: yep They tried.
Scott: they want thinking about drilling a hole in there But the area that they're in is so tiny that drilling in there might just collapse the whole thing and kill them all too.
Rym: And there's a basically a mountain on top of them.
Rym: like there's no good way to drill.
Scott: drilling in would be super super hard.
Scott: They're looking to see if there's a natural opening because they found a natural opening But it goes into a different area.
Scott: that wouldn't help you unless you also scuba dived yep, so So they're bringing the kids supplies right now And they're debating they're trying to train the miracle that none of the professional diving people have you know messed themselves up while bringing the supplies.
Scott: Yeah, they I've read it probably like a doctor in there and stuff.
Rym: I've read a couple of statements that the even these experts said this is an extremely difficult and technical cave dive.
Scott: Yeah, it's like when they go in there's times where they basically can't see anything.
Scott: They don't know which way is up which way is down or anything and they have to keep swimming Underwater with the scuba tank attached to you yep And make it through somewhere and some of the spaces they have to go through like I've you know I've gone in like Archaeological digs with is like certain parts you have to crawl through and it like the place you're crawling through is literally the size Of a tiny human body and you like you.
Scott: basically it's one person at a time in a straight line going through there.
Scott: Yeah, and they're scuba swimming diving through such a space that is narrow enough for just one person
Rym: Yep, and things will happen like which
Scott: is fine when there was no water in there cuz the kids probably crawled through and it was Way fun, but once it was filled with water.
Rym: There's no way through there Yep, and it's not just a danger to the kids like you might say well if the floodwaters start rising Maybe you got to go for it There's a good chance that they try to bring those kids out.
Rym: It'll kill some number of the professional divers.
Rym: Yeah, because the way cave diving accidents tend to work is if one of your people has a problem Pretty much, they're just dead, but if they're too close to you.
Rym: They'll probably drag you down with them Mm-hmm.
Scott: You can't just do something like attach a rope to the kids and pull them through either.
Rym: They're gonna have to learn cave diving and scuba diving Mm-hmm pretty quickly in dark.
Scott: assuming all these kids even know how to swim You don't even know if they know how to swim.
Rym: granted at least most of the swimming they would need There's not that much swimming.
Rym: They need to do.
Rym: Yeah, but they'd have to learn Requisite for diving though, they'd have to learn things like intermediate swimming like how to use The foot flappers.
Rym: I'm not I don't die.
Rym: I don't know any of that stuff.
Rym: I avoided scuba diving.
Scott: I actually did come up with one idea.
Scott: That's not crazy, right?
Scott: So they See is my cross eyes not rolling.
Scott: All right, so where's what you do?
Scott: you make a Tunnel out of like a plastic tube water tight.
Scott: someone posted that exact suggestion Pump the water out of the tunnel and then they can crawl through the tunnel.
Rym: Uh, yeah, I read that exact.
Rym: So here's here's the separate question for you.
Rym: Let's say someone is in like a 10-foot deep pool like not a super deep pool.
Rym: Mm-hmm and Somehow their foot gets stuck on the bottom of the pool.
Rym: Okay, could you just take a tube down and stick it in their mouth so they could breathe through it?
Scott: No, cuz it just spit all the water out.
Rym: So let's say then you give you pump all the water out of that tube.
Rym: the tube the tube Just pulled down.
Rym: no water in it.
Rym: It has a little cap that's edible.
Rym: the kid puts it in his mouth Bites the cap off and now it's just a clean path to air.
Rym: could would that help the kid?
Scott: Yeah, I think so.
Rym: No, it actually wouldn't.
Scott: why not?
Rym: because the water pressure Difference and the tube length combined would make it very difficult for the kid to draw enough air into as long as to not just Here's the thing.
Scott: I'm saying is that you're thinking that the the other end of the tube is in the water.
Scott: I'm like, no, no the kid where the place the kids are in now has air.
Scott: they're in an air place.
Rym: How many kilometers deep?
Rym: do you think they are very many?
Rym: How are you going to make a tube long enough to get through any of these sections?
Scott: It's crazier than drilling the hole.
Scott: I mean, it's less crazy than drilling the hole.
Scott: I think it's more less crazy than making him scuba dive.
Rym: Also, it would have to be rigid and unable to be penetrated by a crawling kid.
Rym: Times 13 plus a bunch of adults.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: it's impossible.
Rym: There's no material.
Rym: science would not allow this to work.
Scott: You could you could do a piece by piece to just got to attach them one at a time carefully.
Rym: No, that wouldn't work.
Scott: There's no way.
Scott: One and when you one end of it is where the kids are out in the air The other end is on the air the other side and then you can pump all the water in And then you can start crawling through.
Rym: why not just pump the water out of the cave?
Scott: It's the same because water is coming into the cave.
Scott: That's why you need the tunnel.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think you could build that tunnel.
Rym: I think it would take months to build that tunnel.
Scott: It would be hard Yeah, I mean, but that's it's gonna be hard no matter what the options are.
Rym: Also, I don't think you could build that tunnel with the constant flooding.
Scott: It wouldn't because you don't pump it until the end once it's complete.
Rym: So how are you gonna?
Rym: so Scott some of those passages are really narrow.
Rym: How is someone going to install the tunnel?
Rym: Carefully, nah ain't gonna work.
Rym: So in some other news, this is a totally sort of fun aside thing And it's I didn't.
Rym: this isn't rigorously researched or anything but inflatable tunnel.
Scott: It starts as a string and then you inflate it.
Rym: how much pressure do you think you need to inflate it?
Scott: enough a Lot, but you know.
Rym: and how thick does it need to be so that it doesn't get punctured?
Scott: Listen, we got to invent it.
Rym: Yeah, I think we might just invent like a teleporter or something first.
Scott: I don't think it teleporters a little harder or a brain scanner.
Rym: We just scan the kids brains and then leave them there.
Rym: It's even harder print new copies of the kids with all their memories up to that point and just tell them they survived.
Scott: I just nuke them out and then we can drill a hole.
Rym: Feel like that might make a collapse Maybe on the kids.
Rym: maybe so in some other sort of side news.
Rym: if you're not aware of the dada movement of art a big part of it is that It came out of the sort of like artistic reaction to the horrors of World War one itself a product of the logic and reason of the middle-class capitalist society that birthed it.
Rym: and I don't want to get into like the history of dada or anything in detail.
Rym: here seems like you do though I do but I don't want.
Rym: I. I want to but that's not what this show is about.
Rym: And also if we go for more than say five minutes I run out of knowledge and I'm in over my head and I will drown.
Scott: and the Internet is someone who knows about art history.
Scott: Come down on Rym who is over his head and is drowning in a tunnel with no.
Rym: So this is a tweet that has a nice thread behind it where basically there's some article that was like why is millennial?
Rym: Culture and humor so surreal and dark and weird and meaningless.
Rym: and I'm just gonna read this tweet.
Rym: This is called dada and it first emerged in the wake of the First World War out of the belief that a society that could Create such a horror had no intrinsic value.
Rym: Replace First World War with modern capitalism and there you go.
Rym: so this is an argument and the thread gets into a lot more details and I actually Googled around a little bit and this is not a new revelation and this is being discussed in art circles Currently by people way smarter than us about how the weird millennial culture and internet bullshit that I like For example, all that nonsense is very reminiscent of the dada movement and has many parallels in terms of the things happening in society that might be driving it.
Rym: so this is my defense of potato conditions.
Scott: This is so Rym because it is a post-hoc explanation, which is the key aspect of Rym ism.
Scott: Well, most explanations are post-hoc because the world quantum theory in the world in and of itself is a post-hoc explanation of post-hoc Explanations, which is metarim ism.
Rym: Yeah, cuz you don't even have any free will you're just rationalizing things You already did so your entire consciousness is nothing but a post-hoc rationalization of things you did probably randomly and that is not just one that you see.
Scott: Post-hoc explanations are a core tenet of Rym ism, but that is the core tenet of written.
Rym: But the parallels are very interesting because honestly the current state of late-stage Western capitalism is Pretty fucked and we're really starting to see that it's gonna destroy society.
Scott: We have an ism without a late-stage.
Scott: It just just keeps working.
Rym: I mean so far late-stage.
Rym: democratic socialism is people mostly have health care.
Rym: Like so far so good.
Rym: but anyway things of the day, so this was making the rounds.
Rym: if you didn't see it it is Utterly delightful, but basically in I think Edmonton this couple a man and a woman try to rob a convenience store and it goes Hilariously poorly.
Scott: it goes way bad like it.
Scott: look this the thing is the cops are doing a bad job, too.
Rym: Well, cuz there's only one cop and he's trying to.
Rym: he's based.
Rym: This cop is really trying to deal with the situation without inflicting undue harm or killing anyone But he's also trying to arrest these people forcibly.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like this cop honestly should have used more force earlier.
Scott: Yeah, just whack him on the head with a stick.
Scott: But that's the problem is in the UK.
Scott: the cops got sticks.
Scott: They just whack you on the head.
Scott: Yes a taser - it looks like I thought as a gun and I think I thought he's.
Scott: I thought the reason he wasn't shooting It.
Scott: cuz he's gonna kill somebody if it was a taser.
Scott: You should have shot it right away.
Rym: yeah, well in this case probably.
Rym: but basically if You watch this video without knowing it's real you would assume it's from a TV show like that is the level.
Scott: Yeah, it is from a TV show.
Scott: It's called cops.
Rym: Yeah But it keeps alternating between the dude in the front having this really hilarious standoff with this derp cop and meanwhile in the back his girlfriend is trying to sneak out and Has multiple attempts of sneaking out of the building all of which end of disaster.
Scott: Oh, I remember the one that I saw which is better than yours is the one that is mashed up with Metal Gear Solid.
Rym: Oh, I did see that one.
Rym: That was really good.
Scott: That's the one that's better.
Scott: So you should post that one because it's better than yours.
Rym: So my thing of the day is that this video.
Rym: you've probably seen it.
Rym: It really made the rounds.
Rym: My thing of the day is that people are mashing this up with all sorts of different music.
Scott: Metal Gear one's the best one.
Rym: The Metal Gear one is the best one.
Rym: Yakety Sax is the obvious one.
Rym: I haven't even.
Scott: I only thought of Yakety Sax one.
Scott: I didn't actually see one but I did see the.
Scott: I'm sure it exists.
Rym: And the Lupin the third one works surprisingly well.
Rym: So, yeah, you can enjoy this.
Rym: so what do you got for me?
Scott: So, you know, there's a. there are Jews have a lot of different levels of you know, observancy, right?
Scott: There are people who are only barely Jewish and there's people who are very very very Jewish.
Scott: Right and the ultra-orthodox and Hasidim in their neighborhoods around the world.
Scott: Some of their neighborhoods are known to be unfriendly to outsiders.
Scott: So if you were to if they were to see you in public, you know disobeying their laws I mean, perhaps you were a woman not wearing enough clothes or you come into their neighborhood But you're not a person that they like.
Rym: I've been yelled at by people in a certain neighborhood in Brooklyn biking there.
Scott: Right, they will do things to you.
Scott: Like some of them will throw tomatoes at you, right?
Scott: This is a real thing that happens.
Scott: So here is an animated gif and the title of the animated gif is ultra-orthodox men drenching sweet innocent girl in bike lane because you know, they there's a. there's a sweet innocent girl biking through their neighborhood and That is exactly what this video is.
Scott: 100%.
Rym: this is a good video and you should watch it and you may enjoy it in the meta moment.
Rym: the book club book Probably not next Thursday, but the following Thursday isn't gonna be a GeekNights next Thursday.
Scott: Yeah, I think with two weeks.
Scott: I think I can get this done.
Rym: I think it's not a long book.
Scott: We are going to talk about most of the way done already.
Rym: Yep, Emily Wilson's modern translation of the Odyssey by Homa.
Rym: It's fantastic.
Rym: We keep talking about it.
Rym: Just read it.
Rym: You could probably start it today and finish it before us.
Rym: Yes It's not long and unlike the translation you read in high school or middle school much more readable.
Scott: It's Not full of ye olde fancy talk.
Rym: it's enjoyable Directly and at face value even if you do zero Analysis and don't worry about any of the metaphor and also the forward gives you all the analysis you possibly need.
Scott: Yeah, where I don't even know what we're gonna talk about other than just repeating what the forward says.
Rym: Yep I think I'm mostly gonna talk about how my opinion of Odysseus himself has changed.
Rym: Yeah, and Also all the slave stuff.
Scott: Yep That's in the forward.
Rym: yeah that that is in the forward but it really hits home when you're reading it Mm-hmm, like especially the knowledge you get bit cuz she's got a lot of slaves like a lot.
Rym: otherwise, uh We are going to be at Pax West.
Rym: you didn't buy a badge for it.
Rym: Well, that sucks.
Rym: Good luck I'm pretty sure.
Rym: only Monday is not sold out.
Scott: No, I mean if you live close that buy one of those Mondays Mondays totally available.
Scott: still you don't live close do not buy what.
Rym: if you live within like a Couple hours trip if you can drive there.
Rym: Yeah, yeah or take like a train there.
Scott: Are there trains ago?
Rym: Yeah, dude I did.
Rym: there's an Amtrak that goes from Seattle in Portland.
Rym: I've used it multiple times.
Rym: Okay It's actually really really pleasant and actually really cheap.
Rym: But anyway, uh Monday at Pax West you might think oh, I don't want to buy the last day.
Rym: It's short, right?
Rym: It still goes to like 6 or 7 p.m.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: It still has an expo hall and it has a Omegathon finale.
Rym: Yeah, it has a thing that only happens on that day.
Rym: so uh Pax West is coming up in 56 days 17 hours 29 minutes and Dateline this episode right now three seconds and then after that there's gonna be other conventions the rest of the year like PAX Unplugged.
Rym: Yeah May NYC Magfest right at the beginning of the new year and then right from there into PAX South and then the cycle starts again Coming up really soon though in New York City.
Scott: When is it?
Scott: It is the 14th of July So not this weekend, but the next weekend after that.
Scott: now Is going to be the game developers of color Expo in?
Scott: New York City in the Schomburg Center, I think right?
Scott: That's where it is.
Rym: That's where it was last.
Rym: It's a really great con.
Scott: it was worth it to go for a few hours Just like we went last year and I saw like of all the in.
Scott: You know the places are people showing off, you know video games and indie games that they made.
Scott: That was the best one that I've seen way better than those sheeps meows and stuff.
Scott: I saw real good shit there.
Scott: So It's worth it.
Scott: If you're in New York, that's Josephine this picture.
Rym: I think there's pictures of our all our friends here.
Scott: Okay, but yeah If you're in New York City It is worth it to go there for a few hours during the day to check out the awesome games there.
Rym: Yep, and also You know, I'm not saying you should do this.
Rym: This is not a GeekNights thing or anything.
Rym: But unless it's like pouring rain Me and Scott and Emily and a bunch of our friends are gonna do.
Rym: the Harlan Valley rail ride Which we talked about we did it last year is the best bike ride.
Scott: It went on last year.
Rym: It was it's way fun and There is a version of it for literally all levels of skill.
Rym: if you can make a bike go forward without falling over You could do one of these rides and the smallest one 28 miles 28 miles something like that.
Scott: Yeah, that's gonna take a slow person like my mom like four or five hours 23 33 45 57 72 hours Probably three hours for a normal person.
Rym: a hundred and the I'm not doing it a hundred.
Rym: There's two centuries one of them.
Scott: just I'm doing baby hundred.
Rym: I'm either gonna do baby hundred or 72 because I don't know if it's 72 last year though.
Rym: Yeah, I might do it again.
Rym: It was real fun.
Scott: I'm gonna do baby hundred and if for some and it's like I can definitely finish it.
Scott: No problem But there is the escape hatch.
Scott: right it's like but the only the only question is it's not.
Scott: will I finish it?
Scott: It's will I finish it in time?
Scott: Cuz I don't go I don't have a puff.
Rym: So I have enough.
Scott: if I don't finish it in time I'll just hop on the the escape vehicle.
Rym: I think mostly it's.
Scott: I gotta probably make it at least 80, you know Whatever the time limit is.
Scott: Yeah, I could do the 80 instead of the 72 Mmm, I think the problem is it's like.
Scott: it's like only eight miles more.
Scott: Why would I do 72?
Scott: It's because the 80 has way mad crazy hills compared to the 72.
Scott: That's why those eight miles are hellish.
Scott: eight miles They tack on.
Rym: the hundred is from the regular.
Rym: hundred is probably easier than that 80.
Scott: That's why I'm doing the regular baby hundred the leg saver hundred is what they call it.
Rym: But the cool thing is basically what we do is we take like Metro North up there with our bikes and other people drive Or whatever and we just can't for free just in this park in town and you can go up as early as Friday night.
Scott: now They changed it.
Rym: I think we're gonna get there Saturday morning.
Scott: I think Saturday Time we went there Saturday afternoon.
Scott: That was too late.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like Saturday late morning is the perfect time to get there.
Scott: Yeah, hang out go to sleep early get a good rest.
Scott: That way you can wake up early and bike right away.
Rym: Yeah, and if it's you me and Emily and our friends, we should eat at the more expensive tapas place.
Scott: Mmm, who knows if it's any good though.
Rym: I looked at some reviews.
Rym: It seems like it's good.
Rym: It seems like the only complaint people had was that it's way expensive compared to the cheapo Italian place.
Scott: We hit it.
Rym: Mmm It's one of those places that like New Yorkers take the train up for a nice bed-and-breakfast Weekend and that's the place they all.
Scott: it's a little town that has nothing going on.
Rym: Yeah that's why I don't want to get there the day to restaurant town because I Don't think there is a second day's worth of stuff for us to do.
Scott: there is biking and enjoying the nature.
Scott: That's what you do up there.
Rym: Yeah, but if we're already gonna bike and enjoy the nature an additional day Let's do it extra.
Rym: Yeah, I guess we just bike around.
Scott: There's a lake there.
Scott: You can swim in.
Scott: Yeah Didn't see probably mad full.
Rym: Oh and there's something new this year.
Rym: There's gonna be a hot shower truck Last year, I didn't get a shower till I got home.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So you might hear this word.
Rym: like Silicon Valley tech pros use this word a lot If anyone ever tells you that something is really is already old hat.
Scott: I don't think they use this anymore.
Rym: the sharing economy Yeah, so they still only care about coins.
Rym: Yeah, well coin crypto the crypto coin sharing economy.
Rym: But sharing economy is one of those phrases like cryptocurrency Where if the person who says the phrase is not making fun of it, they're probably a person to avoid.
Rym: Yes, and We're not gonna talk about the like intrinsic problems of the sharing economy Like why uber is evil because you should know by now we talk about it kind of often.
Scott: But I got a whole thread in our forum about uber here on our evil day.
Scott: Yeah, so we're not gonna dive in how the other uber like companies are not as evil but are also evil.
Rym: Yep We're not gonna get into how all these things just exist and not have to pay people a living wage or give them Health benefits and it's all a giant scam.
Scott: cuz that doesn't have to do with the sharing part.
Scott: that has to do with being an Evil business.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So we do those things with or without having a sharing business.
Rym: So there's been a bunch of news in on the coasts and in the middle of the country - weirdly About all these bike sharing scooter sharing car sharing things that are not uber and lyft though Some of them are becoming lyft right or uber.
Scott: Well, the idea is that you know back in the day you would if you needed a thing you could buy that thing You could rent that thing at least that thing, right?
Scott: You could borrow that thing from a friend.
Scott: But the sharing idea is like well a company owns the thing and you basically you rent it but you rent it for a very short time and actually what you do is you buy some sort of membership and Then you can use that thing whenever and it's like well, that's what a gym is that?
Scott: that is exactly what a gym is.
Scott: it's a room full of machines and You pay money on a monthly basis and then you have free to use those machines as you wish Except here instead of having one, you know place full of stuff You just have the stuff all over the fucking place.
Rym: now the theory of that I'm actually really okay with partly because long as it's a non consumable good.
Scott: So it's like you could have.
Scott: you know, for example, you don't have a straw sharing service, right?
Scott: It's like hypodermic needle sharing service.
Scott: For example, we have laundromats, but you go to laundromat you pay per use.
Scott: What if there was a chain of laundromats and you could wash all the clothes you wanted in any one of the laundromats as long As you pay a monthly fee, I would be all over that.
Scott: I know why don't we start that business?
Scott: Maybe we should but I mean basically people have used this model for basically transportation mostly bicycles cars Yeah, bicycle.
Rym: Go back to the gym example.
Rym: In the suburbs what people tend to do is just buy everything they want because they don't want to share it with people and they Want and they have places to keep shit.
Rym: Yup, and I've noticed that there seem to be two reasons.
Rym: But half the reasons people do this are They don't want other people touching their stuff and they don't want to interact with those people.
Scott: But the other half the reason you live in a suburb with a house that's far away from the street is they don't to interact With other human beings because you're antisocial and bad.
Rym: You got a hundred houses and ever and then in those houses are a hundred treadmills and a hundred weight machines.
Scott: Yeah You can tell.
Scott: if you look at a neighborhood if you see houses that are up on the street and are close to each other And have porches.
Scott: that's a friendly neighborhood where people talk to each other and have good times.
Scott: if you see a neighborhood We're all the houses of gates or have real long driveways and big ass front yards And no porches.
Scott: That's a bad neighborhood where people though are not friendly.
Rym: Don't talk to each other Yeah, but I like the idea like in the city like I could buy exercise equipment.
Rym: That'd be stupid.
Scott: Where are you gonna keep it?
Rym: Where am I gonna put it?
Rym: This apartment's tiny.
Rym: So instead people in cities just share things with each other and Usually you have to charge a reasonable amount of money or else because you have to have one You know group that maintains all the somethings.
Rym: Yep But there are some problems with it because if you have sharing things that are free or cheap enough What tends to happen is really common things just get trashed.
Scott: tragedy of the come.
Scott: Yep So the general business model at least for gyms is that you people are paying this monthly fee But you've only got so many Treadmills at your gym.
Scott: if everyone who paid came all at the same time to use a treadmill You wouldn't have enough treadmills.
Scott: you'd be in deep shit.
Scott: The reason it works is because you have people who pay who never fucking come but they keep paying and you make a lot of Money that way because you don't need to buy that many treadmills.
Scott: You don't need to rent that much commercial real estate.
Scott: Yeah You know you can.
Scott: just you can.
Scott: your expenses are at way low compared to the number of people who join and keep paying and forget to cancel and They join and they use it a whole bunch.
Scott: when they first join in January for New Year's their resolution And then the whole rest of the year they pay and only but in July.
Scott: only hardcore people are there and most of the gym is empty and you're totally chillin.
Rym: and it's always funny because there's a gym in my building and It's pretty much exclusive to me because like no one's ever down there.
Scott: Yeah everyone in this building is Technically in their rent paying for the maintenance and upkeep and equipment in that gym and Rym is the only one using it Every year.
Scott: building makes a lot of money by having it.
Rym: Emily uses a lot too, but every year for about three weeks after New Year's I can't go down there because it's completely full of people and by February.
Rym: They're all gone and it's my private gym again.
Rym: I Think maybe four or five times ever other than January if I gone down there and there wasn't a treadmill to use Right when I wanted to use it.
Scott: Did they have a fake not moving bicycle?
Rym: They got one of those.
Rym: I actually use it cut off it in the winter.
Scott: That's the only gym equipment.
Rym: with you I like lifting weights.
Rym: I lift a lot more weights than I used to.
Rym: You feel you feel a lot better.
Rym: if you lifted some weights I can lift my mouse.
Scott: so here's the deal.
Rym: in New York City We had a thing called city bike Which I signed up for and so did Emily.
Rym: like we all used it I didn't sign up.
Scott: I didn't sign up for it until they put it right next to my house some months ago And then I signed up for it.
Rym: Yeah, and you might ask like less than a year ago, Roman Scott Why did you use this thing?
Scott: You actually my new my new job gives me free membership But I can't take advantage of that and so my current membership expires And it's actually already become a very very critical part of New York's commuting.
Scott: even though I own two Bicycles for one person I use city bike a lot.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And the reason I use it though I use it.
Rym: I don't have a membership right now But I'm thinking about getting it again now that there's one right outside my building one been outside your building longer than been outside My building true, but when I first signed up it cost less than half what it costs now.
Rym: So I signed up because it was so cheap.
Rym: It was also cheap Yeah, but it is more than double what I originally pay.
Scott: It's like a hundred something a year.
Scott: Yeah, I used to pay like I pay more than that for the subway for a month.
Scott: true And I probably use city bike more than he is the subway this month But I'll keep.
Scott: I decided I'll just keep paying the MTA the full price every month because I'll subsidize it.
Rym: Yeah, I can afford to whatever and also I like the freedom of never Yeah, but When they originally made the bike share in New York City this city by thing the deal is that the bikes are awful.
Rym: They're like 55 pounds and made out of steel.
Scott: They vary a little bit.
Scott: They're not all exactly the same.
Scott: Some of them have different shifters and stuff like different lights.
Scott: There's a little bit of variance But for the most part they're all bikes where the there's no top bars, you know It's so you can eat you can step in real easy.
Scott: You adjust the seat.
Scott: You can't take the seatpost out.
Scott: Alright, they all have about three speeds inside of a one of those internal gearing like.
Scott: what are those called again?
Rym: Oh the hub gears hub gears.
Scott: They have all of at least three speeds on a hub gear, right?
Scott: They're heavy as hell.
Scott: The tires are enormous.
Scott: There's really really slow and really hard.
Scott: But you know what.
Scott: I can bike it over the bridge.
Scott: I can bike it anywhere.
Scott: It's like I can ride it pretty much anywhere.
Scott: I need to go.
Scott: the worst bike It'll get you there.
Rym: the worst bike the shittiest scooter is still infinitely better than walking.
Rym: Yep So when they originally did it we got a lot of like.
Rym: there was a lot of resistance to it mostly from all the Garbage scam companies that rent bikes to tourists in Central Park Yep, and all the bike shops who are worried that people won't buy bikes anymore and won't rent bikes from them.
Rym: Well, they were all wrong actually But I saw something that something like 30% of all bike shops in New York went under since city bike opened.
Scott: Oh, well deal with it.
Rym: Yeah, I don't get.
Rym: even the bike shop right here is gone.
Scott: Now is it because the city bike though that bike shop?
Rym: I think it's gone because this neighborhood gentrified very rapidly.
Rym: Yeah, and you can't make a lot of money with the bike shop.
Scott: No I mean, is it the Ben's best deli out in Forest Hills?
Scott: matter business and they blame the bike lane on Queens Boulevard.
Scott: Yeah, right and it's like even so.
Scott: here's the thing right with that.
Rym: Let's say let's say they're right.
Rym: I don't care, right?
Rym: It's likely more important than any business, right?
Scott: Exactly It's like all right.
Scott: If it is probably not true that the bike lane put you out of business the reason you're awesome Judelli, which has amazing food that I want to eat went out of business.
Scott: It's because that food is expensive and people don't really eat pastrami sandwiches every day like they used to.
Scott: Right, but let's say it was the bike lane that put you out of business.
Scott: Well, guess what since 2015 when they put that bike lane in Queen's Boulevard Previously known as Boulevard of death has had zero people die zero, which means putting in that bike lane absolutely Undisputably.
Scott: save somebody's life at least once probably more than once.
Scott: Which means if you if you're complaining about that bike lane putting you out of business What you're saying is that we should murder people to keep Ben's best deli open in which case I say, all right Let's murder Ben's best owners children to keep Ben's best deli open.
Scott: that'll save him the money He needs to spend on their education.
Rym: He might be like, okay win win.
Scott: Well then, okay, I Can't argue with someone.
Scott: Is that evil?
Scott: But yeah, you you see where I'm going?
Rym: Yeah, but what's interesting is that city bike was sort of aimed at tourists and the reason why they doubled the price And like change the business because tourists did not.
Scott: I do see tourists using it.
Rym: I do see tourists using it but not enough.
Scott: almost everyone who used it was like me and New Yorkers are using it and paying The annual fee.
Scott: it's like a hundred something annual fee.
Scott: But city bike as much as you want and I think I can describe the three reasons people use it.
Rym: reason number one They're trying to get cross town.
Scott: Yep, if you don't know in New York the public transportation Which even though it runs 24/7 and even though we complain about it still is way better than other places To the point where you can actually use it Doesn't really go left and right.
Scott: it only handle is in Manhattan.
Scott: It mostly goes up and down.
Scott: so if you're in First Avenue and you want to get to 10th Avenue, you can find a bus or Walk or use a city bike and city bike is absolutely the fastest way in no matter what.
Scott: Yeah, no matter where you're standing and city bike is the fastest.
Rym: The second reason is to get to places.
Rym: the subway doesn't serve that well, right?
Rym: You're somewhere out in Brooklyn or like Kips Bay or something.
Scott: Yeah, kiss bays a good one, right?
Scott: It's like well, you need to get to the train.
Scott: Well, the six trains pretty close, but you got to walk to the sixth train.
Scott: It's gonna take you like 15 minutes, but if you city bike to the sixth train, that'll take you like two minutes Yep.
Scott: And so you can get to a place in Manhattan or even anywhere in New York where the trains nearby But not super nearby like even my apartment.
Scott: I could walk to the train in under 10 minutes.
Scott: I can city bike to the train in less than two minutes.
Scott: I use it just to go to the train.
Rym: and the third reason I think a lot of people use it is when there's a Subway problem.
Rym: suddenly you see people running out of the subway station and all the city bikes are gone.
Scott: last night when I went home From the fireworks, right?
Scott: So it's.
Scott: I went out of the apartment and I felt some drops and I checked and they were not air conditioner We're random water drops.
Scott: It was rain.
Scott: So I said well, it's raining So I'm not gonna city bike which is usually the fastest way home from here.
Scott: And I saw that the end train up above was messed up.
Scott: There was a fire and I saw a message on my phone that said he was messed up.
Scott: So I went.
Scott: and anyway if it's raining the bus is better because the bus goes right to my apartment and then doesn't mean yeah I don't have to walk in the rain.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So remember I said that the the train is like 10 minutes walking, right?
Scott: I don't want to walk 10 minutes get wet.
Scott: So I went over to the bus and a bus came.
Scott: It was 100% full.
Scott: I couldn't get on it.
Scott: the bus driver closed the door.
Scott: Yeah Like I tried to get on the bus start the bus driver was like no mo.
Scott: So then another bus does not come.
Scott: it just doesn't come.
Scott: people are packing it up in the in the station hiding under the scaffold and no buses come.
Scott: none.
Scott: and Cabs come and I'm not paying one of one of those new.
Scott: not for no reason.
Scott: and then I realized wait a minute It's not fucking raining.
Scott: So I walked to the nearest city bike and I pull pull it out and that's got a fucking front flat tires front the front.
Scott: The front tire is flat and I was like god damn it.
Scott: I put it back in and I try to push the repair button to which will lock that bike in place and no one can accidentally take it and will let them know that it needs fixing.
Scott: and the repair buttons broke.
Scott: So luckily that doc had one other city bike at it.
Scott: That was not broken.
Scott: Yeah, and I took it and went home.
Scott: Without that I would had to like walk all the way down 21st Street to get home.
Rym: So the more like it is why we talk about city bike so much.
Rym: is that in our experience as New Yorkers?
Rym: It is 100% a success story.
Rym: It is actually one of the better things that's happened to Transportation in the city in a long time, right?
Rym: It is now.
Rym: it is so important now that a city bike outage Gay like it is as dire to some people as a subway problem or a bus problem.
Scott: Yeah, I mean like.
Scott: there are times they're all like, okay, I go to the end train.
Scott: It's busted.
Scott: Well, if I can get to you know, where Rym lives I can get on a different train like our train or whatever.
Scott: right, but I got to get there and Everyone else is already running for the bus.
Scott: Yeah It's like.
Rym: also how many people like I know who say bike is a critical part of their commute.
Rym: Usually they take a ferry because we have a new ferry system, too And the all and all the ferry docks because they're on the water kind of out of the way.
Rym: There's a million city bikes Mm-hmm and people take the ferry and take the city bike because you don't want to take a Your own bike to.
Scott: the ferry does not go.
Scott: the ferry goes near my apartment.
Scott: It does not go near my work.
Scott: So if I were to take the ferry on the other end, how do I get to work?
Scott: There's not any subways near it on the other end.
Scott: Yeah, you have it, but there is a city bike dock right there next to the ferry terminal on the other end.
Rym: So why is city bike so good and so well run?
Rym: because New York City?
Rym: Basically wallet technically a private company runs it.
Scott: New York City just got bought by Lyft.
Rym: Yeah, we'll get into that.
Rym: New York City Came down on this thing like a hammer and said oh you want to build this in our city We gotta follow our rules.
Rym: and they're basically running it like it's an extension of the subway.
Scott: They just put it everywhere.
Scott: It's everywhere.
Scott: It's spread.
Scott: You know, it's not.
Scott: it's not really everywhere, but this is in fact in my raccoon wounds.
Scott: They spread it a whole bunch.
Scott: You can't walk without seeing one.
Rym: The docks have a ton of bikes on them I see when I bike to work.
Rym: I see easily hundreds of people on city bikes also biking to work.
Rym: Mm-hmm granted.
Rym: I bike to work on my actual bike because I have a bike.
Rym: Yeah, I have one too and I have a bike room in my office.
Scott: I don't use city bike to go all the way to work But like if maybe I take the subway to work Yeah, then I take the subway here to do a podcast and they'll use a city bike to go home.
Rym: exactly I I've even paid one off.
Scott: so I'm not gonna use a city bike to go home today because I have my real bike here.
Scott: Yeah Yep One of them.
Rym: and also it makes it really accessible to people who can't afford to own a bike people who live in apartments too small To have bikes or don't want to worry about their bike and stolen.
Rym: Yep People who just didn't bring their bike today and now it's nice out.
Scott: That's me.
Rym: That is often me, right?
Scott: So the idea see the thing is you can see how When you had this business model of you had you own stuff and then people pay a fee to have access to the stuff whenever It can totally work, but it keeps.
Scott: different companies keep implementing it in ways that are Slightly or very very evil, right?
Rym: So I think this comes down to regulation.
Rym: No, the only reason the New York one works so well, is that the city heavily regulates.
Scott: We talked about the gyms and how they do and that's only slightly sketchy, right?
Scott: It's like it's your fault for buying a gym membership and not using it.
Scott: But you know, they could remind you that you're not using it and tell you to cancel, but they're not gonna do that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But then you get the companies like the uber who take it to the maximum evil where it's like.
Scott: you're sharing this car This well this show.
Rym: you're sharing this exploited chauffeur.
Scott: It's a chauffeur and a car and people are sharing it, right?
Scott: It's the same idea Except yeah, they pay the chauffeur basically nothing.
Rym: Yep And they ignore regulations and there's all sorts of problems.
Rym: Yeah, so The other thing about these city bikes that they have docks there.
Rym: They're like a subway station or a bus stop.
Scott: There's a dock and the bikes had you get your trip has to start and end at one of these locations.
Scott: otherwise you get charged an arm and a leg for stealing the prick holding the bike too long and You have to.
Scott: if you're a tourist you got a dock every 30 minutes that you can go for more than 30 minutes.
Scott: You're even without paying again, you just have to dock and then take another bike or the same bike again.
Scott: I if you're not a tourist you have an ant.
Scott: you pay the annual fee.
Scott: you can do 45 minutes But then you got a dock and then take a bike out and frankly you're not riding this more than 45 minutes, right?
Scott: Well, they're doing it to make sure.
Scott: why did they do this?
Scott: to make sure that you don't bike way far away from the docks.
Rym: Yep, you got to keep it in the system relative Oh, and if you don't leave the bike in a dock and it gets stolen they charge you like thousands.
Scott: If you don't dock within 45 minutes You just start racking up the fees and if you never put it in a dock again, you can get charged $1,200.
Scott: Yeah, so don't fuck it.
Scott: So there's all these startups and ever I whenever I slam the bike in the dock I always wait for the notification that it was confirmed to dock before before I walk away.
Rym: So there's all these startups and things trying to do like more clever bike share scooter shares a thing now or electric bike shares And most of them are ignoring regulations like if someone tries to do an electric bike share in New York Electric bikes are illegal here.
Rym: Anyway, yep, so that won't fly.
Scott: But the arguments we made about whether they should be and stuff like that, but I think they should be but they should be heavily regulated.
Rym: So then there's these companies like lime and jump that are basically trying to do the same thing Depending on the city.
Rym: they're doing it without the city's permission and they're just leaving bikes around with no docks that have like GPS trackers and Self-locking hubs and they just leave them on the fucking sidewalk.
Rym: And if you buy their at you use their app, you can just leave the bike wherever.
Rym: they'll just take care of it Mm-hmm, and it seems like what's happening is people are just picking these bikes up and throwing them in dumpsters Leaving them in people's lawn just leaving them all over the place.
Rym: Some cities are actually just rounding them up and throwing them away like garbage because They never the companies never got permission to actually do anything.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: what's this random bike?
Scott: Just sitting here on the sidewalk.
Scott: That doesn't belong here.
Scott: It's taking up sidewalk space Right, and the thing is what they're doing.
Scott: really that's wrong is it's not that oh your bike share doesn't have this docking mechanism?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: that's not really the problem.
Scott: yeah, the problem is is that you're putting this bike on a sidewalk that is public property and using it that public property as the land of your private business without Compensating forward or getting permission and you're just getting everyone's way.
Scott: It's like, you know, if you want to set up, you know, a little a little vending stand in the sidewalk.
Scott: There's a whole bunch of rules about that because you're taking up this public space for your private business and your private profit.
Scott: You know, you're not buying real estate or renting commercial real estate, you know.
Scott: It's like I can't just go outside and like just set up a studio and in the public park and be like, oh it's mine now This is my space now.
Scott: It's like no, it's not your land.
Scott: It's public land.
Scott: So when you put your dockless bikes out there, you're putting them on this public land.
Scott: I don't belong there You didn't?
Scott: you know, you're not compensating the public for your use of that land for a profit.
Scott: get the fuck out.
Scott: But the docks even though they're you know, taking up this space It's like.
Scott: well the DoD like said you could.
Scott: they Specifically got rid of parking spaces to put docks there.
Scott: more
Rym: importantly by regulating them heavily the city's basically treating them like infrastructure And as a result they get the right level of attention respect Regulation and control to make sure that the system serves the purpose of bettering the lives of the people in the place as opposed to Monetizing some start-up that's paying its employees probably in stock.
Scott: Yeah So the DoD in New York City did it actually are going to legalize and give permission to the dockless one.
Rym: But it looks like they're doing it are out neighborhood.
Rym: They're doing it the same way.
Rym: they do with the green cabs.
Rym: If you don't know in New York yellow cabs are the real regular cabs.
Rym: they work Medallions.
Scott: you should not get in a cab that is not yellow.
Rym: Nope, but well you can get in a green one.
Rym: Yes, because the green ones if the green one will let you in the green ones are special.
Rym: They work totally like a normal cab in New York except they cannot pick anyone up in Manhattan.
Scott: yep, so and they can't pick you up in an airport either.
Rym: Yep, but it cost way Less to ride them and way less to get a license for them, right?
Scott: So if you want to have if you want to drive a yellow cab It needs to have this medallion on it.
Scott: and the price of the medallions have gone way down because of uber being evil.
Scott: Yep But the yellow cabs are legit.
Scott: So you shouldn't ride any ubers or lifts or any of that garbage.
Scott: You should get any yellow or green one.
Scott: But if you're in Manhattan a green one can't turn on the meter because the GPS lock not to work when the car is in Manhattan you can they can drive you to Manhattan.
Scott: They just can't drive you when they're already in Manhattan Yep.
Scott: But the idea was well Look, there's people who want it.
Scott: you need a cab who are in Queens the Bronx Brooklyn far away.
Scott: No, yellow cabs are coming over there, even though they come near me And those people need rides and there's not enough yellow cabs.
Scott: So we'll allow pretty much anyone To make a green cab and but we'll make it so the green ones don't compete with the yellow ones and such and such.
Rym: Yep, so in terms of car shares cuz you know, I've talked about this before I used to use a car.
Rym: I ditched it because it's garbage now.
Rym: But the reason car shares have really failed to work in major cities Like every definitely can't work in a suburb.
Scott: Everyone has a fucking car.
Rym: Yep You have to have a car to live in the suburb.
Scott: The only people who don't have cars in the suburbs are the kinds of and even if you do live in it if it's suburb Without a car that how you gonna get to the bike share.
Scott: It's I mean to the car share.
Scott: you're gonna bike there.
Rym: It's far away yep, and also I suspect the people who live in the burbs don't have cars are too poor for The company that's running the car share to be able to successfully exploit them.
Rym: so in the city the car share was great because the only reason anyone in New York wants a car share is To be able to rent a car to leave the city for a weekend without having to talk to a human being right?
Scott: There's no way.
Scott: if you're living the city You don't need a car except when you're leave going on a somewhat longish trip.
Scott: You don't need it.
Scott: within the city We have public transportation.
Scott: Yeah, like we had all this other stuff and you're going to another city.
Rym: You don't need it.
Rym: You just fly or take an Amtrak right or a bus.
Scott: Yeah if you're going from a major city to a major city you don't need a car.
Scott: the times you need the car is when you're living the city and You're going to a suburb.
Scott: like I'm gonna go to the I'm gonna go on a trip to the woods or you know Something like that that and the train doesn't go where I'm going.
Scott: I need to go visit someone who lives out in Long Island and they're not near the Long Island Railroad And it would take me four hours to bike there and if I took the long on railroad I'd have to take a cab from the train station to them.
Scott: Anyway, that sort of that's when you need a car for someone who lives in the city.
Scott: So that's that's when you want.
Scott: one is only of those occasions But I car.
Scott: usually you're gonna end up taking the car on Friday after work and bringing it back late on Sunday.
Rym: Yep so you no one can make money having car shares in the cities because one No one really needs a car for like a couple hours in the city unless they're moving in which case they probably just rent a.
Scott: Right, so you basically all the cars that would be shared would be sitting there unused.
Scott: Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday disappear on the weekend And then on Friday, there wouldn't be enough of them.
Scott: Right because they're taking up space like that.
Scott: parking spaces cost the money right.
Scott: the cars just sitting there cost the money.
Scott: They're not being used.
Scott: you're losing money every day of the week.
Scott: those cars just sitting there They're not integrated into the transport system.
Scott: The city bikes outside are constantly going in and out and in and out in and out.
Scott: all the data is public.
Scott: You can look at every city bike ride and see how they get used a ton.
Scott: These cars are sitting there five days of the week not making any money and then all of them get used exactly once for three Days, that's when all the money comes in and then they get parked again.
Rym: Now you'd think because when they first I remember when they first did it They put these zip cars at a lot of the Metro North stations way up north The idea being you come out of the city you pick up the zip car Do your thing whatever you're doing upstate in the woods and bring the car back to the sit to the train station when you're done.
Rym: But even then that wasn't enough because most of the people who need a car in that situation Tend to drive it somewhere and want to leave it there like for their commute Which again is not part of the transit system, so it won't actually work, and you can't easily monetize it.
Rym: and on top of all that Uber and cabs seem to have filled the gap of.
Rym: someone needs a car to take them somewhere.
Rym: It's easier to take your evil uber to the Costco and from the Costco Then it is to rent a car from a car share to do it yourself.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So I think what you have to do to make this work is You would need to find a some other way to make money from those cars Monday through Friday.
Scott: right maybe get some shitty hotels.
Rym: you can sleep in them For 40 bucks.
Scott: I think what you could do is you could have people do you know?
Scott: Uber-type driving with those cars Monday through Friday, and then on Friday They that driver has to park the car by a certain time You know maybe like two or three and then it becomes Rented to the person who's gonna take it out of the city and they had to bring it back by Sunday And then Sunday night, then then the person can start driving it again.
Rym: Ah, but here's the problem with that.
Rym: for hire the thing city city bike Irrespective of its monetization because I'd be fine if the city just ran it for free with our tax dollars.
Scott: but it's the same other way.
Rym: it achieves a meta purpose of Adding more transportation to the city like it improves the quality of life of people in the city.
Rym: Anything that puts more cars on the road decreases the quality of life of people.
Scott: right well I think the idea is that hopefully this would decrease cars on the road if it works because You're gonna you have cabs driving everywhere already right.
Scott: so this is going that one that uber driver Just replacing it as already an uber driver.
Scott: Who's just gonna be doing this instead and it's gonna work on the weekend right.
Scott: and then There's someone out there in the city who owns a car and only uses it a few weekends and all the other weekends It's parked and not moving all the rest of the time.
Scott: Well, maybe you can convince that person if this exists and hasn't.
Scott: there's actually enough cars And the price is right that they could sell their car and then use this instead and that would decrease the total number of cars Because just one of these shared cars could replace how many owned cars?
Scott: Yep, that are only used on the weekends, but at the same time.
Rym: The another way you could go is the model of people who own cars and use them usually could could Go into some sort of compact with other people like time shares on their own cars.
Rym: That's a model people have tried But that is something people have tried.
Scott: the problem is people own cars for some reason don't like other people driving them Which I can see.
Scott: even if there's all kinds of insurance and stuff.
Rym: It's like you know I've seen the way other people drive And if I own a car I would never let fucking anyone drive.
Scott: But I mean and even if it's no skin off your back if they crash insurance just buys you a new car.
Scott: It's not your fault.
Rym: Oh, yeah, true But then I don't set out upright that I might not have the car right after they crashed it or they might make it smell like pee.
Scott: Yeah, well you know insurance has to cover all those or handle all those problems.
Rym: Yeah because one problem with all that like the city bikes and those kinds of bike shares is that They are treated with the same respect that people here treat the subway.
Rym: They there's a reason they're 55 pounds because otherwise they would all have been destroyed.
Scott: You know I haven't seen people vandalize city bikes.
Rym: No Why don't?
Rym: early on when they first appeared there was a bunch of vandals and then it just sort of stopped.
Scott: I feel like what we could do is like take a city bike and then we've got you know Like we can.
Scott: if you keep docking and undocking it we can just like paint it real nice Not like like you know put artwork on it, and then put it back
Rym: Unauthorized, but I mean that's technically vandalism, but yeah,
Scott: I mean you know a lot of street art is that kind of end?
Rym: That is true.
Rym: All right, I think we killed enough time.
Rym: okay good This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website At front row.
Scott: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded Live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver Allen Joyce Rebecca Don I'd even Nicholas shimmering rubiobolus caning in the sky kashar tovish in my state e.com Jeremy minor Link Iji Roberto Kingsley Kelly Snyder cold guy Amanda do sheds Sean Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando Mr.. Strong stretching for two and creations.
Rym: no I never ever wonder why we're here.
Rym: semper fi bitch Shervin von Horrell Rory James David white Rochelle, Montanona Superboy tripwire sailor Vista dodge like Jojo Joestar Clinton Walton Renford New Zealand Ryan Payne drew up and Lander Finn Chris midkiff Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Now I leave you with something that will haunt your ears Another day another destiny This never-ending road to Calvary.
Scott: These men who seem to know my crime will surely come a second time one day.
Scott: Thanks for interrupting.
Rym: how can I leave when we are apart?
Scott: Oh one more day out on my own One more day with him.
Rym: and not care.
Scott: Life I might have known and I swear I will be true, but he never saw me.
Rym: Oh One day more one more day to revolution we will.