Rym: It's Wednesday, May 16th, 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights tonight Aggretsuko.
Scott: A much better idea.
Rym: The anime.
Rym: Not the board game.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: But like we were just saying in the forum, it seems like the way the ticket to riches on YouTube is to hoot and holler and be an angry jumping up and down monkey about something.
Scott: Go ahead.
Rym: Some sort of clickbait nonsense.
Rym: So is it time for the clickbait?
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: Actually, we got a bunch of news.
Scott: That time doesn't come.
Rym: We already got one person watching here.
Scott: That clock never rained.
Scott: Ever.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, we skipped the show on Monday, even though the Google Duplex is a fine topic.
Scott: It's a fine news.
Scott: It's not a total show.
Rym: I think it's a topic.
Rym: I think the use of technology for me to avoid ever having to talk to someone on the phone again is very important.
Rym: And I look forward to this future.
Scott: I didn't say it's not important.
Scott: It's just not 30 minutes of a show.
Rym: I think there's 30 minutes of a show if we get into why people are so freaking afraid.
Scott: Anyway, today's Wednesday.
Scott: Leave your Monday.
Rym: You got any anime related or comic related news then?
Scott: There's tons of anime and comic related tiny news is out there.
Scott: So like there's gonna be a Galaxy Express live-action TV show.
Scott: Why?
Rym: Yeah, well, there's a bunch of live-action shows coming lately.
Scott: I noticed it seems like either there's more live-action shows lately based on anime/manga or we're just seeing just more reporting of it in the English anime news, meaning animanewsnetwork.com is reporting on it more.
Scott: Yeah, also, you know, like, like, you know, back in the day, we wouldn't hear about the stage play production of whatever.
Scott: But now I'm seeing, like, updates on, like, the cast of every single YoA Pedal live-action stage play.
Scott: that happens.
Scott: And it's like, why the fuck are there so many live-action YoA Pedal stage plays?
Scott: Who the hell in Japan is going to these?
Scott: Who's paying to make these?
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: What's fascinating to me, and this news is actually from summer of last year, but there was a news that was very recent where some interview happened, and that's how I learned that this exists.
Rym: I guess I just didn't notice.
Rym: They're making a Marmalade Boy live-action film, and what's fascinating to me about that is that Marmalade Boy was very well known among American anime weebs in a very long time ago.
Rym: In, like, the early 2000s.
Scott: Yeah, nobody who's an anime fan from, like, 2005 on even knows what the hell that is.
Rym: Like, it's weird to me how big it, like, just the assumption I had that literally anyone I talked to who watched anime.
Scott: I thought it was an obscure, forgotten show that only, like, certain way-deep people even knew existed or cared about.
Scott: I never even watched an episode of, I just know of it.
Rym: I watched a good bit of the show because the RIT Anime Club had not one, but two full VHS sets of this show because it was so fucking popular.
Scott: And I said, "Yeah, I don't feel like watching that thing,".
Scott: and then apparently, like, the memory of this still exists for someone, and someone's putting actual money to make a production of this in the year 2018?
Rym: I mean, in a midst, like, in an anime weeb fandom in the 2000s, like, everyone knew about this show even if they didn't watch it, but even then, it was a little weird to me.
Rym: Like, it just seemed, like, standard, like, "Oh, people know this show,".
Rym: but thinking about it now in light of modern anime, the plot of this show makes it extra hilarious.
Rym: Do you actually know the plot to Marmalade Boy?
Scott: I thought it was, like, a generic shoujo romance deal.
Rym: Yeah, but do you know the deal?
Rym: Like, what the shtick is?
Scott: I didn't know it had a shtick.
Scott: I thought it was generic.
Rym: Alright, I'm gonna read, 'cause it's summarized here.
Rym: In the story, Mickey's parents announce that they are getting a divorce.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: And swapping partners with another couple who have a son of their own.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So the mom, they basically, the parents of these two kids swap who is married to whom.
Scott: I've seen that.
Scott: That happened to a, there was a Major League Baseball, two players swapped wives.
Scott: Oh.
Scott: That's a real thing that happened.
Rym: And the plot is that the two kids fall in love.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: And the meta-plot-- Isn't that the plot of Clueless, only without the parents swapping?
Rym: Yeah, but I see, only without the parents swapping.
Scott: I mean, it's just, I think the mom died and the dad married someone else, and then she was in love with a stepbrother, right?
Rym: Yeah, but just the parents swapping.
Rym: And also, the show had a lot of AMVs back in the day, like the anime.
Rym: Like, it was a show that just people made a million AMVs to.
Rym: And the AMVs always focused on the fact that basically the dude just sort of stalks this girl, and it's really creepy, and it's extra creepy.
Scott: Is that what happens?
Rym: Uh, sort of.
Scott: I mean, it's kind of easy to stalk someone when you live in the same house.
Rym: Yeah, even in the chat here, people are like, "I vaguely heard of Marmalade
Rym: Boy.".
Scott: How would you even know that it's stalking if they just, like, if Emily was stalking you, how would you know?
Scott: Like, how would it even... Your behavior would change, not at all.
Rym: In fact, I remember, I have, I still have it, when I won that contest at RIT Anime when I was a freshman, and the tape Nazi gave me that curated set of CDs in a box.
Rym: that was a box set of, quote, "important anime music
Rym: videos.".
Rym: Remember, it had, like, that color cover and, like, the insert and everything.
Rym: This creepy-ass music video to this show was on those CDs, and I have it to this day.
Rym: So, yeah, I don't know why they're making all these live-action things lately.
Rym: Is it just the, are they mining old properties that are cheap to get?
Scott: There must be people in Japan who are going to see them, and I'm guessing the production value of them is not very high, so I think they're being produced cheaply, quickly, and there must be just enough people there paying for it.
Rym: Whoa, so, apparently there was a sequel to Marmalade Boy that I didn't know about called...
Scott: Marmalade Boy 2.
Rym: A Marmalade Boy Little.
Scott: Parents swap back.
Rym: Marmalade Boy 2, it turns out you're actually brother and sister.
Scott: Marmalade Boy 2, they got married, and then they themselves swapped with two other people.
Rym: They swapped with the opposite parents from the other side of the other relationship.
Scott: When they swapped, it was gay, so she got with the wife from the other.
Rym: Oh, in a parallel universe.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Apparently, there was a 2001 live-action Taiwanese series.
Rym: Just, I never thought, after the year 2005, I never thought I would say the words Marmalade Boy again, except in making vague references to old anime no one remembers in panels.
Scott: For some reason, right, in, you know, in the United States, it seems like there's some properties, right, that sort of, they have life.
Scott: They're big enough to be repeated and repeated and repeated.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Voltron can get, you know, is like the sort of, I guess, the bottom level.
Scott: If you're Voltron and up, you can get repeated, remade, and whatever, but things below that basically have no chance to be remade, brought back to life in any way whatsoever.
Rym: I don't know, though, look, I mean, I've seen a lot of rumblings over the last four or five years about mask getting brought back in some fashion.
Rym: There was that comic.
Scott: Sure, but, you know, it seems like in Japan, and, you know, the anime manga properties, like, even these obscured small ones can somehow get revived, and, you know, things can happen to them.
Rym: I mean, if I had to guess, there's two ways to go.
Rym: On one hand, it might be older IP is cheap, and thus easy to just take a seat and use to adapt or do something with, or two, maybe something that was really big a long time ago, even if it's forgotten by the average fan, might have had enough of a critical mass of an audience back then.
Rym: who remember it.
Scott: Oh, well, that's the Utena level, right?
Scott: Where it's like, it was done, but because it was big enough, it can be, they can make a new manga volume or put out new merch on the anniversary or something like that, right?
Rym: I mean, if they announced that, like, B-Pop has reformed to make another Utena movie or something, I'd freak out and be all over that.
Scott: Right, but, I mean, you know, you look at some, what's this, like, a small insignificant anime?
Rym: Marmalade boy?
Scott: I mean, even smaller.
Scott: Fushigi Yugi?
Scott: Yeah, like, that's, how can they possibly bring that back?
Rym: Yeah, I feel like if Fushigi Yugi ever comes back, I'll eat my hat.
Rym: I'll buy a tiny chocolate hat and eat it.
Rym: So, in some other news that's comic related, not anime related, I only saw the headline, Scott seems to know about more about this, but-- I know vague details.
Rym: Stan Lee is apparently suing his own company for a billion dollars?
Scott: Right, so I don't know, the billion dollars is crazy, I think, File the lawsuit in excess of a billion dollars, that's on CNN.
Scott: Basically, Stan Lee, if you don't know, like, the Marvel Comics dude, right, you know, whatever you want to think about him, you know, he has their positive aspects to what he has done for comics in America and as a person and whatnot, you know, and basically, he does a lot of stories about him lately, right?
Scott: There's some, you know, because he's an old cranky man.
Rym: So,
Scott: you know, I've heard some, like, stories about Stan Lee that I've heard recently, it was like, A, I've heard stories about him being, like, a kept person, like, since he's an old man, like, I heard stories from, like, I guess, maybe his daughter or something that, like, people were, like, keeping him and controlling his, you know, monies and whatnot, you know-- Which is
Rym: not uncommon.
Scott: Right, because he's so old, he can't do anything about it, so he's sort of semi-prisoner.
Scott: I've heard stories about him, like, Me Too kind of stories because he's an old man, like, you know, being naughty to, like, the nurses who take care of him and stuff like that.
Scott: I've heard those kinds of stories.
Scott: I don't know how true any of this is, but the new story is there's a company called POW something, right, and this company is, like, legit.
Scott: So, basically, Stan Lee, obviously, you know, while Marvel will still use his name and pay respect to him as, you know, an important person in their history, and I think a lot of Marvel-- I don't know if Marvel Comics still say, like, Stan Lee presents at the beginning, or have his name on them anywhere.
Rym: I don't actually know, yeah.
Scott: They used to, but he's not actually, like, work for them anymore.
Scott: I think he has, like, some, you know, like, in-name position, like, emeritus something, something, but he doesn't have any actual, you know, official job there.
Rym: Oh, wow, yeah, here.
Rym: The complaint states that Duffy, the former business manager, whatever, took advantage of his grief over the death of his wife last year and his poor eyesight to basically get him to sign a power of attorney over to then take control of his assets.
Scott: Right, so he had this company, POW, and POW actually produced stuff, good or bad, that, you know, was sort of, I guess, the stuff that they made felt like stuff that was marketed a whole bunch, at least in the nerd community, because Stan Lee's name was attached to it, but no one actually seemed to care about, like, those-- I remember way back, like, I went to New York Comic-Con.
Scott: That's how long ago this was, and they had, like, this comic Ultimo or something that was sort of like Stan Lee's Astro Boy of some sort of, it was weird, and no one cared.
Scott: It didn't seem like anyone actually gave a shit about it, but it had some, like, this big marketing oomph behind it relative to what it was, and they produced a couple other things as well.
Scott: There was, like, an anime they made that actually got made that also, you know, all the stuff that they made, there were, like, three or four properties, had Stan Lee's name attached, had more marketing dollars than it seemed like they warranted, and it seemed like no one cared about them, but I don't know how successful they actually were, and, like, this company actually did stuff, and it seems like now the company has, like, been sold to this Chinese company, which is totally a legit Chinese company that makes all kinds of stuff, but it seems like Stan Lee did not actually approve of that, and other weird things related to this have happened.
Scott: For example, recently, like, just now-ish, he tweeted on Twitter.
Scott: He's like, "This is the first tweet ever from actual Stan Lee on this account.
Scott: Someone else has been controlling this account the whole time.
Scott: Can you help me get my Facebook account back?
Scott: I don't have any control over
Scott: it.".
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it's like, "Huh.
Scott: All right.
Scott: That's
Scott: weird.".
Scott: So, yeah, lots of stuff going on in the Stan Lee department.
Scott: The main thing that surprises me is simply that Stan Lee is still alive and still not Alzheimer's, doesn't seem to be mentally unstable despite being, like, 90-something.
Scott: He's way old.
Scott: He is really old.
Rym: If I appear to be doing as okay as he's doing when I'm 90-something, yeah, I'll take it.
Scott: I'll take it.
Scott: I will take it.
Rym: If I can walk when I'm 90, I'll take it.
Rym: Hopefully, I'm going to be- If I can walk and I know my name, I'm all good.
Scott: My goal is just to be able to bike when I'm 90.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Might be easier to bike.
Rym: You might not be able to walk, but be able to bike.
Scott: Well, there's people who have, is it Parkinson's?
Scott: Or something?
Scott: One of those body disorders, right?
Scott: Where you can't control your body so well.
Scott: I saw a video where those people who had this- With the patterns?
Scott: I don't know which one it is, but they get on a bike and suddenly they're like, "Do, do, do, do,
Scott: do.".
Scott: They get off the bike and suddenly they're shaking.
Rym: There's a whole crazy field of study where regular patterns, I don't want to get into, it's not a Wednesday topic, but there's cool things.
Rym: People are just on glasses that do an AR overlay and show lines that move with you as you walk, and that allows people who have certain kinds of disorders like that to be able to function normally.
Rym: It's kind of cool and crazy.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Rym: So in some other news, part of the reason why we bailed on the show on Monday was that Emily and I were out of town.
Rym: Emily every year, because she is a writer and comic artist and does all those things aside from video games.
Rym: She goes to TCAF every year to hang out with other comics friends.
Scott: And also because it's close to her parents' house and it's convenient.
Rym: Yeah, and it's usually around Mother's Day and Toronto is a pretty fun city, but I could never go because every year, right around that time, there's something in Hong Kong that I always had to do.
Rym: This year is the first time in like eight years I don't have to do the Hong Kong thing.
Rym: So I went to TCAF for the first time.
Scott: It doesn't feel like you've been going to TCAF for eight years.
Scott: Has it really been that long?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: All I know is I have been going to this Hong Kong thing for eight years and it's always been on this time.
Rym: This is the first time I could have gone to TCAF.
Scott: And let me tell you, you could have gone nine years ago.
Rym: So you know how, but back then I think I had mocha.
Rym: Mocha isn't really like, I like mocha, but it doesn't scratch.
Scott: It's been decreasing over time.
Rym: Yeah, TCAF felt like the peak of mocha if that trajectory just kept going up.
Rym: TCAF is really great.
Scott: I know that it's great.
Scott: I've heard SPX is great also.
Rym: I'm not going to say you should fly to it.
Scott: Right, that's what I'm saying is it's still even as great as it is and which I totally believe.
Scott: It doesn't feel like the kind of thing where I would go for more than, you know, I walk around it for a few hours and then I'm done.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So even we'll see the reason we go, we walk around it for a few hours, but also all our friends are doing panels and the panels are actually really good.
Scott: And it still doesn't feel like it's worth going all the way to Toronto.
Rym: Unless you're going to also make it a Toronto vacation.
Scott: Like if I somehow made a comic, I would totally go.
Rym: Or you go, but do something else.
Rym: Like we also went to the hockey hall of fame and like went and saw a hockey opera called hockey noir.
Scott: I've heard of that.
Rym: We saw it.
Scott: I didn't know that it was coinciding.
Rym: It was there because it had some ties to TCAF because it was like a comic.
Scott: So you get to go to Canada.
Rym: So Emily and I went to this opera.
Rym: We're going to do a Patreon review of it.
Rym: It was, I really enjoyed it.
Scott: All right.
Rym: But it was both, it was corny on purpose.
Scott: I imagine.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Like there's this narrator who keeps coming in.
Rym: He's the PI and it's very film noir.
Rym: So there's times where he just like, sometimes there's ice.
Rym: Sometimes there's black ice.
Rym: The trouble with the black ice is that you can't see it coming till it trips you up.
Rym: And it, it, it was, it was the right balance, but it also had some moments where I mean, as soon as you said, sometimes it's black ice.
Scott: I'd already knew the rest of the dialogue, even though I've never seen, but sometimes it was unintentionally funny.
Rym: But also have you ever, so have you ever seen opera?
Rym: Like you've seen, have you ever seen a full opera?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Have you ever seen an, a full opera that is in English?
Scott: No.
Scott: So I saw one in Italian.
Rym: I have before I saw the magic flute in English.
Rym: So I've used to that.
Rym: If you have never seen an opera in English and you speak English, it is really fucking hilarious and weird because the way English written opera tends to be is it sounds like I will kill the man who killed my friend and I will get hit.
Rym: Like it sounds like someone making fun of opera.
Scott: I'm sure that's what Italian opera sounds like to Italian people.
Rym: That's how opera is.
Rym: But very few people in like America ever hear an opera in English because usually performing it in the language it was written in is a way to avoid that problem.
Scott: I mean, that's why I tend to, you know, enjoy music written in other languages more with lyrics in other languages more because lyrics are distracting from music unless the lyrics are really damn good or really damn smooth.
Rym: Like stairway to heaven.
Rym: It's fine that that's in English, but like some Yumi Hamasaki song.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: You're singing about pop nonsense, but because I don't understand it directly, it sounds way better.
Scott: I mean, most K-pop is not any really better than Britney Spears garbage.
Scott: It's just because I don't know what the hell they're saying.
Scott: It's not, it's less asinine.
Rym: But TKF is super great.
Rym: The other interesting thing about it is that it's free and open to the public.
Rym: Just walk right in.
Scott: Oh, I thought TKF cost money.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: Totally free.
Rym: It's in this giant public library.
Scott: You just walk in?
Rym: Just walk in.
Scott: How do they make money?
Scott: They're not selling badges.
Rym: Well, there's a bunch of tables like MOCA.
Scott: Oh, they make money from selling tables?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Also, I think that there's a bunch, there's a bunch of means that TKF has.
Scott: Is it paid for with Canadian socialism?
Rym: I assume Canadian socialism also has a part in that, but there was a huge number of tables.
Rym: It scratched every itch that MOCA used to scratch.
Rym: I got a bunch of weird zines and like fun stuff.
Scott: Well, MOCA was during PAX East this year.
Scott: We didn't, we didn't go.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: So I had a lot of reasons to go to this thing.
Rym: It had the Danish comics pavilion.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, MOCA always had a pavilion from some country.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And it was pretty good.
Rym: There was a dude dressed in Roman armor talking about his Rome comic.
Rym: And I really want to read this comic now, but the comic is not in English.
Scott: Was it Rome armor made recently or actual Rome armor from Rome times?
Rym: He basically just had the helmet.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: Was it an actual helmet from Rome?
Rym: No, I'm pretty sure the realm it was made recently.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: But the cool thing was in the Danish pavilion, there was a little note that was like, you know, every one of these is available for licensing with really good terms.
Rym: If you want to bring it into America or Canada and translate it into English.
Rym: Just saying, just saying.
Scott: Why don't you do that?
Rym: Maybe we should.
Scott: Some of these look pretty good.
Scott: You want to become a comics publisher?
Scott: Do you know anything about comics publishing?
Rym: Uh, I, I think about publishing.
Rym: I actually, I know a little bit and I know the right people.
Rym: Remember, I'm not, I'm not a good producer in this sense.
Rym: I have an executive producer assemble the people to do the thing and just take credit for it.
Scott: Publishing business.
Scott: Ain't easy.
Rym: No, it's not.
Scott: But any medium.
Rym: TCAF was pretty great.
Rym: And if you, if you can get to TCAF, like by driving there or taking a train, if you live close enough to Toronto, you definitely should be going to this thing.
Rym: I may go back next year because I have excuses to go to like after parties and all the stuff.
Rym: I don't think I'd go back every year if I was just going to the comic con.
Rym: But the fact that I can do all the other things means it's, it's pretty worth going to.
Rym: So in some other, uh, kind of surprising news, Rick and Morty, the cartoon is really popular.
Rym: I really, I'm a big fan of it.
Rym: Uh, but it got picked up for more episodes, which isn't necessarily news.
Rym: The show is super popular and makes a lot of money.
Rym: But what is surprising is that adult swim didn't just pick up another season.
Rym: They picked up 70 episodes.
Scott: How many seasons is that?
Scott: Like three.
Rym: Yeah, that, that's more than three.
Rym: The current seasons are like 10 to 13 episodes.
Scott: So it's like five or six seasons.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So 70 episodes for context, that is cowboy bebop plus utenna.
Scott: And then a little bit granted that is, uh, that show is not as expensive or difficult to produce as other animation.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: it's super cheap or anything like $5 anime.
Rym: But you actually seen it, it's higher production value than you might expect.
Scott: Yeah, no, but it's not like fucking space dandy or some shit.
Scott: Uh, it's not ultra fancy high, you know, high, highest production value.
Scott: So like, you know, it probably costs like, you know, 20 to five to 30% less at least than, you know, a fancy show.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So the 70 of it, but I mean, also it's super popular.
Scott: Of course, you know, it's gonna make the money, especially since other shows are ending, you know, they want to at least keep, you know, they got all these new shows coming.
Scott: They got to keep some continuity of old shows continue.
Rym: So in some other sort of like, not really news, this is just an interesting thing that happened to me.
Rym: So on the way home from Zenkai Con, I was on an Amtrak and there was a big group of like late teens, like it seemed like 14 to 19 year olds, like a big group of them who all went to the con and they were super loud.
Rym: And I basically overheard their entire conversation on the entire ride.
Rym: But unlike say the typical naive anime con attendee, they sounded a lot like us when you, we used to go to a lot of cons and that they go to every anime con.
Rym: Like they go to Otakon, Anime Boston, like everything on the East coast, all the things we would do like Katsucon.
Scott: Their only crime is being born too late.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But the, as a result, I got a pretty interesting unfiltered set of reviews about the current state of anime cons now that, you know, we don't go to any anymore.
Rym: And I guess the really interesting thing I noticed was that they talked a lot about panels in particular and how they really like good panel content.
Rym: But in the last three or four years, I'm basically paraphrasing the exact things they said, like I'm not adding my own color to it.
Rym: Anime con panels have gone to shit and all the people who know what they're talking about are gone.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: People like us and you know, and people smarter than us don't go to a lot of cons anymore.
Scott: And they made this funny point that who do go to the cons are fun, you know, to run and run content or punk kids who don't know what you're talking about.
Rym: And one of them said, and all the other ones like, Oh yeah, like why would I even bother going to Otakon anymore?
Rym: Zenkai con has just as good a panels because it's the same people doing the panels everywhere.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And then they spent an hour dragging Otakon and they've been going to Otakon like longer than we went to Otakon.
Scott: Like these kids have been go, they were, we went from oh two to oh nine.
Rym: They were definitely at Otakon oh seven.
Rym: So they were, they, they overlapped with us in terms of going to Otakon.
Rym: And they talked a lot about how the, all the content at Otakon has gone downhill to the point that the only reason to go, and they even said the words was to hang out in the lobby.
Rym: and now we don't even have that.
Scott: Oh, cause it moved.
Rym: Cause it moved.
Rym: And they started having this long debate about should they even bother going to Otakon anymore?
Rym: And then one of them said, we could just go to anime Boston.
Rym: And they all basically said the same thing.
Rym: We always say that anime Boston is the last great anime con on the East coast.
Scott: Oh, it's still an anime con.
Rym: It's I mean, and at least, you know, we don't go to anime Boston anymore either, but that's mostly because it's inconvenient to us.
Rym: Not because the anime content is bad there.
Rym: We only don't go honestly still because of the security checks.
Scott: That is the, that is one of the inconveniences.
Scott: It's also like a whole weekend of my life.
Rym: I have to go to Boston, but it's a weekend where there's bad weather and we, it's not like we'd be biking or anything, but I'd say 80% of why we don't go to anime Boston anymore is because of the bag checks.
Rym: And the other 20% is usually PAX East and other stuff is right around that time.
Rym: And I need a weekend to deal with all that.
Rym: So, but they seem to agree that anime Boston is the last one worth going to.
Rym: And they had a pretty high opinion of katsu con, but then one of them, this is why I know their opinions are pretty quality was like, yeah, but why don't we just go to magfest?
Rym: It's like, we'll do the same thing there, but the everyone else is way cooler.
Rym: And they started getting a lot into like what they like about anime con panels and they seem to want informative panels or professionally run entertaining panels.
Rym: And they are uninterested in 90% of panels because it's all just some attendee who's getting a free badge and talking about like the thing they care about that they don't actually know anything about.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: That's always been the case.
Rym: They don't care about the dances.
Rym: They don't care about any of that nonsense.
Scott: And they do someone does because they go into it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I don't know who.
Rym: And actually they talked about that and they didn't know who they're like, who goes to these things?
Rym: Like there's people we don't talk to that are, you know, uh, they, they speculated on, is it just people who don't know about dance clubs?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Like they just don't know punk kids.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But they actually, they had a really surprisingly high opinion of Zenkai con, like even more so than I would have expected.
Rym: And it seemed to come down to the fact that Zenkai con, unlike say these other anime cons is real cheap and trivial to go to.
Rym: And as far as their attendee experience is concerned, if you don't want to see the Japanese guests, they're basically the exact same experience for these kids who are too young to like go out drinking or do the stuff that like adults tend to do around cons.
Rym: Like they just want to hang out with their internet friends and talk about anime.
Scott: I mean, if it's a fan run con, you know, being bigger and having more money doesn't really allow them to provide content that a small con can't provide other than bringing in a big fancy guest.
Scott: It's like, what can Otakon do that a Zenkai con can't do?
Rym: Cause look, Zenkai con gets a GeekNights panel that Otakon doesn't.
Scott: So it's not, you know, it's like other than bringing in a big guest or having a premiere of a movie that everyone will be able to see soon.
Scott: If they want, like, if they honestly, like they do the AMV contest is in a bigger room.
Scott: Oh, they talked about that too.
Rym: Quote, who gives a fuck about the AMV contest?
Rym: I have YouTube.
Scott: But I mean, the point is, it's like same, most of it is same content, bigger room at a bigger con for more money.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: It's like, what's the, you know, if the con is big enough to have the content in the first place, it's not some really tiny con, then it's like, what's the difference between them if they're in the same geographic area.
Rym: But the big cons, the problem with them is that it's hard to get hotels.
Rym: It's hard.
Rym: It's expensive to go.
Rym: And the con doesn't actually offer them anything different that they care about because all they want to do is hang out with their friends and see good panels, bigger costs, better, bigger, better.
Scott: Cosplay people will be there.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: They talked a lot about cosplay too, and they really care about that, but I don't really have strong opinions on cosplay.
Rym: So I don't, I didn't really follow it like that part of the conversation.
Rym: That's why I started playing slay the spire instead, but, uh, it was interesting.
Rym: because yeah, you're right.
Rym: The big cons, they can get the Japanese guest or the big voice actor.
Rym: Not that these kids cared about the voice actors, but they can't actually attract better normal panel content because there isn't any out there.
Rym: I mean, who are they getting anything?
Rym: Us.
Rym: They'll get anime world order.
Rym: Mike tool.
Rym: There's like a set of people who can do these good panels about anime and those people don't go to a lot of these anime cons anymore.
Scott: What if you paid them, but they don't, they're not paying for that because that's not what's bringing people in the door.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But like, I feel like Mike tool would be a bigger draw in Otakon than a lot of Japanese guests and especially more than a lot of the like voice actor style, I guess.
Rym: Cause those kids, those people who know what's up, the voice actor guests who go to the dance.
Rym: True.
Rym: But increasingly I want, I worry that the voice actor guests seem to draw the kinds of people who go to her con for one day or her too young to afford to go to a lot of cons and there's a self-limiting audience there.
Rym: But I guess my meta point is that we, Scott and I are old enough and interact less and less with the weed anime culture that still goes to cons that it was very interesting to hear a pretty large group of kids who were younger than us talking about their experiences at cons in an unfiltered way among themselves and just being the creepy old guy, listening to their conversation and taking notes.
Rym: And I feel like our opinions are like, we still have a pretty good tap on like that demographic.
Scott: Also, I've pretty much never trust when Rym tells like an anecdote of something he heard someone else saying, cause he does this all, he does this all the time and provides, you know, no proof or whatever.
Scott: Well, I mean, and it's, you know, first of all, even if it's true, it's anecdotal evidence.
Rym: My sample size is a group of eight kids who appeared to be between 14 and 19 and it's been, and even if it's true, it's been through a Rym filter.
Scott: Real often be like, Oh, I overheard this and this and this to try to create evidence to support his own ideas.
Scott: That is a remove.
Rym: But I also, I only took notes on the pant, like the stuff I cared about because when they started talking about cosplay, I just like half listened.
Rym: They, they, the, the only things I remember they said about cosplay were that that's the only good thing of, that's the only good thing.
Rym: Katsucon has was what they said about cosplay.
Scott: Well, Katsucon is like the cosplays.
Rym: And they said, nobody knows how to make a costume for shit at Zenkai Con.
Rym: But, uh, I guess I could have recorded their conversation, but I think that would have gone above the line to creepy.
Scott: I mean, you're already creepy.
Rym: I think that would have been, that would have been over the line, but anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So I'm a, I'm a fan of, well, of useful memes and the, is this a pigeon meme that's been making the rounds lately.
Rym: And I, I particularly enjoy it, but, uh, some, normally there's like the know your meme things.
Rym: I'm going to go do the research, like, wait, where did this meme come from?
Rym: And like that sort of thing.
Rym: But the story of where this meme came from was pretty funny because a lot of people who are using this meme didn't realize that the screenshot, the, is this a pigeon with the guy looking at what is clearly a butterfly.
Rym: They did not realize that that is the actual subtitle from that actual anime.
Rym: And it turns out the person who fansubbed, not just who fansubbed this anime, but who specifically did this fansub.
Rym: like they're the ones who typed the words, is this a pigeon and did like the genlock or whatever it is?
Rym: you did to make a fansub back then.
Rym: They discovered recently that this is a meme and they thought it was funny because they'd actually fansubbed it and they'd like went around and got interviewed and everything.
Rym: But basically the deal with this meme is that this is from an anime that I actually had never seen, but I've heard of it.
Scott: There's a, there's a series of shows called the brave series, like brave.
Scott: I think Gao Gai Gar is included in that series.
Rym: Brave of the sun fiber.
Scott: So this is like a whole series of robot shows called brave something, something.
Scott: And this is one of them.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But basically this is a pretty in-depth look at like where this meme came from and it's all the stuff around it.
Rym: But the reason why this kid clearly does not know what a pigeon or a butterfly is, is that he's an android trying to pretend to be a human.
Rym: And I haven't seen the show, but apparently he really sucks at pretending to be a human.
Scott: I saw the clip, uh, like the video clip of the fansub surrounding the whole scene.
Scott: And basically there's a, the, the android kid is living at this professor's house.
Scott: It was professors taking care of him and gave him the clothes and stuff and disguise.
Scott: And there's also some kids living at the professor's house cause it's a robot show.
Scott: And there's a detective who's snooping around.
Scott: The detective bumps into the android kid and starts questioning him out.
Scott: And that's why this dialogue eventually occurs.
Rym: So yeah, now you know, but the fact that it's someone pretending to be human who isn't could color your perception of some of the uses of this meme.
Rym: So you got to think of the day.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, uh, so the original like Lego set, you know, the one with the blue spaceship with the planet on it.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: So somebody took that theme of the original blue spaceship and Lego and made a pinball machine.
Scott: that is that theme.
Scott: But the pinball machine is basically 100% Lego, but it's actually a working pinball machine, 100% working with scorekeeping and flippers and everything.
Rym: Scorekeeping is pretty impressive.
Scott: I guess I don't know if the metal ball is actually from a Lego set.
Scott: It could be, uh, I'd give them that if they didn't, if they got Lego technique, they got Lego mind storm, they got, you know, all Lego stuff, uh, to make this pinball machine.
Scott: And yes, it is a 100, even the, even the, you know, the, the table is Lego.
Scott: Everything is Lego.
Scott: It's a fucking Lego pinball machine.
Scott: Oh my God.
Rym: This is pretty amazing.
Scott: You can actually play it for reals.
Rym: Also, this, this website has the appropriate as, as many screenshots and pictures of this as you want to explore it.
Scott: This video of it, you can see the insides, the outsides, the top sides, the, you know, the whole thing.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: There are no secrets.
Rym: So in the moment, the GeekNights book is still Emily Wilson's new translation.
Rym: Odyssey.
Rym: Have you read any more of it?
Scott: I have read more Odyssey.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I will then work to finish the Odyssey.
Scott: He's on the Island with, uh, Nausicaa.
Scott: And, uh, I guess his, her, her parents are chilling or whatever.
Scott: We're going to make an awesome boat for you to go on Odyssey with that right around.
Rym: there is where I paused waiting for you to start reading against.
Rym: I'll start reading again.
Rym: We'll probably finish.
Scott: They're going to give Odysseus a boat so he can go on an Odyssey.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And then we're going to get the, the, the stuff that we all remember.
Scott: Cause apparently like we learned where the pop up books.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: No one remembers Telemachus is like pre Odysseus arc.
Rym: Like no one seemed to have read that part in high school for some reason.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I'm really liking this translation and you should read it.
Rym: Definitely.
Scott: We'll do a very easy to read compared to old timey translation.
Rym: And also, you know, we have a book club.
Scott: We've actually done a ton of books over the last, even though it seems to take forever to do any individual book club book.
Scott: It feels like we do like two a year.
Rym: Like we've done a lot.
Scott: GeekNights has been going on so long.
Scott: The book club has been going on so long.
Scott: We have actually somehow accumulated many Rebecca.
Rym: I mean, if I go back, we had five pages of the stuff, the great Gatsby one Q 84 foundation, the lives of Locke Lamora, farewell to arms, Steppenwolf.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: We did Steppenwolf.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I just, I suddenly just remembered Steppenwolf.
Scott: Uh huh.
Rym: It's a pretty good ending there.
Scott: Good band.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Good band.
Scott: Good book.
Scott: Song's still relevant.
Scott: You could think they were written yesterday.
Rym: So, uh, yeah.
Rym: Follow the GeekNights book club and follow GeekNights and all those places.
Rym: Scott's got a YouTube channel.
Scott: Even if you don't follow units book club, read some books.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I read a book.
Scott: It's my better use of your time to listen to this shit.
Rym: Not a sports page, not a magazine book.
Rym: So we, uh, I've, Scott hasn't watched made in abyss yet, so we can't review that.
Scott: I think we could do a show on a Gretsuko cause I've seen two episodes and that's enough.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: A Gretsuko is okay.
Scott: And that's a hot show right now.
Rym: It's all right.
Rym: I only watched one episode.
Scott: So why don't we do a show on it right now?
Rym: Cause I got, I have almost nothing to say about it.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It's okay.
Scott: I could do a show on it.
Rym: The people I, people are talking about it like the characters have very touching, meaningful arcs.
Rym: And I do not know if that is true because I've only watched one episode and I've seen two episodes.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So maybe three.
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I have not seen enough to have any opinion other than it's okay.
Rym: It's cute.
Rym: Uh, I like the characters.
Rym: It seems to have more of a contiguous story than Detroit metal city.
Scott: And it's not the only relation to Detroit metal city is.
Scott: it has the trope of character who is on the surface.
Scott: Nothing like heavy metal sings heavy metal.
Rym: It isn't just the same joke over and over and over again.
Scott: It's contains no other similarities with Detroit metal city on that.
Rym: But it isn't just like, here's the joke or she has to bring coffee and now she's mad and then she does death metal.
Rym: Here's the joke where she gets like almost fired and then she sings death metal.
Rym: Actually, there's more to it than just that.
Rym: It's not just a series of vignettes, but I have nothing else to say about it cause I have only seen one episode.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Do you have any, do you have anything more to say?
Scott: I could talk about it for a whole episode, but apparently Go for it.
Rym: We can do that instead.
Scott: Oh, are we going to do that instead?
Rym: I got nothing to say though.
Scott: You sure?
Rym: I saw one episode.
Rym: What do you want me to say?
Scott: All right.
Scott: So first of all, right.
Scott: So this show is made by Sanrio, which is the Hello Kitty company.
Scott: And they're also making this, which seems somewhat close to Hello Kitty and sort of the character design.
Scott: art wiseness, right?
Scott: Where the sort of like the simple thick line art style, but yet so far away from anything you would consider to be Hello Kitty.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's, it seems like it's going to have the merchandising of Hello Kitty, right?
Scott: There's already a Gretsuko merch up the wazoo, uh, if you look online.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So in that you can see all the different characters in the show.
Scott: When you look at them, it's like, they all have all these really distinctive designs, but like once you, if you think, cause I, you know, that the fact that it's a Sanrio show, right.
Scott: Was like stuck in my mind.
Scott: It's like, as I'm watching, it's like, you can see how all the characters are so mergeable.
Scott: They're designed to be mergeable.
Rym: I mean, that's the Sanrio play.
Scott: Even more so than the way robots are mergeable.
Rym: That that Sanrio, here's characters and here's the characters merge.
Scott: Gretsuko is all about the merge.
Scott: And once you see that the rest of the show sort of falls together and we're like, ah, I see these characters are so different and different stereotypes, right?
Scott: This is the other coworker who's just chill or at least seems to be chill, right?
Scott: You know, the male coworker who seems like normal boring guy, the annoying hippo lady, right?
Scott: The totally cool, bad ass, taller ladies who only walk down the hall and that's all they do.
Scott: The evil boss pig guy.
Scott: It's like every character is like something that somebody is going to relate to or want in some form of merchant, some way, right?
Scott: Like they can sell that pig boss guy as like a stress relieving squeezy thing, right?
Scott: But yeah, it's interesting how the show, while it's got these sort of like, you know, character designs that are so simple, actually is like carrying a full plot, like the pacing of it and the plot lines and structure of the episodes feels like any other, like a real show.
Rym: So, you know, having only seen one episode though, half the people I've talked to who decided to watch the whole show are acting like it's a really serious touching like adulthood story and like it's a, like it's a really good thought provoking show.
Rym: And the other half of the people I've talked to said that it kind of just doesn't go anywhere and everyone's making a really big deal about it for nothing.
Rym: It's mostly just a comedy.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't think that it's a, I don't know yet from the number of episodes, I don't even remember the number of episodes I've seen.
Rym: There's like
Scott: 10 and so that usually when you see a show animated in such a simple way with this kind of style and that sort of hook, it's just
Rym: like you
Scott: expected to be one of those things with short episodes where just sort of, you know, scenes and incidents and whatever and not this sort of, you know, it continues.
Scott: It's like, you know, like she, you know, there's the character who is the sort of childhood friend who is irresponsible and it's like the plot carries from episode to episode in this continuity, which like you don't expect to match up with, you know, the animation style and such.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, imagine if I took like a real, a real, you know, sort of show Joe anime plot and just, and I just bang the microphone into my tooth, you know, but you animated it in like the same way you would animate something like Domiko.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Which is I would argue has at least based on the first episode of Gretsuko, almost a similar level of character arcs, got a million different characters.
Scott: Gretsuko has more going on than Domiko.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, I've only seen one episode that I don't know.
Rym: I don't know how far it goes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But you know, there's this, I think the thing that people like about a Gretsuko is that it touches on things that, you know, people, even people our age are actually like feeling and dealing with in everyday life.
Rym: And like, like some of those Jose manga, there's like, here's normal life for an adult.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In like very modern, you know, present day times.
Scott: Like, you know, it hits home for people who have jobs today who are our age, where we're not like bosses in charge.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: We're not that old, but we're also not, you know, like interns or whatever, you know?
Scott: She's got to deal with issues like, you know, misogynist boss.
Scott: They got to deal with issues like, you know, people pile and work on you, deal with issues like why am I sitting in an office job when I could be out living a real life?
Scott: Should I just quit?
Scott: All these things that like, you know, people who are watching actually relate to in everyday life are happening in this show.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which wouldn't happen with most anime ever.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, because most anime, I mean, even the anime.
Rym: Evangelion, the main characters, these teenagers, but the adult characters are mostly like in their twenties.
Scott: I think actually, you know, when I think about it, I can't think of an anime that I can actually relate to in my real everyday life more than a Gretsuko ever.
Scott: Oh, let's see.
Scott: What anime?
Rym: Count of Monte Cristo.
Scott: No.
Rym: Well, you don't have long term, you don't have long term ridiculously complex plans for revenge against people who slighted you 20 years ago.
Scott: I mean, there might be individual things in an anime here or there that I might be able to relate to, even crazy fantasy ones.
Scott: So like, you know, in Galaxy Express, I can relate to the do I want a robot body, but oh, the woes of immortality.
Scott: But there's, you know, in terms of my everyday actual human life on Earth.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like there's no anime that I know of that matches up more than a Gretsuko does.
Rym: I'm thinking about it.
Rym: So I'm trying to think of an anime now.
Rym: I mean, there's a lot of generic anime from like a decade ago that were kind of like.
Rym: I'm trying to think of one that actually fits my life, though, that are just adults doing a thing and they don't really have a particular strong plot.
Rym: Like kids on the slope did what didn't seem like it was really going anywhere in particular.
Rym: But if you were a musician, it might be like you might be able to relate to it.
Scott: But this relates to a lot of people.
Scott: Dealing with office shit.
Scott: It's like Dilbert, but not off.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, it's like Dilbert updated for twenty eighteen.
Scott: Not awful.
Scott: Female perspective.
Scott: Also, Japan perspective.
Scott: Also, also funny.
Rym: Yeah, I can see that.
Scott: But it's really interesting, you know, as for all Dilbert's problems, you know, in its day, it was relatable for office people.
Scott: I'm just going to find a Dilbert comic that related to your work situation.
Rym: I just see a really wide split between people who say it's really overrated and people who are really relating to it.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I mean, how overrated it is depends on how rated it is.
Scott: I think if people are saying it's like phenomenal, unbelievable, then yes, that's overrated.
Rym: I guess what will be really interesting is it being on Netflix and with the Sanrio cache, will there be a lot of people who we won't see who watch it because it's on Netflix, but who might not even think of it as anime?
Rym: Like they just click on it and they watch this show in English dubbed about this person working and relate to it.
Scott: There is a problem, right?
Scott: And I didn't realize this problem.
Scott: I haven't I don't know if anyone else has commented on this.
Scott: We went to Netflix.
Scott: He turned it on.
Scott: Yeah, I chose Japanese audio English.
Rym: I just watched the dub on the first episode.
Rym: Didn't even try to watch the subtitles.
Scott: I mean, if I turn on anime, I'm going to try subtitles.
Scott: And what happened was is there were some subtitles.
Scott: But there was also this narrator talking and it realized after like a minute, like, hey, the subtitles aren't broken.
Scott: They're just only subtitling the characters and the narrator isn't being subbed.
Scott: The narrator wasn't getting subbed at all.
Scott: And I was like, what the hell's up with that?
Scott: Why isn't the narrator being subtitled?
Scott: So then I'm like, well, I guess we had to watch the dub.
Scott: So you rewind, go back to the beginning, turn on the dub and there's no narrator.
Scott: And I realized that those were dub titles, dub titles, not subtitles.
Scott: Basically, they were closed captions for the dub.
Scott: They weren't subtitles.
Scott: And it must be.
Scott: the Japanese is actually probably quite significantly different because it has a narrator.
Scott: That's a huge difference to begin with.
Rym: So it's Blade Runner.
Scott: That's completely absent.
Rym: We got the Blade Runner problem now.
Scott: So I really would like to watch the show with that narrator and with subtitles of the narrator and the characters to see if it gives a different impression at all.
Rym: So kind of an aside, but there's a similar but different problem with the because we were watching made in the biz, which is on the Amazon dub, actually not a bad dub.
Rym: dub sounded fine, but so we were watching made in the biz.
Scott: It doesn't even sound like an anime dub.
Scott: Like people do those characters pretty well, but it's on Amazon.
Rym: And the way Amazon works, if you start watching it, it's just in Japanese, no subtitles.
Rym: Fuck you.
Rym: So you got to go and be like enable subtitles.
Rym: But Amazon then remembers that globally.
Rym: So then later, like weeks later, days later, you watch some like some American show and the English subtitles are there and you got to go turn it off.
Rym: There's like no intelligent defaults there.
Rym: So you have to turn them off every time you watch something in English and turn them on every time you watch something in Japanese.
Scott: I mean, you should be able to just configure like, hey, I speak only to English, but I want to hear original audio on this, whatever the original language was, Indian, Turkish, Russian, but as an aside, the original audio, but I only speak it English.
Rym: So remember, there's these tropes of like old anime fandom.
Rym: So like when you watch an anime, like a VHS tape that had four episodes, the first episode, the opener would show the Romangi.
Rym: Then the second time when he watched the second episode, the opener would show the actual, like here I got like the characters.
Rym: Then the third time you watch it, it'd be the translation.
Rym: And then the fourth episode would be clear.
Rym: There'd be no subtitles.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And DVDs, what they would do is often just put the.
Scott: the the pure unadulterated opening is like a DVD extra.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So and then the the actual opener would just be subtitled normally.
Rym: Amazon does that.
Rym: There's a weeb advising them somewhere.
Rym: Amazon, every episode, it rotates through all those possible options.
Scott: See what fansubbers do these days, it seems.
Rym: They put them all there once.
Scott: I mean, I haven't seen fansubs in a while because it's just everything streaming.
Rym: Yeah, I just don't.
Scott: Fansubs have been, you know, for quite a few years, just put all the different.
Scott: they put the karaoke, the English, the the, you know, the Japanese characters and the Romangi up there all at once.
Scott: All at the same time.
Scott: Cover ten different colors for the karaoke part.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, and then they they're kind of waiting.
Scott: You can't see the opener because all this you got five different subtitle tracks at once.
Scott: But that's what they do on the closer to.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But yeah, I'm really curious to watch the rest of this to see where I fall.
Scott: It's like on the one hand, I kind of want to see where it goes because it has this sort of continuing plot that I can relate to.
Scott: But on the other hand, I like I stopped after I don't know.
Scott: I can't remember if it was two or three or four episodes I watched and I didn't have like a strong desire to keep going.
Scott: See, that's the thing we all just want instead of watching it.
Scott: Somebody just tell me what happens.
Rym: See, that's the.
Rym: that's one of the metrics I get used to judging anime again when I start watching like, you know, I got to watch four episodes of show to review it.
Rym: But what my one of my main metrics is after I force myself to watch for how strongly do I want to watch the fifth episode?
Rym: Like Initial D as dumb as I thought it was, I wanted to watch that fifth episode desperately as dumb as your pedal is right now.
Scott: I really like.
Scott: I have a desire to watch the next episode and see what the bug is going to have.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Like made in the best.
Rym: What's the deal with the show?
Rym: And I watch four episodes.
Rym: Really wanted to watch the fifth episode to see what happens.
Rym: You should watch it.
Rym: We could do a show on that one.
Scott: I got too much stuff going on.
Rym: Dude, the show is only like 12 episodes long.
Scott: Oh, is it?
Scott: Oh, it's not long.
Scott: That helps.
Rym: And while there might be a second season, the first season, it ends.
Rym: And it tells enough of a story.
Rym: And it's not.
Rym: it's not bad.
Rym: It's a good show.
Rym: Like we watched it and I enjoyed it.
Rym: And it's a terrible secret space.
Rym: And they go the the ship of the show is heading straight for the terrible secret at the highest possible velocity.
Rym: It's like, hey, there's a pit there with a secret in it.
Rym: Episode two, we're going down the pit.
Rym: Never look back.
Rym: Let's go.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I guess we can just stop there.
Rym: I got nothing else to say about it.
Rym: Good to go.
Scott: I told you we could do a whole show on it.
Rym: Only because we went way long on the news.
Scott: Can we redo the opener now?
Rym: Oh, yeah, I guess we should.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: Come on.
Rym: Yeah, we probably will only have one episode next week as I got to fly to Quantico to see my brother's graduation from the FBI.
Rym: So I leave you with this.