Rym: It's Monday, June 11th 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight containers like Docker or some shit.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So if you follow me on Twitter, you might have noticed that I was talking about axe murder a lot recently.
Rym: Why?
Rym: I ended up Randomly partly because you know, I'm into horror.
Scott: He's not give Rym any axes.
Rym: Ah, do I own an axe?
Rym: I don't think I own an axe.
Rym: But anyway, I noticed something While I was learning more about axe murder and what I noticed Was that axe murder?
Scott: I really hope that all these stories about government spying on Google searches is true.
Rym: I realized that Axe murder is its own category of murder separate from just murder.
Rym: No one says like oh he's a knife murderer.
Rym: people say he's a murderer or they say he's a serial killer Or they say that person is an axe murderer.
Rym: and I wondered why is axe murder its own category?
Scott: because it was a thing.
Rym: Yeah Axe murder from like the slate like 1700s early 1800s until about 1960 was its own kind of murder in the u.s.
Rym: Common enough to have its own colloquial term.
Rym: There's a whole Wikipedia page about it.
Rym: Yeah, like axe murder was a thing.
Rym: I know Do you know why?
Scott: because I really there were people who are fucking axe murderer.
Scott: But why did?
Rym: why are there no longer axe murderers?
Scott: Not a lot of people have axes these days back in the day.
Scott: You'd be chopping wood.
Rym: People don't have axes.
Scott: I mean they do but not like in the old days.
Rym: It's actually that people don't have an excuse to carry axes with them all the time Mm-hmm.
Rym: So To the extent of like there's this one case that I was reading about this pretty I mean It's funny as as funny as axe murder can be.
Rym: it's long enough ago to where I feel like I can talk about this.
Rym: But it sort of really drives home the point that axe murder was such a thing.
Rym: So this family was axe murdered.
Rym: the weird thing about the 1800s in the early 1900s is that when there was an axe murder there would always be multiple likely axe murder suspects.
Rym: So in this case this family got axe murder the people who walk around with axes.
Rym: So I'm gonna list for you very briefly some of the suspects in this case.
Scott: That guy was always in the park stroking his axe.
Rym: Let's see if you can guess which one of these people was the axe murderer.
Scott: All of the above.
Rym: So the only one axe murderer in this case.
Rym: The first suspect was a dude who repeatedly Threatened the family with murder.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: He was definitely not the axe murderer But he threatened the family that was axe murdered with murder multiple times.
Rym: Okay, right before the murder happened Okay, but he had a stone-cloak cold alibi.
Rym: there was another person who confessed to the axe murder knew a lot of details about the axe murderer and Was weirdly obsessed with axe murder.
Rym: He was a reverend who wandered around studying axe murder.
Rym: Mm-hmm, despite confessing to the axe murder He definitely didn't do it and was just crazy and apparently confessed to a lot of axe murders.
Rym: Mm-hmm But there was another dude.
Scott: you're really making this quiz easy by telling me the right answer before I get to the bottom.
Scott: So like multiple choice, but they already told you which choices are good because all those are like the low-hanging fruit.
Rym: here's a dude who showed up in town the morning after the axe murders and Guy was dressed in a suit, but his feet his pants are all muddy and wet and ruined and he shows up.
Rym: He's a hobo.
Rym: He has an
Scott: axe
Rym: and he asks for a job and he gets a job with like some company that's doing stuff and His co-workers start complaining to the foreman that he sleeps with his axe That he mutters about chopping people's heads off constantly And when the police go to talk to him about potentially being the axe murdering suspect The police the sheriff like walks up behind him and notices that he is just standing alone in the woods holding his axe Muttering about chopping people's heads off and then suddenly flips out and starts swinging the axe at random objects.
Rym: Mm-hmm That guy definitely was not the axe murderer either.
Rym: He's just a hobo who sleeps with his axe and probably axe murdered other people Definitely did not axe murder these people.
Scott: Well, that was obvious because when he came into town all muddy He wasn't all bloody and his axe wasn't bloody and he doesn't seem like someone who could clean things.
Rym: Yeah So there's like two other suspects in this case One of whom was eventually arrested and convicted of axe murder of a bunch of other people.
Rym: But even that one probably didn't do this murder.
Rym: So yeah axe murder is a thing.
Rym: in the end they bring this back to technology and Monday GeekNights.
Rym: The moral of the story is axe murder was a thing Because a huge percentage of murders in that time period were committed via axe Because axes were the most accessible implement of easy murder.
Rym: Also props to all the creepy people who came out of the woodwork in my Twitter to explain to me how hard it is to Kill someone with a knife compared to an axe.
Rym: really glad to that.
Rym: so many people know so much about knife murder.
Scott: Yeah, if you stab someone a bunch of times At least in modern times, especially they got a good chance of surviving Stab them real good.
Scott: if you if you got someone with something big like an axe or Yeti then their chances of survival go way down.
Rym: That's why when you watch a prison movie You see like someone like runs up behind someone who stabs them like 50 times like pip pip pip pip pip pip.
Scott: Yes you Executioners who have to kill people with the low effort because they got to go home to yeah They don't stab someone with a knife, right?
Scott: They got an axe on a big Long wooden thing.
Scott: so or some other implement.
Rym: The only reason axe murder ceased to be a thing in America is because now everybody has guns and all the murders that would have been axes are guns now.
Rym: I feel like we should start calling gun murder gun murder and treat it like this, like its own category that can be dealt with because it's a technology problem.
Rym: Too many people have access to guns and an excuse to carry them around and have them in their homes.
Scott: Why didn't they ban axes back in the day?
Rym: So just people used to keep axes in their houses because everyone needed a goddamn axe.
Scott: You don't walk around with it when you're not going to chop wood.
Scott: Because people were chopping wood all the time.
Scott: I don't carry my hammer around but I'm not going to hammer some nails.
Rym: Someone walking down the street with an axe back then was not that uncommon.
Scott: Yeah, but unless you're going to axe something right now you shouldn't be carrying your axe.
Rym: Yeah, but if you're eating someone's house and decided to kill them, there's probably a bunch of axes all over that house.
Rym: In the very least there's a bunch in the shed.
Rym: Maybe downstairs in the axe room.
Scott: Don't go in the spooky shed with crazy hobo.
Rym: The hobo, so the scarier thing, this is not relevant to technology at all.
Rym: The scariest thing I learned is that there's a pretty solid theory that a huge number of the axe murders in this era were all perpetrated by one axe murdering hobo riding trains around murdering families.
Scott: The muddy one.
Rym: Yeah, not that guy.
Rym: A different axe hobo.
Rym: The lesson there is that we joke from the Simpsons about the stabbing hobos.
Scott: They were stabbing hobos.
Rym: No, there were not stabbing hobos.
Rym: There are almost no stabbing hobos, but there was at least one prolific axe-in-hobo.
Scott: Close enough.
Rym: So you got any news that isn't axe murder?
Scott: There's a lot of tech news and we didn't use it because it was mostly last week when you have a Monday episode and then we forgot a bunch of it, but some of it was so big we didn't forget it.
Scott: So there's the...
Rym: The biggest one, let's start with the GitHub thing.
Scott: So Microsoft bought GitHub, which is really interesting, I guess.
Rym: It's weird because the technology world, I'm seeing the exact opposite take in about equal numbers.
Rym: I see a lot of the like ultra OSS purists freaking out about how Microsoft...
Scott: Well, because the olden days was Microsoft versus Linux and now this Linux for Windows system, whatever that I use at work, the Windows subsystem for Linux.
Rym: The big difference that happened is that Linux...
Scott: And Git is people who wrote Git originally, Linus Torvalds.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: The big thing that changed, though, not to get into the whole debate around this, if it's a good thing, if it's a bad thing, is Microsoft evil, is whatever, is that Linux is in no way a competitor to Windows.
Rym: No.
Rym: They solve different problems at this point.
Rym: There is no future for like consumer Linux on the desktop, except in, yeah.
Scott: Android is Linux.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Android on the desktop, because for most people...
Scott: There's not a lot of future for the desktop.
Rym: That's the point.
Rym: Android now just exists on the phones, basically.
Scott: But anyway...
Rym: And the phones are the primary PCs for a lot of people.
Scott: The main reason this happened, people don't seem to know, they're just like thinking about the sort of like, you know, Microsoft versus Linux thing, right, is first of all, is anything bad going to happen for actual users?
Scott: Probably not.
Scott: What is Microsoft bought and ruined?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They don't have a history of buying and ruining, really, that I can think of.
Scott: But the main reason this happened is because GitHub was not making money.
Scott: GitHub was very important and couldn't die because it was very important and still is, because a lot of shit's hosted there and a lot of companies depend on it.
Rym: And it is shocking how people are incapable of, like, big companies will use GitHub because if they can't deal with managing version control in-house.
Scott: Anyway, but GitHub also direly needed a new CEO.
Rym: Yeah, that's true.
Scott: This just sort of solved all of GitHub's problems, and Microsoft probably made the best deal of the other people who could have bought them and saved them.
Scott: So they just said, OK, you made the best deal.
Scott: We'll go with you.
Rym: I'm pretty confident GitHub is going to just continue to function as it did.
Rym: And if anything, I think it'll just get better.
Scott: And if it somehow turns evil, well, I mean, GitHub isn't Git.
Scott: You can just host your own Git, you can just GitLab, which is perfectly great, or many other alternatives if you just want to, if you need to host Git on a server.
Rym: It's crazy to me to realize that how much of my career has changed over the years that I realized I don't actually know what all my different engineering teams use for their version control or source control.
Scott: In the year twenty eighteen, you should pretty much be using Git or not being, you know, allowed to use a version.
Rym: No mercurial.
Rym: No, let's go.
Rym: No, so in some other news, Apple Apple stuff happened.
Scott: Yeah, this is the Apple Worldwide Developer Conference, which is when they announce historically all of their software things.
Scott: So mostly, you know, iOS updates, iWatch updates, OSX updates.
Scott: Most of the stuff was really the lame stuff that no one gives a shit about.
Scott: Like, we got new animojis and AR shit guys.
Rym: Yeah, I saw very little social media buzz compared to what I usually see.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, it's it's developer stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the big news is to come out of this.
Scott: Our number one is going to basically be a way to make like a universal app like that's that the same app will go in the iOS app store and the OSX app store.
Scott: And it's the same app.
Scott: If you write the app once in Swift and it, you know, the app looks good on an iPhone, an iPad and a Mac, all the same code, which is sure, why wouldn't you do that?
Scott: And then the other one, the bigger news, at least for nerds, which is great for Monday, actual tech news.
Scott: They have decided to deprecate OpenGL on OSX and their iOS and other platforms, which is a big deal because, well, they never gave a shit about games, really.
Scott: But iOS, I guess they give a shit about games.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it's interesting, though, because in terms of Apple, like there's a level of game that is sort of targeted at that platform now and all other PC gaming will be Windows forever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So you got to understand what like.
Scott: if you don't understand what OpenGL is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you have a computer and you want to write some app that does 3D shit and you want that 3D shit to be done by LED GPU.
Scott: So you import the OpenGL libraries and there's an API for talking to that GPU and making 3D shit happen.
Scott: And it's standard.
Scott: So if you write at your code to speak to OpenGL libraries, you can go to some other platform.
Scott: Say I write it for Windows.
Scott: I can now go to OSX and I don't have to change too much because there's still OpenGL over there and all my code speaks OpenGL.
Scott: I had to recompile it and I, you know, you're not going to be perfectly good to go, but you're going to be pretty close to good to go.
Scott: And this matters not for someone who's actually making a game, maybe unless it's a very, very intense game where you're micromanaging your GPU bits.
Scott: But if you're writing a game engine, that's going to matter a lot.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because the game engine is pretty much just speaking OpenGL all the time.
Scott: So Apple on their platform says this thing called Metal, which is a different API for speaking to the GPU, and they think it's better and whatnot.
Scott: Such and such, you know, because it's all customized for Apple.
Rym: Supposedly it's compatible with Intel, AMD and Nvidia GPUs.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, you know, whether which is irrelevant because you can't really buy your video card with an app, whether whether Metal is is good or not is besides the point because it's not OpenGL.
Scott: So if you write your app to speak Metal, your app ain't running on any other platform without a lot of work.
Scott: It ain't going to run on the switch or the PS4 or the Windows.
Scott: Or pretty much anything else.
Scott: So on the one hand, this could be a lot of work, you know, even if, you know, you're just using a game engine like, say, Unity or something like that.
Scott: Unreal, those people who make those engines now either have to do a shit ton of work to sort this out so that they can build a game on multiple platforms once OpenGL doesn't work on Macs anymore or just not.
Scott: let you you know, you have to write your app twice or basically just make a huge fucking hassle for all game developers, especially since even if those engines, you know, cover all the platforms and, you know, let you build against Metal and against OpenGL and deliver both.
Scott: It's like that's going to be buggy as hell.
Scott: You're going to have bugs that show up on OS X that don't show up on the platform, on the windows.
Scott: And it's basically just creating a nightmare for anyone who works with anything 3D or GPU related.
Rym: What I don't have any stats on because I basically just ignore Apple as a PC gaming platform is how many games using Unity actually run on OS X.
Scott: It's mostly iOS.
Scott: is the real situation.
Scott: Yeah, but for example, I mean, if you want to talk like Hearthstone is actually written on Unity and it runs in every platform, iOS, iPad, OS X and Windows.
Rym: I mean, Unity is fine.
Rym: It'll mostly come down to, I think, games that have a hassle for them to do it.
Scott: And it's going to be bugs, you know, on one way or the other.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because now you've got these multiple targets instead of just one.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But then again, on PC, you always have multiple targets for all the different hardware profiles.
Rym: Most of those things have been washed away thanks to like, you know, I would argue that most of them have just been washed below where you pay attention to them, but they're still there.
Scott: And the game, the game development, most of those things are actually most of those sort of problems these days are, from what I can tell, they're handled by the Nvidia driver itself.
Scott: This is why every time there's new games that come out, you'll see like the Nvidia and AMD drivers will make patches like we fixed bugs with this game in particular.
Scott: I think that in like I think if you open up the source code of the Nvidia driver, this I think there's like files that are like, if game equals this change GPU settings to that.
Scott: And there's like a huge mega list of like detecting what specific game and software is running and changing things based on.
Rym: I've found most of those are just minor performance improvements, like the game doesn't break or anything.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You know, there's a lot of things going on, but they're not as big a deal as you're making them out to know.
Scott: But the people develop when you're developing a big AAA game for the PC, you work with Nvidia slash AMD to work these things out, you know, and things aren't going to match up nicely.
Rym: Well, I mean, I think I think in the end, this doesn't matter that much because big studios either decide if they even target Macs or not.
Scott: And most games, it's not about you keep thinking about Mac, iOS is running the same fucking thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So iOS is tons of 3D games going on.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But I feel like those games are targeting a tablet phone ecosystem.
Rym: And it's a very different business.
Scott: A lot of people write the game once and then they build it to run an iOS and Windows and Android and everything.
Scott: I guess the studios that now that's going to be a way, way more difficult, it's going to be twice as difficult.
Rym: I don't think it's going to be twice as difficult.
Rym: It mostly seems like it's really small shops that are complaining about this and everyone else seems fine with.
Rym: like the articles.
Scott: I haven't seen anyone saying anything positive about it besides Apple.
Rym: I haven't seen people say much of anything about it.
Rym: And these articles are all kind of useless when I was reading them today.
Scott: It's definitely not good for the openness of, you know, if you're on a Mac and suddenly you want to write some code that use your GPU, suddenly you got to go through this, you know, metal closed API business.
Rym: Yeah, but metal will be the default standard for iOS.
Rym: If you're targeting iOS, if you care at all, you'll just support it.
Rym: And that'll be the end of that in some other news, because all the other stuff.
Rym: I mean, I don't.
Rym: Is there any other Apple announcement that you care about?
Rym: Because I don't use any Apple stuff.
Rym: So I don't.
Scott: at this point, most of it is, you know, news that no one cares about.
Scott: Like, oh, these are the features we're going to add to iOS.
Scott: And it's stuff like stuff to help you not be distracted by your phone.
Scott: so much like you can set it to be like, I only want to use Twitter for an hour a day.
Scott: And then your phone after use Twitter for an hour.
Scott: But like, hey, stop using Twitter.
Scott: You used your hour for today.
Rym: Androids had something like that forever.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: That's that.
Rym: That's really a feature that they announced.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Because I realized I don't own any Apple devices at this point.
Rym: Not one.
Rym: So I look to you because you're the only you use the Apple.
Rym: you're in the Apple ecosystem.
Scott: I only have an iPhone and I watch an iPad only.
Rym: You know, you say I guess you definitely don't use it.
Scott: I disable that.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I just say, well, this hell I do use and it's Siri shortcuts.
Scott: You can program your own Siri shortcut.
Scott: So I can say like, Siri, bite Rym and have that program to do a specific thing.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, you got to get the Arduino to hook up to some sort of teeth and some way to get them over to me.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: I mean, I would use something like that, but I found it increasingly because I set up OK, Google.
Rym: I've had the ability to do stuff like that for a long time.
Scott: Listen, I'm fine.
Scott: You know, the only problem with it is I do not want to talk out loud.
Scott: It's too much effort to open my mouth.
Rym: I thought I tried to come up with ways where I would use it at home.
Scott: If I had a car, I might turn it on in the car.
Rym: I use OK, Google when I'm driving quite a bit.
Scott: When you drive.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: I don't drive that often.
Rym: When I'm driving like I was in I was in Virginia a little while ago and I rented a car and I drove a lot.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: I used it to interact with my phone and respond to text messages while I was driving.
Rym: But other than when I'm driving, I don't ever want to talk out loud.
Scott: Any device I had, I can talk to the Apple Watch to respond to Google Hangout while I'm biking, but I don't.
Rym: Well, I would.
Rym: I thought I'd use it like while I'm cooking maybe, but I never need to because at most I have a screen with a recipe up and I never need to interact with any other device while I'm cooking.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: And if I want to change like what music's playing, I just touch my watch.
Rym: Like there's a very brief moment where my hands are covered in like chicken grease where I don't want to touch my watch.
Rym: And as soon as I wash my hands, I can touch my watch again.
Rym: Mostly I just don't want those devices listening to me all the time.
Scott: I mean, turning off Siri won't make them not listen if they want to.
Rym: So one other news is just really funny because it's one of those.
Rym: the news popped up about it a few times.
Rym: And every time it pops up, all I think is, wow, that still exists.
Rym: But as of July 17th, so about a month from now, Yahoo Messenger will actually be dead.
Rym: Apparently, they already shut off chat, but the service is still up until July 17th for people to download their chat histories.
Rym: I'm amazed that anyone was still using Yahoo Messenger.
Rym: I could never think of any use case for it.
Rym: The the husk of Yahoo is slowly being spread out among companies because, as you all know, Flickr was bought.
Rym: So Flickr probably has a real home now.
Rym: I'm going to continue to use Flickr, I think.
Scott: OK, I mean, I'll keep my Flickr alive, but I'm not using it.
Rym: Well, you know what I use it for?
Rym: I don't use it as my photo organizer or anything, but I use it as my primary mechanism to publish in bulk photos I take that other people might want to see.
Rym: It's my online gallery because it is still the best price per function feature.
Rym: Like it's the best service of that kind in the world in terms of how much I pay for it versus how much I get out of it.
Rym: The Lightroom stuff's OK, but it's sort of hard to share with my family and friends.
Rym: They seem more used to Flickr and I just don't want to change.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So Scott has over the years given me shit when he thinks that my thing of the day is too low hanging fruit.
Rym: And yet this is the second thing of the day in a row.
Rym: Scott has brought to the table that is literally just a tweet.
Scott: I accompanied my previous tweet only thing of the day with another thing.
Rym: Yeah, I'm just saying I'm just pointing out that your thing of the day is a link to a tweet.
Rym: You've set the bar at a particular point.
Scott: You've done tweet things the day before.
Rym: I've done tweet things the day many times and now I will no longer feel ashamed of doing so.
Rym: The point is, this one's pretty good though.
Scott: I got to say, though, the Internet has actually been producing fewer things of the day than it has in the past.
Rym: I got plenty.
Rym: I got a whole queue of weird Internet shit.
Scott: Anyway, so apparently this is I guess I don't know if there's a particular kind of caterpillar or caterpillars in general, but this apparently they react to sound, right?
Scott: It's these small vibrations in the air greatly disturb the caterpillars.
Scott: And if you yell, they shake a lot.
Scott: So when you get a situation, there's a lot of caterpillars altogether.
Scott: You can make noise and then they will all disrupt together and in some sort of audio visualization kind of thing.
Rym: Well, it's funny because a lot of fun.
Rym: I was watching the Vine compilations and that's a thing and other people have noticed this over the years.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So we have, you know, we got some caterpillar rave, somebody yelling at some caterpillars on the stoop and they go, nah.
Rym: I mean, I assume it's just a basic self-defense mechanism.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Maybe it's like because the air moves their little hairy bits.
Scott: that makes them confused and they move.
Rym: I don't think they're confused.
Rym: I think they detect it and it's some sort of threat response.
Scott: Caterpillar expert, call us.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So my thing of the day that is not the caterpillar thing is if you ever look at old computers, when I say old, I'm talking like you play a cassette tape into it to load a game and then play the game.
Scott: So Apple II and old Atari XT, Commodore.
Rym: There were these loading bars or loading bands.
Rym: you'd see it back in the day.
Rym: And I remember a lot of things doing this.
Rym: Basically, you'd see these bars just sort of appearing on the screen while the game was loading.
Scott: And they just happen that eventually those computers don't have a lot of hardware in them.
Scott: So the probably memory or registers that are shared between the video and the loading mechanism.
Scott: So probably like while you're loading, you don't need to show anything on the screen.
Scott: So it's probably like using that part of the computer to load it, you know that.
Scott: But as a result, there's a side effect of video appearing on the screen.
Rym: So in the oldest days, there was the pin on the chip, like the chip that did video stuff was also the pin that was used to take the audio data in.
Rym: Just how it works.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So like something like, oh, I don't have enough RAM, but I got this, you know, video frame buffer.
Scott: I'm not showing anything on the screen right now.
Scott: I'll use that as RAM because it's memory.
Scott: And then once I need to show something on the screen, I'll go back to having less RAM.
Rym: But a side effect of this was that those bands, even though they were sort of a random artifact, were actually useful.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, while if you're loading in the same program every time, you should be able to see if you see something different on the screen, you know that some loading thing happened wrong.
Rym: Well, it's not just that.
Rym: It's kind of like old network infrastructure, like old hubs and like old early network devices.
Rym: There'd be little LEDs that would light up or divide.
Rym: They'd light up when there was activity and they basically just piggybacked over the actual signals going over the wire.
Rym: But they also ended up indicating the level of activity because the two things were tied.
Rym: This is a very similar thing.
Rym: The appearance and width of the bands would give you a good indicator of how well you were getting the data, whether or not it was actually loading, et cetera.
Rym: And because people were used to them, you eventually get to this point to where later computers would actually implement the bands on purpose and the bands actually encode information.
Rym: An expert user could watch these bands and understand how well their loader was functioning.
Rym: And it got to the point to where these bands were literally 100 percent virtualized by applications.
Rym: And this is a like five minute video that actually goes into pretty good detail explaining the history of these loading bands.
Rym: And it's actually pretty fascinating, especially.
Rym: you'll probably enjoy this if you don't know anything about that era of computing.
Rym: There's a lot of tangents inside bits here.
Rym: You'll learn a lot about what computers were like back in the day.
Rym: There's a reason why the Nintendo Entertainment System or even the Atari 2600 was a far superior gaming machine to even the most advanced PCs of the day.
Scott: Well, because, you know, the PCs had to run a much wider range of software and a whole keyboard going on and all kinds of, you know, peripherals that the NES didn't have to deal with.
Scott: Yeah, the NES is very limited in some ways in order to become more advanced in other ways.
Rym: Yeah, the gaming on PCs back in the day was basically Garbo.
Rym: In the moment, the book of the book is still Emily Wilson's translation of The Odyssey.
Rym: It's great.
Rym: You should read it.
Rym: We're going to finish it soon and do the show on it, I assume.
Rym: Making progress?
Scott: Yeah, it's not when I ride the subway, which I did today, but it's not a long read.
Rym: If you read this translation, at least otherwise, our next big convention is probably going to be summer, which is hard to read, PAX West.
Rym: And then after that, it's into PAX Unplugged and the Anime NYC, probably there's a good chance.
Scott: I think it's Anime NYC, then Thanksgiving, then PAX Unplugged three weeks in a row.
Scott: One, two, three.
Rym: And then right after that, Anime NYC's first year was last year.
Scott: And the only reason we didn't go was because it was during PAX Unplugged.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And then right after that, I think we got Magfest and then PAX South and then PAX East and the cycle repeats.
Rym: A lot of PAX is coming up.
Scott: Before any conventions, it's going to be summer.
Scott: It's summertime.
Scott: Enjoy the summer.
Scott: Read The Odyssey on the Beach.
Rym: GeekNights content is going to be primarily focused on us being outside, not making content.
Rym: So whenever it rains, you'll see like GeekNights presents you ten episodes come in.
Rym: So, yeah, containers.
Rym: I think we've talked off and on about things like Docker and various containers.
Scott: It's weird because like this is on the one hand, it's sort of like a new hotness of technology.
Scott: But on the other hand, this has actually been around for some years now.
Rym: Well, the core concept has been around.
Scott: The actual thing has been around for years now.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I mean, there's a lot of different container formats and container platforms.
Scott: And I guess Docker is still the most well-known king one.
Scott: that is the one.
Rym: And there's a lot of reasons for that.
Rym: It's it's pretty well supported.
Rym: It's it's a pretty mature container platform at this point.
Scott: So it's so basically is that is the deal, right?
Scott: It's actually took me quite a while to figure out how these things actually fucking work because they didn't they don't.
Scott: all the documentation is like how to use the mode and the examples of even how to use them don't actually cover any real world use case.
Scott: They're all hello world that get you nowhere or they're someone made an application and none of them actually tell you what's actually happening.
Scott: They're just like, type this, then type this.
Scott: Congratulations.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now, that is both good and bad, because on one hand, I do want like the hello world to exist for everything, because I found back in the day when I was trying to write like a lot of soap code for Python and stuff back.
Rym: when I actually wrote code, what I'd find is that there'd always be like a hello world tutorial for some library and invariably they didn't actually even work.
Rym: like you copy paste an example in and it just wouldn't work and you couldn't ask anyone about it.
Rym: So I'm glad that that level exists here, like the babies first, like make it just work.
Rym: But at the same time, I do find in my professional experience that a lot of the people who are using things like Docker literally have no idea how they work.
Scott: No.
Scott: So here's the thing, right?
Scott: You got first.
Scott: you got to think about what problem are we trying to solve?
Scott: And there's a few problems that that these things, the new containers, Docker and all solve that were solved partially or in different ways by older technologies.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And a lot of people confuse the containers for those older technologies, because from a user experience, a user interface perspective, they seem very similar, even though they're doing something completely different.
Scott: So the main problem we're trying to solve is that you have one computer with one CPU, even if it's multi core, doesn't matter.
Rym: I would argue there's other problems you might be trying to solve, but I'll get back to One set of RAM, one hard drive, one network connection.
Scott: But you want to run multiple or develop really multiple applications that really don't go well together.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They can't be, you know, like you only got one network card, but you want to run like two things or two different IP addresses.
Scott: And so
Rym: now before the Linux Santas come in, yes, if you make a fully formed like Linux application that puts all its stuff and all its dependencies and all the right directories in the Linux file system that they shouldn't ever like interact with each
Scott: other, you can make, you know, one computer.
Scott: do all these things at once.
Scott: The problem is now you're trying to deploy this application or deliver it or have somebody else run it.
Scott: You know, you got someone, a new developer comes in, they got to work on it too.
Scott: Every system has to be perfectly identical because everything is so tied to the system.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or, you know, so one thing people did back in the days, we had things like truths and BSD jails, which is just better truths, but they're BSD only where you would log into a Unix machine and you as far as you knew, you were like a root and you would see this whole root file system.
Scott: You have permissions on the whole fucking thing.
Scott: But really, you were trapped in this little area on the file system of a bigger Unix system.
Scott: You just couldn't bust out and go up there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There was actually like if you were on the real system, you would see all these folders like slash something slash Rym.
Scott: And in that slash Rym would be a slash Etsy slash dev slash USRS, a full system in that directory.
Scott: But when Rym logs in, he's trapped in that little world.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, you know, that's that's one way to do it.
Scott: Another thing people would use a lot is just virtual machine, just have a whole virtual machine.
Scott: And the thing is, that actually works great.
Scott: You're completely container inside this whole VM system, but that kills you in terms of performance, first of all.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And second of all, it's doing a lot of things you don't need to do.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The point of a VM is like, OK, I need to pretend that I have, you know, like 10 network cards and I've only got, you know, one in the computer.
Scott: I need 10.
Rym: I'm just going to use software to pretend there's 10 video cards or just I want a bunch of applications running and I want them to act like they're the only thing running on top of this.
Rym: But so nothing there.
Scott: Simulating hardware with software is not an efficient way to do that necessarily, even though VMs have gotten real good, especially the CPU.
Rym: And we've talked about that before, like para virtualization versus full virtualization and all that nonsense.
Scott: And VMs also, if you're if you're a developer, VMs make working hard because now it's like even though you're on your computer, you got to like go into this other computer on your computer to access stuff and shared folders.
Scott: And so what the hell are these containers things?
Scott: How do they fucking work?
Scott: So here's the deal.
Scott: In Linux, they've added these two APIs.
Scott: They added them years ago, but there's a whole other things they've done.
Scott: But the major things they've done is they've added a feature called C groups and a feature called namespaces.
Scott: And what this does on a unit on a Linux system is you create a C group and you create some processes that are in the C group.
Scott: And what you can do is you can specify any.
Scott: it's called control group.
Scott: That's what the C is for.
Scott: Any processes in this control group can only access this much RAM, this much CPU, this much network, this much whatever.
Scott: And you can limit the resources available to certain processes so that they can't take over your whole system.
Scott: And that's sort of like what a virtual machine does, right, is where, you know, if you're, you know, using a VM, but you're really only you're not interested in simulating hardware, you're just interested in keeping some processes from, you know, using your whole system, then C groups pretty much cover that feature.
Scott: It just uses the Linux permissions thing to limit those, you know, processes from using thirty two gigs of RAM.
Rym: They've only got eight gigs because otherwise shared VMs, that's ten operating systems to keep up to date.
Scott: And now you don't need to run another copy of Linux kernel inside a VM and boot it and set that all up.
Scott: You just need to say, hey, these processes get these eight gigs of RAM.
Scott: the end of story.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that's what the C groups does.
Scott: The namespaces sort of covers the other part where it says, OK, these group of processes here, any process in this namespace can only see this part of the world.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They can only see each other.
Scott: They can only see these other processes.
Scott: They can only see these network and you're limiting their vision.
Scott: That's the truth.
Scott: And the BSD jails did.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you combine these two things together and you actually.
Scott: I've seen some tutorials online, people showing you they were hard to find where you can basically do exactly what Docker does just by using just the Unix, just your shell and just like catting certain, you know, and echoing certain things into various files in proc and dev to mostly proc to basically create C groups, create namespaces and put processes in them.
Scott: And then to prove that those were actually doing exactly the same thing that Docker is doing, they then use Docker commands to talk to the processes that were created in those C groups.
Scott: And it's the exact same thing.
Scott: So Docker is really just a wrapper, a convenience wrapper around these C group and namespace features.
Scott: Now, the value of the isolate processes on your OS, but they're basically those processes are running natively, just like any other process is running.
Rym: Now, the value of making that easier shouldn't really be understated, because in my experience, especially like, you know, in the modern world, like it's been a long time since the last time I was writing code or anything, it's actually pretty hard to hire very skilled developers who are also very fluent in Unix Linux.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: So that's been my problem at work.
Scott: forever is like I'm the king of Unix, basically, just because I happen to know what Linux was when I was in high school.
Scott: I used it like even in RIT.
Scott: It was often my primary OS when I wasn't gaming so much.
Rym: GeekNights was produced entirely in Linux for a long time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, not many people were Linux nerds.
Scott: So because I have those Linux, Unix skills, a lot of people don't have at work.
Scott: It's everyone else is a Mac and they don't know how to Linux, except that me.
Scott: So when it comes to things like DevOps and sysadmin, even though I'm programming is my job, I have all these other skills.
Rym: Speaking of which, if anyone out there is a senior skilled CC++ developer who also knows other languages and is a pretty much Linux expert like Scott, I am me.
Rym: You know me, I'm really looking to hire like six of you.
Scott: You have enough monies?
Rym: Yeah, I just can't find people like a million dollars.
Rym: Anyway, I just can't find six of them anyway.
Scott: So, yeah, so that's what's going on here.
Scott: The other thing Docker does that that beyond just managing your C group and and your namespace features of the kernel is they have this sort of repository package system of containers.
Scott: So you can basically make a Docker container, which is really just a list of instructions on how to make a system.
Scott: So it's sort of like, you know, OK, you know, do this command and this command and this command and I've got your container and then you can build a container from a container.
Scott: So what you eventually what you do in real life is you're like your first line of your container file is like Ubuntu version, whatever.
Scott: And then your next line is apt install this.
Scott: And then your next line is edit this config file.
Scott: And now that's that's how to build your container.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So then you take that container and you share it and other people can then go and just download that file.
Scott: or you deliver that file with your code or they use Docker install to get it from the main Docker repository.
Scott: And if you can just download this container and there it is, it's running.
Scott: so you can solve the problem, not just of separating and making your apps not touch each other on the same system, but you can solve the problem of, OK, I've got all these developers all using different computers, who knows what.
Scott: But anyone who wants to work on my application and develop this software, you can get clone and download the software, the code, and then you can type Docker up, Docker and Compose up.
Scott: And now look at that.
Scott: You've got the environment running.
Scott: You don't have to do any environment set up.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And that you don't have to know anything about environment set up or anything about.
Rym: In the previous era, like before, there were like easy ways to do this.
Rym: environment set up was a huge part of the rollout process, if anything I've ever been involved in.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, you would show up at a new job as a developer and it would take you like a day or change to set things up.
Rym: It took me three or four days to say, well, because I was doing IT, I wasn't coding.
Rym: But even then, I needed everyone had to have like a local VM that basically mirrored what the production systems are like.
Rym: You had an environment, there are tools.
Scott: that is vagrant, which is a tool that helps you do that with VirtualBox more easily.
Rym: But, you know, even then it was a pain in the ass.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So but people were amazed at my work when I had it running in like a day, like, I know what the hell I'm doing.
Scott: That's why you hired me.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the thing is, as cool as that all sounds on paper, the reality is that Docker is actually got a lot of crappy problems.
Scott: It's not great.
Scott: So first of all, right, using these Linux kernel APIs, guess what?
Scott: Windows and no access don't have those APIs.
Scott: Yeah, but who cares if you run and run Docker on Windows or OS X?
Scott: What's actually basically happening is you're running a virtual machine with a Linux kernel in it that you then talk to.
Rym: But honestly, who cares what's your server going to be but a Linux server?
Scott: Well, because you're talking about local development, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So the next problem that makes Docker kind of crappy is like this volumes thing, right, which I still don't fully understand.
Scott: But basically, you know, you still want to have some sort of.
Scott: it has to do with storage, right?
Scott: So you have some storage.
Scott: You want to have it shared between containers.
Scott: Maybe that's your source code is.
Scott: Maybe that's where, you know, your binaries are.
Rym: Or maybe you're using these containers on a production environment because you spin what you spin them up.
Scott: You got to be a database in a volume somewhere so that all these different, you know, database servers can all access something like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And basically the way the volumes are implemented, as far as I can tell, I know the details, but the result as a user of them is that is complete garbage.
Scott: It kills like an OS X or performance just goes to shit on Linux.
Scott: You have all these kinds of issues like files getting overwritten or permissions problems and all kinds of like.
Scott: you go into the container and in the container, your root for everything.
Scott: And then so that container writes to a volume and then you leave the container and now the file is root, even though in the other container it wasn't root and you can't get that.
Scott: You can't translate the user permissions over to the inside of the container.
Scott: You got issues like you do Docker up and you have a dependency.
Scott: You say, ah, don't start this container until that other container is started.
Scott: So the other container starts, but it hasn't actually started the application in the container yet.
Scott: But the other container has no way of knowing.
Scott: So now it fails to start up because the database isn't actually started.
Scott: And you're supposed to.
Scott: the solution for this.
Scott: The official solution is to write a wrapper script for everything, which is complete horseshit, duct tape, garbage.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not elegant or good at all.
Scott: So, you know, it's like as nice as this is like, ah, you've made a wrapper for these APIs that are otherwise difficult to use.
Scott: It's still really crappy and not well done and not nice.
Scott: So what I would recommend to people is if you want to solve the problems of I'm developing a software and I need other people to also develop the software who have different computers and I want them to be able to get up to speed quickly and not have to learn Unix, then I think Docker and other containers are a good solution for that because it makes it easy.
Scott: If you want to run your stuff in production, I do not recommend the Docker.
Rym: Yeah, well, well, so it depends on what you're putting in production, because an area that I actually have a lot of wood to cut right now is a bunch of microservices.
Rym: And Docker is actually pretty good for productionizing microservices in certain content.
Scott: If you've got something real simple, right.
Rym: Like if you want to make a real simple API that does really local stuff and provides like a rest interface for a limited set of interactions on one type of thing.
Scott: If you've got something so simple, it just runs.
Scott: It's one process.
Scott: It runs on its own.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It doesn't need a whole lot of dependencies and it's not complicated.
Scott: You can probably just make it in a container and get that container to run on some sort of, you know, serverless platform and it'll be just fine.
Rym: Because a big part of like modern delivery of software, especially web services or web facing tools or like big things in companies, is that there's a lot of physical infrastructure and a lot of machines and a lot of VMs and all this nonsense.
Rym: And environments get out of control or you've got to stage things from dev to QA to UAT to pre-production, to production, to scaled production.
Rym: And if you can break things down into these very simple microservices and Dockerize or use some sort of some way to make sure the environment within the local environment of each one of these services is identical in all these environments, regardless of the hardware or even the OS you might be on top of.
Rym: There's a huge operational win there.
Scott: If you can set it up.
Scott: The thing is, in reality, what I've seen is that most people who try to use these things like Docker pool and Kubernetes and all these platforms for Docker in production.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Where you basically, OK, my application has, you know, these processes.
Scott: There's this process that, you know, three processes.
Scott: I just set up a whole farm, just machines, and then I spin up any number of containers for those processes.
Scott: And if they fail, I spin up new ones and such and such.
Scott: And it's all magical.
Scott: Every basically almost anyone I've seen, like, try to set that up has been a disaster.
Scott: And they have not.
Scott: the benefits have not been reaped.
Rym: I have reaped those benefits and I have that shit working.
Rym: But unfortunately, I'm at a level of the way I interact with my engineering teams that I don't see the details of how they make this happen.
Scott: The point is, if you have the skills to sort of make that happen, well, you could have just set up servers, right?
Scott: You don't.
Scott: the Docker in that case is really only saving you the trouble of having to know things about this.
Scott: It's not really saving you any other trouble.
Rym: I put it this way, use containers if they solve a problem you have.
Rym: that isn't just.
Rym: I don't know how to set up a single Linux server.
Rym: If you're running one Linux server for production and one for UAT and one for dev, you probably don't need Docker.
Rym: You can probably keep those in sync.
Scott: Because like the namespaces issue is about keeping you separating the resources on the machine.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But in production, the only thing running on the machine is your application.
Scott: What else is running on there?
Scott: It's not a local development machines.
Scott: You don't need the namespaces and the secret.
Rym: Unless your production is so big that you've got like 20 different services you're providing.
Scott: So the C groups are to manage the resources.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Don't let this process use more than 25 percent of the CPU, stuff like that.
Scott: But if you're have a big server farm, you can just use.
Scott: you're probably using some sort of pair of virtualization.
Scott: And even though it's one hardware machine, like one giant one thing on a rack, it's actually running multiple VMs in it.
Scott: So you've split things up that way.
Scott: You don't need another layer of splitting up.
Scott: We've already got the pair of virtualization.
Rym: Know what you need your layer for.
Rym: There's like this too.
Rym: You can use things like Docker to make consistent development environments.
Rym: And there's a whole set of challenges and values and pros and cons there.
Rym: And then using this for production services is a different problem.
Rym: And it's a very it's a very different space to decide if it's actually worth it or not.
Scott: And also, you know, and like I said, there's a lot of hassles.
Scott: You're basically trading one hassle for another.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like you can avoid some Munich stuff and some set up and some labor, but that stuff is almost always just going to work.
Scott: Whereas if you go to Docker, you can avoid doing some of that work.
Scott: Instead, you got to deal with these hassles.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The shit not working.
Rym: Well, more importantly, my real my real worry is that a lot of orchestration of, you know, a lot of people at that stage in like a production environment might use something like Docker because it's easy, but not fully understand the ramifications of the way they've set it up.
Scott: I don't think security holes, most people, performance problems, the people I have seen using it don't have.
Scott: even the ones who are pretty good at it and understand, you know, you know, configuring it and making Docker files don't actually understand how it works at the cgroups and the namespaces and all that stuff.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They just sort of, you know, they don't understand.
Scott: People don't understand there's between a container and a VM.
Rym: But if you're using that just to make development environments, at least that's relatively safe.
Rym: Like the damage you could do is minimal.
Scott: That's what I think it's I think is good for.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But don't just take Dockers and deploy them into production.
Rym: If no one on your team can go deep into what Docker is actually doing with the US, you need at least one person who understands what it's doing on the low level.
Scott: Now, the the the one benefit of using Docker in production, right, is that you have a situation where, you know, people are developing locally, right?
Scott: They're using the Docker to make it easy.
Scott: But in production, right, the environment might be different than local.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you use Docker, the one major thing you can do is that to make sure the production environment is the same as the local environment.
Scott: And you can do this with or without using Docker in production.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You can simply make sure that the Docker file creates an environment that's identical to the production one because it's just Linux.
Rym: You could version your Dockers, you have Dockers that reflect various planned stages of production.
Scott: So it's like, OK, in production, we're using this Linux distribution.
Scott: So your Docker container makes that Linux distribution.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And now you made sure it's identical.
Scott: So people are developing in an environment that's identical to the production one.
Scott: And if you do end up using Docker in production, well, then you're definitely using the same exact environment because you're using the same Docker file.
Scott: And this makes it really easy if you have had lots of problems at work in the day when everyone's developing on Macs and then problems appear when stuff goes to production, because guess what?
Scott: They were developing on OS X and the server is not OS X.
Rym: Or you got a complex system with a lot of dependencies and multiple engineering teams.
Rym: At that point, you might be in situations where you could use things like Docker.
Rym: So people who are writing code that will go to production later might be using a Docker that has the updated set of dependencies that's going to be in production at one point.
Rym: And it makes it a lot easier to coordinate when code is production.
Rym: All its dependencies are in production at that time without having to maintain a million VMs.
Scott: Another thing you can do, for example, is let's say you write in a Python app.
Scott: It's just a Python script.
Scott: And you make a container for your Python script.
Scott: And in your container file, you're pretty much there's Python containers available to download.
Scott: You just make a Docker file.
Scott: And the first line is going to be like, it's going to be two lines.
Scott: The first line is going to be, you know, start with the container Python colon version number.
Scott: And the second line is going to be execute my script, Python space, my script.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So you want to test the script, the different versions of Python, just edit the Docker file, run it, edit the Docker file, run it.
Scott: And now you're testing all these different versions of Python without having to install a hundred different versions of Python on your OS.
Rym: Actually, that's a good point.
Rym: That's one use case I've seen.
Rym: You can
Scott: keep downloading all these different containers or building all these different containers with all these different versions of things and run your same code and test it in all these different versions to see, you know, and if you're the kind of if you're making software that needs to be deployed in situations where different versions of things.
Scott: Oh, I want to test my web app on Apache 2 and Apache 2.1 or not.
Scott: even that new version of Ubuntu came out with very complex versions.
Rym: A big problem is actually maintaining and running unit tests against code.
Rym: that actually gets problematic because you might have very complex unit tests that change the state of an environment.
Rym: And I've seen some recent modern QA processes spin up a million different Dockers, each of which is a self-contained environment to test one particular thing is most of the.
Scott: if you look around, if you want to try out containers for testing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's many equivalent, I'm not endorsing this one.
Scott: It's just one I know of.
Scott: But it's CircleCI and they have a free tier.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So what you do, I don't know about them.
Scott: You get it's continuous integration.
Scott: Right.
Scott: This is a super popular thing.
Scott: GitLab has it built in.
Scott: But you basically you go to GitHub, you make your get your thing.
Scott: You go to CircleCI, you get the free tier.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's a free tier.
Scott: I think it's like one one unit or whatever.
Scott: And you basically hook it up to your GitHub.
Scott: You put a dot CircleCI file with instructions and how to run your tests and stuff.
Scott: And then what happens is basically any time you merge into your thing, it's going to take your.
Scott: it's going to go to CircleCI.
Scott: CircleCI is going to use Docker to create a container that runs your app according to your instructions.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they can just do this because they can.
Scott: they can run everyone in the whole world.
Scott: They can run all everyone's apps no matter what you're developing, because they're just making containers and turning them on, running tests in the container.
Rym: That is way easier than like Jenkins running a bunch of unit tests against your environment.
Scott: Maybe that's basically what Jenkins does, too.
Scott: It's basically this is a host of Jenkins.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But you can use Jenkins to do the same thing.
Scott: You make suddenly you got a testing server.
Scott: It needs to test all these different applications.
Scott: It can test anything as long as it runs in a container.
Scott: All it does is turn on container, execute command in container, close container.
Rym: But that's very good for the information for the test unit tests that change the state of the environment or especially negative unit tests that test against a broken on purpose environment.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So, you know, you can basically have your tests run in containers and then you can have these servers that can run any test on anything as long as it's in a container.
Rym: So I really say like a lot of a lot of people listen to GeekNights or younger and they're still in college or they're early in their career.
Rym: You want to have a guaranteed job, be good at both Linux and Docker.
Rym: I mean, you know, if you can be good at both of them, you can solve the kinds of problems that a lot of mid-tier companies have.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, the problem is, is you don't write code, is not that Linux skills are not valuable.
Scott: It's that a lot of people don't value them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Their companies will just get by without learning Linux, though, though, instead of having someone learn how to build a container testing platform and they'll just pay someone else to pay the Circle C.I.
Scott: or the Jenkins or, you know, those pay that.
Scott: then the containers are allowing people to sort of offload knowledge to these centralized companies.
Scott: And they're right.
Rym: Like there is a time and a place to do that.
Scott: The Azures and the Googles with all their, you know, their cloud hosting, basically cloud providers have all the people who have real knowledge about things and then everyone else just pays them and does things the easy baby way and doesn't have anyone working for them.
Rym: But there's not necessarily anything wrong with that.
Rym: That comes down to the stuff that I deal with on the business level.
Rym: What is the thing you're doing and how does that make money?
Rym: And whenever possible, it's not always the best idea, but sometimes a good idea to find the things that don't actually matter to the way you're making money and pay someone else to handle it.
Scott: Problem is those things don't matter until they matter.
Scott: And then you hire people.
Scott: Yeah, it's like it's like, oh, I did everything with these containers.
Scott: Everything's beautiful.
Scott: And then you go live and then your application gets more complex and then, oh, my God, this doesn't work anymore.
Rym: Well, that's the thing.
Rym: What's the scale of what you're doing and set your resources appropriately?
Rym: The GeekNights Forum is just a Docker we download and run.
Scott: Well, yeah, I mean, because that's a good example, right?
Scott: So because back in the day, when you would want to run a Web app, it'd be written in PHP and PHP was done in such a way that you set up your Web server like Apache and you put files in a folder, which anyone can do, even unmanaged hosting, and then it runs.
Scott: You don't have to do anything.
Scott: You just got to type in the MySQL username and password and you're done.
Scott: Right now, if you want to run a Python Web application that's not written in PHP, you can't.
Scott: just I don't know why they didn't make it this way.
Scott: They could have where they could have made it.
Scott: We just put Python files in a folder and they run, but they don't.
Scott: it doesn't work that way.
Scott: You have to run a Python server interpreter and then Apache or Nginx proxies to that.
Scott: That's how it works, which means if you want to if you write a Web application in Python, which is very easy to do, getting into production compared to PHP is for someone who doesn't know, Unix is way hard.
Scott: You can't just put the files you wrote in a folder.
Scott: You have to set up a server, install libraries, do all this stuff, configure Apache.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the containers, they make that problem go away.
Scott: The forum software we use is written in Ruby.
Scott: It needs all that same stuff.
Scott: So instead they want installation for people to run the forum to be easy.
Scott: People who don't have the knowledge, they want them to be able to run this forum software with having to learn anything or do a complicated setup.
Scott: So the instructions are pretty much download the code, type in these couple of commands and make sure you have Docker installed and the form will start and you don't have to do anything.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But again, look at our use case, look at our performance needs.
Rym: There's a look at our operational needs.
Rym: Neither one of us wants to futz around with anything for like GeekNights hosting.
Scott: And then, you know, for example, they have features built.
Scott: on top of that, like when there's an update to the forum, you push a button and the container turns off.
Scott: The content doesn't get pulled.
Scott: The container turns on again and rebuilds itself and so on.
Rym: I think I'm hungry, so we can just stop there.
Rym: I think I'm also also.
Rym: someone just came in expecting a debate on Rubbermaid.
Scott: That was the joke I made before the show.
Scott: You're too slow.
Rym: Should we?
Rym: That could be our next Thursday show.
Scott: I don't have much to say other than buy the glass snap.
Rym: Yeah, the moral is glass is superior, plastic inferior.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon Dangers for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver, Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Heidi McNicholas, Shimmer and Rubiablos, Hanging in the Sky, MyStainty.com, Jeremy Miner, Link Iggi, Roberto Kingsley, Kelly Snyder, Cold Guy, Amanda Duchette, Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brando, Mr.
Rym: Strong Streshen, 421 Creations, no I never ever wonder why we're here.
Rym: Semper Fi, bitch, Shervin Von Horl, Rory, James David White, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, Tripwire, Sailor Vista, Don Schleich, Jar Tovjian, Jojo Joestar, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Opendlander, Finn, Chris Minkif, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.