Rym: It's Wednesday February 7th 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We're finally talking about the delightful little witch academia.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So how about this weather?
Rym: it sure is raining in New York City?
Rym: Just kind of a shitty day and Scott Thought that was the first thing he thought of for like the opening bit to the show.
Rym: so here we go.
Scott: Why don't we just skip the opening?
Rym: because get the opening big.
Rym: got to the opening bit.
Rym: there's nothing going on Stuff going on.
Rym: There'll be no GeekNights next week cuz I'm gonna be out of town.
Scott: He's supposed to save that for the meta moment.
Scott: What are you doing?
Rym: because the rain is actually.
Rym: it has a direct impact on why I'm going out of town Mm-hmm, so it's rain down here.
Rym: You're going where it's dry because that's the bottom half of a big ol snowstorm.
Rym: That's going up where I'm gonna be cuz I'm gonna be skiing out in New Hampshire all week.
Rym: I do on the annual trip.
Scott: This is your last episode of GeekNights everybody.
Rym: Yeah one thing this season Stuff's changed.
Rym: like I ski a lot, but I kind of did up my game from a good skier to a real good skier I think And I'm excited to go back to this place, but
Scott: the only thing is ever heard of the Dunning Kruger face,
Rym: I'm well beyond that I'm just crude.
Rym: But one thing I'll say is that every year when I go to this place There's one mountain there that we never go to cannon Mountain.
Rym: because all the locals say So the way that mountain is facing supposedly all the other mountains in the area are kind of shielded from the wind So the snow lands on any way it's facing.
Scott: mountains are cones Facing in all directions.
Rym: skiing part very few mountains.
Rym: you go to the top and ski off in any direction.
Rym: Usually there's like a direction to go like one side of the mountain.
Scott: one side of the mountains like you know Flatter and one side is straight up and down for most downhill skiing unless you're doing off-pitch stuff.
Rym: They will Remove trees and make paths you're supposed to scan like they make a play.
Scott: Why don't they just do it on both sides?
Rym: Uh, because then you gotta build lifts on both sides and that's pain in the ass There's usually no reason to.
Scott: I guess.
Rym: I guess yeah some mountains have a little cuz.
Scott: you could go lift on one side Ski down the other lifts lift up the side.
Rym: Yeah, so some mountains do stuff like that.
Rym: some of the mountains I go to like loom There's like twice as much to this place to die.
Rym: Yes, you ski up and you ski down to a different place.
Rym: The only problem is two lodges.
Rym: when they're that big one at the bottom and you could two parking lots, dude I bet there's ski places.
Rym: I've been to with two hotels six different lodges.
Rym: The only problem is you might ski somewhere and get lost and then you're at some lodge.
Rym: There's nowhere near your car.
Scott: I'm thinking one mountain with a lot of different bottoms, right?
Scott: So that way you're nicely you can't get lost.
Scott: you can go to the top of the mountain and go down to any bottom you Want but you just got to remember which one has your car, but also some mountains like at hunter.
Rym: There's one way to go down and at 3 30 the lift over there shuts down and there's no road that goes there.
Scott: Well, don't do that.
Rym: If you ski over there good you get to walk a long way around the mountain.
Scott: They should just have at least have a shuttle bus.
Rym: What they do is they rope it off and the only people have this problem are people who go under the rope.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: Yeah but The snow is looking pretty good because.
Rym: but anyway, so I've always wanted to ski at this place called the midder cell Which is connected to the mountain we don't go to because it's facing the wrong way.
Rym: So all the snow blows off of it supposedly.
Rym: so the midder cell.
Rym: the deal with it is it was a ski resort a long time ago and It shut down and went bankrupt.
Rym: but for decades People would ski on the still active ski place that's next to it.
Rym: But they just hike over there and ski in the abandoned ski resort because that's fucking awesome.
Scott: What didn't?
Scott: new trees grow in it because no one does keep knocking.
Rym: that made it even more awesome.
Scott: Okay, this is definitely less So.
Rym: Eventually the government and the ski resort everyone were like, alright if people are doing this.
Rym: Anyway, let's put a lift over there.
Rym: So people can just ski on this thing.
Rym: But the deal is they maintain the barest minimum level of safety But they don't groom it or do any of the stuff that the normal ski resort would.
Rym: so it's basically just wilderness.
Rym: That once was a ski resort.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and it seems awesome.
Scott: Now they turned it from a ski resort to an abandoned mountain into a death trap.
Rym: Yeah So it's not actually that dangerous because I now that I got an oculus riff one thing I did is I went to all the Ski resorts and I actually went over and looked at this thing and saw like what it would be like to ski over there.
Rym: It ain't actually that big or that exciting and I could have the same sort of wilderness experience Just by poaching on any other normal mountain.
Rym: So I think I'm gonna skip this place.
Rym: So the oculus saved me the trouble of going and finding out how underwhelming this place actually is.
Rym: Mm-hmm That is my story, but it is not ski day.
Rym: It's anime day.
Rym: So what do ya got?
Rym: some news?
Scott: I do have a new.
Rym: why isn't there a skiing anime about hot ski boys?
Scott: There might be.
Rym: there will be someday.
Scott: make one.
Scott: Anyway, so there's this guy named Dan slot, right and he his job for the past ten years has been to write Spider-man comics, I mean other people obviously have written spider-man comics besides him in the past ten years, but he's been the number one guy.
Rym: Yeah, well, he's what he's the amazing spider-man like default spider-man.
Scott: Yeah, and the thing is Dan slot writes Real good.
Scott: Like I actually like it.
Scott: if I see him writing something.
Scott: that's a good sign.
Scott: There's actually a recent Silver Surfer comic series that like started and ended and The art Dan slot wrote it and the art is done by what's the guy's name?
Scott: Why do I keep forgetting this guy's name?
Scott: I haven't really read any spider-man anyway, um Anyway, it's oh my god.
Scott: I'm so mad.
Scott: I can't remember the guy's name.
Scott: Anyway, there's a recent Silver Surfer series.
Scott: The Dan slot wrote with this the artist.
Scott: why I can't remember his name?
Rym: and I just start saying names of artists.
Scott: No, it's like top tier.
Scott: It's just all red Mike all red.
Scott: Okay, if you see Mike all right, you might not know the name Mike all red.
Scott: But if you see his art, it's it's unique.
Scott: You'll be like that fucking guy.
Scott: It's it's you know, it's one of those.
Rym: We're like you said like when you see sanctuary and you're like at the manga and you're like, it's that guy exactly.
Scott: It's like an art style that is completely unique and that you can totally tell it's him.
Rym: Yeah, lazy Matsumoto first way exactly.
Scott: So there's that recent Silver Surfer survey.
Scott: Silver Surfer series is amazing and I want to read it.
Scott: It's like on my list as I'm like Kindle or whatever.
Scott: Anyway, the news is that after 10 years of spider-man.
Scott: Dan slot is now gonna write Iron Man and I hate Iron Man.
Scott: I'm in son.
Rym: I don't know why you hate Iron Man sucks.
Rym: Iron Man is like short of the alcoholism.
Rym: He's basically you but rich it.
Scott: yes piece of shit Anyway But maybe this will be the best Iron Man comic ever.
Rym: See the problem is I like characters.
Rym: I like stories that have characters that I hate.
Rym: I don't know why you hate Iron Man stories so much.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: but the thing is like I've been a fan of Dan slot actually for like a way long time even before the spider-man because when he First read when he when it first came out ten years ago He was writing the spider-man and I actually think I actually have the first spider-man comic he wrote I was like, wait a minute that seems familiar.
Scott: and I checked and it was true that the 1990s Marvel comics of Ren and Stimpy were written by Dan slot.
Scott: And if you haven't read really if you haven't read that I did not know that.
Scott: if you haven't read those They are hysterical and awesome and you can see that same Humor writings in the spider-man and hopefully we can get some humorous Iron Man.
Rym: Yeah, I think you'll get some good Iron Man.
Scott: Yeah, so there you go.
Scott: No one cares about this news, but now you maybe semi-related lamblin.
Rym: I actually I actually watched spider-man homecoming.
Rym: Okay, and it was probably the best spider-man movie they've ever made so far.
Scott: Mmm, I guess there's not a lot of kind of a better one.
Rym: Sure, the least smelly poop other than that old what 60s cartoon because that is not a movie though How it is, however, one of the most memorable things on earth.
Rym: Yeah That alone will make it famous forever amazing friends.
Rym: But the one thing I'll say not even a geek bite but spider-man homecoming pretty good.
Rym: The only trouble with it is one.
Rym: the only memorable moment Music wise in the entire soundtrack and score is in the very beginning.
Rym: They evoke the spider-man theme like the one, you know Once and otherwise, it's the Marvel movie problem where it's just this bullshit score that goes nowhere.
Scott: And that was probably on your mind too because you saw the YouTube video.
Rym: I was thinking about it the whole time.
Rym: every time a song swelled in the background I was like this might as well be in Winter Soldier or whatever, which I didn't even say.
Rym: Like it literally energy.
Rym: This is the sad song.
Rym: This is the miniboss song.
Rym: This is the climax saw.
Scott: no one's buying these, you know, I think also I was wondering Cuz back in the day we used to buy movie soundtracks with money.
Scott: Yeah, I bought the Independence Day sound You know, I bought these Star Wars episode 1 soundtrack Not just the original ones but I even bought like the matrix soundtrack was just a collection.
Rym: Yeah, see the problems.
Rym: we keep saying bought but actually it was downloaded.
Scott: Oh, no, this was night late early mid 90s.
Scott: I bought some.
Rym: yeah, I did buy.
Rym: well, yeah, I bought a few anyway.
Scott: yet now there's no buying of soundtracks.
Rym: Right video games actually been really pushing that hard.
Rym: There is a big market for buying soundtracks to video games.
Scott: I'll also listen to on Spotify.
Scott: But anyway, the point is is that because you're not making that extra money off the music?
Scott: is that?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: if it is I'm just Hypothesizing does that?
Scott: is that a reason that the movies are not bothering to me?
Scott: Original score because you're not making any money back on it.
Scott: So just do it cheap.
Rym: in Gennaro cuz I mean we at my family we had the star.
Scott: We're making the same amount of money on the movie.
Scott: If not more right.
Scott: We had Star Wars vinyls when I was a kid Yeah, and then I still have a Star Wars cassette tape to to cassette tape set.
Scott: Because when the special when the special edition came out as bad as the special editions were they put all the soundtracks back out And the special edition soundtracks on cassette and CD were just fine.
Rym: Actually a lot of those a lot of people really are not.
Scott: they do not specialize the soundtracks other than to make them 5.1 or whatever.
Rym: and also a lot of people are really down on cassettes because they seemed like this sort of interim bad technology.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: Well Vinyl there.
Rym: I the usually when cassettes sounded bad.
Rym: It was because it was a cheapo cassette or The thing you're playing it back on was a piece of shit player.
Rym: Yep, like that the kind of thing with the vinyl vinyl sounds a lot better Was used too much and worn out like a VHS, yeah Yeah, but I was fighting.
Rym: my homecoming was pretty good.
Rym: The only other complaint I had was that as good as it was it was like 15 to 20 minutes too long Mmm, and it had one too many fights.
Scott: I think I'm a little spider-man mood, you know, you should watch it.
Scott: It's not that kind of span.
Scott: I think I get some spider-man comics and make you read him.
Scott: No All right, maybe I'll get some old ones that you won't like.
Rym: If I don't like him I'll still read him.
Scott: we'll talk about it.
Scott: I'll get some old ones you won't like and also some dance a lot.
Scott: Read some spider-man.
Rym: The other funny thing was that you plays the villain in homecoming Michael Keaton, it's a Batman.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah the best Batman in my opinion.
Rym: So in some other news you might have noticed this.
Rym: we just never talked about it is it?
Rym: but there's it's.
Rym: see I don't know spider-man villains because I never really read spider-man or being Rhino Green Goblin.
Scott: So the villain is doctor octopus.
Rym: There's the crew that leans up after alien superhero shit happens and this dude Runs like a demolition company that has the contract with New York City to do it.
Rym: Okay, and then the in the Marvelverse the real government comes in and says no no, no, no government's doing this now.
Rym: So he just keeps all the alien tech that he found and builds this giant like owl hawk suit and flies around The vulture.
Rym: maybe I don't know spider-man villain.
Scott: I think it's the vulture.
Rym: They don't really get into it.
Rym: as far as I can tell he is just Michael Keaton Who lost his union job and turned to a life of crime sounds like vulture to me?
Scott: Vultures the old man who makes like a green robot suit and flies around.
Rym: but yeah, the suits really good though But the movies good partly because it does not do the origin story at all.
Rym: It's just you fucking know who spider-man is.
Rym: Here's spider-man.
Rym: He's already spider-man.
Rym: That's it there.
Rym: at no point Do you have to worry about how he becomes spider-man.
Rym: at no point does he have to worry about great power great responsibility?
Rym: It's just I'm spider-man.
Rym: There's a guy doing trouble.
Rym: I'ma get him.
Rym: so There's a short anime thing that you might have noticed around the internet occasionally, but you've probably seen this.
Scott: I saw the title of it somewhere.
Rym: Yeah Aggressive Retsuko or just a Gretsuko.
Scott: I saw the word a Gretsuko recently before you told me about it But I didn't look into it any further.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So it's a Sanrio thing and the basic story is there's no Hello Kitty.
Rym: Yeah, there's this cute red panda girl and she gets a job at her dream company, but she's basically like in.
Scott: what's the company?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: What do they do?
Rym: Who knows but she always wanted to work there But apparently her job is in the mail room and all her co-workers are pieces of shit.
Scott: Yeah, I guess I mean if you work in the mail room, even at like the best company like, you know There is in the whole world.
Scott: It fucking sucks.
Rym: So her co-workers suck and they're mean to her and her life starts to suck.
Scott: Why would you be mean to the cute red panda?
Rym: So by day, she's cute red panda doing her terrible office job and by night She takes all of the anger and rage in her heart from this shitty day job and converts it directly into death metal.
Scott: So it's Detroit metal city only with a cute red panda.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So it's hello Detroit metals.
Scott: Hello metal city.
Rym: So there were some shorts, I guess I'm like TBS Saturday morning Like there was something.
Rym: but now Sanrio and Netflix teamed up to make it a 10 episode 15 minute along episode series.
Rym: that's just gonna be on Netflix.
Scott: Detroit metal city was also short series without a lot of episodes and we got a trailer.
Scott: Sure, not many episodes and short in length.
Scott: We
Rym: don't know who's doing the voice acting in this but already it sounds like it's some people we know But I couldn't look up who it was to confirm And it looks like the right level of production values and humor and I feel like it's gonna be worth watching.
Scott: Mmm, that's I'll give that an episode cuz mostly because I ran out of Detroit metal city.
Rym: Yep Also Detroit metal city as much as I liked it.
Rym: It definitely had flaws.
Rym: like it was not the greatest show No, it's still amazing Repetitive.
Scott: it is perfect.
Rym: You really only needed to see a Couple episodes and then the one that ends with.
Rym: but after all I'm a masochist Which I think is the best episode.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: unless you lived under a rock you've probably seen this steamed hams meme Everywhere like you know, you might have heard it on GeekNights months ago.
Scott: It was my thing of the day way before it was a big thing.
Scott: like it is now I got in riding the ground floor.
Scott: cuz I'm cool.
Scott: I'm so smart.
Rym: I don't know if you did it first or I did because I had a thing of the day a while ago.
Rym: That was team hams set to a piano soundtrack.
Scott: someone go and check and I did Steamed hams guitar hero and that was.
Rym: that might have been.
Rym: you might have beaten me.
Rym: I think I remember that.
Scott: being first that was the first I'm pretty sure like That was like the day steamed hams began.
Rym: Well as a thing the thing is steamed hams well before it became a modern meme was a Simpsons episode.
Scott: not well No, it was part of a Simpsons.
Rym: It was basically in my legit top 10 Simpsons scenes that I find funny in all of the Simpsons.
Scott: It's just one of my favorite bits.
Scott: I mean, I mean, it's good, but it's not one of my favorite.
Rym: It's no the shinin.
Scott: Yes The chin and it's always number one.
Scott: It can't be beat.
Rym: It's invincible Don't mind if I do.
Rym: But steamed hams is legit funny.
Rym: and To bring this around to its Wednesday of all the steamed hams edits.
Rym: This one had the most care and effort.
Scott: I mean, there's a lot of them now that are way way way way way better than that guitar hero one I did.
Scott: Yeah, does that guitar hero one was so early It didn't have the stiff Competition and thus it made it to things of the day.
Scott: if I had to pick a steamed ham today that wouldn't even make the Top 10.
Rym: so not even I found this and I started watching it while Scott was in the other room getting ready to do the show And all I hear is Scott yell from the other room.
Rym: That sounds like some Gundam.
Rym: This is steamed hams edited to be like an episode of old Gundam.
Scott: I saw this a few days ago.
Scott: I don't even think this is top five.
Rym: It's top ten, but you're right.
Rym: It's not top five.
Scott: The problem is I've seen some ones that are so good.
Rym: The problem is the ones that are the best are a little high concept and a little like they're there.
Scott: I saw I saw a JPEG on Twitter.
Scott: That was Junji Ito.
Scott: stick Right, it's like come on.
Rym: I just love that.
Rym: This is a thing.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So what do you have for me?
Scott: So we talked about Japanese animation a lot.
Scott: we talked about comics from all countries a lot.
Scott: We talked about animation from Ireland and US and all the places right but one thing kind of animation We don't talk about a lot is animation.
Scott: That's not really done anymore.
Scott: Nah, which is the animations of the likes of which we saw in the Monty Python days.
Scott: It's a bunch of crap from magazines and cut it out and move it around a lot like South Park did with construction paper.
Scott: Yeah, only he used photographs and other things, you know same idea.
Rym: It's hard to understate or it's hard to overstate really how Desperately funny I to this day find money Python.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it's still like the best anyway, so Those animations like.
Scott: no one's done animation like that Before or since.
Scott: It's never been like part of a real, you know thing right it's like doesn't Like what like there's a lot.
Scott: what movie does that?
Scott: what TV show does that?
Rym: I've just seen like shorts and things on YouTube.
Scott: Yeah, sure But there's no.
Scott: no one's like.
Scott: not that nobody on earth is doing this.
Scott: I'm saying like no movie TV show or you know, mass publicized media is using that sort of thing.
Scott: Anyway This video my thing of the day is incredible because Here is here is Terry Gilliam sitting with somebody I don't know who.
Scott: it is some some British TV person showing you exactly how he does it.
Scott: He's got the actual cutouts he used in the real animations and he's showing you how they move.
Scott: and it's like.
Scott: it is way way Fascinating and it makes you think oh man, I could do that.
Scott: It's like I know not really I can't do that it I'm pretty sure.
Rym: I saw this on a VHS tape at some point.
Scott: It definitely looks like someone took this from a VHS tape and put it on YouTube.
Scott: But man that VHS tape was in good condition.
Rym: Yeah, well, I'm seeing VHS tapes actually had higher quality than most TVs could display.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: I Kind of want to watch the Monty Python now.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Rym: I'm feeling it.
Rym: Have we ever?
Rym: Reviewed a Monty Python thing on gig night.
Scott: Yes There's like one of the first episodes.
Scott: the ignites is Monty Python.
Scott: cuz at that time when GeekNights are starting in 2005 We were watching every single episode on.
Scott: that's right.
Rym: Cuz we had that box set that my mom got me every single episode.
Rym: I Just wonder what I feel like.
Rym: maybe we could get away.
Scott: We could go watch like the Holy Grail.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Rym: Yeah, we We talked.
Rym: no, no, no, we've never done it.
Scott: How have we not?
Scott: it's not possible.
Scott: Is that an episode?
Rym: Here's the only one.
Rym: here's the only one.
Scott: did Rym delete this episode?
Scott: He planned this in advance.
Scott: Uh My thing of the day that I definitely didn't tell him before Tuesday Thursday March 27 2008 that the episode is called.
Rym: What do we do?
Rym: Tonight on GeekNights.
Rym: We had intended to talk about Monty Python.
Rym: Instead after some politics Scott repeatedly We got sidetracked by some some shitty thing that happened in politics and we ended up talking for an hour about politics Instead of talking about Monty Python.
Scott: Another great reason to not talk about politics on geek and whatever.
Rym: the thing is that we talked about is gone.
Rym: It's too.
Rym: 404 errors.
Rym: So I have no idea all.
Rym: I'm afraid we spend much of tonight's show talking about something very sad.
Rym: We're really mad about something.
Rym: in 2008 Scott drove the entire conversation And I don't think there's any way to know what the fuck we talked about.
Rym: Hmm now I'm really curious.
Scott: who like those kinds of episodes of GeekNights.
Scott: Well, they're still out there.
Rym: uh, oh I figured out what it was.
Scott: Oh you went to the forum the fuck.
Rym: So I still don't know.
Rym: but the forum is all posts like wow that really turns my stomach You know, like people are like, oh, I didn't even want to do this episode.
Rym: Oh That's tough.
Rym: I think it's parents not treating their kids because they're religious and then the kids die.
Scott: Oh, is that what I think?
Rym: that's what we were talking about.
Scott: Yeah, I remember that.
Rym: Yep So I feel like we've never talked about Monty Python and GeekNights.
Rym: Mmm think that's gotta happen.
Scott: Mmm.
Rym: I think we should walk.
Rym: Should we?
Rym: should we review the Holy Grail or life of Brian?
Scott: The Holy Grail is the Holy Grail true, but life of Brian is also the holy.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah But only figuratively.
Scott: was the other one is literally and figured.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, anyway in the meta moment We are book club book is Emily Wilson's new modern translation of the Odyssey by Homer.
Rym: Oh, man Writing Homer like us talking Homer were they not the same?
Scott: I want to go like a thousand two thousand years three thousand years in the future.
Scott: Will people be confused between Human history between the different homeless.
Rym: I mean already kids on the internet today Think that a lot of things they make fun of or reference came from the Simpsons.
Scott: I want it's literally.
Rym: do not know that the Simpsons was itself referencing older thing.
Scott: at some point those kids will be old people and we will all be dead and That will be the knowledge of humanity.
Rym: What was that video I found where someone was like check out all these references you missed and one of them was saying Badges, we don't need no stinking badges.
Rym: and they were like.
Rym: this was a joke on this episode of the Simpsons.
Rym: Yes, how many people right what at least go back to Beverly Hills?
Rym: Girl Scout movie.
Scott: How do you know how else which I saw the how do you know that in treasure of Sierra Madre when they Say badges, we don't need no stinking badges.
Scott: They are not in turn referencing something from that is even older that we do not know.
Rym: I'm confident that it is from that.
Rym: how Confident, you know what?
Rym: I'm gonna start trying to get people to believe that it actually came first.
Rym: in true, Beverly Hills.
Scott: I think the problem is most people believe is from Blazing Saddles and not treasure.
Scott: How many people are sitting there thinking I was it wasn't the Simpsons it was Blazing Saddles.
Scott: Turns out the Scott knows more than you do.
Scott: Tell you guys in fact is willing to believe that someone else knows more than he does and that church there Madre wasn't the first.
Rym: I'm telling you guys.
Rym: It's true, Beverly Hills Sure, which I remember.
Rym: I feel like my parents took me.
Scott: how do you know steam dams isn't referencing something else?
Rym: I Imagine if it's referencing anything it's referencing some old Vaudeville.
Rym: It's basically you know what it is.
Rym: It's sort of a like a modern take on a vaudeville bit.
Rym: I'm just saying Anyway, a bunch of the talks we've given at conventions recently are on YouTube.
Rym: You can just see them.
Rym: Mmm They're there.
Scott: You don't have to actually go to PAX.
Scott: Yeah Although you should you should and the next packs you can go to is PAX East which we will be at and it's a ways Away, so don't have to worry about it.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I don't even know what's going on.
Scott: Yeah, but otherwise, it's gonna be four fucking days though.
Rym: But you should follow both me and Scott on YouTube because I'm Scott's YouTube.
Rym: We just uploaded our neg our judge anime by its cover.
Rym: We reviewed the entire winter 2018 The entire winter we reviewed.
Scott: We're never on almost no information whatsoever and we have been wrong and we're getting wronger.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, we're gonna do it.
Rym: Anyway, how are we so right?
Rym: the first time we did it and never again I don't know.
Scott: Anyway, the point is we don't need to mention that again cuz what even you know It's already old by hat by now the spring ones gonna be coming up soon enough.
Rym: I feel like we should do the next Thursday show on true Beverly Hills.
Scott: I don't know anything about you.
Rym: You would not.
Scott: I've never heard of it before.
Rym: now you would not.
Rym: I don't know why I remember this movie.
Scott: Okay, I've never heard of it.
Rym: But anyway, let's get right into it.
Rym: So little which academia.
Rym: We did review the original shorts on GeekNights.
Scott: Did you review the second movie?
Scott: Nope.
Rym: Okay We never talked about little.
Rym: which academia again.
Scott: so here's a deal with a little watch.
Scott: academia first studio trigger.
Scott: before there was kill la kill.
Scott: before there was any of the.
Scott: Before I think there was even Fucking inferno cop.
Scott: I I don't know I don't know if it was before turning girls, which wasn't technically.
Scott: studio trigger was like basically the same people.
Rym: Well, he was 2013.
Scott: I don't know the timeline here But the point is one of the first time I ever heard of studio trigger was with.
Scott: it was the little wet Academia short that went online from the young animators training project.
Scott: Yeah, we I saw it and I said, holy shit.
Scott: That was great.
Rym: You were like it's it's mode sky tie.
Rym: I think it's something.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, and then there was.
Scott: they were kick-starting a movie.
Scott: I think so.
Rym: The original short was I'm not gonna review it again But it was shall we say very well received and it was one of the many things that saved anime in that era.
Scott: So it was a trigger in general.
Rym: Yep so it was so it was so successful that studio triggered put went to make a Sequel to it the enchanted parade two years later And they made it.
Rym: it was bigger budget like they made it on purpose with a budget.
Scott: I think there was Kickstarter money and perhaps it was money.
Rym: It was quote-unquote kick-started but the kick-starting was a very minor part of its overall budget as far as I can tell.
Scott: I don't remember even remember the rewards were or anything.
Scott: It was definitely a Kickstarter really in there somewhere anyway, so then in 2017 with the money of Netflix they made a real anime.
Scott: That was a 2025 episode TV series where the episodes were 20 to 30 minutes long.
Rym: Yep They made a full-on series on Netflix and the deal is they did they kind of like in the old days Which I think at this point most of the people isn't a geek guys wouldn't?
Scott: I think it's technically two seasons like one is 13 And one is 12, but it doesn't matter.
Rym: There were a bunch of anime.
Scott: the opener changes around episode 12 or 13 and that makes it to see.
Rym: it's basically - it's if you Think of it like it's a 25 episode show.
Rym: if you're a we watching it in anime club You would treat it as two different seasons, but it's basically just one show.
Rym: the world's different now But it was a reboot of the original short and movie, right?
Scott: So the short and the movie each standalone separate from each other like.
Scott: there's no continuity between them except for the characters.
Scott: Yeah, they both stand alone independently.
Scott: the TV show Has the same characters the same setting but it Resets the time.
Scott: some of the things that happened in those movies and sure are still true But they those events didn't actually happen.
Scott: Instead it starts back at the beginning where the characters arrive at the school, right?
Rym: It's it's a magic for witches steps back and as a longer arc for the main character Akko, right?
Scott: But the basic plot is actually still like.
Scott: a lot of the stuff is still the same right and unchanged.
Rym: cute delightful Witches have adventures and make mischief.
Scott: there's added characters that weren't in the original two things.
Rym: There's kind of a like low-key utenna style villain toward the end like an odd that Akio character.
Scott: Yeah, a little bit.
Rym: Yeah a little bit.
Rym: But what's funny is that this sort of thing happened a bunch of times in the old days.
Rym: There was like the tenchi muyo av.
Rym: then there was the tenchi muyo TV series that were the same characters Kind of a different story Patla.
Scott: Patla bore a very similar situation.
Scott: Yeah, Patla bore OAV.
Scott: those the first.
Scott: Patla Lazard had the OAV and there was TV one.
Scott: Then there was TV two and there were two movies and then they go after the second movie.
Scott: they started coming out with like fucking more movies that didn't even have the main characters in them, but Ella's art in a Tenchi muyo are more analogous to this.
Rym: because they had an OAV that was short and good and then they took the same characters And basically did it again longer as a TV show.
Rym: The big difference is in both those cases The TV show was kind of shit compared to the original OAV.
Rym: in this case The TV show is just as good as the original away.
Scott: So at this point I have seen every little bit academia thing There is to see.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The only things we have not consumed are the manga.
Rym: Nope, which there's only one volume.
Scott: I think I'm good.
Rym: It says it's saying it it might be good, but I don't really care.
Rym: I guess there's two mangas.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'm good.
Rym: Whoa, there's a sane in manga and a Shonen manga and a shoujo manga.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't need to read them.
Rym: I'm good in ultra jump ribbon and yen, oh, that's a katakawa, okay Monthly Shonen ace.
Rym: Yep, I Get you, you know, it's funny.
Rym: They did the same thing with eska flown a. there was like a Shonen manga and a shoujo manga and then they were both just steaming piles of garbage.
Rym: They were.
Scott: I don't know that these manga are bad or just.
Scott: I don't need I don't need to But those eska flown a. I got enough comics to read.
Scott: I'm good.
Rym: Yep So we kind of want to review the entire franchise as a whole.
Rym: But we're not gonna talk in detail about the original OAV because we talked about that in depth, right?
Scott: So let's talk about that.
Scott: that movie first the the parade one.
Rym: I really basically the bits just if you liked the short.
Rym: It's a longer bigger budget thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean it sort of has this really stereotypical Kids movie sort of plot.
Scott: Yeah, right where you know, it really felt a lot like a lot of animated American kids movies I saw when only obviously anime.
Scott: Yeah instead you know that they have to do a thing their kids in school and then a monster comes out for them to fight at the end and there's some Subconflicts, it's really just an excuse to have these characters interacting in a crazy and also introduces other characters.
Scott: that then our characters in the TV show the the Amanda the awesome athletic girl who's a troublemaker the girl who's a really non character the donut eating one and The mecha one who actually gets one episode in the TV.
Scott: Yeah, but the donut eating one does not get an episode in the TV show and that's kind of like.
Scott: why is she even there?
Rym: I kept expecting her to get one and she's just like this joke off to the side.
Scott: She you know what she reminds me of on The Muppet Show the dynamite guy Crazy, whatever his name is they did kind of use her like to break up a scene, right?
Scott: All she does is this one joke and she just pops in does the joke and pops away just just like dynamite guy Crazy, what's his name?
Scott: crazy something.
Rym: there were a few other characters like that But anyway, so yeah, the the enchanted parade is literally.
Rym: If you're an anime fan, you should watch it.
Rym: It's a movie and it's great Like.
Rym: I don't know what else to say.
Rym: It's cute witches doing stuff super well animated super fun.
Rym: Don't worry about the plot so much.
Rym: It's just.
Scott: it's crazy Harry.
Rym: So the TV series which the only reason we didn't review it until now because I watch it a long time ago.
Rym: Scott didn't have Netflix.
Rym: Scott got Netflix again canceled Hulu.
Scott: I got Netflix not watching Netflix stuff.
Rym: Yep so in a nutshell If you were an anime fan at all, you should definitely watch it.
Rym: Yeah I actually think this is a great show.
Rym: if you know someone who professes to not like anime or just never watched anime It's just a great show and you just get people to watch it.
Scott: Yeah, this show has nothing Objectionable about.
Scott: you know things that you might object to in animes doesn't have extreme violence Doesn't have weeb shit.
Scott: It doesn't have pretty much anything that's gonna turn someone away who is not an anime fan.
Scott: meanwhile, look at the show why it still has the structure and Tropes of being an anime TV series unlike say a Ghibli movie where a lot of people like Ghibli movies But don't like any other anime.
Scott: Yeah, if you like this you're gonna like, you know You could go from this to a full metal alchemist or whatever But as the accessibility of kids in magical school story Which is a story that a lot of people apparently like even though it's been done a hundred times
Rym: and it also does a pretty Good job of having a pretty good plot to keep things going and have sort of a destination for the show to go.
Scott: Well, I think it's actually.
Scott: I think the plot is as issues but the I think The characters are very strong pretty good in that.
Rym: So it is a lot of this solely To take the characters and drag them through this arc.
Scott: There's a lot of anime out there and a lot of things in general these days were like this sort of a terrible secret of Space or some kind of plot where I want to know the deal.
Scott: Yeah I don't actually care about any of the characters like I wouldn't put stickers of the characters on my laptop or on my wallpaper, right?
Scott: Yeah, little witch academia.
Scott: There's gonna be a character that's gonna be your fave if you watch this show, right?
Scott: You know, it's it's.
Scott: there's gonna be someone because the characters stand out.
Rym: Well, cuz the characters are all great and varied but the plot I guess is just.
Rym: it's good enough to give the context for the characters to be pulled through these arcs and It also does go a little like it goes a little darker than I expected.
Scott: But I mean you get riches.
Rym: you got to go dark someone but when it hits the dark spot It had a chance to go way dark and it hints that it's gonna go away dark and it holds back.
Rym: Yeah, it kind of bounces off of that instead of going way dark and goes back to Trigger little witch academia.
Rym: Let's go.
Rym: It's witches.
Scott: Yeah So the thing about the plot that bothers me is not that it's a bad plot is that it feels like as you're watching it.
Scott: I don't know if this how this lines up with like the season divide.
Scott: Yeah It feels almost like they sort of rewrote stuff as they went along.
Scott: Like the first part is like very episodic learning that and then it's like suddenly they're like, oh by the way There's these seven words.
Scott: I forget how many words it is.
Scott: nine words Well, so they sort of just push that in immediately with like no pre like foreshadowing for that.
Scott: It's just a season.
Rym: one sets it up in the most minimal way where she can't do magic and everyone else can.
Rym: It's kind of an open question.
Rym: Why is Akko so shitty at magic?
Rym: Well, literally everyone else can do magic.
Rym: fine Literally everyone right.
Scott: but it doesn't feel like that.
Scott: that was part of the the way the two.
Rym: then she can do magic Because occasionally with this staff.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And then in season two it's so let's see what the deal is with this staff, right?
Scott: but the thing is it feels like the way it's structured it.
Scott: it feels like that they like they Explain the things from season one at the end of season two.
Scott: But it feels like they wrote that they didn't write that from the beginning, right?
Scott: It feels like they came up with that later like hmm I know we can tie these things together with this right because there was no foreshadowing of those particular things in advance.
Scott: You see what I'm saying?
Scott: Yeah, it just it.
Scott: just I don't know if that's true or not.
Scott: But the way that the show is presented it feels that way.
Scott: it feels like they did a thing and then they came up with new ideas and tossed him in and and then managed to use those new ideas that they just came up with to Explain the old things to tie it together in post-hoc.
Scott: We're as opposed to coming up with 24 episodes that are cohesive.
Rym: Yeah, well cuz really.
Rym: it was just like one of the episodes was just let's go into Susie's like poison-filled brain and see what's Going on.
Scott: Well, you gotta have that kind of episode.
Scott: Calvary Bebop had a mushroom episode.
Rym: Yeah, we gotta have a mushroom episode.
Scott: mushroom episode.
Scott: There's the episode where it's just like Dragon stock dealing.
Scott: guys, you know stock guy.
Scott: It's like that episode was awesome.
Scott: Nothing wrong with it.
Scott: You can toss those in one thing.
Rym: I'm very happy about is that The show could have ruined itself if it really focused on the romance or relationships And instead it hinted at them.
Rym: But it basically gave equal pull between ako and this one guy character who's pretty good.
Rym: I like that character a lot.
Scott: Yeah, he started off as being like, oh, here's the guy character.
Scott: It's like oh, no, he's alright.
Rym: Well, cuz he wasn't exactly as he appeared to be.
Scott: no No, he was very cool.
Rym: it equally pulls toward ako having a relationship with Diana Mm-hmm, and it does not commit to either.
Rym: Nope, which was just an interesting choice.
Rym: I guess it was a good way to sort of keep they both like the phone both like shiny cherries Yep, but meanwhile, I did I think it 100% set up that Ursula and what's-her-name the Accio character?
Rym: Definitely had a relationship.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So that's another thing that you know.
Scott: bother me about the show is this is tension I guess spoil.
Scott: It's not a spoiler.
Rym: Yeah, we're not gonna be like super spoilers right now.
Scott: This is not a spoiler because like the audience knows this from the very beginning the show you're talking about Chekhov's gun.
Rym: It's Chekhov's look behind these glasses right at those red eyes.
Scott: So right It's like.
Scott: so so ako the main the central motivation of the main character Is that she wants to be like the superhero like which shiny chariot, right?
Scott: Yep, and then her teacher is shiny chariot, but no one knows that just except you the audience except the audience knows it Right.
Scott: and the whole show is like you keep getting closer and closer to like.
Scott: oh, she's gonna have to talk.
Scott: Oh, she's Johnny chariot is.
Scott: she has to tell right and it's like it's.
Scott: I hate that trope so much Where it's like just fucking saying.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I hate it when they don't just fucking say I want to see the show where they just fucking say.
Rym: But at the same time and that this is not that show the show did not make the like the central point B. Oh, no, she'll find out.
Rym: No, not at all.
Scott: It's not that.
Scott: it's not that something bad will happen when she finds out or it's it's it's you know.
Rym: It's much more.
Rym: how will she find out like you daughter dear or I daughter Do you really want to meet your heroes?
Rym: Cuz you when you find out when the show turns dark is when you find out What the sort of the implied story of why won't she tell her?
Rym: Why is she this teacher.
Rym: and why is everything different?
Rym: and why is Matt?
Rym: because there's this whole like Environmental and implied story in the first half that magic is basically dying or dead, right?
Scott: That is actually something that wasn't super resolved, right?
Scott: I thought that's what was going to be resolved.
Scott: is that so the witches used to be able to magic all over the fucking place?
Scott: Yeah, and now there's only magic like near the philosophers or sorcerers.
Scott: There's a great episode with the the fairies and their Union about their use of the magic and there's like a fault line In the earth that has like magic flowing in it and they could only do magic near it.
Scott: and if they go to town they Can't magic so much.
Scott: They got to bring some magic with them in a magic battery or something.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like so they somewhat resolve that a little bit but not.
Rym: They sort of imply that that's gonna be the plot and there's gonna be a particular kind of resolution.
Rym: You'll probably be watching it and sort of say that
Scott: that's sort of like it looks like from from the first early Episodes that that is going to be the terrible secret that is resolved at the very end and it only sorta is the focus at The end is actually completely different.
Rym: I mean you expect it to be this idea of oh, yeah people like shiny chariot You need people to do inspire people to care about magic and that will make magic better and it's actually much more Dark and specific than that.
Rym: Yeah, it's not that super generic plot But I do like the fact that the plot is like.
Rym: all those questions are not dealt with in depth Because I don't want a show like this to focus on its stupid world building.
Rym: No, that is the least interesting part of this show is the world building.
Scott: It's actually kind of cool how it's in the modern world and they tie together The modern world and also the magic the siloed away school world.
Scott: Yeah without sort of being ridiculous, right?
Scott: It's like okay like magic exists and no one really gives a shit.
Scott: It's like they happen to be near this town that looks really old and it's like yeah, there's still towns like that in Europe Exist and there's people.
Scott: the people in the town are totally modern buying, you know There's like a book series is being written that people are fans of and that the soccer riots.
Rym: really I Really like the soccer riot part a lot because it edges into Nico riot territory like old Byzantium style, right?
Scott: But it's like they.
Scott: the way they like start, you know it starts and like flows in and connects actually kind of works right between the characters who are like connected to the government and Well, it's the opposite of town.
Rym: and then because they're not named country they're in because the other ways to go with that are.
Rym: they're the shows that Set themselves in an old time and never connect themselves to a reference point.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Just to not worry about it There's shows like you Tena that are just sent in a modern time.
Rym: Like it's just normal world.
Scott: It is a lot like a tenant, but
Rym: some
Scott: weird hidden away school, but it's totally the 90s,
Rym: but the difference is your tenet totally Isolates you the viewer from the outside world and it's a jarring Shock that is used to great effect when you are outside and you're sort of reminded of how crazy what's going on inside the school.
Scott: It's like no, they could just be in town with cars and cell phones But actually they just went to magic school because they wanted to yep.
Rym: So I'm real hard-pressed to decide if Suzy or Akka are actually my favorite character.
Rym: Mmm I like Suzy because she is dangerous like really dangerous and I can't and I imagine that other students have died because of her Hakko's loud.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is I tend to like the crazy side characters a lot.
Rym: So like the gang of.
Rym: well, you've always liked anime that have a gang of sort of side characters but who are like like next to the main characters who have that sort of Group dynamic of craziness in the background whenever they show up.
Rym: Mmm, like all the all the half all the people who like come into the background and Pat LeBor and tank police.
Scott: It's like I like, you know, like the teachers for example, right?
Scott: Yeah, you know like especially the the crazy old teachers like haha potions Or like the fish the teacher who's just a fish yep in a bucket the whole fish.
Rym: the show is legit funny Yeah, and it doesn't.
Scott: there's a whole episode about the teacher who's just a fish in a bucket.
Rym: Yep, I also again because it's triggered.
Rym: the animation is fantastic Yeah, like Netflix money, right and it definitely has a theme of like.
Rym: Akko in particular will transform into things a lot.
Rym: It is used to ridiculous comedic effect on a episode by episode Basis and just when you think they've run that joke out they do it again.
Scott: magic shop guy.
Rym: Oh my god I forgot about that guy.
Scott: Yeah magic shop guy.
Rym: Yep So, I mean, I don't really want to spoil anything.
Rym: There's no point in talking about like a deeper level to the show.
Rym: This is a must-watch anime.
Scott: It's not a super deep show.
Scott: But yeah, it's like at worst B plus probably a - anime I mean in terms of.
Scott: I mean, I guess let's see.
Scott: What's an anime better than this?
Scott: I guess a lot of em had better than this an anime.
Scott: That's one step under this.
Rym: So here's a comparison because we talked.
Rym: we've mentioned occasionally my old Scott I magic users clubs better than Maha Until little witch academia.
Rym: that was our go-to cute witch show and I love the hell out of that OAV, but that OAV as Heartwarming well-constructed and cute as it was also had its problematic anime bullshit moments Particularly.
Scott: the first episode is definitely better than Maha.
Rym: It's a guy.
Rym: Yeah, but most guys I was a pretty solid show Has a way better than I like El Hazard.
Scott: Yeah, it's real good.
Rym: I'm gonna say it's nay anime.
Scott: I mean if you guys if you're an anime watcher in the year 2018 That's the anime to watch.
Rym: if you want many if you want to experience or get someone else to experience the craziness of studio trigger.
Scott: I think it's better than kill la kill.
Rym: awesome and The person you're not the kind of person or the person you're trying to get to enjoy trigger is not the kind of person who could Appreciate kill la kill.
Rym: because kill la kill which I think is a better show.
Rym: the little witch I don't.
Scott: I think kill la kill started out maybe stronger in the early parts But then it sort of gets ridiculous and sort of off the chain.
Scott: I mean off the chain.
Scott: It's supposed to get off the chain.
Scott: That's what it's about.
Scott: But the plot just sort of goes all over the place towards the end.
Scott: Right, whereas I think little witch academia even as I said, it was uncohesive before I think is more cohesive I wouldn't say the end of kill la kill goes all goes all over the place.
Rym: I'd say that it doubles down on one very specific thing.
Rym: Sure Anyway, but this is it.
Rym: This is an a must watch anime like yeah, why not?
Rym: There is you just go watch it now.
Scott: if you haven't seen it Why wouldn't you I there?
Rym: I can't imagine that.
Rym: I cannot imagine the person who would not enjoy the show on some level.
Rym: who?
Rym: Enjoys anime if any kind even if you don't enjoy anime, I'm pretty confident I could show this to most people I know and they would like it.
Scott: most people, you know, enjoy anime.
Rym: Oh, that is true.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights in order.
Rym: This is as fast as I can say them because I'm gonna prove that I'm doing this.
Rym: I literally do record this over and over again every single time.
Rym: We record this show.
Rym: You're making me do this Ellen Joyce Rebecca's on hyping nickel a shining Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky my stage calm to remind our genuine bonafide electronic car monorail cold guy I meant to shed.
Rym: Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando captain Cinco Oca see 4 to 1 creations.
Rym: No, I never ever wonder why we're here separate 5-bit shiffing about.
Rym: however, I live out.
Rym: James David White for shot Monona.
Rym: Superboy room says something funny here sailor Vista - like your television.
Rym: Jojo Joestar Sam gordery Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Finn Chris mid give Chris knocked and we're gonna Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: I'm drooling because I'm crazy hungry and I smell food in the other room.
Scott: So now I leave you with.
Rym: I'm not gonna quote your price till I check your credit rating and let me I want to make Myself clear on this.
Rym: This is a formality.
Rym: if you're saying to me Bob is this guy good for it?
Rym: I say yes, I don't check this machine But I don't own the place even though my name's up there.
Rym: long story, but that doesn't matter.
Rym: I'm gonna have to run through the computer.
Scott: Was that a good siren?
Rym: Am I approved you ever known a siren to be good?