Rym: It's Wednesday, December 12th, 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are talking about Mamoru Hosta's new movie Mirai.
Rym: Or Mirai no Mirai.
Scott: Is it really that new?
Scott: Because the baby's name means future.
Scott: Is it just, is Mirai of the future?
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Is this new in just the US or is it new in Japan?
Rym: Who even knows?
Scott: I don't know, Japan 2018.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I finally got some new monitors, and even though it's not a Monday show...
Scott: Well, the one on the right, maybe.
Scott: Yeah, the one on the right.
Scott: The one on the right, which is actually nothing wrong with it.
Scott: It's just really old.
Scott: I bought that monitor in 2000, one, two, three, something like that.
Rym: I remember you were so excited about it because I still had a 19-inch CRT that weighed an infinite number of pounds that had literally bent my desk, and you got this LCD.
Rym: that was the first LCD in the consumer market that had a fast enough refresh rate to use for any modern computing purpose, like playing games.
Scott: Yeah, people don't know this.
Scott: The old LCD monitors, right?
Rym: They didn't refresh.
Rym: Even if you sent enough frames to the monitor, the actual LEDs themselves, like the pixels on the monitor, could not refresh themselves fast enough.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So what happened is you get this ghosting effect.
Scott: Let's say you played Mario.
Scott: You would see a ghost Mario behind the Mario, because Mario's going at 60 FPS, just like any NES game, right?
Scott: But Mario moves to the right.
Scott: Well, Mario was just there, so that's a red pixel for where Mario's overalls were.
Scott: But now it's got to be a blue pixel for the sky.
Scott: But it wouldn't turn from red to blue quickly enough, so you'd sort of be able to see this ghost Mario behind the actual Mario moving, right?
Scott: And you couldn't play games like that, because you'd also have a ghost in front, where things weren't changing to red fast enough, right?
Scott: So it looked like Mario was behind where he actually is.
Rym: Basically, anything moving on screen.
Rym: Remember, this was the early days of computing.
Rym: Even watching a video was undoable.
Rym: They were only usable for looking at static images.
Scott: Yeah, for text, it was fine.
Scott: Or for things that didn't move, it was fine, because you just need... Okay, so this image changes, but then you see what it changed into.
Scott: So text, it's like, okay, it blurs when I scroll, but I can read it when it stopped.
Scott: It's perfectly fine.
Scott: But yeah, it was the SyncMaster, the Samsung SyncMaster 172X, 17-inch LCD monitor.
Scott: It was an amazing monitor, both in its form factor, because it's basically just a panel on a little V-shaped stand.
Scott: It didn't have any extra, like, big chunky plastic or any other nonsense.
Rym: It has a smaller bezel than a lot of modern monitors.
Scott: I really just wish modern monitors have the exact same form factor.
Scott: Also, it only had VGA DVI, because that was the time.
Scott: The HDMI wasn't a thing yet.
Rym: It had its special power brick.
Rym: It didn't use the standard power adapter.
Scott: Yeah, well, that's part of the reason it was able to be so small, is because the power brick was on the outside of the monitor.
Scott: It wasn't in the monitor.
Scott: But you plugged in the cables into the base, not into the panel, and that's why the panel was so thin and able to move so freely, because all the electronics were outside of it.
Rym: But my problem with it was that it just wasn't enough pixels.
Rym: It's this tiny 4x3 display.
Scott: It was a tiny 4x3, 17-inch monitor.
Scott: that's, what, is it 1280x1024 resolution, I think?
Scott: Something like that?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So I need a new monitor.
Rym: But also, my main monitor is pretty old, and it seemed fine.
Rym: But now that I've looked at it next to a new monitor, it had gotten way dim relative to new.
Rym: So anyway, I got new monitors.
Rym: That's not the news or anything.
Rym: The reason I bring it up is that it's around the holidays when a lot of people might be getting new monitors, and the modern way you connect monitors is DisplayPort.
Rym: HDMI is really mostly used for TVs.
Rym: If you have a good PC, you're going to use DisplayPort or DisplayPort.
Rym: That's the standard connector these days.
Scott: If you buy a video card these days, the vast majority of them, like the top-end video cards, right, will have a DisplayPort and an HDMI, or they'll have three DisplayPorts and an HDMI.
Scott: It's really hard to find one that's got two HDMI.
Scott: But don't worry, because you can just get, I bought one, I haven't tested it yet, a DisplayPort 2 HDMI cable.
Scott: I don't think it'll carry sound.
Scott: It might, I don't know.
Rym: Well, here's the interesting thing.
Rym: A lot of those dongles, like DisplayPort to DVI, need power, because they need circuitry.
Scott: DisplayPort to HDMI is just a cable.
Scott: There's no circuitry in it.
Rym: But DisplayPort to DVI, I think, actually needs power.
Rym: In fact, DisplayPort 2, a lot of things, needs power.
Rym: So the DisplayPort spec is actually really crazy, because almost the same spec is using Thunderbolt cables for video.
Rym: I know this is GeekNights Wednesdays, not Monday, and some of you are starting to freak out, but trust me, you need to know this.
Rym: The long story short is that of all the pins inside of a DisplayPort cable, one of them will fucking destroy your video card or your monitor.
Rym: It is pin 20.
Scott: Yeah, pin 20 sends power, right?
Rym: Like five volts, like it's real power.
Rym: Enough power for USB to do something.
Scott: Right, so you could power a device, or you could even charge something, right?
Scott: Or if you had a really weak monitor that didn't need to be plugged into the wall, you could have a monitor that's powered by the DisplayPort cable if it's a really weak sauce monitor.
Rym: So here's the problem.
Rym: In the old days, when someone made a cable, they just wired every pin to the other side, and they didn't think about it.
Rym: DisplayPort actually specifically says, don't fucking wire pin 20 unless you know what you're doing, and no one will know what they are doing.
Rym: There's literally no reason for pin 20 to be wired on any DisplayPort cable that has DisplayPort on both ends.
Scott: Yeah, even though there'll be 20 pins in the connector, because it has to be a standard connector, otherwise it won't fit, you only need 19 wires in there.
Scott: You don't need that 20th wire, you can just leave that one just unconnected.
Rym: Yep, okay, it's 3.3 volt, not 5 volt, 500 milliamp.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: But almost any DisplayPort cable you buy anywhere, even ones from legit brands like Belkin, just wire pin 20.
Rym: And the only way to know they've done this, unless you have like a tester, like a cable tester, or you sit there with a multimeter and like our voltimeter and fuck with it, is you'll plug your new monitor into your computer, it'll seem like it's working fine, you'll turn your computer off, and then you try to turn your computer on and your video card is just dead, because it's been feeding power into your video card from the monitor.
Rym: So I ran into this problem, luckily the failure mode ended up being my computer wouldn't boot.
Rym: So I'm literally like, I bought these new monitors, I plugged them in, I've changed nothing else in my life, and the next day my computer won't boot.
Rym: So at first I think, all right, the odds are that I did not break anything, plugging new monitors in, so I assume my power supply is dead because I hit the power button, power supply goes click, nothing happens.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing is, even though that makes sense based on the symptoms, the fact is you got new monitors.
Scott: If you changed a thing recently and that was a problem, 99% chance the thing you changed is the cause of the problem.
Rym: So in my brain I'm thinking, so thus I have this cognitive dissonance, the thing I changed is highly unlikely to cause problem A.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: The thing I changed directly before problem A occurred is the thing that is unlikely to have caused problem A. So I fuck around a little bit, do some differential diagnosis, and then I remember while I'm doing this, this DisplayPort problem, because I talked about it on Geek Nines a long time ago.
Rym: It's not common knowledge, the moral is, if you use DisplayPort to plug something in,
Scott: only
Rym: use a DisplayPort cable that came with the monitor, that came with your video card or computer, or buy the AmazonBasics one, because that seems to be the only cable that is known to not wire pin 20, and even if you think you're buying an expensive, fancy DisplayPort cable, it probably has pin 20 wired.
Scott: All my DisplayPort cables came with monitors I bought and are thus perfectly fine, and I've never had a problem, but I haven't ever bought a DisplayPort cable.
Scott: The other thing is that you might say, "Well, wait, what if I want the power?
Scott: I would have to get a broken cable on
Scott: purpose.".
Scott: But actually, the thing is, almost any device you buy that needs or wants that power will have an integrated cable.
Scott: That's what you're supposed to do, is like, "Oh, I've made a thing that needs DisplayPort power, so it has a built-in DisplayPort
Scott: cable.".
Scott: Like, it's literally just a weird device.
Scott: Let's say it's a tiny monitor, right, that needs the power.
Scott: It won't even have a hole for DisplayPort cables to be attached.
Scott: It'll literally just have a cable coming out of it with DisplayPort on one end, and the monitor already on the other end, and you can't change the cable.
Rym: Yep, the official DisplayPort fact.
Rym: You're not supposed to make...
Scott: Right, you're supposed to, if you're using the power, you're supposed to have one end of the cable just going right into the device.
Scott: If you're making a cable that's on its own, you're not supposed to have the 20th wire in there.
Rym: Yep, so that was my adventure.
Rym: Thankfully, it only prevented my computer from booting.
Rym: Once I cut that broken-ass cable in two and threw it away and put a different cable on, everything was copacetic, and my video card still works.
Rym: That DisplayPort hole also still works, which was a worry, because that's the common symptom of this.
Scott: I think, I don't know if this is true or not, but I imagine, you know, say Nvidia or whoever, EVGA or whoever's making cards and stuff and monitors.
Rym: They don't want to brick a bunch of video cards.
Scott: I wonder if they would be, you know, building in defenses against this obvious problem.
Rym: Well, it's subtle, because it would, it fixed itself and worked fine if I turned everything off, waited a while, and turned it back on, because, like, that power would dissipate.
Rym: But basically, the deal is, it'll be 3.3 volts on both sides, so depending on luck chance, like, what particular video card you have, what particular monitor do you have, current might be going in either direction.
Rym: Like, it's a weird situation.
Rym: So, thankfully, everything is fine, and now we will talk about, actually, actual animation and such.
Rym: So,
Scott: the huge, biggest anime news that no one can shut up about is that, if you don't know, one of the biggest, most important, amazingest animes of all time that no one can shut up about, even after 20 something, who knows how many years, Neon Genesis Evangelion, which has been unavailable for legal distribution in the United States for quite a long time.
Scott: Which is a travesty, because- Because ADV had it, and then they put out those platinum DVDs, eventually.
Rym: Which I own.
Scott: And then, after that, there was no, like, legal way to buy the show in the United States.
Scott: I mean, those, they got those movies, some of them, right?
Scott: But the actual 26 episode TV series, and some of the original movies, I don't know about those, but the, you know, the newer movies you can get, right?
Scott: Those are a separate thing.
Scott: The re-whatever, the 111- Evangelion- The 111, you cannot watch the original, right?
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: Anyway, so, they've never been, as far as I know, legally streamed on any streamy site.
Scott: They have not been available on DVD or Buray or any sort of other way to legally watch them in the US and most other non-Japan countries that I know of for many years.
Rym: This is a travesty, because I don't care if you love Evangelion or hate Evangelion, you cannot deny that Evangelion is super important.
Rym: There's a reason people keep complaining about it and talking about it to this goddamn day.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's many illegal ways to watch it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And you can always get the old DVDs, nothing stopping you.
Scott: But yeah.
Rym: Except the fact that I don't own any optical drives.
Scott: I have rips of the DVD, and I have, I was playing, if I ever need to, I'm planning to buy a USB optical drive.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, so, a lot of companies were trying to get it, like, Funimation was trying to get it, to license it so they could put it out again for people to see again.
Scott: And Netflix, with their big money sack, has managed to succeed in doing this.
Scott: And Evangelion is going to come to Netflix sometime next year.
Rym: This is big for a lot of reasons, because we don't need, like, existing anime fans who know about Ava to be able to see it, because like Scott said, we've all seen it and have some way to see it.
Rym: The idea here is that a lot of people who might have never watched anime might just watch this groundbreaking amazing show by chance and get into anime.
Scott: So here's the thing, right?
Scott: So number one, issue number one, they're going to redub it.
Rym: Which I 100% approve of.
Scott: Some people are mad because they have this nostalgia for the original dub.
Scott: Guys, like, those people are wrong.
Scott: The original dub was a garbage dub, burn it in fire.
Rym: Like, on one hand, I'm sympathetic to the voice actors who were in that dub, because for a lot of them, like, frankly, that was the, like, most prominent job they ever got.
Scott: And it was a big part of their careers.
Scott: Of course, they're not making any money off it anymore, though.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: But at the point, actually, it's bad for them.
Scott: I think, you know, even though that dub is bad and they did a bad job, I still feel like, hey, that kind of burns them over, right?
Scott: But here's the thing, if you're going to re-release it, you should use that dub so those people can keep getting their money.
Rym: Yeah, but as we've learned...
Scott: I don't know if their deals pay them that way.
Scott: I think they do.
Rym: As we've learned in almost all cases, those voice actors are great on their own.
Rym: The problem with anime voice acting was usually the directors.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, so that's issue number one.
Scott: And I say, even though Netflix is redubbing, you don't want that.
Scott: You want the Japanese language.
Rym: However, one thing, because irrespective of if the dub was good or bad, in terms of anime dubs, the fact remains that pretty much every 90s anime dub was bad by any objective measure.
Rym: Like, they all sound the same.
Rym: You can hear random audio in the room and you'll immediately say, that is a 90s anime dub.
Scott: Right, anyway, so issue number two is that the person in charge of Funimation, the president of Funimation, Gen Fukunaga, I always forget that he's a weird dude.
Scott: He's a weird, bad, Christian, right wing kind of weirdo dude who's not a great person, but he's making news because his comments regarding Netflix's license and he had two main points that are kind of mostly sort of true and we can just not talk about him right now and just talk about the points he's made.
Scott: So point number and sort of his points also include a bit of sour grapes that he didn't get the license as opposed to Netflix getting it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, his first point is that like, look, Netflix is just going to toss this up on Netflix with all the other stuff, right?
Scott: They're not going to like go around promoting it at anime cons.
Scott: They're not going to be like a brand ambassador for this show, pushing it, right?
Scott: Getting it in, you know, on all the different places, right?
Scott: They're just going to get it and put it on Netflix.
Rym: Specifically, like you said, anime cons.
Rym: That is the last audience I would go after if I was Netflix.
Scott: I'm just saying it's like, you know, if Funimation had it right, look at what Funimation, you know, his example was My Hero Academia.
Scott: That was his example.
Scott: Is that like, look, Funimation licensed that show and pushed it.
Scott: Got them.
Scott: You know, you get the merch, you get that, right?
Scott: It's like they pushed the brand and all avenues of media to like.
Scott: make it a thing.
Scott: If Netflix had licensed My Hero Academia, it would have just been another show on Netflix that some people would have watched.
Scott: It wouldn't have been able to grow into the somewhat, you know, phenomena that it is in the U.S.
Scott: as an anime.
Scott: It's pretty big considering, right?
Scott: So it's like, well, look, his argument is kind of agree, right?
Scott: If he licensed Ava, it's like, well, Ava already sort of had its run.
Scott: So it's not the same, really a one for one match with, say, My Hero.
Rym: Yeah, well, I take even more issue.
Scott: They would still be pushing a lot.
Scott: You Funimation would do, even though they're smaller than Netflix, whereas Netflix is just going to be, well, Ava is another show on Netflix.
Scott: But at the same time, like, do you see a push for like Dragon Prince?
Scott: There could be a Funimation at Dragon Prince.
Scott: There would be a push.
Rym: I feel like what's going to happen and what their strategy is that shows like Dragon Prince or in particular Ava, they're hoping for the word of mouth.
Rym: I think they're waiting to see which of the shows they put out there get more general, non-nish audience word of mouth and they can figure out from there what to push and what to invest in.
Scott: Yeah, but Netflix doesn't.
Scott: even the stuff that they make that gets big.
Scott: They don't sort of make this, you know, this they don't make it into a cultural thing.
Scott: They're just.
Scott: they're just things to get people to subscribe to Netflix.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So anyway, the second point that he made, which I think is maybe the more interesting point, is that like, look, Netflix licensed this by emptying their gigantic piggy bank.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's like they bid more.
Scott: That's why they got it.
Scott: And Funimation didn't.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And Funimation didn't have enough money for this.
Scott: But that sets a bad juju for licensing anime in the future by setting that price so artificially high.
Scott: You could have a situation where like, well, now the price of licensing an anime from Japan costs way more.
Scott: So only Netflix can do it.
Scott: And now the Funimation of the world die because they can't afford to license any shows because the price has been artificially inflated by this, you know, this customer.
Scott: But, you know, here's willing to overpay and effectively like Netflix could like overpay for all the anime to destroy all the anime companies.
Rym: If that payment model, if like this going rate is sustainable by Netflix and works out and is profitable, what it really means is that a lot more money will go back into the actual studios and licenses in Japan.
Rym: Maybe it could actually make a much more healthy production ecosystem.
Scott: But, you know, but probably, you know, Netflix is going to be buying it at they're not going to make as much money off as they paid for the license.
Rym: I don't know how Netflix is going to make money in the long run, like at all.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Rym: No one does.
Scott: They're just jacking up the price on these things.
Scott: So that'll hurt the people who are actually licensing at a reasonable price, even though it gives some more money to the Japanese creators.
Scott: But it's like, OK, you're giving money to like Ava already made its money.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, come on.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But also, the other thing is this is different because this isn't funding the production of a new show, nor is it picking up something, but it's going to costing Netflix more than a new show, which probably needs that money.
Rym: I guess what will be interesting, like the real data point we need forget anime fans.
Rym: like the read the redub is probably going to be good.
Scott: I mean, quality wise, I mean, it would be hard for it to be worse.
Scott: I think the redub, you know, considering that, like the, you know, the Castlevania Netflix put out, which is not an anime technique, I'd say it's technically an anime, but I mean, it doesn't.
Scott: It's anime.
Scott: It doesn't.
Scott: It doesn't have Japanese.
Scott: It's original English language is the point.
Scott: that doesn't matter.
Scott: And it's still a dub.
Scott: And that is perfectly fine.
Rym: I mean, Big O2 was released in the US first.
Scott: The original English language dialogue and voice the track.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Studio made it.
Rym: That's the answer.
Rym: It's anime anyway.
Scott: But the point is, is that it wasn't the original language.
Scott: audio track of Castlevania was not Japanese.
Scott: It was English and it was good.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, that's so.
Scott: it does do the same kind of job on the Ava dub.
Rym: I get back to that.
Rym: I get back to the dub when it's the original.
Rym: The reason a lot like anime had a hard time breaking into the mainstream is that regular folk like it or not don't like subtitles.
Rym: And you still can't get away from that.
Scott: I think that people see.
Scott: I think people keep saying things like that.
Scott: I don't see any evidence for it.
Scott: Frigging Crouching Tiger Hidden Dragon here, the theaters in the US and was a huge phenomenon.
Scott: It was subtitled only and it wasn't a fucking problem.
Scott: And people just have this idea that, like, oh, people won't read.
Scott: There are some people who can't read.
Scott: If you put a movie with subtitles and people want to see it, they will see it and they won't complain.
Scott: There's only like a few loud people who are really dumb intellectual complain about subtitles.
Scott: Most people can watch things with subtitles without even thinking about it.
Scott: You can do it often.
Scott: And there is no evidence to suggest that there's anything to contrary.
Scott: I have Crouching Tiger Hidden Dragon, as well as many other mod, you know, that's probably the most successful subtitled movie ever released in the US.
Scott: But there are others that have been released in the US with subtitles that have done just fine.
Rym: You're assuming a lot to their, you know, you're assuming a lot based on no data.
Rym: You're also there's no data for the position that subtitles will kill anything except for all the data that's held inside the studios that make these decisions.
Scott: But people aren't putting anything out with subtitles to get any data.
Scott: You have no data.
Scott: Meanwhile, here is the thing that was put out with subtitles, the only thing that you can think of.
Scott: And it did just fine.
Scott: It did great, in fact.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: One, a movie, not a long TV show.
Scott: I'm just saying you could put things out.
Rym: I'm just saying your evidence is purely anecdotal and you're not putting enough things out with something.
Scott: I have there's one thing that's been put out with subtitles that was major to in the US market.
Scott: And it did just fine.
Scott: Where are all the?
Scott: if you're going to say that subtitles only will kill a thing.
Scott: Show me all the things that were put out with subtitles only that died and weren't big things, you know, to begin with.
Rym: I'm confident that it's not worth the risk.
Rym: If I were running a studio, I would not release subtitle only content for the mainstream.
Rym: I would for a TV show.
Scott: Well, I save so much fucking money and I'd say, oh, look, people are watching it anyway.
Scott: Whoo.
Scott: I've saved all this money.
Rym: Also, you forget that most modern TV watching culture involves people who are either multitasking or they want.
Rym: They need to hear it because they're not actually looking at the screen.
Scott: They're not watching then.
Rym: And you can say that and you can make that point and die on that stupid hill.
Rym: But the reality is that most people consume media.
Scott: Listen, people aren't paying to, you know, to see the individual show and they get Netflix.
Rym: Yeah, but Netflix needs to pay for the download.
Scott: That might matter.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But again, you're conflating the separation of how the fuck is Netflix going to make money in the long run from these, like the actual studio production or like release cycle media.
Scott: They just put, if they put Ava on Netflix with just the subs, then I think I think only anime new weeaboos would watch it.
Rym: No one else.
Scott: Just as many view as just about as it's going to get with their dub that they got to spend a lot of money on.
Rym: I am confident you'd see a like one third audience drop off after a couple of episodes.
Scott: I don't think so.
Rym: I'm pretty confident in that.
Scott: I think the real show is so big and compelling that you're going to watch it.
Rym: To test here, because a big reason why people didn't watch a lot of like mainstream people to watch anime in the nineties wasn't just the dub sub thing.
Rym: It was more that if it was on TV, it was just dubbed and those dubs are all bad and weird.
Rym: If this just has a normal dub, like quote unquote normal and seems like it's just another animated show and someone watches like Bojack Horseman and then it recommends watch this Evangeline show and they just click on it and it's just similar to those shows.
Rym: I think the test will be if a mainstream you watch Bojack Horseman also you might like Evangeline.
Rym: You know, I think there's a better one.
Scott: You might like Evangeline.
Rym: I think that Venn Diagram is also pretty good.
Rym: All I'm saying is that the point of interest.
Scott: you watch Peppa Pig, you might like it.
Rym: Nobody likes Peppa Pig.
Scott: I'm just saying.
Rym: No, Kaluu is the one everyone makes fun of anyway.
Rym: But the point will be, do?
Rym: does the mainstream media watching like non anime, non insider, non niche people start talking about Ava within six months of it being on Netflix?
Scott: Also, Ava is not only Ava, but anime is way more enormous than it appears, right?
Scott: All the nerd culture things in general, you know, watching esports on Twitch, anime, all this stuff is way big, but just doesn't appear big.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In general.
Scott: That's why you get like an E3 smaller than, say, an Otakon used to be.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, well, Otakon makes the local paper and E3 makes the world news.
Scott: Even though the size of the things is, you know, pretty similar.
Rym: Right.
Rym: But the last point before we move on to review the actual thing we're reviewing tonight is the the fact that they're paying all this extra money for Ava.
Rym: But this is an old established, super big show.
Rym: They've really only set a precedent for paying a huge licensing fee for like the top 10 shows of all time.
Rym: Like if they get Cowboy Bebop, they get, you know, I think they're making a live action one.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: This is like the what, the 10th attempt at a live action Cowboy Bebop.
Rym: I'm not super excited about that.
Scott: I'm not excited for any live action, anything.
Scott: Just give me the original thing.
Scott: That was great.
Scott: You don't need to do it again.
Scott: But I am excited for is more of not, you know, redoing a thing in a different format, but more of a thing.
Scott: because guess what?
Scott: We're getting more Ghost in the Shell.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well, I was going to talk about that later, but we'll talk about it once there's more info.
Rym: But the important thing to know about the new Ghost in the Shell is that based on the announcements about the initial creative team, it is much more likely to be like standalone complex as opposed to being like Arise.
Scott: Also Arise is on Netflix.
Scott: And I only saw one episode of it in the theater.
Rym: I've watched it all.
Scott: I haven't watched anything other than what we saw in that theater.
Scott: I watched it all.
Rym: I will give you my review.
Rym: This is everything you need to know.
Rym: It is pretty good, but all it does is make you wish it was standalone complex.
Rym: the entire time you're watching it.
Rym: And every moment, all you can think is, wow, this is okay, but God damn standalone complex.
Rym: And that's it.
Rym: That's the best thing I can say about it.
Rym: It's alright.
Rym: This one, the new Ghost in the Shell looks as close to standalone complex as we're likely ever going to get.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So I was looking around for some actual 4K streaming content because the only 4K content I actually had local is videos of myself and/or Scott.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, there's no one who's streaming in 4K because no one has the bandwidth for that.
Scott: I mean, I do.
Scott: On YouTube, there's plenty of 4K stuff, right?
Scott: But not a whole bunch.
Scott: It's not easy to just search like show me something 4K.
Scott: You're only going to find stuff that has 4K in the title, right?
Scott: Which would be like 4K test videos and stuff.
Rym: So I found a pretty good video that I use to sort of play with these monitors and calibrate them and everything.
Rym: And it really made it clear how big a difference more pixels is.
Rym: This is just a really long fractal zoom into a Mandelbrot at 4K 60 FPS.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: That's my thing of the day.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: Exciting.
Scott: It's pretty cool.
Rym: I liked it.
Scott: Alright, so check this out.
Scott: I learned something.
Rym: I'm into it right now.
Rym: Let's keep watching it.
Scott: It was a rule in ice hockey that I was unaware of.
Scott: There's probably others I'm unaware of.
Rym: I remember when you tried to argue against me when I told you about the rule where it's not offsides if you go into the zone before the puck, but you have control of this puck.
Rym: So you can skate in backwards with the puck and it's totally okay.
Scott: I thought you couldn't.
Rym: We had the argument.
Rym: I convinced you.
Rym: I showed you the fucking rule in the book.
Scott: I don't remember this.
Rym: We didn't have this argument again.
Rym: God damn, Scott.
Scott: The point is, I learned that you cannot score a goal.
Scott: See, you can score a goal in hockey.
Scott: You're not allowed to kick the puck into the net.
Rym: There cannot be a distinct kicking motion by the offensive team.
Scott: You're not allowed to punch the puck into the net.
Rym: Nope, but you cannot throw it into the net.
Scott: You obviously can hit it with your stick into the net unless you hit it like above the waves.
Scott: Can't be a high stick, right?
Scott: But you can always, if you shoot off your stick, you can bounce it off.
Scott: Pretty much anything is the net.
Scott: You can bounce it off the goalie.
Scott: You can bounce it off a teammate.
Scott: You can bounce it off an opponent.
Scott: You can bounce it off the skate.
Scott: You can bounce it off the post.
Scott: You can maybe bounce it off the glass.
Scott: You can bounce the puck off pretty much anything.
Scott: As long as none of your teammates kick or punch it directly into the net and it counts as a goal, but there was something you cannot bounce it off of.
Scott: that I learned because it happened.
Rym: I did not know this either.
Scott: Actually, someone in this video, you can watch, they bounce the puck off the ref and it goes in with a fluke and it does not count.
Scott: It's a pretty amazing bounce.
Scott: It does not count, but it's awesome.
Rym: I feel bad for the guy because...
Scott: Well, you know, every ref gets hit like once a year.
Rym: Yeah, but just the whole drama isn't playing out and meanwhile he's just there doing the like, "Oh, my
Rym: leg.".
Scott: Right, basically bounces off the ref's gut and then goes into the goal.
Scott: It doesn't count, but it's still awesome.
Scott: It's Book Club.
Rym: Book is still 2001 in Space Odyssey.
Rym: We've been busy.
Rym: We'll read it at some point.
Rym: We're busy.
Rym: You should read it.
Scott: How many months has it been?
Rym: Well, we're busy.
Scott: So, someone should go back and see like how many months it took us to read each book.
Scott: and then the thing is, is like if you look at the actual time it takes from start reading to finish reading, it's like a few weeks.
Scott: Yeah, it's like very... It doesn't take me long to read a book.
Scott: It's just I don't start reading it because I'm doing all this other crap.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Otherwise, you might have known we were just at PAX Unplugged where we did two panels.
Rym: One of them, the 40 Tabletop Games You Must Play, is on PAX's Twitch as a VOD.
Rym: You can just watch it with the slides and everything because we were in the biggest panel room.
Rym: So, they like live streamed it with all the stuff.
Rym: The other one, as soon as I have time, the Puerto Rico panel, the new one, I will get it up on YouTube to stay tuned.
Rym: We will be doing at least one panel, possibly two, at PAX South which is coming up not that long from now in January.
Scott: Right, and before PAX South, like a week or two before, is MAGFest.
Rym: Where we're doing like five panels.
Scott: It's gonna be great.
Scott: Which is ridiculously soon.
Scott: It's pretty much New Year's, MAGFest, I think then a blank week, and then South, if I'm not mistaken.
Rym: And then a month after that, PAX East where we're doing at least one panel.
Scott: But yeah, MAGFest comes right after New Year.
Scott: Today is December 12th.
Scott: This is like two weeks.
Rym: My god, I got so many panels to write.
Scott: And also, just so you know, there's gonna be a bunch of holiday biz obviously in the United States.
Rym: GeekNights will be spotty.
Scott: Most countries, right, there will not be a lot of content from us until, you know, post MAGFest, post South.
Rym: There may be a lot of parallel content, like I'll do a bunch of live streams.
Scott: I'm sure there will still be content, but do not expect any sort of regular schedule.
Scott: Expect lots of bailing on GeekNights.
Scott: We almost bailed today.
Rym: I bailed on Monday because I do a work thing and we almost bailed.
Rym: We didn't.
Rym: We're here because we're gonna review.
Rym: So as we say often, you know, common tropes on GeekNights are one, if an anime movie comes out, just go see it.
Rym: There aren't that many that aren't like Naruto.
Scott: If there is a full-length animated feature and it's, you know, it's usually, there's not a lot of those in the world made each year that are at, you know, top production value.
Rym: That aren't just one piece 50, the search for the second piece.
Scott: If you don't count all the ones that are one piece 50 or Pokemon 30 or, you know, compilation of some anime.
Scott: If you're talking about original theatrical animated feature films from Japan or from other countries, say Ireland.
Rym: Song of the Sea.
Scott: Or even the United States, right?
Scott: Not many of those are produced at the top levels of production value every year.
Scott: It's worth it to see pretty much all of them if you are a fan of animation.
Scott: So especially when they are made by a top name director studio.
Scott: So Mamoru Hosoda, who you may know from such films as that Digimon movie that people say is the good one that I haven't seen.
Rym: The one piece movie that's the good one that we did review.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: The Girl Who Leapt Through Time.
Rym: Summer Wars.
Scott: Wolf Children.
Scott: Boy and the Beast.
Rym: Is that all of them?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Boy and the Beast.
Rym: Yeah, that's it.
Scott: Is Boy and the Beast the last one we saw?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So anyways, new movie Mirai.
Scott: no Mirai.
Scott: Mirai of the Future, right?
Scott: The girl's name is Mirai.
Rym: You'll just see it as Mirai in most places.
Scott: It means future.
Scott: It came out in Japan of July this year in the summer and it was released in the United States, limited theatrical release from G-Kids.
Rym: The other thing we always say is that if you live in a major city in the US, like one of the five, every anime movie is just in the theaters.
Scott: It used to be that we would have to go to like, we actually saw Mamoru Hosoda in person.
Scott: when, was it Summer Wars?
Rym: Yeah, I think so.
Scott: Yeah, they screened Summer Wars.
Rym: Yeah, because the kids, all the kids were asking about King Kazuma.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was like, it was the film festival.
Scott: They screened it at the director's guild.
Scott: We go there and Hosoda is there.
Scott: There's probably a GeekNights episode about it.
Rym: There definitely is.
Scott: But the point is we used to have to do that to see this anime on the screen in the US, but now it seems like everything that G-Kids licenses is just in the local theater.
Scott: We went to the theater in Astoria.
Rym: Yeah, just like a movie theater in Queens.
Scott: On a Wednesday night.
Rym: It's a normal movie theater.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And there it is because of what, the Fathom events, whatever.
Rym: Subtitled, though the dub was on Saturday.
Scott: Well, Wednesday night was subtitled and Saturday was dubbed.
Scott: So, you know, you just took the schedule, right?
Rym: So the, the short version of our review is you should go see it.
Rym: And also Mamoru Hosoda.
Scott: Even if it was bad, you should go see it.
Rym: But Mamoru Hosoda is like, what, like?
Rym: we're in a weird golden age.
Rym: He is one of several people who's just batting a thousand here.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, it's pretty much, you got a Makoto Shinkai.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: You got a Hosoda.
Scott: You had Satoshi Kon.
Scott: Miyazaki, I guess, is not retired.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Not really batting a thousand, but batting like 980.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, and then I guess he got the studio Pawnuck, which is not, which not, not really batting a thousand, but they're batting.
Scott: They've had an at-bat.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And I guess production IG also puts something in there once in a while.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I see.
Scott: You know, they did.
Scott: And then we also got, um, um, you know, the, the walk-on girl, what's his name?
Rym: Oh, Yuasa.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's Masaki Yuasa.
Rym: Yuasa.
Rym: Yuasa is batting a thousand, but he's not playing baseball.
Scott: He's definitely playing Kalenball.
Scott: Anyway, but those are, those are your major anime directors these days.
Scott: Sadly, none of them are ladies, but anyway, but look at Hosoda.
Rym: He basically, he paid a Digimon movie that was actually good.
Scott: He made a one piece movie that was actually good.
Scott: People say it was good.
Rym: I haven't seen it, but I'm confident based on the people I know who said it's good anyway.
Scott: So the new movie he came out with is Mirai no Mirai.
Scott: We went, we're like, Oh, let's go see that.
Scott: And we did.
Scott: So what it's, it's just, what it's about is about basically that same old cliche story of there's a kid in a family and the family has another baby, right?
Scott: He's got a new young sibling and there's this jealousy, you know, of like, Oh, my parents aren't paying enough attention to me.
Rym: Because it literally happened.
Scott: This is the oldest story in the book.
Scott: I've never experienced it myself, but I imagine other people do.
Scott: Cause otherwise why would people tell this story if it didn't happen in any family, even though it didn't happen to my family.
Scott: So I can't really relate to it, but I've seen the story play out in so many different mediums over time that like, it's very familiar.
Rym: I've seen other people.
Rym: I know who have kids who have seen it play out live.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: And this, as you said, that core idea and expanded it into is this thing like 90 minutes to two hours, something under a full length animated feature film, 98 minutes.
Scott: That is actually much the story it actually shows, even though that's the core of it is much grander, uh, than that one aspect.
Rym: I guess in general, it's, it's another, it's a very different movie in some ways from what he's done before, but in other ways, it's the same movie in that he's like all his movies.
Rym: They focus on like some idea of what a family is and do it especially really, really well.
Scott: Especially summer wars was about this big, awesome family and the sort of person who wasn't in the family coming to them for their, at their reunion time.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Uh, what children's about?
Rym: like a small isolated family.
Scott: I didn't see the wolf children, but the boy and the beast was about like, you know, it's got wolf children, I think is his best movie.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: I haven't seen it.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Uh, but boy and the beast, right.
Scott: It's sort of like about, you know, adoption, right?
Rym: Where it's like this adopted parent, but also parents that aren't great potentially and dysfunctional families.
Scott: All his movies are about a family in the same way that all Makoto Shinkai's movies are about clouds.
Rym: But Mariah is interesting in that there's two ways to look at it.
Rym: It is on one hand, a fantastical movie about a young child who meets his ancestors and his future self and his future sister when she grows up and has these experiences across space and time that are going to shape him into the person he's going to become.
Rym: But it's also a story where there are literally no fantastical elements whatsoever.
Rym: And it's the story of a kid who synthesizes the family photos and the stories that older relatives tell to each other with his own imagination and is shaped by those two experiences, those two things to become the person that he will be.
Rym: And all the fantastical experiences are literally just a child's animation seeded by like, you know, when you're a kid, like you hear the story grandma tells about that time grandpa shot somebody and you don't quite get it and you don't really understand, like what's going on, but you internalize it and you imagine things about it.
Rym: And those stories, like they impact your growth and development, whether or not you even realize it.
Rym: That's what this movie is about.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The main center, the thing that I really liked about this movie a lot is that, you know, there are a lot of great American movies, old Hollywood movies especially that are based on plays.
Scott: For some reason, plays just become really great movies.
Scott: Like you can just go down the list.
Scott: There's like tons of amazing plays that became amazing movies.
Scott: You Chicago Cabaret.
Scott: They all start with C. But a lot of those great plays that became movies, say like a Twelve Angry Men or a Dial M for Murder, take place mostly in one room.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I love those one rumors.
Scott: You got those.
Scott: What's that one?
Scott: Glass Menagerie.
Scott: Nice.
Scott: Nice one rumor you got there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I love the one room play movie things.
Scott: I just love those.
Scott: And this is not a one rumor, but it's a one house.
Rym: And it's a weird special house.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So you can tell part of this was important for the movie.
Scott: And part of it was the animators slash designers.
Scott: slash people were good at drawing, really having fun and really showing off and having a great time.
Scott: because in this movie, the dad is an architect and they have architected this amazing, super well-designed, super fancy house.
Rym: But it's a weird house.
Scott: That is very unusual.
Scott: Everyone knows it's weird.
Scott: In the same way like a Frank Lloyd Wright house is unusual, but this is more like a Japanese.
Scott: This is like if Muji and Flankroyd had a baby.
Scott: This is like that house.
Rym: I would give almost anything to live in this house.
Scott: This house is so good.
Scott: You could have been an architect instead of an IT person.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like I would build this house.
Rym: I would hire someone to build this house for me.
Scott: The point of the house is that it is the main feature of it.
Scott: that's important for the movie is that there is a yard in the house and the yard is in the middle of the house.
Scott: So it's like you're going from the, you know, it's like the kitchen bedroom area up top.
Scott: It sort of slants down.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And before you get to the front room where it's like closer to the entrance, there's just there's no ceiling and there's a patch of grass and there's a tree and the tree symbolizes the family tree.
Scott: And that is sort of, you know, what ties in all those, you know, imaginative, fantastical scenes where the kid is seeing his, you know, future or past relatives or self, right, is all through this tree.
Scott: This tree is sort of like a magical connection to the actual family tree, which really like it fits the like.
Rym: just as a kid, like you'd go into the yard and when you're a kid, the yard feels way bigger than the yard actually is in the real world.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And you just have adventures in this yard.
Scott: So it's kind of interesting because on the one hand, it sort of plays this role in having this cool, fancy architecture and cool house for them to stage their play in.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's a lot of fun to draw.
Scott: I imagine they did.
Scott: You could tell there's a lot of parts where they're sort of, you know, really getting off on like this.
Scott: The opening scene has the kid like blowing on the glass and then wiping it away and blowing on it and wiping it away.
Scott: And they're like, check how fancy we can do this.
Scott: I'm like watching that.
Scott: And I'm like, how much time did someone spend on that?
Rym: All those big painting shots with those giant painted backgrounds and all that nonsense.
Scott: They put a lot of money and time into this animation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But anyway, but also.
Scott: It's like it wouldn't make a lot of sense for the kid to say, go outside where a tree was.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, it's like having that tree in middle of the house.
Scott: really like makes the story possible to tell the story in the way they want to.
Rym: I think the kid would retreat to the yard in the same way that a real child would retreat into like their imagination.
Scott: There's a couple scenes outside the house.
Scott: I think really goes biking and stuff like that.
Scott: Or like maybe in the cars a little bit.
Scott: But ninety, ninety plus percent is in the is in the house.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In the different rooms.
Rym: So the like basically the where it kicks off, where it goes from just being a story about a family to getting this semi fantastical or not, depending how you read it, thing is right away.
Rym: The dog is jealous of the baby, too, because the dog, which happens with pets, was jealous of the of the first kid when he was born.
Scott: Yeah, the dog has been in the family longer than either of the children.
Rym: And it set that up and basically like not really really spoilers.
Rym: We're going to avoid talking about the details of the rest of the movie because just watch a fucking movie.
Rym: It's good.
Scott: It's only 90 minutes.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Ninety eight minutes to spend.
Rym: You should watch this movie.
Scott: But the kid is actually going to be available to watch outside the theater at home pretty soon, slash easily.
Rym: So the kid is sort of freaking out about the baby and he goes off to the yard and then suddenly like the yard is a giant palace and it's run down and decayed.
Rym: and he meets this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like I didn't know what's going on.
Scott: I thought I'm like, oh, it's another travel to a different world.
Scott: Like I've seen a thousand of these.
Scott: Well, all right, whatever.
Scott: I'm here.
Scott: I'll watch.
Rym: And he meets what appears for a second to be a regal prince who then very rapidly appears to be very shabby and self-entitled.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And then it like pretty much right before the characters said they were the dog.
Scott: I'm like, oh, it's the dog.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And then he's like, oh, I'm the dog.
Rym: I used to be the prince of this house.
Rym: And then I was usurped by this right before he said that line.
Scott: I'm like, oh, it's the dog.
Scott: And then he says, I used to be prince of this house.
Scott: And I'm like, I am right.
Rym: But the movie does something really great in that the dog, like you see the dog and the dog acts like a real dog and the dog seems cute.
Rym: But after you meet the prince and realize that the prince is this personification of the dog, then every time you see the dog after that, the dog kind of has stubble.
Rym: And you just imagine the dog is this kind of like grumpy, shabby older dude.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like they enter, you know, even though the dog is a dog by introducing this personification of the dog in this one brief scene.
Scott: And then, you know, it's not really there a lot for the rest of the movie.
Scott: It's just as one imaginative scene with the kid, mostly, you know.
Scott: But then now this dog you gave managed to give it this human personality.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Without having to do like some sort of Snoopy kind of thing.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Right.
Rym: And bit by bit, the movie just introduces like it goes through these scenes of the dog and a couple other like incidents like that, that flesh out the growth of this child.
Rym: And it basically culminates in a very well done child's nightmare scenario, like literally the kind of nightmare a kid would have.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So the subplot of this movie, the main subplot is the relationship between the two parents, because basically it was a situation where, you know, it's Japan, first of all.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, you know, the working culture of Japan got to incorporate that.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But the mom is the executive.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The mom was at home and the dad was out.
Scott: But now that they had the second baby, the dad is now home and the mom goes to work.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the dad is freelancing architect from home with his laptop.
Scott: And now he's got to take care of the baby and take care of the kid and do all the housey shit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, it seems he's got a little bit of a Mr.
Rym: Mom situation.
Rym: If any of you are young enough to have seen the movie Mr.
Rym: Mom with Michael Keaton.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It does, but it's not a comedic way.
Scott: It's presented in a realistic way.
Scott: And the two parents, they have a very adult and realistic, you know, sort of conflict resolution and dealing with their relationship thing.
Scott: That's like, it's so real.
Scott: It's not, you know, there's nothing corny about it or, you know, none of them are stupid about it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like they talk to each other and get their shit in order.
Scott: the way adults do in the real world, reasonable adults do who are intelligent, nondramatic, real adults in the real world.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They get their shit together and you see them get their shit together, you know, and talk about whether they're good parents and, you know, how their relationship is and all that kind of stuff together.
Scott: And that's really nice to see.
Scott: And it's also good for adults, perhaps who are parents, you know, or were parents or whatever could go and connect with that part of the movie as well.
Scott: It's not just the, you know, kid jealousy part.
Rym: So you like, this is a must see anime movie.
Rym: And I don't like, I don't want to say anything else.
Scott: Just Japan anime movie 2018.
Scott: What other probably what else came out 2018?
Scott: That was a movie that was animated from Japan.
Rym: I think it's this.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: I think it's definitely this.
Scott: I think it is.
Scott: I can't remember another one.
Scott: I could be wrong.
Scott: Call me out on it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are in vague order of the amount of money they give us on a continuing basis with a couple of corrections due to shenanigans from before.
Rym: Craig Oliver, Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Shimmering Ruby Obelisk, Hanging in the Sky, Char Toppeshen, Link Iggi, MyStaky.com, J-Band, Scootalone, Roberto Kingsley, Shawn Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brando, Mr.
Rym: Strong, Strachan, 421 Creations, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn, Shervin Van Horrow, Rory, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, Sailor Vista, Don Schleig, Joshua Joestar, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Finn, Chris Midkiff, Daniel Redman, Shawn Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Yeah, expect a whole bunch of shows to not happen in the next few weeks because we're going to be busy and then we got a whole bunch of cons in a row, like we said.
Rym: So I hope to see you playing Overwatch.
Rym: I have like a 90% win rate at the May versus the Yeti.
Rym: I defy you to beat me as the Yeti.
Rym: And now I leave you with...
Scott: Beautiful Bahia.
Scott: Oh, forgive me, but have you been to Bahia, Donald?
Scott: No.
Scott: No?
Scott: Well, let's go.
Scott: If you go to Bahia, my friend, you'll never return.
Scott: Have you been to Bahia, Donald?
Scott: Uh-uh.
Scott: Well, let's go.
Scott: Do you like it?
Rym: Well, let's go.
Rym: When you go to Bahia, my friend, you'll never return.