Emily: So a Sifa comes through again with some free movie tickets for me and my plus one.
Rym: So we went to the wrong movie the first night and it ended up being ready player one.
Rym: So we just left and got dinner.
Emily: We didn't, we didn't actually go into the theater, but it was one of those small screening rooms.
Emily: Like the way we saw frozen, right.
Emily: Was, uh, the first time I saw frozen, it was in this tiny little box theater.
Emily: The kind that, you know, when a film is in progress, they'll show it to a test audience to kind of get a sense of how people react to the film.
Emily: And this was one of those, you know, it was in this Dolby sound theater.
Emily: I don't think we had been there before.
Emily: It was a different one than the one Frozen was at.
Rym: It seems like these things are hidden in buildings all over Manhattan.
Emily: Yeah, it's, it's basically like a skyscraper will have a built-in movie theater, even maybe partly for like client presentations.
Emily: I don't really know that much about it.
Emily: But anyway, occasionally through my, uh, I'm part of this animated, uh, short kind of film festival.
Emily: And it's an international society and you get a lot of perks like, uh, figure drawing classes and stuff for being a member.
Emily: And one of the things is they'll send out these emails and being like, oh, Fox Searchlight is doing a free screening for people who are members of the academy or members of various professional organizations.
Emily: And so if you send them an email, they'll give you tickets.
Emily: And, uh, that's how we sell the box trolls and Kubo.
Emily: That's, uh, we've, we've seen a bunch of stuff like that, but anyway, so this was kind of nice because I, I felt about this movie.
Emily: Like I saw the trailers and I really, I saw Fantastic Mr.
Emily: Fox recently.
Emily: And I was kind of unsure how this one would turn out.
Emily: Cause it was very like, you see the trailer, it's very like Japanese, but by Wes Anderson.
Emily: And so everybody's kind of raising their eyebrows.
Rym: Like before we went in to see it, I probably would have been less suspicious of it, but a lot of press already came out pointing out some very deep flaws in the movie.
Rym: So I went in expecting that and that aspect of it, like I did enjoy the film, but that aspect of it was way worse than I expected.
Emily: Well, I don't know if it was worse.
Emily: It was actually very similar to how I expected, but like I had been talking when I was at the screening with one of my friends who's another animator and she's of Japanese heritage and she was kind of like, I don't know, like I really like Wes Anderson's animation.
Emily: She liked Fantastic Mr.
Emily: Fox, but she was also kind of skeptical about this whole setting.
Emily: And, uh, I was also commiserating like, yeah, I totally get where you're coming from.
Emily: But I went into it cautiously optimistic.
Emily: And I guess my take on it was I really liked the movie, but there's also some flaws we need to talk about.
Rym: And they're pretty deep in the guys.
Rym: The longer I stew on the movie after I watched it, the more uncomfortable it makes me.
Emily: Well, let's talk about the things we liked, right?
Emily: So one it's the same style of stop motion animation as Fantastic Mr.
Emily: Fox.
Emily: It's very textured.
Emily: Like.
Emily: there's a lot of detail in it, but it's not that very smooth 3D printed quality that, say, Kubo had.
Emily: And I loved the aesthetic of the film in terms of like the way it made use of ruins and decay.
Rym: Because, like I said, it told a very dark story and the characters were appropriately, like everything was dark and broken and violent and kind of gory at times.
Rym: It didn't shy away from those aspects of the story it was going to try to tell.
Emily: It was kind of a gross movie.
Emily: Like there's this scene at the beginning where the dogs, so all the dogs are banished to Garbage Island.
Emily: And so there's this quarantine on dogs because they have the illness and dog flu.
Emily: And so they're all on this prison island and they eat garbage.
Emily: There's this one point where they open up a bag of garbage after getting into a fight with other dogs.
Emily: It's just like crawling with maggots.
Emily: And like these little miniatures of the spoiled food just look so gross.
Emily: Like it looks realistically spoiled and gnarly and nasty.
Rym: Yep, and I mean a lot of the dogs have injuries and they're just very, very bare and present.
Emily: In that same fight, doesn't like the main dog bite off somebody's ear and then you see a rat carrying the ear away?
Emily: It's like they get into a fight with these poodles and the poodles are like, and one loses an ear.
Emily: It's like, hey, he bit off your ear.
Emily: Oh, damn it.
Emily: And so it's definitely grotesque.
Emily: Like the character designs too.
Emily: Some of the character designs are like, you know, they're kind of creepy and grotesque.
Emily: And they're not pleasant to look at, I guess.
Rym: I mean, everything's dirty because it's Garbage Island.
Rym: Like they set it up to be this terrifying place.
Rym: Basically concentration camp where they're going to murder all the dogs.
Emily: Yeah, so basically going into it, I was kind of imagining it was going to be like the great escape sort of thing where it's like.
Emily: these dogs are in this prison and they've got to escape the prison.
Emily: But it was actually a little bit more complicated than that.
Emily: It wasn't just an escape story.
Emily: It was like a journey story where they're trying to find this other pack of dogs.
Emily: And there was also this whole conspiracy with the government.
Emily: And so I also like the voice acting like for the for the American.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, it was an all star cast.
Rym: So even then, that's kind of where the problems come in, too, because it's it's all basically like American white male coated dogs.
Emily: Yeah, there's the one.
Rym: the one girl character exists solely to be the one dog who isn't dirty and beautiful and untouchable and the sex object for one of the other main character dogs.
Rym: And pretty much that's literally the extent of that character.
Emily: They could have mitigated that by making like one or two of their original pack female dogs, because I mean, dog packs, they're not like, oh, all of a sudden there's only male dogs or male wolves roaming together.
Emily: That's silly.
Emily: Like dog packs are mixed.
Emily: So there was no real reason for it to be only dudes.
Emily: But there was like this one beauty dog.
Emily: She was untouchable, you know, and she she licked her fur clean.
Rym: But I guess that the conceit as the trailer showed was that, you know, it's set in this future Japan and everyone just speaks their native language.
Rym: So you'll just have people speaking in Japanese that you can understand.
Rym: And then the only translated characters would be the dogs.
Rym: But yet the movie really breaks that conceit constantly.
Rym: By translating everything one way or another.
Rym: So it says like, oh, there will be subtitles.
Rym: And then it just ends up subtitling a bunch of stuff.
Rym: Or some other character will just translate everything.
Emily: The interesting thing is to seeing different people's takes on this movie.
Emily: Like I've seen some people writing about this film, writing as Japanese people saying that they thought it was kind of interesting.
Emily: And they're like, I'm surprised that an American director, like usually working in English, would make a movie like this.
Emily: Some people didn't seem as put off by it, but obviously didn't consider it a Japanese film.
Emily: I saw other people of Japanese heritage saying it made them very uncomfortable.
Emily: But one thing I will say is it was strange seeing it as somebody who's like relatively bilingual.
Emily: I'm not a native speaker, but I speak enough Japanese that I don't, I can watch movies without subtitles.
Emily: And so I think a little bit of the hiding the meaning of the dialogue was lost on me.
Rym: Of course it didn't matter because the dialogue was almost always completely worthless.
Rym: Or it was actually just an excuse to do a bunch of exposition that should have just been done another way.
Rym: Like I feel like the movie went way out of its way to make sure you understood what the characters were saying.
Rym: Despite ostensibly using this other language to prevent you from understanding what they're saying.
Emily: I would have liked it better if it would have been the people.
Emily: There are no human characters that speak English.
Emily: And the only English is spoken by the dogs.
Emily: And so if they need to translate something, it's a voiceover by dogs.
Emily: Like there's this one dog who watches TV and she would have been the perfect narrator because they're like, oh, she's the oracle.
Emily: She understands the news.
Emily: But it's just because she can understand human TV.
Emily: And so already you've got a built-in plot device for somebody to make that audience connection.
Emily: But instead you had human characters who spoke in Japanese without subtitles.
Emily: But then you had human characters speaking in English with the same language as the dogs are speaking.
Emily: And I think the most egregious example of that was the exchange student.
Rym: Who really was that character hadn't been in the movies.
Emily: I thought she was really unnecessary.
Emily: And also like as a former exchange student, she made me kind of annoyed because she was like exactly the loud, obnoxious American who was like banging around just like, yeah, everybody listen to me.
Emily: And I'm going to chase her.
Rym: I mean, it's very easy to read it that way when she ends up being the de facto leader of the pro dog movement.
Emily: Yeah.
Emily: And like you're supposed to empathize with this person and you're like, she is the hero.
Emily: And she actually ends up saving the day in some cases.
Emily: And you're like, no, I would have rather had that firm delineation between the humans, you don't understand them.
Emily: Or if you speak Japanese, you do.
Emily: But their dialogue and their meaning is mostly told through the actions they do.
Emily: As an animator, it's so easy.
Emily: Well, not easy.
Emily: It takes a fair amount of skill.
Emily: But it's not uncommon to have characters who don't speak and act with their physical motions, you know, the whole environmental storytelling aspect.
Emily: You could have conveyed the story with only Japanese dialogue by the humans.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But they don't.
Rym: They end up translating almost all of the Japanese in one way or another, even down to the point of using English words that would not normally be used.
Emily: Respecto.
Emily: There's this part where the boy, it's a movie about a boy and his dog.
Emily: So there's a lot of interaction between those two characters.
Emily: It's kind of cute that the script is flipped.
Emily: So you have the, at least Western audiences, don't necessarily understand what the human's saying, but they're understanding it from the point of the dog.
Emily: And the boy is like,
Emily: "Sito.".
Emily: And in Japanese, there's already "osuwari" is what you'd usually say when you're training your dog.
Emily: Maybe some people say the English word, but that's a little weird.
Emily: But I feel like the "fechi" and "sito" and the guy going "respecto" and stuff, it was a little bit unnatural because it's not really... And actually the dialogue itself, even though it was spoken by Japanese actors, it was still kind of stilted.
Emily: You know, it was like people would say kind of random things, like ramble on about a war between the dogs and the humans and stuff.
Emily: So I don't know.
Emily: That was an idea that could have gone somewhere, but it was definitely kind of ruined.
Rym: There's a lot of those ideas in the movie where individually you could debate their merits, but when they all add up, the movie invited a lot of the criticism that it's getting for this.
Rym: And a lot of it, much of it, not all of it, but much of it could have been easily avoided by just doing simple things like not having the exchange to the character.
Emily: Well, I mean, there were things that go beyond the cultural appropriation debate.
Emily: This is an interesting one because you know when people talk about cultural appropriation on the internet, sometimes I feel like they go a bit overboard.
Emily: I've heard people say being an exchange student is cultural appropriation.
Emily: I'm a little bit like, "Whoa
Emily: there!".
Emily: I think learning a language but learning it on other people's terms.
Emily: Like when I was a foreign student, I definitely understood that I was a guest and I was beholden to other people for allowing me to come study at their school.
Emily: Appropriation is more taking something for your own personal gain as a culture that's been empowered by imperialism and basically using it as a very surface level.
Emily: For example, people use the idea of putting a Buddha statue in your home if you're not Buddhist for decoration.
Emily: You don't understand all the cultural background of this object, but you're like, "Oh, it looks cool, so let's roll with
Emily: it."
Emily: Especially if it comes for your personal gain as in like, "I'm trying to sell this thing.
Emily: I make this food and I borrow from a national cuisine.
Emily: I'm selling it to
Emily: you.".
Emily: But this one, I guess at least at the very least, I can say I, as a white American, at least thought they weren't rude about it.
Emily: There are some cases where I see people making stuff about Japan and it's just very ignorant and embarrassingly racist.
Emily: And this one, I feel like it had the element where it used the aesthetic to dress up the movie and it was kind of surface level, but at least it was respectful about it in a way.
Rym: Yeah, but I guess at the same time, the fact that their almost stated goal was to use Japanese as an unknowable other.
Emily: It was exotic, exactly.
Emily: It was like one of those things where they put this overlay on the movie and they could have told the same story in... Somebody used the example of Finland.
Emily: You could have like, "Okay, there's this Finnish dog colony off the
Emily: coast.".
Emily: And the Japanese stuff was just there to draw you closer to the dogs and bring you further from the humans and also provide an art style that they could apply to the various look and feel of objects in the film.
Emily: And one thing that I did find very interesting, and that brings me to our second point about things that were kind of a little bit dodgy about the movie, is that it's set in future Japan, right?
Emily: But it's not like...
Rym: Yeah, right around the 100 year anniversary of World War II.
Emily: It's not like cyberpunk future Japan.
Emily: It bows very heavily from like Showa era aesthetics, like 1930s to 1960s, the art and advertising and graphical style of a lot of things from that era, like World War II to the mid-century.
Emily: And that is definitely not accidental because a big part of that movie is about internment.
Emily: It's basically like...
Rym: I mean, they're literally building an internment camp for dogs to use a scapegoat for some other thing and execute them all.
Rym: Yeah, and didn't you say... And then replace them with robots that would then control the population.
Emily: That was kind of a twist.
Emily: I was like,
Emily: "Okay.".
Rym: It's interesting because that was the only part of the movie that was subtle, was that...
Emily: Was the robot dog?
Rym: Only the dog saw the robots acting as these killing machines.
Rym: The normal Japanese people saw them as just cute dog replacements.
Emily: They're like Aibo, you know?
Emily: You see those Aibo toys?
Rym: So the movie could be so utterly unsubtle and very sort of crude about all of its points.
Rym: And then this one point is the one thing that's easy to miss and subtle and in the background and actually pretty interesting.
Emily: You brought up... I didn't even notice some of the things, but they basically... I forget what the gate said, but they basically had the "work will make you free" gate.
Emily: I forget the concentration camp that had that gate, but it was definitely a nod toward that.
Emily: I was like, "One, I feel a little... Let's not get into the wartime atrocities of the Japanese empire, but for Americans to throw stones about internment when it comes to Japanese people is a little like, "Okay, let's look at your own
Emily: house.".
Rym: But again, this is one of those situations where all these little elements of the film individually add up to a fairly, not to use the Tumblr word, problematic situation.
Emily: But there were things I really genuinely enjoyed.
Rym: Oh, the movie was beautiful otherwise.
Rym: I enjoyed it as much as these things were bothering me.
Emily: And I like the bantery dialogue.
Emily: I gotta admit...
Rym: Well, it was Wes Anderson dialogue.
Rym: It was fantastic Mr.
Rym: Fox 2.
Emily: I'm a fan of Wes Anderson.
Emily: I really like the Royal Tenenbaums is one I'm not sure if you've seen, but I really like that movie and a bunch of other ones that I've seen, I've actually really enjoyed.
Emily: And people rip on him for his little bit pretentious, this hipster aesthetic to it.
Emily: But it had all those points, like the back and forth, mundane dialogue.
Emily: It had that deadpan banter that he has going on.
Emily: And the music was really good.
Emily: It had the acoustic indie band that was... I really enjoyed the soundtrack.
Rym: A lot of wide shots of the characters traversing across the... Yeah, like doing their montage of traveling to the other side of the island.
Emily: So all those things were great.
Emily: And like I said, in terms of the animation, it was pretty amazing.
Emily: I loved watching it.
Emily: One thing I will rag on it though, I was pretty mad that they set a dog film in Japan and did not have a Shiba.
Emily: I think there was one Shiba in the background.
Emily: I was like, "What's
Emily: Shiba?".
Emily: That's just 'cause I'm biased, but whatevs.
Emily: And also the whole animal testing subplot, that always really gets to me.
Rym: Yeah, the whole plague dog subplot.
Emily: I was just like,
Emily: "No!".
Rym: But it also complicates the overall themes in the sense that the dogs just basically want to return to the servile life among humans.
Rym: Who, independent of the Isle of Dogs, like the internment, they had been experimenting on dogs anyway before that point.
Emily: Yeah, it was like pre-banishment of the dogs.
Emily: They had been making this... Like there were the dogs who existed before on the island.
Emily: Everybody starts rumors about that.
Emily: That scene actually made me cry.
Emily: That was a scene where I was just like,
Emily: "No!".
Rym: I mean, again, I appreciate how it didn't shy away from that.
Rym: If it's gonna introduce it, it really went into it.
Emily: It had some good emotional beats to the movie.
Emily: And I mean, I do like stories about the bond between an animal and a human and stuff like that.
Emily: So it was definitely a boy and his dog kind of story.
Emily: And it was about that love and that bond.
Emily: The boy would not give up his dog and the dog would not give up on the boy.
Rym: Meanwhile, the primary antagonist in the movie ended up being pretty inscrutable.
Rym: And it was very difficult to understand why the mayor changed his mind and why he did what he did in the first place.
Rym: And that was very much obscured behind the fact that this character has no meaningful translated dialogue, except the dialogue that served as exposition for the story that the dogs followed.
Emily: So there were a lot of things.
Emily: And we talked about this, like, is it because they want a hostile takeover?
Emily: Is it about militarization?
Rym: I mean, that's kind of partly how I read it at-- - I mean, isn't it 'cause you want to get rid of dogs, replace them with robot dogs who then can control the population if need be?
Emily:  It's about losing the country's soul.
Emily: That's what it's about.
Emily: It's about militarization of a country and the rise of imperialism.
Rym:  It's about how these government officials are actually secretly crew cats.
Emily:  Are actually cats, yeah.
Rym: See, but that's what I'm saying.
Emily: What is it actually, why did they do this?
Emily: Is it because they just like cats or is it because they're trying to convert the country over-- - Well, there's that lurch-looking vizier, whatever he was.
Rym:  That's what I'm talking about.
Rym:  The guy who looks exactly like an old Lupin villain.
Emily:  Yeah, he's like this creepy-ass zombie-looking dude who is major domo.
Emily: He's like the military henchman who's like,
Emily: "Mwahaha.".
Emily: And then there was the scientist.
Emily: That was the other thing that I kept expecting the scientist subplot to go somewhere.
Emily: And that was another joke that felt very flat.
Emily: is his sidekick, his assistant, was Yoko Ono.
Emily:  Was that really a joke?
Rym: It was just a cameo that was very unfortunately placed.
Emily:  Yeah, it was just like, "Yoko
Emily: Ono!".
Emily: I was like,
Emily: "Okay.".
Rym:  Like the movie's literally like, "No, her name is literally Yoko
Rym: Ono.".
Emily: And here she is, you know?
Emily: So, I mean, yeah, it was totally a cameo, but it was just a little bit awkward.
Emily: I was like, "Eh,
Emily: whatever.".
Rym:  Especially because that character serves no purpose other than to be a stepping stone for the American exchange student girl.
Emily:  To save the day.
Emily: You know, that could have been executed, that whole subplot with the scientist and the cure serum could have been executed with the Yoko Ono character.
Rym:  Yeah, it's like they added a white character into the mix just so she could be the hero.
Emily:  Yep.
Emily: So anyway, I mean, I can go on and be like what I would have done differently.
Emily: And I do still think that I would recommend this movie.
Emily: Like, it's been reviewed pretty highly on Rotten Tomatoes.
Rym:  I will pretend I didn't thoroughly enjoy it.
Emily:  It's not without good reason that people have been enjoying this movie, but I would warn American viewers to go into this with that sort of skeptical mindset of, you know, you can enjoy the thing, but also be aware that this is definitely a very Western viewpoint.
Emily: You know, don't let the surface level detail of like, "Oh, look, that's written in Japanese fool you into thinking that it's anything
Emily: but.".
Emily: So Wes Anderson, you continue your streak of making odd and slightly pretentious cinema, and I hope you make more stop motion.
Rym:  But maybe don't make another one set in Japan right away.
Emily:  Please, that's probably not a good idea to do.
Rym:  But yeah, we avoided like super spoilers or anything, 'cause you should probably go see it at some point.
Emily:  Yeah, like I feel like we didn't cross that line where it's like, "Oh, and then so-and-so shows
Emily: up.".
Rym:  There's a couple of shocking twists and turns along the way that are actually pretty interesting.
Rym:  Yeah, and I did like- - I mean, right in the beginning, "The Cage with the Dead
Rym: Dog.".
Emily:  Oh my God, that was, I was like,
Emily: "No!".
Emily: But like, it's a disturbing film, but it's disturbing in the way that I like, and it has animal characters triumphing over adversity.
Rym:  Well, the best character in the whole movie is that hacker kid.
Emily:  No.
Rym:  That kid was my favorite character.
Emily:  I think I like the plague dog dogs.
Rym:  Oh yeah, they're good.
Emily:  That was good.
Emily: I actually really like the main character.
Emily: This is basically, he's like the pack leader, and the other is like the second-in-command dog is always mad about this.
Rym: It's like, "Why are we gonna do what he wants to
Rym: do?".
Emily: It's like an ongoing gag.
Rym:  Yeah, the dogs are really funny, 'cause it's just all-star cast.
Rym: It's like Jeff Goldblum and Bill Murray.
Emily: Did you notice when the American actors are talking, like the voices seem more clear?
Rym:  Oh, a bunch of people reviewing it said the same thing.
Rym:  No, it sounded like-- - All the Japanese voices were muffled definitely on purpose, 'cause you can't make that kind of mistake as a voice mixer.
Emily:  You know what it felt like?
Emily: It felt like they were making the recordings kind of match the visuals, 'cause like I was saying, it has a very antique feel to it.
Emily: It sounds like somebody's talking into a really old microphone or something.
Emily: It's got that same sort of muffled quality of archaic film recording or something like that, and it definitely feels very crudded up, whereas everybody else's voice is just very normal surround sound.
Rym:  Yeah, the one interesting, just a frame, the thing that I did like is the way characters were framed when they were talking is they usually wouldn't be shown talking to each other, especially the dogs.
Rym: They'd be shown talking directly at the camera.
Rym:  Yeah, but again, that's one of those things where it's like definitely-- - And you get these 180 flips with the camera, but you clearly wouldn't get any panning shots or anything.
Emily: You just get-- - It was like a dialogue, and you're inhabiting the two characters talking to each other.
Emily: But stuff like that is very interesting artistically.
Emily: I feel like they took certain risks with this movie and the framing of shots.
Emily: Like you were saying, the long shots where they're going along and the background is changing, like different shots of all the rubble.
Emily: And I gotta say, I'm weird in that I like aesthetically that kind of decayed industrial feeling.
Emily: Pictures of old factories and stuff can be really almost beautiful.
Emily: They're like ugly beautiful.
Emily: And that's what this movie was.
Emily: It was ugly beautiful.
Rym:  So yeah, it's probably worth seeing.
Emily:  Yeah, I'd say go for it.
Rym:  I mean, if you like Wes Anderson stuff, it's just more of that.
Emily:  It's basically Fantastic Mr.
Emily: Fox, but in some respects better, but with an added dose of cultural appropriation.
Rym:  I guess in the end, I partly liked Fantastic Mr.
Rym: Fox more because it was more whimsical.
Rym: And while it never really went-- - Way less grim.
Rym:  Yeah, I mean, granted the moral of Fantastic Mr.
Rym: Fox is he's not that fantastic.
Rym: It kind of ruined everything for everybody.
Emily:  But in a way, Fantastic Mr.
Emily: Fox had a happy ending.
Emily: And I just saw it like a few months ago.
Emily: So it's relatively fresh in my memory, but there's a lot of things that go on where it's a constant escalation of like predicaments.
Emily: And it's about somebody trying to like fake it till they make it.
Emily: That was basically the motto of that movie.
Emily: It's like, say you're an average Joe, just tell yourself you're not and you somehow you'll make it through.
Rym:  But Isle of Dogs has its own, the whimsical or weird moments that it has kind of come out of left field.
Rym: And they're lampshaded in the course of the movie, like the exploding teeth thing.
Emily:  Yeah, like it was a very surreal film.
Emily: Like a lot of stuff you'd be like, what is this even?
Emily: And some stuff was just strange.
Emily: And like the whole thing about poison wasabi, I was like, wasabi poison.
Rym:  See again with the Japanese thing, why did it have to be wasabi?
Rym: that is the poison?
Rym:  But the thing is, it wasn't specific.
Emily: I thought they were just gonna use it when they murdered the one guy.
Rym:  But no, that's also the genocide poison for the dogs.
Emily:  Yeah, there was like this elaborate, that was a perfect example of how the animation could be beautiful where they show in like pretty realistic detail, a sushi chef preparing these different fish for a bento that's then poisoned, poisoned wasabi.
Emily: And so that's why I thought it was wasabi poison, but then wasabi poison is the name of the gas that they're trying to murder the dogs with, so okay.
Emily: So cool, whatevs.
Emily: We'll see how it does.
Emily: I'm curious to see when it's released in Japanese theaters, how Japanese film critics react to it because that's something that I've noticed.
Emily: that's kind of interesting because I feel like Asian American viewers often have different reactions to whitewashing or those types of problematic Hollywood habits compared to Japanese audiences.
Emily: Like the whole ghost in the shell thing, a lot of the Japanese people I saw on Twitter were like, "Hey, what
Emily: up?".
Emily: Like they didn't care that much about it, but at the same time, they're coming at it from a different context where they're in the majority where they live.
Emily: So don't feel as culturally embattled, I think.
Rym: But I guess also like combining that with the whole, it's all male characters and the only female characters who do anything are the white girl.
Rym: I guess that she's the only one who does anything.
Emily: No, no.
Rym: The scientist girl doesn't do anything except tell the white girl what to do and Nutmeg, the dog, doesn't do anything.
Rym: She's just there to be a reward at the end.
Emily: She's there to offer enigmatic advice to doggy protagonist.
Emily: Well, I feel like we ragged on the movie sufficiently, but also said that we liked aspects of it.
Emily: So I don't want to belabor the point.
Rym: Yeah, go see it.
Rym: Make your own determination about Wes Anderson.
Emily: Yes, indeed.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Rym: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Rym: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Rym: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.