Rym: It's Wednesday, May 30th, 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Wotakoi.
Rym: Love is hard for the otaku.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So we, uh, we've been fans of anime for a long time.
Rym: I've been a fan of anime since I was in like fourth grade.
Scott: I've been a fan of anime since the last millennia.
Rym: But, uh, The thing about anime is that there's bad anime out there.
Rym: If I, if someone asks me, because Darryl Surratt tweeted the other day, and his tweet was like, "What was that one anime, the first one you saw, that was bad?
Rym: Like, bad to where you realized it was
Rym: bad?".
Rym: 'Cause I will admit, there was a time before I'd seen enough anime to really understand what made a quality show, where I would watch literally any garbage anime I could get my hands on.
Rym: No,
Scott: actually, when I was watching in the last millennia on the sci-fi channel, right, there were some, there were many great things that were viewed there, such as Dominion Tank Police,
Rym: and Vampire Hunter D, Project Aco,
Scott: Galaxy Express, the
Rym: first Tenchi movie,
Scott: and then there was like some Fatal Fury movie, which
Rym: was
Scott: obviously not as good as the other things, and it was based on a fighting game, and yes, I knew it was bad.
Scott: And I did not want to watch it again, even though I wanted to watch more anime.
Rym: But I watched them anyway, just after the fact, I'd be like, "Eh, that wasn't so
Rym: great.".
Rym: But at the same time, I would still be like, "Yeah, but it was anime, I watched some
Rym: anime.".
Scott: No, I knew that Fatal Fury movie was bad, but...
Rym: Well, you got an anime later than me.
Scott: What do you mean?
Rym: I was starved to get ahold of any anime I could.
Scott: It was sci-fi channels as early as pretty much most people.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, the anime, there's two anime that come to mind.
Rym: when someone asks me, "Hey, what's a really bad
Rym: anime?".
Scott: Gray Digital Target?
Rym: Gray Digital Target.
Rym: And not O'Dean, because while O'Dean is bad, it's just boring bad.
Rym: We've talked about that.
Scott: I haven't even seen O'Dean, I've only seen clips of O'Dean.
Rym: Wow, really?
Scott: What, you've watched O'Dean?
Rym: Yeah, of course I've watched O'Dean.
Rym: I've watched Oden on sci-fi.
Scott: It was real long and boring.
Scott: All right, well, good for you.
Scott: That wasn't even a full version.
Scott: Good for me.
Rym: But the other one that comes to mind pretty much immediately is not only the worst anime, one of the worst anime I can think of, it is, without any hesitation, I will say that it is the worst Lupin thing ever.
Rym: It is Lupin the Third, the Legend of the Gold of Babylon.
Scott: I mean, I don't know, I haven't seen all the Lupin things, so I can't say that for sure.
Rym: I say that having seen a lot of the Free Fujiko Mine more recent Lupins that are pretty fucking bad.
Scott: I've seen lots of Lupin and I can say that is a bad Lupin movie.
Rym: I mean, Columbus Egg gives it a run for its money.
Scott: But I mean, it's creative as it has more value than Grey Digital Target.
Rym: Yeah, but if I had to watch this again or Grey Digital Target again.
Scott: I'd watch this again.
Rym: I might watch Grey Digital Target again, I'm not sure.
Scott: I would not.
Scott: Why would I watch Grey Digital Target again?
Scott: Because my memory of Grey Digital Target is so hazy.
Rym: Literally, I remember exactly two things about Grey Digital Target.
Rym: I remember the cyborg grandpa, who all that was left of him was a torso and one arm, somehow climbing that cliff, letting go, not falling, and continuing to climb with one arm.
Scott: It's like that video game where the guy is in a barrel with a hammer.
Rym: And the other thing I remember is that instead of ending, the movie just stops and then the credits just appear.
Scott: No, there's some text on the still frame.
Rym: With this text that says like, "10 minutes later, the base was
Rym: destroyed.".
Rym: And then it kind of gets wavy.
Rym: I literally don't remember anything else about Grey Digital Target.
Rym: Who was the target?
Rym: Was there a color other than Grey?
Rym: I have no idea what that thing was about.
Scott: The guy's name was Grey.
Rym: Was he the target or did he target something?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Well, I don't remember anything about the plot of that movie.
Rym: Was there a movie or was there no AV?
Scott: I mean, I basically figure it had the same sort of plot as like an MD guys where it's sort of like bad guys in the tower.
Scott: Gotta go get them.
Scott: But you're the quiet, cool, bad ass, good guy.
Rym: Legend of the Gold of Babylon.
Rym: My news is that Discotek announced the 51 years of Lupin thing.
Scott: That sounds good.
Rym: Yeah, there was a penalty that apparently at Anime North, which apparently is a pretty good anime con, that they are releasing Legend of the Gold of Babylon.
Rym: Why?
Rym: On Blu-ray.
Rym: With a brand new English dub.
Scott: Why?
Scott: The world wonders.
Scott: Who's going to pay for this?
Rym: Babylon Gold, Daryl Surratt.
Scott: Go look at Daryl Surratt's Twitter.
Scott: I mean, Discotek releases a lot of good anime in America, but who would pay actual American dollars for a copy of Babylon Gold?
Rym: Legend of the Gold of Babylon is so goddamn old and bad that the only releases I know of in English in America were the Rupon titles, because they had the problems with the Lupin name, and they released it on VHS and Laserdisc.
Rym: And we got a bootleg copy from the RIT Anime Club and we watched it.
Rym: It has a scene where Lupin is being chased by Zenigata.
Rym: They're both on motorcycles and they're flying around the face of a giant clown at what I assume is a carnival.
Scott: They're in Rio.
Rym: Oh, yeah, it is in Rio.
Rym: And it kind of pulls the Scooby-Doo reversal, where this is the Lupin where it actually was aliens.
Rym: There's no other plot.
Rym: There's no other like, "Oh, it was a secret plot with a
Rym: projector.".
Rym: No, it was literally just Goddess/Aliens and the Gold of Babylon.
Rym: It is dumb as shit.
Rym: The fact that this is being released on Blu-ray, it's kind of amazing.
Scott: I can say it's ridiculous, creative, and memorable, but not good.
Rym: Yeah, but ridiculous, creative, and memorable.
Scott: It's sort of like when you go to the museum and there's some freaky art and you're like, "Whoa," and you can't forget it, but you would never hang that in your house.
Rym: Ridiculous, creative, and memorable is how I would describe Apocalypse Zero.
Scott: And if the person who made that art was having like a exhibition of just their works, you wouldn't pay to go see it.
Rym: So I guess only watch this if you're curious about it and/or Apocalypse Zero, because you'll see something that is crazy and memorable.
Rym: Even though I don't remember anything about it other than the two things I said.
Rym: So yeah, this is happening.
Rym: You got any other news?
Scott: I got some tiny news.
Scott: So number one, there's gonna be an anime movie screened in the US and G-Kids is hyping it up because it has the same producer as your name.
Scott: Oh, but it's not a Makoto Shinkai movie.
Scott: No.
Scott: No, but it's called Fireworks and they're putting it in the US on these three days very close to the 4th of July lol.
Scott: I assume the Japanese title of the movie is Hanabi because that's one of the few Japanese words I know.
Rym: I guess we should go see it.
Scott: We can go see it, but if you read the plot of this movie, it feels like Makoto Shinkai ripoff.
Scott: These some lovers keep going back in time on purpose to have like an intentional Groundhog Day so that they can get to a universe or timeline where they can stay together.
Rym: That does sound very Makoto Shinkai.
Scott: But it's not Makoto Shinkai.
Scott: As far as I can tell, he had nothing to do with it.
Scott: But the producer of your name though, you know, has something to do with it.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But yeah, if there's bad weather around the 4th of July weekend or whatever.
Rym: Well, the 4th of July, the actual holiday is on like a Wednesday this year.
Scott: So yeah, I mean there's three dates.
Scott: You can go to the website, you can buy tickets and go see this.
Rym: The 3rd, the 5th and the 7th, not the 4th.
Rym: There you go.
Rym: We'll probably go see it.
Rym: We'll do a show on it because, you know, the advice we always give if you like anime, watch pretty much every anime movie that isn't a numbered sequel to a property.
Rym: Yeah, why not?
Rym: Because worst case, well, I guess worst case you get Lupin the Legend of the Golden Babylon.
Scott: Anyway, so more and more news of the comic animation realm, right?
Scott: And they're both Netflix-y news, right?
Scott: One of them is Netflix is going to make, supposedly, I don't know if it's 100% confirmed yet, but people reported it.
Scott: There's a comic series called Locking Key.
Scott: that's real popular.
Scott: I've never read it.
Scott: I've never read it either.
Scott: I don't even know what it's about.
Scott: All I know is it's one of those things where it's like, you go to a comic book store and like, you know, there'll be quite a little bit of section of like locking key stuff and like it's popular.
Scott: And I think there's even a board game based on it or something.
Scott: And like, it's one of those things where it's like, it's big, but only big in a small pond of comic people.
Scott: But like the general population doesn't know, sort of like the way Game of Thrones was before it became a TV show, where it was big and like anyone who knew about fantasy novels and read them, like a huge Game of Thrones section.
Rym: I just read the plot summary.
Rym: It gets deep into a lot of proper nouns in a hurry.
Scott: But you know, like before Game of Thrones, the TV show, you'd go to the bookstore and all the nerds knew Game of Thrones, but other people didn't know what the fuck it was at all, right?
Scott: But it had a board game and it had a card.
Scott: It had all this stuff, right?
Scott: And then it became big.
Scott: Well, lock and key is now going to be an animation on Netflix.
Scott: So it's one of those things where all the nerds knew what it was.
Scott: And now it's going to be big.
Rym: I guess because we're geeks.
Rym: We didn't know anything about it.
Scott: Well, we knew it existed as the same as Game of Thrones existed.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I never bothered to read it.
Scott: And I didn't care.
Rym: I guess my rule always applies whenever anything like that is around.
Rym: If enough people talk about it, it makes enough splash.
Rym: I got to go see what the deal is.
Scott: Did you read Game of Thrones to see what the deal is?
Rym: Hell no.
Rym: Well, because I know that writing's bad.
Scott: You read Wheel of Time to see what the deal was.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And I read the whole thing because it was tolerable.
Rym: I tolerated it.
Scott: Were you going to read lock and key to see what the deal is?
Rym: Well, based on the four sentences of a very long summary of it that I read on Wikipedia, probably not.
Scott: Anyway, so the second one is also Netflix related, but quite the opposite.
Scott: Mark Millar and someone else, some comic people who make popular comic books.
Scott: Netflix is going to publish a comic book in the store on paper, but it's Netflix is the publisher.
Scott: So it's like you're going to go to the bookstore, the comic store, and it's going to say.
Scott: it's going to say Marvel.
Scott: It's going to say DC.
Scott: It's going to say image is going to see IDW and then it's going to say Netflix comic book, which is our move.
Scott: that that see that all the news comic books for many years have been the R and D of stories for movies and television.
Rym: So Netflix is trying to cut even to make a vertical stack, at least genre movies and television books and comic books.
Scott: All the paper stuff has been, Oh, everyone, all the writers make stories over in those mediums and if they're any good, we'll make you a bunch of money by licensing you in these mediums.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So think of it this way.
Rym: If Netflix makes a bunch of comics, then the cost of making those comics is real low.
Rym: And if one of them makes it big enough and they decide to turn it into a show, they get to keep all that money.
Scott: They don't have to.
Rym: They don't have to buy a license from Marvel in DC because if they go out and look for popular comic books, the people who made those comic books know they're popular and they won't sell that license cheap.
Scott: Well, well, that point is had to pay a license period.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If Netflix decides later that this comic, the story in this comic is show worthy and it becomes popular, they had to pay zero dollars or almost no dollars, way less dollars.
Rym: Magic meets mob.
Scott: They'll also be paying some of those.
Scott: They'll probably have to pay the creators some money, but they won't.
Scott: The it's like they're going to license it from themselves.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's, you know, that part of the money goes away.
Rym: It's a bunch of mob families who are also wizards.
Scott: Is that what it is?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Magic meets the mob.
Rym: My family is a magician sworn to protect our world.
Rym: Must battle an enemy who's picking them off one by one.
Scott: That's like, you know, someone who came up with that is basically like, what's popular with the people these days?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Crime stories and wizard stories.
Scott: Well, I know what we should be writing, dude.
Rym: If there was a comic that was just called crime wizards, I would read at least one issue of that.
Scott: Isn't that part of the, your forgotten realms?
Scott: Aren't there crime wizards?
Rym: No, there's more like fascist shithead wizards.
Rym: There aren't really wizards that are just crime into steel stuff.
Rym: They're all evil in like more intrinsic ways.
Rym: And one tiny thing, just a shortest possible geek bite because Emily and I finished made an abyss and you know what?
Rym: It's real good.
Rym: So we're going to probably do a real show on it in the near future.
Rym: When Scott also sees some of it.
Rym: So if you're looking for a show that has the aesthetic of a secret of mana kind of like JRPG action adventure RPG that has a secret of space where the plot and the characters drive a hundred percent as fast as possible into that secret to reveal it.
Rym: And that's the whole plot.
Rym: And you're willing to put up with ultra violence being perpetrated against a small children because that happens in this as well.
Rym: And it's a pretty good show.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: Uh, so someone posted this on our forum, which is a place you should go if you want to see stuff like this.
Rym: Our Roku forum is pretty rocking.
Scott: Anyway, so what this is, is, you know, is a big ass boat and a big ass boat as a big ass anchor.
Scott: And they're letting the anchor out because they got to stop the boat, I guess, because it's what anchors do.
Scott: They keep the boat in one place.
Scott: Uh, so you know that the anchor is tied is, you know, they're letting it go.
Scott: It's got this big ass chain, a chain that could lock up like a cracking and the anchor is going down.
Scott: And basically the way you let the anchor go down is there's like a motor and it's got a break and you basically, you know, the break is holding.
Scott: It's from what I understand, it keeps the anchor from going down into the ocean.
Rym: Turbo in the forum explains this in a lot more detail, right?
Rym: I don't know shit about anchors.
Scott: You basically take your foot off the break to let the anchor go down.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then, you know, you got to ease it off.
Scott: You can't just let the anchor go.
Scott: Whoosh, that's bad.
Scott: You got to, you got to let it go down slow.
Rym: Like the best part of those videos as he's closer to the end, the camera's like backing up a little bit.
Scott: So, uh, they, uh, they fuck it up and the anchor gets a little out of control.
Scott: And I guess it sucks for this boat, but it's great for us getting entertained by watching the enormous boat anchor go down to the bottom of the ocean way too quickly.
Rym: So the video is two minutes long.
Rym: And if you're really are impatient, you can skip to the second minute, but I'd recommend watching the whole thing because this escalates slowly until it's not escalating slowly anymore.
Scott: And even if you think, you know, keep watch to the end.
Scott: Cause even though, you know, well, at least watch till the anchor is gone because you think, oh, they got a handle on it.
Scott: No.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: There's a moment where you're like, okay, I think they got up.
Rym: Oh, that's a shame.
Scott: Keep going until there's no anchor left.
Rym: So my thing of the day, it's, it's, it's not really a cop out, but it is.
Rym: So it's an AMV.
Rym: Occasionally I showcase like a really good AMV or something, but I think AMVs are dead.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So I've, I've looked at the re I've looked at the winners of all the recent AMV competitions from like big cons.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: They're still really like, they're common.
Rym: People make them still have AMV.
Rym: Yeah, they do.
Rym: And they're popular.
Rym: I don't know why.
Rym: Cause most of the AMVs are pretty bad real soon.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Like, yeah.
Rym: So, I mean, I made one AMV.
Rym: I think I made as good AMV as I would ever make.
Rym: And I'm just never making one again, one and done, but this AMV is notable because I first saw this AMV in high school and you know how old I am.
Rym: This is back when one 20 P was a pretty good resolution.
Rym: Like you saw a video online at one 20 P you were living the high life.
Rym: So I saw, this is the first AMV I ever saw.
Rym: I saw an RM of it and it was amazing.
Scott: Cause I, this, I guess the first one I ever saw was the first one they showed at the first anime club.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: Was it, I don't know.
Rym: I don't remember what those were.
Scott: They definitely showed, um, uh, the two mix music video there, but that wasn't technically not an AMV.
Rym: It's just an, it's an animated music video.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I forget what the other things they showed were.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I had already seen white reflection as well because I had an MP2 that I found and spent like a week downloading in high school.
Rym: But in the air tonight, the Sailor Moon AMV, there's actually, I found this video and it's a pretty interesting story.
Rym: So the, I have the original file that I downloaded still.
Rym: I have that RM file.
Rym: It is way bad quality.
Scott: Play them again.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So I was really proud of the fact that I had acquired this anime music video in high school.
Rym: This YouTube video that I'm linking to is my thing of the day, which was uploaded in 2012 is really high quality, like suspiciously high quality.
Rym: So the story is it was uploaded by the person who made this AMV.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It was a very popular AMV because it was one of the early ones that was like available in a digital format.
Rym: And, uh, basically the reason they re uploaded it is I'm going to read this quote here.
Rym: This is probably one of the absolute worst in terms of release quality, uh, due to storage and bandwidth restrictions.
Rym: It was the longest AMV I ever made.
Rym: It was hard to make blah, blah, blah.
Rym: Uh, thanks to my recent rediscovery of my master VHS tape, I can finally put this out here to resolution better than one 20 P. So they found the VHS that they use to master this AMV originally, and they scanned it in and uploaded it.
Rym: So ladies and gentlemen, the first AMV I ever saw in a, in a shockingly high quality compared to what I was impressed with in the nineties.
Rym: In the meta moment, the GeekNights, good book club book is still the Odyssey by Homa translated by Emily Wilson.
Rym: Have you read any more of it?
Scott: Not much, but more than zero.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So you're past, uh, King Nestor.
Rym: You're at a actual Odysseus on his Odyssey.
Scott: Yeah, I've been, I've been on that for a little bit.
Rym: Have you run into polyphemus yet?
Rym: Do you remember who polyphemus is?
Scott: No.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: You'll know when you run into polyphemus or polyphemus depending on where you went to school and read this in, uh, middle school or high school.
Rym: Uh, otherwise, uh, stay tuned.
Rym: If you want to see us at the penny arcade expo West, pretty good odds.
Rym: The badges are going to go on sale tomorrow, or if not tomorrow, next week.
Rym: Wow.
Scott: I will say this based on the history, basically you should be on like, wait, which Defcon is the worst?
Rym: lower is worse.
Rym: We're at Defcon one.
Scott: We're at Defcon one for packs badges.
Rym: Defcon one is the Defcon level of the nukes are already in flight.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Like shit hit the fan.
Rym: It's over.
Scott: That's how on alert you should be for packs badges right now for all we know.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Cause I'm not looking at Twitter right now.
Rym: So if you want to see us at PAX West, good God, don't, you gotta be near a computer.
Rym: Like between the hours of 10 AM and 5 PM Eastern time, you gotta be on Twitter.
Rym: You're going to be subscribed to with notifications.
Scott: The two potential, uh, no, they're, they have an official Twitter account packs badges.
Scott: that will only, the only tweets that makes our tweets to announce badges are on sale or resale or reclaimed.
Scott: And they'll also, if you need to test your badge notification system, they will at you a message on request and that those are the only tweets they make.
Scott: They're also very good about replying to those requests.
Scott: They will always do it.
Rym: Uh, if you want to see the PAX Unplugged, pretty sure that it just ain't even sold out yet.
Rym: You can just buy badges to it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Check in to see right now.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: All days are available, including the kid's badge for Sunday, which I think is free.
Scott: I think it's 10 bucks.
Rym: I think it's like 10 bucks.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So yeah, if you had a little kid, you can, uh, go to PAX Unplugged in November on one day for like 10 bucks with the kid.
Scott: Well, the kid's 10 bucks.
Scott: You're not free.
Scott: You gotta pay.
Rym: Also, they do still sell a three day badge.
Rym: that is cheaper than individual day badges.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: because PAX Unplugged.
Scott: Do they have any, uh, merch you can preorder in advance?
Rym: They in fact do.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They're going to have that for West also.
Scott: So what is the merch you can order in advance?
Rym: Let's see a level up dice stand and dice socks and a blanket.
Rym: I got to see what this blanket looks like.
Rym: Oh, it's that bit.
Rym: I like that bit rod style.
Scott: All right, well you get that blanket then.
Rym: I just got to look at what kind of blanket it is.
Scott: A cheap mass manufactured blanket.
Rym: But is it a, I guess I'd rather have a beach towel than a blanket.
Rym: I would, I would pay, even if it was low quality, the beach towel I would bring to the beach.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's a beach towel.
Rym: I don't care if it wears out.
Scott: And the best beach towel ever had was a free giveaway at Shea stadium.
Scott: It was the MetLife beach towel with Snoopy on it.
Scott: And in those days, nowadays you go get free stuff at a sporting event and it's always el cheapo, right?
Scott: Back in those days, they, I was the highest quality.
Scott: goddamn beach towel.
Scott: That shit lasted for so many years.
Scott: I was like, you go to the store and buy the most expensive beach towel.
Scott: That's what it was.
Rym: But when you're a nerd at a con or in public, you can wear the social currency that says, yo, I'm an, I'm a weeb and you can find other weebs that way.
Rym: Hard to do that at the beach because you ain't wearing much.
Rym: So a nerdy beach towel seems to be the only way to go.
Scott: Why don't we, I don't think anyone's selling nerdy beach umbrellas.
Scott: Maybe we should get on that.
Rym: Ooh, maybe we should.
Scott: A lot of, I've seen a lot of people at the beach when they want to wave their nerd flag, literally wave their nerd flag.
Scott: They'll set up next to their beach tent, you know, or canopy, a flagpole.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And usually it's old people setting up like American flags or whatever, but, or POW flags and stuff on the beach.
Scott: But I've seen people wave like star Wars, rebel flags on the beach.
Scott: So go nuts.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Uh, otherwise the other thing, uh, you might remember team flags also popular.
Scott: Get your East favorite East sports teams flag up there.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: The New York whatevers.
Rym: Cause I don't care, but we also did resume.
Rym: This is Wednesday.
Rym: You probably care about this.
Rym: If you were waiting for us to do that Utena show again, GeekNights presents Utena.
Rym: We actually did a new episode.
Rym: It is uploaded and I have solved probably permanently the copyright problem.
Rym: This video is in the clear.
Rym: It's even monetized.
Scott: So you collected money off a tenant.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I've made like 12 cents off of you lovely people watching this video so far.
Rym: So yeah, if you, uh, liked revolutionary girl Utena and you wondered what the hell it was about, cause you couldn't figure it out on your own.
Rym: Well, you're in luck cause we have talked about in detail.
Rym: The first 16 episodes, uh, we're like halfway, a little under halfway.
Scott: Almost.
Rym: Even though I feel like after we do 39, we're going to have to do a few like, let's go back.
Rym: Do we really need to do the movie?
Rym: Uh, no, we're not doing the manga.
Rym: I'm not a fan of the Utena manga actually.
Rym: In fact, I'm less a fan of the longer, the further, the longer I've gone on thinking about Utena, the less I like Chiyo Saito's manga of Utena new manga volume coming.
Rym: I know.
Rym: I'm not that excited about it, to be honest.
Rym: I'm just shocked that it's happening.
Scott: The, uh, stage plays.
Rym: Those I feel like I could get into actually.
Scott: I know.
Scott: I watched a clip of one recently is bad.
Rym: I watched a clip of the old, old ones.
Rym: So what's a Koi?
Rym: love is hard for the Otaku.
Scott: So we, we, we prejudge this on.
Scott: judge anime by its cover, which we're going to do again in a few weeks.
Rym: Oh yeah, that's right.
Rym: Judge anime by its covers.
Rym: another anime related YouTube series we're doing.
Scott: And basically what we said is, Hey, this looks like, you know, some cute obviously romance, uh, you know, but it's about otaku.
Scott: So I thought it was going to be one of those shows, you know, where otaku's can sort of, you know, fantasize about getting some romance in the office action.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But it didn't have any of the like major rewarding sign flags of.
Rym: it's going to be skeevy or it's going to be creepy or it's going to be too much wish fulfillment.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I thought it was going to be somewhere in between, you know, like, uh, uh, my love story, but yeah, that's what I was thinking.
Scott: Something like that.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Uh, but anyway, so it reminds me of my love story a lot in terms of its pacing, sort of.
Scott: Uh, but anyway, I watched what, seven episodes of this thing, by the way, it's streaming only on Amazon.
Scott: If you have Amazon prime, you can just watch it for free.
Scott: If you don't, I don't know where you watch it.
Rym: I watched, uh, three episodes.
Rym: I watched one of my computer and two of my phone because the Amazon thing just works.
Scott: So here's the deal.
Scott: This girl, uh, who's an otaku.
Scott: She is a bl making comic cat otaku.
Rym: She is a horrifying for Joshi.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: She has a new job because she, I guess she left her old job because they found out she was an otaku and she couldn't take it.
Scott: And I guess her boyfriend dumped her cause she was no time.
Rym: Her boyfriend dumped her because she was a for Joshi and he didn't want to be seen with her and immediately started dating some other girl who wasn't nerdy.
Scott: So she left that job and got a new job.
Scott: So, uh, she came to this new job and she doesn't want anyone to know that she's no otaku.
Scott: And then I can, the first day she bumps into someone who is the childhood friend.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: It's a trope.
Scott: The childhood friend trope in the anime.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And he's no talk.
Rym: And he doesn't even hide it.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: And the first thing he does, like in the hallway is ask her like, Hey, you going to the next comic cat?
Scott: And she's like, Oh shit, no, no, but then it turns out, uh, by luck and this all happens in the first episode.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: That, uh, her female coworker is also no otaku, a cosplay one.
Rym: That bit I actually liked a lot cause it's this like they have this generic office interaction.
Rym: Like you're like, like you do, you've all worked in offices.
Rym: Many of you, I guess a lot of you are in high school, so, but it'll be a point where you're working in an office and someone will reveal a nerdy shibboleth like.
Rym: they will say a word or use a phrase or have a desktop background where you're not sure they're a nerd, but there's a chance.
Rym: like they've got a link key chain.
Rym: You're like, Whoa, do they, do they like, do they just know about link?
Rym: or if they played like every Zelda game?
Rym: Like, I don't know.
Scott: I'm pretty sure they played at least one Zelda game key jade.
Scott: It's just the question of how old they are.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But it's also a question of, are they casually into this?
Rym: Are they a nerd like me?
Rym: Can I immediately start going crazy on them?
Scott: You make it your key chain.
Scott: You can go crazy.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: My son gave this to me.
Rym: My girlfriend gave this.
Scott: No one's got a key chain because someone gave it to, uh, I've seen people who have nerdy key chains.
Rym: They have no idea what they are.
Scott: I've literally said that happened before at work, but she doesn't want to, we should give out nerdy key chains to people for free, but they're actually from like some hentai, but you wouldn't know looking at it.
Scott: These people all have overfeed and key chains.
Scott: They don't realize it.
Scott: So, and then people who do realize they're like, oh, funny stories there.
Rym: Emily had an interaction with a girl and her mother at a, at a convention where she was staffing and the mother was being a pain in the ass, but the girl was definitely cosplaying as something from a straight up porn.
Rym: And the mom clearly had no idea what this costume was, but the other one that's more funny is I wear my ogloff shirt, which is just as cute fox.
Rym: If you don't know, you just see this shirt.
Rym: It's like, oh, that's a cute fox shirt.
Rym: And some people are like, oh, that's a cute fox shirt.
Rym: And some people at conventions will say, I recognize that shirt and that's all they need to say.
Rym: Cause now I know they know that I know and I know that they know.
Rym: And usually all I say is, yup.
Rym: Glad you noticed.
Rym: I'm glad you know what this is.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Anyway, so the back to the, so.
Rym: But she wants to like figure out how nerdy her boss is without her boss.
Scott: But basically what ends up happening, I know, you know, long story short is this four coworkers, her, the childhood friend, who's the gamer nerd, the other coworker who is the cosplay nerd and the other coworkers, the two dudes and two girls, the other coworker who is a nerd who hides it, but he likes things like Evangelion figurines.
Rym: And so you've got like the four kinds of nerdy coworkers in an office, right?
Scott: So basically she dates the childhood friend and the other two coworkers are dating.
Rym: And it's not a will they won't they.
Rym: they're dating by the end of the first episode.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That it's the new style.
Scott: The old style is always will.
Scott: they won't they.
Scott: The new style is dating right away.
Scott: And now we'll show you what the relationships.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: My love story did that and it was great.
Rym: This show's doing it similar.
Scott: That's the new way romance animes go.
Scott: is everyone's dating right away.
Rym: Cause you can't Miyakatama home it like.
Rym: I'm done with that.
Rym: No, that was done with that before I finished watching.
Scott: That's played out anyway.
Scott: So basically each, it's very episodic.
Scott: from then on, there's a little bit of continuity going on, but not much.
Scott: And what the, basically each episode is like, Ooh, there's some sort of trouble or some sort of, you know, relationship drama.
Rym: They both suck at being in relationships and it's really sad actually.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then it sort of resolves.
Scott: And then the next episode there's another thing.
Rym: Like they don't know how to, it's interesting watching characters that are written well to act like people who are bad at basic parts of life, but good at some other part.
Rym: Like it's pretty well written in that regard is that it was what I would say.
Rym: Cause I don't want to spoil what happens in like later episodes.
Rym: Everything I spoiled is like episode one.
Scott: Like episode two is basically like, Oh, the problem is they, they were such close friends, but then once they made it official, they were dating.
Scott: They had a hard time talking to each other.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Resolve that.
Scott: That's episode two, right?
Scott: Episode, I think I forget which episodes are, but one of the episodes is like, Oh, it's Christmas.
Scott: What are they going to do for Christmas together?
Scott: They're all awkward.
Scott: What are they going to, what's going to happen?
Scott: And the thing is, is like the actual sort of conflicts.
Scott: problems aren't really that interesting, but each episode manages to have like at least one or two moments that are kind of funny and unique and hilarious, especially if you're like, if you can relate to this, it's like, or if you're an otaku, who's trying to date.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But I love the underwhelming theme of someone's like, Oh, I'm such an otaku.
Rym: I can't let anyone know where no one will date me.
Scott: This actually teaches like even like lessons that are true.
Scott: It's like, it's like, Oh, it's so true.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: Lols.
Rym: But she's like, Oh no, if anyone finds out I'm an otaku, they won't date me.
Rym: And then the dude's like, why don't you just date an otaku?
Rym: She's like, I don't want to date a fucking otaku, which is, that's kind of how that guys and otaku and that's how they all seem to act.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You know, and it shows, you know, a lot of things like, Oh, you know, if you would have dated not otaku guy, it would have been bad.
Scott: You know, see, it's like if you date not otaku guy, then he doesn't respect any of your otaku stuff, even if he still goes out with you.
Scott: But look, now you're dating otaku guy.
Scott: He comes and works at your table at Kamikaze.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then it's like, Oh, all that she hears, uh, she's walking around Kamikaze after buying something and she hears like girls whispering, Oh my God, there was a cute cosplaying boy selling stuff at this table selling yaoi.
Scott: It's like, Oh my God, I had to get back to my table.
Scott: So it's like that.
Scott: That's the kind of funny moments that you get that are like the good part of this show.
Rym: It's very relatable to like adult nerds in America as well, because a lot of our friends, like a lot of people, it's not super Japanese, actually their workplace, even though it's 100% Japan seems very American.
Scott: They work on time.
Scott: They leave our con time.
Scott: They're not overworked.
Scott: You know, they're chilling at lunch and you know, the, the work they're doing is kind of not, it's not office.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: Not at all.
Scott: Not in any way.
Scott: You don't even know.
Scott: the things I don't like about the show is that there's really only five characters and really only one of them is a minor character that you don't even see from any episodes, which is the main guy's brother.
Scott: Like I feel like this show would be better if it had a little more of a cast of idiots.
Scott: This basically only has four people in the whole show.
Scott: And it's literally just every scenario, at least in seven episodes, the same four characters with the brought that one brother thrown in a little bit in the late in the, some of the later episodes.
Scott: And it's like, how much can I get out of these four characters?
Scott: You're really milking every milk you can get out of this.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You got to pull the Simpsons and bring in the most is like and give him like a whole episode.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I don't, you don't see anyone else in the office.
Scott: You don't see anyone else in the town, you know, as like every single time all four characters end up getting together.
Scott: It's never two of them alone here or two of them alone there.
Scott: And it seems like you get this feeling that they do have entire lives in between the episodes.
Scott: And really what's happening is that any the rest of their lives were not all four of them are together are happening.
Scott: There's like, in fact, it feels like most of their lives, not all four of them are together.
Scott: That wouldn't make sense, but it's like the camera turns on when all four of them get together and then episode begins.
Scott: And then when they all split up and go back to their lives again, the camera turns off and that's in between episodes.
Rym: Yeah, I could see that.
Scott: It's like they're probably been like a weeks, like two weeks since the last episode, you know, but they just weren't all getting together after work.
Scott: And then suddenly an episode starts and it's like, hey, are we all going to the bar after work?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, they go to book off after work in one episode.
Scott: The drama of going to book off.
Scott: Oh, I don't want to buy with cheese.
Scott: I don't want to walk around and follow her and go to the section.
Scott: She's going to, you know, I don't like going to the store alone.
Scott: I don't want to go with anybody.
Scott: I do want to go with someone.
Scott: That was my dream.
Scott: Do you bring go to book off with a friend?
Rym: I'm again, it's an anime that will appeal to people who are in their late twenties to thirties and are kind of nerdy.
Rym: And I mean, like granted in my work, everyone knows like, oh yeah, he's the fucking nerd guy who knows all the nerd shit.
Scott: But I know a lot of you out there.
Scott: People on the nerd right away.
Scott: I'm like nerd coming through.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You want to hire this nerd swerve for the podcast?
Scott: You do.
Scott: Are you sure?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I got, I got my new job.
Rym: My resume GeekNights was literally at the top.
Rym: It was like, I do this podcast.
Scott: I'm going to this packs thing.
Scott: And if you try to tell me no, I'm going to quit.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Just letting you know now.
Scott: Not joking.
Rym: My condition of employment.
Scott: Once I said I wouldn't, I did.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: I don't think I quit a job.
Scott: Jobs.
Rym: I too skipped that.
Scott: Want to go to that wedding more than I want to go to this job.
Rym: But I want to go to packs more than I want to do most things.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: So pay attention to buy tickets this week or next.
Rym: But I like this show.
Rym: I'll probably watch all of it.
Scott: It's not, I don't know if I'll watch it.
Scott: I don't think it's like, I'm not going to go.
Scott: And like every time a new episode comes out, watch it.
Scott: But when I'm bored, someone else is like, Hey, I want to watch more of that show.
Scott: But like I.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Or if I'm bored and like I'm commuting, I'll just watch like an episode.
Scott: Also, it has boob jokes.
Scott: So, but they're, they're less boob jokes than dragon maid.
Scott: So it's, it's a tolerable level of boob.
Rym: Dragon maid.
Rym: They were above the, like they were getting above the line of eh.
Scott: This is below the line of boob joke cannot be tolerated, but they're there in case, you know, that's the thing for you.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's also an anime that is pretty, just sort of fun and benign to watch.
Rym: Like it's not one of those shows you get to warn people about it.
Rym: No, like maiden abyss.
Scott: I like it is one of those shows where you don't know anything about nerdiness.
Scott: Like if you don't know what the hell BL and yaoi is, it won't make any sense.
Scott: It won't make any sense.
Scott: Cause like there's a whole scene in a diner where they're arguing over who should be on top and who should be on the bottom.
Scott: But then I appreciate both that argument and the fact that the show at first, they're arguing about like these two fictional anime, you know, they're arguing about characters in manga and then they're arguing about their boyfriends, which one should be on top and bottom.
Rym: But like a lot of shows that do deal with this kind of subject matter tend to go the route of explaining everything.
Rym: Like there's definitely a show.
Scott: If you don't know what comic kit is and what doujinshi are and what cosplaying is, you won't understand what the fuck is going on.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Also, all of the video games in this are Nintendo.
Scott: It's like obviously monster hunter on the switch, obviously Mario Kart, obviously.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's all Nintendo games.
Rym: Because they're playing their switches all the time.
Scott: There's one episode where they play an MMO together.
Rym: I love you early on when the dude, I think it's actually only half an episode.
Scott: And then the other half episode is something else.
Rym: The like the more crypto nerdy guy comes over to the dude and he's like, hey, something, something, something.
Rym: The guy's like, do you mind?
Rym: He's like, why are you playing video games?
Rym: It's work.
Rym: And all he does is hold up his watch.
Rym: It's 1201.
Rym: And it's lunchtime.
Scott: That's me.
Rym: Do you mind?
Scott: It's me.
Scott: Not working.
Rym: As he eats garbage.
Scott: I'm leaving.
Scott: Bye.
Scott: See ya.
Rym: So, yeah, but I like the fact that the show.
Rym: Assumes the audience knows the subject matter and skips past all that and gets right into like, they're arguing about the drop rate of the Ruby in the game.
Scott: This is a, it's a cute show for nerds only.
Scott: It's inoffensive.
Scott: It has fun moments, but it's not like some kind of a plus anime.
Scott: I'm again, it's just, Hey, it's cool that this exists.
Scott: Have a good time.
Scott: If you've got nothing else going on.
Rym: It's anime I like, I'll watch it casually.
Rym: I'm not going to shotgun all the episodes like I did with Made in This.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver, Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Heidi McNicholas, Shimmering Ruby Obelisk, Hanging in the Sky, MyStady.com, Jeremy Minor, Link Egee, Kelly Snyder, Cold Guy, Amanda Duchette, Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brandow, Mr.
Rym: Strong Stretching, 421 Creations, no, I never ever wonder why we're here, Semper Fi, bitch, Shervin Von Horrell, Rory, James David White, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy with like eight exclamation points, Capybara Pickle Gumquat, Sailor Vista, Don Schleich, Jartavshan, Jojo Joestar, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand with three exclamation points, Ryan Perrin, Dropenlander, Finn, all caps, one exclamation point, Chris Midkiff, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: So yeah, now I leave you with...