Speaker 1: It's Tuesday November 22nd, and this is geek knives.
Speaker 1: tonight We talked about how we completely screwed off the first half of this podcast.
Speaker 1: alright, so The first 20 minutes of this podcast are gone screwed up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Scott in his infinite playing with his microphone Brushed the knobs on the mixer and turned my volume all the way up.
Speaker 0: Hey only part of the blame go to me.
Speaker 0: part of the blame also must go to the knob and the wire.
Speaker 1: All right, all right, but the point is the first 20 minutes of our banter Which we cannot replicate because it is absolutely impossible to Retalk about something.
Speaker 0: yep, but it was good, but it was loud loud loud, and I was normal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm loud loud loud clipping loud and Scott is quiet quiet quiet.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, so it's kind of painful to listen to.
Speaker 0: but rather than deny you all the pleasure Hahaha, we we put it up completely unedited Completely unedited so that at least you get something out of it, and it's in a separate thing so we won't force it upon anyone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so if you really want to hear what we had to say Look in the comments on this week's podcast on the website, and you'll see a link to the bad mp3.
Speaker 0: So we're just gonna jump right into our games bit because it's Tuesday, and it's games day.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep, yep Ah So let's see video game action.
Speaker 1: Well we picked up.
Speaker 1: well I picked up for six dollars soul caliber - that was $12.
Speaker 1: now It was six dollars.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: It used to be 17.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Kind of balked at paying six bucks at first.
Speaker 0: Well, I wouldn't balk at six bucks, and then I realized hey soul caliber.
Speaker 1: I like that game.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's an old game, but you know it's my second favorite fighting game ever.
Speaker 0: second only to Bushido blade - I'm not a fan of the Bushido blade, but you're not good at him, and it's like even if I try to be good at him It's just even if I was good.
Speaker 0: I mean it's a great concept.
Speaker 0: you kill a guy with you know realness like you hit him with a sword he's dead.
Speaker 0: but It ends up not being really fun to play because it ends up just being Kind of see.
Speaker 1: it is really fun to play among people who are good because it's it's ching ching ching ching ching ching ching Ching ching ching ching ching ching ching.
Speaker 1: it takes about as long as a normal soul caliber battle.
Speaker 0: No, I've actually seen people who are good.
Speaker 0: and the thing is is that If you take two of the like the two best Bushido blade guys in the world One of them is just better than the other and goes ding dead.
Speaker 0: And while that's great very realistic.
Speaker 0: I mean you know for sword fighting I guess it's kind of boring and unfun.
Speaker 1: and yet you complain Incessantly while we play a soul caliber - about every aspect of that game.
Speaker 0: see it's not so much so the problems with soul caliber - in Fact soul caliber - is terrific and that it solves most of the problems of other fighting games.
Speaker 0: But the problem is is that there are problems inherent in the fighting game Period in every fighting game, and I disagree.
Speaker 1: I think that fighting games as they are now are a genre and what you want is in a completely different genre.
Speaker 0: I Don't think it's so much a completely different.
Speaker 1: I think it'll be especially the stupid things you've been suggesting.
Speaker 0: It's more like an evolution of the John.
Speaker 1: wasn't one of your suggestions that you want the map to be infinite So you can run away and hide behind a door and then hit someone.
Speaker 0: Yeah sure why not?
Speaker 1: That's a different kind of game.
Speaker 0: Why so?
Speaker 1: fighting game is a genre of Gen of generally two-dimensional sometimes three-dimensional, but not really it doesn't really matter.
Speaker 1: and It's just two people fighting two people engaging in various combinations of button pushing one of which will become the victor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah That's what it is fundamentally.
Speaker 0: But the way it translates on the screen Isn't all isn't always a hundred percent, and it kind of makes you go hurt.
Speaker 1: Only you.
Speaker 0: well like when I see my sword go through someone and it doesn't actually register a hit or when you know some guy You know swings his sword like just above the bad guy's head.
Speaker 0: It's like all right.
Speaker 0: You could have lowered it a little bit.
Speaker 0: You know it's just a little but didn't remember.
Speaker 1: in a fight you make a mistake.
Speaker 1: How many kung-fu fights have you seen really?
Speaker 1: I punches and then the other guy you know?
Speaker 0: Dodges and grabs his arm, but this isn't even like dodging.
Speaker 0: This is just like dumbness and like other things like you know.
Speaker 0: it's just.
Speaker 0: It's like you know when you're playing half-life right and you get this real immersion thing going on But you don't feel like you're playing a video game.
Speaker 0: you feel like you're in half-life, and you're Gordon Freeman right and then you see like Some crate hanging off a crate in a non-possible way Or you see a guy in counter-strike standing on top of a door, and you're like all right It's a video game, and it kind of takes you out.
Speaker 0: You know so I guess I've never had that problem.
Speaker 1: I mean when I get immersed in the game like half-life I get immersed fully and the game is consistent within itself.
Speaker 0: I just have life is really really great and not messing that or even counter-strike.
Speaker 1: when I see a guy jumping on a door that Makes perfect sense in counter-strike world
Speaker 0: but It's it's like there's this feeling and then it can be destroyed and broken by certain things in a game and For all fighting games seem to have this problem where you know it's not.
Speaker 1: you know a game doesn't push ito blade.
Speaker 1: If the sword touches him he's dead.
Speaker 0: I guess that's true, but that game's not fun.
Speaker 0: Oh Revelation There's something we can do that's not Bushido blade that is not the standard fighting game.
Speaker 0: That is also fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well uh Produce it then because you keep saying oh it can be done But you never really come up with anything.
Speaker 1: because I think coming up with it is the hard part not even coming up with solid Concepts, I'm not saying make the game.
Speaker 1: I'm saying just make the concept which you really haven't.
Speaker 0: You control a guy the guy can do Any move.
Speaker 0: the other person is any move.
Speaker 1: How do you translate any move into a combination of button presses on a controller?
Speaker 0: well you you the button presses that we really abstracts like a is punch and Depending on the position of your guy and the position of the enemy the punch is determined.
Speaker 1: wait So you mean you want it all to be determined by the game and not by what I do to the controller.
Speaker 1: Well, no, so I hit I determine I hit a and then my character does whatever punch is appropriate.
Speaker 0: It's not whatever pun It's it's not a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: Just you know always he throws the perfect punch, and it hits.
Speaker 0: then why there's more to it?
Speaker 0: It's like it would be a game more of positioning yourself because you know what punch he'll throw Depending on what you're doing otherwise like oh, I'll you know jump off the wall and I'll you know or I'll go through the window or climb up the ladder and drop down on him and throw a punch or something like.
Speaker 0: Or wait till he ducks and then jump and throw a punch because I'll do a different move if that happens.
Speaker 1: That doesn't sound any different than Soul Calibur.
Speaker 1: Because Soul Calibur you think you you see always in that stance.
Speaker 1: He can do any of these moves.
Speaker 1: all right I'll do this move they don't be able to counter and then oh, but
Speaker 0: it's a lot more complicated in the button pressing it to memorize all these button presses and It's it's very complicated and unless you're like a fight you have to be a fighting game master to really
Speaker 1: actually what I've done.
Speaker 1: I'm not great at the game, but I'm pretty good.
Speaker 1: You know I only play voldo.
Speaker 1: Don't ask why I'm terrible at most fighting games.
Speaker 1: But when I picked up Soul Calibur, and I use voldo.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty good.
Speaker 0: It's scary voldo scary.
Speaker 0: Why voldo?
Speaker 1: and why couldn't it been a cute girl now?
Speaker 1: It's voldo.
Speaker 0: Hey you you should have picked a cute girl.
Speaker 0: I never played voldo.
Speaker 1: I did I played I played Rafael and all these people all the time And I always lost.
Speaker 1: and then I played voldo one time and I started actually beating people a lot.
Speaker 1: yeah But like I don't know the specific button combinations But I have this general sense that I've picked up in my brain of like Voldo standing a certain way, and you're standing there, and I just think to myself I want to do a move kind of like this, and it just comes out
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: it's all very my brain.
Speaker 1: I don't specifically think it's like you're playing DDR.
Speaker 1: You don't think down left down left down left up.
Speaker 1: you just think Arrows are going in my eyes, and they're coming out my feet.
Speaker 0: the problem is generally you want to make a game Where the higher level of skill you have then the more you will win and the less skill you have the more you will lose.
Speaker 1: That's how fighting games are.
Speaker 0: Soul caliber not really the guy with less skill who button mashes can often beat people with a Small a lot slightly larger amount of skill or slightly larger.
Speaker 1: That's effectively negligibly large.
Speaker 0: they can also beat people with a medium amount of skill.
Speaker 0: It's only the people you know insane fighting game skills that can win consistently.
Speaker 1: see I Don't think you have much evidence of that because none of us are good at Soul Calibur.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are people who are good, and they still.
Speaker 1: you know when was the last time we played with someone who was good?
Speaker 0: I played against a crazy obsessive fanboy at an anime club social night and all I did was button mash and I beat him.
Speaker 1: How do you know he was good?
Speaker 0: Because he whupped like ten people in a row.
Speaker 1: That's not that scientific you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, y'all James Randi.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna be all James alright.
Speaker 0: So I guess we're not gonna be able to settle this until we find the Soul Calibur 2 grandmaster.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: And then see if he can beat my close my eyes and hit a bunch of buttons with a Waldo technique And if he can't I guess that's a problem, and if he can all right.
Speaker 0: But you know the thing is if you ace me if you just smash buttons you can beat people with a medium amount of skill.
Speaker 0: You know kind of know what they're doing just because the way the game works.
Speaker 1: See I don't see that so much.
Speaker 1: most of the people I see who the people who button mash who I watched tend to never Win I but rarely win very a lot.
Speaker 1: You don't win that often.
Speaker 0: What are you talking about?
Speaker 1: It's more that you just don't give up the controller when you lose.
Speaker 0: no excuse me excuse me Heads not it at all.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah.
Speaker 1: So we played a lot of board games this past weekend.
Speaker 1: Oh board games I miss be and I figured we just talked about all the board games We played because they're our favorite board games, and it's gaming night, and there's no more video game.
Speaker 0: Well, we didn't play one of our favorite board games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we're done with that game for now.
Speaker 0: kind of yeah It's kind of like you know you might have a Megaman 2 is the greatest video game, but you don't see me playing it too often.
Speaker 0: It's a little played out.
Speaker 0: Puerto Rico's the same way.
Speaker 0: I'm so great, but it's kind of played out and there's no two players.
Speaker 1: So and we really got no more video games to talk about.
Speaker 1: unless you want us to talk more about Mario Kart Which we're playing incessantly.
Speaker 0: I got some good time trial action going on.
Speaker 0: now I'm gonna pretty much do time trials and online play from now on considering.
Speaker 0: I beat all the GPS with God.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So the board games we started out with a little teeny Tigris and Euphrates, which is currently my favorite board game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely currently the hot game to play.
Speaker 0: I could play it pretty much all night And I don't think I get tired of it without like a hundred more plays.
Speaker 1: See tigers and Euphrates is a very open game And there is other than the tiles you draw in your hand which is just an aspect of the game.
Speaker 1: There is absolutely no randomness whatsoever Anything that happens in the game was caused by another player directly.
Speaker 0: Of course, you know the what tiles you draw is kind of random and kind of really important But except it's the only bit is the only thing and you're the only one who's ever complained about not getting the tiles you needed.
Speaker 1: I'm not lying.
Speaker 0: I swear to God.
Speaker 0: my Beginning of the game I drew one red On.
Speaker 0: the very last tile I drew out of the bag was my second red tile.
Speaker 0: you could have Know I could have thrown out all my tiles and drawn six new ones, right?
Speaker 0: But I just don't feel good doing that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well great.
Speaker 1: That was great for me.
Speaker 0: I won the first game though pretty well to with.
Speaker 1: I won the second game handily Yeah by an order of magnitude.
Speaker 0: I just ran for those monuments and bam It's nice Like I'm like how we used to never put out the monuments.
Speaker 0: or maybe we'd put out a monument and then fight over it Ferociously.
Speaker 0: now like every monument comes out It's crazy.
Speaker 1: So T&E is a very open game.
Speaker 1: Basically you place tiles on a board and you can place them anywhere on the board pretty much And you have little leaders.
Speaker 1: you can place them anywhere and you're building little kingdoms and fighting with each other over Monuments and victory points and the game has a really cool gimmick.
Speaker 1: every game that we like has some kind of gimmick.
Speaker 1: It's like you describe the game.
Speaker 1: You're like, yeah, but what's the gimmick?
Speaker 1: and then someone says the gimmick and you go whoo?
Speaker 1: This game's gimmick is there are four different colors of victory points that you get and your final score is The lowest of the four that you have.
Speaker 0: it's the most least.
Speaker 0: That's how you win.
Speaker 0: is you have the most of the least color of point.
Speaker 0: So if you got three green ten red ten black and ten blue and the other guy has four of everything He wins because your score is three because you all your most least is three.
Speaker 0: Yep The other guy has he's got four.
Speaker 0: so ha You could also think of.
Speaker 0: it is getting sets like how many sets do you have?
Speaker 0: But it's it's technically the most least because technically they both work.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, but if there's a tie for most least you look at the second lowest.
Speaker 0: so that's not sets.
Speaker 1: No, all you do in that case is you eliminate your lowest color.
Speaker 1: then you do sets again.
Speaker 0: That's true.
Speaker 1: Anyway, we also played a lot of a little bit not so much st.
Speaker 1: Petersburg.
Speaker 0: st.
Speaker 0: Petersburg is good But I don't see a lot of a variation in the game.
Speaker 1: It's a really fun game.
Speaker 1: It's basically a growth management game.
Speaker 1: You buy workers to get money and then you use the money to get victory points and you have to balance money and victory points Throughout the whole game.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: It's pretty much perfect except for one glaring problem Whereby if one of the big aristocrats comes out the judge Judge of the mistress comes out in the first round.
Speaker 1: whoever buys it pretty much wins automatically.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the thing is sometimes that the guy plays poorly It's.
Speaker 0: I think there's the one balancing against that is if you buy a Kremlin the first turn You stand to get a lot of points out of that Kremlin.
Speaker 1: Not really Well buying a Kremlin the first turn is almost always suicide.
Speaker 0: It's because you lose all this money and the.
Speaker 0: but the thing is is if then one of the big Jews The big aristocrats comes out Yeah, we call them the Jews.
Speaker 0: yeah, see I'm not silly with a German board game.
Speaker 0: don't even guess we are silly.
Speaker 1: I mean you there.
Speaker 1: they are workers buildings aristocrats and upgrades.
Speaker 1: But we call them workers or I don't know Proletarians or we make jokes like all the workers, but yeah Yeah, and then we got Kremlin's because the icon is shaped like a Kremlin because it's a Russian games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's Berg Yeah, and the upgrades just squares.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the Jews are the aristocrats Yep, because the the tile that represents them is this pointy nose guy, and I'll point out that Scott here is Jewish.
Speaker 1: So yeah, so it's okay.
Speaker 0: We're not Anti-semite, so we're just.
Speaker 0: hey, Jerry racism eggs overcooked.
Speaker 0: Anti-semitism racism is funny when it's not real And it's just words.
Speaker 1: NASA.
Speaker 1: Sorry, that is definitely an inside joke.
Speaker 0: It is coal.
Speaker 0: so The Problem I have with st.
Speaker 0: Petersburg is that it's a lot of fun to play But there's not a lot of variations pretty much.
Speaker 0: You know you buy workers you buy Kremlin's.
Speaker 1: Yeah, once you get down to it the game becomes.
Speaker 1: it's no longer a game of playing the game.
Speaker 1: It's a game of either odd evening which is you take a card now to ensure that you will be able to get a card in the next phase or I don't take a card now to make sure that my opponent does not get a card in the next phase.
Speaker 1: yep Or The only other real aspect is when do you turn from making money to making victory points and whoever does it first?
Speaker 1: But not too early will win.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you do too early you won't have enough money, and you'll be stuck.
Speaker 0: But if you do it too late the other guy gets more victory points than you because he bought something a turn earlier And it ended up generating in more points.
Speaker 1: It's a good beginner to intermediate game, and it's really fun, and we still play it, but it'll get old.
Speaker 0: it will get old.
Speaker 0: The other thing is I noticed that a lot of other board game people want to hear them talk about board games.
Speaker 0: They seem to only play a game like a few times a year.
Speaker 0: God we Also play a lot more games in total.
Speaker 0: they have all just a huge variety.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but a lot of games a whole lot because we only buy that like the best best games.
Speaker 1: Then we play them out.
Speaker 1: Yep like when we bought Puerto Rico We the three of us played Puerto Rico one weekend.
Speaker 1: We played it like 15 times in one day.
Speaker 1: We just played it constantly.
Speaker 0: It was great.
Speaker 1: like we'd play it someone would win.
Speaker 1: We'd sit there for a second.
Speaker 1: We'd argue for a while about oh you won because of this.
Speaker 1: oh blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: I didn't notice that.
Speaker 1: yeah And then we just play again and again and again and again and one of us to go to work and come back and play Again, those are good days good days, and we still do that whenever our friends come over.
Speaker 1: We play board games pretty much non-stop.
Speaker 0: Just make a stack.
Speaker 0: We play the top right to the bottom.
Speaker 1: yep Some games get neglected now like settlers, but it's gonna be all good.
Speaker 0: I just order.
Speaker 0: I find there isn't a game store around anymore.
Speaker 0: Well there is but it's not so good.
Speaker 1: No, it's no millennium.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I am gonna go there this weekend because supposedly there's gonna be some gamers there and I'll try to get a game on with them.
Speaker 0: maybe I can get some more consistent games on with them and Because we need players.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we don't have a game store that sells a high Quantity of the in selection of the German games that we like.
Speaker 0: so finally I decided to bite the the bullet And I bought some games online at this website game fest calm.
Speaker 0: It's a good website.
Speaker 0: They had a whole big selection of games And they told you how many of each they had in stock left and a lot of the games were either out of stock Or they had single-digit numbers of copies, so I imagine it's just a game store somewhere that has a nice website.
Speaker 0: There was another one that had a good website fun again calm.
Speaker 0: they seemed like a you know pretty much equal like.
Speaker 0: it was completely arbitrary which one I bought from and The only thing that made me choose game fest was the site was a little bit cleaner a little bit more trustworthy looking and The price was like lower by a dollar on one game.
Speaker 0: Huh so yeah, that'll do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm driving to Rochester this weekend.
Speaker 1: I'll definitely be stopping in Millennium Which is one of the biggest game stores in America might be the biggest.
Speaker 0: yeah I'm gonna get me some board games definitely the best that I've ever been to or seen.
Speaker 0: yeah of course There is one in the city somewhere.
Speaker 0: I just have to find it.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go to it one of these days.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll go Friday.
Speaker 0: I don't know huh.
Speaker 0: I'll think about it.
Speaker 1: We also played some Alhambra.
Speaker 1: Alhambra is always a good game deserving its feel this yeah It's a bidding game and a tile placement game.
Speaker 1: not a tile laying game, but a tile placement game.
Speaker 0: It's not really bidding.
Speaker 0: It's more of a take money buy stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you cut if you keep track of the money people are drawing in their hands Which is very easy to do.
Speaker 0: it's like oh look rim took all the blue money.
Speaker 0: I wonder yeah once Oh, could it be that tile that's on the blue space?
Speaker 1: This game has a gimmick like every game and the gimmick is You don't get change back when you buy something.
Speaker 0: so if you spend if you do something cost ten and all you have is two Nines.
Speaker 0: guess what you spent if you want to buy it right now You got to spend the two nines, and you don't get eight back.
Speaker 1: yep But other gimmick is if you do buy something with exact change you get another action.
Speaker 0: that is very powerful.
Speaker 0: People who basically the winner is the person who both?
Speaker 0: buys things that are that they need while also saving money and not buying useless things and Buying everything as much as possible with exact change in order to get free turns though You can't forget buying the things other people need to deny them points.
Speaker 1: of course it also has a nice mechanic.
Speaker 1: where?
Speaker 1: Games where ties can occur within the game have a number numerous ways of dealing with that.
Speaker 1: some games are everybody loses meaning if there's a tie You either no one gets anything or you divide up everything like among the winners mm-hmm and Alhambra is one of those.
Speaker 1: So say first place is something's worth 15 points and second place is worth six points.
Speaker 1: if three people tie for first place They divide 15 points by three and then the second place person actually gets more points than the first place person.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it basically if that mechanic right there is what makes it a multi-person game.
Speaker 0: without that mechanic It's basically just a race to see who can get the most points the least amount of time based on the random Coming out of tiles and coming out of money cards.
Speaker 0: Yeah That mechanic actually forces you to look at what other people have When deciding what tiles to buy.
Speaker 0: if first second and third play at first and second place are already locked in.
Speaker 0: It's really a waste of money to spend things on the third place to get a tile to tie for third place when you could You know wait for the next tile to come buy that and get something something other color.
Speaker 1: yep, unless you're a Rival, you can tie him in something to take points away from him or there's a bunch of things you can do.
Speaker 0: There is of course one thing that you know Always kind of messes you up in the game is that if you keep looking at the colors?
Speaker 0: Deciding what tiles to buy and what not to you kind of ignore the walls.
Speaker 0: You have to pay attention to the walls, too.
Speaker 0: You might not need a tile But if it has good walls on it and it fits nicely in your Alhambra you can get a bunch of extra points from it.
Speaker 0: So you don't want to like, you know, leave anything out with more than you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, our friend Pete has a problem.
Speaker 1: whenever he builds an Alhambra He tends to wall himself in completely and then he's screwed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got to build the Alhambra nicely a lot of times.
Speaker 0: They'll be like the perfect tile but nowhere to put it in your Alhambra then you're done.
Speaker 0: forget it.
Speaker 1: now It's a great game, but the box lies when it says it's two to six players.
Speaker 1: It's three to six players.
Speaker 1: If you play with two players, it adds this like Deterministic player named Matt.
Speaker 0: It's like playing blackjack.
Speaker 1: It's terrible.
Speaker 1: Don't play.
Speaker 0: always know what dealers gonna do.
Speaker 0: You always know what Matt's gonna do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it never wins unless you're dumb.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the first time we ever played Matt almost beat us.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like playing risk with that neutral army out there only worse.
Speaker 1: Of course we played.
Speaker 1: I mean this was a game where everybody loses in ties.
Speaker 1: We played another game where everybody wins on a tie.
Speaker 1: I'm on ray.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's a fun game.
Speaker 1: It's probably my second favorite game, right?
Speaker 0: I realize that most of our games are Rainier Canizia games.
Speaker 1: They're awesome games.
Speaker 0: He's a great game making.
Speaker 1: I'm on array is a really neat mechanic as well.
Speaker 1: It's a. it's a diminishing returns.
Speaker 1: buy things bid but bid in a weird way By sacrificing things to the gods or stealing from the gods.
Speaker 1: stealing from the gods was very key but the mechanic here the the gimmick is that You build a bunch of stuff on the board and you play the game all the way through and you score.
Speaker 1: Then if the flood comes and wipes everything out except the pyramids that everyone is built and you lose everything you have other than that Everything on the board goes away.
Speaker 1: Then you play the whole game again and the board starts the way it left.
Speaker 1: it ended at the previous round.
Speaker 0: It's really cool because what ends up happening is in the first round.
Speaker 0: play is obvious.
Speaker 0: It's easy to tell which ones are the best and which ones aren't the best to go for and you can just bid on the best provinces.
Speaker 0: You know how much money you have and how much you can afford to bid and everyone gets exactly what they deserve based on the order of play and such.
Speaker 0: But in the second round You know some guy who didn't spend a lot of money for his province that he didn't pay for in the first round But built like two pyramids on it.
Speaker 0: and now in the second round Someone has to decide between a good province with maybe one pyramid and a crappy province with like many many pyramids.
Speaker 1: Yep, I've often found my strategies lean towards if I have a choice if I have a crappy Province while I'm playing in the first round.
Speaker 1: I'll put all my pyramids there and screw someone in the next round.
Speaker 0: I basically try to get the best province I possibly can every time.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, I can afford.
Speaker 1: so uh Yeah, I try to win every game that I play.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's you know, what can I do besides?
Speaker 0: go for the best province possible?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the thing is the way the bidding works is it's like you can't fake out and bid on something crappy and then move To something good.
Speaker 0: You have to pretty much go for what you're gonna go for.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're gonna fake someone out.
Speaker 1: you have to be devious in it.
Speaker 0: It's it's real hard to fake someone out.
Speaker 0: You'd have to go for like the second best province at a low price.
Speaker 0: Hope that someone out bids you and then go to the best province at a higher price.
Speaker 1: Yeah The bidding is definitely fun because you get you can sacrifice to the gods or you can steal from the gods temple and get money.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think that the problem is is that if everyone Depending the provinces that come out that determines if people are gonna steal or bid to the gods.
Speaker 0: And I remember in early games we used to bid to the gods a lot and we go way up.
Speaker 0: But now everyone seems to kind of screw the gods and steal all their money Which is great because that means I give to the gods and the gods give me nice things Yeah, then I also give to the gods.
Speaker 0: I remember one game.
Speaker 0: I just got first place every time and everyone else kept stealing it all.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, that won that game pretty easily.
Speaker 0: But I think that if we played a game where you know different tile the order of tiles came out to where that everyone wanted to give more to the gods that we'd see a crazy high point scoring game as Opposed to the low point scoring games we have now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we had them.
Speaker 1: it changes.
Speaker 1: We haven't played the game much lately.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz we don't own it.
Speaker 1: Our friend who lives far away owns it.
Speaker 0: That's good because it that way we won't get played out.
Speaker 1: Yeah We also played a lot.
Speaker 1: We played some Dungeons & Dragons.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, we actually.
Speaker 1: we were sitting around and we realized all of us really want to play D&D and hadn't played in a long time.
Speaker 1: So, uh, we forced our old Dungeon Master to think up a game.
Speaker 1: So he forced us to roll up characters while he thought up a game and then we played a game.
Speaker 0: It was most excellent.
Speaker 1: We stayed up like four in the morning playing and then we finished it the next day.
Speaker 0: It probably wasn't the best, you know campaign I was ever in ever.
Speaker 1: It wasn't a campaign.
Speaker 1: It was a one-off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, still whatever but it wasn't the best D&D I played in my whole life.
Speaker 0: But because it was such a drought it's like, you know Dirty water at the end of a desert.
Speaker 0: Yeah good is cold water.
Speaker 1: And plus I got to admit our Dungeon Master Alex came up with one hell of an adventure for you know Zero preparation and a bunch of people demanding you run a game.
Speaker 0: Yep, very good.
Speaker 1: My only regret is that I made a character and I had all this stuff set for him and I basically ended up just playing Mal from Firefly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Firefly.
Speaker 0: I don't like Firefly is awesome.
Speaker 0: Whatever you suck I was a paladin and I realized it's hard to roleplay someone who's all Paladin II when you're really in real life.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Hmm Let's see We're going to a village to do some sort of semi-secret business and the paladin walks in and says yo unto you villagers I am a paladin and I am here to grab a brab.
Speaker 1: a brab a paladin's do know Some balladins aren't stupid.
Speaker 0: Oh I only had an intelligence of 10.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that'll do it 10 10 is actually average.
Speaker 0: So yeah average.
Speaker 0: I was as smart as what the villagers were.
Speaker 0: My wisdom was 15 though.
Speaker 0: So Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I think it was.
Speaker 0: part of that was because I didn't quite know how to be a paladin and I kind of know a Little better now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and part of it was because it was way late at night and the next one Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we stopped playing at 4 in the morning only because you were asleep.
Speaker 0: Yeah when we played the next day I got a much better job paladin.
Speaker 1: You were much better the next day.
Speaker 1: Your character was actually somewhat intelligent and did useful things and actually had things to say.
Speaker 0: that weren't I think the next time a paladin I'm not gonna try to be all evangelical gadi as much as like heroic saving.
Speaker 0: I'll try to be more heroic saving, you know, well not saving throws saving others.
Speaker 0: Ah with my powers Yay, paladins.
Speaker 1: We also played some carcass own carcass owns.
Speaker 0: Okay, but it's a quick understand why there's a bunch of expansions for it.
Speaker 1: yeah, we've kind of played it out and You don't seem to learn that you can't beat me in the farmer game.
Speaker 1: You know every time we've ever played You see me build a farmer and you get into your head that you can somehow get more farmers than me.
Speaker 0: and you know Farmer down first in the best spot and it ended up being the whole board and My.
Speaker 0: you know this time you didn't completely dominate the farmer game as in previous times Except I got more points from farmers than anyone else.
Speaker 0: Well, you see what the problem here was that farmers really get you four points per city thing, right?
Speaker 0: It's that I Didn't have enough guys on the board.
Speaker 0: I did good enough in the farmer game to win.
Speaker 0: I just didn't get anything else.
Speaker 0: I didn't get any roads.
Speaker 0: I didn't get enough cities You know and part of it is what tiles you draw and especially in that many players in a game with so with with no expansions It you don't get so many tiles in the game to put guys on So you
Speaker 1: have to put
Speaker 0: a guy in every time.
Speaker 1: I realized right away that I had to jump on any point thing I drew because I wouldn't draw as many tiles.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't realize that till later.
Speaker 0: but now I know that if I'm playing with not any expansions and So many people I have to start putting my guy and every tile I put down.
Speaker 0: pretty much You know.
Speaker 0: whereas in two players you have to be very discerning about where you put your guy because you might not get him back.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's a completely different game with different numbers of people.
Speaker 1: We also played some of Wario aware.
Speaker 0: Wario aware.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's not so exciting to talk about.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: I love that game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's alright, you know, but Yeah, it's it's getting kind of played out for me.
Speaker 0: yeah mostly because I haven't seen any new minigames in it.
Speaker 0: You know and a lot of them are the same just with a different picture.
Speaker 1: Yeah that we played some of that.
Speaker 1: the the pac-man game for the GameCube Pac-man game is very good where one guy has the game boy and they're playing pac-man and the other three people are ghosts and they Can't see where pac-man is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the pac-man game is very good, but I can only play it a few times a night.
Speaker 0: But then and you know at another night I can play it again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like once you played a few times in a row you're done.
Speaker 0: But then if you bring it back out again later, it's I could play it all night.
Speaker 1: But part of that's cuz I win a lot.
Speaker 1: I mean once I get pac-man I just clear the board over and over Depends who the ghosts are.
Speaker 0: if the ghosts are really good they can get you.
Speaker 1: but if the ghosts aren't so good And the thing is the if the ghosts are not so good.
Speaker 1: I clear the board, but if the ghosts are actually really good.
Speaker 1: I Usually get more points because while I don't clear the board because they eventually get me I eat them because they're aggressively going after me and then I get more points.
Speaker 0: You know, I remember when we played it previously The you know pac-man would switch around a whole lot.
Speaker 0: when we played it this weekend It didn't seem to switch around so much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of people were clearing the board and I think it was a difference in the ghost strategy.
Speaker 0: and you know people were Trying to camp power pills and they were trying to eat the fruit a lot.
Speaker 1: Well, that was me.
Speaker 1: I was the only one eating the fruit and that's how I win every game.
Speaker 1: That's my secret.
Speaker 1: I get enough points with pac-man to stay ahead and then I let people who aren't going to win be pac-man while I just Eat the fruit over and over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I eat the fruit over and over also, but you know, sometimes it's a race to the fruit.
Speaker 0: What can you do?
Speaker 1: Well, I always win it because I'm always closer to the pan.
Speaker 0: I got the fruit plenty of times.
Speaker 0: But you know the game.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: It's interesting.
Speaker 0: The price is right on it, you know, or at least was when it was out.
Speaker 0: It was pretty much free.
Speaker 1: The sad thing is that it's the only good thing in that game because when you buy it it comes with this other pac-man game.
Speaker 0: well, you when it originally came out.
Speaker 0: you would get it if you bought like any game on this list, you know be free.
Speaker 0: and Then when that promotion was over and they ran out of the free discs on their own They the only way to get it is to buy pac-man adventure land something.
Speaker 1: It's the worst game ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the worst game ever, but it comes with the pac-man verse in the same package.
Speaker 1: We pulled it out and turn it on to see if it could actually be as bad as we'd heard.
Speaker 1: and it was worse.
Speaker 0: I played it for maybe 10 seconds and you know I was pac-man and it was 3d and I was walking around eating pills and pellets and it was like a ghost And it was like an adventure land kind of.
Speaker 0: oh my god It was terrible.
Speaker 0: after like I played it for five seconds and I want to kill myself.
Speaker 0: So I stopped playing.
Speaker 0: Why do people make games like that thinking they're gonna be fun?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know what they I wouldn't handle.
Speaker 0: let them release that game Nintendo or let you release things as long as you know, they're not full of bugs and they work.
Speaker 0: they don't.
Speaker 1: It's got one glaring bug.
Speaker 1: It's terrible.
Speaker 0: Yeah but you know Nintendo doesn't judge the content of games.
Speaker 0: and they released them which You know, they didn't do for the NES either.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, in fact, no one really seems to do it these days.
Speaker 0: if I had a console I would make sure the only games out for it were crazy awesome.
Speaker 1: But yeah, but then I can games appear in.
Speaker 0: yeah, that'd be a problem, you know Especially when people start saying all your system doesn't have a lot of games for it.
Speaker 0: What does it have?
Speaker 0: these three games and you know?
Speaker 0: sure I could point out.
Speaker 0: Well, look at your system.
Speaker 0: What does it have?
Speaker 0: these three games in a pile of crap?
Speaker 0: But there are people who buy the crap.
Speaker 0: That's why it exists.
Speaker 1: And yeah, mostly parents who know their kid like to movies So they buy the game that went along with the movie.
Speaker 0: you'd be surprised.
Speaker 0: who buys those games with movies?
Speaker 0: Actual people who buy them like they want to play them.
Speaker 0: Wow It's scary.
Speaker 0: the people who buy these non-awesome games Like it's really frightening Like remember we saw that kid in Game stop or wherever and he ran over to the DS rack Like he was excited and he was gonna get a game that he knew he well, yeah, and he got Rayman.
Speaker 0: I mean, come on kid get freakin Mario Kart get advance Wars get any of the other ten awesome games.
Speaker 0: Are you getting Rayman?
Speaker 0: It's a boring generic Nothing new, you know.
Speaker 0: platform game that has been has seen like ten remakes.
Speaker 0: None of which were good.
Speaker 1: Haha way to piss on that kid's parade.
Speaker 0: His parade is thoroughly drenched in yellow urea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're crotched old men when it comes to video games and you know what?
Speaker 0: Crotched yield men are right not like this Muppet Show old man.
Speaker 0: They know what's up.
Speaker 1: So I think that's every game we played.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't play San Juan.
Speaker 1: We played a couple of other video games that you guys don't care about.
Speaker 0: I don't know if we played another board game or not, but it doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: Nah, we didn't all right cool.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I guess the first part of the podcast messed up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and yeah, yeah.
Speaker 0: But I think this one should be good enough on its own.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we went a little long on the video game part to cover the fact that the rest of it was done.
Speaker 1: It was okay because while we had good stuff to talk about It was mostly us dredging the bottom of the news pile because there was not much news.
Speaker 1: that Really?
Speaker 1: We wanted to talk about.
Speaker 0: yeah, and the things of the day are in there.
Speaker 0: then those are messed up But we'll still put the links in the things.
Speaker 0: you can see what they were.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, to sum up my thing of the day is a device that gives you an artificial Nintendo finger.
Speaker 0: My thing of the day was a French book from 1844 that said if you masturbate you will die horribly.
Speaker 0: It had illustrations that were hilarious.
Speaker 0: Haha All right, I think that's.
Speaker 1: it is that it we out and That was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Thanks for listening.
Speaker 0: Please.
Speaker 0: Remember to point your favorite podcatcher at beads dot.
Speaker 0: be burner comm slash geek nights.
Speaker 0: Get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Speaker 0: Also, please visit our website at www.front row crew comm for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at geek nights at gmail.com.