Speaker 1: It's Tuesday December 8th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We talked about our freshman year in college.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So today was another awesomely boring day.
Speaker 0: God.
Speaker 0: It was just like yesterday where I had nothing to do at work only I didn't go to the comic book store after work, and I was just God.
Speaker 1: yeah, I work late to diagnose a silly problem with a switch that I probably shouldn't had to stay late to diagnose.
Speaker 1: Wow it was awesome.
Speaker 0: I was sitting there doing nothing and I really don't want to go tomorrow cuz I'm not gonna do anything tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Oh, you might not have to go do anything.
Speaker 1: tomorrow looks like it's gonna snow a lot.
Speaker 0: if it snows enough I'm just gonna be like fuck it, and I'll stay home, and I'll do something cool And maybe I'll just call in sick.
Speaker 1: I need a day off.
Speaker 1: I'm actually really dragging from not sleeping enough the last two weeks.
Speaker 0: oh, man You know I can't sleep on the trains so easily cuz I have a thing where I need to lay down.
Speaker 0: That's kind of weird, but I was so tired on the way home on the train.
Speaker 0: I was playing Mario and Luigi and like my eyes.
Speaker 0: I couldn't hold them open While I was playing a DS game.
Speaker 1: Why don't you get one of those like neck pillows that goes around your neck because they look silly they work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I might get one.
Speaker 0: actually I just had to find one that I think is good.
Speaker 1: so uh Neopets is Scientology.
Speaker 0: Didn't see that coming.
Speaker 1: Yeah sky was sitting at work today, and Scott sent me a link to this article.
Speaker 1: It's about Neopets and He's like Neopets of Scientology, so I start reading the article and it just talks about Neopets.
Speaker 1: and then on the second page is there's one sentence and the sentence pretty much says the CEO of Neopets Doug Doring or Doring is Super super super super Scientologist, and he runs the company on the principles of Scientology.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you mean there's a lot of people who are just oh, they're a Scientologist like.
Speaker 0: I think the voice of Bart Simpson is a Scientologist.
Speaker 0: Right Isaac Hayes supposedly Isaac Hayes a Scientologist, but you know while that makes you an idiot It doesn't necessarily mean the work you do is bad, so it doesn't really reflect on Neopets, but this guy runs the company with the teachings of L Ron Hubbard.
Speaker 1: Quote here Hubbard's companies follow a system of departmental organization called the org board Which he claimed was a refinement of one used by an old galactic civilization that lasted 80 trillion years.
Speaker 0: Imagine if you were the CEO of a company, and you said I think we should reorganize the company this way because aliens From an ancient time did it this way?
Speaker 0: Yeah, oh right.
Speaker 1: What's even more interesting is that the primary Aspect of this org method of running a company involves having a corrections division that disciplines other divisions of the company and It says no more than that.
Speaker 0: You know some companies kind of need that.
Speaker 1: But at the same time yeah Yeah, so yeah, this may sound silly or like we're making it up, but no Scientology really is.
Speaker 1: they're like hardcore behind the scenes at Neopets.
Speaker 0: Yep, there was another guy who worked at.
Speaker 0: Neopets is like an artist for a short time.
Speaker 1: He got the fuck out of there.
Speaker 0: He was smart, and he didn't Scientology, but he pointed out that yeah There's.
Speaker 0: you know that Neil the Scientology doesn't get into the Neopets.
Speaker 0: So if you're using Neopets you know I would I would encourage you to stop because you're supporting the Scientologists.
Speaker 0: But at the same time Neopets isn't gonna turn you into a Scientologist anytime soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is it at least okay?
Speaker 0: That's that's good.
Speaker 0: They didn't do that because if Neopets was a Scientology recruitment Well, you know we just have a freaking cow, but yeah, not like a Narcan.
Speaker 0: on yeah, but Basically he worked there And he noticed that everyone above a certain level of management basically had to join Scientology and be hardcore.
Speaker 1: And I'm sure most of you know our opinions on Scientology, and I don't we're not it's not an opinion.
Speaker 1: well No, I'm talking about our specific opinions on Scientology, but there's also some facts, and I'm sure you guys know most of them.
Speaker 1: But just very quickly Scientologists believe in an alien named Xenu who dropped atomic bombs on earth billions of years ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they think these little magic guys who stick to you and called body thetans, and you have to get them off of you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're like all inside you imagine if some guy wrote a pulp sci-fi story And you believed it was the history of the world.
Speaker 0: That's what Scientology is.
Speaker 1: yeah pretty much.
Speaker 0: That's not even like a joke.
Speaker 0: We're just dead serious.
Speaker 0: This is really a cult that believes that and if you join them they take all your money.
Speaker 1: pretty much.
Speaker 1: They take it all bit by bit not all at once.
Speaker 0: yep That's all there is to it.
Speaker 1: Though apparently you get superpowers if you become a Scientologist and go all the way or you believe you have superpowers.
Speaker 0: Yeah Tom Cruise, yeah, yeah, I don't see you saving people's lives Alright, so shove it.
Speaker 1: Actually the weirdest thing is it seems like a lot of people have pointed out that a lot of Scientologists despite all their magic powers and disdaining you know things that can harm the body.
Speaker 1: a lot of them are smokers.
Speaker 0: Really, there's just clouds.
Speaker 1: apparently there's clouds and clouds of them standing outside the Scientology building in New York City smoking every day.
Speaker 1: hmm Just a little tidbit.
Speaker 1: I picked up.
Speaker 0: Oh they have a building.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they have a building.
Speaker 0: We should go and like we can't get in we could do stuff in front of it.
Speaker 1: What just stand there?
Speaker 0: We can make a wall of non culties.
Speaker 1: Why don't we just continue to do what we've been doing which is heckle and harass them whenever they're set up in the subways trying to convert people Because that won't draw as much iron.
Speaker 1: It's fun though.
Speaker 1: one time I mean every time we pass these guys in the subway We just stop and walk over and start telling people You know this is a cult right these guys are just trying to get you to join their crazy cult that believes in aliens because
Speaker 0: that's what they are trying to do and
Speaker 1: They really don't know how to deal with that.
Speaker 1: one time they threatened to call the police on us, and we were like all right Fine call the police officer explain to him what you just said to us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they would have been hilarious if a cop came.
Speaker 0: I would have been like these guys are cultists.
Speaker 0: all I'm doing is telling people in the area using freedom of speech that they are cultists and They're calling the police saying we're harassing them.
Speaker 0: Here is proof to their cultists, and the only way that wouldn't work is if the cop was a Scientologist.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that would have not worked.
Speaker 1: Oh, and they like to sue people.
Speaker 1: so maybe we'll get sued after this but uh Awesome.
Speaker 1: I would love to get sued by Scientology.
Speaker 1: Yeah way to give me some publicity Such That would rock Alright, so remember that story We did not long ago about the guy who tried to buy a camera and the company was evil and they tried to screw him.
Speaker 0: Yep, well Someone else told that guy a story about a similar experience at another place that's also in Brooklyn named Wawa digital and Basically he had the same story.
Speaker 0: He wanted to buy a camera.
Speaker 0: He bought it on the.
Speaker 0: you know It was a good price.
Speaker 0: He called up.
Speaker 0: They tried to sell him all these accessories.
Speaker 0: He says and they say you know I get you know.
Speaker 0: and he says fine.
Speaker 0: I want to cancel mom canceling my order.
Speaker 0: The guy's like are you really gonna do that and pay the restocking fee?
Speaker 0: He's like I'm not paying any restocking fee because there wasn't any order and this guy got really pissed off.
Speaker 0: I Guess they have big commissions Or I don't know why these salesmen keep getting pissed off that their scam business model doesn't work on smart people.
Speaker 0: But he got really pissed off and he left the guy a voicemail saying he was gonna break his neck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and fortunately we have the actual voicemail here.
Speaker 1: Yep, so let's roll that sucker 9 to receive at 3.22 p.m Yes, you're in a big trouble.
Speaker 1: To erase press... Yeah, I'm sure there's gonna be no legal repercussions of that voicemail.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know threatening physical harm.
Speaker 0: I don't think anything else needs to be said after hearing that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I guess the moral is don't buy cameras that seem like they're too good a deal to be true from shady vendors in New York City.
Speaker 0: Yeah, basically don't buy a camera from any small place in New York City.
Speaker 0: buy your cameras from like I don't know The company that makes them or yeah a real store or even Best Buy.
Speaker 1: I mean Best Buy is evil in a lot of ways, but they don't directly Steal from you.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: They they kind of like indirectly steal which is I guess better.
Speaker 0: Hmm, I guess All right.
Speaker 1: So also the MPAA.
Speaker 0: Oh this story.
Speaker 0: Okay, so the Someone made a movie called This film is not yet rated.
Speaker 0: It's about the MPAA and how they rate films and it's about the impact of the film rating system on American culture.
Speaker 1: And it paints the MPAA in a really bad light, of course because well, that's the truth.
Speaker 0: So any movie about the truth is gonna make the MPAA look bad.
Speaker 1: So what did the MPAA rate it?
Speaker 0: the MPAA gave a movie about movie ratings a rating of NC 17, huh?
Speaker 0: Now there is the of course the conspiracy theory that says all they did that to keep it out of theaters and to keep it Out of blockbusters and no one will see it.
Speaker 0: and blah blah blah blah blah, which is a very see.
Speaker 1: I made it through my tinfoil hat.
Speaker 0: It's probably partially true if not mostly true, but also The movie's got some Graphical sexual content in it.
Speaker 1: So yeah But apparently they're.
Speaker 1: they point out a lot of interesting things like.
Speaker 1: it seems that the MPAA is much harsher on rating Homosexual sexuality than it is on heterosexual sexuality.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: So it seems like a movie where a man kisses.
Speaker 1: a man is much more likely to get a hard rating Than a movie where a man kisses a woman.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah fancy that.
Speaker 1: Oh, maybe these See the How these ratings are come about.
Speaker 1: but basically the MPAA appoints a bunch of people to do it and they're anonymous And they watch the movie and they assign a rating based on what the average American family would think.
Speaker 1: Oh great, at least that's their directive, but it's anonymous and there are really no repercussions and they can do things.
Speaker 1: however they want Mm-hmm Supposedly it's anonymous to keep them from being bribed.
Speaker 1: But I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think they get bribed a little bit.
Speaker 1: I I don't really know what to say.
Speaker 1: The MPAA is bad.
Speaker 1: They're on every front and I'd rather dislike them.
Speaker 0: mmm-hmm be interesting to see Like if we could get a whole pile of movies from like different studios to independent and you know such and Compare like movies with similar content versus the rating they got and the years.
Speaker 0: You know and see how things changed over time.
Speaker 1: we could you know, actually it's gotten a lot more lenient over time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's good except with regards to homosexuality.
Speaker 0: Boys kissing Well, I can tell you one thing in Japan.
Speaker 0: They don't give two craps.
Speaker 1: Yeah in a lot of ways they seem a lot smarter than a lot of people here and in other ways a lot more nutty.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, that's fine, though Yeah Things of the day.
Speaker 1: We don't have music yet Lazy bums.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just haven't gotten around to it.
Speaker 0: All right, so my thing today.
Speaker 0: Well, you may recall rim who had a great story that he seems to go crazy about and keeps referring to often.
Speaker 0: Is that uh?
Speaker 0: Most women never had the big O.
Speaker 1: Well most American women American women.
Speaker 0: So someone made a piece of software called Lapis, it's a little rabbit L a P is and It doesn't actually run in the Nintendo DS.
Speaker 0: it runs on the computer, but it you know has a little picture of a Nintendo DS because it has the same features of you know touchscreen and microphone and all that and it's kind of like Nintendogs except you have this cute little blue rabbit and You play with this cute little blue rabbit in various ways rubbing him with its stylus and blowing on the microphone and scratching and tickling and all that good stuff and the little rabbit is supposedly stimulated in the same way that a clitoris is.
Speaker 0: so if you want to learn how to stimulate women You just stimulate the bunny until it flies around and yeah That's really the analogy to orgasm in the game.
Speaker 1: The bunny starts flying.
Speaker 0: Yep, and then you've got it supposedly Fantastic.
Speaker 0: So if you think your woman is faking the big O you can play the lapis.
Speaker 0: if you're a woman And you don't know if you've ever had one you can practice lapis and then Go and do it to yourself later.
Speaker 0: I'd like to hear someone who like, you know tried it and Determine if it was accurate or something.
Speaker 0: That'll be cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah We'll see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Think I might just play this game just to have fun with the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just to have fun.
Speaker 0: And then look at some prawn.
Speaker 1: Oh prawn prawn.
Speaker 1: Yeah, my thing of the day is not nearly so cool, but I found it very cool until I heard about this thing.
Speaker 1: Mmm, but uh Apparently recently very recently there was a semi major archaeological discovery in of all places Battery Park in New York City.
Speaker 1: Those of you who don't live out here Battery Park is the park at the bottom of Manhattan where you know Statue of Liberty and all that stuff is they were digging in Battery Park.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, the subway lines go under there.
Speaker 1: Oh, all right, and they were extent they're extending a subway line.
Speaker 1: They're just from subway work and they discovered buried along the shore Gun emplacement from before the Revolutionary War a gun emplacement.
Speaker 1: a gun emplacement.
Speaker 1: Wow, it was just very good guns in it.
Speaker 1: So it has gone Paraffinalia in it and like the foundations for the gun.
Speaker 1: That's pretty cool Yeah, and they were absolutely amazed that it sat there undisturbed for so many freaking years.
Speaker 0: Well, it's made of rock and it's underground where no one's touching it.
Speaker 1: Yeah so the subway workers about and the the city and MTA have actually agreed to Work around it and leave it there so that people can come in and study it.
Speaker 0: That's a good idea.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's all there is to that.
Speaker 0: It's always nice to see because people don't realize that New York City like if you were here, let's see 300 years ago When New York City was actually just like an island Manhattan was just an island with nothing on it except maybe like some buildings.
Speaker 0: But it was actually that the original dirt and trees and such.
Speaker 0: The city we have now is like three or four levels of city above that.
Speaker 0: Oh Really?
Speaker 0: It's like, you know over time they built stuff then they built stuff and they built stuff and they built stuff.
Speaker 0: It's like way up now.
Speaker 1: Well, there's all.
Speaker 1: there's lots of cool abandoned stuff.
Speaker 1: There's abandoned subway stations and subway lines and all like basements steam tunnels.
Speaker 0: But if you look at say the first floor of an office building now That is like at the level that a roof of a house would have been in like the 17 or 1800s Mm-hmm because of the shit they've piled on Over time.
Speaker 0: at least that's what I hear.
Speaker 0: Aha, but of course you can see right here the gun emplacement which would normally be you know on land is underground.
Speaker 0: So you see how that works out?
Speaker 1: I Just thought it was very cool.
Speaker 1: I'm glad that they're at least taking the time to study it.
Speaker 1: Yep, instead of just you know, running the six line or whatever subways over there through it.
Speaker 0: Hey There's not you know, too much stuff left in New York City to study.
Speaker 1: So What about the crazy homeless guys walking around yelling?
Speaker 0: Those are crazy homeless guys.
Speaker 1: You can study them see what they say.
Speaker 1: Hey All right, so basically for our main bid we were tired.
Speaker 1: we didn't have much to talk about today.
Speaker 1: So we figured we'd regale you with stories from our freshman year at RIT.
Speaker 1: It's a geek fable Except there's no moral to this one other than have fun in college.
Speaker 0: Well, I'm gonna make up a moral All right.
Speaker 1: We'll see if you come up with one or not.
Speaker 1: All right, I Mean, we're already told about how we all met.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and You know some stories about our wag the gaming club and our dungeon master Dwayne We don't need to get into that.
Speaker 1: Nope But our life as freshmen in college was pretty fantastic.
Speaker 1: Our IT the dorms are connected to each other by a whole bunch of tunnels.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course I lived in Peterson and our tunnels weren't connected to the other tunnels until like a few quarters in.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I was in the good dorms So I could spend an entire weekend without even sitting one foot outside in the winter.
Speaker 0: you were in the dorm.
Speaker 0: That was all guys and vomitation.
Speaker 0: I was in the co-ed dorm with no alcohol and no drugs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but your dorm was unrenovated and wasn't connected to the tunnel which means my route to which means my rooms were bigger.
Speaker 1: Plus despite all the vomitation sis of my dorm.
Speaker 1: No one ever vomited on me.
Speaker 0: You vomited on you.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah See, it's funny whenever I get the flu or anything I just like I vomit like.
Speaker 1: that's my primary mode of fighting illness.
Speaker 1: And one time when I was a freshman I got real sick and we all right here we have bunk beds.
Speaker 1: Now this is kind of it.
Speaker 1: This is it's kind of a sick story.
Speaker 1: Not that I guess we try told worse things But I'm laying there in bed.
Speaker 1: I'm sick and I wake up in the middle of the night and then I vomit Bargo.
Speaker 1: So I get out of bed and I'm not now.
Speaker 1: my roommate who I never talked to.
Speaker 1: I didn't.
Speaker 1: I don't even know this kid's name.
Speaker 1: I never talked to him.
Speaker 0: I never knew his name.
Speaker 1: He was quiet.
Speaker 1: He wasn't interested anything I was interested in so we just never talked and we left each other alone.
Speaker 0: He was sitting the chair wear headphones guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah I am pretty certain that he awakened and decided to pretend he was asleep to avoid having to deal with what I would ride it Just done.
Speaker 0: that is what I would do also being
Speaker 1: basically the story ends with me putting all my dirty sheets in a hamper not having any more clean sheets taking a shower and then Feebly crawling into my like bare mattress covering myself with my last dry towel and trying to sleep.
Speaker 0: That is hilarious.
Speaker 1: I really don't miss living in dorms.
Speaker 1: Now if I get sick, I have I have my own bedroom I have my own bathroom and I can just call in sick to work.
Speaker 0: I'm glad I Don't vomit and my streak is is very very long of not vomiting.
Speaker 0: I'll get some Ipecac and but I but I do diarrhea if I got a problem in the stomach.
Speaker 1: the diarrhea as I am Well aware.
Speaker 0: Yep But I'd rather diarrhea vomit.
Speaker 1: I'm a hair trigger vomiter, but only what I'm sick.
Speaker 0: See the diarrhea doesn't really bother me.
Speaker 0: what bothers me is like the pain in the stomach I don't have like a bunch of gas like swelling up and hurting.
Speaker 0: then it's all good with diarrhea.
Speaker 1: So anyway, well get off of this tangent that you probably don't want to hear much about.
Speaker 0: bowels.
Speaker 1: Live in the dorms.
Speaker 0: I'd like to buy a stick Aside from that.
Speaker 0: Yep, basically because well you've got nothing to do You don't have to go outside.
Speaker 1: We're a whole bunch of geeks.
Speaker 0: You can?
Speaker 0: you basically would spend entire weekends in Peterson not which was the dorm he was in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because this dorm had a lounge and this is the most fantastic lounge ever at least in terms of our IT.
Speaker 0: Well in our IT now most of the lounges are freaking dorms.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll get into that another time.
Speaker 1: But this lounge had this hump like this thing in it and it was covered in the carpet and Basically, that was the Dungeon Master throne.
Speaker 1: whenever we played D&D Alex our Dungeon Master would sit up there.
Speaker 0: It was perfect.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you really had to have been there.
Speaker 1: Mmm a lot of weekends We would just sit there and watch an entire anime like eska flown a or cowboy bebop just all in one go.
Speaker 0: We actually met a lot of our friends.
Speaker 1: that way we'd be what we were like one.
Speaker 1: We were watching right her friend Laura who actually she writes for gamers with jobs now.
Speaker 1: but we met her because we were watching tenku no eska flown a in marathon form and she walked by with some friends and saw it and Decided to sit there with us and watch the rest of it for the rest of the entire weekend.
Speaker 0: See now if I turned on a marathon of I don't know try gun.
Speaker 0: No one walks by here.
Speaker 0: No one would stop by our house and decide to be our friend.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, they wouldn't see us crying because we all cried when we watched try gun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we were all standing in Scott's room actually in the unrenovated Peterson dorm.
Speaker 1: all of us were standing around like eight people and we're watching a certain episode where a certain person has something bad happen to them as I avoid a spoiler and We're all crying and trying to hide the fact that we're crying from everyone else.
Speaker 0: That was a weird time when we were watching that because it was it wasn't in my dorm room Yeah, and like I was sitting there and people were sitting on the floor and then people started showing up randomly.
Speaker 1: Everyone was just standing there kind of crying.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was real weird.
Speaker 0: I think my roommate was actually in the room.
Speaker 1: I remember him giving us a look of like what the fuck he was a soccer guy.
Speaker 0: That's all I remember about him as he was soccer guy.
Speaker 0: He liked to play soccer and I think he transferred out because he didn't get on the RIT soccer team.
Speaker 1: See it's weird.
Speaker 1: a lot of it seems like a lot of people who went to school.
Speaker 1: they immediately at RIT At least they immediately become friends with their roommate and then they become friends with whatever like frat they join or whatever.
Speaker 1: We were other than one special exception didn't even really know the names of our roommates and we just found friends and hung out with them.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean, I remember like, you know, I saw you guys at our way, you know, we talked there.
Speaker 0: But then I guess we all went to anime club a few times without seeing each other or noticing Yeah, but like I remember once I saw you in Gracie's and I just came up and I was like, oh those little guys
Speaker 1: I remember thinking hey, it's that guy who was super Jew
Speaker 0: Yeah and I went up and I said hey
Speaker 1: and I was like hey and
Speaker 0: Then I walked away because I didn't everything to say cuz they were just some guys.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that was you know It's weird to think I mean we're our whole group the front row crew and there's a lot of us.
Speaker 1: We're like family and it's it's amazing to think that it wasn't that long ago that we'd never.
Speaker 1: we didn't even know each other.
Speaker 1: Yep, everyone in the group was just that guy We met like Greg who we used to be really good friends with was just that cool fuzzy-haired guy who like came around every Now and then
Speaker 0: yeah, he didn't Like I didn't even know he lives in the same floor as me until
Speaker 1: yeah
Speaker 0: a while.
Speaker 0: Just I would recognize, you know his face in it like there's a lot of people I don't know their name But like I see them and I go I know you because I see your face and I recognize it.
Speaker 0: and then you know Then Greg was one of those guys for like weeks and weeks and weeks.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember we talked a lot about a counter-strike and funny otaku military stuff.
Speaker 1: Mmm I remember cop katsu is a kendo guy.
Speaker 1: He's another member of the crew.
Speaker 0: I actually met katsu before I met anyone else.
Speaker 0: Wow like I went into our wag and I went and I was carrying my battle tech box and katsu was standing there with his funny umbrella and we said something about battle tech.
Speaker 0: and Then Dwayne which you already discussed.
Speaker 0: aha Dwayne, but and then I saw you other fools.
Speaker 0: But yeah, it's all katsu before I saw anybody.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay kind of weird.
Speaker 1: I Remember one of the first people I actually met that I was doing anything with.
Speaker 1: I was helping duck boy.
Speaker 1: We won't get into why he's called duck boy quack quack.
Speaker 1: If he's listening you proud doesn't even know that we called him duck boy.
Speaker 0: Oh, I am the dog from the land of friends.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: actually I really don't know why we called him duck boy.
Speaker 0: You will cook me in the French man.
Speaker 1: Uh, why didn't we call him the Iron Chef?
Speaker 0: I think someone else said he looked like a duck or something.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't know, but I was helping him make a third edition Dungeons & Dragons character.
Speaker 0: He was a winner.
Speaker 1: Yeah winner was him.
Speaker 1: as in loser So many we I mean we just we had infinite free time.
Speaker 1: none of us had jobs.
Speaker 1: I Held a job for about two weeks and then I quit.
Speaker 0: I worked at Crossroads freshman year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I remember that it wasn't a bad gig.
Speaker 1: I remember when Crossroads opened It was this cafe that they decided to make on the other side of campus that we rarely ventured to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you didn't really need to go over there if you're a freshman because it was as far away from the dorms as possible And it was like the farthest away academic building, which you didn't really go to unless you had You know crazy crazy classes out there.
Speaker 0: Yep, and freshman year.
Speaker 0: You don't really have crazy classes So they're mostly in the close buildings.
Speaker 1: freshman year classes are pretty much nothing.
Speaker 1: It was pretty much a non effort pass every class without even thinking.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's I mean freaking freshman year my first quarter I got like a freaking four I think or something crazy like some crazy-ass high GPA.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we didn't do homework.
Speaker 1: every day at around six o'clock We'd all congregated Gracie's the giant campus freshman cafeteria aka like pig trough Yep, and we started out like my.
Speaker 0: I remember going to Gracie's in the early days.
Speaker 0: I'd be alone and I didn't know there was takeout so I'd sit there alone Yeah, and then it was like two people and then like four people.
Speaker 0: eventually
Speaker 1: we take up like an entire long table full of people
Speaker 0: And then an entire long table and a half Yeah, and then when we find out the people sucked we kicked them out of the table and we were back down to like You know a half a table God.
Speaker 1: There was one guy.
Speaker 1: I remember he was really big into hentai.
Speaker 1: Yeah So much fans a hentai.
Speaker 0: No, we're definitely the anti hentai fan.
Speaker 1: now I don't mind if you like hentai, but I don't want you to tell me about it graphically constantly Yeah, especially if I didn't bring it up.
Speaker 0: and I mean like don't Get your hentai on me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, just keep it to yourself.
Speaker 1: get it on people who want to get it on them.
Speaker 0: I mean like.
Speaker 0: I don't even mind Being friends with someone who's like wacky religious or anything wacky waving inflatable arm flailing tube man.
Speaker 0: Just don't get your religion on me But this guy keep it to yourself.
Speaker 0: No, I'm gonna pester you.
Speaker 1: luckily hentai guy was real distinctive real ugly God, it's just painful.
Speaker 0: even today I think he's actually lost weight But you see him at conventions now and then I'll point him out to you if you ever find me.
Speaker 0: But you just look at them and you go.
Speaker 0: damn that's an ugly guy.
Speaker 0: Oh, I don't want to look at him anymore.
Speaker 1: Our huge group would congregate in Gracie's and we'd be looking around Just to try to spot him and try to head it off and sit where he wouldn't see us.
Speaker 1: It was hard to do when you're a group of like 11 people.
Speaker 0: It worked a couple times Yeah, and we were often able to escape him like he'd show up and we leave and he couldn't leave because he had a plate Full of food.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus we had a nice filter of only one of us had a car.
Speaker 0: So if we wanted to go anywhere or if we wanted to drop a bunch of people we just say oh Driving somewhere and we pick the people we wanted to keep get in the car drive a bit cover on back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't ever actually do that but we we'd like to go to a diner with the people we wanted to keep and then and then we come back and Actually a couple of times though.
Speaker 1: I can his car was great for that.
Speaker 1: But a couple of times we would honestly just Say like alright, we're all going to bed Let's go home and we'd all like go our separate ways and then reconvene an hour later somewhere else.
Speaker 0: I think we only did that a few times.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but those were critical times.
Speaker 0: Yeah Usually what would happen is we would you know, you'd be somewhere like anime club or Gracie's or something And then we'd walk back to the dorms and then we'd stop outside the dorm and talk for like an hour.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I still think back to that.
Speaker 1: maybe freezing cold.
Speaker 1: We'd be standing out.
Speaker 0: It wasn't freezing cold yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even it was cold.
Speaker 1: We still did it.
Speaker 1: We stand in like a lobby.
Speaker 1: No lobbies Yeah, but there was this.
Speaker 1: there's the thing we called it the thing.
Speaker 1: it was basically this big concrete thing That you could sit on or stand on.
Speaker 1: I guess it was a sculpture.
Speaker 0: imagine if it's like a Like a pyramid but it's got.
Speaker 0: you know, the whole thing is a stair but the stairs like two feet high.
Speaker 0: I don't know if that's a very good description or not.
Speaker 1: I don't think it really matter.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: It looks like a diva hat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it does.
Speaker 0: it's a diva hat a giant concrete diva hat.
Speaker 1: And it was weird.
Speaker 1: it got to the point where we became those guys.
Speaker 1: the guys were always hanging out at like this place.
Speaker 0: Yep, we were the cool guys.
Speaker 1: We're those cool guys.
Speaker 1: We're all just standing there and people walk by like I want to stand on the thing But I can't.
Speaker 1: those guys are always there.
Speaker 0: We're too cool for you.
Speaker 1: if other people were there we'd walk over and we just kind of muscle our way in.
Speaker 1: you know with our geek leave muscles.
Speaker 1: No, we didn't well by muscle our way in.
Speaker 1: we just kind of stand around there and eventually the non geeks get uncomfortable and leave Suck or they'd be geeks and it'd be awesome.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's how you add people.
Speaker 1: it helped that RIT is a real geeky school.
Speaker 0: mmm, if you're a nerd or geek and You're looking for a school Even though RIT has its problems just like every other school.
Speaker 0: There's no place geeky or you can go god damn.
Speaker 0: You'll be freaking happy there.
Speaker 1: Let me tell you One of our favorite pastimes was we'd we'd wander around looking for places to Continue to hang out.
Speaker 1: So we'd be hanging out somewhere and then we'd get restless, but we didn't have anything to do.
Speaker 1: We had no money Yeah, so we'd start wandering around campus until we found like another room to hang out in.
Speaker 0: Oh the tunnels are full of rooms.
Speaker 1: Yeah The tunnels had a lot of old abandoned infrastructure like.
Speaker 1: there used to be a dance club down there that they shut down.
Speaker 1: There's just a big empty room.
Speaker 0: There used to be an arcade.
Speaker 0: that wasn't there anymore, but you can still see the painting on the wall that said arcade here.
Speaker 0: Yep, and there was still like pieces of paper like arcade hours, but there was no arcade.
Speaker 0: It was just a part.
Speaker 1: We busted into conference rooms just to play battle tech.
Speaker 0: Oh Battle tech you've eaten so many hours.
Speaker 0: I wish to play you again.
Speaker 1: Oh battle tech is fantastic.
Speaker 0: Oh my god, if you haven't played battle tech we should do a podcast on battle tech.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, we should.
Speaker 1: we just freakin wander around.
Speaker 1: We got caught by campus safety once because we were watered around late at night in the science building.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and this campus safety guy comes over.
Speaker 1: He's like what the hell are you guys doing?
Speaker 0: Well, the door was open and we just wanted to walk through because it was kind of cold outside.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and this campus safety guy comes in and he's like, what are you doing in the building?
Speaker 0: We're like, well the door was open.
Speaker 0: So we walk through the building to you know Go in that door and come out the door on the other side.
Speaker 0: So we'd be warm at least for that distance of the walk.
Speaker 0: and he's like, you know, the building's closed You can't be in here and we're like, oh But the door was open.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know even though they often forget to lock doors and Actually, there were a lot of like.
Speaker 1: basically there were secret ways in.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they still work But there was basically a secret ways to get into any building on campus locked or not because of those tunnels Yep, but nowadays they lock the buildings much better.
Speaker 0: So yeah, you're not gonna get in quite as easily.
Speaker 1: It's actually sad.
Speaker 1: all the campus changed when we were freshmen.
Speaker 1: The dorms were open until 11 all the time till 11 the doors was unlocked.
Speaker 1: You could do whatever you want.
Speaker 0: They gave me a key to open like the doors of the whole dorms.
Speaker 1: I never used that key Yeah, unless we left late at night and you had to get back in somehow.
Speaker 0: Even so I even late at night, but that door was always open.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz you walk into Gracie's and yeah No, I would just walk into my dorm.
Speaker 1: My dorm was usually locked but I could get into the tunnels.
Speaker 0: nowadays I think they have like locks in the dorms then on the elevators.
Speaker 1: And yeah nowadays in RIT if you're in a freshman in the dorms You gotta put your key in the elevator to use the frickin elevator.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: Yeah And we also had our.
Speaker 1: we didn't do this that often but when we did it was most enjoyable.
Speaker 1: our zeppelin days It was sunny out because there are less sunny days in Rochester than there are in Seattle.
Speaker 0: They're less sunny days in Rochester than there are women at RIT.
Speaker 1: So our zeppelin days when it was warm enough out we'd lay on the quarter mile Which is like this path between the dorms and the academic side.
Speaker 0: Well, it actually went through the academic side.
Speaker 1: So yeah, let's say it connected them and then it continued through the academic and that was the extra quarter of mile.
Speaker 1: So we'd lay there with a boombox playing zeppelin shirtless just kind of sunbathing or tossing a ball around.
Speaker 1: We're really the only ones who did something like that and a lot of people gave us weird looks but no one ever really said Anything to.
Speaker 0: yeah, you had if you wanted to be out on the quarter mile, you had to have a frisbee or something You know, you couldn't just lay out there with music.
Speaker 0: people would be like what the hell you're not working You know, what are you doing?
Speaker 0: Yeah, what's going on?
Speaker 1: I remember we'd see all those people like furiously studying and we just kind of laugh at him.
Speaker 0: I never understood that.
Speaker 0: I mean look I graduated I didn't furiously study ever.
Speaker 0: What were they doing?
Speaker 1: What are you doing?
Speaker 0: Hey, dude Ah Freshman year was good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess the moral here is don't squander your freshman year of college.
Speaker 1: That's the most fun for the least responsibility.
Speaker 1: You're ever gonna have.
Speaker 0: I Think the moral is be one of the people who has diarrhea and not vomit when you get sick.
Speaker 0: Cuz vomiting really sucks All right.
Speaker 1: So well, we'll tell some more stories another time.
Speaker 1: That was a very tiny slice of our life at RIT Mm-hmm, but to move into some meta bits this podcast was kind of blab because Scott's all tired and he won't really talk.
Speaker 0: Hey, I did just.
Speaker 0: you know, what do you want from me?
Speaker 0: Don't be so tired okay, so You better.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, what what what?
Speaker 1: what are you gonna say?
Speaker 1: You're too tired even argue.
Speaker 0: I've has blame on to you with some words.
Speaker 0: Yeah anyway We got a little meta bit.
Speaker 0: The first meta bit is that we're looking for Audio feedback.
Speaker 0: Other podcasts have audio feedback where people call in or send, you know mp3s of themselves Saying something.
Speaker 0: so and as opposed to sending us an email with feedback You record yourself saying the feedback and send it to us now.
Speaker 1: How does this sound?
Speaker 1: We have a specific kind of feedback not really feedback But a specific thing.
Speaker 1: if you guys are gonna take advantage of this that we'd like you to do.
Speaker 1: We were thinking about doing a show about the podcast or about us like specifically why we do this who we are or whatever.
Speaker 1: We decided all these I decided just now Instead of interviewing each other.
Speaker 0: or what a democratic system.
Speaker 1: How about this?
Speaker 1: you guys interview us?
Speaker 1: Send us audio questions and we'll set it up to where you the listeners interview us one day.
Speaker 1: Once we have enough questions do a whole show.
Speaker 0: that could be pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Now there's two ways.
Speaker 0: number one you just record yourself make an mp3 or a wav file or something and email it as an attachment or Put it on the web and email a link to that location any kind of technology way.
Speaker 0: Yeah to geek nights at gmail.com and in the subject put audio feedback.
Speaker 0: The other way you can leave us audio feedback is we have a voicemail box and the way this works is you call this phone number and you leave a voicemail and We will get an email with your voicemail as an attachment and we can use that.
Speaker 0: the phone number you can call is 1 5 3 7. that's 206 3 3 3 1 5 3 7.
Speaker 1: Outstanding.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go use that little program on the internet that tells me what words I can make with those numbers.
Speaker 1: But Yeah, so interview us ask us whatever you want.
Speaker 1: no quite no question is out of bounds though You may not get a serious answer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and If we don't like your question, we are in no way obligated to actually use it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or we might just make fun of you.
Speaker 0: Like if you just call in and go.
Speaker 0: blaga blaga blaga blaga.
Speaker 1: Oh, we'll probably play it but oh Yeah, identify yourself.
Speaker 1: I don't you know in some way like hi, I'm or hi, I'm Fred yeah, and don't make it too long because Yeah, verbosity is not what we're after here.
Speaker 0: Yep Not but if your verbosity is high-quality Yes, I go from penny arcade.
Speaker 0: Yeah, go for it.
Speaker 1: But I had to quote some words of wisdom.
Speaker 1: People who don't understand analogy shouldn't make them and people who don't understand big words should not use them.
Speaker 0: Mmm.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: In addition, I hate asking for like votes cuz you know They had their web pages where you vote for things and then they go up in the list.
Speaker 0: but I kind of Everyone else asks for votes.
Speaker 0: So if you go to podcast alley calm and vote for us then that means our link will like appear higher up and people will see it and That's a good way that you can get more people to listen to us Even if you don't have any other people to tell
Speaker 1: The girl.
Speaker 1: of course only do this if you actually think where we deserve it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you think we suck don't freakin vote for us.
Speaker 0: God Of course In even better ways to just tell your friends.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or spread the word on other forms.
Speaker 1: I'm very happy.
Speaker 1: listenership has been rising steadily from the moment We started at a very steady and predictable rate, which is kind of scary and kind of cool at the same time.
Speaker 0: Yep, also our forums are quite hopping.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're hopping Madly, and they're very much keeping me busy at work when I'm here.
Speaker 0: There aren't a crap ton of people there, but there's quite a few people and they're posting a lot.
Speaker 0: So if you're not in the forums, you need to go there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just go to front row crew calm and Click on forum and then sign up and I'll approve you and post away.
Speaker 1: Oh and also one more bit We're looking for.
Speaker 1: I need some tips on how to make Scott fucking be awake during the podcast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you can find out a way to you know Or just give me a way to drug him with caffeine because he refuses to take any form of caffeine into his body Even though that would solve all of his problems not gonna drink caffeine.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: or eat it caffeine's fine.
Speaker 0: Not a chance.
Speaker 1: There have been two studies recently.
Speaker 1: the show caffeine is good for you.
Speaker 0: And there have been many studies before the show.
Speaker 1: It's only bad if you use it in lieu of sleep.
Speaker 0: nah, you know, what's good?
Speaker 0: no chemicals.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: All right, even though you eat enemas Hey what those those donuts you buy in a box?
Speaker 0: What's wrong with the?
Speaker 1: don't you realize there's edible oils full of preservatives and chemicals?
Speaker 0: It's an edible oil Edible being the key.
Speaker 1: I don't want to go to Toronto.
Speaker 0: I don't want to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, you're gonna go whether you like it or not.
Speaker 1: All right, we've rambled into Randomness at this point.
Speaker 1: So with that and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Thanks for listening.
Speaker 0: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds feed burner comm slash.
Speaker 0: geek nights.
Speaker 0: get the latest episodes as soon as their release.
Speaker 0: Also, please visit our website at Www.front row crew.com for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at geek nights at gmail.com.