Speaker 2: It's Thursday December 15th, and this is geek nights with rim and Scott and Emily.
Speaker 2: tonight They'd like to tell you about shaving.
Speaker 1: Oh boy Let's do this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so uh it's freezing rain out there, and if the power goes out.
Speaker 0: We're not uploading this podcast.
Speaker 2: So yeah well I guess strike MTA strike tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's gonna be fantastic.
Speaker 1: I guess we'll upload it.
Speaker 1: I mean if we get something recorded and saved and the power comes back on at some point Maybe but Scott.
Speaker 0: What are you gonna?
Speaker 0: Do if the MTA strikes?
Speaker 1: I'm not going to freakin work.
Speaker 1: That's for sure I'm gonna do on Sunday.
Speaker 2: There's like a of course.
Speaker 2: It's not rush hour, but they were talking about a four passenger car rule.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well you know what I'll drive you and two mannequins.
Speaker 2: so anyway I'm just here for the weekend to escape the you know seductive procrastination powers of Manhattan.
Speaker 2: well I finished my term paper.
Speaker 2: You know I figure being out here in the boonies.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz there's no seductive procrastination powers in here with all our technologies and Like I know what I know it's weird.
Speaker 2: But like I'm very personal about computers like when using another person's computer is like I don't know like using.
Speaker 2: I'm trying to think of a good personal analogy, but it's like I Sing and like just wasting time and somebody else's computer like.
Speaker 2: I feel like if I'm using a borrowed computer I should be like actually doing work.
Speaker 0: I have the like the dual nature on one hand.
Speaker 0: I'm an IT professional and I'm very good at like.
Speaker 0: I know a lot of people's passwords But like it's I'm not conscious of it, and I see like horrible things that people have hidden on their hard drives But I just don't even think about it, but at the same time I'm very good at computer forensics, and I want to just dig through and see what dirt I can find.
Speaker 1: yeah See it used to be we're using another person's computer was like this alien painful experience.
Speaker 1: But now most of the computers that I use all have Firefox and as long as they have Firefox I can access all my web stuff And I have enough stuff that's web only and web-based that it doesn't matter if I don't have my desktop stuff.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I guess it doesn't bother me that much.
Speaker 2: It's more like it's not like oh, I'm worried I'm gonna find something weird on computer or anything like that.
Speaker 2: It's more like you know stuff's not organized the way.
Speaker 2: I'm used to it being organized and you know Resist the urge to change things you know yeah, yeah, I don't want to.
Speaker 2: you know.
Speaker 2: last time I was here as changed rims desktop, and he still got it changed.
Speaker 0: well because your change was better than my desktop.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's the thing is sometimes like I'm trying to make a change like I know this will make their computer faster.
Speaker 1: But sometimes it's like I know that this way is more efficient.
Speaker 1: But are they used to the other way and will they bitch?
Speaker 0: well remember that time we were at Luke's house And we turned on his computer, and he didn't have a video car driver.
Speaker 0: We installed video car drivers and all this stuff, and he was mad when he came home until he realized that it was better.
Speaker 2: Yeah You just don't know.
Speaker 2: See those are the best good deeds.
Speaker 2: You know don't you?
Speaker 2: don't you feel warm inside?
Speaker 2: Helping people.
Speaker 2: Oh, yeah like like when you helped Alice with her computer, and she like venerated you all weekend.
Speaker 2: That was that was something.
Speaker 0: yeah I've learned that removing spyware is very lucrative because even if you don't ask for money people give you money anyway.
Speaker 2: Don't you love when?
Speaker 2: then the non technology people?
Speaker 2: and like to be honest you know I'll be perfectly frank I'm I'm kind of like one of those people kind of like the people who drive a car and they have a vague idea of what's happening under the hood and You know, but they're not being able to.
Speaker 2: like my sister You know get out the wrench, and you know take the thing apart, so I'm.
Speaker 2: you know I like computers.
Speaker 2: You know I'm I'm a film animation person, so you know I'm more of an art girl than a tech girl But I like the tech end of things.
Speaker 0: I just you know not as not as cool as these suckers here Despite my ancient computer that these two were making fun of me for not two minutes ago.
Speaker 1: I know a lot of you would consider my computer ancient, and it's really not, but it's just not a media computer.
Speaker 2: It's like it's perfectly viable for all the stuff you do.
Speaker 1: Crashes it does.
Speaker 0: yeah, the USB crashing, but for all of you who are following along next Monday We're gonna continue the buying a computer saga And the forms have been exploding about that.
Speaker 0: so expect some good Stuff.
Speaker 2: oh, oh bad thing did I tell you I had like this?
Speaker 2: I I love my 3d teacher, but like every time computers comes up He's like a major Windows fanatic, and I don't know how buddy how anybody can be a Windows Like.
Speaker 1: some podcast was saying like did you know they're actually Windows fanatics, and I'm like what?
Speaker 1: and they were like yeah But they're out there.
Speaker 0: yeah, I always figured that people who use Windows and like it It's just because they don't know better, or they don't want to learn or Linux is scary.
Speaker 1: I met one guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I knew that there was one guy once who I it was a Windows fanatic But he was like Windows XP is the best, and I'm like what do you?
Speaker 1: He runs Windows XP Maya and nothing else unlike this dual processor.
Speaker 1: See this is he doesn't use the computer for anything.
Speaker 2: with the Maya people I've got like this.
Speaker 2: I'm going love affair with Maya.
Speaker 1: It's It's my new obsession cuz they're not really computer people is really just a Maya guy And he runs Maya on Windows as opposed to I guess Mac And I just likes it better on Windows.
Speaker 1: so he's a Windows fanatic.
Speaker 2: apparently Maya does For some reason there's like.
Speaker 2: just talk about that as optimized for Windows or it runs better on Windows or something like that.
Speaker 2: I've got personal learning edition on my Mac in it.
Speaker 2: It's take forever to load like I. Apparently I checked I have sufficient RAM.
Speaker 2: I don't know what the problem is.
Speaker 2: It's just like slow as beans.
Speaker 1: We'll see what happens with the Intel Mac action.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yes One cool guy work is waiting until they come out to buy a new PowerBook.
Speaker 1: I think everyone is yeah Except me who's.
Speaker 2: I've got to find a good laptop before I go to Japan and my sister's got some good deals through her.
Speaker 1: I heard a rumor that Apple's gonna come out with a laptop that doesn't have a hard drive.
Speaker 1: It just has flash.
Speaker 1: So if that happens I might get that because damn it'll be small.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know I remember that Steve Jobs personally comes to your house and delivers it every time you buy.
Speaker 0: So we'll see where that.
Speaker 1: so that's how he sells all those things.
Speaker 1: though speaking of laptops remember the MIT $100 laptop that you want to make you mean the useless thing with a crank on it and the tiny tiny screen.
Speaker 0: yeah It sparked a lot of debate, but they picked a Manufacturer.
Speaker 1: now someone's actually gonna build them.
Speaker 0: well apparently I mean the slashdot article is very misleading.
Speaker 0: They haven't found someone who said they can build it.
Speaker 0: they picked a company and asked this company to come up with a feasible design Didn't they already design?
Speaker 1: and now they're just looking for someone to build it.
Speaker 1: I mean what what what?
Speaker 0: they've designed it, but they it's not $100 what they want.
Speaker 2: I heard it was you know like.
Speaker 2: you know the the case that they wanted for it was very like Like kind of kid looking.
Speaker 0: and yeah, they wanted.
Speaker 1: But that's good because then it'll be you know.
Speaker 1: I guess the idea is that you'll give this to like poor people in Africa and such that they can have Some sort of access.
Speaker 1: you know like.
Speaker 1: I've heard of towns where?
Speaker 1: People have wireless laptops and some guy drives through the town on a motorcycle and collects all the emails Wirelessly and then drives to someplace with this internet and dumps all the emails off.
Speaker 1: So if people had this kind of thing It would just be so much easier for them to get in on that sort of system.
Speaker 0: Well, I like I mean it's a really good idea, but what surprises me is how much absolute Vamint there is in the people who are opposed to the idea of donating these laptops or designing them or anything.
Speaker 2: why?
Speaker 0: Because well their argument seems to be this money could be spent better, or why not give them $100 worth of food?
Speaker 0: or Basically their argument seemed to be we should only focus on one problem at a time instead of trying to fix many problems Was some ways.
Speaker 2: I I think there are Certain certain areas of the world where it does seem not to be a priority.
Speaker 2: as far as you know the things that need fixing Yeah, but I mean if someone's gonna.
Speaker 0: I mean my partake is basically if someone's going to go out of their way to do a charitable thing if they donate something You know if somebody's giving something That can help Why not take it?
Speaker 0: I mean if more that if I'm doing it of my own prerogative I should be able to do whatever I want.
Speaker 0: if I donate a toy to a kid or food or a band-aid or a laptop I donated something.
Speaker 0: yep, so you can't tell people what to donate then it's not really a donation.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the one good thing I have to say is like you know if someone's gonna donate.
Speaker 1: I mean saying that like food is the number one problem here that people are starving in Somalia or something right.
Speaker 1: so anyone who?
Speaker 1: Donates should donate food.
Speaker 1: Well what if I'm?
Speaker 1: you know what if my donation of food isn't so much because I'm not a farmer But I can donate a whole lot of computer stuff and the farmer can donate a whole lot of food.
Speaker 1: You know everyone should donate where they can do the most good in.
Speaker 1: you know their area because I couldn't really donate that much food.
Speaker 1: You know I'm not a farmer, but the bad thing is okay.
Speaker 1: $100 computer.
Speaker 1: It's real cheap.
Speaker 1: it could bring the internet to all these people but $100 is still really expensive for a poor starving person.
Speaker 0: well the the rationale here is that governments will buy them to distribute or Western societies will take donations and use them to buy them for people.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh come on if we're just gonna use them to buy them for people I can buy $100 desktops and just send them there.
Speaker 0: The rationale for this is most of these places don't have access to electricity Like our battery.
Speaker 0: a car better.
Speaker 0: that doesn't work Scott.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no yeah, no why not?
Speaker 0: There's a lot of But things like capacitors and resistors all right whatever and electrons.
Speaker 2: Anyway, the whole concept.
Speaker 2: I guess you know more than the you know charity aspect of it the idea of You know a laptop that wouldn't require any power source or anything with just kind of cool.
Speaker 2: Yeah, the crank.
Speaker 1: You have noticed a lot of Crank and solar chargers lately.
Speaker 1: they got backpacks with solar cells to charge your iPod And they got cranks to charge laptops and digital cameras.
Speaker 1: You know while it's probably not good idea to recharge a whole lithium-ion battery like that.
Speaker 1: You'll hurt yourself Really good for being in the middle of nowhere camping your cell phone runs out.
Speaker 1: You know if you got no power yeah.
Speaker 0: Or say you live in a more enlightened area.
Speaker 0: what if a place like New York City set up little Chargers in the street that just power themselves solarly?
Speaker 2: well You know it's funny because a lot of the you know those little shops that sell like all sorts of I heart, New York goods and like A lot of them sell cell phone charges.
Speaker 2: You know it's like for five minutes You can charge your cell phone at their charger And they charge you like.
Speaker 1: do they have it like an adapter for every cell phone and everything there?
Speaker 2: I'm not sure you know cuz I've never done it, but I've seen this advertise.
Speaker 2: You know free technology charging.
Speaker 1: I knew they had something like that cuz it works.
Speaker 1: one day some guys like you know blackberry died And he for some reason they didn't have a charging cable Or I don't know what was going on But they went down to like the cell phone store like the singular store And they got him a recharge or like a bad or they just traded in his battery for one that was charged that they had Or so I don't know.
Speaker 0: well I think there's definitely gonna be more and more of a market for that sort of thing because Battery technology is not keeping up with technology.
Speaker 1: Yeah But at least like the double-a is dead.
Speaker 1: and but now it's kind of like this double-edged sword.
Speaker 1: We have these great proprietary batteries for everything that are all rechargeable, so everything has its own charger.
Speaker 1: Yes, and you don't have to buy double-a's, but now we have to keep everything charged.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when we go to conventions everyone brings their own personal power strip.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it works out though and stuff seems to be staying charged long enough.
Speaker 1: I mean iPod goes for hours digital camera goes for hours.
Speaker 1: It's good.
Speaker 2: when I go places like on trips I have my Astro Boy lunchbox, and I put all my little gadgets in there with other chargers So I have my little lunch box.
Speaker 1: I cut this stuff around All right, yeah, so we were talking about PC game.
Speaker 0: well PCs on Monday and PC games yes And there's a large large argument in the forums about it, which I would suggest you all read.
Speaker 1: well I came across today one more humongous argument against PC games and to why you probably shouldn't play them.
Speaker 1: They are Drms Apparently.
Speaker 1: you know a lot of games have copy protection.
Speaker 1: You know steam has it, but it steams isn't.
Speaker 1: it isn't really Hurting your computer.
Speaker 1: It's just you have to have an account broken is it really?
Speaker 1: yes.
Speaker 2: It is it doesn't work.
Speaker 1: Mine works anyway.
Speaker 1: There's a DRM for PC games called Star Force and apparently it's Bad.
Speaker 1: not as bad as the Sony DRM, but almost as bad.
Speaker 0: Oh not as bad as the Sony DRM.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't rootkit you, but it does screw up your computer And it can destroy your CD-ROM drive.
Speaker 1: just your CD-ROM will be broken.
Speaker 0: awesome.
Speaker 0: What does it do?
Speaker 0: rewrite the firmware or something it does?
Speaker 1: crazy stuff like that?
Speaker 1: Yeah?
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know if you buy I mean as much as I dislike the Xbox 360 And I have even more reasons just like it now which we don't have time to talk about really.
Speaker 0: But it's nice to say it sucks.
Speaker 0: It won't break your games.
Speaker 1: Well, it will if you turn it from vertical to horizontal while it's on.
Speaker 0: oh, yeah If you have an Xbox don't ever rotate it or knock it over 60 then you know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, there's a list I'm gonna link to of all these PC games some of which are pretty big PC games.
Speaker 1: I mean Splinter Cell 3 X III 13.
Speaker 0: it's called another game with David Duchovny.
Speaker 1: I have no idea.
Speaker 1: I know it's on the GameCube.
Speaker 1: so get the GameCube version if you want to.
Speaker 0: yeah It's David Duchovny's in that the X-Files guy.
Speaker 1: all right There's a bunch of games on here and installing any dead to rights.
Speaker 1: These games will basically screw up your computer big time and it.
Speaker 1: I don't know why you'd play them on the PC.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, all right though They're made much better gaming news.
Speaker 0: a bunch of reporters and people have gotten to actually test drive the Nintendo Revolution controller.
Speaker 1: Well, they did test drive it.
Speaker 1: I think it.
Speaker 1: when they unveiled the thing at E3 Oh, yeah, but those were demos.
Speaker 0: These are like they took a level from Metroid Prime 2 and they.
Speaker 1: that's what the tech demos were when they were at e3.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and these are the exact same things.
Speaker 1: only now they're letting more people use them.
Speaker 0: a lot of people are using them and CNN has an article about it and These are people who many of them aren't even gamers and Pretty much all the reviews are glowing.
Speaker 0: They say such things as wow that was amazing.
Speaker 0: It's perfect.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 2: Yeah, yeah that I totally want to mess with one.
Speaker 2: I mean, I showed Macy the commercial.
Speaker 2: Macy's my roommate and I showed her the commercial and she was like Pretty sweet.
Speaker 1: She was very impressed.
Speaker 0: I saw the controller like that unveiled it.
Speaker 0: I was like what the hell What are they thinking?
Speaker 0: And then I saw like two seconds to that demo reels.
Speaker 1: Ah Yeah, there's another video online that that someone made where some people are real idiots.
Speaker 1: They don't really understand how the revolution is gonna work.
Speaker 1: Someone made a video where it's like this is how it's gonna work.
Speaker 1: Damn you here it is.
Speaker 1: Now you get it.
Speaker 1: if you don't get it after watching this screw you.
Speaker 1: So if you still don't get it, you got to see this video More and more.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking the revolution is gonna make a big Splash in the game industry like Sony and Microsoft aren't ready for.
Speaker 1: I think it's gonna be.
Speaker 1: you know The kind of curve where it grows a little bit.
Speaker 1: It goes a little bit and there's a lot.
Speaker 0: Well, the Microsoft's generating a lot of ill will over the Xbox.
Speaker 1: was that a natural log, I think I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: a Natural log would pretty much be impossible.
Speaker 1: Oh, okay in short order I I forget which sorts of functions make the graphs that do what I think.
Speaker 1: Cuz it's been a while But yeah.
Speaker 1: So there was this contest on in gadget today.
Speaker 1: Actually, it was a week of contest and they were giving away gadgets every day of the week And Basically there was a different thing that you needed to do for each day of the week.
Speaker 1: so like on Tuesday, they said something during their podcast of what to do to win the prize.
Speaker 1: and to win the prize today, all you had to do is post a comment saying what the prize was.
Speaker 1: and They didn't tell you what the prize was.
Speaker 0: there any limit to how many comments you can post.
Speaker 1: any one person can post one guess.
Speaker 1: The big catch was that you couldn't just say something like Dell monitor.
Speaker 1: you had to say Dell 2405 fpw.
Speaker 1: you had to say exactly which gadget it was.
Speaker 1: now What's occurred here is something that's very very interesting.
Speaker 1: There are let me get the current count 1362 comments posted in the single blog entry and There are very very few duplicates.
Speaker 1: so now what we've basically done is made a list of every gadget that people want and Actively desire and think is cool enough to be a prize in this contest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, most of them are Nintendo.
Speaker 1: Well, there's a disproportionate number of Nintendo gadgets because in the blog post they use the question block as the Because they were like question mark and they put a question block.
Speaker 1: So people started Giving Nintendo guesses to me.
Speaker 0: I would not guess Nintendo because that's too obvious.
Speaker 1: I'm beginning to think it might be Nintendo.
Speaker 1: But basically what they're gonna do is they're gonna search for the exact, you know name of the Gadget.
Speaker 1: Oh, wait, there's an update.
Speaker 1: Hold on a couple of you are pretty freaking close.
Speaker 1: No one's got.
Speaker 1: oh wait They do have a winner but way to almost break the news incorrectly.
Speaker 1: Ah Okay, but no there was an update that was made between when I left work.
Speaker 1: when I left work There were like 600 of these and they hadn't bitten.
Speaker 1: So this update was between now and then Where some people were close, but they're looking for a specific version model or addition of a device.
Speaker 1: Wow so people had it, but they didn't have the Version number, right?
Speaker 1: So it might have been like someone might have guessed like iPod But it was probably like iPod u2 edition.
Speaker 1: or someone might have guessed Nintendo DS But it was like Nintendo DS Mario Kart edition or something.
Speaker 0: See this one was all you.
Speaker 0: I mean, I don't really read and gadget.
Speaker 0: I like gadgets, but I don't buy many gadgets.
Speaker 0: I just like looking at them so I don't even bother with in gadget.
Speaker 1: No, I like in gadget because it's like if you reading gadget in gizmodo you get all the gadgets.
Speaker 1: But there's also Akihabara news, which is like Akihabara.
Speaker 1: Yes, they had.
Speaker 1: that's the best gadget site.
Speaker 1: cuz you get all these Japanese gadgets that you'll never be able to own ever.
Speaker 2: Actually, it's really cool.
Speaker 2: If you go there.
Speaker 2: Yeah, my favorite bit.
Speaker 2: Oh, this is a funny story, you know, I Lived in Japan for a while and there was this.
Speaker 2: I knew this guy from oh god.
Speaker 2: Where was he from?
Speaker 2: I think it was Panama and we called him Ken and I was with Ken and Akihabara one day and we were going Shopping at game stores, and there was this one game store.
Speaker 2: It was like a two-level place.
Speaker 2: It was pretty big and I remember there was all these big displays for Dead or Alive Beach volleyball, you know, oh great So it was.
Speaker 2: it was kind of ridiculous, but we go to the second floor, you know The first floor is all standard square soft kind of stuff and we go to the second floor and it's starting to get a little Shady, you know like all the girl get games and stuff like that
Speaker 0: all the games paralyzed.
Speaker 2: Oh, yeah So, you know a little a little sketchy there and you know these these weird kind of hentai looking PC games.
Speaker 2: I'm like, hmm.
Speaker 2: Let's go back downstairs.
Speaker 2: Ken who has no idea what all this stuff is He's kind of like hmm and he's wondering about and he ends up Smacked up in the middle of the yaoi game section and I know this podcast Has like way too much yaoi already.
Speaker 2: what with like you guys wouldn't stop talking about cluster edge.
Speaker 1: It was hilarious, but it was just like because he could have been such a good show.
Speaker 2: But if you guys would ask me about this stuff, like I know I could have told you right away It's like it's straight-up BL On our own and then we scream about it.
Speaker 1: It's funnier when the anime is structured in such a way where you don't find out.
Speaker 1: so like 10 minutes.
Speaker 2: Anyway, Ken was just standing there being like what what and he's like poking at stuff and looking at stuff.
Speaker 2: It'd be like what is this?
Speaker 2: and there are like these school girls in the corner?
Speaker 2: Just like dying laughing because there's this gaijin over there like in the middle of the yaoi game section Just like hooking at everything.
Speaker 2: They're like, oh my god You know, it's getting embarrassing.
Speaker 0: it was like what.
Speaker 0: what's the matter?
Speaker 2: Oh My but anyway Akihabara is a real fun place and you know, you can get laptops for like $69 but they're kind of sketchy and very very old.
Speaker 0: Hey sketchy and old is fine.
Speaker 0: $69 for a laptop.
Speaker 1: those are useful for something man as long as the battery is good Whatever But easy adapting.
Speaker 2: but anyway, there's there's some cool stuff going down in Akihabara.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Personally like Shibuya myself.
Speaker 1: So I found something today.
Speaker 1: Well, I had found a few things today, but one of them really stood out.
Speaker 1: It was a flash game and you know yesterday that would think there was a command and conquer flash game And I think we saw Warcraft flash game out of the command and conquer one.
Speaker 0: I never actually got to see the link died like immediately.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it came back up, but it wasn't worth the trouble.
Speaker 1: But anyway today I found an entire brand new SNES style Zelda game made entirely in flash now.
Speaker 0: I have one really serious question about this.
Speaker 0: Why is tingle in it?
Speaker 0: And why is he like the first guy you meet?
Speaker 1: I don't know because I haven't played the game more than a minute, but I do know this.
Speaker 1: I didn't read the text from when you talk to tingle.
Speaker 1: but it might be funny and it might be making fun of tingle because as soon as you talk to him a bomb shows up and Normally link uses bombs as an item.
Speaker 1: This bomb seems to follow link around like it's a Party member.
Speaker 2: It's it's his pal awesome.
Speaker 1: So I think this is just a really silly parody but also possibly quality Flash Zelda game.
Speaker 1: that might be worth the time.
Speaker 1: It takes to play it, huh?
Speaker 0: Though uh to segue into a real-world tingle.
Speaker 2: My god, I was gonna talk more about flash because my entire life has been Can you make a Zelda game?
Speaker 2: I actually I'm not that good with the interactive Want to learn how to make a game but I use it a lot for like.
Speaker 2: Actually, I don't use it so much for web animation either.
Speaker 2: I've been using it to actually do a lot of my you know 2d elements for my movies and It works pretty well.
Speaker 2: I like the flash and it actually saves me a lot of work When I draw right into the computer, so and Scott's making faces at me like Anyway anyway going into my thing of the day Which is actually a borrowed thing of the day from Scott because I spent all day reading you know Korean modernism assignments about oh European colonialism.
Speaker 2: Yeah, so I guess if you don't want to hear lectures about that I can tell you about hard gay and hard.
Speaker 2: so that kind of fits in with my whole.
Speaker 2: I was going to Akihabara thing and So, you know I've been kind of distant from the Japanese pop culture scene for a couple years since I moved to college.
Speaker 2: and Anyway, there was something Scott showed me today in Google video Apparently one of the Japanese top comedians and a lot of advertisements and stuff.
Speaker 2: He's called hard gay and Looks exactly the way you raise.
Speaker 2: It's like completely over-the-top like biker gear with the hat and these you know.
Speaker 2: He runs around as basically this guy who's like being very over-the-top like gay biker dude running around an office and just messing with stuff and like taking pictures of his face in the copier and In the end he ties himself up with Christmas lights and puts him self up on the billboard of Yahoo, Japan.
Speaker 0: He's like I am the boy from Yahoo, Japan.
Speaker 2: It's I don't know.
Speaker 2: I just I can't picture Yahoo in America pulling one of those sort of commercials.
Speaker 2: It was it was pretty entertaining.
Speaker 1: Isn't it funny how in America like like gayness is like half the people think it's evil, but in Japan, it's.
Speaker 1: it's hilarious.
Speaker 2: I gotta be perfectly frank.
Speaker 2: like a lot of anime fans and stuff in the States think since there are so many, you know Be shown and you know ambiguous There's so much gender Confusion and stuff in anime and manga that Japanese society must be much open to this sort of thing.
Speaker 2: and actually, you know, there's still a lot of problems with prejudice.
Speaker 2: and you know, I think Both societies need to learn to be more open and accepting of the whole.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, I point out that South Africa made Gay marriage and it's like wow, the world has.
Speaker 2: you know, I'm 21 years old.
Speaker 2: The world has changed.
Speaker 1: People aren't really any more tolerant of gayness.
Speaker 2: they are they are they're not like the.
Speaker 2: In the past couple years you just seen Just like this really big Backlash by Christian fundamentalists and this it's like god forbid our government turned into a theocracy.
Speaker 2: It's really starting to make me nervous.
Speaker 2: What would the religious right?
Speaker 2: Commanding the amount of power it does in our political system?
Speaker 2: I mean, I'm sorry.
Speaker 2: I don't want to When it comes to being this stupid.
Speaker 2: and if you start being a bigot if you start being a bigot I don't care if I offend you.
Speaker 0: So yeah, I mean offend people.
Speaker 2: I'm a bigot only against bigots.
Speaker 0: So whoo Hey, hey Now it's weird that we have three things the day and as we were about to start this bit I didn't have a thing of the day ready.
Speaker 0: Good job I was sitting here and I was just about to hit record and I thought alright I need to find something amusing quickly.
Speaker 0: FARC will provide and came through in spades.
Speaker 0: the number one link on FARC as I'm speaking is Well there.
Speaker 0: first of all, it was a link to lyrics to Christmas carols, but not just any Christmas carols Cthulhu.
Speaker 0: Christmas carols Cthulhu photography In Playing the MP3.
Speaker 1: I mean we're talking Rudolph
Speaker 2: the red-nosed cultist
Speaker 0: Carol of the old ones.
Speaker 0: Oh come all ye deep ones, but they don't rhyme and meter the way.
Speaker 1: they should know They're close enough.
Speaker 1: I think you just.
Speaker 1: it's like they have a different syllable in mind and they don't Know.
Speaker 2: You think being blasted with them since Halloween would have kind of ingrained them in the gray matter.
Speaker 1: But no, yeah, but I mean they're cultists.
Speaker 0: They don't like listening to Christmas carols.
Speaker 1: These Christmas carols, you know We need we need a way to like an XML standard format where you can type in like sheet music And then a web browser that can render it so you can actually read it.
Speaker 1: That would be really useful.
Speaker 1: Software yeah But I'm talking like I can.
Speaker 1: anyone can write sheet music using an open standard format and then web browsers and things will render it Properly so that way you can make websites with music on them And if you're writing lyrics or something, then people could see oh, that's how you sing.
Speaker 0: That would be pretty except it's illegal to share lyrics.
Speaker 1: now only if they're real MPA lyrics You can share these if you made them up.
Speaker 2: Yeah I say if you make something up and you want to share I think it's something.
Speaker 2: go you.
Speaker 2: yeah.
Speaker 1: if someone made this Technology and made it work.
Speaker 1: I think what we'd see is a lot of people writing music or a lot of people like Distributing their songs that they wrote to get people to sing them and all kinds of stuff.
Speaker 1: That'd be real handy It would be.
Speaker 1: maybe we should do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz one.
Speaker 0: if it took off we'd be famous and rich - even if it only took off a little bit We get some freaking music for the podcast.
Speaker 1: Yeah, definitely All right.
Speaker 0: So, uh our main bit today.
Speaker 0: and we came up with this not too long ago and we came up with it because old lady's hair But shaving which may not sound like a geek topic but cat attacks.
Speaker 0: there's been a big movement among geeks lately.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of like life hackers and people and and people like us.
Speaker 0: Where we're going back to old-school shaving old-school shaving is where it's at.
Speaker 0: as in instead of spending You know a hundred dollars every couple months on like Mach 3 razor blades and using shaving cream that smells like deodorant We buy using you know a badger hair brush
Speaker 2: and Shaving foam
Speaker 0: and an actual like safety razor that you put a real razor blade into.
Speaker 1: yeah at first I thought the first thing that you got to worry about is are you gonna cut yourself?
Speaker 1: The answer is no.
Speaker 1: it's called a safety razor for a reason.
Speaker 0: Dangerous one is the straight razor.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the straight razor do not go for.
Speaker 1: I mean the straight razor.
Speaker 1: You could be all cool, but you have to learn to sharpen it with the strop and everything.
Speaker 2: Whim was like for a while.
Speaker 2: He was like, I want to buy a straight razor.
Speaker 2: I am gonna buy a straight razor and sharpen it with another thing.
Speaker 2: I'm like, no don't know.
Speaker 0: I thought it would be cool.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I thought it would be cool to your nose.
Speaker 1: Thank you, but then I realized the de razor is just as good.
Speaker 0: Well, plus I pictured myself doing it and I thought alright I can get my chin And I picture trying to shave my that over your jugular.
Speaker 2: doesn't that just send chills up your spine?
Speaker 0: I'm not a barber.
Speaker 1: a couple times I never cut myself with the safety razor.
Speaker 0: Well, I shave every day and I shave against the grain.
Speaker 1: Oh, I don't shave against the grain.
Speaker 0: pretty much go all out.
Speaker 2: Speaking of shaving.
Speaker 2: Let's go see the you know, the new Sweeney Todd Sweeney Tom.
Speaker 2: No, I've heard it's got really good reviews and I might be going with my pop.
Speaker 1: I don't know what you're talking about at all.
Speaker 2: Oh my god scary.
Speaker 1: It's a best musical to go see I mean What does that do with shaving?
Speaker 2: But oh it does.
Speaker 2: it's about a barber Oh people.
Speaker 2: and then they throw them down a chute and the lady downstairs makes them into mince pies and people eat them.
Speaker 1: Anyway Back to actually.
Speaker 0: But like it's we can't.
Speaker 0: I mean we thought there was some shill article a while ago.
Speaker 0: we saw yeah And it explained like there's this movement of people shaving with old technology because the old technology was actually better than the new Technology.
Speaker 0: the new shaving technology only exists to make money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I was like that makes sense.
Speaker 1: But this article seems like someone is really shilling out this website that sells old shaving stuff.
Speaker 0: So we did our own research and all signs pointed to yes Not only is it cheaper to save with a real old like 1950s style razor, but it's better.
Speaker 0: Yep It's better and cheaper.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I got one.
Speaker 1: it is better and it is cheaper.
Speaker 0: My shave is twice as close.
Speaker 0: I haven't cut myself like seriously in a long time.
Speaker 0: No more razor burn.
Speaker 1: Imagine if you could shave and it felt like just wiping a sponge on your face and then when you were done It felt like a baby's ass.
Speaker 0: Actually, no matter how close I shave I still have some stubble so that'd be well.
Speaker 1: It's visible like you see specks and like the first time I did it I was worried cuz they still saw black specks on my face.
Speaker 1: I was like, oh no, but then when I rub my hand on it, I was like, oh Yeah so that's why I'm glad I'm not a guy.
Speaker 2: cuz The daily shaving bit, you know, I'm not a huge fan of shaving.
Speaker 2: I do it merely for public appearances so I can wear short plaid skirt because I like the pad and And I like short skirts, yeah, no, I don't do it merely for you.
Speaker 2: I just like the fashion.
Speaker 2: but I You know winter is great cuz you know, you're never showing your legs a lot so you don't have to shave them a bunch.
Speaker 0: I mean if I went to work with like a baklava over my face Shave that wouldn't go over.
Speaker 1: so well Yeah, and I thought that people would get upset.
Speaker 1: cuz you know I kind of have to wear kind of work clothes and you know, I like.
Speaker 1: I only shave like once every three days.
Speaker 1: Maybe I don't really care at all.
Speaker 0: If I go one day without shaving.
Speaker 0: I have a beard Yeah, it's kind of annoying.
Speaker 2: Yeah The beard Yeah, it is fine.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the first thing you got to know about shaving the old-school way is what to buy.
Speaker 0: Yep, and basically You're all smart.
Speaker 0: Seriously.
Speaker 0: You just googles for like classic shaving to make you smell like a Nancy boy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I smell like a Nancy boy.
Speaker 0: I smell like roses and lavender.
Speaker 2: now You know, you go to Crabtree and Evelyn new Rockefeller Plaza, they have all the old-school shaving stuff, but it's expensive.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this isn't expensive if you buy it online.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We got.
Speaker 0: we got a couple websites that are really good for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we'll also link to the MS.
Speaker 1: We'll just link to the MSN article that had the real deals.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I'll just trust us.
Speaker 0: while this article might sound like someone was paid to write this stuff up.
Speaker 0: No, it we're serious.
Speaker 0: I shave with this stuff like constantly.
Speaker 1: So the first thing you need is a double edge razor.
Speaker 1: You probably want a safety razor.
Speaker 1: Don't you want to get a heavy one to the heavy one?
Speaker 1: You don't have to push as hard because the weight leans against your face and you're not gonna cut yourself.
Speaker 0: Yep, or your legs I mean women use these two.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: So anyway, you want to buy a double edge safety razor?
Speaker 1: It's not double edge.
Speaker 1: Like there are two blades like one on top of the other.
Speaker 1: It's one on one side and one on the other.
Speaker 1: so you can shave Flip it around shave some more and then rinse it off.
Speaker 1: Yep, and basically it means the blade lasts twice as long.
Speaker 0: now He said you want a heavy one and that's true very much because a light one You have to regulate the pressure with your hands.
Speaker 0: a heavy one You literally just hold it let it rest against your skin and then let it glide out duck across your face Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: and as for a beginner That's definitely what you want in life.
Speaker 1: You get a high amount of skill.
Speaker 1: you can get a slightly closer shave with the lighter razors and you know All kinds of different fancy ones with comb open combs closed combs all kinds of crazy things, but just don't worry about that.
Speaker 1: I Got the beginners razor and you know what?
Speaker 1: I'm probably never gonna buy anything better because it's good enough.
Speaker 2: Yeah Wow, it sounds comfortable sounds like you're not scraping hair.
Speaker 2: Yeah body.
Speaker 2: Yeah, you know, which is what I always think of shaving.
Speaker 2: It's like all time to scrape the hair off.
Speaker 0: Oh Plus, I mean they're high quality blades like you.
Speaker 0: take a Mach 3 which is like the most popular razor for men.
Speaker 0: You don't like one stroke with it and it's already dull.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean I want.
Speaker 1: I remember my bio teacher.
Speaker 1: He was teaching in 11th grade taught us about scanning electron microscopes and he had a picture of a razor, right?
Speaker 1: He said well, he didn't even tell us it was a razor.
Speaker 1: He's like what's that?
Speaker 1: And it's like you see this edge full of like these big pits and holes and jaggies, right?
Speaker 1: And you're like, huh?
Speaker 1: He's like that's a razor.
Speaker 1: We're like, wow, that's a pretty used razor.
Speaker 1: Then he shows us another one with bigger holes twice as many pits and like deadly jaggies.
Speaker 1: And he's like, that's the used one.
Speaker 1: The other one is brand new and I'm like, holy crap.
Speaker 1: Holy crap.
Speaker 0: Now those Mach 3 type blades.
Speaker 0: they cost a lot of money a lot of money.
Speaker 0: the blades you need for a safety razor It's about five cents a blade and they've got platinum in them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're platinum coated.
Speaker 0: So if you like platinum platinum is worth something man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and actually it's a lot.
Speaker 1: platinum is actually the real deal.
Speaker 1: it does something as opposed to the.
Speaker 1: What did they say?
Speaker 1: diamond coating crap?
Speaker 1: They yeah, that's not real.
Speaker 0: But the main difference is the blades are actually higher quality because there's just one of them and it's a real razor blade.
Speaker 0: So it won't go dull as quickly as whatever cartridge razors you might use.
Speaker 0: and to even better the blades are so cheap.
Speaker 0: I change blades like once or twice a week because it's just so cheap.
Speaker 0: I might as well use the sharpest blade I can.
Speaker 1: there are also people who seem to think that you know The cartridge razors will start out sharp get a little bit dull and then stay at that Dullness for a very long time and you can just keep using them.
Speaker 1: one guy even said he used them for a year.
Speaker 1: that's probably a bad idea because then you're what you're looking for.
Speaker 1: things like razor burn or Ingrown hairs or not a very close shave at all.
Speaker 1: Can't imagine it would be comfortable.
Speaker 1: The general rule for knowing when a razor is dull is if you shave and you feel it tugging on your hairs.
Speaker 0: time to change because if it tugs on the hair either it's gonna rip the hair out which hurts a lot or It's gonna pull the hair out cut it and the hair is gonna go back in and now you're real likely to get an ingrown hair.
Speaker 1: I got ingrown hairs with the You know the normal cartridge razors a lot.
Speaker 1: as soon as I switch to this, you know old-school shaving I haven't had an ingrown hair and freaking forever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's great Especially if you have sensitive skins.
Speaker 0: now the next big component I mean either razor.
Speaker 0: now you need a brush a shaving brush.
Speaker 1: The brush is the most important ingredient.
Speaker 1: You can.
Speaker 1: probably if you just use a brush your same shaving cream and everything you use now, but you use a brush It'll improve your shave Tenfold.
Speaker 0: now it can't be any.
Speaker 0: you don't want to get like just a brush you see in the store.
Speaker 0: You have to get a badger hair brush.
Speaker 0: That sounds stupid.
Speaker 0: We're not kidding.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the There are boars hair brushes.
Speaker 1: You can buy in CVS for five bucks.
Speaker 1: That's like sandpaper.
Speaker 1: that'll scratch your face up.
Speaker 0: It'll hurt like it really.
Speaker 0: it's a bad idea.
Speaker 0: The money you save is not worth it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a badger hair brush is expensive, but it's so soft and so nice.
Speaker 0: and oh Badgers are so soft.
Speaker 0: I want to pet badger.
Speaker 1: Yeah So vicious.
Speaker 2: it's like that's not a computer that's a rabid Wolverine.
Speaker 2: I was.
Speaker 2: I was reading that your penny arcade comic today and it brought tears and nostalgia to my eyes.
Speaker 2: Those are old strips, you know, you know, we had a published one.
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, I love penny arcade.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, so there are badger hair brushes that are like ultra super badger hair brushes made only of neck hair Because they say the neck hair of the badger is the most soft.
Speaker 1: You don't need that.
Speaker 0: That's just trying to get your money Because a brush like that they'll charge hundreds and hundreds of dollars.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it.
Speaker 1: Just don't go.
Speaker 1: it's unnecessary.
Speaker 0: even better I learned recently.
Speaker 0: I found out why the neck hair from the badger is so prized Because the ends of it are frayed which means the brush will retain more water in it Which we'll get to in a second.
Speaker 0: retaining water is key.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm If you have a normal badger hair brush over time the ends fray and it's the same as having a neck hair brush Mmm, so there's no reason to buy the neck hair brush.
Speaker 0: Just buy a normal brush and use it a lot and as it wears out it'll get better and a brush will last you years And years and years.
Speaker 1: so don't worry about buying it for like 40 bucks Because the money you save on the cheap razors compared to the cartridge will more than pay for that brush and the comfort of the shaving.
Speaker 1: I can't put a price on.
Speaker 0: yep As long as you take like let it dry out like don't just stick it in a closet or in a medicine cabinet where they get Moldy it'll last literally 10 20 years.
Speaker 0: Yep, like no exaggeration Most people buy one or two brushes in their entire life.
Speaker 1: Now the last thing you're gonna need is cream because the cream from the can really won't cut it with the brush.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and once you switch to a real shaving cream it Shaving is no longer this chore you do in the morning.
Speaker 0: It's this pleasant ritual.
Speaker 0: It feels good and it refreshes you Yep.
Speaker 1: Now the cream that we get comes in a little tub and you kind of when you we'll talk about technique next.
Speaker 1: but There's a. what's the brand?
Speaker 1: Something of London bond of Taylor of Old Bond.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: That's the brand that we get.
Speaker 0: It's very.
Speaker 0: I mean they talk about how it's like the mixture is handmade in London or somewhere in Britain and it's actually shipped here.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's actually not really that expensive and all it is it's glycerin and Fragrance.
Speaker 2: Yep Stuff in it, too Cuz I don't like aerosol cans.
Speaker 2: I think they're evil Mmm.
Speaker 1: Well, the tub is just as non-evil as the can.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just a nice little tube whatever and it smells really nice like it's.
Speaker 0: it's perfume, but it doesn't smell like perfume.
Speaker 0: It just smells good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and if you don't want perfume I got because I have really sensitive skin and stuff.
Speaker 1: I got the hypoallergenic one, which doesn't really have a like anything?
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's good because I don't want it to smell like anything.
Speaker 1: But if you do want to smell they have what rose?
Speaker 0: Yep, apparently the most popular among men who use this are rose and lavender But they have a whole bunch of different scents.
Speaker 2: Yep Apparently lavender is the really traditional one.
Speaker 2: Like my mom found out that you guys use like the fancy shaving cream and she thought that was pretty cool.
Speaker 2: Yeah, lavender is a traditional male scent.
Speaker 0: Actually.
Speaker 0: I've wanted lavender and both times I tried to order it It was sold out.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 0: Sorry I ended up with rose.
Speaker 1: There's places you can get it in New York probably seriously It's just hard to find these places because they don't advertise pretty loudly the internet.
Speaker 1: It's easy to find.
Speaker 1: Yeah So anyway now that you've got all your equipment you got to get the technique.
Speaker 0: Basically, you know with a Mach 3 or a shlick or whatever.
Speaker 0: Basically, it seems to be the harder you push and the harder you scrape yourself and the more repeatedly you scrape yourself The smoother the shave is.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's the exact opposite with a real razor Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: What you were gonna do is the first thing I know about shaving is that the water and The cream are there to lubricate your face so that the razor just slides across the skin.
Speaker 0: Water more than anything water is the most important part in this hot water as hot as you can get without burning yourself.
Speaker 0: Honestly, you want to stop up the sink and fill it with hot water and leave it full of hot water the whole time.
Speaker 1: You shave the hottest water that your sink can produce.
Speaker 0: if you didn't shower right before you actually want to dip a washcloth in The water and soak your face.
Speaker 0: Just hold the hot cloth against your face for a couple minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you don't when you heat up your face with the hot water The water helps to lubricate your face when you're gonna get the razor on there, but it also opens the pores so the hairs kind of come out and Then it'll.
Speaker 0: you'll get a much cleaner closer shave and it'll feel a lot better.
Speaker 1: Yep, next you want to put the brush in the water and make sure it absorbs a lot of water.
Speaker 0: Yep, usually while you're filling the bowl you just drop the brush in there and let it kind of float and fill up with water.
Speaker 1: Yep, and as soon as the brush is filled with water and you're ready to shave your face is nice and hot and wet.
Speaker 1: You take the brush and you kind of shush it around in the tub of cream But only do it a little bit because that cream lathers up like crazy.
Speaker 0: a little goes a long way is an understatement.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I freaking I don't even shush it.
Speaker 1: I used to shush it now.
Speaker 1: I just kind of dab it in there once like dab Like like literally just yep Then take the brush and go around your whole face going up and down and swirly swirly with the brush.
Speaker 0: Yep, and don't rush it.
Speaker 0: Enjoy it.
Speaker 0: I mean, it feels good feels really good and what I'll Fascinating.
Speaker 2: Yes.
Speaker 2: I didn't know how this worked either.
Speaker 1: Well, what happens is the brushing is to dual purpose.
Speaker 1: The first purpose is to get the cream covering all the hairs of your face.
Speaker 1: every place You're gonna shave should be covered in cream and it will lather up and cover it all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you'll probably get it in your nose in your mouth.
Speaker 0: Don't worry.
Speaker 0: It can't hurt you.
Speaker 0: It's not like the stuff you buy in an aerosol can and it doesn't taste bad.
Speaker 1: I try to avoid the nose and mouth and I've gotten pretty good at it.
Speaker 2: Yeah What was that kind of shaving cream you used to use before like the the stuff?
Speaker 2: No, it smells like like roses smells real nice.
Speaker 2: The other stuff.
Speaker 0: It was like like the man I used to use like gold spice or something and I haven't worn it recently, but for most of my life I use Stetson.
Speaker 0: I wear Stetson cologne.
Speaker 0: I use Stetson aftershave.
Speaker 2: I cover the inside of the shower Stetson cuz you left it there Like.
Speaker 0: oh, yeah, you used up all my freaking shaving cream.
Speaker 0: It was fun.
Speaker 0: I was like I'm drawing in the walls.
Speaker 0: This is great.
Speaker 2: I called him on the phone and be like I Used all the stuff you left at my house, which was great.
Speaker 0: when I try it wanted to shave and I didn't.
Speaker 1: And then the.
Speaker 1: the second purpose of the brush is that the brush will actually grab the hairs and pull them out a little bit More.
Speaker 1: so you have a hot wet creamy face and you have this brush Pulling the hairs as far out of the pores as they can go without being pulled out of your face.
Speaker 0: Yep, but it doesn't pull them out so far that you'll get an ingrown hair like you do with like the mock three.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you won't feel the hairs being pulled out of your face.
Speaker 1: But no they are being pulled.
Speaker 0: So yeah, and then you just take the razor and it's really hard to hurt yourself.
Speaker 0: Just you know, don't be dumb never slide it sideways.
Speaker 0: Always slide it down.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: If you slide it sideways You're pretty much gonna cut yourself.
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: Now if you're worried about cutting yourself, or if you use an open comb Which basically just means you'll get a closer shave, but it's more dangerous By a styptic pen they're like two bucks and if you cut yourself you just poke you dab it once with this pen and it'll Stop bleeding.
Speaker 1: Yep I've never had really had a need because I'd never had like, you know a gusher.
Speaker 1: Maybe if I had like a little bump on my face from something it would get cut but it would just go away right away.
Speaker 0: Yep, I've cut myself once or twice but they were miners usually because I was trying to get a real close shave for some reason.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you get like a serious cut then you did something wrong.
Speaker 2: I'm just thinking both both my uncles Dave and John.
Speaker 2: they both shaved their heads, you know It's like as soon as they started to go bald.
Speaker 2: They're like, I'm shaving my head.
Speaker 2: they're both really cool the ones from Chicago ones from San Francisco and Uncle John was just I was remembering him talking about shaving his head.
Speaker 2: It's like, you know, that's the stupidest thing.
Speaker 2: you're walking around with toilet paper stuck to your dome.
Speaker 2: That's So, you know, it's like that that styptic pen is is probably Probably a boon if you don't want to look like an idiot.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, though.
Speaker 0: We don't want to scare you You probably won't need one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're like you're.
Speaker 0: it's really hard to hurt yourself with these things.
Speaker 1: I haven't cut myself seriously at all.
Speaker 1: It's not a straight razor It's a double-edged razor and when you see it, you'll know what we're talking about.
Speaker 1: So all I do is I just lean it against my face the razor Drag it down until you know, it's kind of like alright That's about as much as I can shave in one stroke I Take it I flip it around to the other side where the other razor is and I do the equal amount of shaving on the other side Of my face.
Speaker 0: the more hair you have or the thicker it is the shorter more more frequent rinsing you want to do.
Speaker 0: Yeah short strokes rinse often.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Keep that razor clean Keep it to keep your face hot and wet everything hot and keep everything wet and most importantly the first time you shave You go with the grain all the way around.
Speaker 0: Then you can stop there if you want.
Speaker 0: if you want a really close shave do it again going against the grain.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's the way that's more dangerous.
Speaker 0: You'll probably cut yourself before you learn how to do it, but the shave is incredible.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you shave up you shave your whole face down then start from the beginning and shave your whole face up You're.
Speaker 0: you won't probably won't even see little specks Like I do it maybe once a month like I do it before a special occasion like a fancy dinner I'm gonna see someone because it's it's kind of tough to do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do it and I can get away with it But sometimes I get a little bit of razor burn under the chin or some ingrown hairs.
Speaker 1: So I only do it if there's something like right today.
Speaker 1: that's important because the next day my face will be all in.
Speaker 1: Yep, and That's the best way to shave.
Speaker 0: I mean like we're not plugging a product here.
Speaker 0: We don't you know how we hate advertising, but this is really method not a product.
Speaker 2: Yes.
Speaker 2: It's like yes It's like.
Speaker 2: this is the best way to sweep your floor.
Speaker 2: This is the best way to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we're gonna link blueberry muffins.
Speaker 0: that like sells this stuff, but that's just cuz.
Speaker 0: that's the site We happen to buy it from.
Speaker 1: yeah, if you don't like that site go to some other site.
Speaker 1: You know buy a different brand of razor.
Speaker 1: Just don't buy a cheap one.
Speaker 1: Make sure that your razor is heavy and metal.
Speaker 0: Make expect to spend about a hundred bucks total But that includes a razor that'll last forever a brush that'll last forever a pile of blades and a nice thing of cream.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you can make I still haven't.
Speaker 1: I got my first tub of cream.
Speaker 1: When did we buy that first tub of cream?
Speaker 0: Oh almost a year ago, really?
Speaker 1: We were living here.
Speaker 1: Maybe six months ago.
Speaker 0: It was right after we moved here.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I still it's got.
Speaker 1: it doesn't even look half empty.
Speaker 0: I've gone through a tub and a half already, but I shave every day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I see I bought ten blades.
Speaker 1: I still haven't used them all.
Speaker 0: I've gone through about 40 blades But I have a very thick beard.
Speaker 1: Yeah now you can buy the blades that are like fancy and platinum on the internet And they're pretty cheap.
Speaker 1: They're like maybe five bucks or something But if you're kind of cheap, you can get them at the grocery store and they're not as good as the platinum ones But they're almost as good.
Speaker 2: or you can pick them up at the.
Speaker 2: you know The post-production center at NYU.
Speaker 2: they they provide you with a tray of razor blades.
Speaker 2: when you start your semester of sight and sound film Cuz you act well.
Speaker 2: Yeah, I was like This.
Speaker 2: there's this class you get to take your sophomore year and you actually get to deal with like a positive film Strip, you know like a actual.
Speaker 2: And so you're cutting with a razor and you're splicing and it's very nice You know, it's a very tangible approach to media and it is really kind of cool.
Speaker 2: You know This is before you move into all the digital forms of editing and so you're working in the little tiny Steenbeck room with this cleaning solution that makes you feel really weird and really like.
Speaker 2: you've got to keep Ventilation and they provide you all these razors.
Speaker 2: and so I'm like.
Speaker 2: you sent me to college to get high and play with razors.
Speaker 1: How do you paste the film together after you cut it?
Speaker 1: it's Tape.
Speaker 2: oh, it's like you make a splice with a razor blade and then there's this tape with perforations that match the.
Speaker 1: So if you mess up you can just tape it back together.
Speaker 2: Yeah, but you know, you got to be careful where your place.
Speaker 2: cuz every time you splice you can kind of see the tape.
Speaker 2: Yeah, it goes by so fast that it's not really obvious.
Speaker 2: But a lot of splices don't look - yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got you Huh?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: Yeah This went on a lot longer than we expected which is awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, especially since we did a short crap show yesterday We promised we'd make up for it.
Speaker 0: We did so.
Speaker 2: I felt kind of like the third wheel like I. they've got a dynamic going and I'm not sure what I'm supposed to Interject, you know, I'm kind of sitting here like and when they talked about saving I'm like, this is a world I've never entered into.
Speaker 2: you know, I've got to talk about something they can't can't relate to.
Speaker 2: that's cool I can have my keep in mind.
Speaker 0: I mean for all you listen and for you, this was very much like an experiment.
Speaker 0: We weren't sure how we would deal with having someone who wasn't one of us on the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so this whole episode is kind of an experiment.
Speaker 0: I like the way it turned out turned out.
Speaker 0: All right, we're learning.
Speaker 0: I mean, it's hard like if you said in yesterday's episode like I face away from everyone else in the room so I can't see if other people are like signaling me sometimes and We it's kind of hard for us to communicate.
Speaker 0: sub channel where you guys can't hear while we're talking.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should get the DS's and the picto check going on or something.
Speaker 0: I really good idea Yeah, but well enough for the meta bits.
Speaker 1: Visit our website damn it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we see you all listening.
Speaker 0: We can see your downloads and there are far fewer people on the forums than there are listening.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so front row crew.com Forums.
Speaker 0: And that was geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Thanks for listening.
Speaker 1: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds feed burner comm slash geek nights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Speaker 1: also, please visit our website at www.front row crew.com for the latest updates and forum discussion.
Speaker 1: and whether you love or hate our podcast We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at geek nights at gmail.com.