Speaker 1: It's Wednesday November 9th.
Speaker 1: This is deep nights.
Speaker 1: It's anime night, but I want my parents house It's my mom's birthday, and I'm getting a free dinner.
Speaker 1: so uh say yeah Let's not do this.
Speaker 0: What?
Speaker 0: uh yeah, you're not here.
Speaker 0: Are you nope?
Speaker 1: I'm in Connecticut Oh mom's birthday, and I'm at a restaurant eating.
Speaker 1: Oh great So um I didn't think he'd be in the news again.
Speaker 1: who Lawrence Olivier Jack Thompson Jack Thompson Jack Thompson Jack Thompson.
Speaker 1: So you know he's doing that.
Speaker 1: he's doing that wrongful death case against rockstar games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, I think it's the kid who killed the cops or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and he's saying that the kid did it because of Grand Theft Auto.
Speaker 1: right trained him to do it whatever right.
Speaker 1: so the suit is in Alabama and basically for the past week Jack Thompson hasn't been actually doing the case.
Speaker 1: well it's been part of the case, but he's been defending his ethical conduct to the judge and The judge actually Considered a motion to disbar Jack Thompson in Alabama.
Speaker 1: Well, and he's even considered that he would throw the case out.
Speaker 1: So Jack Thompson said well to save the case.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna quit the case and some other lawyer can do it.
Speaker 1: Really that doesn't help the case at all.
Speaker 1: well I guess it does help the case cuz Jack Thompson's not on it, but it's mostly to save face.
Speaker 1: But he's saying oh, it's for the case.
Speaker 0: Yeah as opposed to oh, I'm a crazy fuck and People called me on it this time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think he's gonna be um Winning any cases ever again unless he you know does some real law.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah Except the only thing he really has going now is this video game thing.
Speaker 1: Well cuz he used to be all about movies and comics and all you know anything that was bad for kids.
Speaker 1: But lately he just concentrates in the video games.
Speaker 1: cuz he has this idea that they're somehow different.
Speaker 0: You know I don't think he realized what kind of a hornet's nest he was provoking when he went after video games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know But I can kind of see where he's coming from.
Speaker 1: sometimes cuz he says stuff like all those video game guys from you know Hollywood.
Speaker 1: they're all paying off the government, and we're always complaining like oh those record company guys.
Speaker 1: He feels the same way we feel, but he's wrong in this case.
Speaker 0: yeah, even though those things may or may not be happening I don't see it happening so much because it's not like the government tries to regulate video games so often.
Speaker 1: Now it doesn't.
Speaker 1: but that's the thing is like.
Speaker 1: he's saying that the only reason they're not regulating video games is because the video game Companies they're making
Speaker 0: you know not because there's more important issues like drugs, or I don't know terror wars Budgets welfare Disease poverty Gary mandarin Every real problem in the world that isn't a video game.
Speaker 1: yeah, yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I never liked that.
Speaker 1: there's a worst thing argument.
Speaker 1: You know because there really isn't that much worse than Jack Thompson Jack Thompson Jack Thompson.
Speaker 0: So remember the other day when those pirates attacked that cruise ship.
Speaker 0: It turned into geek because apparently The news is reporting now that part of the reason they got away is because they use this LRAD or long-range acoustic device to scare the pirates off.
Speaker 1: Why do they have one?
Speaker 0: It's like actually because there's a law an international treaty stating that you can't have heavy weapons on ships at sea unless there were ships.
Speaker 0: So a cruise ship can't have like an anti-aircraft gun there to mow down anyone.
Speaker 0: It can't have a reason in case some pirates come so They can't have real weapons.
Speaker 0: They gotta have fake weapons, so they have these non-lethal things that don't count as weapons like LRAD.
Speaker 0: Oh, all right, and it's just don't like.
Speaker 1: doesn't the crew have like you know handheld weapons or something?
Speaker 0: those aren't so useful against pirates.
Speaker 1: No, like you know pistol machine gun something those.
Speaker 0: well They can't really have machine guns.
Speaker 0: some of them do But they don't really help because the pirates stay way back and shoot rocket-propelled grenades at you.
Speaker 1: ah Yeah
Speaker 0: Apparently all these devices do is they're big disk looking things and they point them at someone and when they hit the button it Directs a very focused beam of sound like you could be standing next to this thing in front of it And you won't hear a thing walk in front of it.
Speaker 0: It'll knock you unconscious and do permanent hearing damage.
Speaker 1: Great is there a warning sign?
Speaker 0: Don't know.
Speaker 0: actually the military has been using them in Baghdad to control rioters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I heard something about that.
Speaker 1: Does it work?
Speaker 0: it works real?
Speaker 0: Well it causes people to fall over and scream in horrible pain and vomit.
Speaker 0: it Supposedly sounds like a smoke alarm and it'll be about up to a hundred and fifty decibels in your ear.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, that's more than the space shuttle launching at some distance.
Speaker 0: Yeah
Speaker 1: I heard a thing on NPR about these a while back, but they were talking about him in Shortly after the hurricanes in Louisiana and I think they were demoing them like just outside or they were using them there to get looters and stuff
Speaker 0: uh-huh,
Speaker 1: but the one specific one they talked about was slightly Different because what they were doing is they were shooting it really far.
Speaker 1: They're talking like like miles away even you know if not like thousands of feet Yeah, and they weren't sending noise to knock you out even though they could.
Speaker 1: they were sending like Like messages.
Speaker 1: it's like if you what they were talking about was like if a guy's on a roof.
Speaker 1: you could be in the helicopter and you Could pretty much shoot a laser of sound at him saying You know we're coming to get you and it would sound like you were right next to him talking.
Speaker 1: So no one has to yell.
Speaker 1: No one has to use a megaphone.
Speaker 1: No it.
Speaker 0: I think it's similar because this one it says the effective range of damaging or stopping people is about 500 meters.
Speaker 0: I imagine you can still hear it.
Speaker 0: beyond that it just doesn't hurt you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they were talking about you know.
Speaker 1: let's say you know there's someone way out, and you're an army.
Speaker 1: you could be like.
Speaker 1: you know halt who goes there and such and You know you would be able to give them fair warning and all the or you could pull some wicked pranks on people.
Speaker 1: You could totally pull some wicked pranks.
Speaker 1: We should get one.
Speaker 0: I wonder how to be to make one.
Speaker 1: I Don't know if it's a makeable thing.
Speaker 0: Well, everything's makeable.
Speaker 0: It's just a matter of our resources.
Speaker 1: I don't think RadioShack's got enough.
Speaker 0: nah Yeah, apparently they've used these things in Baghdad.
Speaker 0: They used them in New York City during the 2004 Republican National Convention.
Speaker 1: really I didn't hear about that.
Speaker 0: I think they just demoed them.
Speaker 1: oh Yeah, it seems like they've done a lot of demos in dangerous situations, but I you know the actual use hasn't been Prominent enough for people to make a big thing about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it's.
Speaker 0: It's good and bad.
Speaker 0: I mean on one hand.
Speaker 0: It's a good idea because Non-lethal is always good.
Speaker 0: It doesn't kill people.
Speaker 0: you always give someone a second chance, but on the other hand I think law enforcement will be more readily Predisposed to using things like this if they know that it won't kill anyone.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 1: That's always the Story with any sort of non-lethal weapon.
Speaker 1: I mean just today.
Speaker 1: I read a story about these less dangerous cigarettes right and Every and the one smart guy who commented on it was like no even if they're a zillion times safer Which I guess they kind of were.
Speaker 1: they have like these new filters that only let nicotine through and stuff right?
Speaker 1: He's like back in the 70s and they added filters and stuff and they took out all the tar.
Speaker 1: People just started smoking more and taking longer drags, and it didn't actually make it any safer You know yeah, so it's like all right.
Speaker 1: if you make stuff less potent people do it more And it's always the same potency.
Speaker 1: So if you have a non-lethal You know sound gun There'll be more apt to use it And they'll use it like ten times on the same guy And then he'll die like we've seen with tasers lately.
Speaker 0: Oh every day in the news someone gets tasered like a little girl or old lady or a dog.
Speaker 0: Though actually the tasers?
Speaker 0: now There's two cool things that are come out New tasers that the police use.
Speaker 0: take a picture when you fire them that can't be removed of what you're firing at.
Speaker 0: So if you just taser someone ten times There's gonna be a picture of the guy on the ground obviously unconscious as you're about to taser him again.
Speaker 1: No, so it'll store all the pictures.
Speaker 0: Yes, whoo.
Speaker 0: There's another one.
Speaker 1: Can you cover the picture with like your finger or something?
Speaker 0: I don't think they're allowed to.
Speaker 0: They'd be kind of suspect if you taser two guy five times and magically the last three pictures your finger was in the way.
Speaker 0: And the other thing to protect civilians from like because a lot of muggers apparently use these things to get someone.
Speaker 0: just take their wallet.
Speaker 0: They've got some that have these Thousands of tiny pieces of confetti with serial numbers on them and when you fire it It shoots the taser and it's it just pops these things out with a co2 cartridge everywhere.
Speaker 1: So then if the police come they find the serial number.
Speaker 1: they find out who you were.
Speaker 0: they can at least track where the taser came From.
Speaker 1: it's pretty good.
Speaker 1: I have bullets that do that.
Speaker 0: They're trying there's.
Speaker 0: there's been an effort for the last couple decades to have some sort of registry of fingerprinted bullets.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean they can do it with what do they call it?
Speaker 1: with the The where they match the bullet by Matt, you know, cuz the bullets from the same gun are all ballistics.
Speaker 1: Yep ballistic Such as I knew is a B. But you know, they should just put a serial number on every bullet.
Speaker 0: Well, then where I do is all I have to do is file it off my bullet Put it in the bullet.
Speaker 0: where in the bullet in on the backseat is the bullet You mean in the shell casing that I'll take with me?
Speaker 1: no, no, no, no.
Speaker 1: There's the bullet and there's the shell casing and then there's a gun powder.
Speaker 0: I want to put it on the bullet.
Speaker 1: put it on the bottom of the bullet that's covered by the shell.
Speaker 0: The only problem with that is that bullets get really really deformed when they hit you.
Speaker 1: they do but the back of it You see the part that that's you know, that I guess the explosion the gunpowder might take it off.
Speaker 1: It's a tough one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people are working on it But the taser one is a nice very practical very elegant solution to a real problem.
Speaker 1: Yeah, very good.
Speaker 0: I'm very happy.
Speaker 0: whatever people use science instead of legislation to solve something.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Though there is one other cool thing about these all our ads.
Speaker 0: apparently there are a lot of non weapon uses.
Speaker 0: They're starting to use them in concerts and in stadiums to project sound to people who are far away Without having to have it so loud that it kills people in the front.
Speaker 1: That's pretty good.
Speaker 1: You know what else at the concerts where they could do is you know how?
Speaker 1: um You'll be at a show and like the guy who's doing the show will try to talk to someone in the audience Specific and they won't hear him or vice versa.
Speaker 1: Yeah You could just go around to like a microphone and an l-rad Right and the person on stage could like point the l-rad at a person in the audience and be like hey you Something something something, you know, and then that person could be like something something You know, I could be pretty cool get a whole new level of Interaction going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd like to see the next five years as this technology gets developed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, hopefully it'll be cheaper.
Speaker 1: So like people can buy them and use them and play horrible pranks play horrible pranks is good You know, you can call for pizza with it.
Speaker 0: Well a blockbuster video isn't doing so well.
Speaker 0: they've lost millions and millions 500 million in the last couple months and They're probably gonna go bankrupt because it looks like all their investors and all their lenders are starting to recall all their loans.
Speaker 1: Blockbuster had five hundred million dollars.
Speaker 0: blockbuster makes approximately four point three three billion dollars a year.
Speaker 0: Wow, the apparently the entire rental industry is collapsing.
Speaker 0: I wonder why internet Netflix TiVo.
Speaker 0: But uh Blockbusters collapsing slower and yeah on demand.
Speaker 0: My blockbuster is doing the best of all of them.
Speaker 0: It's only collapsing half as fast as everyone else.
Speaker 0: But the thing is they're not blaming Netflix they're not blaming the internet.
Speaker 0: No, they're.
Speaker 0: I don't think they have any idea why they're losing their business.
Speaker 0: they're talking about how the revenues are only down because they got rid of their late fees and They're blaming like the economy's kind of down.
Speaker 0: so people aren't renting videos like they used to what.
Speaker 1: yeah, you know This reminds me.
Speaker 1: they just have no idea.
Speaker 1: This reminds me back in the day like in the in the dot-com boom like in like 90 Like it's 97 98.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was a guy and he it was in the Silicon Alley which is you know, the Silicon Valley in New York, whatever kind of mag trade magazine, right and This is the most dot-com boom you could get.
Speaker 1: I mean this magazine was this free thing I got because I lied about being an industry insider and There's this article about which companies are doing good on the internet and which companies are doing bad.
Speaker 1: All right, and they talked about these companies doing great things like oh look at the website for this company You can do all these innovative stuff.
Speaker 1: and then the number one worst company was blockbuster.
Speaker 1: Because blockbuster they were like look at what blockbuster could be doing on the internet.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: searching for videos checking which videos are in stock and which stores checking your late fees Getting registrations.
Speaker 1: finding store locations.
Speaker 1: And in those days the blockbuster website was pretty much like this static page with company info.
Speaker 1: and they had a website Barely and that was what the guy was saying.
Speaker 1: is that blockbuster was just so behind the times?
Speaker 1: You know internet wise and I guess it hasn't changed.
Speaker 1: they haven't fired their.
Speaker 1: it's like oh I can't understand.
Speaker 0: Yeah, even the article is like blockbusters facing tough competition from Netflix blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Walmart Blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Walmart with their cheap DVD sale.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're real cheap TV, but they're very poor selection.
Speaker 0: Yes But blockbusters even trying to spin this in a good light.
Speaker 0: They're saying things like This just means we're we're consolidating the markets consolidating and We're gaining market share because all the mom and pops are going out of business and the only ones left are blocking.
Speaker 1: But the mom pops had a business 15 20 years now, there's still some mom and pops about.
Speaker 1: there's still some but those are usually video bars that carry stuff that Blockbuster won't care.
Speaker 0: and summers in the Midwest mammoth video still around.
Speaker 1: I never heard of that.
Speaker 0: Mammoth video was.
Speaker 0: I had never heard a blockbuster.
Speaker 0: when I was a little kid We had mammoth video and there were a bunch of them all over the Hollywood video.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they have like they've been around they're still around but they're not doing so well No, I'm not doing well at all.
Speaker 1: But I heard in my town.
Speaker 1: It was like there weren't any chain video stores.
Speaker 1: yet There was just this one video place.
Speaker 1: It was kind of small but they had you know all the major movies and that was it You know and people would go there.
Speaker 1: and it was like some people would do it and some people wouldn't.
Speaker 1: kind of like today Some people have TiVo some people don't.
Speaker 1: yeah, you know, it's like you were either in on renting or you weren't God?
Speaker 0: I remember going where there were only two stores one had beta and one had VHS.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow He didn't have a beta store.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then this blockbuster opened and it was a little far away from the house like 15 minutes away, but it was huge and we were went to.
Speaker 1: the grand opening is one of the first blockbusters and Everyone got a blockbuster membership Absolutely everyone.
Speaker 1: and then they started opening up everywhere.
Speaker 1: But then as soon as more of them opened they became a lot less spectacular And people didn't care about them as much and we started renting less, you know, you didn't.
Speaker 0: you know When the NES kind of went away, you know, really God I rented more NES games from blockbusters than I did movies and anything else.
Speaker 1: Yeah game renting kind of went away.
Speaker 1: cuz you know No one wanted to rent really Sega Genesis SNES games so much.
Speaker 0: and then when the ps1 came out people started copying those.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we all right.
Speaker 1: I remember ps1.
Speaker 1: We go you rent we burn we go back.
Speaker 1: All right, we burn we go back.
Speaker 0: I don't know what it is with the the plebeians out there who rent videos But how come every DVD and blockbuster was scratched to hell?
Speaker 0: What do they do?
Speaker 1: Well, it's cuz.
Speaker 1: people just don't know that a DVD is a scratchable things.
Speaker 1: you you can't make something That's.
Speaker 1: how can you not know that?
Speaker 1: and the other thing is that they don't know how it works.
Speaker 1: They don't know that the laser that actually looks at the disc and if it's crashed It'll see it differently.
Speaker 0: but think with cartridges and like a cartridge would last forever.
Speaker 0: So you could rent cartridges to people.
Speaker 0: just fine Pls1 discs.
Speaker 0: rent it to five fanboys and it's done.
Speaker 1: The other thing is though is that people want it to be that way.
Speaker 1: not people but the record companies will and the movie companies That way.
Speaker 1: if you scratch it you say my DVD stopped working.
Speaker 1: nine out of ten idiots go and buy it again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or they'll buy a special edition where Someone other than Han Solo shoots first.
Speaker 0: God Yeah for posterity, you know what Han Solo shot first.
Speaker 0: I don't care what you see I don't care what back into the hand.
Speaker 1: solo shot first and not only did he shoot first Greedo I don't think he shot at all.
Speaker 0: No Greedo wasn't even gonna shoot.
Speaker 0: He just had his gun out.
Speaker 1: Yeah to be all menacing.
Speaker 0: Well moving on to the main bit.
Speaker 0: It's anime night.
Speaker 0: And since I've run out of previously recorded clips involving Scott I'm gonna have to do the rest of the show on my own since as you are well aware Him and his wonderful banter aren't here to help me.
Speaker 0: Thus sadly, there's only one thing of the day today.
Speaker 0: And my thing of the day is fairly cool.
Speaker 0: It's not anything particularly new.
Speaker 0: I'm sure people have seen it before but for anyone who hasn't?
Speaker 0: I Stumbled across a small archive of Lego figures, but not just any Lego figures.
Speaker 0: These are Lego representations of Cthulhu himself.
Speaker 0: now There's not much more I can actually really say about them considering that Cthulhu is one of those formless Indescribable terrors that cause nothing but insanity and all to see them.
Speaker 0: But uh, if you're interested check out the link.
Speaker 0: But anyway regarding anime, I haven't started watching anything new though I'm still watching mushishi which as far as I'm concerned is really the best show out there currently.
Speaker 0: but we just got a DVD one of big O in the house again and It's old.
Speaker 0: It's campy.
Speaker 0: It's over the top.
Speaker 0: But you know what?
Speaker 0: I love it.
Speaker 0: And for any of you haven't seen big O It's Probably one of the stupidest sounding shows you will ever hear about.
Speaker 0: There's a big robot called big O and it fights other big robots and there's lots and lots of collateral damage.
Speaker 0: That's really it but it's a great show.
Speaker 0: I mean the best thing about it wasn't so much the show itself But the context of watching it because when I first saw it I saw it with a crowd of people at an anime club and if this show is anything it's a crowd-pleaser.
Speaker 0: Now I've seen the whole show before already and the only reason I'm watching it again is because it's been a while and I actually never saw the sequel big O - and neither is Scott.
Speaker 0: So we're gonna watch all the big O one because Face it.
Speaker 0: It's an awesome show.
Speaker 0: It's giant robots punching other giant robots in the face And then we're gonna watch big O - which everyone we've known who's seen it said is really good.
Speaker 0: But we just never got around to watching it and I got to say as much as I complain about being out of college.
Speaker 0: One of the big benefits of being out here in the working world is that I actually have a chance to just sit down and Watch all that anime.
Speaker 0: I missed while I was too busy running anime clubs back in the day And actually even better than the anime itself.
Speaker 0: now I actually have enough money, you know since I have a job to afford to go to events like Otacon or anime central without having to rely on the sympathy of others for basic necessities like food.
Speaker 0: Now I've been watching anime for a long time and I've been going to anime conventions for a long time And I figured since Scott's not here and I like the sound of my own voice.
Speaker 0: I'll just kind of give you guys a background as to how I got into this thing and why I love it so much and why to this day I'm still very deeply immersed in the Subculture that is anime.
Speaker 0: So the year was well, I actually don't know what year it was but I was in fourth grade back when I was still living in Detroit and I happened to catch Vampire hunter D on the sci-fi channel and at the time I wasn't really sure what it was.
Speaker 0: all I knew was that I liked it and I wanted to see more and the sci-fi channel luckily obliged me right after that.
Speaker 0: they showed a robot carnival and then Dominion tank police and then project echo and Then kashan robot hunter and then like three or four other shows.
Speaker 0: now I should probably note at this time that kashan robot hunter is one of the worst anime ever.
Speaker 0: So don't even think about watching it if you've never heard of it.
Speaker 0: the world has done you a favor.
Speaker 0: so as the years went on I picked up and started watching all the anime I could find and I saw almost all the anime I could get as a result.
Speaker 0: I remember watching eska flown a as it came out every month.
Speaker 0: We'd buy the next VHS tape watch it and then Furiously wait for the next one now at this point.
Speaker 0: I really liked anime In fact, I loved it But I had no idea that there was actually this sort of subculture connected to it.
Speaker 0: I didn't know about fansubbers.
Speaker 0: I Didn't know about conventions.
Speaker 0: I had no idea.
Speaker 0: I didn't know that there was anything to it other than watching this anime.
Speaker 0: Then I got to RIT and I walked into the RIT anime club's first yearly recruitment meeting and I saw this auditorium Absolutely filled with geeks.
Speaker 0: It was then that I knew that I was home So I made a bunch of friends in the club and Then not too long after I went to my first anime convention, which was actually Ohio con.
Speaker 0: It wasn't the greatest convention.
Speaker 0: In fact, it was pretty piss poor.
Speaker 0: I've heard that Ohio con is much better now, but back then let me tell you they didn't check badges.
Speaker 0: There wasn't much going on.
Speaker 0: There were prostitutes at the hotel.
Speaker 0: That's a story for another time, but they were there.
Speaker 0: Ohio con did have one cool thing going for it though.
Speaker 0: They had an old-school Original NES duck hunt tournament and they're having trouble getting people to sign up But me and my Scott and a bunch of other people we knew We're all in the room and they all told us hey join the tournament You don't even have to pay just join because they needed bodies.
Speaker 0: so whatever.
Speaker 0: and they have this.
Speaker 0: they have the duck hunt card for the gun as fully extended as it can be in this tiny little TV and The first guy goes up and he misses a bunch of ducks.
Speaker 0: and then the next guy goes up and he misses a bunch of ducks.
Speaker 0: And we're thinking to ourselves.
Speaker 0: Uh, oh, this may be hard.
Speaker 0: I mean I have the duck hunt skills, but Maybe the maximum distance factor is making it too difficult.
Speaker 0: so then I get up there and I hit every duck and Then Scott goes up and he also hits every duck.
Speaker 0: and then our friend Katsu goes up and he hits every duck.
Speaker 0: So people are getting eliminated and eventually it comes to the point that there is no way to eliminate any of us With ducks because we hit every duck no matter what we hit every skeet no matter what there's.
Speaker 0: just it's gonna go on forever Until one of us passes out.
Speaker 0: So they decide to in the spirit of old school Have the final championship be determined by the original Mario Brothers.
Speaker 0: so Scott and I sit down and we're fighting for first and second place and They just we started going at it and they didn't really tell us what the objective was.
Speaker 0: So we're playing and I turned to the guy who's running and I asked him so, uh What do we have to do?
Speaker 0: He says whoever gets the most points wins.
Speaker 0: So then I asked can I kill Scott's guy?
Speaker 0: and the guy responds?
Speaker 0: Uh If you kill him, he can't get any more points now, can he?
Speaker 0: and I immediately pushed Scott into a green fireball And I won first place Scott won second place Katsu won third place and That is the only good story.
Speaker 0: I have out of Ohio con other than the prostitutes.
Speaker 0: So Ohio con was okay, but it wasn't great.
Speaker 0: then we discovered Otakon and I cannot express to you unless you have been there the sheer magnitude of the geekery that goes on at Otakon.
Speaker 0: That I mean, it's an anime convention, but every aspect of geekery is represented there in quantity.
Speaker 0: in fact.
Speaker 0: We've been to every Otakon since that first one we went to and we plan to go to every Otakon pretty much until we die.
Speaker 0: So, I mean I still watch anime and I love anime but like when I go to these conventions like Otakon.
Speaker 0: I don't watch a single frame of anime while I'm there.
Speaker 0: I Pretty much just go to hang out with all the cool people I've met as a result of anime and That's really the main reason why anime is still such a big part of my life.
Speaker 0: It's not the anime itself because I could just watch that alone in my house if I really wanted.
Speaker 0: it's that community of a lot of people who like this very geeky thing and Like it together and have a sort of shared culture.
Speaker 0: I mean I share more culturally with all the people at Otakon than I do with the people who actually live next door to me.
Speaker 0: Now I don't have much more to really say on this topic without some sort of witty interactive banter with Scott.
Speaker 0: So I guess I'll leave you with My Grimms top 10 anime that I really like Which is actually hard to do because I guess I separate anime I like from anime that I think are good.
Speaker 0: I mean if someone asked me to name the top five anime or the five anime I think are the best Hands-down, it would be Cowboy Bebop Evangelion Escaflowne, Trigun, and Fullmetal Alchemist with nods to things like Lain And a lot of people tend to agree on that point.
Speaker 0: a lot of people disagree about the order But a lot of people agree that those are very very good shows.
Speaker 0: But if you ask me what my favorite anime are they would be Irresponsible.
Speaker 0: Captain Tyler and Shoujo Kakamei Utena, which I won't pretend that they're the best shows in the world, but I like them.
Speaker 0: Now to get a little bit meta.
Speaker 0: It's interesting because I've never actually tried to do this sort of podcast thing by myself and I didn't realize how difficult it is to just sit in front of a microphone with no audience.
Speaker 0: No feedback whatsoever absolutely no idea of how what I'm saying sounds or how interesting it actually is and To just sit here and rant for a while.
Speaker 0: I mean, I love the sound of my own voice But I only love the sound of my own voice when I know that other people are listening to it.
Speaker 0: And while I know people are listening to this now, I can't see you now.
Speaker 0: I can't see you roll your eyes So I'll realize that a joke I made is bad or I can't see Scott Doing his Scott things and it.
Speaker 0: it's actually really hard to do this by myself and I remember Scott said a while ago when he tried to do something like this a long time ago that he had a similar problem and Now I see where he was coming from.
Speaker 0: it's hard to Do a monologue without any feedback.
Speaker 0: So in the interest of saving all of you from my wonderful melodious voice I'll just roll into some more clips that I have handy with Scott and I'll call it a day digital digital.
Speaker 1: We should record in 5.1 just for the fuck of it.
Speaker 0: I was thinking of switching to Recording joint stereo and put you a little bit to the right me a little bit to the left.
Speaker 1: that works or vice versa.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll do something like that because it makes it nicer to listen to even though people usually can't figure out why it sounds nicer.
Speaker 0: They're like, hey, it sounds better.
Speaker 0: I don't know why.
Speaker 1: yeah, a lot of people have the joint stereo podcast.
Speaker 1: I'm actually ones with music.
Speaker 0: Well now that we're using resound which works as opposed to audacity, which doesn't work as well.
Speaker 0: Yep But the only matter we really have is that we need feedback about the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know there are some people listening and I know a lot of them are people who know us anyway and no offense.
Speaker 0: But all anyone tells us is either.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you guys are hilarious.
Speaker 0: or yeah, keep it up or yeah I listen but no one says like oh, but this needs work.
Speaker 1: So right now basically what we're doing is we're going on our own Instincts and trying to change the show based on what we think is good what we think is bad But who are we to judge something that you know isn't for us?
Speaker 0: Yeah We change it a lot today if I don't notice that we try to do a better job of explaining what we're talking about Before we talk about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we did a better job of not, you know rambling off and different topics that aren't related Yeah, and things like that, you know and sticking to the game plan Yeah, we actually did some pre-production.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and knowing the facts of what we're talking about.
Speaker 1: So we don't go.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah Well, what I don't know I didn't read it.
Speaker 0: You know we were both guilty.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, but besides the obvious stuff, you know We want to know what people want to hear.
Speaker 1: What's the good parts?
Speaker 1: What's the bad parts?
Speaker 1: You know who we really need is an idea of what to do on Monday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz we've tried a bunch of ideas and we've got Tuesdays and Wednesdays down.
Speaker 0: We're golden on Tuesday and Wednesday.
Speaker 0: I can talk about video games for like two days straight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know, we've got you know, the three major geekeries can be pretty much separated into Rwag anime club in EGS.
Speaker 1: Yeah You've got anime club in EGS but the our wag gaming type stuff which we're into.
Speaker 1: but there's not really enough of it that you can Talk a whole lot about D&D and for games and stuff for D&D news.
Speaker 0: Is there what happens in D&D?
Speaker 0: I never even seen.
Speaker 0: yeah 3.5 edition.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's like a book comes out.
Speaker 1: Something happens in a campaign world.
Speaker 1: These aren't you know, we like D&D, but these aren't things that we can talk about weekly for like 20 30 40 minutes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, I mean we could talk about old campaigns.
Speaker 1: We could talk about games are playing now if we had more people and you're actually playing them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we're not so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah So we need something to fill the Mondays and then of course we fill the Thursdays with whatever the heck we want craziness.
Speaker 0: Yep, we're thinking of trying to make for Thursdays for a while once we get going interview days where we pick someone to interview them.
Speaker 1: But you know, we need to set up some sort of interviewing technology and we need to find people to interview.
Speaker 1: So I guess if you're out there and you are someone who is interesting to interview you can get in contact with us.
Speaker 1: Maybe we can.
Speaker 1: you know that we're thinking of setting up the Skype or some team speak even though I don't trust the Skype But there's the Bioware.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course one thing anyone who lives near us we can just do an interview.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we might if you're live like a half hour away or closer or something.
Speaker 1: We might come out to see you or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, bring her a little mixer.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: We're always looking for fun things to do like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, definitely looking for people in the area.
Speaker 0: Anyway, but maybe we'll head out to Rochester and do the old alma mater.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but basically what it comes down to is if you're listening to this and we don't know you already and you don't know us Go to our forum on front row.
Speaker 1: crew calm email us geek nights at gmail.com.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you're a hacker and you find our cell phone numbers call us call us.
Speaker 1: We don't care.
Speaker 1: you do something You know.
Speaker 1: get in contact with us.
Speaker 1: tell us what's good about the show What's bad about the show if you like the show how you found us?
Speaker 1: Anything, you know, we need stuff if we get enough, right?
Speaker 0: It's just an echo chamber right now.
Speaker 0: We got nothing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if we get enough feedback, we can probably turn Monday into a feedback show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know.
Speaker 0: or if you have an idea for a thing to do on Mondays that isn't sci-tech because we've tried that it's hard To do, you know if we get people you can make Monday the request.
Speaker 1: show like hey guys talk about this.
Speaker 1: Then we talk about it.
Speaker 0: We thought about doing old-school nights, but that doesn't work because we just do that.
Speaker 0: whenever we talk about anime and video games.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah be like, hey, let's talk about old-school.
Speaker 1: All right, what are we gonna talk about?
Speaker 1: old-school video games?
Speaker 0: Magic the gathering.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah great Cuz I could talk about that for just days and days and days.
Speaker 1: we could.
Speaker 1: we could turn it into like a rant day But then it's really Thursday.
Speaker 1: Anyways, yeah, you don't really grinds my gears But I can't find the droids I'm looking for.
Speaker 0: We could do TV Simpsons.
Speaker 0: we'll think of something we should do.
Speaker 1: yeah, definitely.
Speaker 1: Yeah, visit our website also.
Speaker 0: Yeah posting the forums.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's no one really posting the forums.
Speaker 1: yet You could be the first.
Speaker 1: well not technically not the first.
Speaker 0: you'd be the first person.
Speaker 0: We don't already know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people we don't already know who are listening.
Speaker 1: We know you're there.
Speaker 0: Yeah If you like the show we wouldn't mind getting to know you.
Speaker 1: yeah, I mean, you know, we're not super popular yet We might be.
Speaker 1: one day we will be and you could be totally on the in crew.
Speaker 1: You'd be like I was listening to them since they're you know third podcast and you know I knew them and hung out with them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and meanwhile we have like a thousand screaming fans and you know, we'll actually know who you are and we won't know who they are.
Speaker 0: Yeah Either that or you know 700 episodes from now.
Speaker 0: We still have 30 listeners and we cry ourselves to sleep at night.
Speaker 0: Yeah, little a column a little a column B. We'll see how it goes.
Speaker 0: And That was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Thanks for listening.
Speaker 1: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at deeds dot feed burner comm slash geek nights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Speaker 1: also, please visit our website at www.front row crew comm for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at geek nights at gmail.com.