Speaker 0: It's Tuesday November 29th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about Carcassonne and Hellas.
Speaker 0: You're gonna lay off on the legacy of Amadeus.
Speaker 1: No, cuz it's it's.
Speaker 1: it's our current shtick.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah for anyone who doesn't know us.
Speaker 0: It's real easy for us to get shticks and Let's just say if you ever watch Big O The end of every episode they pick up a phone and a guy with a funny voice says some funny words and We'll leave it at that.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So, uh at work today The one guy there's one guy at work who has a kid who's kind of cool the kids into animes into gaming.
Speaker 0: So I'm trying to kind of steer him toward the proper geekeries and good works and away from the bad geekeries and the MMOs and everything better than no geekeries at all.
Speaker 0: and He doesn't want an Xbox 360 because they're a lot of money, but he wants an Xbox because he can get them cheap.
Speaker 0: So he had a friend who got an Xbox 360 the whole deal and the kid offered to sell him his current Xbox and a Bunch of games and controllers for like 75 bucks though the normal Xbox.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay I was kind of cuz.
Speaker 1: it seemed people aren't even calling cuz.
Speaker 1: 360 is so many words that like people are just saying Xbox.
Speaker 0: So am I?
Speaker 1: yeah, so it's like.
Speaker 1: so I don't we call the old one like Old Xbox and Xbox or just 360 without saying Xbox 360. that could do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so anyway, he had a old Xbox and he was gonna sell it to this kid for 75 bucks and he did so All right, which is fantastic.
Speaker 0: Not bad two hours later.
Speaker 0: He wanted back out of the deal And he wanted his old crappy Xbox back.
Speaker 0: really bad.
Speaker 1: Why is that?
Speaker 0: Apparently his new Xbox 360 Crashes if you play it for more than 20 minutes, maybe he should lift his power supply off the ground with the string.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I gave him some advice and part of that advice was uh, make a giant heatsink and such.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know why if it's if this power strip is heating like this.
Speaker 0: Did Microsoft not test it?
Speaker 1: I think that some of them are bad and some of them are good But why don't they put a fan in it?
Speaker 0: there's already fans Arts in it.
Speaker 0: Remember it's a wall wart.
Speaker 1: It just happens to be very big I know but there are fans and everything else.
Speaker 0: put fans in that too Because it's already too loud.
Speaker 0: People are already complaining about the loudness.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter if the loud if you're already loud being louder doesn't hurt you.
Speaker 0: You're not allowed people.
Speaker 0: people put it they plug it in it's loud So they put it in there like stereo cabinets.
Speaker 0: They don't have to hear it anymore.
Speaker 1: then it overheats Tada.
Speaker 0: so, uh Microsoft if you're listening good game good game In Good computer news.
Speaker 1: Oh Firefox one and a half final came out today.
Speaker 1: I've been using the beta for a while and Whenever they upgrade Firefox, it always amazes me what they add because I always can't imagine more.
Speaker 1: It was a point at which when I was using Firefox point five I was like, you know, it'd really be good if they added this or this or this and They added that and that and that almost right away.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: And by the time point nine was out I was like, what can they possibly add now?
Speaker 1: this there's nothing else.
Speaker 1: I was perfect.
Speaker 1: and then 1.0 they added something and I was like, oh, I guess there was stuff they could add and in 1.5 I couldn't imagine what they were gonna add.
Speaker 1: and then I got the beta.
Speaker 1: and well Hey, they amazed me yet again.
Speaker 0: So what did they add?
Speaker 0: Cuz I'm still using a virgin prior to 1.5.
Speaker 1: Well, first thing they did is the automatic updates and stuff of extensions and themes and Firefox itself.
Speaker 0: it now actually works.
Speaker 0: Ooh as opposed to just downloading an installer and then reinstalling.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's already reason enough for me.
Speaker 1: Okay, the back and forward button performance is increased.
Speaker 1: Basically, what they do is Firefox sort of caches buffers pre gets whatever is Whatever.
Speaker 1: you would normally see if you clicked back or forward.
Speaker 1: So that way if you click back or forward It's like instant because it already got the page when you were reading the current page.
Speaker 0: I like that a lot.
Speaker 1: All right, you can now drag the tabs to the left and to the right to reorder them.
Speaker 0: Ah I'm indifferent to that.
Speaker 1: but yeah, there was an extension to do it before but now you can just do it.
Speaker 1: So if the tab is like to the left you want it to be to to the right.
Speaker 1: you just pick it up move it.
Speaker 1: The pop-up blocking is improved to beat the people who got around it just previously recently.
Speaker 0: Haha, even though I've only seen those pop-ups once when I went to a wares site looking for wares.
Speaker 1: Yep They have this new clear private data feature where base used to go into the options and you'd click clear history clear cache And there'd be a clear all button.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they also clear my cookies, which I didn't want it to clear.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah.
Speaker 1: But now there's a thing you can set up where you say you basically say if I click clear private data Clear the following things location bar you choose which things you want to be cleared and then you just click that button to clear those Things.
Speaker 0: that's real good for if you say you're in college and your mom you visit you fairly often and needs to use your Firefox Just go clear and it clears up the porn so she doesn't see the yeah porn, right?
Speaker 0: God dolphins.
Speaker 1: They added answers calm to the search engine list Which I guess you can add anything you want to that search engine list.
Speaker 1: In fact, there's like hundreds and hundreds of things you can add.
Speaker 0: in fact IBM did something kind of cool and they made they set up a thing Internally where you can makes it real easy for people who don't know anything about Firefox to add a internal IBM search thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I all once made a search thing for that corner, but it was for OED So only people with names and passwords could use it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's not so useful to me anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I use dictionary calm when I need something.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right, so you remember how it used to be in Firefox and you got an error that it would pop up a little window.
Speaker 0: I Used to turn that off all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you would have to do some stuff to make it do in a web page.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all you had to do was change one setting in prefs.js right?
Speaker 1: Well now not only is that setting I guess set by default good But now the site the little error pages that you get are actually good.
Speaker 1: They're not.
Speaker 1: they're not that ugly poop.
Speaker 0: Not bad.
Speaker 1: All right There's a safe mode in case you screw it up with a bad extension.
Speaker 0: That's good because I've been installing Firefox on a lot of servers lately.
Speaker 1: The options menu is redesigned yet again slightly.
Speaker 1: RSS discovery works a little better.
Speaker 1: There is now better accessibility for blind people deaf people all that kind of stuff, you know Braille stuff whatnot?
Speaker 1: There's a wizard for reporting a broken website.
Speaker 1: So if you find a website that doesn't work in Firefox, you just click report and then the Firefox guys find out about it.
Speaker 0: That's fantastic.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: The OS X is improved a little bit.
Speaker 1: So you won't be screwed you know, it's so it competes with Safari better basically and It now supports SVG which you used to have to install something to support CSS to CSS 3 JavaScript 1.6 and a bunch of security fixes
Speaker 0: Obstanding
Speaker 1: that the CSS 3 is really important because now you can use these little canvases and things.
Speaker 1: It's pretty cool You know fast someone already made Quake in a canvas.
Speaker 1: So basically it's quake in JavaScript.
Speaker 0: Oh great.
Speaker 0: Yeah See unless you're really really like opera for some reason.
Speaker 0: There's really no reason to not use Firefox at this point.
Speaker 1: Well fire opera is free now though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't have ads anymore.
Speaker 0: So If you like opera I gotta admit opera is a little faster than Firefox in the loading of pages.
Speaker 1: a little faster I don't you know, but it's just crook slightly different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know what?
Speaker 0: There's no excuse to use IE anymore and None at all.
Speaker 0: I I know most of our listeners don't need to know this and they don't need to hear this.
Speaker 0: but to those of you and I'm pointing this specifically at two people who have mentioned specifically that they still use IE Stop using it.
Speaker 0: You Know they never patched that thing.
Speaker 1: I told everyone about yeah I mean seriously if there's a guy in the corner giving out free I don't know.
Speaker 1: Ferraris right and you have a Pinto and you know, it explodes But you're just used to driving the Pinto.
Speaker 1: Why what the hell's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: I mean serious.
Speaker 0: seriously a couple lines of JavaScript.
Speaker 0: I could put it on our podcast site and I'd get control over your computer.
Speaker 0: Yep, I can just JavaScript.
Speaker 0: you don't have to do anything just visit the site and then we've got you and you know What this JavaScript is all over the internet and Microsoft hasn't even really figured out how to fix it yet.
Speaker 1: and basically anyone who wants to can just stick this on their website.
Speaker 1: and if you visit using IE You're pooned.
Speaker 0: and I know some people say oh well Firefox has exploits too and blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: And as it gets more popular to have more but one not really.
Speaker 0: it's had a handful and they were all patched within 24.
Speaker 0: I think the longest time it ever took for a patch to come out was like 30 hours.
Speaker 1: That was one that took a couple days, but it wasn't a serious like, you know end of the world I can take over your computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the worst Can do is take over your Firefox.
Speaker 1: No one can take over your computer with a Firefox hole.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they can take over your computer with an IE hole.
Speaker 0: in fact trivially I could probably I could tell you right now exactly what JavaScript to type to do it.
Speaker 0: Yep I'm not going to.
Speaker 1: there was actually an interesting discussion the other day about people were talking about Firefox's market share and it's about 10% a little less maybe right in terms of number of people but what they What they were saying is that they don't think that that information that statistic even if it's accurate is really Relevant or important because the people who use IE Aren't people who visit lots and lots of websites.
Speaker 1: so the people who maybe sign on visit website sign off Anyone who actually visits websites and goes around the web and does web things in a daily basis or a frequent basis they all most of them use Firefox at least 90% of those types of people.
Speaker 1: because if you go to websites that are the kind of websites that only nerdy website internet savvy people use like a delicious or Blah or like nerdy blogs or super podcasts most of the visitors are Firefox by a wide margin.
Speaker 1: Yep, so if you're not using Firefox You're really like all the smart people use it.
Speaker 1: There's a reason all this money Seriously, they went through effort to switch to it.
Speaker 0: I look at the statistics on our Site through the feeds and there is one person using Internet Explorer that I can see.
Speaker 0: Awesome one, you know who you are.
Speaker 0: Stop it.
Speaker 0: All right, not to be mean but it's bad for you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not gonna tell you to do something because You know, we have some evil agenda.
Speaker 1: I mean what the hell do we gain?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just your loss that we're trying to prevent.
Speaker 0: Hey, so segue Segue into thing of the day.
Speaker 1: the thing thing thing thing and not the guy who's made of rock on the Fantastic Four.
Speaker 0: That was really bad.
Speaker 0: Shut up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it's the thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah is better Do more.
Speaker 0: All right, so, uh Technology to keep kids off my damn lawn has grown a little bit Really?
Speaker 0: There's this old codger and it's in Britain and he doesn't like the fact that punk kids hang out in front of his shop.
Speaker 1: You know if I had a shop I wouldn't want punk kids loitering in front of it either.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and he realized and this isn't really science But it's kind of true in a general sense that generally older people There cannot hear certain frequencies that younger people can because younger people haven't been to as many concerts plain and simple.
Speaker 0: So he made a little device that makes really annoying high-pitched noises like remember when you were in high school and Like the TV in the corner would be on and everyone in the class could hear it and they're like ah But the professor the teacher didn't hear anything.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's like that.
Speaker 0: so he has this making this noise outside of the front of his store and Teenagers and punk kids hear it, but all the adult customers who come in don't The dogs be pretty pissed.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah dogs hate it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you have if you run a pet shop, you don't want to use this.
Speaker 1: No, so we should go hang out in front of the swing in his pet shop in town.
Speaker 0: So I thought while it's kind of blah it's I got to admit for a guy who doesn't seem to know much about science It's a pretty novel solution to his problem and I applaud him for that.
Speaker 1: I wonder if it'll work though.
Speaker 0: Well, there were places in Britain earlier that were started playing classical music in order to keep kids from hanging out.
Speaker 1: Did it work?
Speaker 0: Not really kids like classical music.
Speaker 1: Yeah, me too
Speaker 0: but the only thing wrong with this is that the guy seems to think he got on this kick when he Reporters interviewed him and he was talking about how we'd like to make a stronger one that could be used against this process or this method of thievery called streaming that apparently happens in Britain.
Speaker 1: Streaming streaming like streaming video.
Speaker 0: Yeah only streaming shoplifting instead.
Speaker 0: imagine you're you're in a little shop and you're standing there and Suddenly like 15 to 20 like young teenage punks run into your store Start smashing things and grabbing everything they can in a giant mess and then they all run out and scatter.
Speaker 1: So while they ran in it first of all, so if this happened more than once I would have heard about it Unless I was the first victim in which case I'm the first victim.
Speaker 1: Oh, well
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: if I'd heard about it as soon as those guys came into my store It took me about the second to realize what was happening and I'd lock the door and they'd be stuck in my store and then I would have a shotgun and Then anyone who tried to walk out of the store with stuff would die.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or I would fill them with rock salt Which would be okay probably.
Speaker 0: now the guy seems to think that he made a stronger version.
Speaker 0: He could stun all these kids when this happens and prevent the theft maybe with an L rad not with one of these.
Speaker 1: no Definitely not with one.
Speaker 0: still I thought it was cool and it was a slow news day.
Speaker 0: So that's all I got All right.
Speaker 1: So do you remember back in the day?
Speaker 1: There was this thing called master maze, which was Basically you paid 50 bucks and you got this big heavy box with this metal already painted modular dungeons.
Speaker 1: Oh And you could make a dungeon for D&D by putting these pieces together and it would be nice.
Speaker 1: and 3d it had walls.
Speaker 0: It was awesome.
Speaker 0: It was just really really.
Speaker 1: it was awesome, but really expensive.
Speaker 1: But it had nice little you know, one inch squares and everything and it was really cool.
Speaker 1: You can make dungeons with opening doors and treasures and everything wicked cool.
Speaker 1: Well some guy took it to the next level.
Speaker 1: what he did is he made a Brand new role-playing game system and this system Depends on something quite like the master maze Only and here's where the geekiness factor doubles and triples.
Speaker 1: It is implemented with 100% Lego.
Speaker 0: Wow, wouldn't that almost be more expensive?
Speaker 1: I think it would.
Speaker 1: but he's got.
Speaker 1: he's got Rules for a system.
Speaker 1: He's got little guys for each class.
Speaker 1: He's got modular dungeons made of Lego like monsters Character sheets the whole thing.
Speaker 0: It's it's an RPG that you play on the table with Legos to represent your guys, you know, not only is that badass, but I probably have enough Legos in my collection to do it.
Speaker 1: I bought mostly Castle Lego in my day.
Speaker 1: I got a lot of Castle Lego.
Speaker 0: now see I guess I'm we're old fogies.
Speaker 0: But there when we were kids you could buy buckets of generic Lego pieces for almost nothing.
Speaker 1: It wasn't almost nothing.
Speaker 1: there was.
Speaker 0: We were like five Yeah, because Lego almost went out of business.
Speaker 0: Well, I think they almost did.
Speaker 0: they had a lot of trouble not that long ago.
Speaker 0: The problem with Lego was that Lego bricks are incredibly durable and it's almost impossible to destroy them.
Speaker 0: so as They sold more and more Legos the demand for Lego drops because parents people would pass them on to kids.
Speaker 0: people would sell them on a well not on eBay.
Speaker 0: back then if you would sell them and trade them and Once you had a certain amount of Legos, you didn't need any more Unless you're not like this guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: so they started.
Speaker 0: they cut back on selling generic pieces and they made their sets more expensive and they added a lot of Special parts that can't really be used in anything else to try to get people to buy more Legos.
Speaker 1: Legos are still cool.
Speaker 1: They didn't go too far.
Speaker 1: Oh, I'm not claiming they're not even went a little farther.
Speaker 1: They would be over the edge.
Speaker 0: But yeah, they're a little too pricey now, but I have enough Legos to make a small house.
Speaker 1: So I got plenty of Lego.
Speaker 1: You're not supposed to call Legos.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it's Lego Lego Lego.
Speaker 1: Lego is the pearl of Lego Lego my ego.
Speaker 0: No, yeah.
Speaker 1: So yeah, if you if you like D&D or role-playing games you just get in or Legos Totally got to check this out.
Speaker 1: It's freaking awesome.
Speaker 0: It's the main bit the main bit Main the main bit.
Speaker 0: that doesn't have music for the main bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah music real soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're working on it.
Speaker 0: so it's a Gaming day and we've got two new games and they're not video games.
Speaker 0: Yeah for once So Carcassonne is a really fun game and we've played it a lot.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 1: if you haven't played Carcassonne it's a tile laying game.
Speaker 1: You basically take turns laying tiles and you put guys on the tiles.
Speaker 1: You could put them on the grass on the road or in a castle and then you finish the roads with other tiles and you finish the castles with other tiles or You build enough castles in the grassy area and that you have score depending on how well you placed your guys.
Speaker 0: It's really quick really fun really simple and it was a good game.
Speaker 1: It's actually so good that it's a German board game.
Speaker 1: they got sold at Toys R Us.
Speaker 0: so yeah, that's saying a lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, now it's a great game, but there are a million expansions for it and we figured out why.
Speaker 0: Well many reasons why but the base set.
Speaker 0: After you play it a lot and get good at it.
Speaker 0: You discover that due to the way the tiles are set up It is very basically it's easier to screw other people than it is to get points for yourself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, for example, if someone else is gonna finish a castle for a bunch of points You know that such and such a tile does not exist.
Speaker 1: So you arrange other tiles in such a way So that they need a tile that does not exist in order to complete their castle and thus their castle does not complete and they Don't score points.
Speaker 0: and if you're playing this game with you know, five people No one ever finishes anything and it's just a game of who screwed who the most.
Speaker 1: Yep It's that's.
Speaker 1: if the people know what's got who know how to play.
Speaker 1: if you play with noobs or if you've never played before This won't happen.
Speaker 1: You'll pretty much play a nice easy game.
Speaker 0: So we picked up the hotels and citadels or cathedrals Expansions and it only adds 18 tiles to the game.
Speaker 0: it adds two new kinds of tiles But and they actually add a lot to the game.
Speaker 0: I found I was skeptical at first but they actually make it really interesting.
Speaker 0: Yep, but these 18 tiles are all the weird tiles that didn't exist in the other game.
Speaker 0: they're all like a city in a city and then like a road coming in in a weird direction or like a City or like four city end caps all around a piece of grass.
Speaker 0: now you play this game with like 40 tiles So you wouldn't think adding 18 tiles makes a difference makes a huge difference.
Speaker 0: It's a completely different game.
Speaker 0: It's now actually a game of Completing things because every time you think you screwed someone and you walled off their city and they can't find a piece They draw the piece they need like three times.
Speaker 1: See the problem was though is without the expansion you end up always needing a tile and then not getting it now with the expansion Not only do you get the tiles you need you get a bunch of really wicked Tiles that you don't need and you have to end up sticking them way off at the edge of the map because you don't have A weird situation to use them in because you filled it up already.
Speaker 0: And I gotta say it's fantastic since there's only two of us.
Speaker 0: We like playing two-player games and there aren't that many good two-player games.
Speaker 0: Carcassonne has been renewed to the point that I think we're gonna play it after we finish the show tonight.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it definitely The expansion revived the game, you know, it was it was big.
Speaker 1: then it kind of faded.
Speaker 1: Then we played a little bit then it faded.
Speaker 1: then the expansion has revived it to full.
Speaker 0: I can't wait to play the expansion with more people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the the thing I think with with more people I think actually all the tiles will get used awesomely.
Speaker 0: yeah, but anyone who tries to go for the size castles we're going for will be unhappy or Multiple people will try to finish castles and then try to edge each other out with a big, dude.
Speaker 1: Oh as opposed to where now we try to edge each other out in the farms.
Speaker 1: The farms won't matter so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah going for the big 70-point castle Cathedral whatever is in them.
Speaker 1: Also, I used to not pay attention to road so much but now with the inns I keep getting lots of road points.
Speaker 0: Yep, but so often you think if you ever play this game, you'll think how could anyone ever screw me on a road?
Speaker 0: How could I ever get to the point where I couldn't cap off a road?
Speaker 0: You freaking can't cap off roads because people screw you.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I won because of it and you won because of it.
Speaker 1: It's a good plan.
Speaker 1: Yeah The other thing is a lot of the.
Speaker 1: there are other carcass own expansions like.
Speaker 0: there's billions of them.
Speaker 1: Well, some of them aren't expansions.
Speaker 1: I actually looked into it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Some of them are actually other games and what they did is they rebranded the games as carcass own The castle or carcass own the something else
Speaker 0: Yep, like no dragon and the princess
Speaker 1: so that people who liked carcass own would be more likely to buy this other game.
Speaker 1: But some of them are expansions like the dragon and the princess or whatever It's called.
Speaker 1: and there's another one with a little count.
Speaker 1: Yeah count Dracula, but not a vampire that goes around the map You know and like the dragon eats your farmer guys and the princess saves them and little witches and fairies and things.
Speaker 1: And I don't know if I like those expansions so much but I haven't tried them so I can't say But if this expansion runs dry, I'll definitely be willing to try some more.
Speaker 0: Yep So if you ever buy a carcass own just pick up ins and cathedrals, it's definitely worth it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but as for the other games that are labeled carcass own that are actually completely different games.
Speaker 1: Well, they're not completely different.
Speaker 1: They're similar in that they are tile laying games that you place guys on the tiles, you know.
Speaker 1: Which is why they're able to label them carcass own.
Speaker 1: but the ones that aren't actually carcass own I don't know.
Speaker 1: I guess you have to look at them individually Maybe what the original games were to figure out if they're good or not.
Speaker 0: We also picked up a bunch of other games, but we only played one of them because the rest require More than two people.
Speaker 1: we'll play those by next week.
Speaker 1: Hopefully.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because they look super awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have to head up to Albany grab some Pete and play some board game.
Speaker 1: Well card games.
Speaker 1: They're card games other games Games games.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the game that we were able to play which is two-player Which I bought because it was two-player and was recommended as a good two-player game is helles H-e-l-l-a-s as in Hellenic culture Greeks.
Speaker 1: It's a big Greek game.
Speaker 1: In fact.
Speaker 1: the names of little guys in the game.
Speaker 1: It just says Greeks put your Greek on the island.
Speaker 1: It's um, we played it once I won handily.
Speaker 1: yeah the game isn't perfect, but it's better than the impression before playing it would.
Speaker 0: yes let you feel because once we played it, it's fun and It looks like once we both get good at it and kind of figure out the strategies and the counters to the strategies It looks like a decent kill some time two-player game.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: The problem was when we were first reading through the rules.
Speaker 0: It sounds real arbitrary.
Speaker 1: It's like you could only have three guys here and you can only have this many this and you can only do This when the moon is in the south.
Speaker 0: If there's a squiggly line on the card you can use it sometimes but other times you can't.
Speaker 1: and yeah and The rules are in.
Speaker 0: they don't have the super preciseness of wording that you know A hundred percent what things do and we actually had to look up errata on one rule because there was no way to know.
Speaker 1: Yep, and you know, sometimes it's a little vague.
Speaker 1: Like can you play god cards now?
Speaker 1: Can you play them now?
Speaker 1: Did this one matter?
Speaker 1: Does that one matter?
Speaker 1: Can I go back on that?
Speaker 1: What are you know?
Speaker 1: And sometimes it feels a little loose like, you know I'm used to having games where the rules are.
Speaker 1: you do this then you do this then you do this and that is the end And you skip this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like you can just play cards whenever.
Speaker 0: yes, like I play a card Yeah, I play a counter spell to that.
Speaker 0: Well, I play a counter spell to your counter spell.
Speaker 0: Well, I play a card.
Speaker 0: Let me take my counter spell back and play it again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I do the same and then I play my original card.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are cards just flying around Everywhere and it feels kind of willy-nilly which isn't such a good feeling except it isn't actually willy-nilly It's actually precise.
Speaker 0: You just have to get over that feeling.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also if you play the game Scott this is why Scott lost.
Speaker 0: he made the mistake of thinking that it was a game of conquer territory.
Speaker 0: move your guys around have Strong armies.
Speaker 0: It's really a card game and maneuvering game.
Speaker 1: Mmm, the cards pretty much make the whole game because you're only allowed to have three Greeks in a city.
Speaker 1: So and you have a limited supply of Greek a very limited supply of Greeks So you basically you must spread the Greeks thin.
Speaker 1: so getting new territory is all about cards.
Speaker 1: You can't do.
Speaker 1: basically if you try to do something without cards your chances of succeeding are pretty much nil or a voyaging Which you just never did.
Speaker 1: I tried to do voyaging But I always felt so weak that I didn't want to voyage because then I wouldn't reinforce my position.
Speaker 0: The thing is I was equally weak.
Speaker 1: So I realized that You were a little stronger than me though in a lot of places that's cuz.
Speaker 0: I'm better stronger braver faster handsomer.
Speaker 1: You want to play it like risk, but you can't.
Speaker 1: you just have to try to get more islands and then it's not risk.
Speaker 0: Don't think it is.
Speaker 0: you lose.
Speaker 1: You'll totally lose.
Speaker 0: Or unless the other guy also thinks is risk and then no one will ever win There is.
Speaker 1: the only.
Speaker 1: the one thing though is that because the cards basically make the game is That if you don't get the cards It's like you'll get every card because there's so few but if you don't have the cards you want when you got them when you Want them.
Speaker 0: see I think that's yes Cuz I. basically what I did is I drew cards that I didn't want and I didn't get the cards I wanted.
Speaker 0: So what I did is I looked at the cards I had and thought well then I can use these cards to do this and I had to change my strategy constantly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I tried to use whatever cards I had.
Speaker 0: I tried to do something with but a lot of times You gotta save cards don't use a card unless you have to.
Speaker 0: that way when you need a card you got a card.
Speaker 0: Yeah The one thing about the game that bugs me is it feels because we said earlier the rules are kind of arbitrary.
Speaker 0: It feels like they made this game and they played it and then they realized oh, it's broken.
Speaker 0: If you do this you win automatically.
Speaker 0: So they made a rule against that and then oh now it's broken this way and they just tacked on rules until the game was balanced.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it does kind of feel like that.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: It's balanced.
Speaker 0: So Yeah, it's balanced definitely not an A game not an A game but not a C game.
Speaker 1: no, oh if you know If I had to take one two-player game with me to the end of the world, this would not be it.
Speaker 0: I'd take San Juan.
Speaker 1: maybe San Juan, but you know if We're sitting around we want to play a two-player game.
Speaker 1: You got you know, the other games are a little played out.
Speaker 1: It's not bad.
Speaker 1: if I you know, it would definitely be in I guess some top ten two-player games so far.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we don't know so many two-player games.
Speaker 0: I mean technically Tigris and Euphrates is two-player, but it only lasts about three.
Speaker 1: It's not a very good of being a two-player game.
Speaker 0: Shogun is two-player.
Speaker 0: So is risk.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those aren't very good.
Speaker 1: That's like a Lombre.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you play with Matt Matt.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but There are a whole bunch of other two-player games in this series.
Speaker 1: they all come in the same little square boxes and they say cosmos on them with a K and One of the other ones is lost cities.
Speaker 1: I'm thinking about gonna try that.
Speaker 1: it's pretty popular and there's some other ones.
Speaker 1: So this is just one of the more popular ones in the series.
Speaker 1: So I got it tried it not really regretting buying it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so so we like the German board games and So since the college ended there hasn't been too much Opportunity to play them because a lot of them need more than two people.
Speaker 0: Granted we've had some crazy weekends of gaming where we played every game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course, but you know, I've since I left college and got here with the job and everything I've been looking for some people to play with and You know board game geek was the place and I did kind of find some people but you know It never really came together a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I missed all this.
Speaker 1: I was out of town Yeah, and I heard about a group called maws like month weeks and months ago Maybe even but I could never actually find them because the only way to contact them was old email addresses that weren't used and all Kinds of stuff like that.
Speaker 0: Why don't they have a website?
Speaker 1: They're gonna have one soon.
Speaker 1: I guess that's least what that was.
Speaker 0: Should we make it for him?
Speaker 1: I mean someone else I think already made it but some people have to look it over.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I don't care.
Speaker 1: stand for Mid Hudson area war gamers society.
Speaker 0: every game every gamer club like that has a weird name like that because they think this Arweg the Rochester area wargaming guild Rochester war game.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that's because all of these things all the clubs that are still around are the ancient.
Speaker 1: They're the really old clubs from like the 70s from when it was war gaming and now that wargaming is left popular They've moved over to the German games and RPGs and CCGs and things.
Speaker 0: Why don't we start our own club with a non stupid name right here in Beacon?
Speaker 1: I Guess the guy who does the board game podcast.
Speaker 1: his his group is the Santa Clarita board gamers.
Speaker 0: We've officially formed a group in Beacon.
Speaker 0: There's two of us.
Speaker 0: We'll name it later.
Speaker 1: I had the beacon board gamers Anyway, so I finally found these guys, you know via someone else posting on board game geek And I was just lucky.
Speaker 1: I visited that day because I don't go there that often and I saw the word Poughkeepsie.
Speaker 1: So I went down to the Dragon's Den, which is local game store.
Speaker 1: It's not the greatest game store.
Speaker 1: It actually moved.
Speaker 1: It's a little better now, but you know, it's alright.
Speaker 1: Went down there played some games.
Speaker 1: The guys are pretty much typical middle-aged gamer guys, you know, they're not very Attractive but you know, they're funny, you know, they don't know how to play games.
Speaker 1: it was a good time and If I didn't have anything better to do I wouldn't mind going back playing some more games, you know There was when I first got there.
Speaker 1: There was some guys were actually playing a super real war game and I was like, whoa
Speaker 0: You mean the kind of game where two guys sit there and like a tank runs into another tank Where
Speaker 1: there are little tiny squares of cardboard with numbers and some they
Speaker 0: don't roll dice.
Speaker 0: They actually sit there with an encyclopedia and they look up the different encyclopedia.
Speaker 1: but like they had a map a real kind of somewhat more real map than any kind of game I play and Little things they're like like Oh airplanes and tanks and the names of airplanes.
Speaker 0: see those games scare me.
Speaker 0: That's the kind of game where you'd look up in a book and then you'd say yeah But this tank in the real world that two-inch armor and therefore the shells couldn't penetrate.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would say yeah, but a bunch of other guys I think in another table, so I sat down with them.
Speaker 1: one guy was the guy that I spoke to on board game geek.
Speaker 1: He was an okay kind of guy, you know, he was a little grumbly took the games like this tiny bit too seriously.
Speaker 0: That's tough for us to say because we take our games pretty damn seriously.
Speaker 1: It was like he'd be a little grumbly like if you did a move against him, you know and stuff like that.
Speaker 1: It was cool.
Speaker 1: There was another guy He I didn't know I don't remember anyone's name.
Speaker 1: one guy was Z man.
Speaker 1: He actually owned a game company Z man games.
Speaker 1: He was an okay guy, but he's a little talk too much a little bit.
Speaker 1: You know, I met the owner of dragons den actually right before I left.
Speaker 1: He was a cool guy, you know I mean he was trying to push his products Which I guess is understandable and you know kind of puts me off when someone is like that.
Speaker 1: But other than that, he seemed like, you know a decent guy looks like a game store owner, you know The game store does sell a lot of paintball airsoft and that seems to be their Biggest moneymaker which is kind of sad You know, but anyway, I also I played a bunch of these simple German type card games that were pretty fun.
Speaker 1: One of them was with these red chips.
Speaker 1: It was like a game of chicken.
Speaker 1: It was pretty cool.
Speaker 0: another one I played was Shit Do I need to add a cue here?
Speaker 1: I remember what the other one was.
Speaker 1: just add the cue and you played some games.
Speaker 0: Yeah So, yeah, that's probably our best chance to actually have people to play board games with nowadays.
Speaker 1: Yeah, oh, I played one other game that was called Vegas showdown.
Speaker 1: It was a game from Hasbro, well, they called it Hasbro Hill, you know Avalon Hill the cut the people label that does like axis and allies and all those things.
Speaker 1: and You know, I was kind of iffy on this game with its Vegas theme and such but actually turned out to be a really good Game, you know despite the the Vegas theme like you bid on pieces of a casino And then you build a casino out of them and use the casino chips for money.
Speaker 0: Oh, I like bidding games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was.
Speaker 1: it was actually a much better game than I thought even though I lost horribly.
Speaker 1: Yeah Overall good time.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: There's some geeks out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you're uh, you know down in the mid Hudson Valley, you
Speaker 0: know Hudson River Yeah,
Speaker 1: and you're looking for some German type board games or anything like that There's a mailing list and I guess you can get on it by some miracle of finding these guys because they like to hide in The hole somewhere.
Speaker 0: Well post whatever links we can come up with whenever we come up with them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and Get some gaming action going on.
Speaker 0: or you know email us and come to beacon.
Speaker 0: We got a big house and we'll play some board games.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I'll warn you though.
Speaker 0: Do you play Puerto Rico or tires and Euphrates with us?
Speaker 0: expect to cry.
Speaker 1: I Know these guys didn't cry when I played against them, even though I did shut the guy down an external conflict with five blue tiles.
Speaker 1: He became after me in this blue external conflict.
Speaker 1: He was so confident He was ahead by five and I was like five blue tiles.
Speaker 1: I was just five blue tiles and he was like he was like dying.
Speaker 1: I was like, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see I'm not saying Oh, we're so good blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: I'm saying we're bastards Like most people who seem to play board games.
Speaker 0: don't bevagon.
Speaker 0: They don't take their turn.
Speaker 1: These guys definitely did not take their turn.
Speaker 1: I think their turn faster than some people I know But they didn't they're not.
Speaker 1: I took my turn instantly and they did not because board game geek.
Speaker 0: I saw a thread where people talking about what do you do when your friends take too long and the Consensus seemed to be that you take no more than a few minutes on your turn?
Speaker 1: We take about five seconds and get really pissed if someone takes more than about five seconds, yeah people wonder like They were amazed when I said I played Puerto Rico five times in a day.
Speaker 1: It must take.
Speaker 1: that must mean ten hours to them.
Speaker 0: It means four hours to me Yeah, so because I mean a lot of games like.
Speaker 0: we have a friend Scott Johnson and he's on defucking feedable at this game called acquired
Speaker 1: apparently a lot of people use that same strategy of
Speaker 0: yeah You save a lot of games if you sit there and think long enough You'll know exactly what to do because you can calculate every option
Speaker 1: because they're only there because there are too many options to think of them instantly.
Speaker 1: But it's not like chess where you would have to think forever to figure out every possible move.
Speaker 1: There's a limited number of moves and you can calculate the points of each one.
Speaker 0: however to me that Reduces the skill of the game because if everyone does that the game takes forever and then everyone makes the perfect move every round.
Speaker 1: and this I don't like a game where you can do that Even if there's a you know a whole bunch of choices because then a computer can beat the game.
Speaker 1: Computer can do it.
Speaker 0: Why am I doing that in Tigris and Euphrates and I've seen ways to do it where I could sit there and count and come up with statistics immediately.
Speaker 0: Well, not immediately, but I could come over the statistics.
Speaker 0: I don't think you could write of Fully optimized AI to play But I could come up with the percent chances I have of everything I want to do succeeding and I thought I sat there.
Speaker 1: You can think of every option and you see every future of every tile in acquire.
Speaker 1: You can see every spot that you can do something and figure out each move.
Speaker 1: That's possible not just each move you might want to do.
Speaker 0: But I think the point is in games like that Part of the skill is not only being able to think of what to do, but being able to think of it quickly.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that they should have.
Speaker 1: a lot of games should have variants with egg timers.
Speaker 1: I might go buy an egg timer.
Speaker 0: We should get one or actually we should buy a chess timer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well you get the little gaming egg timers.
Speaker 1: They're like specifically for games.
Speaker 1: They're one minute.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those are good.
Speaker 0: So, uh, is it to Time to leave?
Speaker 0: it's time to leave a legacy of Amadeus and That was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Thanks for listening.
Speaker 1: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds feed burner comm slash geek nights.
Speaker 1: get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Speaker 1: also, please visit our website at www.front row crew comm for the latest updates and forum discussions and whether you love or hate our podcast We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at geek nights at gmail.com.