Speaker 1: It's Wednesday November 16th, and this is deep nuts tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about anime specifically Gankotsuo and the place promised in our early days.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: So, uh, we stopped playing Mario Kart just long enough to make this podcast.
Speaker 0: That's about right.
Speaker 0: Yeah I played three online games today.
Speaker 0: I won all of them.
Speaker 0: I'm so great.
Speaker 1: Yep So, uh, I work today.
Speaker 1: I've been struggling with this server.
Speaker 0: I've been struggling with all that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I hate all that but I hate the server more.
Speaker 1: to make it And slightly confidential.
Speaker 1: story short I built a server I put a raid card in the raid card died.
Speaker 1: I put another raid card in.
Speaker 1: that card died.
Speaker 1: I then learned that that motherboard somehow specifically destroys that and only that raid car put a different raid card in And Eventually, I got everything working.
Speaker 1: I was very happy and then just today a stick of RAM died and I wanted to cry.
Speaker 0: This computer must be cursed something like that.
Speaker 0: Can't you get like another computer just like it?
Speaker 0: that doesn't have a curse?
Speaker 1: No, because there's only.
Speaker 1: we only have two of the like.
Speaker 1: this is an old kind of server and they don't make them anymore.
Speaker 1: And this I don't need a powerful server.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna spend money to buy like a brand new blade or anything.
Speaker 0: You spend someone else's money to buy a brand new.
Speaker 0: I'll just spend your money unless it's going in this house.
Speaker 1: Yeah I do my job at work the same way I do computers here.
Speaker 1: If I have a computer laying around that'll do the job.
Speaker 1: I don't spend money on a new computer unless I have to.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess that's kind of okay.
Speaker 1: that way if I really need to spend money later, I can spend money.
Speaker 0: It's good for the company.
Speaker 0: But you know, sometimes you don't necessarily want what's good for the company.
Speaker 1: I usually do.
Speaker 1: the problem is sometimes the company doesn't want what's good for the company.
Speaker 1: Yeah, people don't like bad medicine They're new.
Speaker 1: No, it's like All right, yeah, so uh Today I saw that AOL Added some bots to everyone's buddy list.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I read this story.
Speaker 0: But then you know I completely forgot about it until I got home because I can't really sign in to aim at work because the network's broken.
Speaker 0: My jabber aim transport doesn't even work at work.
Speaker 0: work at work.
Speaker 0: But as soon as I got home, I signed into aim and these two bots appeared and I was like, oh my god It happened even on GA on Linux.
Speaker 1: See it even happens in trillion has happened to max.
Speaker 1: But the thing is I saw all these reports and I looked and they weren't in my list and then I got home and they weren't There.
Speaker 1: so I was thinking what am I immune?
Speaker 1: Did it skip me?
Speaker 1: And then I realized that I hadn't logged out of aim Since a power outage a while ago.
Speaker 1: So I logged out of aim and I logged back in and they appeared.
Speaker 1: I said some obscenities to him for a while.
Speaker 1: Then I deleted him.
Speaker 0: Obscenities.
Speaker 0: see I wouldn't really mind the bots if they didn't force them on you.
Speaker 0: I think the reason they forced them on you really is to just inform you of the new feature that they're.
Speaker 0: they gave you Yeah.
Speaker 0: But I mean if they just had a thing where you could add bots if you wanted and some of them were useful and they Didn't send you advertising.
Speaker 0: That's always cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that's what they have now.
Speaker 1: kind of they've there add they.
Speaker 1: basically There's always been this API for having bots in a. no always.
Speaker 1: but now they legitimized it and it's an official thing And they're just gonna start putting out more and more official bots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well Jabber has always been the king of bots and now the Jabber is kind of moving with the Google talk.
Speaker 0: I think they want to you know, kind of head it off at the pass.
Speaker 1: Yeah the only thing I don't get is I didn't like the bots appearing but it wasn't a crushing blow against my computer.
Speaker 1: sovereignty sovereignty, no, not really, but uh the sheer poison and vehemence that I heard on Slashdot and Fark of people screaming.
Speaker 1: How could they do this?
Speaker 1: those bastards blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: I mean AOL aim is kind of free.
Speaker 1: So you really can't.
Speaker 1: I mean you can complain but you can't expect them to listen to you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually AOL is kind of turning around.
Speaker 0: I mean they used to be all bastardly and whatnot.
Speaker 0: But you know, they redid the aim client and they added all the good stuff, but they piled up on the ads like crazy You know, but they're letting all the G aims and trillions slide their ads in the aim client.
Speaker 0: crazy ads I haven't.
Speaker 1: I seriously have not used the official AOL client in like seven years.
Speaker 0: I haven't used the official aim client in longer than that except for why I think I use the everybody once.
Speaker 1: See I never even used aim until I got to college and all of you bastards used aim and I had to stop using ICQ.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't.
Speaker 0: I like having a name and not a number.
Speaker 1: I liked having a number.
Speaker 1: that way I could have whatever name I wanted now.
Speaker 1: I'm shizar 105.
Speaker 0: it's not my fault.
Speaker 0: You weren't cool enough to get shizar first or cool enough to have a unique name.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 1: It's great because in Jabber I've got rim.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Jabber is King.
Speaker 0: everyone should use Jabber.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: if you use Jabber you won't have people randomly adding bots to your buddy list.
Speaker 1: Yeah, unless the server admin decides to add bots to your buddy list.
Speaker 0: But and then when the server admin is me, and I don't know how to do that.
Speaker 0: You have no worries.
Speaker 0: So You know, I got a little iPod nano, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, you didn't break this one.
Speaker 0: No, not yet.
Speaker 0: And I was.
Speaker 0: you know, the other day there was the doom for the iPod nano.
Speaker 0: All right The one that you couldn't get to work the one that I couldn't get to work But only cuz I was dumb and I'm not gonna try it again cuz I really never need for it.
Speaker 0: It's just I was trying to be cool.
Speaker 0: But you know when the doom came out for the nano I was like, yeah, it has a color screen.
Speaker 0: Why can't it play video?
Speaker 0: There's no reason it can't.
Speaker 0: and In fact, there isn't a reason it can't.
Speaker 0: and today they released a video player for iPod Linux and you can watch video on your iPod nano.
Speaker 0: Fantastic the only pro.
Speaker 0: the reasons is that Apple probably didn't put it out right away were because a the battery life Be not so much hard drive space.
Speaker 0: No see the screen isn't really conducive for video viewing.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 0: So if they would have released it as you know market it as this plays video and given it a video feature It would that would have been piss poor.
Speaker 0: that would have looked pretty piss poor.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so I can see why they didn't do it.
Speaker 0: But at least these Linux guys got it under control, so if you really want to you're good to go.
Speaker 1: I Don't think I will be anytime soon, but it's cool either.
Speaker 0: But actually I got the new digital camera.
Speaker 0: I got some pictures on the nano.
Speaker 0: It's actually pretty good for showing people pictures.
Speaker 0: Ah You know, you think it would be kind of crummy.
Speaker 0: No, it's actually pretty hot.
Speaker 1: So Darwinia Okay, made by the same people who made uplink back in the day.
Speaker 0: Those guys are great.
Speaker 1: Yep is gonna be released exclusively through steam.
Speaker 0: Well, at least for Windows.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now you can still just buy the Linux one.
Speaker 1: But if you want the Windows one, you got to get it through steam.
Speaker 0: That's definitely cool because these guys aren't a big-time developer But and they make original games and their games are awesome.
Speaker 0: Really awesome.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah link was fantastic.
Speaker 0: It was crazy good and I played Darwinia and while Darwinia wasn't crazy good It was better than 90% of PC games out there and it was very very original.
Speaker 0: So I think the steam deal is good for them because it gets them a lot more Exposure than they would have gotten say on the shelf in the game store And it's a lot cheaper for them because they don't have to make a box.
Speaker 0: They don't have to make a CD.
Speaker 0: I think it was a very good move on their part.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean, I have no gripes against steam except for the fact that I can't use in Linux.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's pretty much my only problem with steam.
Speaker 0: people who have other problems with steam is because they're like Technologically incompetent or they believe something about steam.
Speaker 0: that's not true, which is a lot of people.
Speaker 0: It's kind of scary.
Speaker 1: Though if you've never played uplink, I highly recommend you find it and play it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's for Linux and Windows and maybe even Mac.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, you know in movies how whenever there's a hacker unless it's the matrix for the SSH into something.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, and you see like the graphics flying by and someone like breaks into a bank and then they're looking through like pictures of People and movie hacking.
Speaker 1: that's what that game is.
Speaker 0: You hack the way they hack in the movies and it feels like the way the game is done.
Speaker 0: It feels like you're hacking against other guys that are really out there and you can really get into computers and do stuff.
Speaker 0: It's like, you know, there's a computer in the game.
Speaker 0: You can get into it.
Speaker 1: It's real freeform.
Speaker 1: Like there's one mission where someone tells you to like do something to a bank.
Speaker 1: So you do something to the bank.
Speaker 1: but While I was in the bank I noticed that I could just take a bunch of money out of the bank and put it in another account.
Speaker 1: So I did and then a while later that screwed me and the police came and got me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, mostly because I didn't cover my track so well.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's very it's.
Speaker 0: it gets pretty difficult.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of fast clicking which is my only problem with the game and there's a kind of a learning curve.
Speaker 0: But other than that, it's it's very excellent and it gives you this great feeling like you're in danger all the time.
Speaker 0: I like it.
Speaker 0: Darwinia is more of a You.
Speaker 0: you use mouse gestures to control these little guys To go around a map destroying monsters kind of like Pikmin, but you control it with mouse gestures.
Speaker 0: That's the closest I can come to describing.
Speaker 0: It's really neat looking.
Speaker 1: It's very like 3d vector graphics.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's very simple, too.
Speaker 0: It's like they're just little green sticky guys But they're 3d and you have cool powers like lightnings and at least that's that I remember.
Speaker 0: It's been a while since I played it.
Speaker 1: It reminds me a little bit of a good version of that old game populace.
Speaker 0: Kind of it's more like a commitment populace.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I kind of kind of it's got aspects of both.
Speaker 0: Definitely a good game.
Speaker 0: It's no mule.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not a mule.
Speaker 0: so There was news about the Nintendo revolution today.
Speaker 0: That was actually very specific.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's going to have something called play control.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I saw that.
Speaker 0: Basically, it's a parental lockout system.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm very much against censorship But I'm fine with things like this.
Speaker 1: because you're allowed to I say you should be allowed to censor your shut yourself as much as you Want.
Speaker 0: yeah, I think this kind of thing is actually really good because a it doesn't keep me from playing any games You know.
Speaker 0: B You can shut people like Jack Thompson up because you know.
Speaker 0: now a parent can do if they if they buy their kid a revolution They could just set it to like.
Speaker 0: play No game.
Speaker 0: don't play any games that are more than mildly violent and don't play games with any sex or bad words in them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then even if the kid borrows a game from a friend or rents one from blockbuster The parent doesn't even have to pay attention to the ESRB ratings anymore.
Speaker 0: It's just done and this is Nintendo.
Speaker 1: There's no way anyone will be able to claim that it's too difficult.
Speaker 1: You know, there's gonna be a big green button that takes care of everything Absolutely.
Speaker 0: It's probably that big a button on the easy to use remote control.
Speaker 0: even a parent can figure out how to use not a game controller, so that just doubles it right there and Hopefully now this will also Get companies to make you know some more.
Speaker 1: You know mature games for the the revolution because you mean mature as in a good game or mature is in.
Speaker 1: Oh, look, there's lots of blood and gore and adult theme.
Speaker 0: Well, no, no, it's.
Speaker 0: it's the fact that there are a lot of games that people make now where you know Sometimes people make a game like BMX xxx where it's mature just for the sake of being mature to get people to buy it.
Speaker 0: And there are other games that are actually good games but they either give the mature content to add to the selling power because the publisher makes them or They add it's mature because the game is mature.
Speaker 0: It's you know, like Solid Snake is has violence Counter-Strike has violence.
Speaker 0: yeah, how the game is and people I think we're refraining from releasing these games for the GameCube because they had kind of these bad impressions or they or Something.
Speaker 0: and I hope a system like this, you know Helps bring those games around because what can happen is, you know, someone like Jack Thompson might you know?
Speaker 0: Put pressure on these companies and they release games for the Xbox 360 or the ps3.
Speaker 0: But if they release them for the revolution, they won't get pressure because this system is in place.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so it might make them feel better about making revolution games, you know, it's just one more plus plus for the revolution.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean the more not that it needs any more plus yeses.
Speaker 1: I mean pretty much.
Speaker 1: it looks to me, honestly I don't think the PlayStation 3 is going to be much of a contender this time around.
Speaker 1: Nope except in Japan Yeah, but in Japan the Xbox isn't selling at all.
Speaker 0: So yeah, yep Pretty much.
Speaker 0: I got the same philosophy at the revolution that I did for the DS And that was I don't know 100% everything about it yet worst-case scenario.
Speaker 1: It's a virtual boys case scenario.
Speaker 0: It's a virtual boy and you know what with the DS.
Speaker 0: it was the best case scenario.
Speaker 1: It's awesome Yeah, so it was awesome and Mario Kart sealed the deal and now it's my primary gaming.
Speaker 0: The deal was sealed before Mario Kart.
Speaker 0: This is like a golden frosting Bonus stage.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: So, uh my thing of the day thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right I assume everyone out there has seen Lupin the third the castle of Cagliostro.
Speaker 0: That's a great freaking anime.
Speaker 1: If you haven't go see it, it's probably the best Lupin movie.
Speaker 1: and if you don't know who Lupin is Go see that movie.
Speaker 0: It's one of the best Lupin movies.
Speaker 0: There are many great Lupin movies and they are difficult to compare.
Speaker 1: It's my favorite though.
Speaker 1: I really like the Fuma conspiracy.
Speaker 0: Everyone loves that one, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah The only one that I really don't like is Babylon Gold, but I still like it for its MST 3k value.
Speaker 0: It definitely is a high MST 3k value with the motorcycles on clown faces.
Speaker 1: but uh Japan's Princess Sayaka Sayaka got married and her wedding dress was based exactly on the movie that the Female protagonist wore at the end of castle of Cagliostro because she is a huge Miyazaki fan.
Speaker 0: That's pretty awesome.
Speaker 0: It's kind of like that guy who's gonna cosplay his car from Gundam and go into space.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah, you know what this tells you is that the people who grew up with anime in Japan are now getting old, you know There's gonna be a time at which people who played Mario Brothers are gonna run for president.
Speaker 1: Hallelujah It might be the kids who died on the first Guma and gave up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got one question about this though.
Speaker 0: It says that when she married a commoner, she's no longer princess, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm wondering who is there that's appropriate to marry?
Speaker 0: That's not a commoner and it's not in her family.
Speaker 0: Is it incest or Scott's the deal?
Speaker 1: You realize that every European Nation back in the day also had to deal with this and They incest.
Speaker 1: you call one you can marry other royal families like if a princess from Japan I don't know if Japan works this way, but like if a princess from France married a princess from a prince Not utana.
Speaker 1: Yeah from say England or Germany.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: But you know notice how there aren't so many lines of royal blood and notice how a lot of lines of royal blood have issues.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess cuz there was mad incest.
Speaker 0: but apparently like all our sisters have married People who are royal.
Speaker 0: so I'm wondering is there incest still going on or is there something?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Um At least in Europe.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's still incest going on.
Speaker 0: among what few noble families are less still they're still incest thing to this day.
Speaker 1: It's not direct incest.
Speaker 1: It's usually like second cousins.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's not so bad.
Speaker 1: But well, actually in fact I saw an article on FARC.
Speaker 1: It was last year where they proved that first cousins and further.
Speaker 1: There is pretty much zero risk and it really doesn't do anything bad unless you repeat it for dozens of generations.
Speaker 1: So if you're into the it's still not something I support.
Speaker 0: but yeah, no, but I'm still.
Speaker 0: I'm just wondering specifically for the Japanese Wait, what do you mean support?
Speaker 1: How could who would you be?
Speaker 1: What an incest advocate standing on the street like Incest.
Speaker 0: try it out.
Speaker 0: Well, no But I'm not gonna go around saying look just the biology.
Speaker 0: the biology does say that doing your cousin doesn't hurt.
Speaker 0: But I'm not gonna go around the street saying everyone do your cousin if you really wanted to when you were just holding out Cuz it was incest.
Speaker 1: I'm of the mind that other people can do whatever they want as long as it doesn't hurt me or anyone else.
Speaker 0: Yes, they can but I don't want them to find out they can.
Speaker 1: So you got a thing.
Speaker 0: I definitely got a thing.
Speaker 0: so this guy calling himself What did he call himself?
Speaker 0: Ray digerati, that's I guess his screen name.
Speaker 0: He's 34 years old and his occupation IT gigolo.
Speaker 0: Basically what he did is he gave some tech support to this girl he knew right and He was looking at her while he was doing the tech support and he said damn she's hot.
Speaker 0: It would be really nice if I could get paid in sex instead of money for fixing her computer.
Speaker 1: That would work.
Speaker 0: Well, I don't think he did it with her But that was the thought that he had in his mind.
Speaker 0: was that you know It would be great to be paid in sex instead of paid in money for a computer work.
Speaker 0: So he put a thing on Craigslist that said I'll fix your computer for a sexual favor.
Speaker 1: That's fantastic, but isn't it illegal in most states?
Speaker 0: I guess it is.
Speaker 0: that's probably why his eyes are cut out and nose or not in this picture.
Speaker 0: Aha, but Um He's doing it and Girls are liking it.
Speaker 0: there's one story.
Speaker 0: it actually says right here that he went to some girl's house to fix her computer and She didn't even wait for him to fix it.
Speaker 0: She just started, you know, giving him head.
Speaker 1: Well, uh Good game for him.
Speaker 0: It's pretty scary though.
Speaker 1: Like yeah, I'm really not sure what to say to that.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean, you have all these nerdy guys.
Speaker 0: You can't get any and it was so easy this whole time.
Speaker 1: Well, I gotta say it's not really related.
Speaker 1: It's kind of related but not in it.
Speaker 1: All right, so way back.
Speaker 1: I stayed with my girlfriend in the city for a while and one of her roommates in the dorms had a bunch of horrible computer problems, so I sat down and fixed it and The adulations that I received for like the next two days were immeasurable To the point that she even snuck a little like car Thank you card with some money in it into my bag after thanking me like a thousand times previously.
Speaker 1: So having mad computer skills can make you popular.
Speaker 0: I think it's just.
Speaker 0: the problem is a lot of these nerds hiding their basements don't exhibit their computer skills and they can't talk to A woman long enough to know to get her to let her him into their house to fix the computer.
Speaker 0: And I guess this guy seems like a you know an intelligent normal guy so that you can talk to.
Speaker 0: so It says here that his fee is a an orgasm every two hours is pretty fair.
Speaker 1: I'm glad that IBM does not pay me in orgasms.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz then I couldn't eat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and also I wonder how I would receive them and from whom?
Speaker 0: Mmm, good question.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So to move on to our main bit which still does not have bumper music bump a bump bump a bump anime.
Speaker 1: After having watched the third episode of mushi mushishi Which it is definitely the best show currently on that we have access to.
Speaker 0: definitely the best show on.
Speaker 0: that is new.
Speaker 1: So if you need a show to watch right now watch mushishi, it's actually really good.
Speaker 0: Yeah the third episode I didn't like as much as the first and second now and I can kind of see this continuing trend from the second episode.
Speaker 0: It's very similar but It's still very good much better than any other show.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: And while there's a trend every episode is very different.
Speaker 0: It's very different.
Speaker 1: So I have a feeling that we'll see many interesting little mushi.
Speaker 0: I'm just.
Speaker 0: the one thing that's lacking from the show right now is this large overbearing and plot from episode to episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I'm sure that'll come.
Speaker 1: I think it has to do with that River thing though I point out that cowboy bebop had no plot the first time.
Speaker 0: it was well It did it.
Speaker 0: just it had it in the first time.
Speaker 1: It was aired.
Speaker 1: They didn't show any of those plot episodes.
Speaker 1: Well, because they were too violent even in Japan.
Speaker 1: They only showed the episodic ones.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they made the episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, but there were though it they put the plot in separate episodes instead of having it bear out through all.
Speaker 0: But even in kawaii bebop, it does a little tinge of plot here and there, you know I think there will be there.
Speaker 1: they keep alluding to all the things that the main character has done in the past.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think what you're learning about mushi and that eventually is gonna be a big mushi conflict and that'll be the plot.
Speaker 1: maybe or Maybe we'll get to the point where we know about mushi and we'll be like I will figure out what the what the guys should Do before the guy figures out what to do.
Speaker 0: That'd be pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Maybe this would be a good video game like saw with the mushi.
Speaker 1: Ah, I wonder if it is a video game could be.
Speaker 1: maybe We'll check that bears looking into.
Speaker 1: yeah so, uh Gonkotsuo is Finally being released on DVD.
Speaker 1: one DVD is out.
Speaker 1: I think the second one's coming soon.
Speaker 0: I was the only good anime of last season.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Gonkotsuo is based on Alexander Damas is the Count of Monte Cristo Alexandre dumass.
Speaker 1: Yeah Now I Won't really recommend the book because it's long very long.
Speaker 1: But if you like that sort of thing the Count of Monte Cristo is one of my favorite books.
Speaker 1: it's absolutely amazing and My only recommendation that if you decide to read it read the penguin classics Translation.
Speaker 1: it is by far the best translation of that book in my opinion.
Speaker 1: See the only warning really is that Alexandre dumass wrote by the line they paid him per line that he wrote man.
Speaker 0: if people got paid that way today Software would be so crappy.
Speaker 1: Hey, it worked out though because he was very verbose.
Speaker 1: so as a result, it's weird.
Speaker 1: You know most books the action speeds up or slows down or skips bits.
Speaker 1: This book skips nothing and the pace never changes no matter what's going on.
Speaker 1: Everything is always described in the same exacting detail Mm-hmm, and oh, you know, is it crazy detail like too much or it's not too much?
Speaker 1: I mean, I really enjoyed it.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of books you read where they just keep detailing something.
Speaker 0: You know, all right, what happens?
Speaker 1: It's not Hawthorne, okay, but the action move.
Speaker 1: here's the thing.
Speaker 1: the action moves that are very swift pace.
Speaker 1: The only reason it's long is because it covers like 40 years At the same pace pretty much.
Speaker 1: It skips a little bit at one point.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, that's still good That now the show is interesting because it doesn't like.
Speaker 1: the book is chronological.
Speaker 1: The show picks up about a quarter of the way through the book and you don't know what's going on And then it reveals things through flashbacks and characters telling stories.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the The anime takes a lot of liberties in order to add more drama and suspense especially if you haven't read the book and to also emphasize the sort of like Anime things.
Speaker 0: they kind of drew out anything that could be remotely anime and they probably yeah Like they pulled up Beppo a whole lot.
Speaker 0: They pulled up like robots a whole lot and fighting Yeah pulled up vampire stuff a whole lot.
Speaker 1: That was only very small in the book Yeah, but part of it is that the book was very verbose and it seems like the show.
Speaker 1: the show is very very Exactingly faithful to the mood and the feeling of the book, but it takes a lot of liberties into the actual events.
Speaker 0: It's also very arty.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It's very pretty.
Speaker 1: It's it's.
Speaker 0: I mean, you can't really expect anything different from Gonzo I know just let it all hang out.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'd say it's even prettier than the utenna movie.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, definitely.
Speaker 0: It's fancy CG action.
Speaker 0: I'm sure though if Iko Hara had the same equipment the Gonzo has now the utenna movie would have been looking more like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe not as dark like night like color dark You know dark is in mood.
Speaker 0: Who knows
Speaker 1: the one interesting thing because I haven't seen the whole show But I've seen a lot of it and I read the whole book multiple times and in the book I was rooting for the count pretty much the whole time I was on the count side because in the book you see what happened to him to make him the way he is today You see what all those people did to him and why he's getting his revenge.
Speaker 1: So you're with him the whole way and every time he wins you're like, yes go count.
Speaker 1: But in the show you see this count and you're afraid of him and you just see him hurting people and you don't know why You don't like him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I watched a lot more of the show not all of it though And at the beginning I was just cautious.
Speaker 0: I was like that counts up to something.
Speaker 0: and then you saw him doing bad things like are he's a bad guy?
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know, they did something to him But they as far as I watched they weren't a hundred percent clear on what it was.
Speaker 1: I'll put it this way and then eventually you were just like all right This counts a bad guy, but once you real like once you see what they did to him You'll be with him a hundred percent and they all deserve what they get.
Speaker 0: I think it has to do with the vampire in it.
Speaker 0: So whenever they try to imply that someone's an evil vampire, you know.
Speaker 0: Then you're not on their side so much anymore.
Speaker 1: Interestingly enough the whole vampire angle while it is not referred to as such is very faithful to the book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't really elaborate without ruining large swatches of a long book.
Speaker 1: the count the ones the bite One batty batty batty batty to batty batty batty batty.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: But the the dub.
Speaker 0: we just watched it for like five minutes blisteringly average.
Speaker 0: Definitely it's like the same voice actor isn't the same?
Speaker 0: everything is every other freaking anime.
Speaker 1: It's not terrible.
Speaker 1: It's not good.
Speaker 1: It's not worth watching in the dub.
Speaker 1: No, I mean they got a good voice for the count, though It sounds like they did a lot of DSP to make his voice sound deeper and more menacing.
Speaker 0: Well, at least they knew to make it deeper and more menacing.
Speaker 1: Yeah And I got to admit while I don't like the voice actor who does Albert it Just because Albert in the count of Monte Cristo is the most naive character ever to grace anime ever.
Speaker 0: That's definitely well translated in the show.
Speaker 0: So, oh my god, like they should just call him, you know, the count day naivety.
Speaker 1: so picture this.
Speaker 1: you're like sitting in a room with all your friends.
Speaker 1: and then the lights go out and there's a flash of lightning.
Speaker 1: and Then this evil blue looking count with like blue skin and he's wearing all black.
Speaker 1: He's carrying all these implements of various destruction and he walks in and he has a deep evil voice and he looks evil.
Speaker 1: He's glaring around and his reflection doesn't show up in the mirror and all your friends are like, whoa That's a bad dude.
Speaker 1: Stay away from him and you're and you look at him.
Speaker 1: You're like, hey, this guy's awesome.
Speaker 1: Don't rag on that guy.
Speaker 1: Let's be friends.
Speaker 1: Come come to my house.
Speaker 1: You're welcome anywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know when that guy comes into the house to steal all your stuff and he says I'm stealing all your stuff and he points a gun at you.
Speaker 0: Hang out play some cards eat some food make yourself at home.
Speaker 0: Yeah, take my TV.
Speaker 0: So on was it?
Speaker 1: Saturday Sunday We watch a place promised finally the place promised in our early days done by the same guy who did a Hoshi no Koi Or voices from a distant star.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's a good guy.
Speaker 1: It was fantastic and I got to admit I can't write.
Speaker 1: It's hard to talk about it without ruining it because the plot goes in the direction that you did not expect we could talk about it in a meta fashion.
Speaker 1: we can the.
Speaker 1: the show starts and it starts in like the present time and then it goes to a flashback.
Speaker 1: and You you just you're sure that something tragic happened to make the present time in the show exist.
Speaker 1: But then you're in this flashback and you're just waiting for it.
Speaker 1: You see all these happy kids together.
Speaker 1: You're just waiting for something horrible to happen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the thing is is it's like in a tragedy like Romeo and Juliet, you know, okay It's tragic and you know what the tragedy is, you know It's just when and such.
Speaker 0: but this one is not only when but you have no idea what the tragedy is.
Speaker 0: You're just constantly anticipating tragedy.
Speaker 0: In fact, there's one keep happening that might end up tragically.
Speaker 1: There's one scene where they hang it over your head and something happens and someone's in danger.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: That's what happened.
Speaker 1: Oh, and then it doesn't happen.
Speaker 0: You're like, oh that wasn't the tragedy.
Speaker 0: I think out on the tragedy.
Speaker 0: this movie fakes out a lot Yeah, but it's definitely the style is easiest.
Speaker 0: It's so if you seen Hoshi no Koi, it's like oh, it's obvious Lee.
Speaker 0: so similar, I mean scenes on empty trains with light shining through.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know people sitting around and quietness with big landscapes.
Speaker 1: It's very atmospheric It's.
Speaker 0: it's exactly the same way that Hoshi no Koi was like just dead.
Speaker 1: You didn't change his style at all though in terms I think in terms of telling a story and the way it was put together I think he's come very far.
Speaker 0: I like the story of Hoshi no Koi more But this one is more well developed and because it's a whole movie where Hoshi no Koi was a little tiny UAV true But I like those, you know Koi story because it's you know space with a robot and such.
Speaker 0: But this one was all it was.
Speaker 0: this one was also very very cool with the big tower.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah, and I gotta say once again not to spoil anything but There is a scene and it was probably the saddest scene I've ever seen wherein no one died and nothing bad happened yet.
Speaker 1: I was still sad.
Speaker 0: Yeah It makes you sad the whole time.
Speaker 0: It's just how this guy works.
Speaker 0: I wonder if the guy who makes it is like a depressed guy or if he just really likes depressing things.
Speaker 1: But I gotta say I was very pleased with it because while a lot of people in this movie are depressed They're depressed for good reasons.
Speaker 1: They're not just angsty.
Speaker 1: They have a really damn good reason to be depressed.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, that's always good.
Speaker 1: You know, it's not like some people we know.
Speaker 0: Yeah some people But if you haven't seen Hoshino Koi or Place Promise see them both.
Speaker 0: Yes, they're on DVD.
Speaker 0: They're awesome.
Speaker 1: Like really awesome, especially considering the story of this guy.
Speaker 1: He pretty much made a Hoshino Koi in his basement in his spare time.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it was pretty rough and him and him and his wife did the voice acting because it only has two characters and then A studio.
Speaker 1: what studio was it?
Speaker 1: Do you remember?
Speaker 0: I don't know but they helped him out and then he made it really professional with real voice actors and they tell the animation again
Speaker 1: Like they picked him up and they redid everything and they showed like they helped him do it the right way and it was Amazingly popular.
Speaker 0: It's like if you did a really bad song, but you recorded it with like a tiny tape recorder.
Speaker 0: But they they noticed your talent and they just realized you were poor and you couldn't do any better.
Speaker 0: And then they brought you to a studio and gave you brand new instruments and a whole band and backup singers And then you did it for real.
Speaker 0: That's what this is like.
Speaker 1: Yeah So I'm actually really looking forward to see what this guy does next.
Speaker 0: Oh, I don't know if he's doing anything next Looking out every day.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling that he's the kind of person who won't do something unless he thinks it's going to be Good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the question is how much money did plays promised make versus how much it cost to produce?
Speaker 1: I don't think it cost that much to produce.
Speaker 0: I don't think it cost that much either because doesn't have a whole lot of characters And a lot of the animation is made on computers pretty cheaply, you know, and it's pretty much made by one guy.
Speaker 0: I got a look at the credits again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I have to see I Wish I knew the guy's name.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I forget and I don't have it handy right now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, there'll be a link on the page But meanwhile, alright We don't even know what the next place promised movie is gonna be or the next thing from this guy is gonna be.
Speaker 0: But the Fullmetal Alchemist movie is out.
Speaker 0: It has been out and we still haven't seen it.
Speaker 1: Ah, I saw the end of that show last year.
Speaker 0: It was the last Super amazing show that everyone liked and everyone was desperate to see the next episode.
Speaker 1: unlike most anime like this the movie isn't a stupid recap movie or a Recap with a little bit of new footage.
Speaker 1: It's just the plot continues.
Speaker 0: Yeah, no stupid summary movies here.
Speaker 0: it's just new whole new thing with the same characters and everyone wants to see the movie and It's been in theaters.
Speaker 0: It's good.
Speaker 0: I think it's on DVD now and we still can't download it.
Speaker 0: We still can't buy it.
Speaker 0: What gives?
Speaker 1: Yeah, some fan subbers do your illegal business and give us our medicine.
Speaker 0: or hey company do your legal business and freaking just put The thing out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I want to see in the theater and Because it's been so long anyway and my flame to see it has died out a little bit I think I could hold out until they actually show it in the theater because I've seen like every major anime movie in the theater Lately since we live next to New York City.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: I actually wouldn't mind watching the show again.
Speaker 0: I should probably buy all the DVDs when they're in one box.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, if you buy that I'll buy Gonkatsu.
Speaker 0: Oh, awesome.
Speaker 0: I Think you were gonna buy Gonkatsu.
Speaker 0: Oh anyway, I am.
Speaker 1: you're gonna buy FMA anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if anyone knows what the story with the FMA movie is and why it's no one's been able to see it Yeah, and if anyone gets us the movie somehow We'll treat you somehow.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean friggin.
Speaker 0: I heard that the Japanese DVD is gonna have English subtitles But then wouldn't there be a Chinese bootleg today?
Speaker 1: If it actually has English subtitles, we could just buy it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we could just buy it from Japan.
Speaker 0: I don't see why not.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 1: Our DVD player isn't region-free anymore.
Speaker 0: Well, my computer is.
Speaker 1: yeah, my computer kinda is.
Speaker 1: yeah My DVD ROM is so old.
Speaker 1: It can't play dual layer discs Awesome.
Speaker 1: So since we ran out of anime and manga to talk about it's the meta bits And we still need bumper music for all of our internal bits.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I emailed Macanized supremacy today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and in all their awesomeness they said yeah sure You can use our music for whatever as long as you give us credit and don't profit bad ass.
Speaker 0: So, I don't know if their music really fits.
Speaker 1: I love Macanized supremacy, but I don't want to be a show that Takes just their favorite band and uses it as their music.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know if you know, it doesn't really fit with the music we have now But we could just use all their music and then our show would kind of change feeling which I don't know.
Speaker 0: I feel about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I kind of like the feeling as it is.
Speaker 1: I want to find some like old Licensed royalty-free big band music.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know what kind of feeling other people have though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know what kind of feeling I have.
Speaker 0: I don't know a feeling other people have.
Speaker 1: well to get the one bit of feedback I ever got about the music from a cute friend of ours and the quote was your opener is pure sex.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we're one for one.
Speaker 0: we're batting a thousand, you know, DJ pretzel still hasn't emailed us back.
Speaker 1: No, so DJ pretzel if you're listening, uh, thanks.
Speaker 0: I don't think he's listening.
Speaker 1: No, I've emailed him twice and Give him credit every day in the closing bit.
Speaker 0: So yeah I'm sure he won't mind.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've heard radio shows using those ear you nixes.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they got permission and I've heard.
Speaker 0: You know, oh, this is an OC remix podcast.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and his songs are freely downloadable on the internet.
Speaker 0: Anyway, well close out like I looked at his website.
Speaker 1: He seems like a cool dude.
Speaker 0: He's very cool, dude There's no question about it.
Speaker 1: I've been looking through his music to look for other music I could use for other bumpers.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah Also, we're still having trouble figuring out what to do with Monday.
Speaker 1: Yeah, because once again, it's hard to talk about gadgets because then it's just an informative.
Speaker 1: Hey this gadget exists.
Speaker 1: Hey this guy's gadget exists and you know what.
Speaker 1: and gadget exists and you don't need us for that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean we could talk about the merits of different things like, you know Oh Google came out with this new program and then we could talk about the program.
Speaker 0: But it's mo it.
Speaker 0: well, there's a little bit of opinion.
Speaker 0: Like I think it'll be useful.
Speaker 0: I think it won't be useful.
Speaker 0: I think it'll have this effect.
Speaker 0: It doesn't last very long at all.
Speaker 0: No answers are obvious and uninteresting Unless we go all you know stupid.
Speaker 1: and we wanted to talk about sci-fi, but we've all already read the sci-fi classics and There's not much news on that front.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I try.
Speaker 0: you know I'm.
Speaker 0: I try to say I'm a well-rounded geek and I like all the geekeries.
Speaker 0: but sci-fi really not so much as the others.
Speaker 1: See me.
Speaker 1: I like it.
Speaker 1: I'm currently reading through a lot of the old classics.
Speaker 1: I've missed that.
Speaker 0: I've already read.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I just picked up the difference engine.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: It's pretty badass.
Speaker 0: It's pretty badass.
Speaker 0: So if anyone you know Knows what they want to hear on Monday we could.
Speaker 0: where you know, we're still experimenting.
Speaker 0: We're still willing to change our format.
Speaker 0: We'll change Monday to a different type of day.
Speaker 1: I mean Yeah, make it like role-playing Gamer type day, but you do you really want to hear us talk about our characters?
Speaker 0: or you know If we played more board games, you could do like session report type things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's already board game podcasts that are better than ours like.
Speaker 1: that's the reason we don't play geeky or 8-bit music and talk about it because there's a million million shows about music and You guys don't need another one.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and there's already weekly shows that talk about all the big tech news with guys who are you know much bigger than we are.
Speaker 1: So well, not physically No, physically in popularity and radio skill unless they got some.
Speaker 1: Paul Bunyan ism.
Speaker 0: Paul Bunyan ism.
Speaker 1: Dr.
Speaker 1: McNinja is funny.
Speaker 1: read it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: It's very rare that I find a new comic.
Speaker 1: It's the new.
Speaker 1: it's the last new comic I added since Like a year ago when I discovered Scary go round.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's the last new first new comic.
Speaker 0: I've added in like forever.
Speaker 0: I can't even remember Yep, and the one before that was ordered at the stick.
Speaker 0: oops We didn't update yet today at least as far as I saw.
Speaker 0: I have to go check again.
Speaker 0: Yeah These penny arcade is updating more reliably now with their new website.
Speaker 1: Yeah I really wanted to go to their child's play charity dinner, but it's on the west coast.
Speaker 0: They seem to really neglect the East Coast even though they know that most of the readers are on the East.
Speaker 1: Send some love out here.
Speaker 0: I know and seriously like you have an event on the West Coast like two or three times.
Speaker 0: Eventually people kind of like, you know get slightly less excited about it.
Speaker 0: If you put it on the East Coast, it'll renew the vigor.
Speaker 1: Don't think that the Baltimore comic-con was a representation of the East Coast interest in penny arcade.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean they went to the Baltimore comic-con and it was in Baltimore Which is one reason people didn't go.
Speaker 0: the second reason people didn't go is that it was a comic-con which?
Speaker 0: Isn't huge on penny arcade fans?
Speaker 0: I mean sure you're a comic and you think of yourself as fitting in with the comics crew but really The video game people and the anime people are what it's all about.
Speaker 0: Yeah Those are the people who love your comic the most.
Speaker 0: that are the crazy thing
Speaker 1: Of course since you're obviously listening to geek nights and you'll respond to this
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz if they're listening to geek nights, we would totally be hosed when we got wang,
Speaker 1: you know what it'd be like when we were at Otacon and An entertainment system this little NES type band play a little concert and Me and a friend of ours named Conrad a bunch of our friends.
Speaker 1: We're doing crazy dances.
Speaker 1: Like they played a slow song I held up my freaking DS with the screen on which is something you learned from reading what Tycho said about the concert.
Speaker 1: it passed yeah, but no one saw that here in the East Coast.
Speaker 0: or Talking about how penny arcade is mad popular in the East Coast.
Speaker 0: They should come here.
Speaker 1: That's something like that.
Speaker 1: So We did like Tetris dance.
Speaker 1: we did a bunch of cool dances.
Speaker 0: So whatever we also stole from the internet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then later We were going to watch a movie at the con and we ran into the lead singer of the band and he runs over.
Speaker 1: He's like you two guys.
Speaker 1: You're those cool guys from the crowd.
Speaker 1: We looked we're like, holy crap You're that cool guy from the band and it was two groups of people who each thought that the other group of people was really Cool and that was a weird interaction that I never experienced before.
Speaker 1: I've never been a fan of someone who was a fan of me.
Speaker 0: It's really hard.
Speaker 0: I mean usually, you know, we're we know we're a group of cool people, you know, and we kind of do cool stuff.
Speaker 0: But we usually find other groups, but it's usually like a person or maybe to a couple.
Speaker 0: We never find a whole other group.
Speaker 0: That is totally cool.
Speaker 0: You might find a whole nother group with a cool guy in it.
Speaker 0: You never find another cool.
Speaker 0: Totally a hundred percent cool other group.
Speaker 0: They're super rare.
Speaker 1: It's tough.
Speaker 0: Well, you know, the penny arcade has one and we want them to bring it this way.
Speaker 0: Yep, because we need more cool groups out here on the East Coast Eventually, we can get all the cool groups and make the order of the cool groups.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah cool group coalition We could turn it into some sort of Skinner colony the front row crew.
Speaker 1: front row crew crew You know what the more.
Speaker 1: I think we should just turn Monday into general geekery and stories, but but Thursday's is whatever.
Speaker 1: Thursday is free-for-all.
Speaker 1: So Monday is general geekery.
Speaker 1: Then Thursday's are like interview days.
Speaker 0: So then on Thursday, are we gonna make it so we can't talk about geekery?
Speaker 0: on?
Speaker 1: Thursday has to be all non geekery Not non geekery, but like one thing like Monday is a potpourri and Thursday is a like.
Speaker 1: actually I lined up some Interviews.
Speaker 1: as soon as we can get around to going to where these people are We got a bunch of interviews we can do.
Speaker 0: maybe I can try to set up that evil Skype to do an interview.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though a lot of the people we can interview now actually live places we can go.
Speaker 0: That's good Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not mentioning any of their names yet cuz we don't know when we're gonna actually get around to this But I got some cool people lined up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think we need to work on our interviewing skills.
Speaker 0: It never really you ever interviewed someone.
Speaker 1: actually I've interviewed a lot of people.
Speaker 1: I wrote for the school newspaper all through middle school in high school and We did a not a radio show.
Speaker 1: but uh, like the morning announcements talk show in school in high school.
Speaker 1: So I've interviewed a lot of people actually.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I also took classes on how to interview people at RIT Since while I'm an IT geek and I got my degree in IT.
Speaker 1: I Had a lot of free time at RIT.
Speaker 1: I took every class in the professional technical communications major.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know how to interview someone like if I want to hire them or not or to find out about them.
Speaker 0: But I don't know how to interview them.
Speaker 0: like to make them say enter and do entertaining things.
Speaker 1: See it depends on what we're who we're interviewing.
Speaker 1: Like if we interview James Randi or someone Like someone informative or someone we wanted to learn about it would definitely be a question and answer.
Speaker 1: We would like to know this and he tells us about this.
Speaker 1: We asked them for what they want us to tell us things like that an informative interview.
Speaker 1: but if we interview like some cool gamer dude, we happen to know or it's like someone who writes a cool webcomic and Everyone already knows the details about him Then we'll just try to be funny and hang out and talk about whatever.
Speaker 0: Try to get them to say funny things like their webcomic is yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is hit or miss.
Speaker 1: Some webcomic artists are exactly like you'd think they are and some are the exact opposite of like you'd think they are.
Speaker 0: That's generally how it is.
Speaker 1: Yeah, some things are like some things and some things are like other things.
Speaker 1: how insightful.
Speaker 1: And That was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Thanks for listening.
Speaker 0: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feed feed burner.
Speaker 0: comm slash geek night.
Speaker 0: Get the latest episodes as soon as their relief.
Speaker 0: Also, please visit our website at Www.front row crew.com for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at geek nights at gmail.com.