Speaker 1: It's Wednesday December 14th, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: We're not really gonna talk about much because today sucked, but there is some anime news.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So, uh, we've been sitting here for the last hour and There's nothing to talk about today at all.
Speaker 1: He ain't kidding.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it's anime day.
Speaker 0: Normally, we have a lot to talk about but we haven't gotten any Netflix's in to watch yet because we've been busy doing other things.
Speaker 1: Netflix has been a little slow.
Speaker 0: Yes, suddenly.
Speaker 0: I don't know if anyone else is having trouble But Netflix suddenly just slowed the fuck down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, hopefully they'll pick back up soon.
Speaker 0: Yeah But anime news.
Speaker 0: we got a bunch of that because it's anime day and we can talk about it But there's really nothing else that either we have interesting commentary on or that you would care about.
Speaker 1: I mean if you don't believe me go look at the headlines on the geek news sites for Wednesday, December 14th and You're gonna see some pretty dumb crap.
Speaker 0: Mean, all right here.
Speaker 0: Let's all look through some of these headlines on slashdot.
Speaker 0: So IBM promotes Linux partners to highest here.
Speaker 0: Well, I work for IBM and that stuff doesn't really mean anything.
Speaker 1: Yep, let's let's find another one that has a whole lot of comments.
Speaker 1: Alright, here's one new object found at edge of solar system Great on Pluto.
Speaker 0: So, uh, people have been saying that off and on a lot for a long time.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm And we're not gonna get there anytime soon.
Speaker 1: No, it's just a rock means nothing.
Speaker 1: Oh, here's one of the whole lot of comments Cyberattacks on us linked to Chinese military, huh?
Speaker 0: China would have a vested interest in attacking u.s.
Speaker 0: IT infrastructure.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they do.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 0: Fancy that I never would have guessed me either.
Speaker 0: Oh Star Wars galaxies.
Speaker 0: Apparently Lucas arts broke it and the fans are all complaining.
Speaker 1: I would complain too.
Speaker 1: They friggin changed the game.
Speaker 1: It's not the same game you bought.
Speaker 1: It's like come on, man.
Speaker 0: the thing is I have no sympathy for the people playing it because if you like if you're playing a game you're paying for it and They change it.
Speaker 0: You don't like it anymore.
Speaker 0: Stop paying.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah keep paying.
Speaker 1: You're just rewarding them for hurting you know, wait Lucas seems to have a trend of making things and then changing them later.
Speaker 0: Oh who shot first?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I forget because he changed every copy of the film except for the ones that we have.
Speaker 0: You cannot take them and let this go down into posterity in case you're centuries or millennia from now.
Speaker 0: Archaeologists discover this show and they listen to it no matter what evidence you find to the contrary.
Speaker 0: Han Solo shot first.
Speaker 1: not only did he shoot first Greedo didn't shoot at all He just slumped over.
Speaker 1: Yep, and there was an explosion of smoke from under the table to signify this.
Speaker 0: Oh The Dungeons & Dragons online MMO moved from alpha to beta.
Speaker 0: Yep exciting Almost everyone who plays it says it sucks.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: I just had a vision.
Speaker 1: we had to go back a little bit.
Speaker 1: Uh, you know, who's that guy?
Speaker 1: Charlton Heston, right and he holds the gun and he says from my cold dead hands Yeah, replace a gun with with a Star Wars DVD.
Speaker 1: That's correct.
Speaker 0: We should do that we should.
Speaker 0: But uh the D&D online MMO, I mean I was really excited about it when I first heard.
Speaker 1: I wasn't excited at all.
Speaker 0: I know there's like.
Speaker 0: I was excited in an optimistic.
Speaker 0: if they do this, right?
Speaker 0: It would be awesome.
Speaker 0: And you know what they didn't do it, right?
Speaker 1: I don't think it can be done, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could if you said because there were services a long time ago.
Speaker 0: We're basically Yeah, there was a bunch of dungeon master types who ran the game and they just played NPCs and ran content for all the players And it was just this role-playing thing.
Speaker 0: That's not a D&D MMO Why not Dungeons & Dragons?
Speaker 0: and it's massively multiplayer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you have a thousand DMS playing NPCs and just running plots for whatever players are in the game all the time And you happen to use the D&D rules can't make that work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could.
Speaker 0: the problem is it'd be expensive because you have to hire all those DMS.
Speaker 1: Even so it wouldn't work.
Speaker 0: Actually.
Speaker 0: It did work.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of games like that in the 90s.
Speaker 1: Yeah, each game was like five people now.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, no, no, actually I'll if you want since I don't have the rest.
Speaker 0: I don't have it handy now But I'll because I used to play a bunch of them and the more popular ones had a couple hundred people.
Speaker 1: All right, now do that with 50,000 people.
Speaker 0: Well 50,000 altogether means you have a lot more money.
Speaker 0: So you hire a lot more dungeon masters.
Speaker 1: Alright, but now what you're gonna do is you're gonna raise any to pay those dungeon masters.
Speaker 1: You're not gonna be able to compete with other MMOs and charge a reason.
Speaker 0: Oh Well, yeah, the thing is it'd be so much better.
Speaker 0: Maybe people be willing to pay.
Speaker 0: No, it wouldn't work, yeah, you don't know.
Speaker 1: you know what.
Speaker 1: even if people are willing to pay There won't be enough people willing to pay that much money.
Speaker 1: You won't recruit the development cost of developing the game in the first place.
Speaker 0: There might not be so much to develop other than things that we could just do here in our spare time.
Speaker 1: No making a game that you can sell these days like millions and millions of dollars At least if you wanted to be published by a major publisher.
Speaker 1: Sure that if you're gonna have a D&D license which costs a lot of money you're gonna need to do.
Speaker 0: You know that alone doesn't have to be specifically D&D.
Speaker 0: I use D.
Speaker 1: Well, there's the problem.
Speaker 1: It's a D&D MMO.
Speaker 1: That's what it is.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 0: It's it's nothing.
Speaker 0: It's just a crap MMO that happens to be attached to D&D.
Speaker 1: That's what I said.
Speaker 1: That's why I said it was crap in the first place with other people because it had the D&D license thought it was so great.
Speaker 1: Well, I said because it has the D&D licenses.
Speaker 0: Oh, doesn't that make you special?
Speaker 1: It does because I know what's crap and what's not see.
Speaker 0: the thing is you said it was crap before we knew anything about it.
Speaker 0: I said, I don't know.
Speaker 0: I hope it's good.
Speaker 1: I knew it had a D&D license and I knew there was an MMO.
Speaker 1: That's all I needed to know.
Speaker 0: So I hoped it would be good.
Speaker 1: There is no way to make an MMO with the D. hoped hoped wait.
Speaker 0: So you're saying there's no way.
Speaker 0: you're absolutely sir.
Speaker 1: There is no way to make an MMORPG with the D&D license.
Speaker 1: That also does not suck.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: once again because he didn't listen to me I meant D&D.
Speaker 0: when I say D&D I mean role-playing is a generic sense.
Speaker 0: I use that word there.
Speaker 0: I use Kleenex our band-aid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you'd use GURPS.
Speaker 0: you could use any number of a million systems that work just fine.
Speaker 1: But we this one we knew that had the D&D system and therefore I knew that it would suck.
Speaker 1: Okay And I was right great.
Speaker 1: That's what I was saying.
Speaker 1: Fear appear anyway, there's other crap news Here this one.
Speaker 1: This is like the second most commented.
Speaker 1: slash that story the tip of the day.
Speaker 1: What makes a good web font?
Speaker 0: Splendid.
Speaker 1: yeah today The news tap had just like molasses coming out.
Speaker 0: Well, there's real news in the real world, but you guys know all about that.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah We don't want to become a real news show.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right.
Speaker 1: So let's get right on into it.
Speaker 1: Things of the day.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So my thing of the day This isn't a cool thing.
Speaker 0: Like I usually have or a cute thing or an interesting thing Something that ticked me off a lot.
Speaker 0: Now actually if you read the site, it's it actually is interesting because you'll wonder how could people believe this.
Speaker 0: but basically about.com and it's good this is good.
Speaker 0: This is all over dig and it's all over delicious and It just it frightens me that people are so interested in this.
Speaker 0: but basically this article is the ten most puzzling ancient artifacts and It brings up all these Supposedly unexplained weird phenomena all over the world that prove like aliens exist or whatever.
Speaker 1: Well, if it's just an artifact, no, no, no, they're not.
Speaker 0: I'll get I'll explain All right.
Speaker 0: So one of them are these grooves fears that people claim they've been finding in like South African mines like inside of fossils and inside of ancient rocks recently and They claim that they're dated to you know, 2.8 billion years ago, but they look man-made.
Speaker 0: The problem is they don't say that they've never been tested.
Speaker 0: No one's ever actually touched these things.
Speaker 0: They're described as composed of a solid bluish metal with flecks of white.
Speaker 0: Because I'm sure if a scientist, you know tested one of these things He couldn't tell you that it was just a piece of metal or what kind of metal it was.
Speaker 1: Hmm, and they've never actually done a carbon test.
Speaker 0: You can't carbon test inorganic Scott.
Speaker 1: Oh, I didn't know.
Speaker 0: carbon-type dating is actually kind of crappy for most things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they're just or like these dropa stones.
Speaker 0: these are even worse.
Speaker 0: Basically to some of these are some spirits like disc shaped stones that have some markings on them and this crackpot Scientists claims that they the the markings on them which are almost microscopic are actually this ancient alien language that he was able to translate and apparently it depicts Alien ships that crashed on earth of these people called the dropa and whose descendants left them in this cave Except that one.
Speaker 0: These were totally debunked, you know dozens and dozens of times.
Speaker 0: and to the guy who talks about him sells them Sells them sells them.
Speaker 0: you can buy them from him.
Speaker 1: Does he have an infinite supply?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: the only Because if it was like if it was really Stones from aliens you imagine there's only a few of them and he doesn't have so many.
Speaker 0: Oh, we've got a whole bunch of them hundreds of stone discs Hundreds of me buried in the dust of ages on the cave so we can somehow buy them all and then he wouldn't have anymore.
Speaker 0: The only other person who has ever even made reference to these things in a positive light is the scientist who?
Speaker 0: Surprisingly enough also sells them.
Speaker 0: Oh Only of the ten things on this site seven of them have been 100% fully and beyond a reasonable doubt debunked by science.
Speaker 0: Wow And what?
Speaker 0: the only one that's even legitimate is the Baghdad battery, which?
Speaker 1: what's the Baghdad battery?
Speaker 0: It was a battery.
Speaker 0: Well, it was a an artifact that was found a while ago in Around where Baghdad is today.
Speaker 0: All right, and it was basically a battery.
Speaker 0: It was a clay pot with a rod through it and it basically if you fill it with an acidic or an alkaline liquid It generated a small current and it looks like they used it in ancient times to electroplate things with various metals like gold.
Speaker 1: That makes sense.
Speaker 1: Yeah, why is that an unexplained artifact?
Speaker 0: Because they talk about oh, how come humans had batteries so long ago And then they didn't have many more than they rediscovered them because they didn't realize that it was electricity in a battery.
Speaker 1: And they they just knew that it was a way to plate things and they didn't realize that.
Speaker 0: The issue was that in the Middle Ages They didn't have electroplating or anything.
Speaker 1: The knowledge was lost, you know Dark Ages Maybe the knowledge is lost but also it could have been that just people didn't want to plate things anymore So they didn't do it in those forgot.
Speaker 0: No, most likely the knowledge was just lost during the Dark Ages Hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but oh it could have been like one asshole came up with electroplating because we've only found one battery, right?
Speaker 0: I believe they found more since then.
Speaker 0: There's actually a lot of cool articles on these batteries.
Speaker 1: No, that's pretty cool Alright, but if it was like just a few it could have been like one asshole figured it out and didn't tell anyone and then He died.
Speaker 0: Well considering the preponderance of electroplated artifacts from that era.
Speaker 1: Oh All right, then.
Speaker 0: Yeah mine and Similar things have been found in other older ancient cultures.
Speaker 1: Just just guessing possibility.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but pretty much everything else on this website.
Speaker 0: It's just complete bullshit.
Speaker 1: I'm sure Randy will find out about it and make a nice little yeah on Friday.
Speaker 0: So I urge all of you out there who use delicious.
Speaker 0: if you see things like this You know, that's just obviously false.
Speaker 0: Tag it with the flim-flam tag.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And if you want to see a list of things that are false just go to delicious slash tag.
Speaker 1: slash flim-flam One word all one word FLIM FLAM.
Speaker 1: Yep, and you'll see all kinds of things that are bullshit.
Speaker 1: So if you see something and you're not sure if it's quite right or not You can ask Randy.
Speaker 1: you can go search his site or you can check delicious flim-flam and see if we've found it.
Speaker 1: Also because we might have and tagged it now Randy of course being James Randy the founder and leader of the James Randy Educational Foundation, which is the premier organization for finding complete bullshit like this and pointing it out.
Speaker 0: We're going to do a whole show on Randy at some point And actually we're gonna try to interview him if we can.
Speaker 0: but that's down the road way down the road.
Speaker 1: All right, my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah If you're in prison, they don't let you have so much stuff.
Speaker 1: They really only let you have what your clothes Like some plastic Utensils in the kitchen.
Speaker 0: prison ain't so bad.
Speaker 0: You can make sangria in the toilet Of course, it's shank or be shanked.
Speaker 1: Oh, of course Yeah, if you drama anyway You know you get a towel get a roll of toilet paper Maybe a plastic bag.
Speaker 1: You know, you don't get a lot of stuff.
Speaker 1: so Prisoners who need things or want things And having a lot of time to think about things are really good at finding ingenious ways to combine normal everyday items into other objects.
Speaker 1: and there is in fact websites and other things devoted to collections of interesting and intuitive and ingenuity prisoner inventions and Some of them are actually really cool.
Speaker 0: Then you give us an example.
Speaker 1: Well, some guys made a chess set by carving out pieces of soap into pieces.
Speaker 1: All right another guy took a roll a plastic bag and he rolled some You know a towel around it and he turned it into sort of like Like a love buddy Great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I need you to steal a banana from the cafeteria.
Speaker 1: I Don't know Because it's shank or be shanked, of course, of course All right, here we go.
Speaker 1: They also made a cigarette lighter out of almost nothing.
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: almost nothing like out of the air?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Well, it's a couple paper clips, right and You know.
Speaker 1: he took some ice cream spoons and he glued them together with paper clips in them to make a plug that can go into the outlet in the wall and Then he you know, he had more paper clips coming out going into a saltwater solution and Get the electricity and use that to light cigarettes, you know, because there was a little where the paperclip came out.
Speaker 1: There was a little.
Speaker 1: he made a little coily bit and it heated up.
Speaker 1: He could also plug devices into it if he had a you know, something that plugged into the wall.
Speaker 1: That's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Aha.
Speaker 1: I mean I wouldn't have the balls to stick paper clips into the outlet in the wall.
Speaker 0: Trying to make a thing to light cigarettes In power devices and being shocked by a hundred and ten volts isn't so bad.
Speaker 1: Isn't it 120?
Speaker 0: Actually, there's a lot of it's 110 and it's 120. awesome.
Speaker 0: it can be anywhere between because it's actually neither and Depending on what school electricity you went to or just where you live people say 110 220 or 120 240 Not bad.
Speaker 0: It's pretty much 50/50 Half.
Speaker 0: maybe we'll do a show about that if we get bored enough.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but that's pretty crazy.
Speaker 0: making a cigarette lighter that plugs into the wall out of paper clips Wow, so I guess prisoners aren't stupid or at least they're canny like animals.
Speaker 1: Well, some of them are Not stupid.
Speaker 0: well considering that most people in prison in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Today are in there for nonviolent crimes that didn't hurt anyone but themselves.
Speaker 0: yeah, it's you know smoking a little bit of marijuana or Being a dissident everything sucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah sucks looks like Mostly just cuz.
Speaker 0: we got nothing to talk about today and this is like the worst show we've done yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now I see why a lot of people don't do the daily shows.
Speaker 0: I Promise we'll have better tomorrow at least guaranteed, yeah Really?
Speaker 1: Cuz something has to happen tomorrow.
Speaker 1: But I guess I never really thought about like this, you know, it feels like there's always something happening.
Speaker 1: So I never really imagined that there would be a day where nothing happened.
Speaker 0: At least nothing happened that we can really talk about on the show that you'll care about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean lots of stuff happened.
Speaker 0: Iran said the Holocaust didn't happen.
Speaker 0: Tookie Williams got executed.
Speaker 0: There's riots all over Sydney.
Speaker 0: There's the riots in France were going on, but They're still going on in France not per se but there's still a lot of racial violence going on.
Speaker 0: is the aftermath great?
Speaker 1: Yeah, great.
Speaker 0: So anyway, it's anime day Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Any new anime except mushishi, which we're still watching.
Speaker 1: She's great waiting for episode eight.
Speaker 1: I think now.
Speaker 1: Yeah Mmm.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So, uh remember Shinsen subs.
Speaker 0: We talked about them last anime day.
Speaker 1: how funimation went and harassed them and said hey stop torrenting.
Speaker 0: Well, we got a follow-up as to why that happened.
Speaker 1: Well it bears.
Speaker 1: apparently Shinsen was actually still distributing many licensed Available things.
Speaker 1: Oh So they deserve what they got.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Mean, I guess it's one of the standpoints of the anime community.
Speaker 0: Is that the piracy is there?
Speaker 0: There's a lot of piracy But ever there's kind of this code of honor where most people stop distributing or stop Downloading and the DVDs still get bought.
Speaker 0: everyone makes their money and no one goes after anyone.
Speaker 0: When a group like Shinsen kind of breaks the code bad things happen.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: It's a delicate balance and frankly I want to keep getting my fans up.
Speaker 0: so Bad fans arbors out there.
Speaker 0: Stop it.
Speaker 1: It's like the code of the schoolyard.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know you you might be able to break the code of the schoolyard and you know You'll.
Speaker 1: you'll screw things up and you might get ahead on that but later everyone will come and destroy you.
Speaker 1: So I highly don't recommend Doing that though actually some cool news.
Speaker 0: Viz is putting out their signature collection of manga in other words The manga that Scott likes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they cut.
Speaker 0: they say it's going to be a more sophisticated Mature manga.
Speaker 1: so they used to have the editors choice manga and that would be all the really cool mangas that Weren't crazy popular or well-known, but they were like the ultra high quality, you know kind of like Citizen Kane.
Speaker 1: No one really likes to watch it, but it's really good.
Speaker 0: I like to watch it.
Speaker 0: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 1: It's not really as entertaining as like the matrix.
Speaker 1: I could watch the matrix a hundred times.
Speaker 1: I could not watch citizen Kane nearly as many times.
Speaker 0: I could probably watch citizen Kane more than I could watch the matrix.
Speaker 1: We not that.
Speaker 1: well, I'm talking about the first one only here All right, but I mean I could watch the first matrix a bajillion times and every time.
Speaker 1: yeah Well, that's you know, that's how it is.
Speaker 1: But anyway, these are like the high quality mangas of awesome like Phoenix.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I got the first volumes of Phoenix from the editors choice printing.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of disappointed that they're gonna reprint it.
Speaker 1: I'm wondering if they're gonna reprint the Phoenix that was never printed yet.
Speaker 1: Cuz I've got five volumes and I know there's more Phoenix than in those five volumes.
Speaker 1: hmm, so if they reprint the more of Phoenix in a different like size or shape or Cover.
Speaker 0: that's like a look good on my shelf, but this could be really good because I mean not too long ago We discovered a type of manga that really didn't what we'd known about it But we discovered it as in.
Speaker 0: we got it and read it all.
Speaker 0: Manga that we'd never really known like mature Yakuza The kind of manga we like, you know, we didn't really know existed.
Speaker 0: It's pretty the opposite of the popular manga out now.
Speaker 0: Yep, like sanctuary Eagle.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yep, apparently they're gonna put Golgo 13 in this new long and I might buy that.
Speaker 0: because yeah for those of you Don't know Golgo 13 take Lupin and James Bond and put them together and then make it more serious.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's very serious and not funny.
Speaker 1: I mean and there's a whole lot of Golgo 13 stuff There's animes and video games and all kinds of video games.
Speaker 0: all suck.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Oh my god The manga is the real deal or so I've heard.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we haven't actually read it.
Speaker 1: So when that comes out, I'll definitely be buying it at least the first volume to see if it's good.
Speaker 0: But I think this is gonna be a really good thing mostly because a lot of these manga They either never came out in the US or some things like they were released here.
Speaker 0: They're out of print and they're really rare and hard to find.
Speaker 0: It took us for freaking ever to get all the sanctuary together.
Speaker 1: Yeah now I finally it's now.
Speaker 1: it's easy to find.
Speaker 1: I know where it's at.
Speaker 1: But You know, it's not.
Speaker 1: It's thing is back in the days When anime was still new and that was sort of what the popular thing was before Tokyo pop Discovered like little girl.
Speaker 1: shojo was the way to go.
Speaker 1: then those are the kinds of mangas they were bringing over.
Speaker 1: you would get your Crying Freeman and your sanctuary and your eagle and all that stuff and they didn't sell that well Just because the market wasn't that big back then.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And then when they switched up the market and Tokyo pop came around a couple years ago and they started doing what they're doing now They didn't really reprint those things and they've been out of print and no one cared about him and forgot about him Except for the people like us.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: We kind of discovered them and they were awesome and we could never find him.
Speaker 0: I remember we'd be digging through discount or bargain whatever bins in the middle of conventions looking for like one random episode Or one random issue or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like first president of Japan.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 1: all right, so Ghibli Is making a new movie Ghibli.
Speaker 1: now, there's two bits of news about this movie - yeah The first bit of news about this movie is that it's being directed by his son Miyazaki son, huh?
Speaker 1: Goro Miyazaki and Miyazaki supposedly is not so happy because he doesn't want his son to be a director.
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 1: It doesn't say Hmm.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, we'll see how it turns out.
Speaker 1: It just says Miyazaki senior does not want his son to become a director.
Speaker 1: I Don't know what that's about But alright, just just keep that in mind.
Speaker 1: great to the movie.
Speaker 1: a lot of Ghibli movies are based on books and things What was I wasn't how based on some book children's but based on a book called howl's moving castle.
Speaker 1: All right, okay This is actually based on a book that I've heard of and read.
Speaker 1: I've actually read all of the series of books except for one which I have and I just didn't read yet the earth sea series By Ursula K Le Guin.
Speaker 0: I've always been meaning to read though.
Speaker 1: It's real easy to read.
Speaker 1: if you haven't read it Just go get all the volumes.
Speaker 1: You could read them all in like double days because they're not written at the highest reading level You know in terms of big words, and it's really fast to read.
Speaker 1: You know a teenager could read it in like a week, you know all of them But it's very deep in its meaning.
Speaker 1: So even someone who's old can get a lot out of it.
Speaker 1: I didn't even find it until like, you know, three or two or three years ago.
Speaker 0: In fact, didn't you know?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I bought all of them wild.
Speaker 0: Would you leave one out in the rain?
Speaker 1: No, that was.
Speaker 1: that was kidnapped by the guy who wrote Treasure Island, ah It was a pirate book.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I just remember that because you you were like we all went inside and there's.
Speaker 0: you saw this book laying out and you thought It was my book.
Speaker 0: So you left it outside, you know, haha screw rim.
Speaker 0: And then you went out the next day and it was your book and it rained.
Speaker 1: the rain was the problem.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so the book the name of the movie is called ghetto Senki tales from Earthsea ghetto.
Speaker 1: I Know this because I could figure it out.
Speaker 1: the name of the main character in Earthsea is GED GED so calling it ghetto Senki.
Speaker 1: It's like.
Speaker 1: I think it's the story of GED Something like that and I don't know.
Speaker 1: Well can ask Emily somebody Japanese tales from Earthsea which is the universe that the World that the book is written in.
Speaker 1: and there's actually a poster for the movie available online that I can see and it shows who GED Obviously staring up and looking at this dragon, right and looking at it I can go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's about.
Speaker 1: you know, having seen many Ghibli movies and read all the books I can look at that and I say yeah, that's pretty accurate.
Speaker 1: You know, that's about what I expected and That means it's probably gonna be really good.
Speaker 1: however, the one thing that bothers me is that GED at least as far as I can see him in this picture is really white and A big part of the story is that he's not really white.
Speaker 1: He's like dark.
Speaker 0: So what's this?
Speaker 0: I hear about?
Speaker 0: a Naruto marathon?
Speaker 1: Well, you know how like on New Year's like the TV channels tend to do big marathons of things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I remember watching all bond last year.
Speaker 1: Oh, I like the all bond ones.
Speaker 1: I like the all Twilight zones on sci-fi channel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the outer limits sometimes.
Speaker 1: Well Cartoon Network They used to do like these cartoon cartoon things.
Speaker 1: They would show the cartoon the cartoons that were only on Cartoon Network.
Speaker 1: They would just keep showing those all day for like the whole weekend even sometimes and I liked it.
Speaker 1: I remember the when I first got Cartoon Network, that's what they had on and it was like, ooh, all right but it looks like you can really tell that things are changing in this country because December 31st is gonna be eight and a half hour.
Speaker 1: Naruto marathon gray 17 straight episodes That's cool.
Speaker 1: If you like Naruto, yeah, I'm not the biggest fan of Naruto.
Speaker 1: I think I watched the first 13 episodes and then I realized that The last like eight of them were a single fight.
Speaker 0: The show is much better when they were in ninja school.
Speaker 0: It was just funny.
Speaker 0: ninja school antics.
Speaker 1: I know it's like you watch the first few episodes like.
Speaker 1: this is the greatest show.
Speaker 1: ninja school.
Speaker 1: You read the first manga You're like ninja school.
Speaker 1: Yes, the rest of the thing isn't about ninja school It's just fighting.
Speaker 1: they should just made a ninja school manga.
Speaker 1: It would have been the greatest.
Speaker 1: I would have be still be buying it.
Speaker 1: Oh Well, it's gonna make some people happy.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yep, and it definitely shows that anime is Seriously on the move.
Speaker 1: and the last thing isn't really so important Sunrise, you know the animation studio that does like cowabeebop and all those other good shows, you know usually under bandai.
Speaker 1: They're making a new robot show which means potential new good anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying it is good But it shows more potential than most of the shows that I've seen in the past couple years.
Speaker 1: So it's called zega pain Zega pain zega pain.
Speaker 0: So it's a robot show.
Speaker 1: I Think I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: it looks like it might be a one robot show which is the good kind.
Speaker 1: So we're gonna have to find out.
Speaker 0: Could be I mean Gundam seed wasn't a one robot show.
Speaker 1: that's true.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying only the one robot shows are good.
Speaker 1: I'm saying this looks like it has serious potential for good.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also I point out that you hate giant robo, which is the quintessential one robot show.
Speaker 1: I don't like giant robots.
Speaker 0: a giant robo is awesome.
Speaker 0: I like Gigant or in fact, it's in the Netflix queue.
Speaker 0: We're gonna watch it.
Speaker 1: No, I'm not gonna watch it.
Speaker 0: I'm fine.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: so, huh, basically We had nothing today, this is probably probably the low point.
Speaker 0: I mean you gotta we got off days every now and then you got to give us that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at least we're not like, you know, not every penny arcade comic is equal But they come out with one even if they come out with it at 4 p.m Now,
Speaker 0: hey, man, no Today's penny arcade mostly because Scott and I have basically had that exact conversation multiple times only with different words and different bits, but the same idea.
Speaker 1: Yep It's always scary how comics and things mirror real life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or maybe real life mirrors comics and things.
Speaker 1: Dun Dun Dun BB OCS always did the best job of that God Bastard.
Speaker 0: Yep All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, we got nothing.
Speaker 0: Rather than forcing ourselves to talk for a lot longer You'll get an extra long episode tomorrow with good stuff.
Speaker 0: Yes, I'm sleep and hopefully stuff will happen in the world that we can complain about.
Speaker 1: Mmm visit our website.
Speaker 0: actually, yeah visit the forums because the show from Monday is still generating a lot of arguments and feedback and yelling and Screaming and it's fantastic
Speaker 1: which gives high hopes for next Monday show Which is a continuation
Speaker 0: because our how to buy or how to build a computer series looks like it's gonna be our most popular Series ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess the informative does work and we were trying to shy away from it.
Speaker 1: What do we know?
Speaker 1: Yeah, so front row crew calm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, go to the website Go there.
Speaker 1: I know people are listening who have never been there.
Speaker 0: go We know actually quite a quite a number of people are listening.
Speaker 1: Yeah front row crew calm and Then click on forum and then talk.
Speaker 1: it is fun Huh?
Speaker 0: If you don't join our forums, we'll keep doing shows like today's instead of ones like Monday and Tuesday.
Speaker 1: No, then just stop listening and go away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe yeah.
Speaker 0: All right, we're out and Tomorrow, hopefully we'll have something.
Speaker 0: hopefully whoo The beard and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Thanks for listening.
Speaker 1: Please.
Speaker 1: Remember to point your favorite podcatcher at beads dot bead burner comm slash geek nights.
Speaker 1: Get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Speaker 1: Also, please visit our website at www.front row crew comm for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at geek nights at gmail.com.