Speaker 1: It's Thursday December 1st, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about geek nights.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I get to work this morning and the boss has this extra LCD monitor on his desk.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh, and he says some user did something.
Speaker 0: I thought was impossible.
Speaker 0: He burned an image onto the screen of an LCD monitor.
Speaker 0: Really now I'm like wait a minute.
Speaker 0: that can't be because the way an LCD monitor works How can that be?
Speaker 0: that would mean that like the memory chip had to have the same?
Speaker 0: Frame stored in it and then it had to be a memory chip that saved the state like a flash or a hard drive And that's not what it is.
Speaker 1: So was there actually an image there?
Speaker 0: No, it wasn't an image burned into the screen.
Speaker 0: My boss just said that but it was very broken Very broken.
Speaker 0: you turn this thing on.
Speaker 0: the screen went white heat white and Gradually the top of it got dark dark dark and then the middle of it got dark and then the sign there were these colored Lines.
Speaker 0: all it was broken as hell.
Speaker 0: Wow, so we opened it all the way and took out every piece and I knew how LCD monitors worked before but now I have a much much better understanding.
Speaker 1: You are aware that there are various carcinogens and things in there.
Speaker 0: right and an LCD?
Speaker 1: Yeah, not as bad as a CRT, but the you shouldn't open them.
Speaker 0: Well, let me explain to you what's in there.
Speaker 0: first You take off the plastic.
Speaker 0: All right, and then there's the LCD screen itself.
Speaker 0: The LCD screen is maybe one quarter of a millimeter thick and it has this little circuit board attached to it and one side of it is the side.
Speaker 0: that's the front of the actual front of your screen and the other side of is ultra shiny and Awesome like your screen was when you bought it and I kind of wish that side was facing out.
Speaker 0: But anyway, and that's the screen.
Speaker 0: the rest of it is all the other stuff.
Speaker 0: it's pretty crazy.
Speaker 0: and Beyond the LCD screen are these two really thin pieces of plastic.
Speaker 0: They're like kind of lens filter II things.
Speaker 0: But they're you know, like.
Speaker 0: what are those lenses with the circles?
Speaker 0: What are they called?
Speaker 0: They used to magnify stuff on the beach and stuff what you mean a magnifying glass Plastic sheets that are lens.
Speaker 0: Oh Fresno Fresno.
Speaker 0: It's like one of those.
Speaker 0: only imagine if it's like.
Speaker 0: the grooves are so fine and precise And there's millions of them all over the place.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: And then there's another one that's kind of white to keep the color straight.
Speaker 0: and Then there's this piece of plastic.
Speaker 0: That's like three-quarters of an inch thick just a big hunk of plastic.
Speaker 0: That's the size of the screen.
Speaker 0: It's freaking huge and all that piece of plastic does is Take light in the top and send it straight out the front in an even square.
Speaker 0: The light is yes he's too thin sticks of light bulb that go inside this thing at the top and shoot down into the piece of plastic from the top.
Speaker 0: and That's the whole thing except for the power supply and a very very tiny circuit board that translates VGA into an array of LCD Controlling electricity, uh-huh, because I did want to smash open a CRT and there's a lot of complex tiny machinery in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and LCD is freaking simple as hell.
Speaker 0: That's why laptop, you know that they can just frickin stick them on there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're really.
Speaker 0: I mean, they're so expensive.
Speaker 0: But the expensive part is just that LCD screen because there's some stuff in it That's like rare or hard to get or something.
Speaker 1: but and yields they've gotten a lot better, but they're still not perfect.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean the rest of it is like a piece of plastic some light bulbs two very simple cheap-ass circuits and like some buttons is Actually, you know really interesting this pictures on my flicker actually of the pieces of plastic and lenses and huh?
Speaker 0: My co-worker holding the LCD part.
Speaker 1: because I can tell you one thing if you ever decide to smash open a CRT bad idea That glass is a lot thicker than you think it is and you're not gonna break it no matter how hard you try.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we didn't actually break the part that had the liquid crystal in it, you know, okay That's what I'm saying is you'll see the LCD is just this very very thin thing That is just as liquid crystal in it.
Speaker 0: You don't?
Speaker 0: we didn't break it.
Speaker 0: We just took all the layers of the actual monitor out.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh, you know It'd be like equivalent if I opened up a CRT and looked around as opposed to press smashing it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but imagine if a CRT wasn't a tube.
Speaker 0: It was a bunch of layers of things.
Speaker 0: You took the piece of glass off and then you took whatever was behind the glass off and then there was something else there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, it's it's very cool All right.
Speaker 0: So remember that a photo guy who they Vigilante eat.
Speaker 1: Yeah, apparently the guy they vigilante Got gotten.
Speaker 0: Well, the the story is is that number one that did hurt their business when they were vigilante, which is good - the reason that this whole thing started which I wasn't 100% clear on was The guy had been shopping for the camera.
Speaker 0: He found the good price on their website and When he tried to order it They didn't want to sell it to him for that price.
Speaker 0: And when he said I demand it for that price I won't negotiate with you.
Speaker 0: They said we're out of stock lying that they were out of stock.
Speaker 0: Yep, so, you know, he got pissed and he was fighting not with the owner of the company But with an employee named Steve Phillips, right?
Speaker 0: The owner of the company the this the president is the owner of price right photo.
Speaker 0: ed lopez emailed the guy Apologized, you know said a bunch of you know, I guess nice.
Speaker 0: Okay things Told him that you know, it was all.
Speaker 0: they fired Steve Phillips and everything and you know, it's supposedly a happy ending.
Speaker 0: The one thing though is that they're like the company seems to be acting like Steve Phillips was the only one doing that BS crap.
Speaker 0: But According to you know people on forums who posted things about price right photo long before this happened You know had complaints about the same thing from other people.
Speaker 0: Yep Policy that's now gone.
Speaker 1: They'd advertise the price but they only actually sell it to you if you bought a whole bunch of overpriced accessories.
Speaker 1: Yeah And if you didn't buy the accessories See, it's like Best Buy.
Speaker 1: Best Buy always has the loss leader and then they make their money because they sell, you know, the $30 USB cable And the monster power strip.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all that all that Randy bullshit.
Speaker 0: monster cables don't make it sound any better than no radio shack cables.
Speaker 0: They will make it so that you have to use less amplification to get the same volume unless you're using Minuscule amount.
Speaker 1: if you're using digital you can use a five cent cable.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: It doesn't matter.
Speaker 1: It's bits.
Speaker 1: Yep But uh at least with Best Buy they can't refuse to sell you the loss leader by itself.
Speaker 1: They can try to make you not want to go into your store by making the store unpleasant to people with a brain But they can't really kick you out.
Speaker 0: I'm doing a real good job of making the store unpleasant to people with brains Except for the fact that we still shop there fairly often.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't shop there So I go there to look buying rarely very rarely how we bought our DVD shelves there Then no place else had one DVD shelves like the hardest thing to get.
Speaker 1: yeah furniture stores either have really really Expensive ones that are not exactly what you need or they're so cheap.
Speaker 0: They just fall apart or they're ugly Yeah, or people have fancy ones that don't hold.
Speaker 0: I need to hold a great quantity in a small amount of space.
Speaker 0: No one has real efficient ones.
Speaker 1: Well, someone did Best Buy.
Speaker 0: Well, it wasn't really that good.
Speaker 0: It was just the most efficient we could find.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah Okay So, uh bell south, oh, yeah, my grandma has bell south DSL and you know She doesn't know how to use it.
Speaker 0: But other than that they suck.
Speaker 1: take heart in what I'm about to say because according to what I've read since then Pretty much the entire rest of the industry thinks this is batshit and is ignoring this guy as much as we're going to ignore this Guy,
Speaker 0: well, so they suck and now they said something that makes them suck worse.
Speaker 1: basically, they think that the way the internet should work is that say I'm an ISP I Should be able to offer to Yahoo the ability to pay money to me and in return I'll make Yahoo load faster than say Google.
Speaker 0: How's it gonna work?
Speaker 1: Oh Oh with some magic restructuring of basic internet architecture on a global scale.
Speaker 1: You know enforcing QoS and I mean QoS is kind of a good idea except for the fact that The moment you make a bit that says this packet is more important than any other packet Everyone's who's smart is gonna have all their packets have that bit and then every packet in the world I have that bit and then that's that it doesn't work anymore.
Speaker 0: Nope doesn't work.
Speaker 1: And this guy goes on and on and he makes silly analogies.
Speaker 1: He's just like the guy who said that the Utah guy who said that there should be a porn port.
Speaker 1: This is someone who is in a high position Involving technology, but who does not understand the technology?
Speaker 1: He is actually responsible for and is trying to use it as though it's a different medium.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Well, it's a big problem.
Speaker 0: is someone's a businessman and they think you know, they're trying to think of business things.
Speaker 0: So they just imagine stuff up and they know nothing about technology whatsoever.
Speaker 0: So they'll think up any old business thing and they'll say oh, wouldn't it be great, you know?
Speaker 0: Look, these people are making money and they're using Ma the hardware that I own my wires to make their money.
Speaker 0: I should.
Speaker 0: I should be able to make money by charging them money because I'm not making enough money with these flat fees from Customers.
Speaker 1: he probably makes the most incorrect analogy ever regarding this.
Speaker 0: so he thinks some stuff up and then he invents, you know some Dream of how the technology works.
Speaker 0: But because he knows nothing is wrong.
Speaker 1: If I go to the airport, I can buy a coach standby ticket or a first-class ticket in the shipping business.
Speaker 1: I can get two-day air or six-day ground.
Speaker 1: I don't think he realizes that I can go to an ISP and buy a very tiny pipe or an OC 48.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see that's the correct analogy to that You know, but the funny thing is the Bell South is lobbying on behalf of this.
Speaker 1: but because they don't understand it They're actually lobbying against themselves.
Speaker 1: They're they're lobbying in Congress.
Speaker 1: right now in the house.
Speaker 1: There's a bill in the house that will prohibit network operators from impeding internet contents or impeding internet traffic based on content.
Speaker 1: So if I run an ISP and this bill is passed I won't be able to say slow down sites.
Speaker 1: I disagree with or block them just because I disagree with them.
Speaker 0: So it's a good law.
Speaker 0: We want.
Speaker 1: yes, it's a good law.
Speaker 1: All right, he is supporting the law because he says that.
Speaker 1: And this is fantastic.
Speaker 1: What I envision doesn't impede anyone.
Speaker 1: it just speeds other people up.
Speaker 0: You realize my speeding one person up.
Speaker 0: You're slowing another one down.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, it can't go.
Speaker 0: right now Everything goes as fast as it can possibly go.
Speaker 0: The only way to make one person go faster is to slow other people.
Speaker 0: you can't understand technology.
Speaker 0: there should be a thing where like if you want to Like say some.
Speaker 0: if you want to legislate something you have to prove that you know about it.
Speaker 0: like.
Speaker 0: there should be a law that says the problem.
Speaker 0: any law that is that proposed that proposes any legislation that proposes something which is not Scientifically or technologically feasible is automatically void period.
Speaker 0: It would be so simple.
Speaker 1: You know what they're effectively void anyway, because even if the laws get passed there's no way to implement them.
Speaker 1: and Yeah, people who lose are the taxpayers who pay for it.
Speaker 0: I know but think about this.
Speaker 0: someone could make a law right that says Everyone Must go into outer space.
Speaker 0: Well, that's not technologically feasible.
Speaker 0: for everyone to go into outer space.
Speaker 0: I'm just thinking of something random and crazy.
Speaker 0: Okay, but you know, of course, no one's gonna make this law, but someone could You know, we should have it in writing that if someone makes a law that's not technologically feasible That the law is void the whole thing just doesn't count.
Speaker 0: even if every congressperson voted for it Even if the president signed it doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: if it's technologically infeasible it doesn't count.
Speaker 1: the thing is there are a lot of crazies who would say things are technologically feasible when they aren't and We would say okay Yeah, we'd.
Speaker 0: someone would say the law that I'm proposing would say if Something in this is in dispute whether it is technologically feasible or not Someone must merely demonstrate the technological feasibility.
Speaker 0: if you can demonstrate it then you can have your law cannot demonstrate In the law a technical rundown of how to implement it even better.
Speaker 1: Actually, I think in many cases any law that requires someone to do shot something should either provide a means or provide a method to Do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah Because when you just say do this people do it and they do it some way that ends up making you bad and not.
Speaker 1: there's a law in Florida right now that If it passes will require Spanish to be taught in all schools all public schools.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm All right, it doesn't provide any money to provide these classes.
Speaker 1: So these schools are probably gonna cut, you know art class or something to pay for it Great.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the federal government does that a lot though, too.
Speaker 1: I mean a lot of times.
Speaker 1: I'll pass a law that says you must do X and then they don't provide any money to do It and people do it shittily and then the government complains.
Speaker 0: the people really that's really a thing We need a constitutional amendment for.
Speaker 0: is any law you know that proposes action must provide the means and Instructions and how to execute that action?
Speaker 1: You know, the problem is the people who understand what we're saying are not the people in power.
Speaker 0: That is true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they will be and the idea of a constitutional convention scares the living hell out of me.
Speaker 0: Constitutional convention bad.
Speaker 0: constitutional convention Scott equals airplane.
Speaker 0: Yes big airplane fast go.
Speaker 1: Because sure, I'm sure one or two good things would happen, but I imagine a lot of things would become very illegal very quickly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, unless we can go to the constitutional convention and make mischief maybe we could win out.
Speaker 0: huh See the problem is a constitutional convention isn't necessarily bad It's necessarily crazy and out of control and fickle.
Speaker 1: Yep, because we've never had one so we don't really know what would happen?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we don't even really know how to do it.
Speaker 0: Well, there would be the this questions constitutional questions Like does the Congress decide when and where and who's allowed to be there and what can they do there?
Speaker 0: You know because technically it doesn't say you make a constitutional convention to write a new constitution.
Speaker 0: It says you can have a constitutional convention.
Speaker 0: is one of the ways to pass an amendment, right?
Speaker 0: But it doesn't say what's allowed there.
Speaker 0: The question is can Congress limit what's allowed to be done at the Constitutional Convention like in Congress say this Constitutional Convention is only for the discussion of this amendment which pertains to this only?
Speaker 1: or furthermore the Supreme Court could well interpret how the Constitutional Convention is to carry it out.
Speaker 0: That's what would happen is the Supreme Court would have to decide if Congress Can limit what is talked about at the constitutional convention.
Speaker 0: and if they could limit what is talked about then?
Speaker 0: It wouldn't be so exciting because it would just be one amendment that gets made there.
Speaker 0: But if they couldn't if they could not if Congress does not have the power to specify what is done there Then even though they might go to originally talk about one amendment that a bunch of states decided to have a convention over.
Speaker 0: They could just start talking about random stuff and do whatever they wanted and No one could vote them out or stop them.
Speaker 0: or do it basically be a room full of people who would be Like a as a whole a council that rewrites the Constitution any way they please at least.
Speaker 1: the one thing is it's still a one Vote per state.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we'd have like 50 or 100.
Speaker 1: There's mostly red states even though there aren't so many people in them.
Speaker 0: Oh All right, so I'm gonna use the initial D music.
Speaker 1: right yeah, so there's that video game cheater guy.
Speaker 1: oh Yeah, this is great.
Speaker 1: There's this guy who had a video game cheating site and he claims that it's his soul is his primary source of income Apparently has ads on it or something.
Speaker 1: Okay, and he's suing someone who he claims stole the cheats from his site and put them on his own site.
Speaker 1: I Point out he's a public knowledge mostly even if they're not.
Speaker 1: I point out that how does he gonna press?
Speaker 1: the same is?
Speaker 1: Say someone put on their website an equation one plus five equals six and then I put that same equation on my website Because I derived it independently and then he sues me saying I stole it from him.
Speaker 0: if he can he might be able to prove That someone Did like.
Speaker 0: if he hasn't a web log of someone like?
Speaker 0: Snarfing his website and taking all his pages and uploading them to their website and proving that it's the same thing.
Speaker 0: You know, that's that's something right?
Speaker 0: But if he's talking about, you know He went to a site that happened to have cheats for the same game.
Speaker 0: go to game facts, man You're gonna sue game facts.
Speaker 1: But even if she was so the website in fact Even if someone stole the website verbatim if the website is generic enough It still really doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: Well, it depends if he creative commons to his website or if he didn't because if he didn't it's technically a copyright infringement.
Speaker 1: It's the website is just a collection of facts and all this and the presentation of the website has changed to where it's not identical.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then it's just a collection of.
Speaker 0: they would have to change the presentation significantly enough to where it's not infringing.
Speaker 1: However, what if the first website is just black text on a white background?
Speaker 1: then I can just a list of cheats.
Speaker 0: Then the guy doesn't have a leg to stand on.
Speaker 1: I don't think he has a leg to stand on anyway.
Speaker 0: No, he definitely doesn't.
Speaker 1: I think the saddest thing was the reporters talking about this case who don't know anything about it at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just like the guy who doesn't know anything about internet architecture from Bell South.
Speaker 1: Yeah reporters are starting to take me off lately.
Speaker 1: I mean when I was a little kid, I remember I'd read the newspaper and I'd always think like wow Oh, I didn't know that.
Speaker 1: but now I read the newspaper and I think I know that's untrue because I know about it Or that's not right.
Speaker 1: lie because I that quote.
Speaker 1: that's not that what that guy said I know.
Speaker 1: But then I started realizing that I Think every article is that way and anyone who's an expert in any field immediately sees that.
Speaker 0: yeah The problem is is they don't have a reporter who's an expert in everything.
Speaker 0: Nope.
Speaker 0: They have you know Reporters who are just guys who report.
Speaker 0: they don't know about any of the things they're reporting on which is why they do research and things.
Speaker 1: But a long time they only have fact-checkers and you couldn't say anything in the newspaper unless you had a.
Speaker 0: they still have.
Speaker 0: they still do Fact-check, you know, they don't do it quickly and they don't do it thoroughly.
Speaker 0: Oh So they don't do occurs.
Speaker 0: the fact-checkers also don't know if they give you.
Speaker 0: if I wrote a highly technical Article and I'm a highly technical guy and I put it in a newspaper Who can fact-check that other than someone who's also very technical?
Speaker 0: so, you know, we'll get college professors to check it.
Speaker 1: Yes, the newspapers fact-finders job should be to find the fact and if they don't know it, they should find it somewhere.
Speaker 0: But then you won't get your story in today's paper and then it'll be a day late even though it's already 16 hours late because it happened, you know a long time ago and it's newspaper have everything.
Speaker 1: So maybe newspapers need to not go for the breaking news and go for the in-depth local news instead.
Speaker 0: Well, that's for the local newspapers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but even for the national news instead of having an article that says holy shit Something happened in Congress have an article two days later that says here's exactly what happened in Congress two days ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then you know, what about the people who are dumb?
Speaker 0: they only read a newspaper the old people.
Speaker 0: they don't get the news fast.
Speaker 1: That seems to break every good business model.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but the the way cuz you know, why is the way you make money is by taking advantage of dumb people.
Speaker 0: Yeah And you don't have to do much to get money from them.
Speaker 0: if everyone was smart Then all the smart business models would work.
Speaker 0: Dumb business models wouldn't but because people are dumb dumb business models work and it sucks for the smart people.
Speaker 1: But at least in the newspaper case It doesn't matter because the average age of newspaper readers a year ago was 55 and this year.
Speaker 1: It's 56.
Speaker 0: Only old geezers read newspaper.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and not like funny in Soviet Whatever.
Speaker 1: only old people use email, but actually only old people read newspapers with rare exception.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I mean if the average age is 55 I see that means For every 30 year old out there who reads the one.
Speaker 1: how many 70 year olds are there an equal number?
Speaker 1: No, not an equal number.
Speaker 0: well, you know a close enough number but not an equal number mr.
Speaker 0: Math It's good music.
Speaker 0: It is we're kind of giving up on the you know, a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: No stealing music thing.
Speaker 1: Well DJ pretzel never technically answered.
Speaker 1: I sent him two emails and he never answered.
Speaker 1: so I credited him and I just used his music.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Mike and I supremacy said we could use the music but we haven't used it yet because we just didn't.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 1: So if you ever just hear mock and I supremacy music for you know, 40 minutes on our podcast It means we really didn't have anything to say.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you should go to their website and check out the music because they're awesome and they didn't pay me to say that They're just really that awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right, so the things of the day.
Speaker 0: what's your thing of the day?
Speaker 1: I Expected you to go first.
Speaker 0: Well fine.
Speaker 0: All right, so so my thing.
Speaker 1: So in a Final Fantasy there were there was the potion item probably the most ubiquitous item in the game.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, you know 99 of them and they gave you 50 health.
Speaker 0: Gee, those are pretty useful.
Speaker 1: Well, uh in The fact that Final Fantasy 12 is coming out what kind of game is gonna be a one-player?
Speaker 0: What's it gonna mean?
Speaker 1: Oh, it's definitely not an online MMO.
Speaker 1: That's good And a lot of people have mixed feelings about it But the real matter here is that it's costing a lot of money to make like insane amounts of money.
Speaker 0: That's about right.
Speaker 1: I've seen many articles to the fact that this is going to be possibly one of the most expensive to bruise games ever.
Speaker 1: Sounds right and they're having a little bit of trouble coming up with all this money.
Speaker 1: yep, so they are marketing the hell out of Final Fantasy.
Speaker 1: and Part of this marketing is they have now released potion the drink.
Speaker 0: Does it actually heal you?
Speaker 1: I imagine it's some sort of high fructose corn syrup carbonated concoction.
Speaker 1: I bet may I'll wager it's some sort of energy drink the sights in Japanese and there aren't many details out yet.
Speaker 1: Other than that the bottles look really really cool and I'll probably buy some just for that just for the bottle might be worth it If it's not too expensive.
Speaker 0: You know, I mean hell.
Speaker 0: I buy a cool bottle.
Speaker 1: Well considering that a Red Bull is 250 out of a vending machine at work.
Speaker 0: Really Wow Any of those things as I think they're poisoned.
Speaker 1: so I don't I love Red Bull, but it is kind of expensive.
Speaker 0: So I don't really know how much those things cost.
Speaker 0: Those are small little cans though - yeah Yeah, well, no wonder those freaking people are making a killing.
Speaker 0: That's how they afforded to buy that f1 team.
Speaker 0: Oh It contains some weird herbs in it.
Speaker 0: the potion is here.
Speaker 0: it contains hyssop Hyssop Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: I know that was.
Speaker 1: are you sure that wasn't hyssop be?
Speaker 0: Telest I'm sure but apparently I guess it's also got some sort of Randy herbal thing that doesn't really heal you.
Speaker 0: But I guess they kind of put it in there to make it more potion ish of healing.
Speaker 1: Well, you know what push be select.
Speaker 0: Yep All right, so my thing of the day.
Speaker 0: well, do you remember the SNES?
Speaker 0: there was the super FX chip.
Speaker 1: I Remember even seeing ads where they talked about the super FS exact Super FX chip.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well, the super FX chip was a chip they put in a few games starting with Star Fox and then stunt race FX and doom and a few other games that allowed the Super Nintendo to do, you know, very primitive vector polygon kind of graph very primitive.
Speaker 0: The Genesis also had a similar thing.
Speaker 0: they used for Virtua racing and what you know those early early early 3d games the stuff that came out before Virtua fighter won.
Speaker 1: Yeah, definitely a step up from like mode 7.
Speaker 0: definitely a step up from mode 7.
Speaker 0: But anyway some if you ever played these games even in an emulator Star Fox and whatever is kind of jaggy in the frame rate sometimes even on an SNES.
Speaker 0: so some guy who knew about electronics took a Star Fox and he opened it up and he replaced a resonator with a 24 megahertz quartz crystal and Some capacitors and whatever and he basically overclocked his effect FX chip and got rid of the frame rate lag.
Speaker 1: that's kind of badass.
Speaker 0: and there was a post where he says I think up here's that he shows pictures of all the stuff that's in the Cartridge and then he says this is what I plan to do.
Speaker 0: Let's see if it works at worst.
Speaker 0: It just won't boot.
Speaker 0: Because he's smart electronics guy.
Speaker 0: he did it and he said well my god it worked.
Speaker 0: He gets three to four more FPS, which is about all you need to get it You know to work better.
Speaker 0: because you know, it runs at about 25 FPS and your TV's about 30 something.
Speaker 0: So three to four just brings you right up to what you needed.
Speaker 0: to be damn.
Speaker 1: We couldn't do something similar with a dodgeball.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's thinking about getting a better crystal to put in there like a 26 megahertz.
Speaker 0: That way you can get the like, you know Five or six maybe seven frames and he'll just be like a few frames over what a TV can do.
Speaker 0: So it'll always be perfect.
Speaker 1: That's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: I gotta say yeah, this is why I kind of want to know electronic stuff even though it's hard.
Speaker 1: So this is the last main bit that won't have music before the main bit starts.
Speaker 0: Yep, and we decided that today we're gonna have a meta cast meta Which means if you are not knowing what meta means The podcast today is going to be about this podcast.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like when you're on slashdot and someone posts about slashdot.
Speaker 0: That's about it.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah information about Information about the thing that it is within itself.
Speaker 1: So we just want to say to start we'll just get this right away.
Speaker 1: Visit our website, please at least once.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we know there are people out there Listening.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we have statistics.
Speaker 1: We know exactly how many of you there are who are not our.
Speaker 0: a lot of you are friends who already know us but we know a lot of people are listening who were complete strangers to us and We want to make like a fun happy community where we all can get together and geek out and such.
Speaker 0: see go to our website.
Speaker 0: We have a nice forum.
Speaker 0: Yeah join.
Speaker 1: so far.
Speaker 1: Only one of you was cool enough to try to post something.
Speaker 0: Yep, that guy's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also I don't like you know these things where you vote to get people boosted up and promoted and whatever.
Speaker 0: but You know, I we kind of want people to listen.
Speaker 0: I mean it takes a lot of time to do this, even if it isn't particularly difficult and the more people listen the more worthwhile it would be.
Speaker 0: so Go to like podcast alley and those other places and like vote us up and put our links around And tell your friends and all that kind of good stuff.
Speaker 1: There are links are around enough already because I've noticed that if you search for geek nights on Google We're number one far above geek nights.
Speaker 1: calm.
Speaker 0: Well, it's cuz eat nice.
Speaker 0: calm is some poop site and I went around like a bunch of pod Aggregators and put us up there.
Speaker 1: Yep, as did I I went to several to put us on there and you would already put us.
Speaker 0: yeah, now see the trick is we want people to find us if they search for geek podcast or Nighttime podcast or video game Geek podcast even though there's a bunch of video game specific podcast that'll beat us out, you know, but yeah get the idea All right.
Speaker 0: The second thing we want to talk about is our content particularly Monday and Thursday.
Speaker 1: We're getting better.
Speaker 1: Well, we've been.
Speaker 1: we're forcing ourselves to actually have something good to talk about instead of just flubbing those two days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean originally I was kind of hoping that you know The geekeries are pretty much split into three general categories.
Speaker 0: There's board gaming role-playing Gay wargaming type stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then there's Anime manga comics art type stuff.
Speaker 0: and then there's video games because video games are just that awesome that they you know.
Speaker 0: yeah, and then there's technologies and computers and all those sorts of things.
Speaker 0: is the fourth geekery, but You know, we don't.
Speaker 1: we can't really talk about No matter what we did involving science tech.
Speaker 1: we got complaints either.
Speaker 1: We talked about specific like computer things and half our listeners go what the hell?
Speaker 1: Yeah We don't care about window managers or talk about science and that's boring to most of our listeners because we're not the most informative types.
Speaker 1: We're just interested in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then you know, we can't really talk too much about Bored role-playing war games because we play board games, but we tend to play the same ones over and over.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you wanted we could talk about Tigers and Euphrates every week and never run out of stuff to talk about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we just keep playing it and playing it.
Speaker 0: talk about you know game session reports and and new strategies and things until we eventually Solve the game.
Speaker 0: but you know, I mean we get new games occasionally But you know, we decided to lump those in on the video game day because video games don't come out every week You know, so you just made it game day and I think it works out pretty good.
Speaker 1: Yep and the same thing went with anime and manga and all that because I've noticed whenever we don't have a new anime to talk about we always have a new manga or new comic or if anything There's a bunch of anime news.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I'm going to the comic book store every week now.
Speaker 0: So that should you know, even though I'm starting to because of this and other things I'm not actually reading all the comics as soon as I get them like I used.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like we got Netflix not too long ago and we had anime streaming in pretty much We would watch a DVD and mail it back that day and then get another one the next day and we had a movie Every single day no more.
Speaker 1: now now we're lucky to watch one a week.
Speaker 0: Yay podcast You know, but I did get a video game and that's you know Gonna eat up a bunch of my time and slow down comic read.
Speaker 0: Yeah pairing our geek content down to only two days You know, we were able to you know, always have fresh content guaranteed for those two days.
Speaker 0: but we decided we want to do a four day a week podcast and those other two days were kind of and You know, we have a few bits.
Speaker 0: We had like the geek fables bit.
Speaker 0: We have the.
Speaker 0: what are they?
Speaker 0: We had another bit.
Speaker 1: we had the how not to suck how not to suck bit.
Speaker 0: We had just stories stories bit but the stories originated as an end of the power.
Speaker 0: still Experimenting with our general format, you know, even though it's pretty locked down into you know, something that happened today, you know news Items or interesting things on the internet and then the thing of the day and then the main Topic of depending what day of the week it is and then we're done.
Speaker 0: It's pretty solid.
Speaker 0: I think it works.
Speaker 0: if you don't think it works tell us Yeah, yep.
Speaker 0: Yep, you know pretty much.
Speaker 0: tell us anything that you think about the podcast.
Speaker 1: negative positive We don't care because I mean we've had ideas like worst case.
Speaker 1: We might just only do Monday Tuesday Wednesday and then only do a Thursday when we have a reason to do a Thursday like an Interview or something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, though.
Speaker 1: Once again, I got a bunch of cool people lined up to interview.
Speaker 1: It's just a matter of us getting around to doing it.
Speaker 1: So probably after the holiday season.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's also the question of you know, what if we really had nothing?
Speaker 0: because for a few weeks We were really starving for?
Speaker 0: what do we do Thursday or what do we do Monday now?
Speaker 0: I think we have a little better handle on it this week maybe because of the Thanksgiving buffer we had.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but You know Would you rather have us?
Speaker 0: Still go over up to thing of the day and then just stop the podcast if you don't have anything?
Speaker 0: or do you rather have Us keep going and talk about something that may be kind of crappy and boring?
Speaker 1: or more important We could probably always as long as we're a good forum come up with something.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean in the very least we have funny store.
Speaker 1: We have probably enough funny stories to fill this podcast out for a year.
Speaker 1: Probably the problem is days like today when we have plenty to talk about.
Speaker 1: We're just real tired.
Speaker 0: Yeah tiredness is.
Speaker 0: I guess that's part of the nighttime podcast.
Speaker 0: I mean letterman records his shows at like the middle of the morning like 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: Or something like that.
Speaker 0: There's a reason he doesn't actually do it at 11 p.m Whenever he's on TV.
Speaker 1: We had a plan where we were gonna record all the non time dependent stuff whenever we could like.
Speaker 1: if one weekend we were feeling Particularly good we do as many bits as we could and just cue them all up.
Speaker 0: We haven't done any of that.
Speaker 1: We did that once and then we immediately use them like two days later when Scott went out of town.
Speaker 1: Maybe we can and now we keep going out of town every weekend, so it's like yeah We're going out of town this weekend to play some board games Which is good because now we'll have stuff to talk about on board game day.
Speaker 0: Yeah Maybe the week after that we won't do anything and I can actually do some computer work and we can get some podcast work in.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if we get one free weekend We'll pretty much be will polish up this podcast as far as it's gonna get polished.
Speaker 1: Yep, we need one more weekend of work and this thing will be gold.
Speaker 1: and this is gold as we're gonna be okay.
Speaker 0: So if you have we really want user input on our what our content is our format things we should talk about.
Speaker 0: so We don't care.
Speaker 1: We just want to hear things is right now We're not hearing anything even a post that says you suck and I hate you and I had sex with your mom.
Speaker 1: Yep, cuz I'm sure I'd like to know you can do that on the forum.
Speaker 0: You can also email us geek nights at Gmail.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so though I'll point out that to all you iTunes listeners out there and there's quite a few of you who probably have never Seen the website there's stuff on the website often in the comments.
Speaker 1: Well one on the website We had linked to everything we talked about.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So if we talk about something you're curious about it We have a link there for you.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: and two there's comments by us and sometimes by other people on the actual Items in the feed for the podcast and that were.
Speaker 1: that's where we'll explain things like oh we screwed this podcast up.
Speaker 1: That's why it's so short.
Speaker 1: or rim fell asleep during it and Scott had to wake him up or you know Things like that.
Speaker 1: anything that happened that might be relevant.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you want to read those things because I think it you know, it enhances your experience.
Speaker 0: I mean I listen to a lot of podcasts.
Speaker 0: rim doesn't listen to any but now I will soon.
Speaker 1: Yes, I if I actually get the job information that I've been waiting for.
Speaker 0: I'm buying an iPod I'll sue but and a computer when I you know I listen to a podcast.
Speaker 0: if they have supporting information and cool stuff and a community on their website You know, it really makes it good for me.
Speaker 0: I really like that sort of thing and I think a lot of other people do also and we're trying to make that.
Speaker 0: So if you you know, that's what you want.
Speaker 0: We've got it use it.
Speaker 0: All right Next thing we'll talk about is some of the technical issues with our pod.
Speaker 1: Yes Mainly Darth Scott in the fact that he breathes into the microphone An ambassador.
Speaker 1: I'm sorry, we have a shtick that we don't know why it won't end but randomly we just say We are not comic book guy, but somehow we still know every line from Star Wars.
Speaker 0: if this is a diplomatic mission Where is the ambassador?
Speaker 1: I always love that scene because he chokes the guy to death.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yep Darth Vader's just freaking cool in any episode.
Speaker 0: All right, so technical issues you have with the podcast.
Speaker 0: We don't.
Speaker 0: I'm not a professional radio guy and I talking to the microphone kind of yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't want to sound mean because I had problems with my audio at first too, but I fixed all mine.
Speaker 1: I got a I got a pop filter here and I got a microphone stand and everything.
Speaker 1: Yeah Scott lays on my futon with a microphone in his hand like squirming around pulling on the cable Talking into it funny rolling it around bumping into his face breathing on it.
Speaker 0: I think we'll buy a stand with a boom stick and it'll be all cool.
Speaker 0: Like yeah, maybe and then I can still lay down.
Speaker 0: I don't want to not lay down No seek.
Speaker 1: I mean people could have pictured us sitting at a desk like on The Letterman Show.
Speaker 0: It doesn't matter because you know what if people ever see us we will be sitting at a desk wearing nice blue suits white shirts and red ties, yeah, and As long as they don't see us, they'll just imagine that we're in this palace, which we do live in a palace.
Speaker 1: Yeah, honestly, we kind of do.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, it's got turrets and and Port colors, we like port color.
Speaker 0: We have a port colors.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we have a moat with the dragon in it and inside the dragon is a laser.
Speaker 0: Yeah, generally.
Speaker 0: and the other thing is we all run Linux here So are?
Speaker 0: we don't have a large selection of audio software.
Speaker 0: is that causes a few problems?
Speaker 1: Yeah, we have audacity which is great at multitrack, but sucks at a lot of other things.
Speaker 1: We have resound.
Speaker 1: That's the closest thing to cool edit.
Speaker 1: I've ever been able to find for Linux, but it has some idiosyncrasies.
Speaker 0: There are other things like our door which we can get to work, but they're complicated and they're very powerful.
Speaker 0: But we have to learn them.
Speaker 0: So maybe we can get some success using those things.
Speaker 1: We got to work it out or honestly if anyone out there Happens to have a copy of cool edit Pro or cool edit 2000 for Windows.
Speaker 1: that was my favorite audio suite ever and I use that in all my digital audio classes and I made awesome stuff in it and I had pirated it.
Speaker 0: Yep, and then I lost it's on the guy in the train using it the other day.
Speaker 1: You should have asked him for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: All right, so Now for those of you who are unfamiliar we're gonna talk about for the first time where this podcast came from.
Speaker 1: yeah, because it's kind of a. we Come up with ideas like this on a hourly basis Minute basis.
Speaker 1: we've had.
Speaker 0: I just came up with one thousands upon thousands of crazy But usually pretty viable ideas that we never acted upon Mostly because we didn't have the resources to execute them.
Speaker 0: the balls to execute them even though we have a lot of freakin balls.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But usually what happens is something either has you know a little bit of balls that we have but too much resources if you don't Too much balls and no resources.
Speaker 0: So we you know, it's more balls than anyone has.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but anyway We finally found something we could do so we did it.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: In fact, I remember we were talking about it We should do it about three weeks before we actually started doing it.
Speaker 1: We said we should do it.
Speaker 1: We should try to ride this rising tide like the early webcomics did in and trench ourselves.
Speaker 0: Well, it's more like and then we didn't.
Speaker 0: it's more like surfing where it starts to break and then you're surfing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know the it really started way back in college with the with the pillow talk action.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we had this idea for a show because in college we shared a bedroom and what we didn't share a bed but we shared a bedroom
Speaker 0: yep,
Speaker 1: and It was sad because I never got any sleep because we lay in bed and it'd be like 3 in the morning after we did all our geekery we lay in there and We just talked about.
Speaker 1: we pretty much do what we're doing now only without an audience.
Speaker 0: It was a great game called keep talking until the.
Speaker 1: oh, yeah I can't really ignore you trying to sleep because I had a you know work the next morning or a class at 8 a.m And Scott would would say things to me and I'd try to just ignore him.
Speaker 1: pretend I was asleep, but he knew I was awake and he'd say more and more Exasperating things till finally I turn around and yell at him and then we'd argue for four more hours.
Speaker 0: Yep It's an awesome game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and So he figured hey people love to listen to this shit.
Speaker 0: You know which?
Speaker 1: we actually have evidence of that because every now and then we had someone just like stay in our apartment overnight And they wouldn't go sleep on the couch.
Speaker 0: They'd sit in the bedroom and listen to us and they would laugh hysterically and then none of us could get sleep.
Speaker 0: And it was kind of you know.
Speaker 0: So we always thought we should record it, but we never did because it's kind of hard to record people laying in bed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus we didn't have microphones.
Speaker 1: We didn't have money.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so now we got this going on.
Speaker 0: I think it's pretty good.
Speaker 0: Other people seem to think it's good.
Speaker 0: I mean, they're still listening.
Speaker 0: I see numbers All right.
Speaker 0: Now, where's the podcast going?
Speaker 1: We'd like to one have the energy we've had.
Speaker 1: I mean some of our podcasts are really good and some of them are kind of ad because we're tired.
Speaker 1: We want to get to a point where we do it So efficiently that we still get enough sleep and we always have that funny bantery energy.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: That's a good thing.
Speaker 0: A lot of people out there who are podcasting have this kind of idea Mostly from certain podcast companies that they can you know.
Speaker 0: Eventually, they're gonna quit their day jobs and be like professional podcasters for a living.
Speaker 1: You know what screw that.
Speaker 1: We don't want to make money off of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't really care for that.
Speaker 0: I just want to like make a cool show and have a little community and you know be cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like if we were after money, there are a million things we could do to make money and we're still working on some Of those schemes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean as far as what I want to get out of the podcast is, you know Meet people.
Speaker 0: I want to you know Go to a convention and you know do a cool podcast and I want to use it as a means to do cool things That you know money can't buy.
Speaker 1: I mean, how cool would it be if we went to like Otacon and we ran into some people were like, hey You're the geek night skies.
Speaker 1: We know you and then we hung out with those people for the weekend.
Speaker 1: Yep, or if we were like, you know the official podcast of some thing somewhere which Yeah, I got some really small venues that are all about us being like a podcast.
Speaker 0: live there Yeah, and we could just keep moving on up eventually would be like, you know The official podcast of something really big or something really cool and maybe like packs or something.
Speaker 1: Yeah We're going to packs next year.
Speaker 0: Damn it.
Speaker 0: No one's gonna stop me You know and as far as the future of our content, I figure you know, we just want to keep doing what we're doing.
Speaker 1: We'll keep making incremental changes But we'll change real quick if our listeners really want something or really don't like something or really like something
Speaker 0: Yeah, like if all of a sudden every one of our listeners decided that you know Our anime talk is like the best anime talk of any podcast there is and we should make an anime only podcast.
Speaker 0: I guess you know, we might be persuaded to do that.
Speaker 0: No, I don't think that's gonna happen.
Speaker 0: No, but You know, that's you know, we will go wherever You know to a point where we have a lot of listeners who are happy and We're happy.
Speaker 1: Yep, because it's easy to make us happy because I like the sound of my own voice.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean it's because we're not trying to make money.
Speaker 0: So we're not just gonna do whatever we can, you know, whatever it takes to make money.
Speaker 1: Well, we just do a podcast about mesothelioma.
Speaker 1: Yeah But Yeah We'll talk about that someday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we're not gonna do whatever it takes to make money.
Speaker 1: We're gonna do whatever we enjoy with while simultaneously Please we've got two sliders our enjoyment and your enjoyment and we're gonna get them both as high as we can.
Speaker 1: Yep Without sacrificing one or the other because we really there's a lot of reason we don't want to make money.
Speaker 1: one.
Speaker 1: I Advertising.
Speaker 1: really Well, it doesn't bother me because I don't see it But whenever advertising penetrates my little rim bubble if I don't see advertising it bothers me a lot Yep, and I hate ads.
Speaker 1: I block ads to the point of like.
Speaker 1: there's ad block.
Speaker 1: A lot of people use ad block and it blocks ads in Firefox.
Speaker 1: I use such a blunt Slash-and-burn filter of blocking ads that you wouldn't believe it.
Speaker 0: I just use the automatic filter that other people set up.
Speaker 0: but rim if he sees Like a website that has one ad he'll block every image that ever comes from that domain.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm net or org just the whole any any any domain that contains that Part of the URL in it just every image block never seen again.
Speaker 1: I'm real Uh, I'm real pro capitalism, but capitalism involves my right to not listen to you.
Speaker 0: Yep Capitalism's cool.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well this job will miss on Adam Smith.
Speaker 1: Capitalism is cool.
Speaker 1: The problem is America isn't really capitalist anymore.
Speaker 1: It's kind of Something bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah evil is not socialist because I like socialism too, but Yeah, it's broken.
Speaker 1: but anyway, we're we'll get into that, you know, well next Thursday, we don't have anything else.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about economics.
Speaker 0: economics is good.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll get a copy of the old Wealth of nations wealth of nations.
Speaker 1: read it read key passages pull out the Communist Manifesto just because I like quoting it.
Speaker 1: It's funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah a lot of it's funny anyway.
Speaker 0: So the best way for all this to keep going where we want it to go Is if you email us and go to the forum.
Speaker 1: Yeah post in the forum because one if you like listening to us at all You'd probably really like hanging out with us and you probably really like our friends because they're all a lot like us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, unless you are all unless you are socially inept in which case we don't want to hang out with you.
Speaker 1: But but keep in mind our definition of socially inept is probably far below what you'd think.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean I hung out with some like 30 year old 40 50 year old board gaming guys over the weekend and that was okay.
Speaker 0: So it's tough to play with it this way there.
Speaker 1: There are probably there are less than five people.
Speaker 1: We've known that we actually don't like Yeah, like the number is so small that I think we could spend a Thursday on each one of them telling you all about them Because it's funny.
Speaker 1: They're all really funny stories.
Speaker 0: Well, it's really funny when someone is such a loser or such a terrible person.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like we don't give someone shy that doesn't bother us.
Speaker 1: We're talking about people who are socially inept in the abrasive talking about horrible Pornography all the time because they somehow think that you want to hear about that.
Speaker 0: God God that guy.
Speaker 1: All right Fuck What you gotta have the fuck.
Speaker 1: we see we think of a lot of silly ideas.
Speaker 1: one day We thought we were gonna put a number at the end of every Post for a podcast and we wouldn't say what that number is and it would just be the number of times We swore during the podcast.
Speaker 0: It's like the math teacher who put a tally on the board every time.
Speaker 1: 69 was the answer to a math problem Or the game we played with our Cal teacher in high school because he said, uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Okay Constantly and If actually if no one answered him, you just keep doing it.
Speaker 1: It was kind of scary.
Speaker 0: All right, I think we're getting off track.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're getting off track way off track.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 0: But you know, this is the kind of stuff that we do here and That's what you can expect more of.
Speaker 1: yeah, and if you don't like it yell at us or don't listen to us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know we don't change to what you like because no one's making you listen.
Speaker 0: Whoo, whoo Whoo geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yeah So now we're just gonna trail off.
Speaker 1: Keep saying a few words and then at some point I'll paste the music in after the fact.
Speaker 1: All right Though I got I just had a couple of good ideas actually for what to do on Thursdays.
Speaker 1: Yeah whole bunch of ideas.
Speaker 1: we could have opinion Thursdays where we pick a topic We state our opinion on it and then we defend that opinion.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it has to be Where we don't have the same opinion Yeah, or even if we have the same opinion we broadcast our opinion to the world like if we did one on economics things We're really opinionated on more things We disagree on.
Speaker 1: if we disagree will argue and our arguments often end funnily.
Speaker 1: if we agree strongly Well, he will talk about it forever because we just keep it's like a feedback loop.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as long as you know, you don't just dip down to the same baseline Philosophical argument every single time.
Speaker 0: Yeah what the topic is pornography up?
Speaker 0: No, we got to talk about this flat philosophical argument.
Speaker 1: Well, we have And the only thing I've ever experienced in this world is my own Okay, whatever talking about computers the same philosophical argument every time, you know, we have this problem when we argue.
Speaker 1: Sometimes we argue to come to a truth Like we're arguing about what the best blah is and then we come to an answer and we both agree.
Speaker 1: But a lot of times we start arguing and we're not arguing to convince the other person.
Speaker 1: We're not arguing to find the answer to something.
Speaker 1: We're just arguing for the sake of arguing to beat each other.
Speaker 1: and then we both pull some stupid dirty argumentation tricks.
Speaker 1: Add hominem attacks left and right and hominem We really like.
Speaker 1: When someone makes a logical fallacy We like naming it in Latin and then yelling at each other then arguing over what it actually means and whether or not it was.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah I think I'm gonna go in my room and do some stuff and they go to bed I'm gonna play some Mario Kart and get some sleep and Yeah, we're going to Albany tomorrow.
Speaker 0: We're gonna play some better And some lighter boy terror and see which one's better.
Speaker 1: oh and some Tigers and Euphrates duh Alright.
Speaker 0: so it's yeah Leroy Jenkins Leroy, you can cut a whole bunch of the end off.
Speaker 1: I think I just leave it on cuz it's a little long, isn't it?
Speaker 1: No, our part of this podcast is not our longest podcast.
Speaker 1: We only talked 23 minutes just now.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: How long do we talk for the beginning news parties about 20 minutes?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah Are fucking fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: Hey, I wonder Alright, well then keep this on hold on
Speaker 1: see cuz I one thing I've noticed is on a podcast that it Matt You can't ramble early on because then people lose interest but you can ramble at the end because if someone stops listening now Now it doesn't matter because you're not missing anything important.
Speaker 1: You're just missing us going.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I wonder if they'll listen again.
Speaker 0: I mean the real listeners listen to the whole thing intently.
Speaker 0: You know, that's that's the goal.
Speaker 0: is you you you don't.
Speaker 0: I don't want to be like a super professional radio guy and do everything The radio way because that's against the point of podcasting.
Speaker 1: We don't want to be so amateur.
Speaker 1: it hurts.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't want to be so amateur that it hurts the listeners.
Speaker 0: and I do want to like do things that aren't obviously Professional, you know where it doesn't feel professional, but it you know, you do things to keep people Like going.
Speaker 0: good like you can give a speech in such a way where you have a conversational tone but you still apply the right speech techniques the people pay attention and Are more inclined to agree with what you're saying because you say them in you know, the right way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know and that's what I kind of want to do is I want to do the podcast in a way where people are interested paying attention Caring going to listen again, but I don't want it to feel professional sound professional.
Speaker 0: I want it to sound.
Speaker 1: You know, we want to sound like a car is a way to feel like you're just sitting here with us.
Speaker 1: Yeah which actually one of our friends said something to that effect.
Speaker 1: because but we had a one show a while ago where we argued about Something and a friend of ours, you know who you are Actually told me that he a couple of times He actually started to argue with us a little bit and then stopped himself when he realized that we couldn't hear him.
Speaker 0: That is excellent.
Speaker 1: Yeah See our biggest problem is whenever we're tired We tend to talk at you and whenever we're not tired, we have more of a conversation with each other.
Speaker 1: That's informative or entertaining to you.
Speaker 1: The moral is we got to not be tired.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what do you?
Speaker 0: it also depends, you know?
Speaker 0: It's another thing we want feedback on is should we talk to the listener like I am right now.
Speaker 1: Hello listener Hello, or should we talk like hey Scott guess what?
Speaker 0: Yeah Oh by the I. I guess people who don't know us don't realize that I'm Scott and I'm rim.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we maybe we should do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't do that.
Speaker 0: maybe yeah, I didn't even realize that until just now.
Speaker 0: see that's the kind of thing we screw up on.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz we don't they didn't think of that until just now alive on the air fair.
Speaker 1: Oh Yeah, yeah, all right, we're actually gonna stop now.
Speaker 1: so cue the closing music.