Speaker 0: It's Wednesday November 30th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talk about anime in the news ADV and the Evangelion movie.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So uh yeah Hillary Clinton is at it again and Lieberman yeah Lieberman and the rest of those those Democrat bastards.
Speaker 0: Not that we're pro-republican, but we're kind of anti everyone anti Anyone who anyone has ever heard of.
Speaker 1: if we haven't heard of you, then you're probably good.
Speaker 0: So pretty much they're backing another one of those.
Speaker 0: get rid of violent video games over the love.
Speaker 0: God think of the children laws Gray.
Speaker 0: This law is fantastic.
Speaker 1: So the law basically says that if you are a store You cannot sell M games to minors without getting in trouble.
Speaker 1: also, there will be federal inspections of stores to make sure that they're You know not giving games to minors and such.
Speaker 0: so the same way they go after people who give alcohol.
Speaker 0: now They just send a kid in to try to buy an illegal game.
Speaker 1: I imagine I don't know, but it's some sort of auditing.
Speaker 1: and then basically you know on the surface you say oh all right Well people can still make M rated games and sell them and whatever but really not so much because this is why Let's say you're Walmart right you have two choices.
Speaker 1: you can Submit to these audits and things and you know Only sell M rated games to non-minors.
Speaker 1: But then why?
Speaker 1: why go through all the trouble just to sell the M rated games?
Speaker 1: now that you're gonna sell so many fewer copies They're just not gonna sell them which means that if you make an M rated game You're not gonna be able to sell it in as many places.
Speaker 1: and sadly Walmart and other places like that are the places where you Get most of your copies sold.
Speaker 1: so basically While the law itself you look at it, and you say oh, that's not so bad.
Speaker 1: It just means that you know stores actually can't sell Really mature things to minors, which is you know it seems kind of okay.
Speaker 1: what it really means is well You won't be able to make them because they're so expensive to make and Store because we're gonna hurt the stores so much.
Speaker 1: We're basically coercing them in making it not reasonable for them to carry your games Which means you won't make enough money selling them so no one will make them.
Speaker 0: the main thing that bothers me about the law is that it gives the FTC the power to review and Audit also how the ESRB does its ratings yep, and basically fiat how they rate things mm-hmm?
Speaker 0: And that all comes out of some study that Clinton keeps bringing up where they basically some stupid family group That doesn't like anyone to see anything bad Decided that the ESRB is terrible.
Speaker 0: They give it a grade F And they said that almost every game this really should actually be an AO game and not an M game.
Speaker 1: Yeah The other thing that really bothers me about this that other people mentioned was okay All right this makes you know even if you want to say this makes sense.
Speaker 1: How come we don't have this for movies?
Speaker 1: You know we're gonna say r-rated movies can't be sold to children.
Speaker 1: if Little three-year-olds can walk into any store and buy an r-rated movie on DVD and no one stops and no one cares Yeah, you can't go into the theater and see it even though.
Speaker 0: It's not illegal.
Speaker 0: the theaters I remember when I was in high school.
Speaker 0: I went to write it our movies all the time don't even blinked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what about what about steam?
Speaker 1: How you gonna make sure that little kids don't buy and I'm ready to game on steam though They're cracking out now.
Speaker 0: apparently movie theaters really cracked down And they check ID for a lot of people.
Speaker 0: they won't let you into our rated movies even though.
Speaker 0: There's no law.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's no law.
Speaker 1: the movie rating system has no basis in law.
Speaker 1: It's just through a voluntary Rating system.
Speaker 1: no one is obligated to follow it or anything.
Speaker 1: you're not even obligated to get a rating.
Speaker 1: You don't have to.
Speaker 1: if you don't want to.
Speaker 1: you know just movie theaters won't show you and such.
Speaker 1: but You know there's no.
Speaker 1: a little kid can go and buy a freaking triple x-rated book written by scooter Libby on Amazon or Borders and no one so no one check.
Speaker 0: actually sometimes people do.
Speaker 0: I have I have a small anecdote.
Speaker 0: When I was in middle school, I had a friend.
Speaker 0: her name was Sarah, and she was really into those smutty Danielle Steele books.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know what those are but that's all right either.
Speaker 0: They're they're smutty terrible books.
Speaker 0: Okay, and if anyone out there is offended.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: You shouldn't be reading those books, and if you read those books You shouldn't be listening.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Okay, but anyway So she we go to the mall to hang out cuz that's what middle school kids did back then before kids were banned from malls.
Speaker 0: and She goes into Walden book and tries to buy this Danielle Steele book and the cashier looks at her and says you can't buy that You're not 18.
Speaker 1: Did it have a thing on it?
Speaker 1: No was there a sign?
Speaker 0: Alright just wouldn't sell it to her.
Speaker 0: and we started to raise a stink And then they just kicked us out because we were just punk kids.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but no one will stop you from buying an x-rated manga unless you know Taku works at the bookstore.
Speaker 1: They don't know the difference.
Speaker 0: You know what most of them wouldn't even know because anything that's actually bad is shrink wrapped in plastic.
Speaker 1: anyway I know they'd have to open it to find out that it was bad.
Speaker 1: There is a label on a lot of them with some sort of rating.
Speaker 1: I don't think there's an official system, but I know that like Tokyo pop has their own system.
Speaker 1: They kind of self You know regulate things like and they say they say have a letter and then they have a little descriptive words.
Speaker 0: I have my own rating system.
Speaker 0: the more angular and thin the characters on the cover are and the more feathers and rose petals there Are the less likely I'm to read it.
Speaker 1: You know what.
Speaker 1: that does not coincide with the manga you just bought.
Speaker 1: Well, you just had me five.
Speaker 0: is there not that thin on the front and besides the manga I just bought which we'll talk about later is crap and I know it's crap, but it's awesome.
Speaker 0: I love it.
Speaker 0: It's crap.
Speaker 1: Okay So video game law on the surface seems like an okay law.
Speaker 1: who can argue with?
Speaker 1: you know Not selling the bad games to the miners and making it official.
Speaker 1: as to now We're 45% of the time the GameStop will check in reality bad reality bad.
Speaker 1: It means people won't make em rated games Which means no games for the people who should and have a right.
Speaker 0: and of course the sad reality.
Speaker 0: It's quite obvious that I don't know about everyone else involved.
Speaker 0: at least Hillary Clinton doesn't care about this issue Probably doesn't even agree with this issue But it's a nice safe issue to make a otherwise Democratic candidate look very pro family values.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and of course, you know the way Congress works these days is you know, they make the law and then of course You know the courts overturn it and then people like us go yay court and the people who go boo court the congressman Just go.
Speaker 1: Well, I did what I could do.
Speaker 1: I can't control those crazy judges Activist judges and not taking responsibility Congress.
Speaker 1: That's not gonna get my love.
Speaker 0: the term activist judge How dare you use the power given to you by the Constitution of the United States of America?
Speaker 1: Yeah, good job congressman.
Speaker 1: not using any of the power given to you by the Constitution of the United States of America And not listening to your constituents.
Speaker 0: one whit They listen to him a little bit spec, yeah a little spec.
Speaker 0: Anyway Though kind of doing some other dumb things lately and I normally don't care but this one affects me and it affects me in a Way that sucks.
Speaker 0: I can't get Nyquil anymore.
Speaker 0: And neither can you.
Speaker 1: you can get Nyquil?
Speaker 1: You just can't get the real deal.
Speaker 0: So it's not Nyquil, is it?
Speaker 0: it's something that has a big Q on it and the word letter and and why and It's green or red and it tastes like crap, but it's uh, it's not Nyquil.
Speaker 1: I think it's just Nike.
Speaker 0: Yeah Nike.
Speaker 0: so for anyone who hasn't been paying attention to the news for the last 20 years There's a big crystal meth problem in the United States.
Speaker 1: I don't know such a big problem because if you do crystal meth you're stupid and Making crystal meth is hard and it can kill you in a horrible explosion.
Speaker 1: You
Speaker 0: know who makes crystal meth, you know where most meth is made
Speaker 1: the middle of the desert
Speaker 0: small-town rural America
Speaker 1: Sounds right
Speaker 0: actually up north like peat town type areas - yeah Because there are people there young people who want to get high but It's hard to get marijuana because marijuana is illegal and
Speaker 1: you can get marijuana in other places in
Speaker 0: a city.
Speaker 0: It's hard to get marijuana when you live in a town with a hundred and ninety people in it.
Speaker 1: You can get in a suburb though.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right, and they can't really drink because they're not 21.
Speaker 1: Well, you can drink it's not a problem.
Speaker 1: under a drinking is ramp.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but they just make meth.
Speaker 1: Well, I guess that works.
Speaker 0: so the Congress and his infinite wisdom in many states has decided instead of you know Dealing with this problem like maybe looking at our drug laws or trying to find other better things for kids to do made laws that made it difficult if not stupid to get anything that contains of Anything that can be used to make crystal meth
Speaker 1: pseudo veteran.
Speaker 0: Yes, basically pseudo veteran.
Speaker 0: a couple other things.
Speaker 0: In some states if you want to get a drug like NyQuil you have to go up to the pharmacist.
Speaker 0: They take it out from behind the counter.
Speaker 0: You have to show two forms of ID.
Speaker 0: They take a photocopy of your ID and then they log how much you bought and make you sign it and you can't buy More than a certain amount per year.
Speaker 1: I'm wonder why Vicks didn't do anything about this.
Speaker 0: They did.
Speaker 0: they took it out of NyQuil Thus not having to have their NyQuil be hidden behind the counters anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean Shouldn't Vicks be like hey, this is really, you know ruining us.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should make you know Push type on it.
Speaker 0: this is much easier for them because aside from the few people who read the internet No one's gonna know or care.
Speaker 0: They won't even notice.
Speaker 1: Well, apparently oh I see a comment right here.
Speaker 1: you ready for this comment?
Speaker 0: I'm ready.
Speaker 1: Tylenol cold and flu day/night is your new Savior.
Speaker 1: I switched to it a few months ago and it wipes the floor with NyQuil and a quill even the old formulas.
Speaker 1: It's got pseudo veteran in it, too.
Speaker 1: Haha And you know, um, oh the second comment don't.
Speaker 1: how am I gonna make my crystal meth now?
Speaker 1: But the thing is okay and some you know We hear these stories about them checking IDs and things.
Speaker 1: I can go to the store by night.
Speaker 1: I can go to the CVS and buy real-deal Sudafed.
Speaker 1: right now No one would stop.
Speaker 0: We live in New York State where it's not a huge problem.
Speaker 1: So why don't they just ship?
Speaker 1: How about this if they I got it?
Speaker 1: Here's what you do.
Speaker 1: ready so simple.
Speaker 1: You don't have to change the drug laws you don't upset anyone if They're the cops.
Speaker 1: find people making crystal meth in an area, right?
Speaker 1: The drugstores in the area aren't allowed to carry the stuff anymore Until the crystal meth problem is gone from the area.
Speaker 0: But you see you don't.
Speaker 0: that just makes it easier to make crystal meth.
Speaker 0: You can make it without that stuff.
Speaker 1: Oh, well if people are gonna make it without that stuff Then why even bother?
Speaker 0: because that makes it easier.
Speaker 0: remember Congress is very good at putting band-aids on problems.
Speaker 0: It's not very good at solving problems.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe they should use, you know their power.
Speaker 0: I mean There are a lot of ways you could deal with the crystal meth problem one of which would be make marijuana legal And hopefully they'd smoke something that at least wouldn't eat their brain physically.
Speaker 0: Maybe or maybe give kids something to do.
Speaker 0: So instead of wanting to yeah giving kids something to do is the number one because I mean where we live now.
Speaker 0: There's a mall near us and it doesn't affect us anymore because we're actually adults.
Speaker 0: She's kind of scary.
Speaker 0: But uh the mall banned anyone under the age of 18 being in the mall Alone or in groups without a parent all weekend Mmm, so kids can't hang out in the mall on weekends.
Speaker 1: So what are kids supposed to do?
Speaker 1: Well, their parents yell at him for playing video games for too many hours.
Speaker 0: Alright, but they won't let him go outside and run around in the street because it's dangerous.
Speaker 1: Yes, someone will kidnap you.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can't go on this playground because the playground sucks Because I took away the swings and the seesaws.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like.
Speaker 1: You know, these are the things you absolutely should never do.
Speaker 1: These are the things that we're gonna stop you from doing because you just won't make them available.
Speaker 0: I know there's nothing left except crystal meth yep, and basically the kids just hate to sound old.
Speaker 0: but Really?
Speaker 0: It's changed a lot from when I was a kid and I'm sure our parents said the same thing, but god damn Yeah, I was a kid.
Speaker 0: I wandered around within about a six mile radius of my house willy-nilly on my little bike.
Speaker 0: I disappear for hours at a time.
Speaker 0: I come home with cuts and bruises and gashes and my parents just didn't even notice Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I mean it's like, you know everything.
Speaker 1: just you know.
Speaker 1: changes over time gets worse gets better Who knows.
Speaker 1: but there's a line for everything.
Speaker 0: When was the last time I got better?
Speaker 0: When was the last time they added something more dangerous to a playground?
Speaker 1: When they invented the seesaw and they invented the swirly slide.
Speaker 1: In other words not in our life, but the thing about before then there were no swing sets.
Speaker 1: There were no playgrounds.
Speaker 0: you realize there have been swing sets since you know, the Industrial Revolution.
Speaker 1: if yeah, okay But sure, but what are the 1700s man?
Speaker 1: It sucked.
Speaker 1: it sucked ass.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm a loop of wood and a stick in a 70. if you had a ball you were like a freaking rich dude.
Speaker 0: by the time you were 17 you had a wife and five kids work in the farm and You had a gun and you fought in Revolutionary War.
Speaker 0: outstanding.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so it did get better but now it's just getting worse.
Speaker 0: people are so afraid of Everything.
Speaker 0: it's scary.
Speaker 1: See I wouldn't even mind the people being afraid of things just they take their way from here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I used to have a problem when I was in high school.
Speaker 0: I like to go out at night I'd always ride my bike at night or I'd walk over a walk at night or I just wander around at night And I always get harassed by police officers.
Speaker 0: They'd stop me and they'd be they say things like what are you doing out?
Speaker 0: Well, are you out at night?
Speaker 0: go home and I'd say I'm outside.
Speaker 0: Am I not allowed to be outside just because it's dark out.
Speaker 0: There's no curfew There's no law and they'd be they just say go home or I'll do something to you.
Speaker 1: What are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: I really just laughed and ignored him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz they couldn't catch me.
Speaker 0: They were fat cops in cars and I was on a bike and I was a young spry kid.
Speaker 1: But even so even if they caught you what are they gonna do?
Speaker 0: Well, there were.
Speaker 0: technically there were curfews in all the parks which is another thing that grinds my gears.
Speaker 1: yeah Anyway, so let's get off this topic.
Speaker 1: Anyway, there was this guy.
Speaker 0: there was a guy.
Speaker 1: he bought a I think a camera.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he bought a digital SLR camera and whatever Uh-huh from.
Speaker 1: he was really wanted this camera and he kept going around the internet to find the best price.
Speaker 1: He found the best price on price right photo, which is a camera store in the city, right and he ordered it And his order didn't go so well Really?
Speaker 1: No, it didn't go so well at all.
Speaker 1: so Basically, he was upset and he was upset with the customer service and he was really upset.
Speaker 1: so, you know he got into sort of a Not so nice conversation with the people at the store and then he received the following message from the store Owner guy and it says I will make sure you will never be able to place an order on the internet again.
Speaker 1: I'm an attorney.
Speaker 1: I will sue you.
Speaker 1: I will call the CEO of your company and play him the tape of this phone call.
Speaker 1: I'm going to call your local police and have two officers come over and arrest you.
Speaker 1: You better get this through your thick skull.
Speaker 1: You have no idea who you were dealing with.
Speaker 0: Wow I Don't know where to start on that.
Speaker 0: So this guy this isn't Jack Thompson.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay But anyway this guy that that's from the guy at the photo place where the guy had a bad experience.
Speaker 1: So, of course the guy placed his whole experience on his blog duh, and he got dug.
Speaker 1: it got dug a lot and As soon as he got dug well in the comments on dig people found well the store the phone number the address the fax machine the email the everything and Considered to enact vigilante justice in an internet fashion.
Speaker 0: Ah internet justice.
Speaker 1: We hope the guy learned a lesson.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of updates.
Speaker 1: I haven't read them all but I Think the guy who runs the store is pretty unhappy, you know, I think I'll call the guy and ask him how he's doing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think he'll Jack Thompson.
Speaker 0: you you know what.
Speaker 0: if you Jack Thompson's me I'll play it the next time we do a show.
Speaker 1: awesome Totally awesome Yeah, but I just wish you know, it's like vigilante justice happens.
Speaker 1: I just wish it happened more often and more people were vulnerable to it.
Speaker 1: Like we can't vigilante justice Hillary Clinton.
Speaker 0: It doesn't work Now because she has buffers.
Speaker 0: she has people between her and us that read her email for her Yep, and we couldn't beat her up in the street.
Speaker 1: There's like Secret Service guys and we can't like Because she's.
Speaker 0: eating up a politician in the street is the best way to prove that gamers aren't violent.
Speaker 1: it is.
Speaker 1: and then you know when You know, we can't like egg or house cuz it's but fence in a big yard.
Speaker 0: and I don't know.
Speaker 0: I egged Eminem's house once Not really the chocolate with the shell?
Speaker 0: no, no Eminem the singers.
Speaker 0: I Really did singing chocolate.
Speaker 0: Wow, you're more devoted divorce from pop culture than I could ever imagine.
Speaker 1: I Just don't know who famous people are.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Well, I egged this famous guy's house.
Speaker 0: All right, I'll tell that story someday perhaps.
Speaker 0: so, you know, I told it right now I fucking egged his house.
Speaker 0: So if you're listening, that was me.
Speaker 1: Why did a guy name himself after chocolate?
Speaker 1: wasn't he looking for jokes or what?
Speaker 0: You actually don't know who.
Speaker 0: Eminem not you have no idea nothing.
Speaker 1: Not really.
Speaker 0: All right Moving on.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: so His things of the day things of the day things of the day Two things, all right thing.
Speaker 1: one is going to my thing.
Speaker 1: Oh, we should do a little dr Seuss type intro for that, you know thing one and thing two with a red and thing blue.
Speaker 1: That's not how it goes.
Speaker 1: You obviously haven't read the cat.
Speaker 0: one fish two fish red fish.
Speaker 1: No, this is a cat in the Hat, you know when thing one and thing two come out and they run around.
Speaker 1: Okay, you don't know dr.
Speaker 1: Seuss enough, but that's all right That's we should get some sort of audio clip of that and use that.
Speaker 0: we could I think somewhere actually cool Alright, so, uh, mine's real short.
Speaker 0: I won't go into detail on it because I think the headline says it all.
Speaker 0: monkeys have accents.
Speaker 0: Monkey language is different depending on area and it's not genetic.
Speaker 0: different monkeys have different accents and some monkeys make fun of other monkeys They meet who have funny accents.
Speaker 1: Oh, I am the French monkey.
Speaker 1: I will fling my French poo at you.
Speaker 0: Haha Yeah, something like that.
Speaker 0: But it's actually kind of interesting because they talk about how this gives us a lot of Clues as to how language appeared and evolved in humanity because this is kind of what early human language was probably like.
Speaker 0: Yep, that's really all I got to say about that.
Speaker 1: All right, it definitely means that Evolution happened.
Speaker 0: intelligent design is bullshit.
Speaker 0: That is part of it something like that.
Speaker 1: That's good enough.
Speaker 1: so This story is a little little tiny bit involved.
Speaker 1: There was a guy and he was kind of unhappy because people were speeding through his urban neighborhood.
Speaker 0: Did he put a trap in the road?
Speaker 1: Well, we're getting to that.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: I haven't read it But he's
Speaker 1: I think he's a professor somewhere and as part of his study He tried to find ways to curb the speeding to make people go slower through his neighborhood without Just putting up signs and warnings and fines and things
Speaker 0: I can think of a real good way.
Speaker 0: Well make very lifelike mannequins that look like little kids and toss them in front of speeders cars.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, no, he like.
Speaker 1: he put an 11-foot high rabbit on the side of the street so people would slow down and look.
Speaker 1: He put like a giant bed on the side of the road.
Speaker 1: It says for a sleeping policeman.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It just says that in parentheses.
Speaker 1: I don't get it.
Speaker 1: Okay, he put a Fake crash scene on Halloween next to the road speed would rubberneck.
Speaker 0: it Rubberneck is good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so one day he just set up a living room in the street.
Speaker 1: The living room is set up So where he's got like a couch like a table on either side of the couch and a coffee table in front of it Is that like a plant and some magazines.
Speaker 1: and then he's got a rug and then across from the rug there's a long kind of table with a TV on it and you know a little stand.
Speaker 1: and He's got this whole living room set up in the middle of the street and there's enough room on the rug for a car to Drive through this little living room in between him and the TV, you know, there's like five Monty Python sketches about that.
Speaker 1: Yep, there probably are.
Speaker 1: I think it's actually in Britain too, which is why it's funny.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Oxford.
Speaker 1: There you go.
Speaker 1: So Basically he noticed that you know the men who drove down the road to be kind of girl and go on but the women were like crazy girl Really and like one guy like an SUV even like bumped into his stuff and you know, it wasn't good.
Speaker 1: But You know, it's it's pretty cool because the idea is like, you know, hey the street, you know Right now in urban environments across the Western world It's like the street is the domain of cars and basically the whole city is the domain of cars and he's like, you know He's kind of like taking it back saying hey cars are just here.
Speaker 1: This is you know people it's a place for people kind of you know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I can say if you're real nice they didn't allow cars in New York City It didn't allow cars at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah How would they deliver goods?
Speaker 0: Trucks are allowed.
Speaker 1: Okay But all right What if you need to get somewhere across town and there's no cross town subway because there is?
Speaker 0: I think it's obvious that I was Not actually advocating the removal of cars from New York City.
Speaker 1: That's good.
Speaker 0: I was being facetious.
Speaker 0: feces just Was not funny.
Speaker 1: I never thought of it before.
Speaker 1: so I had to let it out.
Speaker 1: I had to let out the feces.
Speaker 1: I Couldn't the feces in any longer.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I mean this is the first time they appeared.
Speaker 0: they they had to Exo, uh, what do you say?
Speaker 0: we have Thursdays because we're still talking about what to do on Thursdays.
Speaker 0: We'll make poop jokes.
Speaker 0: Poop joke Thursday poop joke Thursday.
Speaker 1: I'm liking poop joke.
Speaker 0: There's nothing.
Speaker 0: poop jokes.
Speaker 0: Maybe fart jokes a little fart every now and then you know spice it up.
Speaker 1: Anal jokes any jokes involving the rear end and not.
Speaker 1: uh, they can involve the front end as long as they also involve the rear end.
Speaker 1: Just we'll call it the rear.
Speaker 1: It's it's the end of the week.
Speaker 1: So we make jokes about the end of your of your body.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't be surprised if some morning zoo show didn't already have that exact bit.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure the bit is taken and I'm pretty sure there's no poop joke.
Speaker 1: We can come up with that.
Speaker 1: Someone else is already not heard.
Speaker 0: Nah, nah.
Speaker 0: Nah, so a rabbi and a piece of poop walk into a bar and I Figure.
Speaker 0: that's enough No Anyway, so, uh, it's time for the main bit.
Speaker 0: In the main event, there should be music here.
Speaker 1: we really got it and it's even the crappiest crap podcasts have like Bumpering music and intro music.
Speaker 1: I don't know where the hell they get it from.
Speaker 0: See, I think a lot of people just take copyrighted music and use it.
Speaker 1: It doesn't sound like I already music to me.
Speaker 0: see you say that but I played a whole bunch of classical jazz for you And you hadn't heard or recognized a single one of them.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I have to go do some research into it.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna maybe email some people tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Actually.
Speaker 0: I got a couple of friends at RIT.
Speaker 0: I think we'll ask them to do some geeky guitar riffs for us.
Speaker 0: We'll just use guitar riffs.
Speaker 1: That could work.
Speaker 1: if we had a synthesizer we could do it too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could just be like.
Speaker 0: I like guitar riffs an actual guitar like an acoustic guitar even and whatever.
Speaker 1: it's all say.
Speaker 0: But it's anime manga comics day.
Speaker 0: All right, and there's a lot of not a lot But the quality of it is very high.
Speaker 0: anime news.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Basically fortune magazine went and did some sort of super interview of I don't know Many many pages on The guy who runs a TV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and of course the summary is that anime is extremely lucrative now.
Speaker 1: And the people who the American anime companies are super smart and the other companies not so smart Yeah, yeah, but namely the movie companies and other media.
Speaker 0: Hmm.
Speaker 0: Let's see MPAA sues anyone who uploads or downloads anything.
Speaker 1: Anime fan subs are just fine as long as you take them off before.
Speaker 1: You know, we put it out and you know what they all take them off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you can still find it out there.
Speaker 1: You guys don't find it.
Speaker 1: But I mean anime ski the fat.
Speaker 1: I mean think about it.
Speaker 1: No one with a bit torrent of movies site right like puts movies out and then when the movies release takes them all off.
Speaker 1: right Anime ski, it's like not gonna parents It's licensed.
Speaker 0: take them up, even though you can find the torrents to any anime you want pretty much any time.
Speaker 1: Somehow the anime still sells a lot Yep, it's like hey, we bought freaking FMA and you also downloaded it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I watched all of FMA and now you're probably gonna buy it.
Speaker 0: Yep sells.
Speaker 1: But the point is this a TV guy.
Speaker 1: They talk about how he's cool like that and how the company doesn't do dumb things and you know They know their audience and they get to know their audience by hanging out with them.
Speaker 0: Was he the one who had the fanboy knock on his door?
Speaker 1: He had a fanboy knock on his door talking about Ava, right?
Speaker 0: It was like late at night and this fanboy apparently knocks on his door.
Speaker 1: He was early in the morning I don't know.
Speaker 0: It was some off-hour and this fanboy just wanted to say that he didn't like the end of Ava And the guy was like.
Speaker 1: I didn't make it.
Speaker 1: I just brought it here.
Speaker 1: Leave me alone.
Speaker 1: Needless to say now the a TV guy lives in like a gated community with an alarm system and a gun.
Speaker 1: but You know The main point is that you know, you can't go up to like a movie producer and talk about movies.
Speaker 1: So he would know what's good and what's not.
Speaker 1: but the anime companies are really connected with their customers And that's why they please their customers so much.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, that's definitely true.
Speaker 0: They spend a lot of money on just finding out what's going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I speak at all those anime cons Like I said on the club summit and I do all that like Otakon and everything and I get to meet a lot of the club advocates or the like Convention advocates from the big anime companies and basically these people are paid paid very well Mind you to pretty much go to every anime convention talk to people make friends have fun and just figure out the word of mouth of what's popular and what isn't and what they should License and what's doing.
Speaker 0: well and all that stuff.
Speaker 1: Yep They mean think about imagine if they got rid of all fan subs, right because they thought it was piracy.
Speaker 1: and Imagine if they just you know, they were just a business and they didn't talk to the fans or anything.
Speaker 1: How would they know which anime series to show?
Speaker 1: Well, they could go by the Japanese numbers.
Speaker 1: But then something like Trigun would never get over here because no one in Japan watched that.
Speaker 0: but it's crazy popular here or even big Oh big.
Speaker 0: Oh flopped terribly in Japan and it did super well in the US It was also.
Speaker 1: that was also kind of.
Speaker 1: it was a different show was kind of made for u.s Japan's.
Speaker 1: I'm a little bit simultaneous and a cowboy bebop didn't do that.
Speaker 1: Well at first not at first but that made it crazy popular in like countries like Italy and such.
Speaker 1: yeah, so it was.
Speaker 0: it was a different story, but it's an example of an industry that cares about doing what it does well and cares about making money and isn't afraid to Ask for help and find out what they should really be doing.
Speaker 0: Yeah or make changes if necessary.
Speaker 1: You mean you look at something like, you know Naruto.
Speaker 1: freakin Anime companies didn't find out about Naruto what you know, some kids found out about it sort of fans Something it like crazy.
Speaker 1: and then the anime company saw there was crazy Naruto action going on.
Speaker 1: So then it got on to Cartoon Network and then BAM craziness.
Speaker 1: There goes, you know movie companies don't sit around, you know talking to fans they kind of shun fans.
Speaker 1: You know, they're like get away from us We're making movies.
Speaker 0: plus in some ways the American anime distributors are Doing things in a much smarter way than the original Japanese companies that made the anime.
Speaker 1: that is very true.
Speaker 1: But that's because a lot of Japanese companies Not only go by, you know capitalism of you know do things to compete and get more money, but they have other factors like
Speaker 0: pride
Speaker 1: and Old-fashioned like, you know, just yeah, we take these are the values we stand by these things period.
Speaker 1: We don't even have reasons for them or anything But they have such problems like DVDs.
Speaker 0: Japan cost about twice as much as DVDs here.
Speaker 0: so now there's a big problem in Japan whereby Anime will come out on DVD in Japan and a lot of people don't buy it and they wait and then when it comes out in the US They re-import the US version because it also has the Japanese audio on it and it's half the price.
Speaker 1: Gee, maybe uh, you know if you want globalization and free trade, that's what you have to deal with.
Speaker 1: It's a global market.
Speaker 1: You can't have these artificial separate markets in separate countries.
Speaker 1: Haha, I'm using capitalism.
Speaker 1: you want to sell something you have to sell it to everyone in the world at the same price Yeah, or else you're just gonna be competing with yourself.
Speaker 0: But instead they do silly things like.
Speaker 0: didn't you ever wonder why it takes so long for a show this license to get released In the US?
Speaker 0: it's not because it takes that long to dub it.
Speaker 1: People fans sub these things overnight.
Speaker 0: Every single anime company with rare exceptions.
Speaker 0: when they license the show They always put a stipulation in the contract that it will not be released for X months Thus ensuring that in a lot of people who want it in Japan will be forced to buy the Japanese one and they can't wait And then buy the American one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't even understand like it's good that we have it the way it is because the American companies do good things for us.
Speaker 1: But if the Japanese companies didn't suck they could just do it themselves.
Speaker 1: Because I mean think about it they all they get out of the deal is the money for the license.
Speaker 1: They don't get anything else.
Speaker 1: And if the American companies are profiting that means that they're making more money offs using the license.
Speaker 0: Then they're paying for the license I in many cases they wouldn't have.
Speaker 0: they wouldn't have to hire Americans and dub it.
Speaker 0: because a while I like dubs I I can't.
Speaker 0: I gotta be a fan.
Speaker 0: I'm not really fanboy, but most dubs suck and most people who like anime actually prefer the subtitles for a lot of reasons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, at least the super fans, you know, yeah dub it if you're gonna put it on TV.
Speaker 0: Remember the shitstorm that erupted from the fans of initial D when they saw that dub?
Speaker 1: Well, that's because that they just twisted the whole show around.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Tokyo pop apologized for that and hasn't done it since.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so now Fox bot is doing that to one piece.
Speaker 0: Oh great actually what they're doing to one piece is worse than what was done to anything ever with the possible exception of Nausicaa.
Speaker 0: eskaflowney TV.
Speaker 0: Are you familiar with warriors of the wind?
Speaker 1: Yeah, but are you familiar with the eskaflowney that was on Fox?
Speaker 0: Actually, I have a friend and she's wonderful and awesome.
Speaker 0: But the first several episodes of eskaflowney that she saw she saw on Fox God and one time She asked me if if it was any different and I almost cried.
Speaker 0: I didn't know what to say.
Speaker 0: Yes, yes, it's different.
Speaker 0: It's not even close Not even close but at least the plot was almost the same.
Speaker 0: warriors of the wind took footage from an anime Rearranged it and then dubbed over it and made a completely different movie.
Speaker 1: I'm a robo-tech a robo-tech Taking you know, let's see.
Speaker 1: they took three animes.
Speaker 1: they took Macross one of the greatest animes there is.
Speaker 1: they took Southern Cross, which I've never actually seen and they took Genesis rider MOS PETA the thing with the people have wheels on their back ah, and they put them in order and they remixed them and redubbed them with this story of proto culture throughout all three of them and That didn't exist in two of the shows.
Speaker 1: And they made a new show and they called it robo-tech and people liked it because they had didn't realize what was going on.
Speaker 0: Or early on when companies were picked something up like Sailor Moon.
Speaker 0: They're like, alright, we can show this to kids We'll just dub out all these bad things and then they try to get the second season.
Speaker 0: They're like, wait a minute that a lesbian there That girl just gets shot.
Speaker 0: Ah Crap, you know.
Speaker 1: a TV however is smart unlike those other companies and they know what the real deal is.
Speaker 1: And so there's some other companies letting.
Speaker 1: viz knows what the real deal is.
Speaker 1: You know despite not getting the best animes, I think CPM and them know what the real deal.
Speaker 1: and I Bandai definitely knows the real deal is.
Speaker 1: but band I think is is not quite the same because that's actually a Japanese Company, yeah doing it but they do it.
Speaker 0: Well, yes, very well.
Speaker 1: They do it Well, you know they.
Speaker 1: in fact if you if you actually go take a look at your DVDs well genie on knows what's up to.
Speaker 1: but Go take a look at your DVDs or your your manga or whatever and look look where the bandai is at.
Speaker 1: And I'm betting if you have good taste, you'll see more bandai than you realize.
Speaker 1: Like there was a poll which American anime DVD company is the best and I was like, huh?
Speaker 1: I don't really have loyalty to any of them.
Speaker 1: I just have loyalty to shows.
Speaker 1: So I look to see which shows are my favorites in which companies they came from.
Speaker 1: 80% of her bandai It's just bandai bandai bandai bandai gundams all bandai.
Speaker 1: Yeah, how we bebop bandai eska flown a bandai Reagan.
Speaker 1: almost everything was bandai and I was like well Yeah, I guess that's an easy choice.
Speaker 1: not to say that no one else has any good shows You know because that's far from the truth.
Speaker 1: But yeah Well some company.
Speaker 1: well, even even the crap crap companies like CPM I have like one or two movies or something like that that they got, you know There are very few anime companies that have nothing.
Speaker 1: I Think there is zero that have nothing.
Speaker 0: Well, Fox bot has nothing because what they did to one piece is not.
Speaker 1: that's not an anime company.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know, actually it's kind of scary.
Speaker 1: the the way that works is.
Speaker 1: there's a company called Viz, you know, this is good Viz.
Speaker 1: this is other company.
Speaker 1: They're with.
Speaker 1: I forget the name of it.
Speaker 1: I wish I remembered it.
Speaker 1: that does like the TV stuff, right, but it's actually combo with Viz.
Speaker 1: somehow I forget the exact.
Speaker 1: it's a weird company arrangement that I don't know the details of but That's where all the things like card captors soccer And things like that go through to get on TV.
Speaker 1: And that's that's the part that screws everything up on Fox.
Speaker 0: You know, what really screws it up is trying to put anime on TV because American TV networks don't like that sort of thing at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they don't like the idea of a cartoon.
Speaker 0: that might not be for little tiny kids.
Speaker 1: Or you know what they do like.
Speaker 1: they do like the idea of having a cartoon without having to pay to make one.
Speaker 1: They do like that and they like the fact that hey people watch it.
Speaker 1: You know That's all they really want.
Speaker 1: is they need a cartoon to put?
Speaker 1: because the only reason they want a cartoon is that they can put Advertisers for toys in the cartoon.
Speaker 1: I don't care what the cartoon is.
Speaker 0: as long as more little kids Look at it helps if the cartoon is about a toy that they can then sell.
Speaker 0: Yep transformers.
Speaker 1: That was like the dream.
Speaker 1: It's even better if they don't have to pay to make the cartoon.
Speaker 1: They can just buy a cartoon that's already made.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so that's why do you see the anime on the little kids shows and that's why.
Speaker 1: but you know, you see Adult Swim Alright, so the the other great thing that I found out in this article with the ATV guy is I found out the real deal With the the live-action Evangelion movie.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 1: I've been waiting for that to come out forever I don't know not so much forever at least a year whatever the the story is is that it's not some you know Japanese some person making it.
Speaker 1: it's this ATV guy wants to make this movie and the reason he wants to make this movie is because More people bother him about Evangelion than anything else.
Speaker 1: fanboys came to his door to complain about it.
Speaker 0: Well, even though he didn't make more series.
Speaker 0: I mean in Japan when the show first ended There were almost many riots.
Speaker 0: Yep, people went nuts.
Speaker 1: Well, it says here.
Speaker 1: There's a quote.
Speaker 1: Fortune says that Evangelion is to anime fans as Star Trek is to Trekkies and I'm like, alright It's not a perfect analogy cuz starred Trekkies don't like anything else.
Speaker 1: Yeah Some do some do but you know, but that's like whatever.
Speaker 1: the thing is is that The ATV guy wants to make it so that he can make a bunch of money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm making a live-action Ava.
Speaker 1: So he's got in touch with the computer where the digital guys who did the Lord of the Rings?
Speaker 1: CG stuff, right and Apparently those weta digital guys They get about 25 emails about this live-action Ava movie.
Speaker 1: to every one email they get about Lord of the Rings This movie that isn't even made yet the movie that isn't even made yet.
Speaker 1: The guy's trying to raise money to make the movie first.
Speaker 1: He's got about a hundred million already gotten.
Speaker 0: Is there any way we can get in on this?
Speaker 0: I'd invest cuz I think this thing is gonna make a pile of money.
Speaker 0: You can give the guy money, but will I get money back?
Speaker 1: Write him an email.
Speaker 0: I showed you like I'll invest.
Speaker 0: I'll give you like 500 bucks.
Speaker 1: I think he's looking for millions though not think about it.
Speaker 0: what if he took up a thing where he let fans invest like say make the minimum five hundred dollars or $500 increments and pay back a set dividend based on how well it does and I think a lot of fans would jump on that chance to get the rest of the money he needed?
Speaker 1: Maybe?
Speaker 1: I think it's pretty much a sure investment anyway, so basically the guy went to the San Diego Comic Con where all the nerds are hanging out right and He was talking to some people trying to raise money for the movie.
Speaker 1: right and a guy who's gonna sit down with this guy and Before they could sit down some fan recognized him and came up to him and he said, you know He didn't ask him about anything except he asked him about Ava.
Speaker 1: so The guy who's trying to raise money for the movie?
Speaker 1: Turns to the to the producer next to him that you know He was trying to get money or whatever from and he says this is why we have to do this movie.
Speaker 1: I Just basically he's got two feet.
Speaker 0: He's got two serious Ava fanboys on the job and That's probably a good thing because while fanboys are fanboys They know their stuff and they know what makes a show like that.
Speaker 1: Yep so he's these people.
Speaker 1: anything they work on has to be cleared by these fanboys and He's invested money's gonna make a live-action Evangelion movie I guess in English and Hope it not sucks.
Speaker 0: Yeah I I really got a lot of hope because Ava was fantastic and the only thing I worry is that they're gonna have to cut A lot out.
Speaker 0: so I wonder how they're gonna pace it.
Speaker 1: Well, I don't know if it's.
Speaker 1: is it gonna be a?
Speaker 1: they didn't even say.
Speaker 0: is it gonna be a summary movie or will it Just be like the end or will it skip it?
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: I know what it'll have.
Speaker 1: It'll have Giant robots have some giant robots awesome angst.
Speaker 1: They'll have some aliens and you'll have some crazy ass ending.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it'll also have girls in plug suits.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it will.
Speaker 1: And that's what it's gonna be.
Speaker 0: or maybe he'll make it like he'll make one and it'll actually just be like the first five Episodes of Ava and then it'll be like, all right, I need more money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but then see I Don't know if you want to go that path because what if he never makes another one?
Speaker 0: then it's kind of yeah See, it's a risk, but that's the guy like Firefly.
Speaker 0: there's talk that after the moratorium whatever ends They might just start making Firefly direct to DVD and all the fans will buy it and that'll cover everything Whatever.
Speaker 0: they could do the same thing with this.
Speaker 0: But the thing is we don't know.
Speaker 0: we'll just have to wait and see.
Speaker 1: Costs a lot of money.
Speaker 1: more money to make a live-action Ava than it costs to make a Firefly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, depends on how well the live-action Ava does.
Speaker 0: I mean if it does well great if it does really well.
Speaker 1: Hmm I have a feeling it's just.
Speaker 1: he's already figured out how much money he needs to make it.
Speaker 1: I think he under he understands how much he's probably gonna make off of it and he'll probably profitable.
Speaker 1: You know knows how much.
Speaker 0: but well the initial D movie the live-action everyone who's seen it loves it.
Speaker 0: Yeah We haven't seen it yet.
Speaker 0: So that's my only reason we haven't talked about it.
Speaker 1: Yep Apparently they also mentioned the live-action transform live-action slash CG transformers movie.
Speaker 1: that's gonna come out.
Speaker 0: Wait, you said slash CG because Like there's no CG and the Ava movie, right?
Speaker 1: You know, but it's mostly CG because the CG guys are the main characters as opposed to just the robots.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but because he can't make Optimus Prime be some guy in a cardboard suit You could that'd be awesome it would be.
Speaker 1: but anyway Apparently for that which I did not know Steven Spielberg is the executive producer.
Speaker 1: What?
Speaker 1: Yeah of the Transformers no action movie.
Speaker 1: That's not made yet.
Speaker 0: That's great.
Speaker 0: Cuz it's not George Lucas.
Speaker 0: I would cry.
Speaker 1: Apparently they're also tapping the Transformers fan base of it.
Speaker 0: It's a pretty big fan base.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean how many of us remember that movie?
Speaker 0: I I'd cry.
Speaker 0: I didn't really cry But I cried a little when spoiler Optimus Prime died.
Speaker 1: It's not all the other transformers.
Speaker 1: Well a bunch of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Rodimus Prime just couldn't cut it either.
Speaker 1: No, I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's like ultra Magnus was so cool and powerful except his personality was so weak.
Speaker 1: He couldn't meet a leader anything.
Speaker 1: I should have made his Personality difference that he would be like the secondary leader His rod and this was just more like, you know, I guess they could have done worse.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Bumblebee could have taken over.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I made Rodimus his personality different and make ultra Magnus just some guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the Rodimus work because he was kind of the reluctant.
Speaker 0: I've now until they got rid of them because he's like I have this thrust into my hands and I don't feel capable or Confident.
Speaker 0: and oh, I'm not.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, so, uh, is it to time to come up with something to say at the end of the podcast every day?
Speaker 0: yeah And that was geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 1: Thanks for listening.
Speaker 1: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds feed burner comm slash geek nights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Speaker 1: also, please visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast.
Speaker 1: We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at geek nights at gmail.com.