Speaker 0: It's Monday December 12th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We talked about how to purchase a computer without getting ripped off or buying more than you need.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So I heard something happened to you on the way to work on the train.
Speaker 0: a train hit a deer.
Speaker 1: Who won train?
Speaker 0: yeah, I figured deer didn't You know?
Speaker 0: entirely?
Speaker 0: lose though the train broke.
Speaker 0: like they were like yeah, the air is leaking out of the brake pipe.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we're gonna stop the train like three times.
Speaker 0: I could have gotten off at 1/25th But I didn't know.
Speaker 0: it was broken.
Speaker 0: and then we went in the tunnel and then the train stopped.
Speaker 0: great you can't get off in the tunnel cuz you'll uh die.
Speaker 0: and Then we waited in there, and I was like a half hour 15 minutes.
Speaker 0: I was late.
Speaker 0: It sucked.
Speaker 0: I sat on the train with these annoying people.
Speaker 1: Too bad you could have just taken the four or five six At least for the first time in about a month.
Speaker 1: I am well rested and ready to go.
Speaker 0: I was also very well rested today, and you don't know it's a Monday which means I had to go to work.
Speaker 0: work was quick.
Speaker 0: It's yeah, my knees are great, and I left.
Speaker 1: I was sitting down in this a data center doing work and suddenly I look up and it's like four o'clock.
Speaker 0: I think it's partially because on Monday.
Speaker 0: There's a whole lot of brand new podcast episodes Yeah, also a whole bunch of webcomics whole bunch of webcomics internet news and everything.
Speaker 1: plus while we had a crazy geek end and we played a bunch of board games which we'll get to tomorrow and Did bunch of stuff we actually got to sleep early Sleep because there's people left early.
Speaker 1: Yeah, everyone left early.
Speaker 1: You know honestly.
Speaker 0: I would have rather had them stay to play more games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wanted to play another round of a verator Verators freaking awesome.
Speaker 0: It's awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right, though There's some pretty big news at least for anime fans.
Speaker 1: media play is going out of business.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that means I can go get a clearance sale.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're totally looting the nearest media play.
Speaker 0: Thank God there is one nearby which
Speaker 1: I guess we should have seen it coming because I mean when we lived in Rochester media play was like huge and that's where all the anime was and
Speaker 0: it was great because it was the closest thing to the Yeah,
Speaker 1: that media play realized this and catered to it.
Speaker 1: mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: now We moved here, and you know years later and our media play here is really kind of shitty.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the media play here is definitely like a crap hole.
Speaker 0: No one goes there.
Speaker 1: It was sparse.
Speaker 0: It's in the low-rent mall.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they never had things on time.
Speaker 1: Yeah had the same.
Speaker 1: does nobody sitting there on display.
Speaker 0: There was nobody in it?
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely not the peak of media play.
Speaker 1: well apparently the anime and manga is really the only thing.
Speaker 1: profit media play up at all.
Speaker 0: Well, they they always kept so many CDs in that store.
Speaker 0: I was like why did he won't have a CD section?
Speaker 1: I don't know why the people who own media play who started that company back in 1995 or 96 wasn't that long ago?
Speaker 1: They were primarily record sellers and CD sellers.
Speaker 1: good job and their business model actually was CD store.
Speaker 1: that also sells other media.
Speaker 0: That's a great idea.
Speaker 0: It should have been other media store.
Speaker 1: Well that worked real.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: You know for about a year, then you know Napster Mp3s.
Speaker 0: it's just hard to compete for them with these other stores.
Speaker 1: Well, they can't compete with bookstores because bookstores have all the books, and they don't have so many.
Speaker 0: That's a problem.
Speaker 0: media play should just gotten rid of its book section because it was really never really worth anything and They should have just be gone all out with the DVDs.
Speaker 0: cuz like Walmart and Best Buy sell the most DVDs and stuff.
Speaker 0: But media play you know really had the good DVD section because they had the box sets.
Speaker 0: yeah But they spent all their money like they had a video game section that wasn't as good a GameStop a book section That wasn't as good as borders You know a CD section that was Right, but they had the best DVD section better than any other store.
Speaker 0: They should have just turned into a DVD store.
Speaker 0: I think their problem though was that their stores are real big too big to be just a DVD store.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz even the small media play cuz you know every box store like that is different sizes was real big.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not like FYE.
Speaker 1: They have like one version was real tiny and fits in them all.
Speaker 0: yep That's the problem with being in a diverse Products.
Speaker 0: is that you know you Have so much like space and other things.
Speaker 0: you can't really give up or on too many of them.
Speaker 0: If you know if one of them fails, that's alright, but if all of them fail, but one you're screwed.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though I hear FYE isn't doing so well either.
Speaker 0: Yeah, FYE cuz that's the same kind of thing.
Speaker 0: is they diversify?
Speaker 0: yeah They do sell mostly CDs at FYE.
Speaker 1: Well actually the FYE back when I lived in Michigan that opened up it.
Speaker 1: I had an arcade in it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so did mine in my mall.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then the arcade disappeared.
Speaker 0: No we still have the arcade in ours.
Speaker 0: I think it's the only arcade for many many miles.
Speaker 0: But they see the store is mostly a music store although the DVD section Expanded a whole lot and the video game section kind of shrunk it back there.
Speaker 0: but that video game section is actually useful because it's like the last place people look in the mall to buy video games and They always carry games that like you're kind of a little bit off.
Speaker 0: So when you can't get a game they always have it.
Speaker 0: so I'll go out there, so they're still still making money.
Speaker 1: Well, I wonder if this is gonna affect the anime DVD trade at least for a little while.
Speaker 1: I mean media play in a lot of areas is the major seller of anime related goods.
Speaker 0: yeah, that's cuz.
Speaker 0: they have the nice anime section, but I don't know Best Buy does have the anime DVDs and Yeah, but I mean really they're overpriced, and they don't have the new anime.
Speaker 0: They do have the new anime actually not the day it comes out.
Speaker 1: They're always been.
Speaker 0: not the day it comes out I don't know.
Speaker 0: I wonder what the anime companies think of media play like.
Speaker 0: what a cuz they know Like they're usually into like the Suncoast type of thing like the Suncoast always has the anime.
Speaker 0: That's the place.
Speaker 0: Yeah You know.
Speaker 0: but Suncoast is media play is all of.
Speaker 0: is it just media player?
Speaker 0: all the media play related stores.
Speaker 1: Cuz.
Speaker 1: I know that back in the day when I still ran the RIT anime club We started working with the media play, and they were all about that.
Speaker 1: They'd give us just hundreds of dollars of free stuff to give away to draw people into the store to buy anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think that media play is actually profitable and that like they should just close the other ones and leave that one open.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they should.
Speaker 1: but I heard from actually got some friends who run a hammer girls.
Speaker 1: It's anime store right there in Rochester like across the street from media play.
Speaker 1: They're gonna go loop media play for all its stuff when they go liquidating in January Yeah, and then sell it in their own store.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which is gonna work for them.
Speaker 1: They're pretty much gonna have a monopoly on everything except manga.
Speaker 1: That's related to anime now.
Speaker 1: Yep Because Walden books honestly is making a killing on manga.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's the anime store here doesn't sell.
Speaker 1: No, they sell like dealer room stuff here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like going to a dealer's room It's not?
Speaker 0: you know, you can't get the pro stuff.
Speaker 0: There's really isn't.
Speaker 0: now I don't think there's gonna be a reliable place to buy all the pro things in our town anymore And I haven't gone without that for a long time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the more I think about it one a lot of shows I really like but I don't want to buy.
Speaker 1: But I want to see him.
Speaker 1: and now that we have Netflix I mean Netflix killed a lot of it, but I also shows we're not gonna buy now.
Speaker 0: But expect Amazon to start selling a lot more anime DVDs.
Speaker 1: Yep, or actually buying direct from a TV.
Speaker 0: They have some damn good sales every now and then that's only their old stuff.
Speaker 0: on clearance.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if you want to do stuff clearance That's the Scott Johnson strategy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you better off.
Speaker 0: you get a better deal at the con.
Speaker 0: sometimes It Depends but you don't buy anything from a TV or rights.
Speaker 0: don't buy right stuff ever.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right stuff is like they have everything there is so there's nowhere else to get it.
Speaker 0: get it from right stuff.
Speaker 0: But they sell everything at like the real price except if it's like a cold day in hell.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they'll change the price or sell something on sale.
Speaker 1: so I got to say you're not gonna hear much about this until January when they actually close and I imagine we're gonna have a.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'll have to go see try to get the best deal, you know, maybe I'll pick up.
Speaker 0: I know they have good stuff there and I'm pretty confident that no one in this town is gonna pick it up.
Speaker 0: So I'm gonna go get like, you know, all those box sets.
Speaker 0: I wanted like pick up all the FMAs they've got.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll get all the gakutsu.
Speaker 0: Oh, they get like the Azumanga dial box.
Speaker 1: Yeah, captain Tyler my favorite show.
Speaker 1: I still don't own it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll go clean it out and then we'll fill in the holes from Amazon or something.
Speaker 0: Later.
Speaker 0: Let's buy another DVD rack Yeah, but maybe they'll be one of clearance.
Speaker 0: All right, so the Xbox 360 Didn't sell so well in Japan.
Speaker 0: Nope, well the kotaku does the guys in Japan.
Speaker 0: so he pretty much covered the whole thing.
Speaker 0: He went around Japan to all these stores on the launch day and they were taking pictures of everything and you know They showed this one kind of.
Speaker 0: uh, it wasn't even a store You can enter.
Speaker 0: it was in Osaka and it was just one of those stores that faces the street.
Speaker 0: you know, it's just like the wall of a building and there's you buy stuff and there was
Speaker 1: a little
Speaker 0: tiny tiny line of like two guys and a whole bunch of Xbox 360s and yeah, and He showed the scene from like the huge store in Tokyo And there was a line of about a hundred guys, you know Nice respectable normal line the kind of line you saw when the Game Boy Advance came out, maybe You know, but Didn't sell out?
Speaker 1: No, no, not actually.
Speaker 1: if I were in Japan, I'd buy two or three and sell them on eBay.
Speaker 1: back to the u.s.
Speaker 0: Yeah, apparently the only difference According to these people is that the remote control has Japanese characters on it, huh?
Speaker 0: And I think the default language is Japanese.
Speaker 0: I don't know about any region coding though.
Speaker 0: We still have to find that out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but honestly I'll bet for fanboys having the Japanese remote would be a status symbol.
Speaker 0: it would be.
Speaker 0: there's also this rumor that they're Selling.
Speaker 0: they've already lowered the price to about a hundred and fifty bucks With wait a hundred and fifty bucks in the equivalent yen, but you have to get an ISP contract.
Speaker 1: That's fine.
Speaker 0: A hundred and fifty bucks Are you sitting in a contract for the Japanese ISP?
Speaker 1: I'll pay that they can't.
Speaker 1: they won't be able to sue me.
Speaker 1: I'll say I'll take the contract then I'll just stop paying and keep the Xbox.
Speaker 1: Hmm what the hell.
Speaker 0: Maybe you could pull it off.
Speaker 1: You know easy that would be to refute when your credit card you code the credit card company and say why would I pay?
Speaker 1: For a Japanese ISP.
Speaker 1: I don't live in Japan.
Speaker 1: It's obviously identity theft.
Speaker 0: I Guess but you could get in trouble if they find out it's real hard to prosecute anything like that over national boundaries.
Speaker 1: Not that I'm officially advocating anyone.
Speaker 1: try that.
Speaker 0: But uh, yeah, I'm definitely Thinking.
Speaker 0: I mean, I know some good there was some guys who were podcasting.
Speaker 0: they were just in Japan.
Speaker 0: I don't know why they didn't take advantage of this.
Speaker 0: You know, just pick up some Xbox 360s.
Speaker 0: Oh Maybe they'd you what they wouldn't.
Speaker 0: let you take them on the plane or ship them or any.
Speaker 0: it might be tough.
Speaker 1: Oh, you'd have to ship them to yourself as a gift.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's tricky, but that's tough because then you can't get a lot of insurance on it.
Speaker 1: So if it gets borked or destroyed you're kind of screwed.
Speaker 0: yeah, you have to get like buy like ten of them and send them all separately.
Speaker 1: and Is really just because Michigan happens to be relevant.
Speaker 1: again, we lived in Michigan.
Speaker 1: you couldn't bring a lot of stuff over the border and There was a big business in being shipping companies that would ship things over the border kind of surreptitiously.
Speaker 1: You know things like liquor and cigarettes and all that sort of tax type stuff.
Speaker 0: So apparently I thought that the leading cause of liver failure was drunkenness.
Speaker 1: I figured it was hepatitis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I does due to drunkenness.
Speaker 0: most hepatitis is not caused by drunkenness But anyway, well actually pretty much any liver disease is hepatitis, isn't it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, there are many different kinds of hepatitis and also liver diseases that are not hepatitis.
Speaker 0: Anyway, well the leading cause of acute liver failure is let me guess.
Speaker 1: Let me guess Tylenol, it's Tylenol.
Speaker 0: Well, yeah, actually it's acetaminophen which is Tylenol.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's also in other things like well and such it's in almost every Like cold syrupy stuff you drink.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: The number of cases doubled between 98 and 2003.
Speaker 0: Now this guy who is not a doctor or anything.
Speaker 0: He's just a blogger or whatever great.
Speaker 0: But he says he noticed something smart.
Speaker 0: Over the last several years regular strength Tylenol, which is 325 milligrams Has been disappearing in favor of extra strength 500 milligram Tylenol.
Speaker 0: and he wonders huh?
Speaker 0: maybe Deliver disease doubled because the Tylenol strength is increased.
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 1: I remember Jerry Seinfeld and his stand-up did a bit about that.
Speaker 1: It was like extra strength.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just the same thing as before but more.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maximum strength just take up with a maximum possible human dose.
Speaker 1: One more drop would kill me.
Speaker 1: back it off a little bit.
Speaker 0: It takes.
Speaker 0: it takes 4,000 milligrams to Kill you in a day.
Speaker 0: so you can take eight Extra strength Tylenols in a day and then you'll be on the edge.
Speaker 1: see I personally generally always avoided Tylenol Because I was very acutely aware from when I was young and my I took some Tylenol.
Speaker 1: My doctor always said don't take too much causes liver damage.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you're better off taking aspirin.
Speaker 0: I avoid drugs in general.
Speaker 1: Well, see it's it's weird.
Speaker 1: I mean Tylenol was billed when it first appeared or acetaminophen as a safer painkiller because Aspirin the the side effects of aspirin come right out.
Speaker 1: Oh and ulcer.
Speaker 1: Oh my stomach.
Speaker 1: Oh that that are raised syndrome or eye syndrome that kids can get.
Speaker 0: yeah That's really all aspirin can do to you is fuck up your stomach or if you take a whole bunch It'll kill you.
Speaker 0: Well, of course you take a whole bunch of any of drug It'll kill you.
Speaker 0: you take a whole bunch of freaking children's Tylenol It'll kill you.
Speaker 1: but Tylenol all the side effects are hidden.
Speaker 1: You're not getting.
Speaker 1: your liver is not gonna go.
Speaker 1: Oh my liver suddenly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but seriously to get acute liver failure from Tylenol You really need to be taking too much town or take a lot of it.
Speaker 1: Take a normal amount too often.
Speaker 1: Yeah over a long period.
Speaker 0: I'm pretty sure that most of these people dying of acute liver failure and Tylenol are the kind of People who are just like oh something hurts Tylenol.
Speaker 0: Oh something hurts town Yeah, and they're just taking it daily multiple times a week all over.
Speaker 1: also if you happen to drink in addition That's just a double whammy on the liver, right?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, if you friggin drink with Tylenol like oh, I think I'll put some Tylenol in some beer and drink it.
Speaker 0: You're just kill.
Speaker 0: That's a kill.
Speaker 1: You know, what probably leaves?
Speaker 1: a lot of that?
Speaker 1: Let's see drink all night wake up in the morning.
Speaker 0: Hey hangover Tylenol.
Speaker 1: See I'm smart.
Speaker 1: I got a hangover Aspirin or actually, you know what?
Speaker 1: Multivitamin and orange juice and then I go back to bed.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I just don't get drunk and then I don't take Tylenol.
Speaker 1: Yeah We'll see what.
Speaker 1: how you do when I open up that pushers rum We'll see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this is definitely an aside, but I Got a hold of just randomly on a whim.
Speaker 1: This is definitely an impulse.
Speaker 1: buy Pussers rum which is apparently is the same rum that they used on the sailing ships of Britain back in the Horatio Nelson slash horn blower days.
Speaker 1: All right, and I got a recipe for grog.
Speaker 1: and I'm gonna make grog because I'm curious what it tastes like and I'm gonna give you all an update as to whether Or not it tastes like ass.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna drink it as per my not drinking rule But I'll like put my tongue in it just to see what it tastes like.
Speaker 0: so I know what pirates were drinking.
Speaker 1: You gotta at least swish it around in your mouth and you can spit it into a bucket like wine testers do.
Speaker 0: I'll probably just drink like a teaspoon of it.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't do anything though I gotta say I got some sad commentary for Americans.
Speaker 1: We went to the wine store the other day and we were you know looking at wine and they had about a table where they had a bunch of bottles of port and They had samples and you could try the port and I tried.
Speaker 1: one actually end up buying a couple bottles.
Speaker 1: well one bottle but they had the bucket out and I don't think anyone else there other than the guy giving the samples and me knew what the bucket was for.
Speaker 1: because I went and I spit in the bucket because you're supposed to taste the wine and then spit it out so you don't get drunk and I spit in the bucket.
Speaker 1: I was the only person who have ever spit in that bark as far as I could tell and there were a lot of people Sampling the wine.
Speaker 0: Why why?
Speaker 0: why didn't they put a little thing on it like don't think no being a liquor store That's been open for how long that no one ever spits in the bucket Wouldn't it be hilarious if it wasn't actually a spit bucket and it was like something else and you spit in it.
Speaker 0: I Mean you looked in.
Speaker 0: there was no spit in there, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, wouldn't it be hilarious?
Speaker 0: It was just a bucket like he was gonna put ice in it or something and then put a bottle in there But no you spit in it.
Speaker 1: The while we're on the topic of Tylenol and disease and all that and since it's Monday, which theoretically is Science Day a little there's some interesting evidence that some forms of childhood cancer may not be caused by environmental factors so much as by pathogens.
Speaker 0: Which pathogens?
Speaker 1: maybe the common cold?
Speaker 1: They're not sure.
Speaker 1: this is Currently the best this research can be called is a statistical anomaly but basically they did a study where they looked at all a lot of cases of childhood cancer in a bunch of regions in London or Britain somewhere in Britain and They noticed something odd.
Speaker 1: apparently when a disease breaks out The disease spreads in certain ways that you can analyze statistically and you can say like wow This was a disease because look it's spread in clusters in this type of way in this time this place, whatever
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm
Speaker 1: and diseases or illnesses that are caused by environmental factors like poisons or pollution or carcinogens Tend to cluster in the same area over a long period of time to cluster a different way and you can see these patterns in the long term by looking at who got what disease when and where?
Speaker 1: and The data coming back from the study, which they were studying something completely different.
Speaker 1: But they discovered that the cancer in childhood seems to be clustering and this is 8% above what was expected Statistically in space time as opposed to in space.
Speaker 1: So it's it's happening in areas at a certain time in a cluster and then disappearing instead of happening in one area repeatedly.
Speaker 1: hmm, which would Lend one to believe that these cancers are being caused by some sort of pathogen more likely than some sort of environmental factor?
Speaker 1: Hmm this is very preliminary Evidence, but there's.
Speaker 1: it's a statistical anomaly and they're looking into it and the most obvious culprit They seem to believe is the common cold.
Speaker 0: Well, the common cold is a virus, right?
Speaker 0: Yes, so don't bash my Rudimentary biological knowledge.
Speaker 0: but a virus goes in a cell, right?
Speaker 0: It makes mischief Yeah, and then the cell explodes and a bunch of viruses come out and they go for more cells, right?
Speaker 1: It alters.
Speaker 1: well some viruses alter the cells DNA some use their RNA to the retro viruses.
Speaker 1: you right right right?
Speaker 0: that sort of and Those sorts of things as in destroying cells and modifying cells would be the kind of thing to cause cancer Would it not possibly one thing though?
Speaker 0: It does make a little sense.
Speaker 1: They're suggesting that possibly it's a common illness Coupled with some sort of genetic predisposition and the two together cancer.
Speaker 0: So if your DNA was such-and-such and you got the common cold The common cold would normally modify someone's DNA to make some common coldness.
Speaker 0: But if you have DNA that's messed up and the common cold comes in there and makes a cancer that's one of the theories.
Speaker 1: it also has a nice blurb at the end about how it's important for kids to be exposed to diseases but at the right times and All this sorts of cool stuff.
Speaker 1: I'd like to see the real study But I don't have access to that sort of.
Speaker 1: if it's true Then maybe the common cold plus cancer could be some sort of arbitrary Darwinian push possibly in certain DNA Except that there's actually a fairly good track record of treating many forms of childhood cancer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, which is a good thing a lot easier than treating some old guy who's got like a stomach full of cancer.
Speaker 1: Well in some ways, I mean sure children are more resilient But at the same time children aren't as mature emotionally to handle that.
Speaker 1: imagine being five and a guy in a suit Sticks a needle in your arm and says you've got cancer your life's going to suck for the next three years.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean, you know emotional troubles you might not be able to cure but you can at least cure the physical things easier.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean like it seems like everywhere I look I mean, this isn't statistical or scientific at all All right anecdotal here.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I see a lot of old people who die of cancer and I see a lot of young people Who survived it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm not.
Speaker 1: I mean, I'm not saying the emotional effect.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's just more of a. It's harder to help a child deal with something like that emotionally.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, and that's why I didn't expect to.
Speaker 1: but big plug here.
Speaker 1: child's play.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: penny arcade runs a charity.
Speaker 1: You probably all know it since you're all geeks.
Speaker 1: you listen to our show Where you donate money to child's play and or you donate video games or games or you just go to their Amazon list and buy Something.
Speaker 1: yeah and they distribute these goods to Children with cancer and children in hospital and children who have nothing else to do because they're on chemotherapy things like that.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and While we tell you to be leery of certain charities because they waste the money child's play doesn't waste the money.
Speaker 0: It's a it's the only 100% safe charity.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: They even show pictures of here's the giant pile of things We're about to distribute.
Speaker 0: Yeah the first year they had that pile.
Speaker 0: That was too too big.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is the third year I think isn't it it is.
Speaker 1: Well every year it's grown just gangbusters.
Speaker 0: Yep You know, I never really went to the hospital because I'm too healthy.
Speaker 1: Actually, I did.
Speaker 1: I had a very dangerous flu and I was hospitalized for a slightly significant part of my early childhood What's.
Speaker 0: but anyway when I went to the orthodontist and it was gonna hurt that game boy was freaking awesome Played some Zelda or some Metroid 2 and oh, yeah, that was that was the greatest.
Speaker 0: So I imagine if I had Cancer or a broken leg that a nice GBA.
Speaker 0: That'd be freaking great.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and without it it would freakin suck Especially for kids who their parents can't really get him anything because they're paying all the medical bills.
Speaker 0: Yeah, absolutely.
Speaker 0: So, you know, I know there are children's hospitals out there that you know, don't have the video games But child's play is definitely cutting that number way down.
Speaker 1: Yes, and anything that improved the increases the number of video games out there is just a win for me Mm-hmm and a win for kids with cancer.
Speaker 0: So what you got schmo?
Speaker 1: How do you like our new thing of the day music?
Speaker 0: I don't know because we added in later.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's like.
Speaker 0: I heard part of it, but I didn't hear the final product.
Speaker 0: I'll tell you tomorrow.
Speaker 1: That's like finding out that the late shows you like are recorded during the day.
Speaker 0: They are.
Speaker 0: that's why that's why they're not sleeping during theirs And we are ours is actually recorded at night.
Speaker 1: We're geek nights.
Speaker 1: See the reason it's geek nights is because we started recording it at night and doing it the next day and then we decided screw That we'll just put it out at night after we finish it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like at midnight 1 a.m.
Speaker 0: Whenever we put it out.
Speaker 1: But anyway my thing of the day I I'm really not sure how I found this.
Speaker 1: I think someone just linked me to it at work and I stumbled upon it somehow.
Speaker 1: But basically it's just this site where people keep uploading cute pictures and it's kind of like your daily shot in the arm of cute Things.
Speaker 0: I don't need that.
Speaker 1: I like stuff like that.
Speaker 1: They have a little plushie flu virus.
Speaker 1: I've seen that before a little sugar glider flying through someone's house.
Speaker 0: I don't even know what that animal was till I saw that picture.
Speaker 1: Yeah flying squirrel really cute really friendly big eyes fluffy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like where the hell do they sell those?
Speaker 1: Exotic pet shops.
Speaker 1: They're actually not that uncommon.
Speaker 0: a swing in his pet shop in town.
Speaker 1: Actually a friend in high school had a sugar glider.
Speaker 1: No She also had a baby fox and it was probably the cutest animal I've ever played with.
Speaker 0: well when it got older didn't it turn into a nasty evil Fox?
Speaker 1: actually, it's really sad.
Speaker 1: it got crushed by a board.
Speaker 1: a Board a giant piece of wood fell over in their basement and crushed it one day.
Speaker 0: What was it doing in the basement?
Speaker 1: It was just down there.
Speaker 1: They didn't think the board would fall over.
Speaker 0: It was doing evil Fox things.
Speaker 1: foxes aren't evil.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're harassing people.
Speaker 1: Anyway, they're not harassing people.
Speaker 1: They're hungry and they see a chickens.
Speaker 1: They kill the chicken and eat it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's great for the chicken farmer.
Speaker 0: Damn foxes fox isn't useful to people.
Speaker 0: chicken is anyway, so is that all you got?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's all I got.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sure when people look at the cute pictures.
Speaker 0: They'll get more out of it.
Speaker 0: So, um, there's a thing some guy wrote on Craigslist.
Speaker 0: It's pretty old.
Speaker 0: It's from March 2004, but I just found it.
Speaker 0: I'm a little late to the party.
Speaker 1: Well, you know, there's this thing called the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a very, you know, it wasn't Big on the internet maybe in some areas, but not in my field of vision.
Speaker 0: But you know, you're.
Speaker 1: you'd better pray that I haven't already seen what you're about to talk about.
Speaker 0: I'm Brian.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it's called.
Speaker 0: Hey crackhead and This guy wrote this little kind of essay letter to these crackheads.
Speaker 0: now The thing is is the guy was I think he was hanging with his girlfriend in the city or something like that and he had a motorcycle.
Speaker 0: and One day he came outside and the motorcycle the spark plugs were sawed off.
Speaker 0: Why the spark plugs of his motorcycle were sawed off?
Speaker 1: What kind of a jerk would you have to be to saw off the spark plugs of some dudes motorcycle and he's like what the hell?
Speaker 0: He's like, alright, so he freakin, you know takes it to the you know the shop and he gets everything fixed and he had to pay a ticket for leaving it on the Street that night and everything and it sucked.
Speaker 0: So he finally got it fixed and when he got there the guy told him You know that crackheads cut spark plugs off of bikes to use them as crack pipes.
Speaker 1: Um, I submit to you that you can buy a top-the-line spark plug for about a dollar.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 0: So this guy ended up paying a hundred dollars to fix his bike at the shop.
Speaker 0: And he says but then I remember that I just paid $100 for your crack pipes.
Speaker 0: Dot dot dot, you know, there's so many choice lines.
Speaker 0: I can't read the whole thing.
Speaker 0: You're just gonna have to visit it.
Speaker 0: But um, you know, so he bought a few extra spark plugs and he like taped them to his bike.
Speaker 0: So he's like here you want crack pipes here.
Speaker 0: They are Right, but again, they screwed up his bike and cut off one of the spark plugs and he had tools.
Speaker 0: He had extra spark plugs and he was ready for it, right?
Speaker 0: But he didn't have the right size ratchet and you didn't have the right size thing.
Speaker 0: So you have to go to the store and get a different ratchet and everything and he's pissed off again, right?
Speaker 0: And he says and he says alright, I'm rambling but the point is crackhead.
Speaker 0: You've done me wrong.
Speaker 0: Now I get that you love crack.
Speaker 0: That is totally understandable.
Speaker 0: I've heard it's really fun at first and quite addictive.
Speaker 0: But I don't understand.
Speaker 0: is you are is all caps this last sentence.
Speaker 0: You are a crackhead.
Speaker 0: Why don't you own a crack pipe?
Speaker 1: What they probably keep losing it.
Speaker 0: I'm an engineer.
Speaker 0: Do you ever see me shaking down bums in the loin for a calculator and slide rule?
Speaker 0: No, you don't because engineering is the main thing I do.
Speaker 0: I went and bought myself a calculator.
Speaker 0: the main thing you do is crack.
Speaker 0: How do you get by without a crack pipe?
Speaker 0: The other crackheads must clown you non-stop, I mean the fucking saw you used to saw off my spark plugs.
Speaker 0: It's probably worth five or ten bucks.
Speaker 0: Why not sell or trade it for a crack pipe?
Speaker 0: You haven't put much thought into this.
Speaker 0: And then he just goes this stuff before that and after that but he basically it's his open letter to the damn crackheads.
Speaker 0: like Goddamnit, leave my bike alone.
Speaker 0: You fucking crackhead It's just hilarious and it's so well-written.
Speaker 1: All right, I'll admit that I have not seen this and I'm gonna read it after I finish the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, I guarantee you Sarah go laughing.
Speaker 1: All right, so we don't have music for our credit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, great ice capades.
Speaker 1: Yeah inside joke anyway, so uh Well this we were inspired to do this because of one of our friends this weekend.
Speaker 0: Yeah genius.
Speaker 1: He's a smart guy.
Speaker 1: We like him a lot.
Speaker 1: He's a good friend.
Speaker 1: He likes the board games the video games And he likes the pcs.
Speaker 0: everyone likes the pcs.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's the number one tool and he wants to buy a new PC.
Speaker 1: definitely needs one Can't can't agree more and we've realized that a lot of people even really geeky people Grossly over or underestimate what they actually need a PC for.
Speaker 1: yep So, uh today's show is how to buy a goddamn computer or how to at least choose a computer How to not get ripped off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't buy more than you need.
Speaker 0: Don't buy less than you need.
Speaker 0: Don't spend more than you need.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh and make don't buy something that's gonna fall apart.
Speaker 1: And just so you know We take our own medicine.
Speaker 1: Scott has a pretty fancy fast computer because he replaced the oldest most decrepit computer we had.
Speaker 1: My computer is now the oldest most decrepit computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah My previous computer is the shittiest computer in the house and I have not upgraded my computer because it's fast enough to the podcast And I don't need it for anything else.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: So anyway, our friend he's like, yeah, I need a new computer, right?
Speaker 0: And I'm like, all right.
Speaker 0: Well, you should probably get a Mac Mini cuz I knew what he needed, right?
Speaker 0: And I knew that he wasn't so good with putting computers together.
Speaker 0: cuz no offense Cuz.
Speaker 0: once he did hold a stick of RAM and walk across a carpet while wearing a sweater and wool socks.
Speaker 1: God, I forgot about that.
Speaker 0: Yes, so I was like you should get a Mac Mini.
Speaker 0: That's all that would be perfect for you because you wouldn't worry about this evil spy.
Speaker 0: Where is?
Speaker 0: you would have your web you'd have your email you'd have your.
Speaker 0: I am you'd everything you need.
Speaker 0: It would be cute.
Speaker 0: It'd be powerful.
Speaker 0: It would look good.
Speaker 0: You'd be happy, right?
Speaker 0: Now he was kind of wary of this because he wanted to play the games.
Speaker 0: Right and I'm like, alright what games are you gonna play?
Speaker 0: you haven't played a PC game in two years.
Speaker 0: The most games that he I could see him playing was half-life 2 which is understandable with the whole steam.
Speaker 0: That's the only thing I keep windows for yep, and maybe a couple MMOs.
Speaker 0: if he decided to get into them, right?
Speaker 0: Now, okay that would.
Speaker 0: those three games would cost him maybe about a hundred and fifty dollars and two monthly fees at most Right, but the difference between a computer that could run those games and a computer that would do everything else He needed except run those games would be about eight hundred
Speaker 1: dollars.
Speaker 0: Okay, I guess if those games are worth nine hundred and fifty dollars Plus, you know what?
Speaker 1: for nine hundred and fifty dollars you can buy an Xbox and a pile of games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and this guy now that would be alright, you know for just about anyone except for that.
Speaker 0: ten minutes earlier He was complaining that he couldn't get Paper Mario because it was still thirty five bucks at the store.
Speaker 0: That was too rich for him.
Speaker 0: So I'm like, oh you can't buy Paper Mario Which is awesome and is 30 hours of fun for 35 bucks But you can pay nine hundred and fifty extra dollars for a computer to play three lousy games Versus the $400 computer that'll do everything else you need better than you need it to do.
Speaker 1: So I guess the first rule is if you're gonna buy a computer and you really need one Or you're serious about getting one sit down and just write down or use your computer to sit at the computer you have now.
Speaker 1: Use it for a while and write down every program you run in the course of an hour.
Speaker 1: I guarantee the list is gonna be a lot smaller than you think it will be.
Speaker 0: I mean, I have quite a few programs on my computer, but all I really use is Firefox email aim media playing SSH text editing maybe word processing Maybe maybe maybe Spreadsheet or money keeping track of and you know some of those things I could do on the web.
Speaker 1: You can buy a computer for about a hundred dollars.
Speaker 1: That'll do all that adequately.
Speaker 0: hell.
Speaker 0: an apple 2gs from 1986 will do all that if you upgrade it and you're madly Yeah, but if you're not madly spend a couple hundred bucks and get a real.
Speaker 0: just get a normal normal computer.
Speaker 0: We'll do all of those things just fine.
Speaker 0: A normal normal computer will do all of those things better than you can possibly need.
Speaker 1: Now also, there's the.
Speaker 1: there's the level of computer you need.
Speaker 1: So once you pick like I'm gonna get I'm not gonna get a Mac Mini.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna get a PC.
Speaker 1: I want a PC because I want to play games.
Speaker 1: Think about what games you want to play Because a crap old computer will play everything up to and including counter-strike natural selection.
Speaker 1: the previous generation of FPS is perfectly Hell.
Speaker 0: if you get nowadays you can get GeForce 4 and Like a pile of RAM and all kinds of stuff for still really freaking cheap.
Speaker 0: You only have to pay out the ass if you want top-of-the-line stuff.
Speaker 1: I mean consider this my current computer can play any half-life 1 based steam game.
Speaker 1: So counter-strike natural selection ricochet All the battlefield whatever all those games.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: My computer is a 1 gigahertz Thunderbird 512 megabytes of old-style PC 2100 DDR RAM and a GeForce 2 yep.
Speaker 0: So if you get a new computer right now with an Athlon XP or a low-end Maybe a sempron or the crummiest f AMD 64 512 megs of nice DDR RAM a GeForce 4 A cheap GeForce 4.
Speaker 1: not the top-of-the-line.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the built-in video the built-in one might not do it if you really want to play a game But it'll do it for anything but games Any game but half-life 2. well, no, you can actually play half-life 2 if you have a real geforce 4.
Speaker 0: It just won't be the greatest half-life 2 experience.
Speaker 0: up to turn the graphics down a little bit Yeah, which isn't acceptable for me, but your taste may differ.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean if you if you're not gonna be playing half-life 2 hardcore and competitions are going to mad land parties The good geforce 4 or maybe a lower number geforce FX will totally pull you through.
Speaker 0: you'll be you'll be just fine.
Speaker 1: I mean do you need to play half-life 2 right now?
Speaker 1: I mean you can play it right now for an extra five hundred dollars on top of what you're gonna buy anyway.
Speaker 1: Or you can wait a year.
Speaker 1: buy a four hundred dollar computer.
Speaker 1: That'll play half-life 2 perfectly and you won't be able to play the next generation game Which is fine because you never played half-life 2.
Speaker 0: the expensive the really really expensive computers that the The the greater than one thousand dollar computers only really makes sense If you are hardcore playing a whole bunch of PC games all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if PC gaming is your thing by all means splurge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, unless you're a hardcore gamer always buy this the one generation back of everything.
Speaker 1: You'll save so much money.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yep, and I mean I used to be big in the PC gaming, you know.
Speaker 0: So my current computer like I can I can play a lot of PC games on it, but I didn't pay too much for it.
Speaker 0: I only paid $1,000 in the day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know I paid about $3,600 for my computer, but that was in the year 2000 Mm-hmm, and that included the 19 inch CRT that I still have to this day.
Speaker 1: the SCSI card and the SCSI CD burner CD RW didn't really exist yet.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So anyway, if you want to if you need a new computer What you need to do is make a list of the things you're gonna do with it.
Speaker 0: So I went to CompUSA once and actually there was a smart guy who was he was shopping for a computer Like I never saw anyone shop for one before because usually I go around that I'm like, how fast is it?
Speaker 0: You know, what's the video card?
Speaker 0: how much RAM is in there?
Speaker 0: Cuz I know I can.
Speaker 0: I know that on that level this guy He wasn't a computer literate guy like like we are but he knew the right questions to ask.
Speaker 0: He was like, will it burn a CD?
Speaker 0: Can I plug my video camera into it and make a DVD with it?
Speaker 0: You know, he at he won.
Speaker 0: he knew what he wanted to do with the computer.
Speaker 0: He wanted a device that did X Y & Z and he said does this one do X Y & Z?
Speaker 0: I want the cheapest one that does X Y & Z reliably and well.
Speaker 0: And that's what you have to do when you get a computer now, that's just the hardware.
Speaker 1: and while we're very pro Linux there That's another thing to look at.
Speaker 1: Windows cost money.
Speaker 1: You don't buy a Dell or a gateway.
Speaker 1: Windows cost a lot of money.
Speaker 0: See any other thing is when even if you buy a Dell you're still paying for Windows whether you know it or not.
Speaker 1: However, you're all really only paying about 30 bucks for Windows in that case because they pretty much give it to Dell for free.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you are still paying for it.
Speaker 1: But basically you've got to consider if you build a computer yourself because there's two different cases here Do you really need Windows?
Speaker 1: because if you don't get Windows that's two hundred and fifty dollars of more computer you can buy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also if you compare if you look at the Dell heart just the hardware alone and you try to build the equivalent computer Especially if you use an AMD processor, you know, which is just as good as an Intel processor If not better, it'll
Speaker 1: be less than half the cost.
Speaker 0: Yeah it'll be less than half the cost and faster.
Speaker 0: and You know while Windows is technically only $30 of the Dell computer.
Speaker 0: What's all that other money?
Speaker 0: That's the Dell profit.
Speaker 0: Yep, you can avoid all of that and give the money straight to the people who actually make the parts.
Speaker 0: the only thing is you either need someone to build it for you build it yourself and While building it yourself is not for a complete idiot to do it is so much easier than anyone will let on.
Speaker 1: I mean quite seriously.
Speaker 1: you open your computer and you see all the connectors are all different sizes and shapes.
Speaker 1: You can't plug anything in wrong.
Speaker 1: Nothing will let you plug it in wrong.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it doesn't fit.
Speaker 1: flip it around It'll fit or you're plugging it into the wrong spot And if you just try everything on everything eventually everything's gonna be in the right space.
Speaker 0: Yep The only trick is knowing that Which ones have to be connected because some of the holes don't have to be connected to anything and some of them do Yeah, but I consider that I mean, what's it worth to you?
Speaker 1: Do you are you confident that you'll be able to diagnose a problem?
Speaker 1: if you're really not and you don't want to worry about it?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I get the Dell.
Speaker 0: it'll be slower, but you'll get their tech support at least for whatever it's worth And it'll probably work as soon as you bring it home and turn it on.
Speaker 1: Because that's actually I mean, I always recommend build your own computer and there are a lot of reasons for that.
Speaker 1: You'll know what's in it.
Speaker 1: You'll learn a lot about computers.
Speaker 1: You'll generally get a good deal.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all those things.
Speaker 1: But say you're say your parents need a computer or your little brother going to school needs a computer.
Speaker 1: Now normally you say oh, I'll build it for you, but then there's a problem.
Speaker 1: They call you when it comes time to do tech support.
Speaker 0: So the trick is if you're gonna do that You have to make damn well sure that nothing's gonna happen to that computer.
Speaker 1: or you tell your parents to buy a Dell and you'd never Speak of it again.
Speaker 0: Yeah, some of my parents I built them a computer and it worked out pretty well because I threw the Ubuntu on there and they never have a problem.
Speaker 0: when They had Windows they kept calling me about spyware and stuff and it sucked.
Speaker 0: But now I gave them Ubuntu and I set up everything.
Speaker 0: everything they complained about, you know, it doesn't do this It doesn't do that.
Speaker 0: I fixed all of those problems and now they don't call me anymore because Ubuntu doesn't break.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and they can't break it because it's not Windows.
Speaker 1: and look they're using Linux.
Speaker 1: These are people who I mean I've met his parents.
Speaker 1: They are not Technological people not at all.
Speaker 1: They do not.
Speaker 1: they don't know what this Linux thing is But they kind of know now because they've been using it.
Speaker 0: You know, I actually brag to their friends.
Speaker 0: really Yeah, that's kind of cool because their friends go why is your computer different?
Speaker 0: and they're like, oh we have Linux It doesn't crash like your computer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, no I mean, I remember they were leery at first but you know what.
Speaker 1: there was a button that started a web browser.
Speaker 1: There is a button that started email.
Speaker 1: They didn't do much else and when they really wanted to do something else They had to either learn how to do it or not do it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then they realized there wasn't much else.
Speaker 0: That's all they use is aim in Firefox.
Speaker 0: They don't use anything else at all.
Speaker 0: They could.
Speaker 0: if they had an aim in Firefox machine that had all the aim the Firefox plugins they needed they would be set.
Speaker 0: They don't need anything else at all.
Speaker 1: Seriously you out there our listeners really don't use your computer for much.
Speaker 1: almost No one does because the people who use their computer for something weird already know what they need.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: They already have Linux Yeah, or a Mac.
Speaker 1: I mean say if you're if you want to do a podcast or something an Apple is really the best way To go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we're using Linux just because you don't have an Apple.
Speaker 1: Yeah we seriously considered buying a Mac just to do our this podcast.
Speaker 0: when it comes to arts and media and audio and video and Graphics the Mac is where it's at.
Speaker 1: I mean if you want to do image editing there are a lot of but there's the gimp.
Speaker 1: There's mature platforms that'll work in Linux.
Speaker 1: If you want to do audio, there are fairly mature platforms.
Speaker 1: There's still no flash equivalent that works.
Speaker 1: There's still no Maya that works.
Speaker 1: No, I'm not gonna even pretend there is.
Speaker 0: if you do that stuff You can't use Linux this blender which a lot of people are using but it does.
Speaker 0: it's not quite the same.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah But anyway, the only real reason to use Windows is if you really want to play the games Or if there's some proprietary program you really need to use.
Speaker 0: that has no alternative.
Speaker 1: Yeah, which really only applies if you are a company.
Speaker 0: Yeah, companies are the ones that often have things and like a proprietary database You know and they can't get it out and you know what.
Speaker 1: honestly if you really need something to run Most Windows programs you can run them in Linux.
Speaker 1: You'll have to learn how to use wine Which is actually not that easy because Windows is weird and wine is a wine is a weird Implementation of that weird interface.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is a little mini rant that's kind of related to that.
Speaker 0: But there's a difference people don't often see it between easy to learn and easy to use Like Linux is not easy to learn if you know.
Speaker 0: if you only know Windows and because you already know Windows Windows is easy to learn.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're not gonna pretend it's easy to learn.
Speaker 1: I mean, well, we'll do a whole show sometime and we really will on Linux and what it is and why it's different.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean if you only if you don't only use Windows and you figure out that the Firefox is the big blue E Then you'll be able to browse the web and Linux like nothing.
Speaker 0: if someone else sets of Ubuntu or something for you You know, that's that's not the hard part.
Speaker 0: But really, you know being able to use your computer like you use your Windows computer is gonna take learning.
Speaker 1: but the difference is is that Linux is easy to use and That once you know it it's a snap because once you learn how to fix a certain problem one You'll fix it and you'll never have that problem again.
Speaker 0: Yep, and it's also think the best example people give is VI.
Speaker 0: VI is hella hard to learn.
Speaker 0: I mean the commands for VI are like push rant seemingly random keys on the keyboard to make things happen.
Speaker 1: Yes I I actually have witnessed hilarity especially at RIT and at my job where someone starts VI to type something And they try to type and it won't type and then they can't make the program stop.
Speaker 1: They don't get out.
Speaker 0: I Mean escape.
Speaker 0: colon WQ is how you save and quit?
Speaker 1: Yeah VI is it.
Speaker 1: you can also do the text editor.
Speaker 1: I don't know if we said that and you might not know Yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway, the point is is that you'll never learn.
Speaker 0: in order to learn VI You have to read books and practice and get used to it over many many moons and this isn't being condescending.
Speaker 1: We had to learn it and read books.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm still not the master and I use it every day But the thing is is that once you learn it think about this in wind in Microsoft Word if you want to delete five lines of text, right?
Speaker 0: You have to click drag and select very precisely those five lines of text and hit backspace.
Speaker 0: That's easy to learn but it takes a little while.
Speaker 0: in VI.
Speaker 0: I press d5d That's the easiest thing in the world.
Speaker 0: delete five lines of text.
Speaker 0: I pushed three keys did it and they're gone immediately.
Speaker 0: That's real easy to do.
Speaker 0: but to learn that you have to learn something and that's what Linux is about.
Speaker 1: Yep, and we're just building a computer is about I'm saying one is better than the other.
Speaker 1: There's just two different approaches.
Speaker 1: Are you willing to not want to learn and then that's fine.
Speaker 1: And it's really easy to learn how to do new things, but you won't be able to do them quickly or optimally Yep, or are you gonna spend all that time and effort and it's not that easy sometimes?
Speaker 1: And then you'll be able to do things quickly and optimally.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and that's what building a computer is all about is that you have to learn something to build your own computer.
Speaker 0: But in the end everything will be awesome for you once it's built.
Speaker 0: You'll save a pile of money and your computer will be all slick and you won't have crashes and viruses and who knows?
Speaker 0: It'll just be great.
Speaker 0: But if you get a Dell you don't have to learn anything But it's not going to be so great later and it might not be the easiest to use.
Speaker 1: Now we just realized as we've been talking for pretty much as long as we wanted to talk in one show that there's a lot More to this topic than we can cover.
Speaker 0: Yeah one show like which parts to select and such.
Speaker 1: So this is now going to be a continuing series until we finish every Monday.
Speaker 1: until we complete this series We are going to go through all the steps and all the components of building a computer.
Speaker 0: You know, I'm actually kind of pleased because you know, we kind of shied away from the tech science because it was informative on Monday.
Speaker 0: But I think we we did pretty good with informative.
Speaker 1: I think it helps that we did informative that we're also knowledgeable about Mmm, that's excited to teach people about.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean you heard me floundering earlier when I was trying to explain that Biology article because as much as I love that stuff.
Speaker 1: I'm not well versed in the hard sciences anymore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had that great, you know fifth grade bio description of how a virus works.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I have the slightly better like AP biology from high school.
Speaker 0: I took honors biology in high school but it was mostly molecular biology and it wasn't so much the viruses and the bacteria as it was the DNAs and the Anatomies and things.
Speaker 1: I bred fruit flies until they had mutations and then I cataloged them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we know what did.
Speaker 1: some flies all look the same and I didn't find shit awesome Totally awesome.
Speaker 1: All right, we out And that was geek nights with rim and sky special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Thanks for listening.
Speaker 0: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds feed burner comm slash geek nights to get the latest episodes as soon as their release.
Speaker 0: also, please visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at geek nights at gmail.com.