Speaker 1: It's Tuesday December 6th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about board games Verator Helles and Tower of Babel.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So you ever gone to a hibachi?
Speaker 1: Well, of course, you've gotten hibachi and I'm considering that the hibachi down the street knows us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know people who listening might not have ever gone to one.
Speaker 0: But basically this guy cooks food right in front of you in a flat hot thing.
Speaker 1: really fun.
Speaker 1: He bounces an egg around he sets things on fire.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's fun It's good Japanese food, too.
Speaker 0: But basically you look at he makes chicken if you order it of course and all he really does is put the chicken on a flat hot piece of metal and Then it tastes good real good better than any chicken I've ever made in my life.
Speaker 1: now I submit to you that the chicken you made for dinner tonight Did not taste like the chicken that that guy makes.
Speaker 0: no not so much But all I did was put chicken in a hot piece of metal.
Speaker 0: What the hell is he doing then?
Speaker 0: he's doing less than what I did and somehow it tastes better.
Speaker 0: what the hell.
Speaker 1: We love stir-fry and it looks so easy and we've never made a good stir-fry.
Speaker 0: No, we said never.
Speaker 1: No, the meats always stringy and tough and gangly and gristly Undercooked possibly cook the vegetables are burned the vegetables aren't cooked.
Speaker 0: What the hell what the hell is that guy doing?
Speaker 1: Hi, how you doing that?
Speaker 0: It just sucks.
Speaker 0: See, it's so.
Speaker 0: it's like any.
Speaker 0: I can cook something out of a cookbook and it can taste okay, especially if it's something that involves like sauces.
Speaker 0: cuz sauces cover up anything but You know the actual that kind of stuff.
Speaker 0: I just don't understand it.
Speaker 0: What the hell do you?
Speaker 0: what the hell's he doing?
Speaker 0: Yeah Maybe it takes years of training or you know chef school maybe but if I learned it we'd be eating some good food Cuz.
Speaker 0: I mean I wouldn't need much.
Speaker 0: all I need to do is throw meat onto a hot thing and we'd be eating like Kings,
Speaker 1: yeah All I know is that this morning or I was on the phone with someone in the morning while you were getting up for work I
Speaker 0: thought you were and
Speaker 1: I thought it was funny that you came home.
Speaker 1: you you mentioned to me that Apparently I talk in my sleep and I do so really clearly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was like, uh rims talking to sleep But the holy well, he said words real words.
Speaker 0: What the hell?
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: I was on the phone at 630 in the morning.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's kind of weird And Usually people only talk in the phone that more early in the morning if they're like Night watchmen or is an emergency or who knows night watchmen.
Speaker 1: That's the example you come up with.
Speaker 0: That's the only people I could think of that work at night.
Speaker 1: What about people, you know, there are people who get up well before 630 Don't talk on the phone until like 7 or 8 depends depends.
Speaker 1: What if they're an important businessman?
Speaker 0: The other important businessmen are still sleeping now those loser businessmen.
Speaker 1: Well, they might be calling other loser businessmen, yeah so, uh Podcasts are doing real well, but apparently radio not so much duh.
Speaker 0: Oh, wait newsflash CDs not selling.
Speaker 1: Well, I Think every downloads doing great understatement of the day.
Speaker 1: here the quote from the article radio has to reinvent itself Mmm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I mean, I gotta say my car is not the best car and the the CD player's lens gets fogged up.
Speaker 1: so whenever it's cold or rainy, I can't listen to CDs and I'm stuck listening to the radio and Honestly more than half the time rather than listen to the radio.
Speaker 1: I just turn the damn thing off and don't listen to anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm gonna buy a new.
Speaker 0: I trip soon and we'll be cranking up the iPod in a car.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's actually better than the previous one.
Speaker 0: So I don't feel so bad about losing the old one.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's just nothing on the radio.
Speaker 0: Nothing on the radio.
Speaker 0: That was a good song.
Speaker 1: I mean I flipped through this area.
Speaker 1: anything.
Speaker 1: I mean, there's a lot of punk kids around here and pretty much it's our rap station at stations in Spanish.
Speaker 1: God people more God people country country.
Speaker 1: God people country God people country.
Speaker 0: They'd be like one rock station, but it plays the same ten songs.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I heard the Led Zeppelin song that I like and then I hear this that song every day and then I give up Same songs every day.
Speaker 1: More ads than music.
Speaker 0: Yeah more as the music will do it to you every time.
Speaker 1: not only more ads but really piss poor ads Because the radio only gets local ads.
Speaker 0: it doesn't get like national big ads.
Speaker 0: So it's always like some poorly produced like hack job at a local car dealership or something.
Speaker 0: It's just annoying as hell with some Stupid jingle that you just want to kill God.
Speaker 0: Who makes these things?
Speaker 1: People who probably make more money than us.
Speaker 0: if you want a car dealership you sure as hell make more money than we do.
Speaker 1: Yep Though, uh, I mean radio is free and it's doing poorly and yet serious.
Speaker 1: next M gangbusters.
Speaker 0: They're not doing that much gangbusters compared to radio.
Speaker 0: They are yeah, but don't expect that to last too long.
Speaker 1: Well, actually that's what the CEO of clear channel says.
Speaker 1: he's not worried.
Speaker 1: I mean hit.
Speaker 1: the quote here from him is why would you pay for something you can get for free?
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's exactly why we're gonna do podcasting and not listen to clear channel or serious or exit.
Speaker 1: Yeah Though I mean that analogy.
Speaker 1: I mean you can pay.
Speaker 1: you can get food for free if you go through enough dumpsters.
Speaker 1: There's a reason you pay the dollar to buy some ramen.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's cuz the ramen tastes a little bit worse but is a little bit less disease in it.
Speaker 1: Hey, don't be knocking my kitsune ramen You know, it comes with the freeze-dried bean curd, I like bean curd, I don't like freeze-dried bean curd.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what are you gonna get for a dollar?
Speaker 0: Four packs of bubble gum.
Speaker 1: so it seems that I mean radio is on the downturn but Inversely, the podcasts are on the upturn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we just said that.
Speaker 0: yeah, but we're not the only one saying that now Apparently, I think people said it before we said it.
Speaker 1: podcast is this year's Word of the year from the new Oxford American dictionary.
Speaker 0: There's an Oxford American dictionary.
Speaker 0: Yeah, wait, but we've been looking in the Oxford English dictionary.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe we should have been looking in the Oxford American dictionary because that one is our language.
Speaker 1: you realize this only applies to Scrabble.
Speaker 1: Really Our use of dictionaries, where's the last time you used a dictionary that didn't involve Scrabble?
Speaker 0: doesn't argue about when a word is real or Not.
Speaker 1: yeah, and you go to dictionary or how a word is pronounced.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't know how to pronounce things.
Speaker 1: You don't know how to pronounce things solder And I use a soldering iron.
Speaker 0: Let's go look in the Oxford English dictionary and see what it says.
Speaker 1: How do you pronounce solder?
Speaker 0: solder Titan.
Speaker 0: you know that the Greek tall guys is a difference between the Greek tall guys.
Speaker 0: They don't exist Titan.
Speaker 0: They're not real.
Speaker 1: What do you?
Speaker 1: how do you say it?
Speaker 0: Titan?
Speaker 0: Titan like the Titanic or Titan only without the a depending on how Midwestern you are?
Speaker 1: Anyway, but they pick a word of the year every year and the the runners-up this year were bird flu.
Speaker 0: That's not a word.
Speaker 0: It's two words.
Speaker 0: hack.
Speaker 0: Life has one word that's not Persistent vegetative states, I guess this cuz the stupid.
Speaker 0: that's not a word though.
Speaker 0: That's a phrase.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, oh, here's one squick.
Speaker 1: What the hell's quick cause immediate and thorough revulsion?
Speaker 1: I don't know never heard of it.
Speaker 1: not what I think of when I hear the word square.
Speaker 0: It's not.
Speaker 0: it shouldn't even be a word.
Speaker 0: No one uses it at least no one.
Speaker 0: I know yeah Maybe it's a British thing.
Speaker 1: so I guess podcast has the dubious honor of beating those other words.
Speaker 0: last year the word of the year was blog.
Speaker 1: Ha I see a trend.
Speaker 0: you know what.
Speaker 0: if I can figure out the word of the year for next year I'll be loaded cuz the guy who thought of blogs loaded guy.
Speaker 0: I thought a podcast loaded Yeah, so I think up what it's gonna be next year.
Speaker 0: loaded All right, so Speaking of podcast.
Speaker 0: iTunes you know they got the little video downloads for the iPod video.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah, they.
Speaker 0: finally some TV companies You know I guess networks turned around and decided hey We got to get out on this.
Speaker 0: and now there's a lot more videos coming from other networks and things.
Speaker 0: actual shows Actual shows now.
Speaker 1: I watch some Dukes of Hazzard and Knight Rider.
Speaker 0: There's some Knight Rider.
Speaker 0: There's no Dukes of Hazzard.
Speaker 1: now There should be.
Speaker 0: yeah, let's see they got Show.
Speaker 0: I don't care about law and order.
Speaker 0: my grandma can watch that some show I never heard of.
Speaker 1: the grandma has a video iPod.
Speaker 0: no But she watches anything having to do with police detectives or lawyers all day.
Speaker 0: That's the only thing she watches on TV police detectives and lawyers.
Speaker 1: I wonder what this is gonna do to the whole TV model Especially if they notice that people are willing to pay to get little TV shows without commercials on a tiny tiny screen.
Speaker 0: well, what's probably gonna happen is TV will die and They'll keep selling all their old TV shows.
Speaker 0: for you know a few bucks per episode to download on the internet.
Speaker 0: Probably DVD sales of TV shows will probably go away because people only get the episodes they want instead of paying out the ass for a giant box set.
Speaker 0: yeah, and We'll all be good as long as there's no DRM.
Speaker 0: DRM as long as you know DRM is will buy into it.
Speaker 0: I would if there was no DRM.
Speaker 0: I would totally get it.
Speaker 1: Yeah depends on the price.
Speaker 0: definitely depends on the price.
Speaker 0: I mean apparently most of these people are doing the two bucks an episode.
Speaker 0: It's not too bad But I think people were talking like the Conan O'Brien stuff is like mispriced or like they set the prices on that to like be ridiculously stupid or something and I Can.
Speaker 0: I can guarantee you the sales that are gonna be less than everything else because of that and they'll learn their lesson.
Speaker 1: I guess two bucks seems fair, but I'm still a.
Speaker 1: 99 cent seems like a lot for a song.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what I'm hoping for actually is the only thing I really missed from TV.
Speaker 0: besides like you know a few shows.
Speaker 1: sports Yeah, sports pretty much just hockey and f1.
Speaker 0: Yeah if someone could tell me that like I can download like all the Rangers games for a hundred bucks a year with no Commercials and no annoying talking guys.
Speaker 0: or I can select the talking guys that I like.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean, I don't even need to see the game live because I can find out who won on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or I can download Say every f1 race of the year in full video with no commercials and select the guys I want to talk or you know have no guys talking.
Speaker 1: well apparently we can download that a moto across.
Speaker 0: well It's moto GP is is the?
Speaker 0: it's like the Formula One of motorcycles.
Speaker 0: They're 500 CC bikes, and they could go 200 miles an hour.
Speaker 0: They don't they don't.
Speaker 0: well they could mechanically, but the people who ride them don't push them that fast cuz they'll die.
Speaker 1: I need 500 CC.
Speaker 0: my Mario Kart goes 150 CC right there Anyway but you know and they drive on the sum of the same courses that f1 drives on.
Speaker 0: so it's like the f1 of motorcycles and For them if you pay some I think it's like 50 bucks a year something like that.
Speaker 0: You can watch every race on the computer.
Speaker 0: if they don't have it on TV where you live or you know if you just want To save them and watch them later.
Speaker 0: You know rewind fast-forward no commercials, and it's really helping them out.
Speaker 0: in fact I'd never even cared about Michael motorcycle racing.
Speaker 0: I think I'm gonna go to their website and watch a race and see if it's entertaining to watch.
Speaker 1: I got to say I'm curious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, definitely especially if this bikes going over 100 miles an hour with a guy hold on freaking dear life.
Speaker 0: That's got to be freaking good shit.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of things like that that I'm interested in but there's really no way to enjoy them or to Watch them without paying out the ass, and I'm not willing to do that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I like rally racing and I like f1.
Speaker 1: I can't see it.
Speaker 1: nope I can get like stupid clips of idiots crashing their cars trying to do like super drifto.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I heard the ESPN was talking with the iTunes music store And you know maybe they're gonna do some stuff like you know.
Speaker 0: maybe Sports Center or something.
Speaker 0: I would pay 50 bucks a year to have Sports Center automatically downloaded to my computer every day with no ads with no ads.
Speaker 1: Yes, no ads is key.
Speaker 0: No ads and no DRM.
Speaker 0: I would pay 50 bucks a year for Sports Center.
Speaker 0: I think they're gonna charge you two dollars an episode for Sports Center in which case there's no way, but Yeah, plus uh iTunes doesn't run in Linux.
Speaker 1: Yep, and I don't have Windows anymore.
Speaker 0: I mean think about this.
Speaker 0: this is gonna be big money because Most people I mean I could get ESPN as part of a cable package right for 50 bucks a month.
Speaker 0: Right 50 bucks a year for just one show.
Speaker 0: think about how many shows I get for 50 a month.
Speaker 0: I'm willing to pay 50 a year for one show.
Speaker 0: if you give me five shows That's 250 bucks.
Speaker 0: the cable companies are cut out of the loop.
Speaker 0: the guys making the actual content.
Speaker 0: Fuck their ad dollars.
Speaker 0: They're getting so many dollars and people like me buying the show for a year.
Speaker 0: They get rid of all the shows that nobody watches see.
Speaker 1: part of the problem.
Speaker 1: is that be great?
Speaker 1: I saw a statistic.
Speaker 1: It was kind of scary, and I can't verify this at all because I don't really care.
Speaker 1: But they were saying that on many networks modern new TV shows are pushing the 17 minute mark in terms of content versus ads.
Speaker 0: awesome 17 minutes of show you know.
Speaker 0: actually that's not so bad because if they cut the ads out right I Don't want to watch a show for like a freaking hour.
Speaker 0: I want to watch like a 10-minute show if it you know especially if it's something like Sports Center.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't want to sit there for an hour Watching sports news.
Speaker 0: I don't have time for that shit.
Speaker 0: well I point I want to do is I want to?
Speaker 0: I want to sit on the train and go push a button and get all The sports news and maybe 10 15 minutes.
Speaker 0: see the awesome clips You know and have someone tell me what happened, and I'm done.
Speaker 1: well I point out the addictive power of our day killer tapes mmm the day.
Speaker 1: Can we have these day killers?
Speaker 1: Basically when I was young my family taped everything off a TV And we taped it in such a way that there are no openers closers or advertisements.
Speaker 1: So I have eight hour tapes of just you know Simpsons Simpsons episodes running into each other constantly until the tape runs out Seinfeld all that stuff.
Speaker 1: and in college if one of us put that tape in They were shot, and we'd pretty much just sit there until the tape ended.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's how that stuff goes.
Speaker 1: So I could see someone downloading episodes or something one by one and just getting hooked and just buying the whole thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see I'm looking more to add to my podcasting stuff because what I do now is because The podcast.
Speaker 0: that the reason I like the podcast because I can listen to them and work at the same time.
Speaker 0: Because you know if it's not on my screen I can have work on the screen and work doesn't go on my ear because I'm not an audio worker.
Speaker 0: So it's good.
Speaker 0: But if I had video I could watch it on the train.
Speaker 0: I try not to listen to podcast any other time because then I think oh I could listen to it at work But I can't do anything else.
Speaker 0: So if I could get like a couple shows maybe like a half out an hour of shows worth a day Or maybe an hour and a half of shows a day.
Speaker 0: I could watch those on the train to and from work, and I'd be all set.
Speaker 0: you know be perfect You know.
Speaker 0: But right now.
Speaker 0: I can't get that for a price.
Speaker 0: I'm willing to pay in a format I like well.
Speaker 1: plus you don't seem to have enough time to even play all the video games We've got.
Speaker 0: I'm playing Mario and Luigi.
Speaker 0: I'll finish it.
Speaker 1: Yeah bit by bit.
Speaker 1: You're slacking off in the Mario car.
Speaker 0: You're slacking off big time more than me.
Speaker 1: I'm playing my Mario Kart.
Speaker 0: I beat my Mario Kart All right anyway.
Speaker 0: speaking of them video games a claim a claim who went out of business a long time ago.
Speaker 0: Someone's auctioning off the publishing rights to all their games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now we're not sure if this is the like rights to the name or just the rights to that one specific.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it says publishing rights now.
Speaker 0: I'm sure that if you buy the publishing rights.
Speaker 0: Let's see something on the list.
Speaker 0: That's obvious.
Speaker 0: Here we go fantastic.
Speaker 0: for if you buy the publishing rights to Fantastic Four Somehow I don't.
Speaker 0: this is the video game from August 97 by the way.
Speaker 0: yeah I don't think this gives you the right to like go publishing Fantastic Four comic books and things.
Speaker 0: yeah Make no new Fantastic Four thing.
Speaker 1: I could see being feasible would be if say you got the right to make another Fantastic Four game or modify the game you just bought.
Speaker 0: I'm sure you can modify the game We just bought all right.
Speaker 1: what if I modified it to the extent that it's now 3d and runs on the Xbox?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: see that's the problem.
Speaker 1: We're seriously gonna call them and find out.
Speaker 0: yeah I'm gonna call these guys tomorrow because there's some games on this list that are worth owning I mean, and they have no bids like we could just buy them for five bucks.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: if we could buy them for five bucks there might be a minimum.
Speaker 0: They're willing to accept, but I'm surprised that Mortal Kombat's 1 & 2 don't have any bids.
Speaker 0: I mean alone.
Speaker 0: if I bought Mortal Kombat the the rights to publish Mortal Kombat 1 & 2 right let's say the only right I got was that I could publish and sell these games in their current state ROMs for a buck.
Speaker 0: I could sell ROMs of Mortal Kombat 1 & 2 for a buck and go around suing people who are distributing ROMs of it I'm suing.
Speaker 0: I could make back my $1,000 investment on those rights so fast.
Speaker 0: It would be totally worth it, but some of these other games not so much worth it.
Speaker 0: I mean who wants to buy the rights to?
Speaker 0: Let's see let's find a real bad one Real bad one.
Speaker 1: I can think of super high impact from October 93. super high impact sounds cool.
Speaker 1: You know I got objects hitting things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you buy the rights to publish that game You're not gonna make so much money.
Speaker 1: kind of game is it?
Speaker 0: I have no clue.
Speaker 0: It doesn't say it's just a list of numbers names and dates and years.
Speaker 0: It's it.
Speaker 1: how do you know that isn't some awesome game?
Speaker 0: I don't but I imagine it's it's really old and I've never heard of it.
Speaker 1: see they're not selling the rights to like that Pac-man world game.
Speaker 0: I Don't think it's an acclaimed game is yeah I think Namco owns the rights to all the Pac-man games because you know they invented Pac-man.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you'd have still the worst game ever made.
Speaker 0: you'd have to name an acclaimed game anyway.
Speaker 0: All right, you you fuckers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you don't like our music.
Speaker 0: fine.
Speaker 0: You won't get any.
Speaker 0: yeah You'll get something annoying instead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's fine.
Speaker 1: We're.
Speaker 1: I mean we're glad that you guys were very honest and didn't say like oh, it's okay If something sucks tell us it sucks, and we'll fix it like right away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we're playing it right now.
Speaker 0: We'll still be bastards to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we'll be bastards, but actually we came up with a good idea this as soon as I get a chance I'm gonna sit down with my piano and make some short little like piano riffs.
Speaker 1: That'll go before all the bits.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like a chime or a jingle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or like Yeah, yeah something like that something like that.
Speaker 0: Anyway, what's your thing?
Speaker 1: Oh my thing?
Speaker 0: Yep?
Speaker 1: It's not a new thing, but it's new to me.
Speaker 1: It's kinda and I heard about it.
Speaker 1: I forgot about it, but I wanted to talk about it, then I forgot about it again.
Speaker 0: Alright, alright get to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but uh Remember doom and doom - no I forgot what the hell those?
Speaker 1: yeah, well you can play them online now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I could have played them online before.
Speaker 1: you can play them online easily with other people over the internet and not.
Speaker 1: you know IPX network serial modem style.
Speaker 0: I could do that before It just you know with the Kali.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Kali Kali still around.
Speaker 0: I Don't know I had it.
Speaker 0: I bought it for 20 bucks for life, so I still own it.
Speaker 1: technically I don't think Kali still exists.
Speaker 0: it kind of stopped working after like a couple years of it being awesome And yeah using it.
Speaker 1: But this is basically just doom and doom - online now in a little account based thing kind of like steam only not big and bloated And you can just play doing with people.
Speaker 1: And I think I'm gonna get on board this if I can because uh as many people are aware I am the greatest doom player there ever was.
Speaker 1: well.
Speaker 0: We'll soon find that out won't we will uh?
Speaker 0: Hallo my name into the heavens until Maybe you'll just get a face full of rockets and plasma.
Speaker 0: You know shot a hot plasma.
Speaker 1: See uh I don't use rocket launchers.
Speaker 1: I feel they're too easy.
Speaker 1: I Use solely the regular shotgun in the plasma gun.
Speaker 1: I'll use no other weapon.
Speaker 0: yeah, we'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: And you like you know get.
Speaker 1: yeah I will see if I actually get to play because windows only and wine doesn't always like things like this.
Speaker 0: anyway My thing of the day is this cool board game here.
Speaker 0: now You've played those things online where it's like there's a laser, and you have to rotate things to get the laser.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know it.
Speaker 0: There's like they simulate a laser beam and you have to move things to reflect it to go in a certain path And then you solve the puzzle.
Speaker 0: yeah, yeah, well someone made a board game called deflection.
Speaker 1: Is there a K in there?
Speaker 1: No
Speaker 0: it's D E F L E X I O N ah D E F L E X I O N dot biz and it's a board game where you have an actual laser an Actual mirrors and a grid with like little triangle prism pieces and stuff and you move things around Trying to get the laser to reflect in the way you want.
Speaker 1: that sounds fun.
Speaker 1: It's not a set of rules, but it sounds fun.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is gimmicky, but it's like think it's like a competitive Turn-based puzzle game of moving things in a tile grid But they have mirrors on them and some of them don't have mirrors on.
Speaker 0: they just block the laser.
Speaker 0: Huh, so it looks pretty cool like it could be fun.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the rules are and I don't know how much it is.
Speaker 1: if I want to pay for it I will find out on board game geek.
Speaker 0: Yeah Probably if it ends up there, which it?
Speaker 1: yeah Though that segues nicely since you guys seem to want segues into our main bit.
Speaker 0: segue and whoever spelled it S-e-g-w-a-y that means the little two-wheeled thing that you ride on.
Speaker 0: segue Yeah segue that Transitions from one topic of discussion to another.
Speaker 0: That's segue Yeah.
Speaker 1: Anyway, so it's board game day and we've got the good the bad and the mediocre.
Speaker 1: Though starting with the good that game verator better a Verator.
Speaker 0: in German it means Traitor.
Speaker 1: it's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: It's very cool.
Speaker 1: We only played it once and we played it three player which I contend three player is broken.
Speaker 1: Scott disagrees We're not sure.
Speaker 0: yet I'm pretty sure the three player is not broken.
Speaker 0: because look if you're in third place Right, what you do is you team up with the second place guy, right?
Speaker 0: So both of you are getting.
Speaker 0: the second and third place guys will continue to get points Hopefully because they'll win.
Speaker 0: Theoretically if it's a team of two against one you'll win.
Speaker 0: if you're not gonna win then you lose.
Speaker 0: Anyway, the other guy beat you and the first place guy will keep not getting points.
Speaker 0: Then as soon as you're you know, the second place guy overtakes, you know and becomes the first place guy.
Speaker 0: you pick the verator and you now you're again.
Speaker 0: you're with the former first place guy and now.
Speaker 0: so basically you got points because you were with the winner and you switch and now your points with the winner again and See except the problem with that.
Speaker 1: Is that one?
Speaker 1: every fight is always two verse one.
Speaker 1: unless it's everyone There's no one which is dumb.
Speaker 0: It could be three verse one In a three-player game no, it's always - alright could be three verse zero.
Speaker 1: Yeah, three verse zero doesn't have any effect on the game really.
Speaker 0: The problem yeah, but what you could do is if you're ahead and you're in first place You want to make it three versus.
Speaker 1: that's the problem in in the three-player game.
Speaker 1: basically, whoever's losing always wants to berate and One.
Speaker 1: it's hard to get cards in the game.
Speaker 1: Not like Morterer.
Speaker 1: I think I like Morterer more even though we haven't actually played it yet Because it's actually hard to refill your hand so often.
Speaker 1: you know exactly what you should do But you don't have any means to do it, but everyone else also has to refill their hands.
Speaker 0: You're not alone.
Speaker 1: But like if I'll some way if someone else takes the raider or the raider just happens to be Hidden in the pile of cards that aren't used your bone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you got nine turns You know if you just got to play it right straight from the beginning.
Speaker 0: Yeah, meanwhile I could in the one game that we played I point out that I was you know, you complain that oh The guy in third place couldn't catch up whatever.
Speaker 0: well, how did he end up in third place?
Speaker 0: I was the one who figured out the game right a freaking way taking the operator and like the second turn, you know The idea is that one some people are gonna get points and other people aren't.
Speaker 0: you always want to be on the side That's gonna get points.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you don't always get to choose your side and you don't always get to choose which side win you get to chew.
Speaker 0: Well, you get you know, you put as much into it as you can and if you don't put enough into it Or if you can't well, that's you know, that's part part of it.
Speaker 1: I'm disillusioned because Moira looks so much more interesting.
Speaker 0: Moira looks a little better.
Speaker 0: We're gonna have to play it and see.
Speaker 0: yeah, it is a newer, you know game on the same Engine and it's a little more refined.
Speaker 0: So we'll see.
Speaker 1: Yeah, plus it's got pirates man.
Speaker 0: Yeah pirate theme always helps.
Speaker 1: now the bad.
Speaker 1: we talked about Hellas before but now we've played it a little more and Every single time we've played we have run into multiple as in more than one Ambiguous rules that we had to look for a rat online and there was no errata to be found.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what kind of German board game doesn't have perfect rules?
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean we I both of us were guilty of avoiding certain strategies because we were afraid that they would end up in an ambiguous Situation where we wouldn't know how to resolve it by the rules.
Speaker 0: It doesn't help that.
Speaker 0: you know, this whole game is you know Playing cards that have certain magic powers on them and some cards are clearly better than others.
Speaker 0: Some cards are clearly better than others and you can pick which kind of card you get and the text on the cards is the only Information the game gives you as to how the cards work and the text on the cards is completely not descriptive enough
Speaker 1: Yep, or it's overly descriptive in a useless way.
Speaker 0: Yep, like this one that says take two attacks one after the other It's like alright, well do I get to regroup between the attack or am I forced to regroup?
Speaker 1: Do I lose my extra guys because I have a three limit or does that happen at the end of my turn?
Speaker 0: Doesn't tell?
Speaker 0: doesn't tell you any of this stuff anywhere and people online are basically making arbitrary decisions.
Speaker 0: Yep Not a good thing.
Speaker 0: in a game where you want to be very precise, especially for people like us.
Speaker 1: I mean there's I guess there's two kinds of board gamers and there was evidence way back.
Speaker 1: We had a risk party where we had a bunch of people at someone's house and we split the room up and we've ever Went like.
Speaker 1: we had two groups on two different risk boards.
Speaker 1: Just playing two different games.
Speaker 1: one group just started playing immediately.
Speaker 1: That was the other group.
Speaker 1: our group sat there for about 40 minutes arguing about the rules before we even started to play.
Speaker 1: Yep, they were the latter.
Speaker 1: That's us.
Speaker 1: We won't play a game unless it's perfect and if the rules don't match up We will search the internet until we find errata or we just give up.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean, what's the point of playing a game if you you know, you're not gonna play it, right?
Speaker 0: I mean The reason you play a game is because you want to have a competition that's fair and under certain rules And you have a nice thinking exercise.
Speaker 0: if you're not clear about what the rules are or or what?
Speaker 1: What's the hell's the point because then it's hard to come up.
Speaker 1: I mean you can't even really come up with a strategy because like in Hellas I came up with a great strategy To load up a place and then play the to attack card and then attack twice and I'll have a bunch of guys for two Attacks, but it's not clear if I lose those extra guys due to the limit of how many guys you can have in a place.
Speaker 0: I mean imagine just if you don't understand think about playing a game like soccer.
Speaker 0: Imagine if you weren't clear about the rules of soccer, but you played anyway, I say you weren't sure.
Speaker 0: it's no longer game.
Speaker 0: It's just some people kicking a ball around all willy-nilly.
Speaker 1: So, you know the rules.
Speaker 1: you just weren't sure if the goalie could actually touch the ball with his hands or not and say The ref didn't know either and you asked the rifle.
Speaker 1: What do you do if I touch the ball with my hands?
Speaker 1: And he says I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: Try it.
Speaker 0: You can't play a game like that And then when the goalie actually touches the ball with his hands the ref has to like call a timeout and you know What the hell's the point of playing?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just crap.
Speaker 0: The game I think would be a much better game.
Speaker 0: if you know if you solve all the rules problems It would still be a very.
Speaker 0: it would be an okay game.
Speaker 1: yeah, I think what we're actually gonna do is sit down and Decide on every ambiguity and write our own little fact and put it online.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it would be like we can't find the official real deal.
Speaker 0: But this is what we have decided for all these rules and if any of the rules decide, you know Turn out they don't work.
Speaker 0: We'll change them.
Speaker 0: Yep But what I'd like to do even more is because the pieces of the game are so cool and it's two-player little Greeks little ships Little Arpa archipelagos.
Speaker 0: Yeah is to make up some sort of other game using the same pieces.
Speaker 0: That's two players and it's cool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we need two-player games.
Speaker 0: maybe we can make the game better just by me replacing all the cards, you know, huh?
Speaker 0: with a different set of cards where all the cards are equal.
Speaker 0: who hiccups where all the cards are equal and also fully descriptive?
Speaker 1: Yeah No, uh the mediocre.
Speaker 1: Yeah Tower of Babel.
Speaker 0: I'm glad I didn't buy that game.
Speaker 0: It sounds bought it.
Speaker 1: We feel bad.
Speaker 1: our friend bought it and it looked like a cool game.
Speaker 0: You always feel bad when someone buys a game that no one likes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the game is just really really simple and everything's out in the open and really short.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually was really short You're right because you just you.
Speaker 1: basically all you do is bid on these little discs and you get points based on the discs.
Speaker 0: The end yeah Any of you bid on certain discs and you bid certain amounts or offer certain amount.
Speaker 1: Yeah it has this really cool offer these acceptance dynamic where everyone offers bids and then the person who Started that action gets to choose which offers he takes and it affects everyone accordingly.
Speaker 1: so you're playing with four people and you pick your friend Steve bid because he's losing and you'd rather Give him some points that won't help him win.
Speaker 1: or you know, it's.
Speaker 1: it's got a lot of coolness to it.
Speaker 1: It just wasn't really well executed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the other problem is that the offering is such a cool mechanic except for the fact that It always it seems to always pay to offer as much as you possibly can.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like I was trying I looked there was I offered my entire hand every round for most of the game and I tied for first.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean I kept looking at the side of the board where there's extra scoring track and it looked to me like the extra scoring Track was where to get the big points.
Speaker 0: So I went all out for that.
Speaker 0: but the people who just offered a bunch of cards and didn't have their offers accepted because if someone Rejects your offer of three cards you get three points.
Speaker 0: so the people who just offered a whole bunch of cards and never had them accepted and Kept getting a bunch of points Ended up getting more points than I did going through all the effort of scoring big on the on the track.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was fantastic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was pretty silly.
Speaker 1: So I would I'd like to play the game one more time to make sure but I think I'm done with that game.
Speaker 0: I think I want to have a bidding game but I'm thinking that this game I get that Medici Medici that I hear about is the Supposedly the bidding game.
Speaker 1: to get Pizarro was fun.
Speaker 1: I liked it.
Speaker 0: Pizarro was the worst bidding game.
Speaker 1: I love Pizarro.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you suck Pizarro is the purest bidding game ever.
Speaker 1: you bid on like six things and then that's it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: That's it.
Speaker 1: Then you score.
Speaker 0: Yeah There's also that a Vegas game.
Speaker 0: I played with the board game guys that you talked about that multiple times already.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it seemed like a cool bidding game.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know I might actually buy it depending how much it is.
Speaker 0: now that I know that I'm gonna get a pile of monies Hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe I will.
Speaker 0: we would have fun playing it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, worst case it goes on the pile of games We don't play anymore.
Speaker 1: like to call and El Grande.
Speaker 0: Well, I just wish that you know, we had more.
Speaker 0: if we had three people we could play all these games.
Speaker 1: But well this weekend we're gonna have one of our friends out.
Speaker 1: All right We're thinking interviewing him because he knows a lot about biotech and that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Place a moiré and he mispronounces anime words in a comical fashion can't even pronounce water.
Speaker 1: That's just because he's from Pennsylvania.
Speaker 0: What are what are what are?
Speaker 1: yeah, but we love Scott.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the other Scott there's two Scott's.
Speaker 1: That'll be great on the podcast.
Speaker 1: Hi, I'm Scott.
Speaker 0: Well, man, it'll be awesome and hilarious.
Speaker 1: Yeah It works out cuz we call him sco Joe instead of Scott.
Speaker 1: It seems we've got a lot of instances in our lives where we've had multiple people with the same first name And we just kind of democratically assign one of them a new name and it becomes their name.
Speaker 0: Haha I am always this guy.
Speaker 1: there were three Alex's so we named one of them John Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yep All right.
Speaker 1: So you guys once again wanted segues.
Speaker 1: So, uh some meta bits here Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well Yeah Oh We're glad that so many of you actually join the forums and checked out the website after we asked you to yep.
Speaker 0: The forums are a-hoppin.
Speaker 0: Well, they're not super hopping like some other forums I hang out in for other podcasts and things but they're definitely the most hopping ist forums that I have ever had.
Speaker 1: for me They're hopping more than our secret forum where we play Dungeons & Dragons with our friends Shh.
Speaker 0: But you know now that it's hopping, you know if anyone else is out there and wasn't joining the forums before or just joined us and Isn't in the forums or anything like that Come hang out in the forum.
Speaker 1: Yes, we're getting a lot of good discussion.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't be a lurker I don't like lurkers.
Speaker 0: I lurk in a lot of places though I don't lurk but or at least if I lurk I post at least super rarely like when I can't contain myself.
Speaker 1: Now when I lurk I lurk as in I don't even have accounts.
Speaker 1: I just read forums.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so here's what I'm gonna do.
Speaker 0: I'll make I make a discussion in the forums for every podcast.
Speaker 0: now I'm gonna try to keep doing that.
Speaker 0: also it helps me keep track of the number of the podcast episode.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think we're coming up on 20.
Speaker 0: This might even be 20.
Speaker 1: Well, your numbering is one off from not my numbering.
Speaker 1: We should probably correct that at some point.
Speaker 0: How was your numbering off?
Speaker 0: I counted all the posts on the blog.
Speaker 1: Yeah And one of the post is it doesn't have a track number because we posted it well after the fact after we'd started.
Speaker 0: I don't care about that.
Speaker 1: All right So the track number is one off from the number you put in the forums.
Speaker 0: The number I put in the forums is the number of Podcasts that we have put on the internet and that's how I consider to be the right.
Speaker 0: unless you want to name number the first One zero.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the first one zero then that's fine.
Speaker 0: All right, so then I'll subtract one.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever We're not worried about it.
Speaker 1: You guys are smart.
Speaker 1: You'll figure it out.
Speaker 1: It's not a big deal, but Yeah, we also noticed that there's no Previous button on the main page of the of our site.
Speaker 1: So it's tough to get into all the old podcasts.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna fix that.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: This is a broken WordPress theme.
Speaker 1: We just noticed it.
Speaker 1: So don't hate on us.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone's had a problem with it yet.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I hope no one tried to go into our archives and couldn't get there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there is a search box so you can search for a podcast, you know the format of the day.
Speaker 0: You can just type in like.
Speaker 0: oh You know seven.
Speaker 1: whatever the number the date is and then There is not a single one that has 007 in it.
Speaker 0: I just be quiet.
Speaker 1: Where did you come up with that?
Speaker 0: They all start with zeros And I picked seven because it's a nice number You know, I must add James Bond in my mind or something, yeah Alright, yeah, that's all we got.
Speaker 1: So I'm gonna segue into the closing music now.
Speaker 0: Yeah and tomorrow we're gonna talk about.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah tomorrow tomorrow is anime day.
Speaker 1: We actually just watched Ghost in the Shell standalone complex 2 second gig.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we can talk about that.
Speaker 1: It's pretty badass.
Speaker 1: We had a lot to say about it.
Speaker 0: Yep Maybe I could talk about some of the cool comics.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna buy tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Yeah comics and manga.
Speaker 1: Yep So it's gonna be a generic anime day But our main bit is gonna be standalone complex 2 and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Thanks for listening.
Speaker 0: Please remember to point your favorite podcatcher at feeds dot feed burner comm slash geek nights to get the latest episodes as soon as they're released.
Speaker 0: also, please visit our website at www.front row crew comm for the latest updates and forum discussion and whether you love or hate our podcast We won't know unless you send your feedback to us at geek nights at gmail.com.