Speaker 0: It's October 31st 2005, this is geek nights with rim and sky.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: We should probably put lira in there whatever.
Speaker 0: Doo doo doo doo?
Speaker 0: Oh, I got four.
Speaker 0: you start the news like doo doo doo doo doo doo doo But not the noise.
Speaker 0: dude me going doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Speaker 1: You want to do that originally?
Speaker 1: We're gonna have the So, uh, I guess we could do that or I could make that sound.
Speaker 0: I think this copyrighted or patented by whatever news.
Speaker 1: No, we'll just make it something else.
Speaker 1: It's just Morse code.
Speaker 1: We'll make it say something geeky.
Speaker 0: Ah Let's do this in Morse code.
Speaker 1: that's real slick.
Speaker 1: I like it.
Speaker 0: All right, we're good.
Speaker 0: Okay, so Scolito Scolito.
Speaker 0: so Personal lawyer didn't cut it to no surprise.
Speaker 0: So he picks the most conservative judge he could find in all of the appeals.
Speaker 0: course Samuel Alito.
Speaker 1: Yeah He's a little conservative Little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, cuz this I mean the Senate's main gripe at least the Republicans main gripe with Meyers wasn't that they didn't know about her.
Speaker 1: It was that she wasn't proven to be conservative and not.
Speaker 0: Well, this guy's real conservative, but you know, you look at not real real conservative He's.
Speaker 1: I don't think he's yeah States rights.
Speaker 1: I think he's more.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah Rovers his way.
Speaker 0: they pretty much call him Scolito and his name is Alito because he's scalia, too.
Speaker 0: But if you look at there's a Scalia, however, you're gonna pronounce.
Speaker 0: I don't know how the correct pronunciation.
Speaker 0: I've heard both but Scalia I look at his voting record and like and a lot of things he votes the way.
Speaker 0: I want a Lot of things.
Speaker 0: he votes horribly and I don't want him to be alive.
Speaker 1: Well, I worry because Susanna Sherry She's actually a university law professor at Vanderbilt and she said that he would quote allow a lot more government support of religion than justice o'connor did.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's Not good.
Speaker 1: see I'm all down with religion, but I don't think SCOTUS should have any Kind of backing for it.
Speaker 1: or you know.
Speaker 0: You know that the problem here is if they let in just a little bit of religion and not enough.
Speaker 0: if they let in too Much religion because we'll just fly in there with our flying spaghetti monsters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but if the Supreme Court votes against us, there's no one to appeal to.
Speaker 0: well No, but the thing is is that if they give someone else some other religion some sort of you know, nudge Then we just run in there and we say we demand the flying spaghetti monster also gets the same nudge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, then we'll deal with.
Speaker 1: they will have the schism the ramanites and the pastafarians.
Speaker 1: But I mean he might not get confirmed.
Speaker 1: the Senate might filibuster until the end of the Bush administration, we don't know what's gonna happen.
Speaker 1: Hmm oh Speaking of the Supreme Court, they found two more moons on Pluto.
Speaker 0: apparently Isn't Pluto?
Speaker 0: they don't even know if it's a planet or a moon or what?
Speaker 0: There's nobody's decided how big you have to be to be a planet.
Speaker 1: Basically what the news is is a tiny Rock that's far away from our planet has rocks a tiny rock floating around.
Speaker 1: It might have two more tinier rocks floating around it that we couldn't see until recently.
Speaker 0: Yeah So now this makes you wonder that like we can see like Jupiter sized planets at like very close stars How do we know they don't have like earth sized rocks around?
Speaker 0: and we can't see if we can barely see rocks around Pluto These rocks that are infinitely farther away.
Speaker 0: Well, not infinitely farther, but many many more times farther away.
Speaker 0: Who knows what's going on out there?
Speaker 1: Pluto was discovered in 1930?
Speaker 1: Fairly long time ago.
Speaker 1: Pluto's moon wasn't discovered till 1978 and Now in 2005 we discovered two smaller rocks.
Speaker 0: Well in 2050 we should be discovering the Mountains of Pluto and the mountains on the moons of Pluto.
Speaker 1: I don't think there any mountains on Pluto.
Speaker 1: No, I think Pluto is just a rock.
Speaker 0: It's just smooth.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's big enough to where you could qualify as mountain Must.
Speaker 0: it can't be perfectly smooth.
Speaker 0: It has to have some hills and craters and things.
Speaker 1: Yes, because obviously I was trying to say that Pluto is perfectly smooth.
Speaker 1: It is made of cheese and it has people like he's isn't perfectly smooth.
Speaker 1: some cheese is well.
Speaker 1: No, nothing's perfectly smooth.
Speaker 1: It's made of atoms little quarks bouncing around.
Speaker 0: Hey, they could all be crystalline in a perfect grid and that's smooth.
Speaker 1: No Because it's the grid itself isn't smooth and there's gaps in it.
Speaker 0: It could be really cold and then they'll be really close together and smooth.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so I guess maybe a Bose Einstein condensate might be smooth.
Speaker 0: So is a baby's ass Bose?
Speaker 0: I'm condensate whatever.
Speaker 1: Moving on Halloween, yeah, and uh, I didn't do anything this year.
Speaker 0: Me neither.
Speaker 1: I wanted to carve a pumpkin I didn't.
Speaker 1: I was gonna go to the parade downtown Went to a j-rock concert instead.
Speaker 0: So, you know, it really bothers me though.
Speaker 0: Oh It's Halloween, all right.
Speaker 0: It's a good holiday like the holiday like candy like scare and stuff like jumping out and going boo.
Speaker 0: Right like mischief like costumes.
Speaker 0: I Saw like three news stories today about people Think their ghosts are real and I had to link to Randy like four times.
Speaker 1: I'll just point out that while I was in the city.
Speaker 1: It's not really Halloween related, but I saw these ads For psychic detectives and this is on court TV court TV.
Speaker 0: And is it a fictional show?
Speaker 1: the subscript is.
Speaker 1: it says psychic detectives?
Speaker 1: This isn't based on a true story colon.
Speaker 1: This is a true story.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we can sue them right for the false advertising.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess it is a true story.
Speaker 0: Whatever they show really happened.
Speaker 0: The psychic part was just made up.
Speaker 1: something like that something like that.
Speaker 1: Randy should buy some commercial time on court TV, of course There's also a lot of people who are still believing in things like someone's gonna put razor blades in the apples They give to kids.
Speaker 0: or you know, you know At least while that's crazy You could put a razor blade in Apple.
Speaker 1: There's no way you could put a razor blade in an apple that I wouldn't see before you'd see it But you know what?
Speaker 0: You're never gonna see a ghost ever Not a real one at least.
Speaker 1: Well, hey if I did I get a million bucks out of Randy sweet With those million bucks.
Speaker 0: I wonder how many razor blades you could buy.
Speaker 0: I Mean you could probably just buy a bunch of.
Speaker 0: you really wanted to see children eat apples full of razor blades.
Speaker 0: if you won the Million dollars you could just buy children be You can feed them apples with razor blades.
Speaker 1: and Yeah, who's that?
Speaker 1: Roman Polanski is a very famous pedophile who fled the game is pedophile because he fled the country and he's still out there.
Speaker 1: They never got it.
Speaker 0: Why don't they get him?
Speaker 1: because he's not.
Speaker 1: he got away All right.
Speaker 0: Now, how does razor blades and apples relate to pedophilia?
Speaker 1: You want to do something to little kids?
Speaker 0: Not sexual and I don't want to do it.
Speaker 0: I was just suggesting it that whoever Was obviously going about it the wrong way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah The hours wondered like say someone actually was putting razor blades and apples and say somehow you didn't see the the razor blades sticking Out of the Apple or the hole in the Apple where the razor blade was shoved in.
Speaker 1: Say they're a sicko and they like this sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Like oh, I love the idea of a kid eating a razor blade in an Apple.
Speaker 1: How would they see the kitty?
Speaker 1: third?
Speaker 1: How would they get any pleasure out of it?
Speaker 0: Well, I imagine it would be a lot like the old man who tells you to get off his lawn.
Speaker 0: I mean, he sees you get off his lawn, but he doesn't see you go home and cry to your mommy Even though he thinks about it and laughs.
Speaker 0: So Bill Gates, he gave like a hajillion dollars to fight malaria a Jillian a yeah hundreds of millions something like 250 million Something by malaria of all things.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is if you actually look at the bill and Melinda Gates Foundation thingy They're always like we give money to fight the diseases that the poor people have instead of the rich people diseases like diabetes and such.
Speaker 0: So malaria is a poor people disease.
Speaker 0: It has a cure.
Speaker 0: We just need to spend money to give the cure to people who have it and kill mosquitoes.
Speaker 0: So it's pretty much a sure bet.
Speaker 0: but I realized why he's doing this, huh?
Speaker 0: See Apple gets in the news with their little iPod video.
Speaker 1: Microsoft doesn't get the.
Speaker 0: Google gets in the news doesn't do anything.
Speaker 0: Google gets in the news with their googling Microsoft Vista.
Speaker 0: it gets negative news.
Speaker 0: So Bill Gates has to go and spend money to fight malaria to get some positive news for the Microsoft.
Speaker 0: Notice how there's no positive news for any of their products services.
Speaker 1: Ah I saw a thing talking about how Microsoft Office was good on like a Windows blog Somewhere written by a guy who works for Microsoft.
Speaker 0: once there was a guy Who was using the Vista beta as his OS and he talks about they have the ribbon on all the programs.
Speaker 0: now I don't know about the ribbon.
Speaker 0: I never actually used it.
Speaker 0: So I can't yeah me either.
Speaker 1: Well, you know suppose it because I dumped the windows.
Speaker 0: I'm done with that totally dumping the windows and you know what.
Speaker 0: if the ribbon is any good someone will steal it and make it in for the Linux.
Speaker 0: So it's been an apple.
Speaker 0: He sold a million videos in 20 days.
Speaker 0: I Think it's catching on You know, and this is with two dollars a video For basically crap TV shows.
Speaker 0: some other people would say they're not crap TV shows, but I say they're crap TV shows.
Speaker 1: I agree that most of them are crap, but I like certain TV shows.
Speaker 0: Well, there there are good TV shows, but none of them are available for $2 an episode from Apple.
Speaker 1: No, they're not.
Speaker 1: I see I can't get my eyes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a wonderful show.
Speaker 1: I had a busy prick me with an AIDS infected needle.
Speaker 0: Good luck with that.
Speaker 0: But You know, imagine if they had.
Speaker 0: you know Real deal, you know full-on everything.
Speaker 0: just put on old things that aren't on TV anymore and charge 50 cents for them.
Speaker 0: You're making zero dollars off of them.
Speaker 0: Now you could be making hundreds of thousands of dollars off of them.
Speaker 1: No Call that stuff in DVD box sets.
Speaker 1: that cost a lot of money not everything.
Speaker 0: There's still a lot of things that haven't made it to DVD box set.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but a lot of things have.
Speaker 0: a lot of things have.
Speaker 1: but our box set of old crappy Hitchcock movies.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean that actually comes out to be cheaper than the downloading that box.
Speaker 0: But like BBC is putting the Monty Python full things for download.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know Well, that was you got it for a present you wouldn't have bought.
Speaker 1: it was so much money I would have bought it for the price they paid for it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they bought it at like Costco, which is like Sam.
Speaker 1: They got it for nothing anyway.
Speaker 0: anything else going on, uh There really wasn't much.
Speaker 1: I mean I went to the city all weekend and I didn't really read the interwebs all weekend.
Speaker 1: So I kind of missed out on whatever happened, but I did find something cool.
Speaker 1: It's probably old but it's cool.
Speaker 1: It's a website dedicated to spoiling things like movies and books and anime and whatever.
Speaker 0: Oh, so I guess they could be useful but also incredibly painful.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's really useful.
Speaker 1: like I wanted to find out how a stupid show ended so I looked like oh so-and-so dies and then Marry, so hey if the show like other shows were like you see the ending but you still don't know what happened.
Speaker 0: Does it explain those?
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Yes here.
Speaker 1: I'll go into one.
Speaker 0: Go to Evangelion.
Speaker 1: I'm going into Donnie Darko.
Speaker 1: Everyone's seen Donnie Darko.
Speaker 1: All right, there's about.
Speaker 0: this is spoiler.
Speaker 0: Watch out.
Speaker 1: All right, it describes an Extremely great detail.
Speaker 1: It doesn't not only spoils it it Explains why what it's telling you spoils it and then explains in great detail the scenes that actually do the spoiling.
Speaker 0: now Is this guy is this one guy writing all this or it's like a wiki?
Speaker 1: or what is this like a wiki?
Speaker 1: It acts like a wiki and it looks like a wiki.
Speaker 1: I don't think it's actually a wiki.
Speaker 0: People are people like editing it in or like.
Speaker 1: it has some stubs and people are adding entries like there's one listing for every James Bond movie ever and it says Bonds right-hand man dies bond gets the girl another girl dies.
Speaker 1: He doesn't die and the villain does die.
Speaker 0: Awesome The coolest thing I saw today was the jack PC.
Speaker 1: I Saw a picture of that thing.
Speaker 0: So it's it's a PC.
Speaker 0: But first there was three.
Speaker 0: comm made the hub that you put in the wall.
Speaker 1: Yep, and the switch.
Speaker 0: Oh They made a switch also.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they made the switch right after they made them.
Speaker 0: Basically just you take your outlet out of your wall and you put this hub in there And you run network cable to it.
Speaker 0: And well, there you go or you guys you could cut a hole in the wall.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, they made the jack PC.
Speaker 0: now, which is just you cut a hole in the wall.
Speaker 0: You put this computer.
Speaker 0: It's you know, not so big.
Speaker 0: it fits a hole in the wall.
Speaker 0: It has a DVI Head headphone in and out microphone in I guess.
Speaker 0: and then for USBs, huh?
Speaker 0: If you just plug the DVI cable to a monitor you plug in a keyboard and mouse of USB.
Speaker 0: You have two USBs left push a button on it a light turns on and you have a computer.
Speaker 1: I take it it's not that powerful considering, you know heating and it has a.
Speaker 0: I think it had a very very low power Embedded AMD type processor, which is actually still good enough and that one problem with it is it comes with the windows CE.
Speaker 1: ah, ah
Speaker 0: The windows CE ah, but um, I imagine if you were mad slick you could either a Switch up the OS that's in the flash by taking the flash out reflashing it putting it something else on there like a custom Linux kernel or if you were extra slick you could plug in like a USB hard drive to the USB hole and get it to boot off of it.
Speaker 0: It's.
Speaker 1: you know, I've got this USB hard drive sitting there on the floor Defeating the purpose of having.
Speaker 0: it's a lot easier than having a laptop with a power cable and then a DVI cable.
Speaker 1: Good for our media box in the living room hooked up to the TV.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you use it like dude check this out.
Speaker 0: the only oh it didn't have a network thing was the other problem.
Speaker 1: There's got to be some sort of network thing.
Speaker 0: Well, no, you'd have to use like a USB Like network card or something.
Speaker 1: So I didn't make one.
Speaker 0: I didn't see a network thing on it.
Speaker 0: There might be an Ethernet hole in the back of it Like you.
Speaker 0: just put you have the Ethernet in the wall.
Speaker 1: make a lot.
Speaker 0: It could be wireless built in could be wireless built in it and see it though and I didn't see words saying it.
Speaker 0: But it could.
Speaker 0: if it had that You just wouldn't need a PC in your living room.
Speaker 0: you plug this thing in and you just have all the T Boeing myth TVing done by another computer and you just use the Windows CE thingy to do a connect up some sort of Samba share maybe snacks forward like a thin client.
Speaker 1: So, uh, we realized that it's hard for us to talk about science and tech even though we made it a bit Because All our good banner comes from us arguing with each other or disagreeing or saying things the other person doesn't know.
Speaker 1: We agree on science.
Speaker 0: I don't see how you could disagree on science seeing is it it's?
Speaker 1: Yes, I mean if there's evidence that says X is true and we both see that evidence then we both agree that X is true and Our caught podcast basically goes hey, uh, so evolution is pretty much a fact, isn't it?
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah Hey, you see that chair?
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: What color is it?
Speaker 1: Kind of bluish blue?
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep See now if I had said green, it's not really that entertaining because well, I'm just wrong.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would say no it's blue and then I'd post a picture on the blog and then the world would go Oh, it's blue.
Speaker 1: Maybe Colin or colorblind friend wouldn't but everyone else Sucks to be colorblind Especially if you like German board games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, especially the camel game.
Speaker 1: oh god, it's like four different colors like four different pastel camels, it's a good game.
Speaker 0: Oh Hiccups, what do you do about those in a podcast you punch someone squarely in the solar plexus?
Speaker 1: No It'll care him.
Speaker 1: I guarantee you won't be hiccuping anymore.
Speaker 0: You know, actually science says differently.
Speaker 1: Why do you science say?
Speaker 0: Science says that hitting someone in the solar plexus does not care the hiccups.
Speaker 1: Um, I believe we could conduct an experiment to find out.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what?
Speaker 0: I don't really have any hiccups anymore.
Speaker 1: We'll see about that.
Speaker 0: We will see.
Speaker 0: but you know what?
Speaker 0: science.
Speaker 1: but I mean Despite the fact that you can't really disagree on science unless the evidence isn't clear enough Like say there's not enough evidence for something.
Speaker 0: You don't have a theory yet.
Speaker 0: You still have a hypothesis.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you have a hypothesis and I have a hypothesis.
Speaker 0: I like to say hypothesis Yep, the most and there's no experiments conducted yet that are conclusive then Who's to say?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we both seek out more evidence.
Speaker 0: See, you know how you can disagree on science if one of the people you're discussing science with doesn't understand science Yep, or if someone is stupid You know.
Speaker 1: if you don't understand science it's the same as being stupid Yeah, or if someone is misinformed, but that gets fixed immediately when you get the facts out.
Speaker 1: The part of the problem is some people will disagree on the facts and then therefore they can't agree on a conclusion because they've got the facts wrong to begin with and Won't look at actual evidence showing them.
Speaker 1: They're wrong.
Speaker 0: The only way to disagree on facts is number one.
Speaker 0: if you The place where you're getting your facts from like if it was a study you might claim that the study was done improperly Yep, or two.
Speaker 0: you just don't like it and you're denying it.
Speaker 1: I think two is the biggest part of this.
Speaker 0: two is a pretty big problem.
Speaker 1: I mean America's still debating evolution and every other country in the world is laughing hysterically I mean during the original scopes monkey trial so long ago.
Speaker 1: I mean we're talking before World War two.
Speaker 1: even back then the French newspapers had headlines like Americans debating facts or Americans are stupid or I could pull out some actual headlines if you wanted me to.
Speaker 1: They were making fun of us then.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the one thing I heard from another country was this British guy and he was basically saying how in Britain they're paying real close attention to it Because they're worried that it'll come over there next.
Speaker 0: Like if they win in America that next they'll be coming to Britain trying to win and they don't want that.
Speaker 1: a bunch of Australians Who are pro intelligent design got together?
Speaker 1: because they saw how well it was going in America and they decided they were gonna push it in Australia.
Speaker 1: because the I Forget exactly how their government is set up, but like their equivalent parliamentary I think yeah, but I mean like the different departments or whatever.
Speaker 1: But their equivalent of like a minister of education is kind of pro intelligent design Supposedly and These people are like, yeah ID ID go and the government put a blanket statement out saying Intelligent design is not science.
Speaker 1: It will never be considered.
Speaker 0: go away cool Good for Australia.
Speaker 1: Yeah, too bad.
Speaker 1: We can't get some of that here.
Speaker 0: Yeah thing is though Australia is like half awesome Half crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're real big on the DRM and things like that.
Speaker 0: You get Nintendo games like years after they come out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, their gameboy advances don't work with other people's gameboy advances.
Speaker 0: from what I heard from an Australian guy I don't know how true it is, but there's an outback.
Speaker 0: There is an outback.
Speaker 0: There are rough-and-tough people out there.
Speaker 0: There's great sports.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's clean It's Play pleasant to live in.
Speaker 1: the water's cancer a lot of skin cancer.
Speaker 0: You got to watch us just cuz the Sun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, but my grandparents tried to move there actually.
Speaker 0: Well, you need mad skills to move there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they won't just let you move in.
Speaker 1: you have to prove that you have a skill that they need and that you'll become gainfully Employed and you don't have any diseases and a whole bunch of others.
Speaker 0: I actually heard a guy talking today about moving to Australia.
Speaker 0: He's like it doesn't matter how much money you have.
Speaker 0: You need to have a special something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, be like a rocket scientist or something in because they respect science there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he us As long as you're not Mexican They'll let you in.
Speaker 0: it seems Oh Arabs they don't the Arabs in it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't like them so much.
Speaker 1: They don't like people who look different.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so they're okay with a lot of the white aliens because they look the same.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, British people are coming to our board Canadians, oh, they don't like Canadians though.
Speaker 0: They just don't know you're Canadian till you say something.
Speaker 0: Hey Canada's cool, though.
Speaker 1: I love Canada.
Speaker 0: It's just cold.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Now we need a passport to go there.
Speaker 0: Thanks.
Speaker 0: We've been watching some do right.
Speaker 0: I love that.
Speaker 1: I don't like Dudley do right so much.
Speaker 1: I was more a fan of the fractured fairy tales, right?
Speaker 0: Where does it good?
Speaker 0: but you gotta you gotta love the snidely whiplash that the one that I just watched.
Speaker 0: It's so great snidely whiplash is like foreclosing on these mortgages.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Yeah You don't understand.
Speaker 1: So, uh, yeah, we got on a tangent.
Speaker 1: I mean The point is just that we can't argue about science here because there's no argument.
Speaker 1: There's either something's true or something isn't or we don't know and There's no way we could ever disagree.
Speaker 1: So we can't come up with any way to get banter.
Speaker 0: We could probably try to get some side tech guests who?
Speaker 0: You know, maybe know some science.
Speaker 0: We don't know or are dumb and dumb and dumb and dumb and they don't understand what we just said.
Speaker 0: They don't under.
Speaker 0: so then we can.
Speaker 0: you know science them.
Speaker 1: or another angle we could take is We could go the informative route and pick a topic that we know a lot about and talk about it.
Speaker 1: I don't know how Unboring that would be.
Speaker 0: yeah, the thing is also is that we're not experts in any particular area other than Computing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least as far as science.
Speaker 0: I mean we know more science than the average person.
Speaker 0: You don't know enough about any one science.
Speaker 0: Like we couldn't give you a lecture on Particle physics.
Speaker 1: Yeah About quantum physics, but I couldn't talk about it in a way that there are other people who could talk about it better.
Speaker 0: I could talk about quantum physics for maybe about 10-15 minutes.
Speaker 0: I just tell you everything I knew about it and that would be it and that wouldn't be Exciting or anything.
Speaker 1: wasn't there a time when you didn't believe in atoms?
Speaker 0: Hey, you know that was before you could see him and I didn't say, you know, all I saying that was that Atoms were a model for describing the particles that made up everything and we knew that everything was made of smaller bits But we didn't know for sure that it was.
Speaker 0: it was Protons neutrons and electrons.
Speaker 1: Well, actually, yeah, we did before we saw him.
Speaker 0: How did you know?
Speaker 0: It was only a model that worked.
Speaker 0: It wasn't.
Speaker 0: no it was a model.
Speaker 1: it That sort of physics as opposed to quantum physics didn't come out of the model.
Speaker 1: and then discovery Ideology it came out of the.
Speaker 1: we discovered these particles Because we could see them cut.
Speaker 1: we could detect them coming out of things when certain reactions happen.
Speaker 1: if you detect particles, you don't You know, it's it's like it really you can't ever see an atom because it's you know Photons bouncing off of something is how you see.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's always a problem.
Speaker 0: We should try to fix that.
Speaker 1: That's impossible to fix.
Speaker 1: You can't see you can only represent based on data.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know, it's like.
Speaker 0: alright, we keep trying to use vision.
Speaker 0: We keep trying to detect things by bouncing a photon off of it and then detecting.
Speaker 1: No, we don't do that at all.
Speaker 1: We try to detect it using other much more advanced sensory apparatuses.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but how do those things work?
Speaker 0: I've always heard about these sensory things they use in accelerators.
Speaker 0: I've never actually heard about how they work or anything.
Speaker 1: They're all very very different like a neutrino detector.
Speaker 1: One way to do it is.
Speaker 1: they have a big tank of water Pure pure pure water and if a neutrino goes through the water the odds are it'll hit one of those water molecules.
Speaker 1: make us a flash.
Speaker 0: They're actually flashes.
Speaker 0: like you can see it flash.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Wow, that's pretty cool.
Speaker 0: or Just look at this big tank of water and I'll see.
Speaker 1: like I don't know if humans can see it.
Speaker 1: I think they need a camera to see it.
Speaker 1: I don't know how fast they're or powerful.
Speaker 1: These flashes are Much cooler.
Speaker 0: if it was a real like a big like a flash bulb You like you take pictures?
Speaker 1: Like when they discovered positrons and all that sort of stuff electrons and egotrons.
Speaker 1: They would set up photographic plates and then they could see the spirals as the particles flew away from the reaction.
Speaker 0: Remember say but I mean, how do you think of this to begin with?
Speaker 1: Science.
Speaker 0: But I mean who thinks of that.
Speaker 0: Hey, I'm smashing atoms here.
Speaker 0: Let me um put a big tank of water next to it and see if anything happens in the water.
Speaker 1: This was more huh?
Speaker 1: Every time I collide these two atoms it a certain result happens.
Speaker 0: I wonder what's happening, but how do you detect the result and know what it was before they made the detector?
Speaker 1: Because they had other detectors that detected larger scale events.
Speaker 1: Like if you run two atoms into each other, you can detect that energy is released Huh?
Speaker 1: Yeah was released.
Speaker 1: Where did the atoms go?
Speaker 1: and then you set up a thing like well I'll put this thing around it where if a if an atom hits it It'll react in a certain way and I know it reacts that way because I fired atoms at it and reacts that way.
Speaker 1: So I'll put it around.
Speaker 1: so I'll see if the atoms bounce off each other.
Speaker 1: Hey, they had never detected an atom.
Speaker 1: the atoms must have disappeared.
Speaker 1: So what they turn into where they got energy?
Speaker 1: Maybe actually they turn into energy and particle.
Speaker 0: Well, you do math to figure out how much of it turned into energy and then the rest obviously did not Something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz you know equals MC squared and such.
Speaker 1: that's actually not the equation.
Speaker 0: I know it has a lot.
Speaker 0: well, it's actually this the the.
Speaker 0: there's another version where it's like M equals No, no, no.
Speaker 1: over equals MC squares is is a representation but is a simplification of the actual equation Significantly more complex.
Speaker 0: Well, there is.
Speaker 1: the whole thing is it's a large theory of relativity, which has many equations encompassing it equals MC squared is just saying that either time or Speed of light has to be constant.
Speaker 1: Einstein made the speed of light constant because that made his equations.
Speaker 1: Awesome he could have done it the other way and it would have worked just as well, but he chose this way and He was smarter than I was.
Speaker 0: so what it really says is that You know matter it has a whole lot of energy in it.
Speaker 1: No, it more just says that mass is energy it is energy, but it is a whole lot.
Speaker 0: In fact, it's C squared a whole lot Yeah, which in a grand scale isn't and a grand scale isn't that much but on a human scale?
Speaker 0: That's a lot.
Speaker 0: I mean, you know if you got all the energy out of like a piece of wood all of it all C squared of it It's a lot of energy.
Speaker 0: you could pry power a city on that for like Weak.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you know keep in mind entropy.
Speaker 1: You really can't get that energy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it sucks.
Speaker 1: You know the whole thermo.
Speaker 0: does that something we can do about science if we can't argue about it.
Speaker 0: We can complain about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, stupid thermodynamics.
Speaker 0: I mean Bringing.
Speaker 0: if I burn a piece of wood, I can't get all the heat.
Speaker 0: I mean, come on.
Speaker 0: I burnt it.
Speaker 0: It's all mine.
Speaker 0: Where's it going?
Speaker 0: It's my wood.
Speaker 0: friggin laws of physics stealing my fire Lisa in this house.
Speaker 1: We follow the laws of thermodynamics.
Speaker 0: Oh, I forget the quote.
Speaker 1: Oh Busted own food, whatever.
Speaker 0: I know it's from the Simpsons.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was a whole thing recently about math in the Simpsons.
Speaker 0: how hard it was for them to get these math jokes in.
Speaker 1: because I Remember the first one remember way way back when Bart went to the genius school and there was the rdr.
Speaker 1: rdr Already ha ha.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I remember laughing at that.
Speaker 1: I was real little when I saw that episode and then I took AP physics and an AP physics.
Speaker 1: we were calculating a Gaussian surface and we were calculating the Gaussian surface of a doughnut shaped objects and then I realized that the operative part of the equation we were using was rdrr and I realized
Speaker 0: up
Speaker 1: that it was the shape of a doughnut and I laughed for like At least a minute straight and everyone's looking at me
Speaker 0: Don't?
Speaker 1: I said rdrr?
Speaker 1: Hardy ha ha and they're all geeks.
Speaker 1: they all got it and then we didn't.
Speaker 1: we just stopped working all day and laughed about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was great.
Speaker 0: there was a. I don't know this for a hundred percent, but there was a tale of the of the Friends went to Fairfield High School and they told a story that there was a teacher there and He was a math teacher and when his problems arrived at an answer involving the number 69 he would put a tally above the board and Yeah that's That's not as funny as rdrr.
Speaker 0: No, but it's definitely stranger.
Speaker 1: Yeah, actually my calculus teacher in tenth grade He pretty much He said okay, I think more times than he said any other word including definite and indefinite articles.
Speaker 0: Oh, I hate it, especially when there's good teachers that say words over and over.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like I had one teacher who would always say in essence In essence in essence in essence everything was in essence.
Speaker 0: I was like so nothing's for real It's only in essence the same.
Speaker 1: I had an English teacher who said quintessential at least twice a day Twice a day isn't so bad.
Speaker 0: I'm talking about like constantly.
Speaker 1: the MK guy was terrible because he'd say it like, okay, and He'd expect some sort of response like yeah, and then he'd keep going.
Speaker 1: But if no one said anything he would quite literally stand in front of the classroom going.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: All right Okay, okay, and then he'd move on like he'd get stuck.
Speaker 0: Some people got these problems.
Speaker 0: Yeah, can science explain them?
Speaker 0: probably Maybe they should.
Speaker 1: we should get a scientist in.
Speaker 0: you know, I'm actually pretty sure that you know, some of those problems like ADD and such Like.
Speaker 0: I'm not a super expert, but at least from the few things I've read there's no Gene for ADD.
Speaker 0: There's no virus No bacteria.
Speaker 0: There's no Chemical.
Speaker 1: I think the problem here is more simply that I believe ADD is something that does exist and can affect people.
Speaker 1: I do believe however that it is Wildly over diagnosed that many people who are told they have ADD are just you know kids.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, ah Maybe if we let him play on proper playgrounds Yeah, yeah cuz I mean when we were kids we were already complaining about the decline of the playground because when we were kids They were taking away the seesaws and they're taking away the merry-go-rounds.
Speaker 0: Actually, you know, I had a pretty good at my elementary school.
Speaker 0: There was there were three playgrounds and when I was in kindergarten There was the old playground and then there was the the big toys which is the new playground.
Speaker 0: the old playground consisted of some old style swings two long chains of the rubber seat a sandbox a spinny thing Two wooden splintery seesaws of metal handles.
Speaker 0: Ooh and this big square tower thing.
Speaker 0: It was a square tower and you climbed up it various ways.
Speaker 0: It's just big Frickin tall rectangle structure at the top.
Speaker 0: You could stand up there and those are railing and there was a slide from up there to get down.
Speaker 0: This thing was like at least 10 feet tall.
Speaker 0: It's pretty tall.
Speaker 0: then the big toys is a big wooden thing and they had the the tires and The tube and a swirly plastic slide and some chains to climb up in those plastic.
Speaker 1: Worst things ever because the plastic slide was fun and we got a Van de Graaff generator.
Speaker 1: you'd go down that thing.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, but they were still fun to go down.
Speaker 1: but one time I got I've slid down one and I went to stand up and I brushed my arm against a little like Metal thing like a little screw and it shocked my arm so hard.
Speaker 1: My arm was dumb and I went crying to my mom and I couldn't explain what happened.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but when we were little kids the little the swirly yellow slide was still pretty good.
Speaker 0: now as big kids We need the long metal slides to get any fun or the carny slides But they're all going away there.
Speaker 1: I mean think about it when we were kids.
Speaker 1: They were taking away the seesaws and all that stuff I saw a few days ago.
Speaker 1: They're taking away swings now because swings are too dangerous.
Speaker 0: So if there's gonna be no moving parts, what's?
Speaker 0: what's the fun?
Speaker 0: You could just.
Speaker 1: They're also taking away sandboxes because animals might do things in them.
Speaker 0: You could use that white sand And Animals might do things.
Speaker 0: They might just pee on the kids.
Speaker 1: I've seen kids peeing on stuff.
Speaker 0: so oh my god I remember nursery school.
Speaker 0: Some kid was peeing in the back of the nursery school playground, and I told her oh one time When I was in second grade You know, we're in a Catholic school.
Speaker 1: There was this kid named Pierre.
Speaker 1: He had pretty French.
Speaker 1: No, he was not French.
Speaker 0: Why was his name Pierre?
Speaker 1: His name was Pierre.
Speaker 0: What the hell are those parents thinking?
Speaker 1: So anyway, one day Kids gonna get picked on and he just peed Even glass?
Speaker 1: He just sat there and he just unzipped and peed.
Speaker 0: Wait, he unzipped?
Speaker 1: He unzipped and peed.
Speaker 1: He was sitting in his desk and he just peed.
Speaker 0: Where'd he peed?
Speaker 0: Did he just go on the floor?
Speaker 1: Just went on.
Speaker 1: the floor started because the classroom was kind of slanted and started making his way toward the front of the room.
Speaker 1: And Who's a nun looks and says who's got a drink and no one says anything.
Speaker 1: and then everyone's looking and we all real Everyone realizes at this point.
Speaker 1: What is happening?
Speaker 0: I never heard this story and no one wants to react to it.
Speaker 1: cuz no one's sure what to do.
Speaker 1: We're all second graders.
Speaker 1: We didn't even think to laugh cuz this was just too weird.
Speaker 0: second grade.
Speaker 0: Holy crap.
Speaker 0: I can grade.
Speaker 1: And it was you know, this was back before, you know would have been a biohazard because you know wasn't.
Speaker 0: it's not a biohazard It's sterile.
Speaker 1: It's sterile If you get a tooth pulled by the dentist.
Speaker 1: You're not allowed to take it home in a lot of places because it's a biohazard.
Speaker 0: I took it home.
Speaker 1: So, you know what the nun did?
Speaker 1: She made him get some paper towels and clean up his pee and then we went back on with the lesson.
Speaker 0: Sounds about right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she hit him too with the ruler a couple times.
Speaker 0: That's not so right.
Speaker 1: I was a college school.
Speaker 1: They hit us.
Speaker 1: They hit me a lot.
Speaker 1: Cuz I was smart ass.
Speaker 0: I would hit back.
Speaker 1: I Didn't hit back.
Speaker 0: I would hit back Cuz.
Speaker 1: I'd always ask questions about science and they give me God answers and I'd ask for science answers and then they hit me.
Speaker 0: I always read stories you ever read.
Speaker 0: they caged the animals at night.
Speaker 0: No, it's basically this guy's autobiography of his childhood.
Speaker 0: This is sequel and it's actually pretty sad.
Speaker 0: cuz like his mom is all screwed up in traction all the time And his brothers don't care for him and he's always in like You know foster houses and things and it's terrible.
Speaker 0: and you know, his life pretty much sucked as a child Uh-huh, and he came to my middle school once and told us about it after he read it and he cried.
Speaker 0: whatever You know put on a show I think but you know, it's true.
Speaker 0: basically.
Speaker 0: Well, one of the things is he's always in Catholic places where nuns would hit him a lot You know and I was always just like you never hit back.
Speaker 0: You can't really you know, I get you get my sympathy for some stuff, but not for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's hard to hit back cuz remember when you're when you're in second grade, you're a little kid.
Speaker 1: So those nuns are tall.
Speaker 1: They're strong.
Speaker 1: They're stronger than your old ladies.
Speaker 1: Nah, they weren't all old ladies.
Speaker 0: If you push one over they'll break their hip and you win.
Speaker 1: Actually, some of them were pretty young.
Speaker 0: if they're young.
Speaker 0: Why are they hitting kids?
Speaker 0: They're not mean old ladies They're mean nuns.
Speaker 0: You're mean and young none.
Speaker 1: There was one real nice none who gave me some gerbils Gerbils.
Speaker 1: Yeah, she had gerbils and she gave me a couple.
Speaker 0: I know could you I can't imagine like like a 20 30 year old nun hitting kids.
Speaker 1: Yeah one nun she was old, but she used a metal ruler.
Speaker 1: Everyone else used wooden rulers and regime with that metal ruler.
Speaker 1: That was endgame.
Speaker 0: Maybe it's because she was so old.
Speaker 0: She needed the metal one to.
Speaker 0: You know spice it up.
Speaker 1: I only ever saw her actually hit a kid once and the kid kind of deserved it.
Speaker 0: You know kids do deserve a hitting sometimes But I don't think that you know, I don't think that's not should be doling it out.
Speaker 0: Yeah You know, actually, you know, the Singapore hitting is a little too hard.
Speaker 1: I'm kind of an advocate of caning because the more I see people doing stupid things It'd be a great way to solve problems.
Speaker 0: if someone was stupid if you just whacked him and said hey no See the thing is it's like it's not really cruel or unusual I mean the caning they do is a little cruel because a little too much.
Speaker 0: but seriously if someone Let's say someone robbed a convenience store instead of locking them up in prison where they'll come out and just you know Not change their mind or anything
Speaker 1: or if anything they'll learn how to rob one better from the people who are yeah
Speaker 0: You just whack them right just not caning.
Speaker 0: but like Whipping or something something like between spanking and caning or just humiliate him just a good spanking Spanking's good.
Speaker 0: The judge himself does it with a giant paddle.
Speaker 0: a paddle paddling paddling is good paddling of the swollen ass.
Speaker 0: That's that's how we get him great.
Speaker 0: It'll be so much cheaper.
Speaker 1: You know and people why this won't happen because we do have the whole, you know prison industrial complex going in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Now it is but the prison doesn't make us money.
Speaker 0: It loses us money.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the thing is the prison exists The prison system is huge.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and a lot of people work for it.
Speaker 1: Everyone who works for the prison system has a vested interest in what we'll be.
Speaker 0: still need prisons I mean for like crazy murders.
Speaker 1: we do you realize how many people are incarcerated in the United States?
Speaker 1: We have one of the highest per capita rates.
Speaker 0: I think the highest.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we have more people in prison per capita than China then a communist oppressive China.
Speaker 0: We have more than Australia, which was a prison colony.
Speaker 1: Well, isn't Australia a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, yeah, yeah Even Though we want to go there and they just don't let us.
Speaker 1: you know I think we got a topic for a Friday coming up the prison industrial complex prison industrial complex because it's a something I'm we totally lost science.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we lost science, but we couldn't talk about science.
Speaker 1: We'll have to come up with a way to talk science.
Speaker 0: I think we do a problem of Microphone close to the mouth a little less far from the mouth and you can see it on the wave getting bigger and smaller.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll see if anyone complains when they listen to this.
Speaker 0: I'm sure they will.
Speaker 1: Anyone still listening this far into it?
Speaker 1: because we got on off on a tangent.
Speaker 1: Yeah Hey Alex Pete if you hear this right now, it's no good.
Speaker 1: Say something.
Speaker 0: That's no good.
Speaker 1: We won't do that.
Speaker 1: We won't make a habit of that.
Speaker 1: but This podcast kind of went off on a crazy tangent.
Speaker 1: We went from science to a kid peeing to prison industrial complex.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think tomorrow and the next day will be a lot better though because we can argue about things.
Speaker 1: I like games you don't like you like anime.
Speaker 1: what?
Speaker 0: hey maybe we should you know pick something else or we can talk about like it and not liking because it's really the only room for Any real discussion unless we made an informative Monday night like today.
Speaker 1: This is how to Build a Linux box or this is how to use jabber properly.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just think that might be a little boring.
Speaker 0: It sounds almost like a separate podcast we should do.
Speaker 0: Yeah Let's get some suggestions from people we know.
Speaker 1: yeah, what do you want to hear?
Speaker 1: What should we add other than sci-tech because we don't have so much sci-tech.
Speaker 1: Anyway, that was geek night special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening music.
Speaker 1: Promotional consideration was provided by Noah.