Speaker 1: It's Thursday August 3rd, and this is geek nice.
Speaker 0: We're at Otacon right now.
Speaker 1: in fact exactly at this minute We are probably either in the pool or in the hotel having a wine and cheese party.
Speaker 0: Well at the moment that this was released.
Speaker 1: well of course at the moment now.
Speaker 1: We're still in beacon recording ahead.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well if you're listening to this the day it came out odds are you aren't at Otacon?
Speaker 1: And that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at two oh six three three three one five three seven.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.