Speaker 1: It's Monday November 6th.
Speaker 1: I'm rim and I'm Scott and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We talked a bit about shameless self-promotion.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: So what do I always say on Monday man this weekend?
Speaker 0: It was so crazy Etc, etc.
Speaker 0: Yeah tired blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: I'm not tired.
Speaker 1: It was just a great weekend.
Speaker 1: But once again, we were out of town.
Speaker 0: Yep, I think it was actually pretty good because you're out of town.
Speaker 0: What do we do?
Speaker 0: we laid around and not didn't do what you laid around and did nothing.
Speaker 1: We all went for a hike.
Speaker 0: Yeah once for a couple hours.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the rest of the time you spent laying around True true.
Speaker 0: So it was mostly laying around and eating and watching things.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though most importantly we went to see Lewis black and that other guy.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I forgot.
Speaker 0: No, I didn't forget I'm just being silly.
Speaker 1: Okay Yeah, but yeah, we'll see Lewis black live and it was pretty badass.
Speaker 1: I haven't gone to see a professional comedian in a long time, but I got to say it sounds silly.
Speaker 1: But I forgot that it's that funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like I went to see Lewis black when he was at RIT years ago.
Speaker 0: It cost five bucks and at the time I had listened to his album, you know from downloading it when those are the Napster days.
Speaker 0: But so when I went to see him live then I knew all the jokes so it wasn't so exciting.
Speaker 0: He told maybe a couple jokes I hadn't heard.
Speaker 0: But we went to see him in Albany now and he had all new stuff that I never heard before and I didn't listen to His newer album.
Speaker 0: or maybe it doesn't have an album with those jokes on it.
Speaker 0: So it was hysterical.
Speaker 1: Well, he also put out I think a much better performance than he did at RIT.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think it helps these in New York guy and it was the Albany show.
Speaker 0: So he kind of know he made a lot of Albany jokes and you know, he knows what's going on, Chris He made Rochester jokes.
Speaker 0: He made Rochester jokes.
Speaker 0: Of course.
Speaker 0: He's a New York guy.
Speaker 0: Rochester is also in New York barely.
Speaker 0: Yeah We made a Rochester joke while talking about Rochester jokes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though the one point of interest that there was a heck not really a heckler but a dumbass in the crowd who?
Speaker 1: Periodically would yell.
Speaker 1: Whoo Or he'd shout out a name like he was making fun of things.
Speaker 1: Lewis black was like holy and everyone laughed.
Speaker 1: You know, he's doing this whole thing where he's naming names of people who have caused trouble in the news And then this dude just yells out a name and at this point Lewis black has had enough and he's pretty basically Stopped the show and says all right, mister.
Speaker 1: You need to stop this and the guy goes well, he's like that I'm not kidding.
Speaker 1: You need to stop this.
Speaker 1: these people all paid a lot of money to see me up here doing my comedy and If you want I can just let the show hand over to you and you can yell out funny names all night long.
Speaker 0: Well, I think it was one guy yelled out a name and he actually he didn't yell it out Like yeah, he has yelled out a name like so-and-so and it was a funny name and everyone was like ha ha ha You know Lewis black was like yeah, see that guy.
Speaker 1: Okay you not okay Yeah, that other guy just kept trying to yell shit out.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: And finally Lewis black just starts digging into him and basically yelling at him in a. it still ended up being a funny because it's Lewis Black.
Speaker 1: yeah,
Speaker 0: it was cool because so much like I always thought of him as someone who thinks of his jokes beforehand Then he definitely is he's someone who writes his jokes and then delivers them really really well with his angry, you know Persona, but it was good to see that, you know when there was stuff going on.
Speaker 0: He could be funny just out of nothing as well instead of just delivering pre-written stuff.
Speaker 1: I just couldn't believe that the guy he was yelling at didn't get it.
Speaker 1: He kept yelling out like stop that I'm Sarah.
Speaker 1: Whoo.
Speaker 1: I'm not kidding.
Speaker 0: And I thought I saw the security go over.
Speaker 1: security did indeed go.
Speaker 0: security found the right guy.
Speaker 0: They found the right guy found someone and I thought they gave him a talking to.
Speaker 1: I want that to security.
Speaker 1: people came from both Sides and I'll.
Speaker 1: practically we're about to make the guy leave and he shut the hell up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's cool Actually, though.
Speaker 1: What was the guys that I don't remember?
Speaker 1: the guy's name went before him.
Speaker 0: I'm sure it's on the internet.
Speaker 0: Yes on the Penn Jillette radio show with Lewis black a few weeks ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah, apparently they're good friends.
Speaker 1: All I got to say is the guy was really funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't think he was gonna be funny like he started out and I was like, haha You know, but he didn't really do anything.
Speaker 0: that spectacular does this joke, but then he did this joke.
Speaker 1: Oh, man He'd starts a joke and then he doesn't really finish it and then he goes off on this crazy Tangent that borders on not being funny at all for a while minutes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was like, okay, man Where are you going with this?
Speaker 1: And then he brings it back and oh man It comes full circle and I was laughing out loud as hard as I could.
Speaker 1: Yeah Once it dawned on me the joke he was making and it dawned on the rest of the audience about the same time.
Speaker 0: It was sort of like this.
Speaker 0: not it wasn't like, you know, someone says something and then you're like pop.
Speaker 0: It was like say something.
Speaker 1: Indianapolis, Indiana.
Speaker 1: You might need what joke could possibly funny where the punchline is Indianapolis India.
Speaker 1: don't get started on your Tom Jones.
Speaker 1: We got other things from the weekend.
Speaker 1: the weekend was fantastic.
Speaker 0: not gonna talk about those things now.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we have enough stories from this weekend to last another week not to mention the like 2,000 items in my Google Reader when I got home.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was news.
Speaker 1: I mean we could talk about how Saddam is gonna be hung.
Speaker 1: we could talk about the election.
Speaker 0: It's a. it's a. it's a Jew song about Saddam Hussein.
Speaker 0: no, it's about Heyman.
Speaker 0: Oh Heyman Yeah, a guy who probably wasn't real most likely wasn't.
Speaker 1: isn't that the guy where you're supposed to toot a horn every time?
Speaker 1: Someone tries to say his name.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's the holiday of Purim and there's a song they sing on.
Speaker 0: Purim You know is the.
Speaker 1: I don't need to hear the song.
Speaker 1: Okay, I That okay.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so we got some news.
Speaker 1: It's Monday News Oh news.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, there's so many news is hard to pick just one.
Speaker 0: Well, I think last week this I'll do this one because it was relative to our Related to our Thursday episode last week the help we talked about on Thursday who we're gonna vote for.
Speaker 0: All right So rim was talking about our congressperson.
Speaker 0: district 19 of New York State is Sue Kelly.
Speaker 1: We disagree with her on Everything that humans can disagree on every.
Speaker 0: if you look at her voting record and you say hey What if Scott Rubin was the representative instead of Sue Kelly every single vote would have gone the other way every single one.
Speaker 0: So rib was talking about her opponent in the current election John Hall,
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: how we were kind of pissed at John Hall because he kept calling us on the phone and it was annoying and We you know We liked him less because the really only reason we like John Hall is because he's the opponent of Sue Kelly.
Speaker 1: Also, his platform is very simple and I do not disagree with anything.
Speaker 0: he has said yeah, but at the same time He was giving us all these phone calls.
Speaker 0: They were kind of upset and I was sort of like girl.
Speaker 0: He shouldn't be calling us.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll vote for the third guy.
Speaker 1: I was getting to the point where I was gonna vote for Sue Kelly just to make sure this guy's spamming me lost.
Speaker 0: Whoa, that's crap.
Speaker 0: I would do that.
Speaker 1: go that far cuz she's so evil because she is evil in an abstract way.
Speaker 1: This guy was directly affecting my life.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it turns out that John Hall wasn't calling us.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in fact, it was what the Republicans and Sue Kelly was calling us.
Speaker 0: and Apparently what's happening is they have this new trick where they'll call you on the phone They'll have a row a machine call you on the phone and the machine will say something like we'd like to talk to you about John Hall.
Speaker 0: He supports good thing good thing good thing good thing and you immediately think This is John Hall telling me to vote for him and you hang up and you hate John Hall You're not gonna vote for him now, but if you continue to listen it says but John Hall is evil evil evil evil evil.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually Sue Kelly calling you But if you hang up early You hate John Hall because you think he called you and if you stay on the phone You hate John Hall because it says bad things about him.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: I didn't believe Scott.
Speaker 1: so then I went through my voicemail because quote unquote John Hall had called me like nine times over the past several days and left voice messages and sure enough They were all actually from Sue Kelly secretly.
Speaker 0: The other thing is if you continue if you if you hang up on it It calls you back.
Speaker 0: if you don't hang up on it, then it never calls you again.
Speaker 0: It's got.
Speaker 0: it's a crazy kind of computer making all these calls and apparently people are reporting this happening Not just in our district with our candidates But in quite a few districts and quite a few different races around the country mostly important races like ours is pretty important.
Speaker 1: Actually, here's my one of my contested.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: And also I think John Hall is a good chance of winning.
Speaker 0: I do think so - I hope so.
Speaker 0: Well Kelly's a bitch.
Speaker 1: I was listening to NPR It's all politics, which is actually one of my favorite short news politics podcasts.
Speaker 1: I listen to one news politics podcast.
Speaker 1: So it is in fact my favorite news politics podcast.
Speaker 1: but they really sum up the American political situation pretty neutrally in about 10 minutes and They are pretty sure that the Democrats in America are going to take control of the house And they're about 50/50 on them taking control of the Senate.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if the voting machines work, it'll it'll turn.
Speaker 1: Well, they're already not working.
Speaker 1: I almost use the news that there have been like eight voting machine fuck-ups already.
Speaker 0: I think if they get they have electronic voting machines instead of the old-fashioned, you know pull them.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I'll demand a paper or provisional ballot if there's a die-bold d-bold machine there.
Speaker 1: I will definitely vote on paper if there's a machine except half the problems now Or that the machines that read the paper ballots don't work either.
Speaker 1: Ah Person's got to read it that people don't and the people are often stupid.
Speaker 1: They're not paid very much.
Speaker 0: Well, they're old ladies who volunteer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least where we go.
Speaker 0: So yeah, apparently I think in New Hampshire There's talks of the Republicans are gonna get in trouble because they admitted they were Setting these calls and they're gonna get fined like five thousand dollars.
Speaker 0: Oh, no Yeah, and all kinds of stuff like this is going down now.
Speaker 0: So we'll see if this tactic actually gives them an advantage or if in the end The news that they did this tactic gets out and does harm to them.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: I just generally dislike spam and I really it bothers me the way our laws are set up Especially when you look at who writes the laws We have.
Speaker 1: this do not call list in America Which means if you sign up for it people can't call you to sell their crap.
Speaker 1: They can only call you if they want to give a survey which is a stupid loophole.
Speaker 0: number one Well, it has to be a nonprofit organization Giving a survey which usually it's like coca-cola can't call up and ask for a survey.
Speaker 1: But coca-cola could fund a nonprofit organization that asks you about coca-cola in a positive way.
Speaker 1: They very well could yeah And that happens all the goddamn time.
Speaker 1: Yep Second politicians can call you no matter what.
Speaker 1: yep now I'm fine with an exemption for so politicians can call the constituents.
Speaker 1: However, I am of the mind that that exception should state that the politician himself can call Directly.
Speaker 1: none of this pre-recorded message BS.
Speaker 0: Oh, I think that's a good idea.
Speaker 1: I thought I was morning.
Speaker 0: I was gonna make the exception that says they can call you as long as it's.
Speaker 0: you know.
Speaker 0: They can give a political call as long as it's not, you know Soliciting votes.
Speaker 0: like my congressman can call me to inform me about a bill that he's gonna hold on.
Speaker 1: Here's here's what's wrong with that.
Speaker 1: So alright say rim is I'm in the house.
Speaker 1: I'm trying to get reelected.
Speaker 1: You'll get a call that says rim voted Yes on blah and rim voted yes on blah and rim did this and rim did this.
Speaker 1: All right It was awesome.
Speaker 0: call the only thing I can't call within two months of an election in which the hair.
Speaker 1: What if there's something important that they have to say to the people, uh, I don't know.
Speaker 1: I just say he has to call personally and that's the end of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it sounds good.
Speaker 0: I'm proud of that.
Speaker 0: I didn't think of that one.
Speaker 0: It's great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz then I would totally talk to him.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah I mean whenever I meet a politician I always try to.
Speaker 1: well at least not a local politician.
Speaker 1: I've met a lot of local politicians.
Speaker 1: I really care about him.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in fact, I'd say that meeting more local politicians has turned me more and more away from trying to get into local politics.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I wondered like earlier in the election season I saw those signs everywhere that said Bob for Congress and now I don't see them anymore.
Speaker 0: What happened to that guy?
Speaker 0: I don't know anything about him other than his name was Bob and he's running for car.
Speaker 1: What about Bob?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But yeah, I wonder what happened to that guy.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna go look him up.
Speaker 1: So speaking of wondering what happened to things I'm on a roll with these segues.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm proud.
Speaker 1: a lot of things I've said today Alright.
Speaker 1: so anyway, I have For despite the fact that I'm generally anti-war in most cases and I'm not really a pacifist But I'm just generally against war.
Speaker 1: but I've always been fairly fascinated with fighter jets and air combat and air tactics and all that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Probably because I grew up next to Selfridge Air National Guard Base, which hosted a great number of f-16 fighters I've flown f-16 fighter Simulators like the actual military ones.
Speaker 1: I've hung out with pilots.
Speaker 1: I went to all these little programs when I was a kid and I know a lot Relative to how much you'd think someone like me would know about fighter jets.
Speaker 1: not saying that I know a lot Far be it from me But one of my probably my third favorite fighter slash bomber ever is the f-117 Nighthawk or stealth fighter.
Speaker 1: It's the black triangle the weird-looking thing with all the flat panels on it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, not the one that's all you know, not the giant black triangle the little the smaller black triangle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, too.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: This was the America's first Production functional as far as we know stealth Aircraft.
Speaker 1: it was designated the fighter f-117 a which means it's a fighter.
Speaker 1: But really it was a bomber and there's all sorts of Theories as to why they designated it fighters.
Speaker 1: that a bomber and I you none of you care about any of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it really fight against an f-15 or anything.
Speaker 0: It would get shot down if they could see it.
Speaker 1: now It is very recently and finally after 25 years of service Many of those years unknown to the vast majority of human beings because it was one of those secret skunkworks projects.
Speaker 1: In fact, this thing was used to bomb Panama in like 1989 or something.
Speaker 0: Wasn't it a bitch to fly a parent?
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is it looks really weird and it's very hard to fly.
Speaker 1: They had all these funny nicknames for it But the way it actually flew is a computer controlled it and a computer kept it level.
Speaker 1: The computer did most of the actual flying.
Speaker 1: if the computer died No human being could keep that thing in the air for any amount of time.
Speaker 0: Oh shit.
Speaker 1: Now actually the f-16 was kind of like that.
Speaker 1: the f-16 has a lot of computer stabilization without which it's almost impossible to fly.
Speaker 1: But I digress the f-117 stealth fighter bomber.
Speaker 1: Well, it's just what I keep getting.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna get on that.
Speaker 1: the f-117 has been retired much like yes, our 71 blackbird was retired.
Speaker 0: Oh, but the blackbird is like the coolest thing ever.
Speaker 0: It's still useful.
Speaker 0: the x-men get use out of it Don't not?
Speaker 1: with that they need the sheer technology Yeah, which we don't have yet the she are tech.
Speaker 1: whatever stupid underwear pervert comics.
Speaker 0: They got a blackbird though.
Speaker 0: It's cool now.
Speaker 1: I just know that the news really didn't make a big deal about this and it's probably not a big deal But I think it was a really cool weapon that did a lot of good in the theater of war
Speaker 0: And I
Speaker 1: think it's progressed technology in a great way.
Speaker 1: I think it was a really neat thing.
Speaker 0: My only question is they invented the b2 which is sort of better in almost every way and is the bigger better black triangle Even though it's more expensive I think.
Speaker 0: why did they just stop using the f-117 when they invented the b2 instead of?
Speaker 1: one of the main reasons we keep using Older fighter jets when we make a new one is that it costs a lot of money to make new fighter jets and the old ones who don't have enough.
Speaker 1: the old ones of any Aircraft the Americans have while generally very inferior to the newest one We've made is still leaps and bounds beyond what most of the world has.
Speaker 0: Yeah everything I've read so far Just keep saying that basically all these planes are slowly being replaced with the f-22 Raptor, which looks pretty cool.
Speaker 0: It's not black though, but apparently it must be just better than every other goddamn fighter jet there ever was.
Speaker 1: now I have an interesting anecdote about the f-117.
Speaker 1: You see back when we were at RIT I said something about the f-117 out of the blue and Scott through no fault of his own intelligence Decided to try to argue with me saying that the f-117 Was the newer stealth weapon and that the b2 and anything else came out way before?
Speaker 0: Because I somehow knew yeah that the I was just using logic, you know That one looks cooler and newer.
Speaker 0: therefore it must be cooler and newer But it doesn't look cooler and newer.
Speaker 1: It looks like something that was made because we didn't have enough technology to figure out how to make it better.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I can tell looking at plane.
Speaker 1: All right, how many planes have you seen that have all flat surfaces?
Speaker 1: All right I guess they got to go to things of the day as much as I want to talk about all this.
Speaker 1: other fighter jet stuff Like skunk works and the fact that all all the technology we civilians know about is usually way Behind what they're actually working on.
Speaker 0: but area 51 OMG.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's not UFOs Yeah, but instead I guess we'll just have to save that for I don't know war week or military week And instead we got things of the day.
Speaker 0: You want me to go first?
Speaker 1: I guess so.
Speaker 0: I found this flicker photo set from some guy and it's just a bunch of pictures, but they're Flicker photo set.
Speaker 1: that is a bunch of pictures.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: The first picture says internet and I go, okay, I look at the next picture and It's like I forget what the order was, but it's like omfg and there's a crazy monster and the next one's like Orly or really and there's two owls there and it's just a bunch of pictures of you know internet words like WTF and teh and all that suchness.
Speaker 0: so and eat.
Speaker 0: each little acronym is accompanied by an Illustration which perfectly illustrates the acronym in question and it is high Larry's.
Speaker 1: it seems to be just a small collection of what to internet Actually is.
Speaker 0: yeah I'm definitely instead of any time from now on if I have to say ZOMG or early in a post I'm just gonna link to these little pictures on flicker.
Speaker 1: You know the whole adding Z to the front of things Really didn't sit well with me and I kind of skipped over it until our friend Jess Whenever she types to me has never not said Z something It's a given point and it kind of grew on me.
Speaker 1: and now I just use it some G. Yep ZOMG zombie his axe is on fire.
Speaker 0: Yeah, some of these are particularly hilarious though.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well Scott basically saw the site and went huh and immediately clicked on the or really owl and ignored everything else for a good Several minutes, of course, of course.
Speaker 1: Oh, really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, really?
Speaker 1: No way way Alright, so I discovered this kind of randomly and I wasn't sure what it was because it's kind of weird.
Speaker 1: But then you figure out what they're doing and it's kind of cool.
Speaker 1: now I'll start out by saying that a few people have said on the internets that this video is fake.
Speaker 1: They sped it up to which I say no shit That's the point.
Speaker 1: Good God It's not fake.
Speaker 1: if you intended it to be that way Renault did.
Speaker 1: this cool thing looks like it's for some f1 race or something some little.
Speaker 1: hey Hello, look at us and they got a bunch of people and they have little placards that they hold up with colors on them And they act out a little f1 video game scene real quick from the top down and it's really kind of cool.
Speaker 0: We should do this only with pac-man's.
Speaker 0: with pac-man's you say yeah, we just have like a. You know like a guy a pellet runs into the pac-man as the pac-man opens and closes and then a pellet runs out the back Of the pac-man.
Speaker 0: Oh, it doesn't run out the back of the back man.
Speaker 1: I was gonna say unless pac-man has the diarrhea's Pac-man has the diarrhea's sucks for the ghosts.
Speaker 1: So with the elections coming up, we decided we'd talk those eyeballs.
Speaker 0: They go right through your digestive system.
Speaker 1: a little bit about marketing Marketing.
Speaker 0: you say what do we know about that?
Speaker 1: Well, we know about internet marketing.
Speaker 0: No, we do only but the only the non shady part specifically because you are anti shadiness.
Speaker 1: Well, we know all about the shady part, but we're not gonna tell you how to do the shady parts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because we're against the shady parts.
Speaker 1: see we've noticed in our forums Not so much mostly because our forums are well patrolled by very angry individuals.
Speaker 1: But in the internets as a whole it seems like spam and I don't mean email spam because spam is not related to just email.
Speaker 1: If you go to any internet community that is not fully moderated and very carefully watched it will fill With nothing but people linking to their own bullshit and trying to promote it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know.
Speaker 0: it seems like there's different levels of Ethicality in terms of promoting yourself on the internet because everyone's got a website Everyone's got a maybe a video on YouTube or a podcast or a webcomic or something and they want to get the word out.
Speaker 0: and The internet is a crazy way to get the word out because there's millions of people looking at all kinds of shit all the time.
Speaker 0: So if there are links to your shit all over the place.
Speaker 0: there's more chances of people coming and looking at your shit and thus you becoming popular and awesome and There are many ways to get your links on to already existing popular shit that range from That range from horribly evil to perfectly.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I generally dislike marketing but there's a fine line.
Speaker 1: I mean, let's say you're on a community somewhere and you do something cool and you've been there for a while.
Speaker 1: So you say hey guys check out what I just did.
Speaker 1: That's probably okay.
Speaker 1: but say you want to promote an event and you join a community with the express purpose of promoting your event and not Actually contributing to the community.
Speaker 1: not so cool
Speaker 0: Yeah, but then what are you gonna do about these people now where there are companies that have people working for them and people hire these companies and What the companies do is they have their employees go out and become members of communities and they contribute to the communities in a valuable way and After about a week they come out with you know, promotions and spam and links and all that kind of crap.
Speaker 0: But it looks okay If you just look at the forum and there's no way to know that person isn't actually a legitimate member of the community But is actually an employee of some company being paid to do that.
Speaker 0: What do you do then?
Speaker 1: Yeah, especially when now there's this it's been coming out that a lot of blogs are being paid to say certain kinds of things By very large advertising networks that do it semi shadily.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and seriously those bloggers, you know what I guess they feel special that someone's giving them money for blogging.
Speaker 0: Now I can blog and not have to work, you know, they just want money.
Speaker 0: They think they made the big time but at the same time What the hell.
Speaker 0: now your blog is worthless.
Speaker 0: The reason people read it before if anyone did read it before is now gone now.
Speaker 0: You're just an ad now.
Speaker 1: I have a lot of experience trying to generate buzz for things on the internet in generally ethical ways And I think I can safely say that I've never delved below the line of what I would consider shady.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've actually delved low less low than rim has.
Speaker 0: yeah I definitely stay.
Speaker 0: I'll stay away from things that you know, I know aren't considered shady, but I consider them shady.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the closest that the lowest I've gotten is that I have Numerous names on the internet.
Speaker 1: I have many many many full name Identities on the internet that are not active in communities or anything, but they exist Only have one name.
Speaker 1: they exist mostly if I need to get the word out about something I've done and I can if I want like say I want to dig so I want to dig myself for some reason.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna use my own account because that just looks particularly shady to everyone else.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you're not.
Speaker 0: there's nothing wrong technically with digging yourself But if people notice it and what you've dug isn't that great then they're gonna be like hey and people bury you just for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it seems like people generally really don't like it if they see someone promoting something they've done regardless of the actual intent Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: So as a result if I want to if I ever want to promote something that I myself has done I never do it under my own name ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but at the same time it's not like I'll just make this secret alternate Identity and join a community and then fake a thousand posts so that in the future I'll be ready to make my evil marketing ploy and it'll be brilliant.
Speaker 0: Yeah, ha ha ha.
Speaker 1: I just participate in the communities with a different name So no one connects my participation there with my participation somewhere else.
Speaker 1: So people can't try to follow me around and see what kind of things I promote what kind of things I don't promote Today's.
Speaker 0: I don't try to promote myself in communities I'm not a member of.
Speaker 0: it's like if I'm a member of a community a legitimate one Then I feel okay once in a while, you know promoting myself.
Speaker 0: If I do something crazy now I won't promote.
Speaker 0: I do a lot of things and the thing is if you promote every single thing you do Like if I went posted a link to every single episode of geek nights in the forum of some other Podcasts that I might frequent that's not cool.
Speaker 0: But there's nothing wrong with keeping a link to geek nights in my signature there.
Speaker 0: I do that.
Speaker 1: in fact, I'd expect that if you're on the internet You should put the signature of whatever cool thing you do there.
Speaker 0: So people who seem to like you can see what stuff you've done And then you know if we perhaps come out with a crazy episode of geek nights that that community would care about Then I would say hey guys check it out.
Speaker 0: I would also check out.
Speaker 0: You know other things that the community might be interested in.
Speaker 0: I'll just promote myself.
Speaker 0: I promote others, which is always okay.
Speaker 1: now I mean we could go in a lot of directions with this show.
Speaker 1: so I think I'd like to take a look at
Speaker 0: probably
Speaker 1: an example of someone who was doing shady things or Someone who is trying to game a system in order to promote themselves as Opposed to just trying to let themselves naturally become popular if what they're doing is actually worthwhile.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Now you might remember a while ago Scott linked to this site.
Speaker 1: That's already turned into a complete steaming pile of feces called pop currents.
Speaker 1: Ah now we didn't let anyone in the show know.
Speaker 1: But as an experiment in the forums only Scott posted and said we want to see if we can game this site.
Speaker 0: But for whatever reason yeah, I wanted to experiment with the site see how it worked, you know I mean I had no doubts in my mind.
Speaker 0: This site was pretty much just going downhill and no one cared about it.
Speaker 1: so a bunch of people in our forums pop because it's kind of like dig.
Speaker 1: only you can pop things up or down instead of Just digging things up and a bunch of people in the forums went and popped us up and we've got like 30 pops right away And and then everyone stopped because that discussion disappeared And the site was kind of meh and it seems like everyone else was trying to do the same thing.
Speaker 1: Hey Everyone is a fan of my thing.
Speaker 1: come in here and dig me up like all those stupid lists of top 100 whatever Podcasts or top 10 webcomic whatevers.
Speaker 1: Yep Now I ignored the site forgot about it and you know We had our laughs and we went on.
Speaker 1: a few weeks later I went back to the site just curious what had happened and I saw that we have been popped down like 20 times And then I saw that many many things on the site had been popped down a lot.
Speaker 1: Then I noticed that most of the people who had popped us down and popped all these other things down had popped down Everything within a genre of whatever and then popped up exactly one thing.
Speaker 1: huh and there were numerous different things that had this phenomena surrounding it and it seems like people like This guy here called Brody solo on myspace who has some kind of band or something.
Speaker 1: I don't know what he does.
Speaker 1: He seems to have been the biggest perpetrator of this.
Speaker 1: It looks like he either made a bunch of alternate accounts or else got all of his friends to go in pop his Whatever myspace page up and then systematically pop down Anything that is in the same genre or could compete with him in any way, huh?
Speaker 1: Now, why would someone do that?
Speaker 0: It is clearly unethical.
Speaker 1: It's clearly a bad thing to do.
Speaker 1: You're obviously trying to game a system specifically for your own profit And you're trying to resist the natural tendency of things that are actually good coming to the top.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think what it is is people feel that you know They have something good to share and if it doesn't show up at the top of dig or it doesn't get posted to Slashdot or Fark then no one will ever see it.
Speaker 0: It'll stay hidden from the world, you know, they're trying to manufacture the spontaneous and random popularity of things like Numa Numa and All your base and You're really out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean Numa Numa was just a guy who thought he'd do something funny and he became famous for it.
Speaker 1: The million people Star Wars kid who's yes Star Wars kid was awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah Who sit there and try to do something like that and make themselves internet popular Are doomed to fail because that sort of thing is transparent and shitty Even if it isn't transparent like no one can tell that.
Speaker 0: let's say you no one can tell that you're promoting yourself But you're doing it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, right the fact that you are promoting yourself, even if no one knows it Immediately means that it's you're not gonna be able to manufacture the spontaneous popularity.
Speaker 0: It's the spot.
Speaker 0: It's the completely random discovery of things over time by a bunch of people that makes those things so crazy.
Speaker 0: You know if you you can't try to make that it does.
Speaker 0: it's not possible.
Speaker 0: If it's if there's any effort involved at all, it's sort of like spoils the soup, you know It's like you make a soup.
Speaker 0: We need water and chicken and maybe put effort into it.
Speaker 0: now all of a sudden no one likes anymore because you can tell when There's effort there.
Speaker 0: It's like aha someone tried to make this popular and not holy crap.
Speaker 0: It's some random crazy thing to me.
Speaker 1: It just comes down to the methods you use and your rationale behind it.
Speaker 1: I mean promoting yourself even.
Speaker 1: I mean not shadily obviously But if you buy ads or you put out flyers or you do anything to you know, hey check it out.
Speaker 1: I exist That's cool.
Speaker 1: The moment you go beyond that and actively try to put yourself like insinuate yourself into things where you probably don't belong or Actively try to get people to demote or put down anything that competes with you at all.
Speaker 1: That's really shady You know.
Speaker 0: you look at it.
Speaker 0: It's sort of like Advertising is something that people sell.
Speaker 0: and while we buy, you know, who knows what we think of advertising?
Speaker 1: Well people know exactly what we think of advertising.
Speaker 0: Yeah But someone trying to do this is sort of like trying to steal free advertising, you know It's like dig.
Speaker 0: dig sells ads on dig.
Speaker 0: All right, but dig also has content which happens to be links to other things.
Speaker 1: So how many people post a million links to Lou Rockwell?
Speaker 1: calm?
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, so trying to artificially get yourself to the top of dig is trying to like sneak an Advertisement into the content section of dig.
Speaker 0: you're essentially stealing Advertising from dig.
Speaker 1: now, I don't care about that because advertising is a pretty piss-poor business model.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, what I can?
Speaker 1: I just care that people who do this stuff always seem to do it really transparently and shittily.
Speaker 1: You'd think that if they were trying to do this They'd be more like rolling peak Bailey and do it in a somewhat subtle way.
Speaker 0: rolling peak Bailey isn't subtle.
Speaker 1: He was for a long time for a little bit till people caught on.
Speaker 0: Yeah I think the thing that bothers me the most is this search engine optimization.
Speaker 1: God if you ever Contract the services of a search engine optimization person or you ever think that that's an important thing to do or you ever offer a Service like that to paraphrase a semi-famous person kill yourself.
Speaker 1: Good God Do I not respect what you do for a living just so people know.
Speaker 0: in case you don't know search engine optimization is Basically, I don't know what to call it.
Speaker 0: But there are people who really really really want their website to show up on like the front page of Google.
Speaker 0: So let's say your website about anime and you want it to be so that when someone searches for anime on Google or Yahoo or MSN or wherever that on the front page is a link to your site.
Speaker 0: You really want that to be the case because that way Supposedly a lot of people visit you when they want to look at anime.
Speaker 0: Well, your site isn't popular and no one cares about it.
Speaker 0: It's a brand new website and it doesn't show up on the first page.
Speaker 0: when you search for anime shows up I'm like, oh the tenth page the eleventh page.
Speaker 1: So what are these SEO people try to do?
Speaker 1: They try to game the search engine by fucking with your site in order to make your site Artificially have a higher ranking than it actually deserves.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they try to figure out, you know How does the search engine determine what links are on the front page and what links are on the 11th page?
Speaker 0: Then they change their site and they change other websites and they do everything they possibly can To get their website to be on the front page instead of the 11th page.
Speaker 0: now the thing is the way especially Google.
Speaker 0: the way Google determines who goes on the front page is An algorithm that is based on what's useful It actually can.
Speaker 0: you know?
Speaker 0: over time they've learned to develop a method that says ah That is actually a really good site for anime and that is not.
Speaker 1: in fact If you use one of these BS SEO companies you pay them money.
Speaker 1: They might make your site go up in Google for a while but Google catches on real quick and your site will probably in the long run be punished and Put down further than it normally would have because they realize you were trying to game them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and not only that but while you might you know get some popularity for yourself.
Speaker 0: if you consider a popularity You'll probably just get visits from people who will then leave because your site is crappy.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean we get on geek nights and keep in mind that we've never even Cared about what kind of things.
Speaker 1: search engine.
Speaker 0: we have never made a change to our website Which has taken search engine position into consideration.
Speaker 0: We changed the website for every pretty much every other reason.
Speaker 1: but search engine optimization our forums alone get hit by hit from people on Google about once every five minutes 24/7.
Speaker 0: the trick to getting lots of it from search engines is to make a legitimate website with good content.
Speaker 0: if you're trying to if You need to optimize your site to get it to show up higher in search engines.
Speaker 0: It's probably a crappy site.
Speaker 0: That's why it's showing up low.
Speaker 0: It's an unuseful crappy site and if you're trying to make it go up in search engines you successfully do so.
Speaker 0: You're actually ruining the search engine and making it less useful by filling it with crap And putting the actual good sites down lower.
Speaker 1: Yeah Try making a nice site that maybe Wikipedia will legitimately link to you thus boosting your pan drag.
Speaker 1: Don't go into Wikipedia make a BS article link it to you and then hope no one deletes it.
Speaker 0: If you want people to come visit your site have compelling content that people will eventually catch on to and care about.
Speaker 1: I mean, I guess case in point I mean we recently started putting flyers out at cons and stuff for geek nights.
Speaker 1: But for the first I don't know five months of our existence we never advertised anywhere.
Speaker 0: Nope, not a place.
Speaker 1: We didn't even really tell a lot of people we were doing a podcast.
Speaker 1: We figured it would just spread by word of mouth and it did to Australia.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean look at all the popular websites right.
Speaker 0: look at see boing.
Speaker 0: boing is a huge blob dig slash dot far dig slash Not far.
Speaker 0: Do you think any of those those sites weren't always huge slash that used to be pretty small?
Speaker 0: Do you think that they did search engine optimization?
Speaker 0: No, no, they did not because they have such compelling content and great websites.
Speaker 0: That is not necessary.
Speaker 1: So I guess let's just go over a whole bunch of things and say whether let's talk about all the things that are Okay to do and all the things that are shady to do.
Speaker 1: All right, just so we kind of have a nice roundabout way to end this discussion.
Speaker 0: Okay paying for Google ads Perfectly, okay, that's nothing wrong with paying for it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean if you have crazy ads about mesothelioma you pay more.
Speaker 0: So it's a good system.
Speaker 1: Yeah Posting a link to your thing in the plugs area of a forum you frequent.
Speaker 0: Oh, it's in the plugs area.
Speaker 0: It's or the plugs thread.
Speaker 0: There's nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 0: That's where plugs are supposed to be which means I won't look at it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Making a new thread about the thing you're doing the project you're starting in a forum That is a part of a community of which you've been a member for a long time and have many friends in and are very active And you're a legitimate member.
Speaker 0: not you're not just there thinking about one day posting this link one day one day.
Speaker 0: Nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 1: Yeah All right.
Speaker 1: Going to the Otacon forums and posting a thread as your first post about the new anime review site you made Not okay, probably not so great.
Speaker 1: No, not posting that same link in three other parts of the Otacon forums.
Speaker 0: Not okay.
Speaker 1: Not only not okay, but they'll ban you.
Speaker 0: Yeah rightfully so.
Speaker 1: and delete your post Hopefully digging a story that is on your website.
Speaker 0: It's kind of it's technically okay.
Speaker 0: I say the chances of getting more digs might be lower if people notice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I hate to say it.
Speaker 1: It's one of those situations where it's perfectly okay, but it won't work.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean if if it's really good like let's say I you know I actually come up I make a video of a crazy Rube Goldberg machine.
Speaker 0: I made this the craziest one ever and I put it on YouTube and I dig my own Rube Goldberg machine and It's really that good.
Speaker 0: It's gonna get dug.
Speaker 0: But you know if it's not that good if it's just as good as the Rube Goldberg machine.
Speaker 0: They made the front page the other day and people notice that I dug it and they make the connection that it's my video.
Speaker 0: Then I'm gonna get less digs than the Rube Goldberg machine.
Speaker 0: last All right.
Speaker 1: So digging a story that is yours with a name that is not obviously yours Which I say is fine because the internet is basically anonymous and you shouldn't ever have to reveal who you are for any reason.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there's nothing wrong with that and you know, you can't.
Speaker 0: it's not really that bad.
Speaker 0: I mean, you're just basically getting a few.
Speaker 0: the number of digs you're gonna get back by doing that is insignificant.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah, it's pretty much gonna be the same deal, but you might as well.
Speaker 0: but here's what shady already hiring someone to dig up your story with a bunch of accounts or Making extra accounts and having them all dig your story Yeah, or setting up some sort of script that will create dig accounts and dig your stories.
Speaker 1: Telling all your friends to dig your story is not that shady.
Speaker 0: It's not that shady.
Speaker 1: It depends a lot on how you go about it.
Speaker 1: And I don't really want to go degree I can't really say how many friends you have But it's really just the way you go about it and the type of community you have.
Speaker 1: if your friends are smart And they'll only dig it if it's cool then it's probably okay.
Speaker 0: For example, someone recently asked me to go vote for you know They're their friends webcomic in some poll of like best webcomic of the week and I went there and I was gonna vote for it.
Speaker 0: You know whatever but there was a better webcomic there.
Speaker 0: So I voted for that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, wasn't that much better?
Speaker 0: wasn't that much better, but I can't not vote for penny arcade.
Speaker 1: It's sort of like this thing Maybe but then there's like podcast or webcomics out there who whenever like, you know They're one of those ranking sites like the top hundred whatever's this week.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the big the big thing is podcast alley Which is this website that lists podcast and I really think the only people who go to podcast alley or podcasters Yeah
Speaker 1: And it seems like the rankings there all they are is every Podcaster tells all their listeners to go to this site and vote for them.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't know what it is.
Speaker 0: Like I don't the only podcast.
Speaker 0: Well, no, I can't say the only one but many podcasts I listen to the podcasters will at the end or beginning of their shows say please vote for us on podcast alley.
Speaker 0: the way podcast Alley works is you go there you find the show you want to vote for.
Speaker 0: you type in your email address And then you you go and confirm the email and that show gets one vote and every month All the votes are erased and everyone has to vote again.
Speaker 1: now I hate to tell you all that about these sites because this has existed since the dawn of the Internet's when Where sites appeared and then top 100 where sites appeared?
Speaker 1: Basically, these sites are engineered to get you to direct all of your listeners to their site on a regular basis Where they will see ads and generate money for this site.
Speaker 1: These sites don't give one flying shit about you.
Speaker 1: They're just trying to get you to direct your listeners toward them if the scant Hope that they will somehow in return generate traffic for you When in fact the majority of the people going to these sites go there only to vote for the thing that told them to vote For them.
Speaker 1: Yep, but podcast alley isn't a site full of ads but podcast alley is not that bad But I still generally dislike the idea of it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't really see the use.
Speaker 0: I mean Podcasts just seem to have this idea that if they get enough votes that they show up in a high ranking on podcast alley That that will somehow bring them a giant pile of listeners in attention, you know, and I just.
Speaker 0: it might be true But I don't really care.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna spend every pot at the end of every podcast telling you all to vote for us in some stupid site and waste Your time especially having to tell you to keep doing it on a regular basis every month.
Speaker 0: go vote for us.
Speaker 0: Screw that shit.
Speaker 0: Why should you have to go?
Speaker 0: it's a free show, you know.
Speaker 0: Why should I go and tell you to go do work for us?
Speaker 0: That doesn't actually get us anything.
Speaker 0: It was like go go my listeners go twiddle some bits somewhere.
Speaker 0: do my bidding.
Speaker 0: Haha, you watch shows on TV.
Speaker 0: They never tell you to go and you know go vote for us on some site.
Speaker 0: You don't do that shit.
Speaker 0: It's bullshit.
Speaker 1: I guess all we're really trying to say I mean, we've gotten kind of rambly all over the place.
Speaker 1: We didn't really structure our discussion at all.
Speaker 1: We kind of got off on a couple of rants.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we did.
Speaker 0: I guess that's what's gonna happen If we don't sit down and make an outline of what we're gonna say.
Speaker 1: Except we never need to do that for Tuesdays Wednesdays or Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just those shows are easier.
Speaker 0: What do you want?
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, I'm also kind of distracted because I really want to go downstairs and get a Klondike bar.
Speaker 1: But I want to finish the show first.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I've been thinking Klondike bar Klondike bar for the last eight minutes at least.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking about going to read something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I got I get your dream.
Speaker 1: Yeah But I guess the point here is very simply.
Speaker 1: whenever you are going to promote yourself on the internet Before you do whatever you're gonna do just think for a second.
Speaker 1: Does this feel wrong or shady?
Speaker 1: if the answer is no go right ahead.
Speaker 1: if you're not sure Well go to our forums and ask us.
Speaker 1: we'll tell you.
Speaker 0: And the best way to promote yourself on the internet is to do awesome things.
Speaker 0: Yes Believe you do something, you know and you put it on the internet and it's not getting visited as much as you would like.
Speaker 0: Don't try to attract more attention to it.
Speaker 1: Try to do something better because if you do something really worthwhile on the internet 95% of the time people will find it on their own Eventually.
Speaker 1: because if you're makes if you make something that is good that people want and people actually want it They're looking for it and they'll eventually find your thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if your thing sucks don't go around messing up sites like dig or delicious popular.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't tell all your friends to pop your thing and then flop everyone else's thing Brody.
Speaker 0: Yeah, just let it be and if your stuff is cool People will find it.
Speaker 1: if you pop it they will come.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Just one more example to because I got a complaint about this kid.
Speaker 0: There's a kid on YouTube and he makes I guess his own animated videos of some sort.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure cuz I'd never watched his shit because I don't like him and He's apparently complaining on YouTube that in the animation category All you see is Naruto Naruto Naruto Naruto Naruto and you don't see his thing.
Speaker 0: it doesn't show up and he somehow thinks that he has a right to show up and Naruto shouldn't be there and That it's not fair that he has to compete with Naruto.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I had to say it kid.
Speaker 1: But if your thing was actually that awesome, you wouldn't be competing with Naruto.
Speaker 0: The reason the reason that no one's watching your animations is not because you know They go to the page and all they see is Naruto and they don't think.
Speaker 0: you know They don't find your animation somewhere and look at it or whatever.
Speaker 0: If your thing was really cool Someone would dig it and it would get dug up.
Speaker 0: Hey or something would happen and people would notice it, you know I mean, you don't see all those episodes of Naruto getting a bajillion hits.
Speaker 0: They're just a lot of uploads there.
Speaker 0: that animation page on YouTube doesn't have like a million visitors who are just looking for your stuff.
Speaker 0: It's how shit goes.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're probably all looking for Naruto.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: So so even if your thing showed up number one, they'll skip past it to number two Which is Naruto.
Speaker 1: character number five kick in and our two character number eight in the face.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and if you know and this kid has been complaining that they should make a separate category for original Animations as opposed you
Speaker 1: know what on podcast alley They need a category for podcast done by two 20-somethings in downstate, New York about geekery that air four nights a week.
Speaker 1: I Mean what kind of bullshit is it that they don't have this category?
Speaker 0: It's not fair I know but even if they did have this category for this guy people are you know?
Speaker 0: Zach's somehow gonna make his stuff better or more popular?
Speaker 0: make more people like it.
Speaker 0: just cuz it's.
Speaker 0: it's gotta.
Speaker 1: if I had any Non laziness left in my body tonight.
Speaker 1: I'd go find that Arnold Schwarzenegger soundboard and I'd end the show with stop whining Stop whining.
Speaker 1: Yeah This has been geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: we say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.