Speaker 1: It's Wednesday December 6th.
Speaker 0: I'm rim and I'm Scott and this is geek notes.
Speaker 1: tonight We begin a very long and in-depth series on the proper care and feeding of anime clubs.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Life is good.
Speaker 1: I just finished a gigantic vanilla ice cream and orange juice smoothie that I made not moments ago.
Speaker 0: Let's not really a smoothie if it doesn't have like yogurt and stuff, right?
Speaker 1: I consider a smoothie to be pretty much any whipped thing.
Speaker 1: That isn't a milkshake.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: it's a little less viscous than a milkshake and you drink it through a straw.
Speaker 1: It's a smoothie.
Speaker 0: so I don't know.
Speaker 0: cuz If you just combine orange juice and ice cream It's not really a milkshake.
Speaker 0: because to make a milkshake you need you need a ice cream and milk and then you know That's a.
Speaker 1: actually when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: I used to make milkshakes, but I never used milk.
Speaker 1: I pretty much just use ice cream and vanilla extract.
Speaker 1: Maybe I'd use like a teaspoon of milk.
Speaker 0: Hmm stuff call.
Speaker 0: we got to go figure out exactly the difference between like a smoothie a milkshake What all the ice all kinds of different?
Speaker 1: I think a more important thing would be to figure out whether or not cheesecake is a chip as a cake or a pie or something else entirely.
Speaker 0: It's tough call not really.
Speaker 1: no, it's not it is not at all.
Speaker 1: We had that argument to completion years and years ago, I forget which side I was on.
Speaker 1: Well, then I guess I win.
Speaker 0: Okay, what side were you on?
Speaker 1: doesn't matter?
Speaker 0: Okay, then are you sure you weren't on the same side as me?
Speaker 1: I'm absolutely sure cuz I remember arguing with you about it.
Speaker 0: I probably just picked the other side for fun.
Speaker 0: Oh Really?
Speaker 0: I don't remember.
Speaker 0: I don't really care.
Speaker 0: either way cuz you know what.
Speaker 0: whether you call it cake or pie it tastes the awesome.
Speaker 1: So anyway in response to the other day when I used a slightly different thing of the day music I'm surprised so many people brought it up because you see I was messing around with that keyboard.
Speaker 1: So I decided oh I'll record some stupid bit and throw it in the show to make fun of me messing around with the keyboard.
Speaker 1: and I've gotten more emails and feedback of people saying how much they liked it or how they want more music like that in the show.
Speaker 1: I made that as a joke in my when I was bored.
Speaker 1: That's not gonna be the thing of the day music ever.
Speaker 1: I don't even have the wav file anymore.
Speaker 0: and The scarier part is that rim just basically banging on the keyboard is somehow sounds good to people Like what the hell?
Speaker 1: Well, I bang on the keyboard all the time.
Speaker 1: What do you want?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know but it's not good.
Speaker 1: I mean, well, I don't know what your standard is gov good is?
Speaker 1: I mean you have kind of weird tastes and just about everything.
Speaker 0: I think it's more like relatively speaking like you could not be a keyboardist for even like well Maybe the most garages of bands you could be the keyboardist, but if entertainment system needed a keyboardist I could do it.
Speaker 0: I could also be their drummer perhaps, but I don't think you.
Speaker 0: you're in a very low level of keyboarding talent Compared to.
Speaker 1: here's the thing if you take the average person in the world.
Speaker 0: I'm well above average But compared to all the keyboardists in the world that you are down near the bottom.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, but I'm still pretty good according to our listeners.
Speaker 0: You know what that tells us.
Speaker 0: your listeners don't know much about keyboarding.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Speaking of listener feedback two people sent us odios and you know what odeo fucked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, odeo has never really been the most reliable useful or really in any way relevant or interesting Service to be perfectly honest yeah, and now that we finally decide to use them they don't work.
Speaker 0: But we've been using them It's just.
Speaker 0: no one actually sent us anything and in fact people did send us a couple things in the past and it did work.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna.
Speaker 0: I emailed odeo, and I'm like hey fix it fix it fix it fix it fix it fix it
Speaker 1: fix it fix it
Speaker 0: and we'll see if they fix it or not, but I Think if it's not fixed pretty soon And I'm gonna try testing it to see if I can make it work and it's gonna send ourselves an odeo.
Speaker 0: And you know try different things.
Speaker 0: if I can't make it work I'm just gonna give odeo the big double deuce and We'll make fun of them and tell everyone never to use them again, and you can just send mp3s attached to emails yep And also in the the mini contest we're having.
Speaker 1: We said we wanted it to be 30 seconds long.
Speaker 0: Yeah The two odios that we got that we were unable to listen to because odeo sucks.
Speaker 0: one of them was 11 minutes long and one of them was 5 minutes long.
Speaker 0: That's a lot more than 30 seconds.
Speaker 1: Are you sure they weren't 11 in 5 seconds?
Speaker 0: I'm sure absolutely sure.
Speaker 0: No, oh, okay, but I'm estimating to the nearest minute.
Speaker 0: Either way much too long people.
Speaker 1: yeah, no matter you I guess I'll put it this way in order for us to play an 11 minute Audio that would have to be some fucking speech.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean look at it.
Speaker 0: We spend maybe 20 minutes on the show before the things of the day and then like 30 or 40 minutes after that 11 minutes you're getting like a fifth or a sixth of the show.
Speaker 0: just to yourself Even five minutes you're getting like one dozen of the show.
Speaker 1: So I guess what I'm gonna do is for all the long odios we get I'll listen to him cut him down into something that might Not exactly represent what you were trying to say and play that.
Speaker 0: yeah, and you can't complain.
Speaker 1: No one can complain anyway.
Speaker 0: I know but if you we like voice feedback, but if it's too long It's not gonna get played of course.
Speaker 1: now everyone's thinking well.
Speaker 1: I'll just give geek nights the double-deuce.
Speaker 1: They want audio feedback, but they don't want it to be too long, but now audio doesn't work.
Speaker 1: Fuck it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 1: Yeah anyway in the news it being anime day I would just like to note that for kids who among other licenses had one piece has decided to stop Translating it and be done with it.
Speaker 1: They have aired 78 of the 104 episodes they had and that's the end of it.
Speaker 1: I imagine that one piece wasn't really doing so well in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Well the part of the problem is one they were not mark.
Speaker 0: one piece is something that Was only really popular among the anime crowd.
Speaker 1: yeah, and even then a small subset of the anime It is.
Speaker 0: it is not like a. I mean It's a big show in terms of its size especially in Japan.
Speaker 0: It's crazy popular, and it's a lot of stuff.
Speaker 0: It is a lot of episodes.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of movies as a lot of manga.
Speaker 0: one piece is a lot of stuff But it's not really popular enough to sell all that stuff.
Speaker 0: to make matters worse They brought it over to the u.s.
Speaker 0: And tried to make it a kids show and not complete with animation with the editing required.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they edited the hell out of it And they put it on you know like Saturday morning cartoons for kids or get home from school cartoons for kids Instead of you know making it a show for anime fans.
Speaker 0: That is on DVDs unedited with subtitles, and we all buy it and we're all happy.
Speaker 1: yep I mean I just think to back to the cons for the last several years where there would be More one piece stuff than anything else.
Speaker 1: one piece stuff was everywhere and still a lot of it out there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I don't see a lot of people buying it and I every year I've seen the prices on the big one piece plushies going down.
Speaker 0: yep I mean I was reading the one piece manga and I can already tell like I watched the first few episodes of one piece back In the day, and I kind of liked it because it was party.
Speaker 0: But then I knew that it was gonna turn into like some fighting things.
Speaker 0: so I got the manga And it was okay.
Speaker 0: even if it was a little childish It was still funny and interesting.
Speaker 0: But then it reached this stretch of like three or four volumes of manga.
Speaker 0: that where it went nowhere And it was like one fight, and I'm like all right.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: I'm done ordering this.
Speaker 0: I'm done with one piece.
Speaker 1: Why did you keep reading even that long?
Speaker 1: I dropped one piece after the first volume because I knew exactly where it was going and I already gotten everything out of it I ever would.
Speaker 0: well anyway.
Speaker 0: I stopped ordering it and the last volume that I received right Was a good was a volume where it stopped the fight and got back to the stuff that makes one piece not suck.
Speaker 0: So I think I'm gonna like go to the store and read it now And then I can pick it up and say oh this whole volume is one fight.
Speaker 0: I'll just put it back on the shelf, and if it's a good volume.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll buy it and bring it home.
Speaker 0: Maybe I'll just read it in the store.
Speaker 0: who knows?
Speaker 1: see I don't understand how when it comes to anime You'll drop an anime like a brick in in less than 10 seconds.
Speaker 1: if you don't think you like it yet You'll continue to read one piece or initial D long after they've Stopped being good.
Speaker 0: initial D. Still good.
Speaker 0: It's not second of all.
Speaker 1: no It's not.
Speaker 0: initial part of the reason is that I'm ordering these things two months in advance now.
Speaker 0: So if it sucks I usually end up getting all right.
Speaker 1: all right.
Speaker 1: I could predict that the rest of fourth stage was gonna suck.
Speaker 1: from the beginning They ran out of ways to go with initial D.
Speaker 0: There's.
Speaker 0: no I thought that but the manga it keeps going in ways.
Speaker 1: What ways?
Speaker 1: oh he wins this race by?
Speaker 1: Balancing his tires over a gap.
Speaker 1: Oh he wins this race by fucking teleporting to the bottom.
Speaker 1: awesome The show pretty much the initial D ended for me at the end of the first season.
Speaker 1: Yeah with the possible exception is definitely better.
Speaker 0: I will agree.
Speaker 0: however I still enjoy.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna say it's like top quality shit, but it's still good.
Speaker 1: It's like the difference between chocolate and shit.
Speaker 0: no But that is an initial D reference.
Speaker 1: so yes from what you know what from the first season.
Speaker 1: Yep anyway Yeah, so you got some anime related news.
Speaker 0: I hear it's not really so much in news as it is.
Speaker 0: Hey look at this article about anime.
Speaker 0: There's an article on reason calm Called when piracy becomes promotion.
Speaker 0: how unauthorized copying made Japanese animation profitable in the United States.
Speaker 0: the article is by Henry Jenkins Who is the director of the MIT comparative media studies program and author of convergence culture?
Speaker 0: Blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: he would like to acknowledge the help of MIT alum Sean Leonard.
Speaker 0: that tells me that Sean Leonard did all the work.
Speaker 0: Anyway I'm gonna sum up this article by just reading to you the last two sentences.
Speaker 0: Many media companies in the u.s.
Speaker 0: Would have regarded all this underground circulation as piracy and shut it down before it reached critical mass.
Speaker 0: Instead we have moved from a world where a speed racer Operated on the fringes to one where Pokemon is better known in the United States than many of its American counterparts.
Speaker 0: Yep, here's a smart guy telling you that fan subbing is the awesome and Japanese people are smart and American people are stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, though.
Speaker 1: I still have a lot of choice words for the Japanese animation companies.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the problem is they just don't understand that they can't charge that much money for To sell the licenses in America.
Speaker 0: and if they're pissed off that someone else is gonna Sell the shows in America for more money than they're paying the licenses for than the Japanese companies should just release the anime here themselves.
Speaker 0: And you know get rid of people like the middleman ADV and such.
Speaker 1: yeah, though I don't think they quite understand the American market though.
Speaker 1: I don't think the American companies quite understand the American.
Speaker 0: I don't think the Japanese people understand the Japanese market.
Speaker 0: sell your DVDs for like a hajillion dollars.
Speaker 1: No They understand it perfectly well because they make a lot of money and the only threat to that is Re-importation in American fan subs now.
Speaker 0: I still really think that if someone released DVDs in Japan.
Speaker 0: Like let's say I was an anime company and I made an anime in Japan and it was on TV.
Speaker 0: And then I came out with the DVDs.
Speaker 0: if I put those DVDs out in slim cases and boxes at American DVD prices I'm pretty sure I would make more money than the Japanese companies.
Speaker 0: that they're $40,000 collector things.
Speaker 1: you know what I would do.
Speaker 1: first I'd release the fanboy early copies for the crazy amount of money because they'll buy it no matter what and As soon as sales drop below a predefined threshold.
Speaker 1: I will immediately Release the cheaper versions the thin the thin cases.
Speaker 1: I really as soon as sales of those start dropping off I'll release the super double bonus box that comes with a goodie because the fan buys will all buy that again.
Speaker 0: And I would also if I was a Japanese company is I would hire a translator slap some English subtitles on there And send it over to the US like when the Japanese DVD comes out the American DVD comes out Simultaneously from my company directly.
Speaker 1: now once none of those middleman business I would hire the fan subbers to do it because they're really good at what they do really quick.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah We should probably do a whole show on that?
Speaker 0: Yeah, probably that the thing is you know and you think about a show like one piece.
Speaker 0: That's perfect for this kind of plan because selling one piece on DVDs.
Speaker 0: You know there's a whole lot of episodes There's not a whole lot of fans But you want to make money because you spent money to make one piece or you spent money to get the license.
Speaker 0: So what do you do?
Speaker 0: you slap a whole bunch of episodes on as few DVDs as possible and sell them as cheaply as possible And that's how you make the big money's with one piece.
Speaker 1: Maybe maybe not because a lot at least in my eyes any show that isn't grade a that I want to own and show to People forever.
Speaker 1: it would have to be so amazingly cheap for me to buy it when I could just watch it on Netflix for Practically nothing instead.
Speaker 0: yeah, but then you would Netflix it which means Netflix buys it.
Speaker 1: yeah But here's the thing Netflix buys far fewer copies of any given anime than the number of people who watch that copy.
Speaker 1: You got to admit though that if one piece was ten episodes a disc for If I wouldn't go anywhere near that show cuz I know where that show goes you would work.
Speaker 0: But imagine what it would sell to normal people's.
Speaker 0: I don't know if it was unedited and properly done.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, there was unedited knowledge.
Speaker 1: But even then I don't think you'd make as much money as the people in Japan make by selling it for a lot of money.
Speaker 0: That's just because it's more popular in Japan.
Speaker 0: I think you know when you have a lot of stuff, and it's not very popular you have to sell it.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well I agree with you in that one piece is already pretty much failed over here And they have the license until it expires.
Speaker 1: they already paid for the license as far as we know.
Speaker 1: I mean for all we know.
Speaker 1: Maybe the license is weird, but you'd think they would do whatever they could to recoup their losses And it doesn't cost too much to print up pieces of plastic.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if they have even if they haven't made a profit yet They're either gonna lose more money, or they could just flood the market with super cheap one piece DVDs.
Speaker 1: one It'll sabotage anyone who wants the license in the future, and maybe they could negotiate a better deal if they ever wanted to pick it up again.
Speaker 1: And two they would at least recoup their losses.
Speaker 0: well that is a good thought though It's like if you flood the market now Maybe you can make more money by selling the license to someone else.
Speaker 0: Then you can buy.
Speaker 0: you know selling a whole bunch of DVDs now.
Speaker 1: Or maybe if you're evil threaten the Japanese company and say we have this license pony up reduce the cost something some sort of extortion.
Speaker 1: or We're going to sell one piece a dollar a disc.
Speaker 0: I think the license like prevents you from doing.
Speaker 1: see I was about to ask I wonder what provisions the licenses have for minimum sale prices or Levels of promotion or number of episodes per set or per disc.
Speaker 0: who knows it's all crazy.
Speaker 1: I wish the anime industry would open up.
Speaker 1: I know anime world orders talked about this time and time again.
Speaker 1: Why all the secrecy?
Speaker 1: they're not gaining anything from us not knowing?
Speaker 0: well That's something I gotta have a problem with most companies is what does any company have to gain for being secret besides pissing off?
Speaker 0: customers and Covering up corruption?
Speaker 1: well, no I can see them keeping you know Proprietary trade secret.
Speaker 1: oh yeah, yeah, but even more like production schedules or upcoming products that might not be made Because people get super pissed if they hear about a product that you know.
Speaker 1: Oh Sony's working on the blah blah blah And then the blah blah blah never comes because Sony while they were working on it realized it was a bad idea and canceled it.
Speaker 1: But the fanboys heard about it.
Speaker 1: now they wanted anyway.
Speaker 0: Yes But on the whole companies have more to gain from being open and most companies are far more closed than they need to be now.
Speaker 1: I'll agree with you on that especially the anime industry.
Speaker 1: This is not rocket science.
Speaker 0: the other thing is you don't have to make a press release about everything You know.
Speaker 0: you don't to be that.
Speaker 0: It's just that if someone asks Tell them you know and then only made.
Speaker 0: only the really really enthusiastic people are gonna even pay attention to that.
Speaker 0: So I mean if you let some nerd on the internet know about your new gadget You're making you know maybe a few people here, and there will go.
Speaker 1: But then again I realized something.
Speaker 1: look at all the interviews you see with anime Company people at cons because that's where most of these interviews happen.
Speaker 1: No one even asks the hard-hitting questions and at a con the only questions you get are the stupid lame You gonna get blah show?
Speaker 1: or when is episode blog gonna come out?
Speaker 0: well You know the one quite.
Speaker 0: I had one hard-hitting question for a TV at Otacon, and that was what the fuck happened to your manga and Still don't have a real complete answer.
Speaker 0: They were like yeah, it's coming back.
Speaker 0: Yeah something Yeah, it's like why don't you tell me you know yeah?
Speaker 0: We did this in this and that screwed us over, and this is what we're doing right now And this is the person working on it, and this is where we're at.
Speaker 0: and that way you know I go.
Speaker 0: oh instead of leaving me in the dark like
Speaker 1: Maybe we should add some of these smaller cons Show up with our equipment and do our stuff like we always do and then if we run into any anime industry people Corner them and ask the hard-hitting questions, and if they answer we win.
Speaker 1: if they don't answer we still win.
Speaker 1: well They they usually say we cannot confirm or deny blah blah And then I'll say why and I'll be a complete jerk until I get the information I want or I have proof that they're dodging the issue.
Speaker 1: hoo-hah That's the geek night's away Things of the day.
Speaker 1: we've got double Asian action today.
Speaker 0: Oh No, it's those crazy Asians.
Speaker 0: What do they come up with next yep?
Speaker 1: We have uncovered the vast Asian conspiracy, and we've discovered a technique that is unknown to the West Alright, so who wants to go first.
Speaker 0: I guess you can okay.
Speaker 0: I found this video And it said behold the Asian squat.
Speaker 0: and of course the first thing I thought of were those Asian squat toilets, so I watched it You know and to learn how to use a squat toilet even though I kind of knew how already.
Speaker 0: and then I realized This is not a video about the squat toilet.
Speaker 0: This is a video about just Squatting.
Speaker 0: and I watched the video and I saw.
Speaker 0: and the first thing you see in the video is this Asian guy looking all cool With the sunglasses and these squats and you go yep, that's the way Asian people squat.
Speaker 0: I can see it right there You know so typical I've seen it in a million places before and you watch it some more.
Speaker 0: and they say Look at this Western guy squat, and you go wow.
Speaker 0: and then they actually point out the difference, and it's like yeah, it's true.
Speaker 0: The thing is I try I realized because they it's pretty much plain as day that the Asian squat is superior in many ways But I can't do it.
Speaker 0: I like fell over.
Speaker 1: It was kind of sad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like the Asian squat is not easy to do.
Speaker 0: the difference is Asian people.
Speaker 0: when they squat they put their heels on the ground and they shift.
Speaker 0: you know their their knees aren't as far forward So their weight most of their weight goes straight down onto their entire foot.
Speaker 1: It's kind of like they're sitting on their legs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Tried to do it, and I just couldn't get all my weight to go Evenly distribute it across both feet like it was either like on the insides of my feet or the Outsides or the front or the back on the heel.
Speaker 0: I couldn't get it.
Speaker 0: even so no matter what I did I was like gonna fall over in one direction or another or it hurt part of my foot.
Speaker 1: So you know I actually had no trouble doing it.
Speaker 1: I could just get down I could sit that way for a while,
Speaker 0: but
Speaker 1: for whatever reason when I sit like that it's uncomfortable because the muscles in my thigh and the muscles in my calf kind of grind up against each other and It feels like I'm crushing the muscles when I sit like that and it actually kind of hurts.
Speaker 1: Yes, so And then I realized I could do it if I shifted my legs to the left and right like outward But that just put all the stress on my knees instead.
Speaker 1: that was not a good idea.
Speaker 0: That's not a good idea at all.
Speaker 0: So it's like I did exactly what the video said trying different amounts of spreading my legs apart and trying different amounts different angles of foot positioning.
Speaker 0: and I don't know the the Western squat.
Speaker 0: while it does have the deficiencies that they state in the video It still works better for me than any of those Asian squats.
Speaker 1: Yeah I just remember Emily used to always tell me it like the the Yankees squat like the way Like you can see a punk punk kid in Japan.
Speaker 1: He's kind of squatting outside his store.
Speaker 1: They laugh about like yeah It's the Yankees squat Uh-huh, and it was it's kind of I remember she showed is the kind of different from the way they squatted.
Speaker 1: I'd show it to you right now, but I don't want to move the microphone or anything.
Speaker 0: Yes I want all the listeners watch this video and try to do the.
Speaker 0: if you're Asian try to do the Western squat And if you're not Asian try to do the Asian squat and give us feedback.
Speaker 1: We really want to know your thoughts feelings and experiences and we will talk about them next week.
Speaker 0: We might have to come up with some sort of combined super squat of sorts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, hey say we.
Speaker 1: if we do this, right?
Speaker 1: We might come up with the superior squat for the future generations of America and Japan.
Speaker 0: I have a feeling that the superior squat is number one.
Speaker 0: have a body Conducive to what the Asian squat and do the Asian squat properly.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Maybe that the actual answer is to become a great kungfu master and just sit like there's a chair there when there isn't a chair.
Speaker 0: That's also a good plan.
Speaker 1: Anyway, speaking of Emily.
Speaker 1: She sent me this video the other day and it's kind of the shaky cam.
Speaker 1: It looks like a guy's spying on two Japanese people - yeah - Japanese people eating in a restaurant and they're drinking wine they're using forks and knives and they're eating something and They go on to talk about how they've pulled a fast one over those thick Australians and the guy's like Yeah, so, you know this fish we get him to eat it raw What?
Speaker 1: no way.
Speaker 1: even better.
Speaker 1: We don't give him a fork and knife.
Speaker 1: What what do you give him?
Speaker 1: Just two sticks?
Speaker 1: We make him take their shoes off.
Speaker 1: we make him sit on the floor.
Speaker 1: It's obviously something that was filmed like for one of those variety shows as a comedy bit, but it's kind of funny.
Speaker 1: What can I say?
Speaker 1: No, I mean, did you ever wonder if like say you have a friend who's from a country?
Speaker 1: You don't know much about?
Speaker 1: and they tell you like oh it's customary to do blah and blah might be a little weird.
Speaker 1: And maybe you wonder are they making this up?
Speaker 1: just to mess with me?
Speaker 1: In old country you spit in face for happiness and in old country you spit in face for luck?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's quite an old joke.
Speaker 0: and you always wonder like if you're going to another country It's always good to study the customs there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, don't or you go I recommend or if you don't use Wikipedia and only Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: Yeah We should go on Wikipedia and insert like a strange custom into every weird country, huh?
Speaker 1: Maybe in terms of the squat if you guys are telling us about squats Tell us about a weird thing that we should add to Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: granted I won't do it because I edit Wikipedia for good.
Speaker 1: This is all Scott.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna do it either because mine won't be as funny as other people's.
Speaker 1: Well, maybe someone else should do it and Pick a country pick a weird custom.
Speaker 0: That's not true and add it to that country.
Speaker 0: But make sure it's good be best.
Speaker 0: It was something that sounds true and maybe you have a little bit of evidence for so won't get deleted.
Speaker 1: Even better even better.
Speaker 1: do it and then in the forums on geek knives and front row crew calm.
Speaker 1: Put a link to the article.
Speaker 1: you put it in and see if anyone can pick out without cheating what you added Before it gets deleted by someone else.
Speaker 1: if it does I mean the.
Speaker 1: I'll tell everyone a secret.
Speaker 1: the key to slipping bad stuff into Wikipedia is To do it to articles that people don't care about or to articles that don't have active dedicated maintainers.
Speaker 0: You've got to do this to the countries that no one cares about.
Speaker 1: The problem is a lot of cut small countries that are on there have like one guy from that country who watches it all the Time I was thinking more like Canada.
Speaker 1: You know I hear they play this game up there where they put metal blades on their feet and they run around on frozen ponds hitting a Big black rubber thing around with sticks.
Speaker 0: Yeah, sounds good.
Speaker 0: What kind of shit is that?
Speaker 0: Right maple leaves maple leaf leaves.
Speaker 1: so today is anime manga comics day and Last week we talked a bit about this and we also sent numerous emails to anime world order about it, but they have been Soliciting.
Speaker 0: just can't stop mentioning anime world order.
Speaker 0: Can you?
Speaker 1: well because I don't play promos anymore So I'm gonna.
Speaker 1: I periodically mention the shows I listen to and also they're the sole reason we decided to do this series of shows.
Speaker 1: well, actually they were the first reason and then Unrelated to that a bunch of people in the forums and via email have been asking us about this topic a lot lately.
Speaker 1: So we figured we'd kill a whole bunch of birds with one stone.
Speaker 1: If we if you asked us this question, and we didn't answer it yet.
Speaker 1: That's because we're answering it right now.
Speaker 1: You see they were talking about how anime clubs are kind of obsolete or aren't doing well anymore and people don't want to go to anime clubs to watch anime and Just like showing rooms have become almost completely Unusable and no one cares about them and anime cons.
Speaker 0: so too if anime clubs fallen You see way back in the day way back there was anime and dinosaurs and dinosaurs But no one in the United States could get anime because most of them did not speak Japanese Especially the people who would have liked anime.
Speaker 0: they could not speak Japanese.
Speaker 0: There are mostly small children.
Speaker 1: So the people who for whatever reason discovered this Japanese animation would get it somehow Usually difficulty raw and get groups of friends who also liked it and watch it.
Speaker 1: and the only way to see anime I mean there weren't even VCRs back then.
Speaker 1: you could only see anime by knowing someone who had it.
Speaker 1: So whoever had the most anime ran the local anime club and the anime club existed solely to show people anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and then came the VCR and the VCR made craziness happen.
Speaker 0: people You know They had.
Speaker 0: back in the day if you wanted a fan sub some guy somewhere would get laser discs from Japan.
Speaker 0: He would take his laser disc player and a machine called a genlock.
Speaker 0: I was wondering if you're gonna bring up the genlock genlock any good day and he would put subtitles using the genlock on to.
Speaker 0: He'd take the.
Speaker 0: he took the laser disc and the genlock and a blank videotape and he would then Basically put subtitles on the laser disc video and it would go on to the tape.
Speaker 0: and if you sent him a blank tape He would copy that onto the tape for you.
Speaker 1: Yep, some people you could send them the cost of a tape and then they would mail you one just to save, you know Shipping costs and no one was charging money for it.
Speaker 0: They weren't like pirates trying to make money like some of the Hong Kong bootleggers are today, you know They were trying to give out the fan subs.
Speaker 1: I actually got a lot of anime that way.
Speaker 1: I remember from V kill V kll who back in the day was my favorite fan subber.
Speaker 1: I got all of Sailor Moon first generations from the mat from the laser disc VHS's and I got the end of Evangelion though.
Speaker 1: I didn't know that Evangelion was a show.
Speaker 1: So I watched end of Ava like it was some movie and I remember thinking what the fuck is this?
Speaker 0: Yeah, what what?
Speaker 0: Why?
Speaker 1: so I showed it to everyone I knew and then I found out it was a show and they were all pissed at me For ruining it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, either way I didn't even know you could do fan subs that way till I get to college and by then there was no Point in doing it.
Speaker 0: The point is before digital fan subs came which was about 2001 2002 they started really going.
Speaker 0: they had him in 2000, but not so much.
Speaker 0: It was not easy to get anime.
Speaker 0: You could buy a very little bits of anime for lots of money in the store.
Speaker 0: You had to pay even more money if you wanted subtitles.
Speaker 1: Yeah, seriously, it would be like 30 bucks for a dubbed VHS and 35 for a subbed VHS and that thing had between three and four episodes on it to a lot of times.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe one movie was if you're lucky I mean early on.
Speaker 0: there's a lot mostly movies.
Speaker 0: just because it was so much money you if you're gonna pay that much you were Gonna get a whole movie.
Speaker 0: then it moved on to the TV shows.
Speaker 1: later when the prices started to go I bought the original Tenchi OAV disc for disc over the course of like seven months because I couldn't afford it.
Speaker 0: Well Anyway Because of all that situation we had to have an anime club which is a place where people got together and combined their anime so that People could see more anime than they could afford.
Speaker 0: I mean sci-fi channel was alright.
Speaker 0: But eventually, you know They weren't consistent enough to really serve your anime needs and they only showed a very limited amount of stuff and blockbuster was alright.
Speaker 0: But they only had a limited amount of stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they all blockbusters seem to have the same things.
Speaker 1: They all had like Armageddon wind of amnesia random stuff from Ava Do Megalopolis Vampire hunter d lotus war in the heroic legend of ours if it was on sci-fi channel is usually a blockbuster.
Speaker 1: Yep I remember I rented tank police a multiple times just cuz I couldn't find here.
Speaker 0: They had Akira.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they always had Akira Yep, and that was the way of things.
Speaker 1: So anime clubs pretty much just existed to show people anime and to popularize anime.
Speaker 1: Yes, like the the stated goal of many anime clubs or Japanese film cultural Whatever societies was to promote the acceptance and love of anime in North America.
Speaker 0: and mission accomplished Yep, they was accomplished a long time ago, but no one had a party.
Speaker 0: Where was this party when they you know, it's very rare to see like someone, you know trying to do something intentionally Accomplished the goal and then not be like we?
Speaker 1: Well, I think part of it was that it was kind of a slippery slope, I mean things came in gradually.
Speaker 1: It wasn't like one day Watching Akira in your basement was you were a loser and the next day Watching Akira in your basement with your friends.
Speaker 1: You were a winner.
Speaker 1: It was just kind of this gradual Boom of anime and it seemed to really culminated the whole Ava, Eska Bebop kind of era when anime really started getting crazy.
Speaker 1: Yep, at least in terms of adding new fans.
Speaker 0: So you had these anime clubs and they had succeeded in their goal.
Speaker 0: It was now easy for everyone to get anime.
Speaker 0: You could buy plenty of anime.
Speaker 0: You didn't need to go to club to get it.
Speaker 0: There were plenty of anime fans.
Speaker 0: anime animes on TV was on Cartoon Network.
Speaker 0: You could buy it in the store.
Speaker 0: media play had a giant anime section before it went out of business And it didn't go out of business because of its anime section either.
Speaker 1: now at this point Anime clubs seemed to diverged over time into three kind of distinct bodies As as anime fandom kind of changed.
Speaker 1: I mean on one hand you had the clubs that stayed the same and they just they showed anime and their primary focus was to show Anime to people.
Speaker 1: but because you could get all mainstream anime easily The way the club survived and still made people come to their showings was to show the stuff You couldn't get the stuff that wasn't released in the US the fan sub that your friend made the weird Asian movie.
Speaker 1: That was never.
Speaker 1: no one's even heard of that you got because a friend of yours taped it off Japanese TV.
Speaker 0: The really old but really cool show.
Speaker 0: I know there's a. there's this club of really old anime guys and They always show up at the club summit at Otakon like a few of them.
Speaker 1: They're awesome guys.
Speaker 1: We talked to him ever.
Speaker 0: there are awesome guys Like.
Speaker 0: I've seen them there for like three or four years in a row But I never actually talked to them that much.
Speaker 0: But I know that they're these old guys and they have an anime club and they just watch ancient anime wicked ancient.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you want to know how think this air of eight man after was an animated movie that I saw a long long time ago and I really liked and it's kind of old school for someone like me.
Speaker 1: they Considered eight man after to be the newest of new school because they used to be fans of eight man.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Tobor the eighth man Tobor Robot get it and that's one of the newer anime that those guys watch.
Speaker 1: But they're awesome dudes.
Speaker 1: I mean they they have kept it real.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So now you have this problem is that people like their anime clubs.
Speaker 0: they have clubs.
Speaker 0: They want to keep these clubs because they're fun, but people aren't going to the clubs because there's no need.
Speaker 1: Well, I said the three kind like the three ways clubs diverged at this point and they all stayed successful.
Speaker 1: I mean the second way was some clubs moved into running conventions instead of having clubs.
Speaker 1: and the third way the way we're gonna talk About today mostly was the clubs that transformed into social clubs that were centered around As opposed to anime clubs that included social elements.
Speaker 0: Well, there are the clubs that refuse to transform.
Speaker 1: Oh, yes, but they died back then.
Speaker 0: Yeah, or some of them are still around and but they they're still dying.
Speaker 1: Yeah Though I'd say that most of those clubs Transformed into the first kind the ones that survived by showing the stuff people couldn't get and that was fine.
Speaker 1: They still serve that purpose.
Speaker 1: then came fan subs on the internet followed by YouTube and Google video Followed by bit torrent followed by huge conventions followed by DVDs in the stores followed by deep discount DVD followed by pod.
Speaker 1: I mean now there's nothing obscure.
Speaker 1: if something exists in Japan and anyone finds it amusing.
Speaker 1: It's on the internet Immediately and everyone downloads it and watches it.
Speaker 1: and if you go to a con and they try to show it have the audience says What.
Speaker 1: I saw that a month ago.
Speaker 1: What the fuck's wrong with you.
Speaker 1: Yep All right, so now that first kind of club is in the same situation they were when anime exploded.
Speaker 1: they're losing members.
Speaker 1: No one comes to their showings anymore.
Speaker 1: they don't know why they think that people don't want to come to showings anymore.
Speaker 1: and We're gonna do a whole series from this point on Various weeks on how anime clubs have to be run to be successful how to run an anime club I maintain an anime club how to start an anime club how to promote anime.
Speaker 1: all that stuff all rolled into one.
Speaker 0: But the first thing is because the old goal of anime clubs has been accomplished.
Speaker 0: if you have an anime club now What's the goal?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and that's something you really have to think about because there's no clear answer anymore.
Speaker 1: There's no right answer anymore.
Speaker 0: There wasn't a right answer to begin with.
Speaker 1: Well back there really was a thing.
Speaker 0: is everyone else came up with the same answer independently.
Speaker 1: Well back then there really wasn't an answer other than to promote anime or possibly to enjoy anime itself.
Speaker 1: It was just at something something anime or anime something.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Now you can have all sorts of goals and Before we get any further.
Speaker 1: I do want to point out that I know what anime world orders.
Speaker 1: first thing They're gonna say is yeah clubs that changed are popular but the old clubs are dying and that sucks because clubs don't show anything anymore.
Speaker 1: and I think today's example see we're not going to talk about the specific logistics yet of running club.
Speaker 1: We need to Skype in a whole bunch of different people that we know including the legendary Scott Johnson about all legendary.
Speaker 1: Well, he's legendary.
Speaker 0: I'll dig I'll try to turn it only according to new type magazine.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just love type USA.
Speaker 1: It says Scott Johnson legendary anime club expert, but then it shows a picture of me in the front of the audience talking.
Speaker 0: Yep I felt so.
Speaker 1: I only felt bad because that happened to him at anime central years and years and years ago Where someone made a video of us doing some event in a room party and the subtitle said Scott Johnson But it was me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then it showed me and it said Scott.
Speaker 1: Anyway What we're gonna start with today is an example of pretty much the most successful Anime club in the United States and probably in North America the RIT anime club.
Speaker 1: and before you get.
Speaker 1: but I'll just say right now Their primary thing is still to this day Straight-up showings of anime.
Speaker 1: they show anime in a room and they still get over a hundred people Minimum at every single showing they do every single week.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know enough about what they do now because I haven't been there in years.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well luckily I can talk a lot about what we were doing a couple years ago and a couple years ago The situation really hasn't changed much.
Speaker 0: fan subs are still everywhere.
Speaker 0: You know, it really isn't that much different from doing it right now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and in fact that the real because the club was originally I mean the club is a very old club.
Speaker 1: the club was founded long before I knew what RIT was or what anime was or anything and it was originally the same kind of Anime club that every other anime club was and they transformed into a different kind of club
Speaker 0: Way
Speaker 1: ahead of the curve way before anyone even thought there would be a problem and as a result They've almost always been very large very popular and very well run.
Speaker 1: But don't forget don't argue that they're a different kind of club and that that's bad because they still show anime straight up.
Speaker 1: That's their primary thing.
Speaker 1: In fact, they show anime like three times a week Yes, and they get as many people at those things they do as all the other things.
Speaker 0: Yeah, part of the advantage is being at RIT, which is basically sitting in a pile of nerds.
Speaker 1: Yeah Look at RIT.
Speaker 1: They have an anime club.
Speaker 1: They have a Japanese culture club.
Speaker 1: that's separate from that.
Speaker 0: They used to have two anime clubs a long time ago.
Speaker 1: Yeah competing they have a gaming club.
Speaker 1: separate from that.
Speaker 1: They have the go club the chess club.
Speaker 1: I think there's a shogi club now What I don't know if it came to be but I know people were trying to start it.
Speaker 0: Wow.
Speaker 1: and a video gaming club That was separate from the other gaming club.
Speaker 1: Yeah, those video gaming and then gaming gaming and then chess and all that and all these other separate clubs.
Speaker 1: I mean there are a lot of geeks at RIT.
Speaker 1: So but the thing is other anime clubs in the upstate New York area are.
Speaker 1: They're not.
Speaker 1: I mean, they're obviously not as gigantic as this club But they're still doing very well and they're growing or at least staying the same.
Speaker 1: They're not shrinking like a lot of the clubs people have been talking about in the rest of the country.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I went to Cinecon right and there weren't too many people at Cinecon But they're all.
Speaker 0: Cita is the SUNY IT anime club and they ran the con and it seemed like they had a whole bunch of nerds from SUNY IT and also the nearby community college that were in their club and they were all the staff of the con and there was at least 30 of those people.
Speaker 1: it really seems that a lot of the anime clubs at least up where we are and in this whole area are doing very well and While they may not be huge that's more a function of where they are as opposed to how well they're wrong.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it seems like if a club is run Well, it will continue to exist and do things and if a club is run poorly It will die and disappear and the number of people that are actually in the club is dependent on the location of the club.
Speaker 1: So what what we'll do today is we really just want to go over exactly what the RIT anime club did and How they did it and some of the reasons behind why and then in the upcoming episodes on this we're gonna talk a lot about The specifics like how to run this kind of an event how to promote a club how to start a club how to end a club Why you might want to end a club.
Speaker 1: But anyway, sometimes you do the RIT anime club.
Speaker 1: when we came to power You see when we were freshmen at RIT the club was already gigantic and their original format at that time as it had been for Ages and ages was very simple every Thursday night They would have a meeting a main meeting.
Speaker 1: the majority of the active members would come to this meeting.
Speaker 1: in addition periodically on Weekends, they would have anime marathons.
Speaker 1: They would pick an anime and show the whole thing all the way through as a one-time event like a Saturday Sunday or Friday Saturday.
Speaker 1: They would have quarterly social nights which are basically a small convention.
Speaker 1: I mean anime RIT anime social nights are seriously larger than some anime cons I've been to.
Speaker 0: yeah, basically what they did at the social nights.
Speaker 0: They get a few rooms.
Speaker 0: They set up some video games they set up a VCR and they showed some anime on it with a projector and You know, maybe a little DDR tournament Maybe something like that and then a table full of manga to read a
Speaker 1: trash talk Mario tennis tournament
Speaker 0: and that was that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, maybe a lot of people showed up and hung out all night having fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah They would also periodically and these came and went depending how much money there was have anime dance nights with live DJs Anime and Japanese techno and dance music and crazy parties.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they did that and then they didn't do it and then they did it again and it was sort of an on-and-off thing.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean that that sort of thing requires a lot of resources that aren't just human resources So they're kind of hard to pull off from even large clubs.
Speaker 0: Yep, unless you want to do them shoddily Yeah, you could do anything shoddily Yeah, and if people don't know good from bad Like if they don't know good piano playing from rims piano playing then get away with shoddy.
Speaker 1: Now they also had club days where they would sit somewhere prominent on campus and just promote themselves.
Speaker 1: And you know explain what anime was to people who didn't know and a surprising number of people didn't know.
Speaker 0: It was scary like they would put up posters all over the school full of nerds and they would send emails to everyone in the Whole-school almost who cared and they did all this stuff to say hey come to the goddamn anime Club if you like anime and You know what?
Speaker 0: There are still people who liked anime.
Speaker 0: went to RIT Multiple years went to classes there for multiple years and somehow did not know that the anime Club existed despite it being huge.
Speaker 1: They walk past anime club fire.
Speaker 1: They'd come to us and say holy shit.
Speaker 1: There's an anime Club.
Speaker 1: Yeah, where can I join?
Speaker 1: Wow, yeah Now there were all other one-off events.
Speaker 1: like a couple times We rented a local movie theater and showed anime in that.
Speaker 0: well, we got the.
Speaker 0: the local art theater showed spirited away.
Speaker 0: So we just bought all the tickets.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, we kind of we kind of have convinced them to show it like.
Speaker 1: we talked to them a lot about it And then they agreed they'll show it and then we would buy all the tickets and then the anime the whole anime Club went and watched The movie in the theater.
Speaker 1: Yep, along with a bunch of other people from the area And there were all a whole bunch of other random events that we can kind of talk about You know like anime dodgeball events and a whole bunch of one-off things.
Speaker 1: But the core is as we have already said now that there's Thursday showings The main showings were structured in a very specific way.
Speaker 1: that seems very conducive to having a popular anime Club.
Speaker 0: The first thing they did is they stood up in front of the club and they announced the club business.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean you got to have some kind of a ritual a shtick.
Speaker 1: people really like that sort of thing.
Speaker 1: So every time someone would walk up to the front of the room, you know The crowd would gather people would show up an hour before the club meeting and just hang out.
Speaker 0: But it's like if you had no class before the club you had nothing else to do.
Speaker 0: You might as well come and hang out.
Speaker 0: There's gonna be at least one other person there.
Speaker 1: But people would shuffle in the new room be very loud and when it was time to start The president of the club would get up and yell.
Speaker 1: Hi everybody.
Speaker 1: Hi, dr Nick and that was kind of the cue.
Speaker 1: and then the whole club would shut up and yell back.
Speaker 1: Hi Rim or hi Luke or hi, whoever's president Mmm, and everyone would get quiet.
Speaker 1: and then the people on the board whoever was running the club at the time would give all sorts of announcements and They kind of do all like not really a stand-up act But they'd be very humorous in the front of the room in a very calculated way.
Speaker 1: engage the crowd talk to the crowd yell at the crowd get the crowd to yell back get everyone really worked up and You think that sounds cheesy But it worked without fail every week on the same people for years and years and years.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's quite amazing.
Speaker 1: It was so easy to get an anime crowd pumped up.
Speaker 1: I mean literally if like if I'm at a croc con and I need to do crowd control Just yell the name of an anime and that'll shut everyone up and then they'll yell back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it it's people are.
Speaker 0: if people are such a fan of something you can just yell out Almost anything related to that fandom and you'll get their attention and you know, they'll start really getting into it now.
Speaker 1: in addition I mean we do announcements.
Speaker 1: what's coming up?
Speaker 1: We do the funny stuff we'd and then we would talk about what we were going to show that day give a little bit of insight Into it.
Speaker 1: maybe like well, this is a famous anime blah or this is a secret.
Speaker 1: We can't tell you what it is because that'll ruin the surprise.
Speaker 1: or this was so-and-so's last work.
Speaker 1: Yep, a little bit of education there.
Speaker 1: It also again engages them gives them a reason to show up even if they don't want to see the show.
Speaker 1: Then we would have a raffle.
Speaker 1: now We're not going to talk about the format of the raffle because that would require time.
Speaker 1: But suffice to say the RIT anime Club came up with a very unique Method of holding raffles at club meetings.
Speaker 1: that is extremely conducive to getting people to show up to the meetings.
Speaker 0: Yeah, people would get a raffle ticket and the raffle ticket that they had could get them a prize But only if they showed up.
Speaker 0: therefore they would show up to pretty much every meeting where there was gonna be a raffle.
Speaker 0: Even if they weren't gonna watch the show they would show up to your meeting and they might stick around.
Speaker 0: You know, they're not gonna come.
Speaker 0: just do the raffle and leave.
Speaker 0: they're gonna come watch a little bit And then if they don't like it, they're gonna leave.
Speaker 1: Yep, then we would show the anime music videos.
Speaker 1: See we had people in the club on the board whose only job Was to find good anime music videos that we hadn't shown before every week every single week.
Speaker 0: That's 30 weeks a year.
Speaker 0: You need to find three or four good music videos.
Speaker 1: not easy But it worked really well because people would come even if they didn't want to watch the show.
Speaker 1: they would come for the announcements and all that and they'd come to see the anime music videos because it is almost Impossible to find the good anime music videos on your own without someone else telling you where to look.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you could go out and get the music videos yourself off the internet.
Speaker 0: That's not difficult.
Speaker 0: And you know The thing is to know which ones are good.
Speaker 0: to act as a filter is like this service that does not exist.
Speaker 0: you go Music videos org.
Speaker 0: It's not easy to pick out the good from the bad.
Speaker 0: It's actually quite difficult.
Speaker 0: They're we have YouTube now But even then it's really hard to pick out the good from the bad and a lot of times like you'll know a good video Because it won an award at a convention.
Speaker 0: You can't find the place to download it on the internet.
Speaker 0: It's just not it's nowhere.
Speaker 0: Yep, and if the anime club, you know provides all the best videos every week on the screen It gets people to come.
Speaker 0: it gets people all hyped up Especially if the video is humorous and a lot of people even if they've seen the show Even if there isn't a raffle will come watch the music videos.
Speaker 1: and also there's the whole and we'll talk about this a lot Through the whole series the crowd dynamic people who came to the club had realized partly due to marketing and partly on their own That watching these things with a group of people is almost always more fulfilling than watching it alone.
Speaker 1: I mean a good AMV.
Speaker 1: if you watched it in your room you go Wow, that was good.
Speaker 1: If you watch it with a crowd of people if it's a sad AMV, you'll get that collective At the end.
Speaker 1: or if it's an action AMV, you'll get people yelling and screaming at the end and people really get into it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean there's a lot of shows that just don't work out.
Speaker 0: if you watch them alone like Excel saga watching Excel saga alone You know, it's just kind of like oh my god There's something crazy going on the screen.
Speaker 0: it hurts but you watch it with a crowd of people and it's like oh There's you know, it just changes the whole thing.
Speaker 1: So then now this is probably the most important part and this is the thing that a lot of clubs seem to get wrong.
Speaker 1: And I say wrong because every club that is adopted the RIT anime club method of show a picking what to show and showing it Has done better than if they'd done it the old way and very few clubs that follow this format Well have failed as far as I'm aware Because most clubs don't seem to do it this way.
Speaker 1: A lot of clubs will show an anime all the way through.
Speaker 1: like every week They show the next X episodes of why show?
Speaker 0: so week one they show episodes one two and three.
Speaker 0: week two They show episodes four five and six.
Speaker 0: week three.
Speaker 0: They show episode seven eight nine.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about this in more detail Yeah in the future.
Speaker 0: But some bad idea.
Speaker 0: some clubs like will show three or four shows and they'll show like episode one and two of three different shows.
Speaker 0: And the next week they'll show episode three and four of the same three shows.
Speaker 1: again now RIT anime did that But they didn't do it.
Speaker 1: on their main Thursday shows They had a whole separate track of showings on Monday night.
Speaker 0: that didn't come till later.
Speaker 1: Yes, and it was a good success and it's still going to this day.
Speaker 1: Wow and but yeah on the Monday shows they would pick two or three shows and show them all the way through a couple episodes of each every week.
Speaker 1: and Actually a whole different crowd shows up to that kind of showings.
Speaker 1: but the Thursday showings they would show either four episodes of a new show as in the first four episodes or One episode of a bunch of different shows.
Speaker 0: rarely like a sample That was usually on the first meeting of the whole year is they would show the first episodes of like four different shows and four Different genres.
Speaker 0: Yeah to kind of you know.
Speaker 0: So here's a look at all these different anime.
Speaker 0: one of these has to interest you.
Speaker 1: or if we were doing a theme day like Tonight is violence night.
Speaker 1: Here's the poor violent anime.
Speaker 1: Yeah, or one movie Yep Now this worked very well because one we'd promote what show we were going to show.
Speaker 1: Two people who wanted to see that show would come and see it.
Speaker 1: people who didn't want to see that show would come anyway for all the other stuff at the start of the club and then a Lot of them would end up sticking around anyway because they realize oh I kind of do want to watch the show.
Speaker 1: or maybe Like initial D is the best example initial D. If you don't know what it is and then you see it or hear about it It sounds so stupid.
Speaker 0: I actually watched the first four episodes and thought it was stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it worked because no one wanted to watch this show and everyone thought the club was stupid for showing it But they stayed and watched the first four episodes.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you know 130 people are in the room watching initial D and they all walk out like yeah I don't know what I think about that.
Speaker 1: and then a lot of them showed up to the marathon.
Speaker 1: I'm a few months later.
Speaker 0: when I watched the marathon Months later.
Speaker 0: I was like, ah shit But why do I have to like this show?
Speaker 1: because the club shows a different show or a different movie every week one.
Speaker 1: You don't lose people who miss one week and can't catch up.
Speaker 1: Instead you get people who come every week because maybe they don't know about a lot of these shows.
Speaker 1: We took great pains to pick Very specifically the shows we wanted to show to one draw people in and then to especially later in the year to expose people to Anime, we know they'll probably like but they would never seek out on their own.
Speaker 1: So we showed a lot of weird stuff a lot of old stuff a lot of things that people would never dream of watching on Their own.
Speaker 1: but they trusted us because they knew the club was good.
Speaker 1: So they'd come they'd watch this show and if they really didn't like it they'd leave.
Speaker 1: but most of the time people would get a kick out of it and Hundreds and hundreds of people would come to us all the time and tell us wow I never thought I would have liked Excel saga, but that show was hilarious.
Speaker 0: Thanks for showing it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know a lot of clubs especially high school clubs.
Speaker 0: They say they have this problem where you know, the members all they want to do is watch Naruto and Dragon Ball.
Speaker 0: they don't want to watch any of this other stuff, you know, and They keep incoming and complaining.
Speaker 0: The problem is is you have this sort of assumption already that the members somehow decide what the showing is gonna be?
Speaker 0: the RIT anime club?
Speaker 0: that was never even Thought of that.
Speaker 0: that could be a possibility that someone else decides what to show besides the people who run the club.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I hate to say it but autocracy worked a lot better than democracy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, now part of the reason is that the people who know good anime or old anime fans They know what they like They know what they don't like and they're usually a lot more open-minded about trying something so you don't need to worry about them.
Speaker 1: The young Naruto one-piece Dragon Ball fanboys who haven't been exposed to a lot of anime.
Speaker 1: Don't know that there's a lot of stuff out there They'll like.
Speaker 1: but because if you have things to get them to come to club other than just the showing like the raffles The anime music videos the funny announcements the social events the tape check out.
Speaker 1: I'll get to that.
Speaker 1: then they'll come They'll watch the show anyway, or at least give it a try.
Speaker 1: They'll probably like it and you have just created a more mature more widespread in interest anime fan.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you must decide.
Speaker 0: this is the show we're showing.
Speaker 0: end of story, you know It shouldn't even be possible for anyone else to decide what the show is gonna be besides the board or the people running the club.
Speaker 1: We'll talk a lot about how to pick shows because that was the primary duty of the board Was to pick the show for each week.
Speaker 1: We very carefully crafted it to Balance between drawing people in and exposing people to new things.
Speaker 0: Yeah And don't worry like if there might be some people who only show up when you're showing a robot show.
Speaker 0: There might be some people who will show up and then leave as soon as the show starts.
Speaker 1: That's the sign of a healthy club.
Speaker 0: That's fine.
Speaker 0: You know, people are coming people are going, you know As long as you get people to show up they don't have to sit there the whole time.
Speaker 1: I mean one night we'd get you know 180 people because we're showing like the cowboy bebop movie and everyone's excited about it and a lot of people come even people who don't Normally ever come.
Speaker 1: and then the next week we show I don't know big O and we only get 120 people.
Speaker 1: But 40 of those people are people who didn't come to the cowboy bebop showing Mm-hmm, or that not the cowboy be the cowboy movie showing.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then the next week We show Sailor Moon and 160 people show up But 20 of them have never even come to anime club before and 40 of them came to cowboy bebop But didn't want to see big O.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's crazy.
Speaker 0: So people would come and go as they please and and of course There's always like the 50 people who show up no matter what and we'll watch the whole thing no matter what and they're always there.
Speaker 1: Yep in fact one time we tried to show the worst crap we could to get people to leave just as an Experiment and they wouldn't leave and they watched it anyway, and they cheered.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: See the other benefit I don't.
Speaker 1: we're already going long.
Speaker 1: So we'll have to save this for future episodes.
Speaker 1: All right, even bad anime is good in a crowd.
Speaker 0: Well some bad.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah some anime is Unsalvageable like gray the digital target.
Speaker 1: Yes But if you think if you pick the wrong show and the show is not good and the crowd doesn't like it They'll stay anyway And they'll probably have a lot of fun yelling at the screen making fun of it talking about how shitty it is and then leave Having just as much fun as if they'd watched a Miyazaki masterpiece.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean when we first went to the club before we were in charge of it at all They would always yell at people who made any sort of noise during the showing.
Speaker 0: and you know Generally, you don't want people making noise during the showing if they're whispering or anything.
Speaker 0: It's been knowing.
Speaker 0: it's like it's like a movie theater.
Speaker 0: You don't want people going blabbity-blah interrupting other people watching but at the same time if people have witty and hilarious things to yell out or They want to laugh real loud or you know point out something or anything like that.
Speaker 0: Go for it You got it.
Speaker 0: Like, you know, you don't want to just shut people up, which is what they did originally.
Speaker 0: you want to Encourage one sort of not shutting up while encouraging Shutting up at the appropriate times
Speaker 1: and we will talk about that also in great detail because while there is no hard and fast rule I think we can lay out a fairly specific set of guidelines that if you follow them in terms of enforcing quiet rules Your club will do better almost overnight.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And then after the showing Afterward in the anime club office we would have tape check out which we'll have to talk about that as a whole episode.
Speaker 1: because yeah the Landscape of tape check out and anime libraries is changing.
Speaker 1: But before fan subs were really widespread on the internet.
Speaker 1: All right, the anime had always had a gigantic gigantic library of tapes that members could check out.
Speaker 1: and then we expanded that.
Speaker 1: in fact Scott Johnson are the President before me when he was librarian and the even when he was president is Known, you know kind of like in the roles of history as the president who Expanded the library.
Speaker 1: amazingly.
Speaker 1: He made the library gigantic.
Speaker 1: He switched us to DVDs.
Speaker 1: We got rid of old fan subs.
Speaker 1: It was kind of this reformation of the anime club library, which made it even more popular.
Speaker 1: the library existed one to give people access to old anime that they couldn't get otherwise which now isn't as much of an issue and To it got people to stay around even if they didn't want to watch the show.
Speaker 1: They'd show up in the beginning because they wanted the and these.
Speaker 1: They'd show up at the end for tape check out and to hang out in the social area during tape check out.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the other thing is that people didn't like to show.
Speaker 0: often They would just go directly to the tape check out even if they couldn't get the tapes.
Speaker 0: yet They would sit around and talk to each other about Anime or whatever because you have all these people with a common interest.
Speaker 0: if they're going to a club and they could get the anime On their own what are they there for?
Speaker 0: they're there for some sort of social interaction or to get a raffle prize or something.
Speaker 0: Usually the social interaction.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if they don't want to watch the show They're gonna want to have someplace to go during the show.
Speaker 0: You just hang out and talk.
Speaker 0: I could talk about when he had the social room, but I'm not gonna waste time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what we'll do is we're basically gonna break up each of the topics that we brought up today Episode per episode skyping in relevant experts.
Speaker 1: We know when they're appropriate and we'll tell you exactly how to do all of these things.
Speaker 1: But all we really did today was overview how the RIT anime club ran its main showings.
Speaker 1: and Even if you don't listen to any more of our episodes on how to run anime clubs All I can say is that if you try to model your club after the basic idea of what RIT anime does I?
Speaker 1: guarantee your club will be more successful than it has been in the past.
Speaker 1: and If you think that anime clubs are dying or changing to the point that they're not fun anymore If you live anywhere in upstate New York go to the Rochester Institute of Technology on a Thursday night and check out the RIT anime Club.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what other good anime.
Speaker 0: I guess I will assume that CITA is a good club because Corbin runs it.
Speaker 0: Well, I guess Delaware.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Delaware anime club.
Speaker 0: I hear good things about what other ones are there?
Speaker 1: Um, actually there used to be a very active and awesome anime club at the University of Rochester right next to RIT But apparently there is some trouble with the college and I think they shut the club down.
Speaker 1: I don't know if it's back yet.
Speaker 0: I don't know it was it.
Speaker 1: I mean it worked out.
Speaker 1: Okay, cuz they all just kind of went to the RIT anime club.
Speaker 0: MIT supposedly is a big anime club.
Speaker 1: Yep, I've heard tell that the University of Michigan has a very large and active anime club.
Speaker 1: I mean not as big as RIT anime But still very big and very active and I've news of people who went to it years and years ago.
Speaker 1: I know their format was in some ways similar to RIT.
Speaker 1: I should try to track those people down and see if they are still the way they are.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there are a lot of big anime clubs out there.
Speaker 0: on the internet there's sites that list all the anime clubs.
Speaker 0: You can find one.
Speaker 0: They're out there.
Speaker 0: They're not either not difficult to find.
Speaker 0: They're not hiding.
Speaker 0: They want to.
Speaker 0: they want you to find them.
Speaker 1: Yep, anime clubs are doing just fine and they can still be about showing the anime.
Speaker 1: It just it's a matter of showing the anime in a way that will be conducive to Modern fans still wanting to go to lot.
Speaker 1: Well not live but showings with groups of people in theaters as opposed to sitting in their smelly dorm rooms Watching I don't know negima by themselves in their underwear.
Speaker 0: Mmm, Wow scary.
Speaker 0: The thing is the people who are gonna do that.
Speaker 0: You don't want them at your club.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and we can talk about that, too.
Speaker 1: there's a fine line between getting as many people in your club as possible and Keeping the people that you know will cause problems out of your club or at least minimizing the damage they will do.
Speaker 1: So I guess the only other thing I'll open up before we end the episode is one We're gonna do our spoilers final thoughts episode sometime next year.
Speaker 1: Go to the forums and vote.
Speaker 1: if you care about what show we talk about all the way to the end and spoil all the Way through - if you have any comments or specific questions about anime clubs Post them in the forums or send us an email or an.
Speaker 1: oh Maybe not an audio because it might not work and we probably won't get to him right away.
Speaker 1: But when the episode that is topical to your question comes up, we will answer your question.
Speaker 1: Guarantee it, of course, you can just go to any anime con in the Northeast and see us do this exact same thing live.
Speaker 1: But what's the fun in that?
Speaker 1: This has been geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Speaker 1: We say feeds plural because geek nights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Speaker 1: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Speaker 1: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Speaker 1: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Speaker 0: You can send us feedback by email to geek nights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Speaker 0: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Speaker 1: If you like what you hear.
Speaker 1: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Speaker 1: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Speaker 0: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Speaker 0: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Speaker 0: But unlike those other late shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.