Speaker 0: It's Thursday October 19th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We discussed the burden of proof.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So today I ended up working in a place in the Bronx.
Speaker 0: I normally don't work very very South Bronx as in right next to the river where I could see Manhattan.
Speaker 1: What kind of place was it?
Speaker 1: hospitals?
Speaker 0: Yeah big old hospital in a really economically depressed area.
Speaker 1: awesome.
Speaker 0: I parked my car behind a gate.
Speaker 1: Whoo good idea though.
Speaker 0: actually the other day I went down to the same place, and I parked my car in the street on a shady alley next to an empty park.
Speaker 1: Uh-oh at least is a park.
Speaker 1: parks are cool.
Speaker 0: Well the thing is my car looks kind of shady so I can park in a shady area.
Speaker 0: just fine Mr..
Speaker 1: Shade Shady McShade shade.
Speaker 0: yeah, it'll be a couple more years before I buy a new car, but my car I mean it actually looks really nice except for the Small gash in the left side from when someone backed into it while was parked on the street earlier.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you told me about it, and then I saw it was pretty bad.
Speaker 0: I don't know really doesn't?
Speaker 0: it's?
Speaker 0: a tiny little dent.
Speaker 0: I could pop it out with a rubber mallet.
Speaker 1: It's mostly those white streaks of the with a.
Speaker 0: actually half of that will wash off.
Speaker 0: Okay, I tried it.
Speaker 1: I couldn't tell it like it.
Speaker 1: look it's hard to tell what of that is paint that scratched off and what of that is stuff That's rubbed onto your car.
Speaker 0: That's stuff.
Speaker 0: That's rubbed on and I have touch-up paint.
Speaker 1: no touch-up paints.
Speaker 0: cool I just don't really care cuz I'd have to knock the dent out before I did anything.
Speaker 1: I like how my car didn't come with touch-up paint, but then a few months after I got the car They mailed me touch-up paint in the mail like here's a special gift.
Speaker 1: You know it's really expensive.
Speaker 1: Here's some touch-up paint, and I was like oh great the touch-up paint.
Speaker 0: You should have given me for free Yeah, like 40 bucks for a little thing of that.
Speaker 1: It's all.
Speaker 1: that's a lot of money.
Speaker 0: Yeah Car paint is it anyway.
Speaker 0: I'm down in this area.
Speaker 0: I haven't really been before and it's kind of out of the way.
Speaker 0: and to get home I'd had to take the Deegan Interstate 87 the New York State Thruway.
Speaker 1: You took 87 all the way here and cross the Hudson River twice.
Speaker 1: That's a long way.
Speaker 0: well No, I took it most of the way up And then I cut off onto the taconic at an opportune moment.
Speaker 1: so before you went across the river you said oh shit No, actually I knew that it touches the taconic.
Speaker 0: I'll not too far before it goes across the river.
Speaker 0: It also touches the sawmill.
Speaker 0: I could have gotten off there.
Speaker 0: ooh sawmill You know what the sawmill can die in a goddamn fire.
Speaker 1: all those roads that go north out of New York City They're all fine.
Speaker 0: the taconic I can just blow down the taconic unless there's an accident.
Speaker 0: the Bear Mountain Beacon Expressway I can just fly right through at 90 miles an hour.
Speaker 0: My problem is the sawmill because the sawmill has traffic lights for the first like five miles Which isn't a big deal, but that completely and utterly stops fucking traffic.
Speaker 0: That's okay, and there's no way around it.
Speaker 0: The only other way is to take route 9 through like 10 tiny little five-person towns with speed limits of 25.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just the Hudson River is so Poorly placed.
Speaker 1: it just gets in the way.
Speaker 1: if that wasn't there You know easy it would be to go north out of the city to get here.
Speaker 0: I think the problem is more than all the roads that go north out of New York City Were built before we understood how to make good highways.
Speaker 0: So they're not highways their parkways with at-grade entrances and at-grade exits and often traffic lights.
Speaker 0: Also, they're narrow and windy and often two lanes in any given direction.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that is true.
Speaker 1: It's out of New York City.
Speaker 1: It's mostly like two three You know it's.
Speaker 1: it's mostly two-lane roads But there's a lot of them.
Speaker 1: if it had been designed properly there would probably be like one or two Like five or six-lane roads that are all raised and superhighway.
Speaker 0: ish well You'd probably just have a superhighway that went from the top of Manhattan all the way up to like halfway to Albany.
Speaker 1: Yeah, probably and it probably go down through New Jersey and everything like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but no we don't have that.
Speaker 1: nope nope instead It sucks.
Speaker 1: you got to pick one of a multitude of roads.
Speaker 1: Hope you pick the right one for that day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is the radio is useless.
Speaker 0: I thought oh, I'll listen to the radio and find out when the trap like if there's traffic.
Speaker 1: Well, if you do listen to 880 a.m.
Speaker 1: Which is I think the most powerful radio and radio station in the country you can get the news and traffic and weather on the 8th totally useless.
Speaker 1: traffic and weather is within eight minutes.
Speaker 0: I've already committed and I've never once heard a traffic update that saved me from anything.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you could sit in your car for 10 minutes Until the 8th and then that's just stupid and then go that's just really stupid.
Speaker 0: Hey and I tried to get you know traffic information online and I learned that all Traffic information online is either incorrect or useless.
Speaker 1: That's that's true.
Speaker 1: I don't know why that is.
Speaker 0: There is no single website that has accurate reliable good traffic information for the New York State area.
Speaker 1: All someone really needs to do is you know You take a Google map and whenever there's a traffic incident on a major highway you you know, you put a little flag.
Speaker 1: This is major incident here.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem author South back.
Speaker 0: Here's the problem one.
Speaker 0: Most of those incidents aren't reported until later, especially not to you.
Speaker 1: I know they really need to report them much faster.
Speaker 1: I like the traffic cameras on the highways.
Speaker 0: I want more of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean my mom before she goes somewhere cuz Connecticut has you know traffic highway cameras everywhere like the news always shows them you can just look at them online, which is how public camera should be and You'll just go and look at the cameras at the road.
Speaker 1: She's gonna go on you know, and then maybe take an alternate road if it looks like there's too many cars there.
Speaker 1: I Wish we had that.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I also had a subway for lunch, which made me very unhappy.
Speaker 1: You went to subway the place.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I there was nothing.
Speaker 0: this area is really economically depressed.
Speaker 0: I didn't trust any of the places I saw to eat within walking distance.
Speaker 0: So I found a food court that had a subway in it.
Speaker 0: Oh I had an Italian combo.
Speaker 1: You know, there's very few things at subway that actually tastes good.
Speaker 1: You know, I mean it's okay to just get the breads.
Speaker 1: Okay, it's bread, you know the stuff they put the vegetables or vegetables.
Speaker 1: It's terrible.
Speaker 0: It's the terrible subs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's pretty bad.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: So what do you got in the news?
Speaker 0: I don't want to talk about subway.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: so everyone knows or you should know that Nintendo promised that Zelda Twilight Princess would come out for GameCube and then Wii and it was told to everyone that the GameCube version would come out a Week before the Wii version which is such a brilliant yet evil move.
Speaker 1: Yeah now They've decided that in Japan.
Speaker 1: This is old news that in Japan They weren't going to sell the GameCube version in stores.
Speaker 1: They were only gonna sell it online.
Speaker 1: So if you want it in Japan if you're a Japanese person and you want Zelda Twilight Princess for the GameCube You got to order it online But they were still gonna sell it in the US in the stores.
Speaker 1: today people who work at EB and GameStop are reporting all over the place and this is confirmed pretty much that the What the SKU the SKU?
Speaker 1: For a GameCube Zelda Twilight Princess, it's been removed from all the computer systems.
Speaker 1: It's not in there anymore.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh People are pretty much saying up they're not gonna sell it in stores.
Speaker 1: The question is are they gonna sell it online?
Speaker 1: Well, maybe you know, they they sell the electro plankton.
Speaker 1: that game was sold online.
Speaker 1: It was also sold in stores, but it was mostly sold online in Nintendo US.
Speaker 1: So We'll see if GameCube Zelda Twilight Princess comes.
Speaker 0: You know, this could be a little bit of a test of Nintendo to see Exactly how well they could just cut out the middleman and sell their games direct.
Speaker 0: Who knows who knows but I'm because no no normal parent would have bought that game.
Speaker 0: that game purely in the realm of.
Speaker 0: I'm a fanboy and I need it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, here's my thinking now, right if this game isn't sold in stores This might be a rare awesome game to get.
Speaker 1: be like.
Speaker 1: I got the GameCube Twilight Princess bitches.
Speaker 0: You know what that?
Speaker 1: if there's not maybe they're doing it on purpose to make me think that You know, so it's like should I buy the GameCube one a week before the week comes out or not?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: The only rare games that I care about are the gold cartridge Zelda's and I have them both.
Speaker 1: So I kind of want those like the Nintendo World Championship cartridges like not even to have because they're you know They go for so much in eBay just to play it once to you know.
Speaker 1: See how I would have done.
Speaker 0: and sure there are ROMs out there.
Speaker 1: I think there is a ROM but I haven't.
Speaker 0: I found a ROM for the Nintendo official Diagnostic cartridge awesome.
Speaker 0: You can find a ROM for that.
Speaker 0: I guarantee it.
Speaker 1: Maybe there aren't so many of these cartridges out there, but we'll find one maybe someday.
Speaker 0: Yes, someday.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So this is actually really interesting news that I found.
Speaker 0: I found it a while ago and I was thinking of doing a whole show on it But I couldn't wait anymore because eventually you guys will all notice that has been sitting in my delicious for a while unspoken about.
Speaker 0: according to the US Census is 2005 something something to study.
Speaker 0: I forget the name of the study.
Speaker 0: They apparently have recently released all of the data for it.
Speaker 0: For the first time ever there are more Non-married non-traditional households in the United States than there are married traditional households.
Speaker 0: More people are in the in the eyes of fundamentalist Christians living in sin than not living in sin as of now.
Speaker 0: Fifty point two percent of American households are non-standard meaning they are either a single mother heading a household a single father heading a household or Heterosexual or homosexual Partners of either gender living together for various reasons or bachelors or no No, they don't count people who live alone.
Speaker 0: So the numbers are actually even higher.
Speaker 0: there are fifty five point eight million non-traditional households in the u.s.
Speaker 0: They're an additional thirty million men and women living completely alone.
Speaker 1: Oh, wow.
Speaker 0: They don't count as households.
Speaker 1: Why you live alone?
Speaker 1: You don't cut?
Speaker 0: No, you know the definition of a household is multiple people living in a house.
Speaker 1: anyway, the point is is the Family the you the normal family in nuclear family mother father 2.5 children dog is To dying.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not.
Speaker 0: it's not dying It's just it's on the decline.
Speaker 0: But the thing is so it's dying.
Speaker 0: It's on the decline rapidly It's not dying.
Speaker 0: that dying implies that it'll go away, which I highly doubt it will maybe in the long long long run.
Speaker 0: No, probably not.
Speaker 0: There's no evidence at all to suggest that if it's declining Signs of increasing, um Scott something that's declining like this There's no indication that it's going to decline fully.
Speaker 0: these things tend to level off.
Speaker 0: I mean if anything, it'll probably decline to a static level and remain there Perhaps until something else comes along to make it decline more and more.
Speaker 0: Okay, I think you're reading way too much into this study.
Speaker 1: Anyway, what does this mean for us?
Speaker 0: It means awesome, I think all it really means is that there are a lot of people who aren't getting married anymore.
Speaker 0: I mean the divorce rate beat the marriage rate and Marriage is actually very rapidly becoming something that is not desirable by the majority of Americans.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I guess so but the gay people seem to really really want to get married.
Speaker 1: So who knows me, you know, is it people still want to get married or is it people?
Speaker 1: Just can't make their marriages work and they really even though they really want them to.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of that just comes down to the fact that a lot of people marry people they don't actually like as evidenced by Many of the people I have met in my working professional career who complain about their spouses Constantly.
Speaker 0: and yet when I try to say here's here's what this study says to me Our generation is finally smarter than the previous generation when it comes to love and family and marriages.
Speaker 0: Because all of the older people I've known always try to say, you know Yeah, you're just not married yet.
Speaker 0: someday in the next five years or so You'll get married and you'll be miserable just like I am.
Speaker 0: you'll have kids and they'll drain you dry of money and you'll hate Your wife and you'll live in a giant house miserable and everything will suck and you'll work long hours to stay away from them and a marriage will cost a lot of money and you're gonna spend all this money and blah blah blah and you'll never have sex anymore and blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: and They honestly just tell me yeah, you dumb kid.
Speaker 0: You don't realize that it happens to everyone.
Speaker 0: It'll happen to you, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think this definitely shows that people just aren't doing that anymore.
Speaker 1: You know, it's like it used to be.
Speaker 1: that was the thing to do.
Speaker 1: people did it.
Speaker 1: Who knows what their reasons were but that was you know, the way to be was, you know You went to school.
Speaker 1: You got a job.
Speaker 1: You made a family.
Speaker 1: It was sort of like the thing to do and it was the status quo.
Speaker 1: and now people are While they're still doing the other parts, you know go to school get a job.
Speaker 1: for the most part They're not doing that whole.
Speaker 1: make a family part at least not in the way that it's been done for many many years.
Speaker 0: See except now.
Speaker 0: here's why your thing about yeah It's gonna die out is kind of BS and not gonna happen.
Speaker 0: most likely The shift is primarily in urban areas as in almost all of these non-traditional households are in the metropolitan areas of major cities or in the suburbs of major cities and almost all cool people are and almost all Of the traditional households are in the Midwest of America.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like literally they're all like, you know the Midwest and generally rural areas and undeveloped areas.
Speaker 1: You know rural areas, you know, we always pick on them because they're behind the times.
Speaker 1: But if you go back in time the rural areas now are Would be you know modern for those times.
Speaker 1: So, you know 50 years from now the rural areas now Will be will be like now.
Speaker 0: I think that's a silly gross over simplification that overlooks the fact that rural life is just inherently different from urban life and always has been it is.
Speaker 0: in the days of the Romans urban and rural were very different because it's Different kind of world a different kind of living.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but they eventually, you know, they weren't behind the city They're behind the times.
Speaker 0: in what way?
Speaker 0: in many ways such as modern ways of thinking Like what there are a lot of progressive people in the Midwest.
Speaker 1: Yeah in the Midwest but not living in the boonies.
Speaker 0: Well by the Midwest I meant the boonies, you know the middle of America.
Speaker 1: the people in the boonies are not hip and cool.
Speaker 0: How do you know a lot of people who move out there hippies?
Speaker 1: Yeah hippies aren't hip.
Speaker 1: there's a difference in a hipster and hippie.
Speaker 0: Alright, I just I don't really see what you're going at here.
Speaker 1: Eventually, you know stuff that's you know happening in the cities.
Speaker 1: It's exported and spreads around to the rural areas.
Speaker 1: It takes a long time for it to get out there.
Speaker 0: what like living in apartment complexes with a lot of people and not having Agriculture that's never gonna get to rural areas.
Speaker 1: then we'll run out of food but other aspects of life.
Speaker 0: Okay, like pop culture type things and social culture pop culture is bigger out there than it is in urban areas.
Speaker 0: Urban areas are much more alternative pop culture.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 1: Yes The point is that because the the alternative pop culture is the pop culture in the urban areas and the pop pop culture While it's there.
Speaker 0: I don't think it's the majority.
Speaker 0: even in urban areas.
Speaker 0: I mean even in New York City most people watch American Idol and all that crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the stuff that's you know The you know that the cities is where the stuff that's down low Bubbles up to the top and becomes the American Idol type crap.
Speaker 1: You know it moves up to that level and then it goes from there out to the rest of the country.
Speaker 1: You know, that's where that's kind of stuff is grown, you know You know, yeah, you know and the rural areas is to where it's distributed.
Speaker 1: It just takes time for that stuff to happen.
Speaker 0: Well, the only point here is that the household in which I live is now the majority.
Speaker 0: and to all of you with families Things might be changing a little bit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe all those, you know groups that are like, you know Family interest.
Speaker 0: I gotta interrupt you.
Speaker 0: I was gonna wait until the break.
Speaker 0: You said, you know about a thousand times.
Speaker 1: What the hell?
Speaker 1: I'm sorry You know all those groups There's no.
Speaker 1: why am I supposed to start the sentence?
Speaker 0: You know, I don't know.
Speaker 1: So all those groups better, you know protect our family Family interests or All that stuff.
Speaker 1: Maybe they'll be losing a lot of power.
Speaker 1: If the majority of the country is not families then the interests of families will hold less sway.
Speaker 1: Your supposed family interests and values.
Speaker 0: see the thing is households that have children are still primarily at least as far as most of the studies go Normal traditional households with a mother and a father or some variety thereof.
Speaker 0: But the other thing is that people are breeding less and less so that there are more and more Households that are comprised of friends or lovers or people who don't intend to have children or people who just don't have children.
Speaker 1: yet You know Things that you know.
Speaker 1: the you know day day, you know, you know, you know, all right.
Speaker 0: So I had a couple things today that were kind of you know I have a bunch of you know Things of the day.
Speaker 0: nothing really really crazy cool stood out and I was gonna pick one of them.
Speaker 0: But then our good friend Lisa had left a message for me and upon further investigation Lisa had sent me a link to a website that lists in generally real time all of the health outbreaks Epidemics that sort of thing in the world via Ajax and Google Maps.
Speaker 1: Well, do they really mean like epidemics like holy crap the whole town is, you know got a disease?
Speaker 1: Well, I mean just like.
Speaker 0: well as in you know outbreaks Uh-huh Outbreaks of disease and you can pick by disease.
Speaker 0: You can click on anthrax and see all the outbreaks of anthrax on the map.
Speaker 1: Well, this does one anthrax count as an anthrax outbreak.
Speaker 0: Well, if you click on one, it'll show you all of the related ones And it gathers it from all sorts of different news sources of varying reliability and applies certain metrics to it to figure out what is Going on.
Speaker 1: That's pretty cool.
Speaker 1: So before you go on a trip Check out this map to make sure you're not going somewhere that's loaded with diseases or just look up your hometown and then freak out.
Speaker 0: When a thousand kids died of E.
Speaker 1: Coli two days ago I'm sure you would have seen that on some sort of local news source.
Speaker 0: I don't watch local news.
Speaker 1: I did do I but I would find out if there was a thousand E. Coli's around here.
Speaker 0: Maybe I have zero contact with local news at this point.
Speaker 0: I've realized I mean, I don't listen to the radio.
Speaker 1: Look who loses.
Speaker 1: kind of important.
Speaker 0: We don't even have TV.
Speaker 0: No internet site covers aren't our local news at all in any reason.
Speaker 1: I actually found out recently that if we have cable television Which we don't that one of the channels is the beacon channel and there's beacon town stuff on that channel.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we're gonna pay for cable.
Speaker 1: No, we're not.
Speaker 1: But I figure we need some sort of local something.
Speaker 0: So sure enough.
Speaker 0: I looked and yeah a kid got polio in Kenya Sucks, why didn't he get the vaccine?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I didn't read the actual thing.
Speaker 0: Maybe he did and it didn't work.
Speaker 0: Maybe he probably just wasn't vaccinated.
Speaker 0: yeah, I mean, you know all those nuts in America now who are trying to not vaccinate their kids against things because they think that the Thermosol or whatever that isn't even in a lot of vaccines causes autism.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can think of other reasons to not get a vaccine.
Speaker 0: There's no reason to not get a vaccine.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, I mean the vaccine.
Speaker 1: The thing is the vaccine will not 100%.
Speaker 1: it is possible to get a vaccine and not get and still get polio.
Speaker 1: It is possible.
Speaker 0: So what's your point?
Speaker 0: Everyone should be vaccinated against everything that needs vaccination.
Speaker 0: Yeah, really?
Speaker 0: No two ways about it.
Speaker 0: It's a good idea.
Speaker 1: But you know what.
Speaker 1: it's not a hundred percent awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I percent awesome.
Speaker 0: No, it's a hundred percent awesome because in the few cases where a vaccine causes harm It still is much to the benefit of society if everyone is vaccinated.
Speaker 0: if there are people who aren't vaccinated We lose our herd immunity against a lot of diseases.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we do but at the same time we don't evolve a natural immunity, um There's really no selection pressure regardless of whether or not we do that.
Speaker 1: I know I want to get some selection pressure going on.
Speaker 0: So you want millions of people to die on a regular basis?
Speaker 1: No I'm figuring we should just get up like a group of people together in our own little society and that society will have some selection Pressure.
Speaker 0: screw the rest of the what how the selection pressure means you prevent people from breeding in some way?
Speaker 0: No, they die Before they breed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so in a small population you expect that by not vaccinating people against diseases Some of them will die thereby eventually over the course of tens of thousands of years generate an immunity in that population.
Speaker 1: Maybe that's well, you know, it may be.
Speaker 1: as some people move to the moon those people would Slowly, you know the people who couldn't live on the moon and didn't have good, you know Traits to live on the moon, but you know, yeah And the other people who did well on the moon would live and breed some more and we'd have awesome moon people.
Speaker 0: I gotta say I'm much more in favor of just using science and technology to overcome our genetic failings.
Speaker 1: Oh, you lazy bum.
Speaker 1: You got no patience to wait 10 million.
Speaker 0: I want to be a coordinator.
Speaker 1: We gotta wait 10 million years.
Speaker 1: that didn't develop our own business.
Speaker 0: That's the way I gotta say if I were to become a father somehow And and I and there was a way to make them a coordinator like in Gundam seed That the question wouldn't be yes or no.
Speaker 0: The question would just be when or how much money?
Speaker 1: And then they'll have a sorrow filled life of Torment.
Speaker 0: Yeah followed by awesome at the end of their life with a giant robot.
Speaker 1: But they'll be forced to fight with giant robots and protect their friends from horrible disaster.
Speaker 0: Maybe maybe or they'll just be awesome and then they'll live an awesome life.
Speaker 0: It could be they'll be the con chair of every anime con tough call piloting giant robots around left and right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, my thing of the day is a YouTube video of this kid.
Speaker 1: in it says India and it says as a girl Even though I think it's a dude, but who can say okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who is roller skating?
Speaker 1: and this kid roller skates a whole real fast down a hill and then does a complete split like whoop and puts their hands on their ankles and You know puts their body, you know, yeah, I think I'm gonna go every time.
Speaker 0: you you know for the rest of the show.
Speaker 1: So this kid is on roller skates going real fast slightly downhill yeah, completely flat against the ground limbo champion of the world flat and The kid goes under a bunch of cars.
Speaker 0: It's really kind of crazy watching this because the kid just goes whoop and disappears under this big truck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it says the kid goes under 40 cars.
Speaker 0: You can't go under 40 cars.
Speaker 1: It might be 40 cars.
Speaker 1: I can't.
Speaker 0: you can't really tell it takes a while.
Speaker 1: It does take a while.
Speaker 1: I'm pretty sure it might be 40 cars.
Speaker 0: See the thing is, you know You're waiting for this kid to come back out if he hit his head or she hit her head and you know Just stopped and was hurt under there.
Speaker 0: It'd be a while before anyone figure.
Speaker 1: They would just move the two adjacent cars because there was someone watching with the camera.
Speaker 1: That's why this is on YouTube.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: I couldn't see anything in the camera when it showed.
Speaker 0: I just saw a blob that may or may not have been moving.
Speaker 1: Oh, I could.
Speaker 1: I saw the kid very clearly.
Speaker 1: I could see the wheels on the roller skates and everything.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: You just need bad bad eyes.
Speaker 0: Anyway, maybe it was the fact that it's on your crappy laptop with its terrible angle of viewing and I was standing on my bed.
Speaker 1: It's still.
Speaker 1: I could see it from my angle.
Speaker 1: So that's all that matters.
Speaker 1: Okay Anyway, I'm sure the people there could see it even better because they didn't have YouTube compression blocking their eyesight.
Speaker 1: however The thing I want to talk about in this video is after the kid emerges right all these people from all over are like cheering and dancing and partying in the street and they pick the kid up and the kid gets laid and Everything's awesome.
Speaker 1: And I just you know, it reminds me a lot.
Speaker 1: It reminds me when I was a kid and people were like that, you know, the neighborhood had a community.
Speaker 1: You know people would come out of their house and talk to each other and you could party in the street.
Speaker 0: See I had to say it, but I don't really like that.
Speaker 0: I kind of disagree with that.
Speaker 1: Why not?
Speaker 0: Well, here's the thing.
Speaker 1: Look, it'd be nice to live in a place where everyone was all friendly and happy and no friendly and happy is one thing.
Speaker 0: But in almost everywhere I've lived physically until I went to college and lived with people I actually had shared interest with.
Speaker 0: I Had almost nothing in common with any of my neighbors and I really had no desire to ever really talk to them And I certainly couldn't bring myself to stand around and cheer in the street.
Speaker 0: I'm just really jaded and I find it really difficult to get into something that much.
Speaker 1: Oh, I think it'd be awesome to live in the place where you know, you you know, even if you don't yeah Even if you're not the best friends in the whole world and have you know have things in common with your neighbors You know doesn't mean you you know, you can ignore them.
Speaker 1: What the hell you keep saying, you know You're just gonna turn this into the you know show.
Speaker 1: it's totally making what I'm saying, you know that not get through Whatever.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: I'm just fine.
Speaker 0: I keep saying, you know, alright, it's a bad trend if this keeps up It's gonna be the you know show with rim and Scott.
Speaker 1: It's only turning to you know show.
Speaker 0: cuz you're pointing out No, cuz yeah, I think you've been doing it for a little couple days now.
Speaker 0: I think there's something in your food.
Speaker 0: I think you're eating the.
Speaker 0: you know beans.
Speaker 1: You know beans, you know beans.
Speaker 1: You read five, you know You know.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I got it Even if I'm not best friends in the world and even if my neighbors aren't awesome geek.
Speaker 1: So I want to hang out with all the time.
Speaker 1: It's still nice to be friendly with your neighbors and have block parties and see I don't.
Speaker 0: it's cool I don't have time for stuff like that.
Speaker 0: I mean, I want to spend time with people who I can talk to.
Speaker 0: I really can't talk to.
Speaker 0: well I mean I meet a lot of people in town Especially when I worked at IBM and I often had time to.
Speaker 0: you know, now I'm saying it's infectious.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh what you're doing to me.
Speaker 0: I should put it on the Google Maps.
Speaker 1: Maybe you do it all the time and I just don't pay attention point it out.
Speaker 0: Now I usually say other things.
Speaker 0: I have my own tics and I'm well aware of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what is rooms?
Speaker 1: What words does room say all the time?
Speaker 0: You know what I say the most.
Speaker 0: I say now Pause the thing I was going to say now pause the thing I'm going to say.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah All right.
Speaker 0: So anyway, I don't have time to be doing that anymore.
Speaker 0: and even when I did, you know I used to go walking around a lot in town before I worked down and I had a long commute and I met a lot of people and they always struck up conversations and It was always a little interesting, you know meeting someone new and talking to them.
Speaker 0: But I couldn't talk about a single thing I was interested in because never did I run into someone in beacon or in fish kill or in poke way or in Poughkeepsie Who had any interest in anything.
Speaker 0: I had to say that I cared about the most.
Speaker 0: room didn't know anything about computers.
Speaker 0: They didn't play video games.
Speaker 0: They didn't care about anime.
Speaker 0: one of them wanted to tell the only cool guy ever met wanted to tell me about how he was on a ship that took the people from when the That other ship was attacked by the Israelis during the war When they want a US ship was attacked and he knew people around that ship.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see I know most people in town don't care what I you know about the things that I'm really really interested in.
Speaker 1: They're not gonna listen to geek nights.
Speaker 1: They don't they don't give a shit Yeah, and which is why I'm not gonna hang out with them all the time and constantly have deep long Conversations with them but it you know, at least to be cordial with them as human beings.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cordiality goes doesn't go beyond they.
Speaker 1: also I'm interested in pretty much it.
Speaker 1: almost anyone has to say at least once You know, it's cool to do what I didn't say, you know, yes you did Just said it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I'm not gonna stop the recording.
Speaker 0: Our listeners can tell you that you said it.
Speaker 1: It's cool to be able to walk around your neighborhood and see people and know who they are instead of just giving them kind of Stairs.
Speaker 0: see I'm very friendly to people.
Speaker 0: I'm cordial to me.
Speaker 0: cordial means if I see someone I acknowledge their existence.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm not gonna.
Speaker 0: small talk about the weather I'm not gonna.
Speaker 0: I hate that.
Speaker 0: I hate small talk.
Speaker 1: I hate just well, but if some kid down the street is roller skating under 40 cars I think it'd be a lot cooler if all the people, you know from around came out, you know to see and we're like Hey, you said, you know again.
Speaker 1: I didn't know.
Speaker 0: you did whatever you said, you know again, I think you're insane.
Speaker 0: I'll just know one last time that this is all being recorded.
Speaker 0: You know, we're doing a podcast So you're free to say that you didn't just say, you know, but I've got a record of what we said.
Speaker 0: So if you're confident, you know what we'll see what was said.
Speaker 0: I'll bet you $100.
Speaker 1: I've got it.
Speaker 1: You're only $100.
Speaker 1: Sure.
Speaker 0: I'll bet you because that's what I got in my wallet right now.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: I have a little over $100.
Speaker 1: I got nothing on my wallet, so I can't bet.
Speaker 0: I'll lend you credit.
Speaker 0: No, so you're not that sure.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure of anything which is what this episode is about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just I I mean a lot.
Speaker 0: like our town has a lot of festivals and get-togethers I go to them occasionally because I like to get you know an elephant here or some deep-fried something's or some lemonade.
Speaker 0: but the people I really don't have any way to hang out with or talk to on any intellectual level and I really just don't have the time or the inclination to deal with people that I'm not interested in.
Speaker 0: I mean no offense to them.
Speaker 0: I don't think they're bad people.
Speaker 1: I'm just not interested in them on a personal basis, but people in your neighborhood a neighborhood community isn't about having Conversations with people.
Speaker 1: it isn't about being intellectual with people.
Speaker 1: It isn't about spending a lot of time.
Speaker 1: So it's not about anything in particular.
Speaker 1: it is there.
Speaker 1: there are more.
Speaker 1: there are other ways to interact and You know join up with other human beings.
Speaker 1: then in the way that we do it with geeky people You know what?
Speaker 0: I don't have any non geeky friends.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know that.
Speaker 1: to be friends with them.
Speaker 1: You just you know, you'd be a queen someone's not who they are You know, you can rely on them.
Speaker 1: for like you can go over and say hey, you got a you know Can I borrow some sugar?
Speaker 0: I would never do that.
Speaker 1: See that's what I'm talking about.
Speaker 1: I would like to live in a place where people all the time went over and said hey could borrow some eggs.
Speaker 0: What's up, see I wouldn't want my neighbors bugging me all the time.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't want people knocking on my door who I kind of know asking to borrow screwdriver.
Speaker 0: I just wouldn't answer.
Speaker 1: the best was because it where my grandma lived in Queens, right?
Speaker 1: We would go sit out on the porch and people would walk down the street and you would say hey, how's it going Joe?
Speaker 1: What's up?
Speaker 1: Yeah when I when I was young and we lived in Detroit The door open on the house people would walk in and say hi and bring some food and take some food.
Speaker 1: and you know It's like a constant Happy go party time.
Speaker 0: see I now we live in this isolated, you know Kind of we're in our house and you're in there your house and as a way should be no I don't want people wandering into my house and borrowing my stuff or I just I really don't like interact.
Speaker 0: I don't like to inter put myself into Entanglements with people I don't care about.
Speaker 1: That's the thing is I you should.
Speaker 1: I would like to live in a place where people cared about the people they lived near.
Speaker 0: I care about him on an abstract human level.
Speaker 0: I care about them in a in a. you know, we all exist in the same world level.
Speaker 0: But I don't want to lend them my screwdriver.
Speaker 0: I Would I mean if someone asked me for my screwdriver I'd give it to him.
Speaker 1: But I would prefer to live in a place where we cared about the people near us on a more than abstract human level.
Speaker 1: But it doesn't have to be.
Speaker 1: you know friend.
Speaker 1: Why don't you come over and play a board game level?
Speaker 1: It's you know, it's it's like.
Speaker 0: well Scott.
Speaker 0: Let me put it in our the way we live our lives.
Speaker 0: Anyway, it doesn't matter what the community is like we never even have the opportunity to see people from our city.
Speaker 0: I think that's because wait because what how could we see people from our city?
Speaker 1: I think if the neighborhood was the way that I like it to be we would do it more often.
Speaker 1: No, we don't walk it around.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't go walk.
Speaker 0: I don't have time for that.
Speaker 0: if I'm gonna go out walk and I'm gonna go out running So you'd go run around and see people and I go run in the mountains alone.
Speaker 0: So I run into hikers and sometimes they try to talk to me.
Speaker 0: every single time I've ever run into someone on the mountain with a couple exceptions.
Speaker 0: They start talking to me and I have either have to make an excuse and get away or be stuck there for like a half Hour while they talk at me.
Speaker 1: That's another thing.
Speaker 1: is that the way we live is that we have these very separated houses.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's our house and there's some car dealers and there's a Big buffer and then a neighbor's house.
Speaker 0: That's great Cuz.
Speaker 0: I want to be able to make a lot of noise and do whatever I want and not be bothering.
Speaker 1: making noise is good But I would trade the you know freedom to make lots of noise if it was a whole lot more people.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't not unless it was cool geeky people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm all about just people.
Speaker 0: if you're so How come you don't know anyone in town?
Speaker 0: Because it's you know, how come whenever the old lady is talking to us?
Speaker 0: You're always trying to get away from her because the old lady's kind of annoying everyone.
Speaker 1: She talks too much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a lot of people around here like that.
Speaker 0: That's why I avoid people.
Speaker 1: now It's still you know, when you it's good you never.
Speaker 1: I think you just never lived in a place.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it is friendly and when I lived in Detroit on a Harvard Street.
Speaker 0: Oh everyone we know all the neighbors and we'd sit on the porch at night.
Speaker 0: A lot of people would walk by.
Speaker 0: we lived on Berkshire.
Speaker 0: It was the same way.
Speaker 0: we had other family who lived like next door and down the street and I remember I used there's an Old lady's house next door and we knew them and we'd walk around the neighborhood.
Speaker 0: We knew other people and it was fun for a really little kid.
Speaker 0: But as an adult, I don't have time for that.
Speaker 0: My life's too short to be bother.
Speaker 1: It's like when you go to Wildwood and you know, Scott Johnson's dad's friends are all walking around and it's all friendly.
Speaker 0: You know, I could care less about that.
Speaker 0: I'd rather just surround myself with all of my friends and meet new people I can actually talk to.
Speaker 1: and that's the problem with America's people aren't being friendly anymore.
Speaker 0: I'd rather people be honest than be fake friendly.
Speaker 1: It's not fake friendly real friendly Honest friendly.
Speaker 0: I'll say that there probably is a lot of fake friendly.
Speaker 1: It probably is but there's real friendly and that's the way it used to be see friendly to me.
Speaker 0: All you need is if you see someone on the street and you're not Adam and they nod back and then you go about your business you Suck, what do you want?
Speaker 0: I don't want to bother with people.
Speaker 0: I don't have any interest to share with.
Speaker 0: I don't want to spend any time with people that I can't in any way have an intellectual conversation Because intellectual conversations the only reason to interact with any people or to have fun or edges.
Speaker 0: I can't.
Speaker 0: I don't have fun.
Speaker 0: I mean, I've got a lot of company picnics and things like that and I'll admit that they were mostly horrible and boring.
Speaker 0: I only went because they were during work hours.
Speaker 0: So I got out of work and I still got paid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would never have gone to a single event with any of my jobs if I weren't paid to do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I was even friends with some of the people at my jobs.
Speaker 0: I just had no desire.
Speaker 0: They weren't fun.
Speaker 0: It was a bunch of people standing around making small talk.
Speaker 0: No one said anything.
Speaker 0: really non small talk.
Speaker 0: ish ever.
Speaker 1: What do you know?
Speaker 0: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: What do I know?
Speaker 0: That's how things are.
Speaker 1: You're just an ass.
Speaker 1: I'm not an ass and you're like, yeah, all you people are peons.
Speaker 1: You're not worth my time.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna spend any time with you.
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: what I expect them to attitude is that see I Expect them to look at me the same way.
Speaker 0: They have.
Speaker 0: they have no interest to share with me.
Speaker 0: Why would they want to spend their time on me?
Speaker 0: Yeah, if neither one of us have any shared interest then what kind of conversation could we possibly have?
Speaker 1: it's not just about conversation.
Speaker 1: What's it's about just having a community of people who join together and not just a bunch of separate Isolated people who don't communicate and aren't friendly and are just no hold up in their own little, you know Isolated TV watch and not caring about anyone else places.
Speaker 1: I don't watch TV But what would you rather live in a you know?
Speaker 1: Happy town?
Speaker 1: or people walk down the street and you know the names of everybody and everyone's friendly or do you rather live in a place or everything's quiet and everyone's in their house and no one cares about anyone else on the street and Everyone does their own thing and it's
Speaker 0: all I know why I'd rather live.
Speaker 0: I'd rather live in a college campus where everyone was generally awesome and you had both and you.
Speaker 0: everyone was friendly with everyone.
Speaker 0: You knew all these people.
Speaker 0: there were people walking around talking all the time, you know a million people all over campus.
Speaker 0: You have a million acquaintances But you're also surrounded by awesome people who have like interests.
Speaker 0: and the community Isn't just based on the fact that everyone in the community happens to live in the same physical place.
Speaker 0: It's based around the fact that everyone has generally common goals and interests.
Speaker 1: They're all the people who live in the same physical place have a lot of common goals and interests.
Speaker 1: Not really they do pertaining to the place in which they live.
Speaker 1: It's like Scott.
Speaker 0: We live in a commuter town.
Speaker 0: Most of the places around here are commuter towns.
Speaker 1: Yeah, most of the why it's kind of crummy.
Speaker 0: I think it's fine.
Speaker 0: I like beacon a lot.
Speaker 1: All right, whatever.
Speaker 1: Let's do the actual show bit.
Speaker 0: I'm just I'd you you talk about this.
Speaker 0: if you never make any effort to go see normal people out there non geeks Because this is the kind of place doesn't isn't Scott?
Speaker 0: actually it is the the city of beacon and the people in it are really really really townie.
Speaker 0: beacon has this huge Reputation in the whole county for being a really really townie and everyone knows each other and they all go to the festivals together And they all go to the pub crawls together and they all climb the mountain for fun all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can't do that.
Speaker 0: You haven't gone to a single town festival and they happen regularly because I'm out of town on the weekend.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, you've been home for several.
Speaker 0: I've gone to some of them and you stayed home.
Speaker 1: Those aren't like real Scott.
Speaker 0: you realize that even the the the weekly farmers market half the town goes.
Speaker 0: is this huge thing?
Speaker 0: There's a crazy number of people and all these booths and crafts and music and everyone hanging out and having a grand old time Every single Sunday that happens.
Speaker 1: you've never gone once Because I'm doing stuff like oh, oh, so what's the point of having the community if you would see you're not going to the Farmers market to be friendly with people.
Speaker 1: you're going to buy some farmers goods and come back.
Speaker 0: Yes, and the thing is that's because I know what I want and I get it.
Speaker 0: but you say you want something yet You don't put forth any effort to get it.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying is I like a place?
Speaker 1: that's like that.
Speaker 0: This town is like it But it's not like on my street.
Speaker 1: it's all the way over there at the farmers.
Speaker 0: Well, that's just because you happen to live a couple blocks away from the center of town where everyone is I know but that's I'm saying is I want to live, you know You're saying you want to live a quarter mile further down the road.
Speaker 1: That'll be nice.
Speaker 0: It wouldn't be any different.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it would.
Speaker 1: I don't see how you've never lived in a place like that.
Speaker 1: So, what do you know?
Speaker 0: Berkshire was just like that and isn't it great?
Speaker 0: No, I was indifferent.
Speaker 0: I was a little kid.
Speaker 0: I didn't care You suck.
Speaker 0: These were just all these adults trying to talk over the kids heads, even though the kids weren't stupid We all knew what they were saying.
Speaker 1: Anyway, let's do the show.
Speaker 1: All right, how long do we spend on that?
Speaker 0: We pretty much did a whole show on that.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's no good.
Speaker 0: We can talk for about 10 minutes.
Speaker 1: They think our main bits gonna take more than 10 minutes.
Speaker 0: Not really I don't know.
Speaker 0: there's not so much to say.
Speaker 0: it's a very cut-and-dry issue All right.
Speaker 1: So a lot of people lately seem to be confused about this concept of burden of proof.
Speaker 0: Mostly people in our own forums, you know who you will know.
Speaker 0: you don't know who you are.
Speaker 1: Well, mostly people in the United States who do not understand science.
Speaker 0: All right, let's before we get into it.
Speaker 0: Let's do a couple examples and then we'll go from there.
Speaker 0: I think we can illustrate the point very succinctly.
Speaker 1: All right, you ready?
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: Hey rim Yeah, did you know that I'm actually the fifth resurrection of Hitler?
Speaker 0: fifth that can't be because I'm the sixth.
Speaker 1: Oh Well, see here's the perfect example.
Speaker 1: I have claimed that I am the fifth resurrection of Hitler.
Speaker 0: now This is a claim that is extraordinary.
Speaker 1: now take as an alter even if it's an ordinary claim It doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: but extraordinary claims are especially You know, well now let's take I got my own counterclaim.
Speaker 0: All right Today I had an Italian combo sandwich.
Speaker 1: Oh, did you now?
Speaker 0: I'm actually lying.
Speaker 0: I had an Italian BMT Mm-hmm, but I said I have an Italian combo and My claim was an ordinary claim.
Speaker 1: So the question is if I say that I'm the fifth resurrection of Hitler and you try to say no you're not How do I you know who has to prove?
Speaker 1: can I just say well you can't prove I'm not the fifth resurrection of Hitler.
Speaker 1: Therefore I am.
Speaker 0: But meanwhile, I could say you can't prove I didn't eat an Italian BMT or an Italian combo Whichever one I said because I don't remember.
Speaker 1: now You said Italian combo you ate a BMT.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I did eat a BMT.
Speaker 0: I remember now because I had pepperoni on it.
Speaker 1: So the question is is it up to rim to prove that I'm not The fifth resurrection of Hitler?
Speaker 1: and if he doesn't if he fails to prove that I'm not I automatically am or is it?
Speaker 1: I have to prove that I am the fifth resurrection of Hitler.
Speaker 1: Otherwise, I'm not now.
Speaker 0: first Let's look at the ordinary claim because ordinary claims are very easy to solve and second ordinary claims rarely matter.
Speaker 0: Yep So I said that I ate the Italian combo when actually the truth is I ate the BMT.
Speaker 0: But if I claim that I ate the Italian combo Scott doesn't need to prove.
Speaker 0: I mean he needs to prove me wrong.
Speaker 0: I don't need to prove I'm right because one the matter is trivial and two it's a falsifiable claim Meaning it is possible to be proven wrong Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: so if it became a matter of Scott had to prove me wrong because I Murdered some guy and my alibi is that I was eating the one instead of the other and if I ate the BMT then That means I'm the killer.
Speaker 1: then Oh cheap cheap murder mysteries that are like two pages long.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah Then if Scott the burden of proof is on Scott because he has to prove that I ate the BMT.
Speaker 0: Meanwhile, I don't have to prove anything.
Speaker 0: I made a normal ordinary credit claim.
Speaker 0: I mean if I say yeah, I saw a cloud today.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah I'm pretty sure you saw cloud today.
Speaker 0: Yeah, an ordinary claim is a claim that doesn't put forth any sort of extra Baggage, it's hard to really put it succinctly without using, you know, stupid logical terms that half of you would try not care about.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but if my claim does not affect your worldview does not affect the world does not counter any Widely held reasonably accepted claims and does not go against accepted scientific theory There is no reason to doubt it and there is no reason for me to have to back it up Every time I say 2 plus 2 is 4.
Speaker 0: I don't have to prove that 2 plus 2 is 4.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Now let's go to Scott's claim about Hitler.
Speaker 1: I I'm the fifth resurrection of Hitler now one.
Speaker 0: If Scott's claim is true, then the following are also true Resurrection is possible.
Speaker 0: Hitler is back.
Speaker 0: Scott is the resurrection of Hitler.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm Jewish.
Speaker 0: Now this this has all sorts of ramifications for the world.
Speaker 0: it has all sorts of baggage.
Speaker 0: it goes against Accepted theory.
Speaker 0: it goes against accepted knowledge.
Speaker 0: It goes against accepted everything.
Speaker 0: the burden of proof is on Scott.
Speaker 0: I don't have to prove that he's not Hitler because that's just stupid.
Speaker 0: Scott has to prove that he's Hitler or his claim is effectively to be ignored by anyone who has a brain.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if it's basically what is it false by default?
Speaker 1: or is it true by default?
Speaker 1: and generally everything in the whole universe?
Speaker 1: any statement or claim you can make is Automatically, I don't know by default Technically speaking and then yeah, we're not gonna get into Gnosticism.
Speaker 1: Yeah Oh, but the point is when you say something even if it's a negative something like let's say I say that A red mushroom gives you an extra life in Mario 1 and rim says no a red mushroom does not Give you an extra life in Mario 1. those are both claims even though one of them is a negative claim.
Speaker 1: If you make a claim you have to provide evidence for your claim.
Speaker 1: if you do not provide evidence Then you got nothing.
Speaker 0: So if I say that I am actually an elf let's say mm-hmm Now I've got to prove that I'm actually an elf because that again has all this baggage and I'm the one making the claim.
Speaker 0: I'm the one asserting that there's a truth in the world a truth that has far-reaching ramifications Yep, and therefore you must provide the evidence now Even if it doesn't have far-reaching ramifications.
Speaker 0: if it's an ordinary claim, let's say I say I am a man Or now to bed the same.
Speaker 0: it's the same argument.
Speaker 0: I'm making a claim and I have to back it up.
Speaker 0: However, because it's an ordinary claim my claim does not in any way impede or go against accepted knowledge.
Speaker 1: I don't have to back it up because there's already so much evidence out there.
Speaker 1: It's just already.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't matter if my claim is true or not.
Speaker 0: So if you want to challenge my claim you can but I'm not forced by default to back it up because he's already got a Mountain of existing evidence, which is pretty obvious.
Speaker 1: It's obvious evidence.
Speaker 0: The key here is extraordinary claims.
Speaker 0: that the quote that says it best is very simply.
Speaker 0: Extraordinary claims require extraordinary evidence, right?
Speaker 1: Let's say I make an extraordinary claim like I can fly without you know, I can fly.
Speaker 1: I like Superman, right?
Speaker 1: Now rim will come up and say you can't fly like Superman can't fly like ten Superman's and I'll say yes I can.
Speaker 1: I'm just not doing it right now and I'm not gonna do it when anyone can see.
Speaker 1: You can't prove.
Speaker 1: you can't prove that I can't fly like Superman.
Speaker 1: Therefore I can fly like Superman.
Speaker 1: and well, it is possible that that could be true.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is indeed a possibility.
Speaker 1: However, you don't believe me.
Speaker 1: It's crazy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if I believe if I take Scott's claim without him providing evidence for it because it's an extraordinary claim.
Speaker 0: I'm an idiot.
Speaker 1: Yep, it's up to me with my crazy claim to provide evidence.
Speaker 1: if I can't provide any evidence That's that proves and at least partially proves if not fully proves that I can indeed fly like Superman.
Speaker 1: For example flying like Superman when someone can see Then I'm full of crap.
Speaker 1: and that's how it works.
Speaker 1: So next time you argue with someone and they say you can't prove me wrong You say no, the burden of proof is on you.
Speaker 1: You made a claim.
Speaker 1: Therefore you must provide evidence to support that claim.
Speaker 1: if you cannot provide evidence to support your claim You are wrong by default.
Speaker 1: if your claim is extraordinary Yeah, in fact the only day I don't you know, you don't need there's nothing can be proven wrong.
Speaker 0: a hundred percent I mean, well, no things can be proven wrong.
Speaker 0: It's a lot of things, right?
Speaker 0: Basically you prove you you make an assertion Especially in science and you test it and ivory test you do.
Speaker 0: you've done a thousand tests.
Speaker 0: all say yes This looks like it's true.
Speaker 0: The evidence supports it.
Speaker 0: You can't ever prove it a hundred percent.
Speaker 0: But you can prove it wrong because the moment you have a counterexample the whole thing is proven wrong.
Speaker 0: Oh, look, it didn't work because of that.
Speaker 1: There is crap It's true, but just because you know, let's say you didn't do those a thousand yes tests, right?
Speaker 1: You just did.
Speaker 1: you know the one other test.
Speaker 1: am I thinking this right?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: It's very.
Speaker 0: it's much simpler if we go with.
Speaker 0: there are two kinds of arguments You want to really get into it over?
Speaker 0: The nature of something as it is or the nature of something as we have defined it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so we're.
Speaker 0: if we're talking about, you know, if I say this thing I'm holding up as a picture of food from samurai Champloo, I am indeed holding up a picture of food right now.
Speaker 0: and see it is now because we both agree on what food is.
Speaker 0: I can make the claim that this is food and it can be proven a hundred percent by evidence.
Speaker 0: Yep But natural world things can't be proven a hundred percent Because we don't have an objective viewpoint and we didn't make up the rules.
Speaker 0: Yep But that that's a whole topic for another day.
Speaker 1: Yes So if I say I have magic powers and I say you can't prove I don't have magic powers And you can't because you can't prove I don't have magic powers.
Speaker 1: It's not possible.
Speaker 1: That doesn't mean I have magic powers.
Speaker 1: It means that I have to prove I have magic powers or else I don't.
Speaker 0: the burden of proof is always on the person making the claim.
Speaker 1: now Let's say I'm standing here and I you know just standing and rim comes up and says you don't have magic powers.
Speaker 1: And that's his claim.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I've still made a claim.
Speaker 0: I've made a negative claim I've stepped forth and made an assertion.
Speaker 1: then he has to you know, then his claim requires evidence.
Speaker 1: I'm like do you have any evidence that I don't have magic powers?
Speaker 1: because I'm not saying I do.
Speaker 1: He's just saying I don't.
Speaker 0: and of course then I can try it.
Speaker 0: I can try to force Scott to do all these magic tricks and he fails at all of them and I try to make him fly He can't and all these things.
Speaker 0: then I've effectively brought forth more and more evidence that my claim is in fact true and Like say it say in science.
Speaker 0: now We talk about evolution.
Speaker 0: people make the claim that evolution is happening.
Speaker 0: evolution has happened and we've studied it and studied it and we keep making Evidences like well, what about this situation?
Speaker 0: Hey, it works.
Speaker 0: What about this evidence?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it fits.
Speaker 0: We're getting closer and closer to saying you know what it's very likely to be true when there's no reason to say it's not true.
Speaker 1: Yes, you make a claim and the claim is backed up by evidence.
Speaker 1: you make a negative claim.
Speaker 1: The claim is backed up by evidence.
Speaker 0: an extraordinary claim is one by which there for which there is not any Extant evidence or at least any known extent evidence as ghosts.
Speaker 1: The Ghostbusters are real.
Speaker 0: Yeah, saying evolution happened is not an extraordinary claim.
Speaker 0: There are mountains of science backing that up saying that the Markian evolution happened.
Speaker 1: There's mountains of evidence against the Markian evolution.
Speaker 0: So if I want if I if ice claim that Lamar can evolution happened I better provide some crazy freakin evidence to back that up because there's already all this evidence saying it isn't true.
Speaker 0: So it would require crazy extraordinary evidence.
Speaker 0: Yes, which I probably can't provide because Lamar can evolution probably didn't happen.
Speaker 1: So just because you have a claim that cannot be proven wrong doesn't make it true.
Speaker 1: nothing is true unless it has evidence behind it and extraordinary things that are crazy and not normal require Incredible amounts of evidence because they're so crazy if it's a normal everyday thing.
Speaker 1: You don't need so much evidence because it's not crazy.
Speaker 1: That's how it works.
Speaker 1: So next time if someone says something crazy If they you know, and then they say you can't prove it wrong.
Speaker 1: Well, of course, you can't prove it wrong.
Speaker 1: There's a lot of things you can't prove wrong.
Speaker 1: You can't prove that.
Speaker 1: I'm not God.
Speaker 1: You can't prove that rim doesn't have magic powers.
Speaker 1: You can't prove that I totally have magic power.
Speaker 0: You can't prove that.
Speaker 1: fairies, you know don't exist you can't.
Speaker 0: you know, there's a lot of things You can't disprove that are all false because it's really hard to do things now And just to head off any people who might disagree with that bit right there.
Speaker 0: We're talking about Pedantic and semantic arguments.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm the real I mean the real world is false.
Speaker 0: You can't ever prove anything.
Speaker 0: a hundred percent due to a lot of very complicated Philosophical and scientific ideas.
Speaker 0: Yes, which we'll get into on another day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because I know we've already gone long.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because we did two shows about how.
Speaker 1: I don't think of it.
Speaker 1: Hey, I think it was the thing today about a kid on roller skates.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 0: We almost went into the similar thing about the marriage the household thing.
Speaker 0: We just cut it short on purpose.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we could have done three episodes tonight.
Speaker 0: Uh That's fine.
Speaker 0: It's Thursday.
Speaker 0: All right Once again, I'd like to say that we are going to uber con this weekend.
Speaker 0: on Saturday.
Speaker 0: We are at least I am a guest.
Speaker 0: Scott will be there.
Speaker 1: yeah, we'll see how this turns out.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna have words.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it'll be fun.
Speaker 0: I think uber con will be a fun time.
Speaker 1: as always I just show up and be like, hey you sent him a one you didn't send me one.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is I would have gone to uber con even if they didn't want us to do a panel.
Speaker 1: I also would we weren't getting in free.
Speaker 0: So it's not a big deal at all.
Speaker 1: I'll just say something and if they go and no, I'll be like, alright fine.
Speaker 1: I'll pay.
Speaker 1: Yep, but I'll still I'll say something.
Speaker 0: I think we're really gonna bust out at the next uber con.
Speaker 0: I think we're gonna go the whole weekend.
Speaker 1: Maybe maybe want to see.
Speaker 0: I really want to.
Speaker 0: yeah, it depends depends on a lot of things And also a lot of people in our forums have noticed that.
Speaker 0: well They were talking about the dice jewelry that our friend Nury was making.
Speaker 0: Oh, there was talked about a while ago.
Speaker 0: The thread disappeared somewhat recently because people people in our forums are very fickle and a thread Will flash and get like 40 posts and then suddenly everyone forgets about it and it disappears.
Speaker 0: Sorrow well sinks to the second page.
Speaker 1: what a neglected thread.
Speaker 0: where dragons sit.
Speaker 0: Dragons be there there be dragons on the second page of the forums there be.
Speaker 0: But she now has her website up and you can buy custom and semi custom and not custom Dice earrings as in Dungeons & Dragons.
Speaker 0: dice and dice jewelry that are really kind of cool and this isn't an advertisement or anything.
Speaker 0: It's actually really cool and she's a good friend of ours.
Speaker 1: So many sided dice.
Speaker 1: more than six sides sometimes less than six sides I mean one.
Speaker 0: Scott John from her got this giant d30 Hanging on a chain that he wears around.
Speaker 0: It's kind of gaudy You know But it's gaudy in an awesome 70s way.
Speaker 0: imagine him at a nightclub with a polyester suit and is a big You know big collared shirt with the top.
Speaker 1: That's exactly the kind of gaudy it is.
Speaker 0: Yeah with the with the chest hair hanging out of the giant d30 hanging there.
Speaker 0: That is an awesome aesthetic for that kind of thing.
Speaker 1: it is D&D was made in the 70s.
Speaker 0: So yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah plus I got to say I really like disco.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'll say straight up that I like disco and You know what?
Speaker 0: I'm making a claim disco is awesome and I have extraordinary evidence.
Speaker 1: No, I also have the evidence.
Speaker 1: Yes, I believe we'll have to bring it up some other day and you know Just saying you can't prove the disco isn't awesome isn't enough.
Speaker 0: And that was geek nights with rim and Scott.
Speaker 0: special thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1 537.
Speaker 0: geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.