Speaker 0: It's Thursday September 21st, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: We discuss.
Speaker 0: Why ice hockey is awesome.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: You know I really can't complain about my job because they pay me better than IBM.
Speaker 1: I make quite a bit of money considering how little work.
Speaker 1: I do at least in terms of technical work.
Speaker 1: But I'm kind of thinking about looking for a new job already.
Speaker 1: Why did you get this job up like four months ago?
Speaker 0: You know I'm thinking about quitting the job that I've had for two years.
Speaker 0: Four months.
Speaker 1: when I first got to IBM the main reason I could bear it Was because I knew that I was going back to RIT and the day I went back to RIT from my first stint at IBM was like the happiest day in.
Speaker 1: Well, not that it was at least in the top five of happiest days in my life Mmm because first off I was poor, but then I worked for IBM for a while.
Speaker 1: I had like $7,000 in the bank.
Speaker 1: I had just spent a month living in Wildwood, New Jersey going to the beach every day with Scott Johnson.
Speaker 1: And now I was back at RIT the president of the anime club a badass senior taking nothing But awesome classes.
Speaker 0: life was absolutely perfect, and that's why he was so expensive.
Speaker 0: It's like oh you want some awesome life.
Speaker 0: Well you had to pay like a hajillion dollars.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know what two months later that $7,000 was gone.
Speaker 1: My car was almost repossessed, and I had to rely on the the Sympathy of cute girls to actually give me food.
Speaker 0: This is the way of things you know.
Speaker 0: tomorrow speaking of work tomorrow There's actually people come into my work.
Speaker 0: I'm not really yeah, they're they're coming I see at first earlier in the week.
Speaker 0: They emailed me.
Speaker 0: They're like are you gonna be there on Friday?
Speaker 0: I'm like yeah, they're like oh cuz we're coming to see you.
Speaker 0: We wanted to know make sure you were there.
Speaker 0: It's like okay.
Speaker 0: either They're coming to fire me.
Speaker 0: Which is a you know maybe cool, or They don't expect me to actually go to this place every day.
Speaker 0: They want to know if I was gonna be there.
Speaker 1: You know what they probably figured.
Speaker 1: He we haven't had him do anything in a while.
Speaker 1: He probably doesn't even go there.
Speaker 0: Well, they you know I'm technically doing something, but there's like no deadline or anything.
Speaker 0: I'm just kind of you know have these open Tasks and I work on slowly and whenever they ask me to report on my progress.
Speaker 0: They're very pleased.
Speaker 0: so I don't see I did.
Speaker 1: I handled because I had the same situation IBM.
Speaker 1: I'd absolutely no deadlines And they pretty much would give me systems or goals and say have at do what you can.
Speaker 1: I would do as much as I could because I had nothing else to do at work.
Speaker 1: I mean you can only surf the internet for so long.
Speaker 1: yeah Yeah, but when you go to FARC the fourth time and it still hasn't updated There's nothing left to do on the internet.
Speaker 0: See what I generally do is I get to work I go to everything once and then I'm done with that for like you know until like five Minutes.
Speaker 0: no until like the end of the day, but I'll check my email one.
Speaker 1: No.
Speaker 1: That's a horseshit.
Speaker 1: You're constantly chatting with me over aim, and you post in the forum somewhat regularly.
Speaker 1: You're always.
Speaker 0: I keep the forums in the email open.
Speaker 0: yeah everything else.
Speaker 1: See basically I work and read FARC and read our forum and read slash dot and chat Simultaneously no matter where I am and yet I do enough work to where they're always very pleased with what I do.
Speaker 1: It's kind of weird.
Speaker 0: the thing is like I replaced the time I would do work.
Speaker 0: I end up like reading a comic or see I can't do anything like GBA game.
Speaker 0: I mean I guess he has game.
Speaker 1: the thing is I do all the work I can do it's.
Speaker 1: it's not that I'm slacking from work at this new job It's more that the work is all just kind of stupid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like it's all it's all paperwork and bureaucracy and every now and then someone wants to know something technical and There is no way they understand when I explain whatever they ask to them like.
Speaker 1: people ask me like.
Speaker 1: But the only people ask me things like how do I make this kind of formula in Excel?
Speaker 1: Oh my god, and I'm like equals the math.
Speaker 1: well No, he wanted something really complicated and weird and I was like.
Speaker 1: I don't know I could write it for you but I'll have to sit down and relearn that crap and look at the syntax a little bit.
Speaker 1: and It was like yeah, what do you know?
Speaker 1: but yet people ask me things like blah blah blah Linux.
Speaker 1: And I'm like blah blah blah blah Colonel blah blah blah blah blah like what.
Speaker 1: what did you just say?
Speaker 0: yeah?
Speaker 1: I said there's an instance recently where we needed some vendor needs remote access to some software.
Speaker 1: I can't say anything about who or what but they require PC anywhere, which is some remote access.
Speaker 1: Oh god That's not the thing.
Speaker 1: I'm getting to okay now.
Speaker 1: I go to my one of my managers, and I say all right we need a VPN To or no?
Speaker 1: we need remote access to this box via.
Speaker 1: they want PC anywhere.
Speaker 1: And I'm about to say you think we can convince them to use something else.
Speaker 1: and the guy said no PC Anywhere is crap.
Speaker 1: I agree, and I think we.
Speaker 1: then he says we'll just give them VPN access To which I said But VPN doesn't do what we need done.
Speaker 1: VPN doesn't do anything by itself.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you need a little more than that I.
Speaker 0: That's all there's.
Speaker 1: just like it goes on there's just no one's technical.
Speaker 1: I'm in an IT firm that does a lot of awesome stuff, but no one really knows a lot about the technology at all.
Speaker 1: It's kind of frightening.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I guess that would be frightening, but anyway.
Speaker 0: No they're not coming to fire me they're not.
Speaker 0: they're coming to bring the new furniture to this empty office where only I work and They told me to bring a box cutter to work tomorrow.
Speaker 0: We have one right?
Speaker 1: no Okay, I have one.
Speaker 0: Uh I'll just buy one at the hardware store on the way to work.
Speaker 1: I wouldn't bring out if I bribed my work said to buy a tool and bring it to work.
Speaker 0: I didn't say to buy a tool.
Speaker 0: They said bring one.
Speaker 0: if you have one I wouldn't bring one.
Speaker 1: Of course then again my work won't let me crimp cables or anything so I can't even bring all my tools to work.
Speaker 0: Wow well Anyway, the point is is that hey, you know they think I'm doing a great job and tomorrow They're gonna be like hey, what's up?
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's weird.
Speaker 1: We both work for companies that think we're doing a great job, and yet.
Speaker 1: We're doing maybe 2% of what we could be doing for them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think you know as soon as like I you know don't have things to distract me from doing work.
Speaker 1: You know what the most common joke people make when they walk by my cube at work is They see me typing or they hear me typing and I type really fast And they always say something like slow down you'll get us all fired.
Speaker 1: Hey yuk yuk yuk Wow like what are you trying to do?
Speaker 1: put us out of a job or the Union will get you.
Speaker 0: You should be like if I was the manager.
Speaker 0: you would be a homeless bum.
Speaker 1: I mean they all do their jobs.
Speaker 1: It's just I'm sitting with a bunch of administrative types, and I don't have any contact with the technical people But yet I'm paid more than some of the technical.
Speaker 1: I don't get it.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's like I'm lower middle management at this point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I need a job being like see the thing is right now I'm like an individual worker But after working on teams Forcing to be working on teams like forever I really I want to work on a team of like a bunch of guys who are smarter than me.
Speaker 1: Working on teams is great because in the corporate world I found that team means you are no longer responsible for anything that's done.
Speaker 1: everyone else is stupid and won't do their work.
Speaker 1: and When the axe comes to chop off the heads of everyone who fucked it up You'll have all the copies of the emails you sent to people tell them what to do And proof that they didn't respond to.
Speaker 0: work on like one big piece of software with a bunch of other Programmers who are all smarter than me and then I'll actually work hard and it'll be awesome.
Speaker 0: That's what I want.
Speaker 0: or even better I have a bunch of programmers who were less smart than me.
Speaker 0: But I'll be like the team like boss and I'll have to organize these dudes and get them to do my bidding.
Speaker 1: Let me put it this way.
Speaker 1: I have never in all of my years of work been given a task.
Speaker 1: That was not either impossible as in actually impossible or So unbelievably mundane.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, there's never been a challenging interesting project like all the projects.
Speaker 0: They've given me are pretty much it.
Speaker 0: That's my real problem.
Speaker 0: The reason I'm not like, you know, super excited on finishing all the work right away Is because the work I'm given the projects they assigned to me aren't anything that requires thinking or solving of problems.
Speaker 0: It's simply implementing a known solution.
Speaker 0: It's like.
Speaker 0: I already know how to make Scott you realize Database driven website.
Speaker 0: I just had to make like a million database driven websites that are real big and I'm there.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 0: It's well, you realize.
Speaker 0: so it's not mindless.
Speaker 0: God God.
Speaker 1: You realize that probably less than 1% of companies needs you to solve unsolved problems.
Speaker 0: There doesn't have to be an unsolved problem.
Speaker 0: It has to be a problem that I haven't solved.
Speaker 1: um, the vast majority of computer science work is writing bullshit little programs for companies that don't realize a solution already exists or Customizing something that already exists for a company just like IT.
Speaker 1: It's all just support or like putting in a network or building a server.
Speaker 1: There's nothing special.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's work out there.
Speaker 1: See I got some hope though because next week I've been invited to have breakfast with the CEO of the company.
Speaker 0: Didn't you see the CEO of the company before?
Speaker 1: Yeah with a whole bunch of new hire people and I asked him one technical question and he didn't really answer it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, but this is a smaller thing and I'm pretty much gonna tell him straight up a thing I think the company can do to make a shit ton of money and I'm gonna try to convince him to put me in Charge of it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I'm just gonna go balls out.
Speaker 0: That's a good idea Cuz I never tried, you know, you always think is something like that And I'm not gonna say what it is.
Speaker 1: cuz you know the what.
Speaker 1: it's weird.
Speaker 1: This company didn't make me sign any NDA's.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they're really.
Speaker 1: I don't know what they're thinking.
Speaker 1: cuz I probably could talk about all this stuff But I'm not going to because if I work for any of the other companies I've worked for they'd kill me if I said what I could say Yeah, no but that's great because I used to think you know.
Speaker 0: trying to tell the bosses what to do or act like you know better and Tell them all your crazy ideas is a dumb thing because 99 percent of the time your ideas are dumb And you just don't know why because we're not businessmen.
Speaker 0: See no, but now I read a thing recently that says no you got to tell the crazy ideas.
Speaker 1: I used to think it depends Do you are you more worried about the chance of something awesome or the chance of a promotion?
Speaker 1: Because if you make the bosses look stupid Then you're probably never gonna get promoted even though you'll do good Unless your boss is one of those smart ones.
Speaker 1: or your idea is that good?
Speaker 0: Mmm, but I've learned because it also depends if your idea makes money.
Speaker 0: I mean it could be a great idea that makes no money.
Speaker 1: Well like an IBM I ran to a lot of situations where I'd say why don't we do X and the business guys all say?
Speaker 1: Because of blah blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: It's like a lot of times.
Speaker 0: you go be like hey Why don't we do this and buy one of these and we'll have perfect security because that is a spending thing that knows no money.
Speaker 1: That was never the answer.
Speaker 1: They gave me the answer.
Speaker 1: I was always given was no That's not how it's done.
Speaker 1: or know that you know?
Speaker 1: my SQL solution isn't Scalable buzzword buzzword.
Speaker 1: you need the enterprise Oracle buzzword buzzword because that's how the industry works And you just don't understand that.
Speaker 1: Oracle buzzword buzzword is better than those.
Speaker 0: people Need a bludgeon on the head because they don't know.
Speaker 1: that's the most of the industry.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they don't know shit.
Speaker 1: But anyway, maybe I'll tell you the idea off the air because if nothing else we should just start a company that does this.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I can't do the coding part because I'm not a coder at all But I got a handle on everything else anyway.
Speaker 1: News yeah news all right.
Speaker 1: I'll do mine first because you'll think this is stupid news all right.
Speaker 1: You'll hate it.
Speaker 1: Okay, I think it's great, and I think most people out there will agree with me.
Speaker 1: Okay.
Speaker 1: I hate McDonald's food.
Speaker 0: I also hate McDonald's food.
Speaker 1: I'm like not like for ideological reasons cuz I used to eat it when I was a kid.
Speaker 1: But McDonald's I ate it when I was a kid too and Burger King and pretty much any fast food other than a few Select items that a few select places and I've been known to eat a chicken McNugget and anything on the White Castle menu.
Speaker 1: Oh, I love White Castle.
Speaker 1: Yeah, makes me nauseous like McDonald's burgers Make me physically ill and I'll usually have diarrhea.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I get sick.
Speaker 0: Just looking at him.
Speaker 1: no I don't get sick looking at him, but I get sick if I actually eat them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I just don't eat fast food.
Speaker 0: however for rare rare occasions There is one.
Speaker 1: No There's one thing that is perhaps one of the greatest things ever given unto man by technology and that is the McDonald's breakfast bargo.
Speaker 1: McDonald's breakfast sandwiches are so Amazing.
Speaker 1: bargo.
Speaker 1: see you never had that experience of you know waking up at 9 o'clock And looking around and realizing that it's before 11.
Speaker 1: I can go and get a McDonald's breakfast.
Speaker 0: I mean, how many times I'll eat an eggo waffle.
Speaker 1: I'll better off now how many times would I go?
Speaker 1: eggos are disgusting, too.
Speaker 0: You're telling me eggos are disgusting, but a McDonald's breakfast is okay.
Speaker 1: So how many times would I go out?
Speaker 1: You know I wake up and it's like 10 10 and I think I want a McDonald's breakfast.
Speaker 1: I try to go get it But then they're not serving breakfast anymore because they stop serving it.
Speaker 1: well it seems that McDonald's Recognizes my plight and is trying to rectify this.
Speaker 1: you see the only reason McDonald's doesn't have breakfast all the time Is that the way their restaurant?
Speaker 1: well?
Speaker 1: I wouldn't call them a restaurant.
Speaker 1: the way their kitchen wouldn't call it a kitchen.
Speaker 1: the way they're they're processed food factory Mini mini food factory.
Speaker 1: the way their slot price is put together Is that you can only make a set number of things at one time.
Speaker 1: like things are dual purpose you can't make breakfast sandwiches and burgers at the same time.
Speaker 1: They've only retooled their kitchens a couple of times in the past and the last time they did it was fairly recent.
Speaker 1: all this stuff I read you don't care about.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna talk about making more efficient kitchens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know about making less efficient kitchens on purpose.
Speaker 1: Why it's like I said, I don't want to get into it.
Speaker 0: Oh god.
Speaker 1: I'll do a whole show on this shit all right now.
Speaker 0: The thing
Speaker 1: is they're talking about how they're gonna try to retool the kitchen so that they can have some breakfast items available 24/7 because places like Tim Hortons and Dunkin Donuts are starting to kill them in the late-night market Because the late-night market is comprised mostly of college students and punk kids who all want their breakfasts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, generally, that's that's what that is.
Speaker 0: a lot of people want breakfast.
Speaker 0: You know later, and I mean how many times to go to the diner for dinner and you get waffles or French toast.
Speaker 1: I probably ordered breakfast at diners more than I've ordered any other food at diners ever.
Speaker 0: yeah brats I think that's exactly right.
Speaker 0: I I mean yet.
Speaker 1: I know I rarely go to diners at breakfast time.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean until very recently I pretty much should only order breakfast at diners because I was always afraid that the other food would be Nasty.
Speaker 1: you know the foods not nasty.
Speaker 1: It's great until you get food poisoning.
Speaker 0: So breakfast is all.
Speaker 0: It's bread and sugar and fruit.
Speaker 1: Anyway, my nose a breakfast consists comprised mostly of egg meat more meat and more egg.
Speaker 0: egg and meat can also be included As long as that meat is bacon.
Speaker 1: No it's got to be sausage Canadian bacon.
Speaker 0: no it's not good.
Speaker 1: or a breakfast steak.
Speaker 0: I'm okay with the breakfast, and that's not good either.
Speaker 0: steak is a dinner.
Speaker 1: Anyway steak and eggs no.
Speaker 1: So what kind of BS news do you have?
Speaker 1: you can't beat the McDonald's breakfast.
Speaker 0: so link?
Speaker 0: You know the guy with the sword in the shield.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he's left-handed.
Speaker 1: Yep, you probably didn't know that.
Speaker 0: yeah, you probably never noticed.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: our listeners They probably all knew that.
Speaker 0: yeah, probably, but if you didn't know link you know link to quote who comes to town?
Speaker 1: He saved the day.
Speaker 0: yeah He has always been left-handed.
Speaker 0: The shield has always been held in the right is great and the sword has always been held in the left And that is the way it has been.
Speaker 0: however Zelda Wii is coming out and Apparently Miyamoto realized that most people are right-handed.
Speaker 1: so first off this news is basically a big Double deuce to anyone who's actually left-handed.
Speaker 0: well no no no cuz they get.
Speaker 0: so You know what happened was a lot of people were swinging the wheeze.
Speaker 0: you know sword with their right hand But would link is holding it in the left hand.
Speaker 0: that didn't work out so well You know cuz it's kind of weird to sweat feel like you're swinging a sword in your right But the guy on screen swings his left hand around.
Speaker 1: well You know there was a big controversy in counter-strike way back when they switched it from being left-handed to being right-handed.
Speaker 0: Well, you could choose.
Speaker 0: you could always configure.
Speaker 1: well Yeah, but it wasn't always obvious right away, and originally you couldn't and people bitch about it to no end.
Speaker 0: I like the right-handed guns actually in counter-strike better.
Speaker 1: Well.
Speaker 1: That's cuz.
Speaker 1: you started with those.
Speaker 0: No No, not really yeah, no I remember when they switched also, okay The reason I like right-handed guns better is because when I usually would hide on the left side Of an open doorway, and then I would come around the right So I'd be able to see the guy sooner and my gun wouldn't block him What
Speaker 1: is counter-strike?
Speaker 1: I usually hit on top of the door with a hostage stuck to me.
Speaker 0: that works, too anyway.
Speaker 0: anyway Zelda we they made it where link left-handed because links left-handed.
Speaker 0: But then they you know because they've realized people are right-handed, and they're gonna be swinging the sword They flipped the entire game.
Speaker 1: now That is not as stupid as you might think because they designed the game very precisely.
Speaker 1: So a lot of the puzzles were meant.
Speaker 1: so you're looking at it, and you'll react with your left hand to it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they'll be like a lot of fights.
Speaker 0: We're like let's say there's a bad guy, and you have to sneak around the bad guy and then hit him You know with a certain sword But if he's against a wall that can totally screw up the game making a guy harder to hit.
Speaker 0: and you know game design isn't As simple as you think.
Speaker 0: there's a lot to it.
Speaker 0: But if you just mirror the entire game including all the maps and all the levels and everything They don't do anything else.
Speaker 0: It's just what one switch and the whole thing's perfect.
Speaker 0: However, if you are left-handed there is going to be an option for left-handed link, but it won't be left-handed world.
Speaker 1: No, it'll be right-handed world And you'll be just like you are in real life a left-handed man or woman in a right-handed world.
Speaker 0: Yep, so you'll be used to that and there's no left or him.
Speaker 0: yeah The thing is you know people are still uncertain because there is still a GameCube version of Twilight.
Speaker 1: they already said that the GameCube version is also going to be flipped.
Speaker 0: did they cuz I?
Speaker 0: I didn't because I saw a Link that said so-and-so confirms GameCube version also flipped, but when I clicked on the link it didn't say anything like that.
Speaker 1: Oh, I didn't follow the link.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure at all.
Speaker 1: get it the link.
Speaker 0: I'm fairly not.
Speaker 0: link.
Speaker 0: yes I'm fairly certain that Nintendo won't release a game on two systems where one game is totally flipped from the other game.
Speaker 1: now Here's some brilliant marketing.
Speaker 1: if they did.
Speaker 1: they could have two different versions of the strategy guide.
Speaker 0: They could have a lot of nuts would probably buy both to get the full experience I might but not like right away like I'd wait for the GameCube version to be wicked cheap like five You know 20.
Speaker 1: how weird would that be to play like imagine playing Mario?
Speaker 1: Somebody make a flash version of Mario Brothers 1 that's identical except you play from right to left.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: We got to do that.
Speaker 0: That's brilliant genius.
Speaker 1: That'll get that.
Speaker 1: That is going to be the front row cruise project at least one level of it because we can do that.
Speaker 1: We can do that easily right to left Mario right to left Mario.
Speaker 0: But we just took Zelda 1 and we took the whole Matt every map and just went whoop like we kept the game exactly the same.
Speaker 0: We just flipped them the whole overworld.
Speaker 0: so the graveyard was in the top right instead of the top left.
Speaker 1: I think I'd rather do the Mario one because that would be so weird.
Speaker 0: God would that be?
Speaker 1: well the Zelda one wouldn't be that weird just like a new man.
Speaker 0: see you know This.
Speaker 0: the thing is is this problem was solved way back in the day by a very old game known as pitfall.
Speaker 1: You can go either way.
Speaker 0: you could go both ways in pitfall like a bisexual.
Speaker 0: Yes, Ted That was the joke, but the thing is in pitfall even though I was right-handed I would go left because it was easier to jump over the logs and the snakes and all that business because they would always come From the right.
Speaker 0: so you just keep running to the left and nothing would ever catch you because everything went at the same speed as Pitfall.
Speaker 1: Harry plus when you die.
Speaker 1: I don't recall which way it went But if you died you always started on the left side of whatever screen you died on.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 0: So if you did get hit while you ran onto a screen you'd skip over that screen immediately.
Speaker 0: It was pretty good, so yeah pitfall run to the left.
Speaker 0: Hello out there.
Speaker 0: We're on the air.
Speaker 0: It's hockey night tonight.
Speaker 0: Tension goes the whistle blows and the puck goes down the ice The goalie jumps and the players bump on.
Speaker 0: the fans all go insane.
Speaker 0: Someone roars Bobby scores at the good old hockey game.
Speaker 1: now This is the end of hockey fight week, so we have to end with pretty much the two best hockey fights ever.
Speaker 0: Well, there's one problem with that is I realized I used the best hockey fight ever as a thing of the day before hockey fight Week.
Speaker 0: what was I thinking?
Speaker 1: not only that but the best hockey fight?
Speaker 1: I ever saw personally.
Speaker 1: There is no video of it I can find.
Speaker 1: all I can say is that I was there and Every player on both teams was fighting except the two goalies who were staying out of it.
Speaker 1: Um the refs were fighting the managers the teams were fighting the coaches were fighting and the crowd was fighting.
Speaker 1: The crowd jumped onto the ice and there was a massive brawl My dad and my little brother, and I had to get the hell out of there.
Speaker 1: It was fantastic.
Speaker 0: Sweet now.
Speaker 1: no uh my hockey fight today is a very important historical hockey fight.
Speaker 1: that illustrates a number of points.
Speaker 1: I think it is the best way I could end hockey fight week.
Speaker 1: Now you might watch the video and wonder why is it in black and white rim?
Speaker 1: Why is there no sound?
Speaker 1: Why does it look like it's from the 50s?
Speaker 1: well?
Speaker 1: It's from?
Speaker 1: 1955 and it's of a very famous hockey player Maurice Richard of the Montreal Canadiens involved in a spectacular fight.
Speaker 1: Now one thing that you should notice when you watch this video is that hockey fights in 1955 looked exactly the same as hockey fights in 2006.
Speaker 1: Nothing's different.
Speaker 1: It looks like the guys fight.
Speaker 1: Jersey comes up guy gets knocked down They do that little dance where they're kind of like you want to fight The ref just kind of stand there and hold them.
Speaker 1: it's identical.
Speaker 1: hockey hasn't changed?
Speaker 0: Yeah, unlike all these other sports.
Speaker 1: well no hockey culture hasn't changed.
Speaker 1: hockey has changed quite a bit And in fact hockey has changed a lot this year in ways that we might touch on briefly at the end of this episode.
Speaker 1: Maybe.
Speaker 1: but no there's more to this fight than that.
Speaker 1: if it had just been an old hockey fight that wouldn't been anything.
Speaker 1: But Maurice Richard was a very very famous hockey player one of the most famous ever at least in Canada.
Speaker 1: he's effectively a national hero and In 1955 the fight you were watching you can't tell but he's fighting with some other player.
Speaker 1: I forget who it was.
Speaker 1: and While they're fighting the linesman Jerry LaFlamme comes in to break the fight up And he takes the linesman out to.
Speaker 1: Linesman is like a mini referee.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so he takes that guy out.
Speaker 1: You can't do that.
Speaker 1: that is a match penalty meaning you get banned from hockey for a while.
Speaker 1: So he was banned from hockey.
Speaker 1: as a result He'd the team lost the Stanley Cup to the Red Wings.
Speaker 1: as a result There was a riot where the president of the NHL was attacked by fans of the Canadians.
Speaker 1: It was absolute chaos.
Speaker 0: No, oh my god.
Speaker 0: Oh my god.
Speaker 1: So yes, this video is very cool, and I suggest you watch it Alright.
Speaker 0: my hockey fight since the you know Super-amazing hockey fight that lasted half a game or an entire period is already been used as a thing of the day in the past.
Speaker 0: I'm going to talk about just a hockey trip a guy.
Speaker 0: He got tripped and he fell down.
Speaker 0: However in the course of this the most famous picture in sports ever The most famous photograph in all of sports was taken.
Speaker 1: you've probably seen it.
Speaker 0: You've probably seen it.
Speaker 0: and if you haven't what's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: if you haven't seen this picture You don't know what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: You need to even if you never look at the things that they before ever Need to go to front row crew comm and click on this link and see this picture.
Speaker 0: now Let me set this up for you.
Speaker 0: this Bobby or who basically is probably the best defenseman in hockey ever.
Speaker 0: He changed what it meant to be a defenseman in ice hockey.
Speaker 0: He like used the most scoring defenseman ever like when he came out and you know started playing hockey for the Boston Bruins And then he just kept scoring more and more goals every season.
Speaker 0: and he was just like amazing Like, you know one of the like guys like on the Wayne Gretzky level.
Speaker 0: exhaust Wayne Gretzky's number one.
Speaker 0: so he's like in the next tier right under that, you know, the amazing hockey players of all time.
Speaker 0: and 1970 the Boston Bruins were in the Stanley Cup finals against the st Louis Blues who weren't as good and it was the fourth game.
Speaker 0: and the Bruins, you know They'd won the previous three games and they're probably gonna win the Stanley Cup on this night.
Speaker 0: Well Bobby or came in in his usual fashion.
Speaker 0: it was going to score a goal that was gonna be the game-winning goal and win him the Stanley Cup with his goal.
Speaker 0: as He was scoring this goal to win the Stanley Cup the greatest trophy ever made he got tripped and he was sent flying through the air headfirst and For a moment, he was.
Speaker 0: he was like few feet off the ice and he was completely horizontal Like Superman flying except he's about to fall on his face.
Speaker 0: And he he was.
Speaker 0: he knew he just won the Stanley Cup.
Speaker 0: So his arms were way up like whoa Hope.
Speaker 0: he was completely horizontal and at that exact moment Ray Lucey of the Boston Herald Pushed the button on his camera and he took perhaps the greatest picture in all sports ever.
Speaker 1: See, that's one thing about hockey that I mean.
Speaker 1: other sports have their iconic pictures.
Speaker 1: I mean there are famous pictures in soccer and everything but There are so many more of those kinds of pictures in hockey just because of the way hockey is.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so if you've never seen this picture, you don't know what I'm talking about.
Speaker 0: It might be called the dive the trip, you know, the Superman whatever It's Bobby.
Speaker 0: or if you search for Bobby or on Google Images, you're going to see this picture like a thousand times Bobby or our Bobby or one of the greatest hockey players ever most famous picture ever.
Speaker 0: go look at it.
Speaker 1: So anyway, we had you know hockey fight week for the last week and we're gonna end it with a bit of talk about hockey.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know a lot of geeks and nerds and people out there might not like ice hockey.
Speaker 0: They might not appreciate it as you know much as we do.
Speaker 1: They might be wondering what the hell what's up with these geeks and their hockey liking now, of course one I want to note that it's nerds who generally dislike sports because geek is a much more broad term and there are sports geeks.
Speaker 0: There are indeed.
Speaker 1: I mean there are people who are geeky about sports the way you're geeky about video games Yep, and so we decided to do a little episode.
Speaker 0: just a quick thing about why we like hockey so much and perhaps maybe You will begin to see hockey the way we see it and think it's awesome or perhaps not.
Speaker 1: now in the very least I know a lot of you are in college and if you're in college and you're in a place where there is hockey because there Aren't that many places you might be in college below the Messier line.
Speaker 0: And if that's the case, what can I say?
Speaker 1: or you might be in sub-saharan Africa or I don't know where there's not hockey.
Speaker 0: in A lot of places you pretty much have to either be in Europe Russia is a good place Ukraine is very good Canada all of Canada or the northern United States or Alaska.
Speaker 0: Are those the only places where hockey exists really?
Speaker 1: Well, we're hockey as we know.
Speaker 1: it exists.
Speaker 1: There's high elsewhere, but it's not the same field.
Speaker 1: hockey is what even when they have ice hockey down south It's not the same.
Speaker 0: No, it's not.
Speaker 1: It's not real ice hockey Of course what we had it's like.
Speaker 0: it's like when you know, if we tried to play cricket, it just wouldn't be cricket.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's just be us hurting ourselves with that flat bat.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the wicked googly.
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sure we have a listener now who's like in Britain or something.
Speaker 0: It was all about cricket.
Speaker 1: Actually a lot of people at IBM played cricket.
Speaker 1: And in fact, I got hit with a goddamn cricket ball.
Speaker 1: Well, I was trying to play volleyball one day.
Speaker 0: Were they from India?
Speaker 1: actually every one of them was yep.
Speaker 0: See in India crickets real big Yeah, and you know what?
Speaker 1: It was.
Speaker 1: I played a couple times with these guys.
Speaker 1: it was really fun.
Speaker 0: Slurpee Indian not the Obviously, yes Yes, the Native Americans were playing crickets and they might have been.
Speaker 0: They might have picked it up at some point.
Speaker 0: But no, no, the Slurpee Indians are all about cricket.
Speaker 0: Anyway, anyway
Speaker 1: now we're not really gonna go into the origins of how we got into hockey because suffice to say it's pretty much the Fact that I was born in Detroit Which is no and you know every like New York is the Big Apple and you know There's the Big Easy and all the names.
Speaker 1: first, you know cities the Sin City for Las Vegas Detroit in the Windy City Detroit is hockey town.
Speaker 0: It's I thought it was the Motor City or motel.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's most.
Speaker 1: the thing is it's called hockey town by most of the natives and in effect in all the NHL stuff, too They always call it hockey town.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm and Detroit takes hockey.
Speaker 0: Seriously, you know if you're in Detroit, I mean look at the other teams.
Speaker 0: They have to go on.
Speaker 1: they've got All right, I was gonna say other than the Lions the Tigers did pretty well this year.
Speaker 0: this year but not usually.
Speaker 0: They're not known for being great.
Speaker 0: They were great a long time Yeah, but I mean they're not like, you know a team that wins a lot there.
Speaker 0: They just happen to be good this year.
Speaker 0: They might know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the Pistons have had a long run of being very good Yeah, but no one cares about that.
Speaker 0: At least we don't care about Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well, the thing is in hockey people care more about hockey than they do about all the other sports combined.
Speaker 1: hockey is so big in Detroit.
Speaker 1: you might as well be in Canada.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Well, it's pretty close to Canada.
Speaker 0: So I think that has a lot to do with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: well when the Red Wings won the Stanley Cup in 1997 1996 when I was a freshman in high school at the end of that
Speaker 0: was 96 95
Speaker 1: when they won the Stanley Cup for The first time in however long the entire it's like southeastern half of the state Completely shut down the next day for the biggest frickin parade that the city had ever had.
Speaker 0: When the Rangers won the Stanley Cup in 94, you know who hadn't?
Speaker 0: they hadn't won since 1940. so that was what 54 years they hadn't won the Stanley Cup and they won it.
Speaker 0: There was a parade in New York City and everyone was crazy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was pretty much the same deal.
Speaker 1: I mean they gave us the day off school.
Speaker 0: I mean you don't see like they're being a parade.
Speaker 0: when the Yankees win the bit the World Series You know, but when the Rangers win the Stanley Cup goddamn parade.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is when the Red Wings won it again the same deal.
Speaker 1: when they won it again same deal.
Speaker 1: That's the one thing about hockey, you know.
Speaker 1: to jump right into remain discussion when anything happens in hockey It's like baseball is kind of this generic.
Speaker 1: Whoo.
Speaker 1: Oh, we did this.
Speaker 1: Oh, look.
Speaker 1: He's running to second base.
Speaker 1: Go go go go go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we got a home run.
Speaker 1: Oh my god our basketball.
Speaker 1: It's two points two points two three two two two two.
Speaker 1: Oh god, he missed two two two two three.
Speaker 1: But hockey is nothing nothing Uh-huh, uh-huh.
Speaker 1: But when something happens when a Gore is gold when a guy gets hit the crowd just goes absolutely fucking nuts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's kind of like football.
Speaker 0: football is sort of the same kind of mood.
Speaker 0: The only thing is that in football you basically have this nothing and then a play starts and then some maybe something happens.
Speaker 0: Maybe nothing happens, but then there's this nothing.
Speaker 0: in between the plays, you know I mean, there's still the same excitement when there's touchdowns or huge tackles or interceptions or anything like that.
Speaker 0: But there's all this time.
Speaker 0: It's basically like spikes and some spikes are bigger than others and it always returns to zero.
Speaker 0: Hockey is kind of like soccer and that it stays at like one all the time.
Speaker 1: There's this constant level of tension because at any moment someone could break away.
Speaker 1: Yeah any moment someone could fall down constantly playing hockey.
Speaker 0: They don't stop playing hockey.
Speaker 0: The puck is constantly in motion, you know, and they stop it as little as possible.
Speaker 0: They want to keep the game.
Speaker 0: Ideally a game of hockey will be three periods with no stoppages except for goals scored.
Speaker 1: Of course that never happened never happens, but because you go in the box for two minutes You have to sit in the box, of course, but you know, the puck is constantly in motion.
Speaker 0: You're constantly paying attention You're always at one and then you know, it rumbles and spikes all along the way.
Speaker 0: But the goals aren't so common like basketball that they're unexciting, you know.
Speaker 0: and the hits?
Speaker 0: I mean there are hits all over the place, but the big hits are like, you know, they're there It's like doom.
Speaker 0: It's not like, you know football was a million hits at once and not one of them really gets noticed Except for the one that matters.
Speaker 1: I mean when a goal gets scored in hockey It's a lot like, you know, when you see other countries playing soccer or you know, football out there and when a goal is scored Yeah Real football, not American football.
Speaker 1: Everyone in the in the crowd in unison Screams as loud as they can and jump as high as they can and they don't stop for a while.
Speaker 1: That's hockey.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's really, you know not only is it every sport even the sports that aren't fun to watch like NASCAR or Basketball are real fun to play.
Speaker 0: pretty much any sport is fun to play.
Speaker 0: I can't really think of a boring sport to play.
Speaker 1: Punch for punch is really kind of stupid.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's stupid But it's more fun than say watching Yeah, curling.
Speaker 1: I was about to bring up curling because curling is really fun.
Speaker 1: It's really fun.
Speaker 0: I mean shuffleboard is fun to play but to watch no good.
Speaker 0: Curling I imagine is very similar to shuffleboard on ice.
Speaker 0: So it's the same kind of thing.
Speaker 1: You know what I would rather watch than play?
Speaker 1: Outrunning Bears.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah I would rather watch that than play it.
Speaker 0: The bowl thing in Spain.
Speaker 0: I'd rather watch that and not participate.
Speaker 0: Although successfully participating that has to be hella fun.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the thing is I get more adrenaline rushes from things that aren't quite as dangerous.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd rather they should just replace all the bowls with hot naked chicks.
Speaker 0: That would be awesome.
Speaker 1: Anyway, here's some Benny Hill music.
Speaker 0: Okay, I found out that song's called Yakety Sax.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I didn't know that.
Speaker 0: I just learned that recently.
Speaker 1: I'm surprised you didn't know that.
Speaker 0: Well, I didn't know and now I do.
Speaker 0: and now if you're out there You now know that the Benny Hill song, you know It's called Yakety Sax.
Speaker 1: AKA the being chased around by naked women song.
Speaker 0: Exactly.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 0: So hockey in addition to being fun to play is awesome to watch very awesome Especially if you get into it.
Speaker 1: Now my best advice here is that if you live anywhere Like I was saying before before we got sidetracked, especially in a college where there is local hockey It's usually like five bucks to go see non NHL hockey.
Speaker 1: You just go and see a game but don't go alone.
Speaker 1: get as many friends as you can Especially if you can find one person who's your friends with who knows about hockey you can explain what's going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's another thing about hockey is you know, a lot of people don't really understand Completely how it works.
Speaker 0: I mean, obviously they push the puck around and try to get it in the goal, you know.
Speaker 0: But not everyone understands like why that hit was okay And why that hit is a penalty or why did they just stop playing and have a face-off?
Speaker 1: or how come guys keep going in?
Speaker 1: out of the bench all the time just like during play and The best way.
Speaker 1: it's weird because when you watch like you can tell People who don't know about hockey or people who are new into hockey versus people who know about hockey at a game Because you'll see the people who you know Never been to a hockey game before.
Speaker 1: I don't know a lot about it.
Speaker 1: They always watch the puck They're just staring at wherever the puck is no matter what.
Speaker 1: they're just following the puck and you can watch their head track the puck.
Speaker 1: But people who watch hockey and know about it You'll see like something's going on with the puck, but they're looking down ice watching the setup for what's about to happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's this flow to hockey and once once it clicks once you realize and one day you'll notice that wait a minute I'm not even looking at the puck.
Speaker 1: That's the date which you can fully appreciate the absolute brilliance.
Speaker 1: That is that sport.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the number one thing that you have to understand I think the first thing that you have to learn about watching hockey is the offsides rule.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna teach you what the offsides rule is But pretty much like if you go to a hockey game and you see some guys You know the pucks floating around near that blue line and people are going oh or come on.
Speaker 0: Come on.
Speaker 0: Come on Oh, you know and you're just sitting there going what?
Speaker 0: because it doesn't look like anything happened.
Speaker 0: And then the whistle blows and they have to have a face-off.
Speaker 0: That's offsides is happening pretty much.
Speaker 1: You can't go to the enemy team side To use the puck.
Speaker 0: the puck has to go over the blue line before a person goes over the blue line.
Speaker 0: Yes Yeah to put it put it as simply as simple as it's as far as I'm going.
Speaker 0: But yeah that you know.
Speaker 0: It's rules like that.
Speaker 0: Icing is another rule like that that you won't notice unless you know how hockey works.
Speaker 0: and if you don't know those rules You're not going to be able to really tell what the hell's going on.
Speaker 1: at the same time Don't try to read the rules to hockey.
Speaker 1: That's not gonna help.
Speaker 1: just go to a hockey game with a friend who knows about hockey and when something happens You don't know what it was.
Speaker 0: Say why did that happen?
Speaker 1: Here's the thing.
Speaker 1: if your friend actually knows about hockey They'll realize that you don't know what's going on and I'll just say things throughout the game.
Speaker 0: Like if they're that kind of person.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah I found that most hockey people are that way.
Speaker 1: go to any hockey game and half the people in the crowd are going.
Speaker 0: they'll just Say under their breath whenever something happens like I interference offsides or when something's about to happen They'll be like ice ice ice ice ice.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yep And even then just the best way if you want to see why we like hockey so much Especially if you ever get to go to a hockey game with us Is that you'll see us sitting there and we won't say anything.
Speaker 1: But we'll slowly start edging forward and standing up and we our fists start clenching and start rising.
Speaker 1: then they go back down Rise go back down and the tension just builds and builds and builds.
Speaker 1: It's almost sexual.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz like you can tell when you know, if someone knows hockey they can tell when like a big play is gonna be set up, you know, it's like I can tell just looking at the way guys are arranged and where the puck is like.
Speaker 0: There's a goal opportunity right there and in like five seconds later You will be either a goal or really close to a goal, you know, you know, see it way ahead.
Speaker 1: There's the same thing in football cuz like you see the formations you go.
Speaker 1: Oh, they're gonna try this kind of pass.
Speaker 1: They're gonna try to do this But there's always that stop or you sit and look at it.
Speaker 1: hockey is just fluid and it keeps going.
Speaker 1: the situation is changing Every second.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Alright, let's let's just do some hockey anecdotes cuz I got a few here Because I think that as by example is a great way to show people, you know, how hockey can be awesome.
Speaker 1: Oh, I got I'm trying to think I got so many hockey stars.
Speaker 0: I got I got a few or three prepared.
Speaker 1: All right, you gonna pull one out?
Speaker 0: Yeah at first I want to tell everyone about Dennis Potvin.
Speaker 1: Potvin sucks.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well Dennis Potvin was a guy who played for the New York Islanders who play at the shitty Crap hole Nassau Coliseum, which is like the worst arena ever, but He played for the Islanders like in the 60s and such now the 60.
Speaker 0: Oh, no, he actually played in the 70s and 80s.
Speaker 0: But anyway In 79 he was playing in a game against the Rangers the New York Rangers who play in Madison Square Garden a very nice arena and you know where the good teams play.
Speaker 0: and He he hit this guy named Olf Nelson and he broke his ankle.
Speaker 0: and You know, the Islanders would always chant, you know 1940 because the Rangers hadn't won since 1940.
Speaker 0: Well that night after Potvin broke this guy's ankle all the Rangers fans started going.
Speaker 0: Potvin sucks Potvin sucks, you know yelling at this guy.
Speaker 0: well the That chant, you know about Potvin second cuz.
Speaker 0: Potvin was an asshole and no one liked Dennis Potvin.
Speaker 0: He's you know, he's in the Hall of Fame.
Speaker 0: He's a great player.
Speaker 0: But no, he's an asshole and You know, they they kept doing this chant, you know, the Islanders would come to play and they would say Potvin sucks.
Speaker 0: and to this day, even though Dennis Potvin has retired and Even if the New York Rangers are not playing against the Islanders They might be playing against like the LA Kings if there are they even still a team.
Speaker 0: I don't think there's still a team though.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't think so.
Speaker 0: I don't think so either.
Speaker 0: they're playing against the Mighty Ducks of Anaheim right and you'll go to Madison Square Garden for arrangers versus Anaheim and you will hear someone in the You know the crowd of mad square garden.
Speaker 0: go like, you know, dude, dude, dude, dude.
Speaker 0: And then everyone will say Potvin sucks Even though he's retired and they're not playing.
Speaker 0: the Islanders now.
Speaker 1: See that is another aspect of hockey that you see more like you can experience more directly at local games and college games But even in the NHL it's there is that like soccer ball football.
Speaker 1: The game is highly ritualized among the fans and often hilarious.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there's like a tradition when it comes to hockey, you know, you go to like a baseball game Like if you go to see a Mets game, I just using the teams that are my teams because I've been to the games.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll be talking mostly about the Red Wings.
Speaker 0: Yeah hockey You know.
Speaker 0: people say, you know, let's go Mets which is the thing that the giant scoreboard tells you to say, you know It's there, you know, there's some tradition there, but it's not really expressed.
Speaker 1: You won't notice it unless you know where to look and you're you know, like our God RIT the Red Wings whenever You know, they're getting close to a Stanley Cup.
Speaker 1: The whole thing is they'll play.
Speaker 1: I want Stanley.
Speaker 1: I Want Stanley and the whole octopus thing is still alive and strong in Detroit At least the last time I was going to games there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and like in hockey if you score three goals in one game one player scores three goals in one game.
Speaker 0: That's a hat trick and people throw hats on the ice.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you throw your hat in the air.
Speaker 1: That's just that's expected.
Speaker 0: They throw hats on the ice, you know, it's like a bunch of hats show up on the ice.
Speaker 0: Just there they are.
Speaker 1: I never threw my head on the ice.
Speaker 0: I never threw my hat on the ice because my hat was always too nice to get rid of.
Speaker 0: but I was sure.
Speaker 0: but if I Had a cheap hat like like a dollar sombrero from the store or like a plastic hat from a bar mitzvah away It went.
Speaker 1: you know now if you go to more local hockey games There's a lot more of that and we have many anecdotes from RIT.
Speaker 1: We'll try to do a whole separate show about RIT hockey.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know local teams like if they don't already have a tradition they try to create a tradition, you know It's like.
Speaker 0: is that's what hockey is all about?
Speaker 0: is that sort of thing?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean in terms of tradition Rivalries between teams.
Speaker 1: like in football a rivalry lasts like, you know a couple of seasons maybe or there'll be like a kind of ride.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like ooh, they played the Super Bowl against each other last year.
Speaker 0: We're gonna make the Monday the first Monday Night Football game of next year.
Speaker 0: is those two teams hockey?
Speaker 1: There'll be things like you fuckers caught us out of the Stanley Cup in 1906.
Speaker 1: We're coming back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like one of your guys and your team injured one of our guys in 1937. we still hate you even though none of no one involved with either of those teams is alive.
Speaker 0: They don't care.
Speaker 0: They still hate each other.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but it's always a good-natured hate.
Speaker 1: I mean, like I said yesterday watch any hockey fight and Usually you'll see the two guys who fought just talking to each other after the fight like that was great.
Speaker 1: We had a fight that was awesome.
Speaker 0: Yeah the amount if you actually counted like the real fights the fights where people are trying to hurt each other in hockey and Compared it to the number of fights in other sports in which pretty much any fight in another sport is a guy trying to hurt Another guy for real.
Speaker 1: Yeah, most fights.
Speaker 0: You will see that hockey actually has less real fights.
Speaker 1: fights are either totally consensual or they're part of this tit-for-tat where like a red-wing will check the Claude Lemieux because Claude Lemieux hurt a Guy on the Islanders the week before and that was payback because he didn't get paid back in that game.
Speaker 0: Something crazy like.
Speaker 0: like hockey.
Speaker 1: teams look out for each other too If someone does something really bad, even if they get away with it the other teams take note Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I mean Claude Lemieux got clobbered by pretty much every team in the league for a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's the other thing is like remember the NHL strike was two years ago, right?
Speaker 0: All those players, you know you go to other sports and those guys are in it for the money.
Speaker 0: You have guys on football teams who are holding out on their contracts.
Speaker 0: They're refusing to play football because they think they'll get more money.
Speaker 0: Hockey players are crazy.
Speaker 0: All they care about is playing hockey.
Speaker 0: You don't give a shit about money.
Speaker 0: during the strike They all join like minor leagues or other leagues or the 80 and during the strike most hockey players ran away to Europe because they Wanted to play hockey.
Speaker 0: They didn't care.
Speaker 1: They just wanted to play hockey.
Speaker 1: people play hockey because they love it.
Speaker 1: No one plays hockey for the money because you make more money in other sports.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean when guys play on like the Olympic team in hockey, you're like, hey, you know These guys are in the middle of a hockey season.
Speaker 0: there does a break because there's Olympic hockey going on.
Speaker 0: Why would these guys try very hard in the Olympics, you know, why would they risk getting injured for you know When there's a real NHL season going on?
Speaker 0: Yeah Because they're crazy hockey players.
Speaker 1: You think the New York Yankees would let their star pitcher just pitch in the minor leagues for fun in the middle of a season.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like go to the if there are a baseball Olympics.
Speaker 0: Do you think they just let him go?
Speaker 0: You know, there's a break so they're not missing any games, you know.
Speaker 0: But do you think they'd let him go pitch in some games that don't matter in terms of the World Series?
Speaker 0: They matter for some gold medals and something else.
Speaker 1: I mean if the NHL disbanded there would be just as much hockey Nothing would change and all of those players would just join other leagues and continue playing even if they didn't make any money.
Speaker 0: Yeah That that's part of why hockey is there because anyone playing hockey Wants to play hockey real bad and they're trying as hard as they can and they care about the game They're playing and they're not there for some other reason, you know, it's not what it is their job But they're not doing it like it's their job.
Speaker 0: They're doing it, you know the same way that I would play a German board game Or that you would play a video game.
Speaker 1: now, I guess cuz we got to wrap this up, you know It's Thursday, and I'm tired.
Speaker 1: We got a concert tomorrow to go to.
Speaker 1: we'll talk about that at length on Monday Mm-hmm, but suffice to say hockey.
Speaker 1: I mean most of our friends at RIT were not sports fans at all.
Speaker 0: No, they were not.
Speaker 1: we systematically dragged everyone we knew to RIT hockey games.
Speaker 0: Well, I think RIT hockey the fact that RIT hockey was slightly Enthusiastic and good helped a bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was normal hockey.
Speaker 0: They wouldn't have been into it.
Speaker 1: but even though I mean the fact that we dragged these people who generally hated sports to these games and By the end of a couple games, they'd be coming to us.
Speaker 1: Like we're going to the hockey game, right?
Speaker 1: No, I mean our senior year even started going to the girls hockey games.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we went to like two or three of those.
Speaker 1: They're well, the thing is the one thing that bothers me about hockey is that girls hockey really sucks, but it's not the girls fault.
Speaker 1: Yeah rules for women's hockey are different.
Speaker 1: they're not allowed to fight they're not allowed to check each other Which is hitting basically.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Yeah Generally if you look at hockey the only real difference between like kids hockey Women's hockey minor league hockey and NHL.
Speaker 0: real hockey is the speed.
Speaker 0: Yes I mean if you go to a college hockey game It looks just like an NHL hockey game only in a smaller ice rink where everyone's skating slower.
Speaker 0: NHL hockey is exactly the same they the same setups and everything only they're going real fast.
Speaker 0: There's a lot more ice real fast and the pucks going faster and shot harder and everything like that.
Speaker 0: That's really the only difference.
Speaker 1: Well that and you'll see a lot cleaner plays like our in college hockey even in good college hockey You'll see a lot of you know passes that don't quite go or formations that just fail.
Speaker 0: But but a lot of that is you know things require the more speed to work properly.
Speaker 0: There is of course the lack of you know technique because you're just a college kid and you haven't played hockey for four more years Necessary.
Speaker 1: and I guess because there's one other aspect real briefly because we got to wrap this up But we talked a bit about f1 which we're kind of fans of too.
Speaker 1: it's got more so than me, but I enjoy it and we talked about you know, the technology and how tiny changes like a 16th of a degree on a fin completely changes the car.
Speaker 1: Hockey is the same way.
Speaker 1: tweaking the rules like in any direction totally changes the game and this year This is just as an example They have allowed you to have a slightly more curved blade on your hockey stick.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, it's like the tiniest little difference.
Speaker 1: and Good God, is that going to change the game and make it more offensive make shooting bigger and more accurate Make the goalie's job harder and make the game in my opinion more awesome.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be very awesome.
Speaker 0: We're gonna shooting harder passing faster.
Speaker 0: They can be able to you know, prevent.
Speaker 0: they're gonna handle the puck better.
Speaker 1: It'll weaken the trap.
Speaker 1: now we're just talking in total hockey lingo.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's gonna weaken the trap kind of team.
Speaker 1: So teams like the Jersey Devils are pretty much fucked.
Speaker 0: I don't know if they still play that way.
Speaker 1: I don't know either.
Speaker 1: I haven't actually watched because I don't watch TV.
Speaker 1: So I saw.
Speaker 1: I watched the Jersey Devils, you know before the strike and unless they've changed they they really have no chance.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: But anyway, oh one last thing I want to say.
Speaker 0: my thing of the day from Monday was Ty Domi.
Speaker 0: You know punching Olaf Samuelson in the face and knocking him out.
Speaker 0: on Tuesday Ty Domi retired.
Speaker 0: Kind of a coincidence.
Speaker 1: better call Randy.
Speaker 0: I know really I mean I use him in a thing of the day.
Speaker 0: the next day He retires.
Speaker 0: He must have listened to the show and then said up people are talking about me on some geek show.
Speaker 0: I better quit.
Speaker 1: They're on to me.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so in closing hockey's awesome.
Speaker 1: We front row crew comm join the forums.
Speaker 1: They're crazy.
Speaker 0: And if you're an RIT student, you know, there should be hockey.
Speaker 0: You should go to the home hockey games as many as you can though.
Speaker 1: They're not as great as they used to be They're not.
Speaker 0: they used to.
Speaker 0: the only difference is they used to win all the time and now they don't really win all the time Because they move to Division one.
Speaker 1: now when we say win all the time.
Speaker 1: We mean win all The time.
Speaker 0: yeah, if just go to one of their games and look at the ceiling and you will see all the little championship banners They they don't just give you those, you know to make your arena look nice.
Speaker 1: Yeah art now that if you needed any other endorsement of hockey RIT in my opinion probably the geekiest University in the nation of the United States.
Speaker 1: Yeah, definitely I mean MIT and you know and Caltech are really geeky But I think overall RIT has the highest concentration and the greater number of geeks.
Speaker 0: I think that the only data you need to support that claim is the fact that it is the most piracy of Yeah How many times did like the FBI?
Speaker 0: Customs that came.
Speaker 0: it's crazy.
Speaker 1: FBI came at least once anyway, I mean I worked for ITS.
Speaker 1: I saw some shit.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but hockey was so Unbelievably popular at RIT.
Speaker 1: I mean more people went to hockey games than went to pretty much any other sport that RIT combined.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and when they played the rivals the game would sell out even though the school was full of geeks.
Speaker 0: I mean people would walk through the snow in the cold and that's part of why hockey was important there because it was cold.
Speaker 0: That's the sport you could play in this place and the school had its own ice rink, which is kind of huge.
Speaker 0: Also the peep nerds who normally spent all day inside playing counter-strike would turn off Counter-strike or at least pause it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they go to the Disconnect from the server.
Speaker 0: leave it running, you know?
Speaker 0: Walk out in the snow in the cold in the winter to pay five bucks To sit on a cold bench in an ice rink to watch some college.
Speaker 0: You know bums play ice hockey to watch some hotel management majors.
Speaker 1: Yeah hotel management majors from connect Canada.
Speaker 1: I almost said Canadian.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all of RIT's hockey players were hotel management majors from Canada.
Speaker 1: Yeah fancy that.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, oh most of them were.
Speaker 0: some of them were real majors.
Speaker 0: One guy was like a painter right and he painted a like a picture of hockey and they sold.
Speaker 0: they auctioned it off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, oh god I just remember we got stories about RIT hockey players that live next door to us in colony.
Speaker 0: We have lots of stories about.
Speaker 1: alright, we're gonna do an RIT hockey episode in the future.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll leave it at that Mm-hmm, and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at Www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.