Speaker 1: It's Wednesday October 18th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We discussed the brand-new death note anime.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: You know we haven't really plugged it much yet, but we are going to be guests at uber con this weekend.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well, we'll see exactly what the state of that is.
Speaker 0: I am a guest at uber con this weekend.
Speaker 0: I don't know about Scott.
Speaker 1: yeah uber con seems to have a little problem in there.
Speaker 1: I don't know what you call it.
Speaker 0: Well the thing is they just they didn't really respond very much to emails.
Speaker 1: We need to work on our communication Plus.
Speaker 0: uber con wasn't really a high priority for my end because we're only doing one panel there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean it's like I'm going to this con mostly for the stuff that a con goer goes for and not so much of the You know con guest action is going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: There's some guests I really want to meet and hopefully I'll be able to interview them though that means dragging all the equipment out there.
Speaker 1: I definitely feeling like at CITICON.
Speaker 1: You know there weren't so many get you know con goers there And but I did have a whole blast you know doing networking and stuff with all the other guests.
Speaker 1: So I'm definitely feeling a strong bit of that.
Speaker 1: at uber con like I'll spend a lot of time Chilling with our guests you know meeting people talking it up You know letting him in about the show and all that good stuff.
Speaker 1: But also I'm gonna play some games because I need to play some new games some games.
Speaker 0: We'll see how much gaming we actually get to do.
Speaker 1: I know I really want to play some games Man, but I'll try to play at least two.
Speaker 1: That's my goal if I play two games.
Speaker 1: It's a good con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but we'll be at uber con.
Speaker 0: It will not be difficult to find us the people who con is small.
Speaker 0: well It's bigger than CITICON and the people who went to CITICON to see us in numbers of people.
Speaker 1: yes It's bigger than CITICON.
Speaker 1: however in space it takes up.
Speaker 1: It's just one two hallways of one hotel room You know.
Speaker 0: so our panel apparently is either going to be in the pool or in a suite upstairs somewhere.
Speaker 1: Who knows I'm not really too interested in the panel because they threw all these other people on it.
Speaker 1: And who knows who they are?
Speaker 1: we're gonna have to find out.
Speaker 0: yeah great.
Speaker 1: Maybe they'll cramp our style.
Speaker 0: You know if you don't want to be in the panel.
Speaker 0: I'll.
Speaker 0: just I'll do the panel.
Speaker 1: I'll be on the panel.
Speaker 1: I'm just saying I don't know how it's gonna go because there might be people cramping our style.
Speaker 0: Well there were people with us at CITICON too.
Speaker 1: That was a different kind of panel.
Speaker 1: Okay anyway Yeah, so uber con, New Jersey this Saturday.
Speaker 1: We're not gonna go on Friday and Sunday just because We can't do it.
Speaker 1: It's not worth it.
Speaker 1: so all day Saturday, New Jersey come see us And play games.
Speaker 0: yep, and Scott apparently doesn't like the other guests, so I don't even know the other guests.
Speaker 1: I didn't say I didn't like them.
Speaker 0: You're just like these other guests.
Speaker 0: They're gonna cramp our style.
Speaker 1: They're guys.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 1: so it's.
Speaker 1: you know it's a gaming con.
Speaker 1: odds are at a gaming con.
Speaker 1: It's someone who will cramp the style even though this is a distinct possibility.
Speaker 1: They could be cooled.
Speaker 1: awesome, dude.
Speaker 0: See I don't see not ruling it out.
Speaker 0: I don't see why they would be more likely to cramp our style at a gaming con than an anime con.
Speaker 1: Come on.
Speaker 1: What kind of people go to gaming cons?
Speaker 1: So the latest Studio Ghibli movie is that one that's directed by Miyazaki's son Goro.
Speaker 1: What's-his-face Goro Miyazaki right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, same last name.
Speaker 1: He's his son could have figured that out.
Speaker 0: not so good a director though.
Speaker 0: apparently.
Speaker 1: well who knows about that?
Speaker 0: I haven't seen the movie so I had not heard a single person say much good about it.
Speaker 1: Anyway, it's based on this series of books called the tales of Earthsea Which are written by Ursula K Le Guin and I've read them And I got.
Speaker 1: I read a lot of her books, and they're really awesome like almost Lord of the Rings awesome.
Speaker 1: If you haven't read the Earthsea books I highly recommend you read at least the first three.
Speaker 1: the fourth one's still good And I think there's another one that I haven't read that I've got somewhere.
Speaker 0: They're not boring like most of the middle of the Lord of the Rings are they?
Speaker 1: No?
Speaker 1: And Lord of the Rings is boring.
Speaker 0: I got to admit that much of the second book was tedious and boring and I ended up skipping a big portion of it.
Speaker 1: Well you suck, but Earthsea is not boring at all, and it's super awesome.
Speaker 1: Okay, anyway There was a sci-fi channel miniseries based on Earthsea that really sucked really really sucked.
Speaker 1: that came out like in 2004. ish and Sci-fi channel must still has some rights to Earthsea in some way, and they're not going to expire until 2009 as a result if Sci-fi channel continues to be an ass you know or decides to be an ass who knows?
Speaker 1: if they decided yet The new Ghibli movie ghetto Sankey might not come out in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Legally until 2009.
Speaker 0: you know it's sad to say it, but that doesn't affect me at all.
Speaker 1: It doesn't affect me either, and it's just sort of annoying.
Speaker 1: like hey this company you know made a live-action TV show based on a book and Even though the person with the book that who wrote the book thinks differently And even though like you know Disney is probably gonna bring this thing over and they're huge You know because some guy made a short live-action miniseries of like four episodes.
Speaker 1: This blockbuster movie can't be.
Speaker 0: So what exactly is the situation?
Speaker 0: I mean does sci-fi have the rights to u.s.
Speaker 0: Release of a work based on that?
Speaker 0: because the other the movie was made in Japan.
Speaker 0: I mean, what's the deal here?
Speaker 1: It doesn't exactly say the details because this is a part of an interview in the New York Times About you know okay, so you don't actually know.
Speaker 1: all it says is that in it's in the New York Times.
Speaker 1: So it's real and according not doubting that it's real and Ursula K Le Guin said in the New York Times Mr.
Speaker 1: Miyazaki's movie won't be shown as long as the sci-fi channel.
Speaker 1: people sit on their rights Which they have until 2009 unless they decide to stop being a dog in the manger He tells the New York Times.
Speaker 0: well see this is a case kind of like what's happened to a con We talked about a while back that Somebody screwed up and most likely either Ursula K Le Guin or the estate Gave up the rights for the US release of a TV work or something or a movie or some sort of derivative And they gave it away in such a way that prevents other words from coming out meaning They fucked up and now they're stuck with this.
Speaker 1: I do remember.
Speaker 1: I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Speaker 1: this is just what I remember of when they talked to her when the TV series came out how she thought it sucked and You know when they came to her telling her that they had this idea They wanted to do it And they told her that she would be really involved and they would seek her input And then they never sought her input And they just came out with it without her saying anything about it, and she really didn't like it.
Speaker 1: So I have a feeling she must have screwed up something back then.
Speaker 0: who knows what seems to have been fairly often.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know it's cuz not everyone's a lawyer and this kind of shit can happen to people.
Speaker 0: well What you got to do is either hire a lawyer or learn about that stuff or at least read a contract before you sign it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, who knows plus a lot of times?
Speaker 1: You know you'll write something and then like some publisher will have the rights and they'll do stuff with it.
Speaker 0: That's only if you signed away the right.
Speaker 1: yeah who knows it's all crazy.
Speaker 0: see a lot of young artists and young writers screw up By.
Speaker 0: if they get they'll get a publishing deal offer from some company and in return They have to sign away pretty much all their rights, and then the company just takes it does whatever they want with it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I noticed this stuff a lot actually lately with comic book publishers.
Speaker 1: You'll notice you'll see stuff like you know Marvel Comics, and then they'll have a separate imprint.
Speaker 1: That's like epic and that is a Marvel comic where the creator still owns the rights of the characters.
Speaker 1: if you write a Marvel Comic and you make new characters Marvel owns them, but if you're at an epic comic Which is still published by Marvel.
Speaker 1: they don't own it, and they have all.
Speaker 1: you know you.
Speaker 1: every different publisher also has you know a different way of Compensating and paying.
Speaker 1: you know the the creators that make comics for the public.
Speaker 0: see I just think the idea of a publisher having any copyright interest in a work is really kind of outmoded in old school.
Speaker 1: I agree completely.
Speaker 1: What can I say?
Speaker 1: yeah?
Speaker 0: It's all stupid though speaking of anime and anime related news it being anime day here on geek nights This is this poll.
Speaker 0: There's a poll on anime news network a little while ago about you know who's your favorite director?
Speaker 0: And it went on for a while.
Speaker 0: it ended.
Speaker 0: I think sometime last week or early this week.
Speaker 0: I don't remember exactly when it ended, but if you might recall at Conventions we were going around asking people if they could name any Director of an anime other than Hayao Miyazaki yep.
Speaker 1: Oh, oh you can't say Who's the other one you can't say?
Speaker 1: Hmm, I forget there was another one You're not?
Speaker 1: that was too easy that we didn't let people.
Speaker 0: I can think of a bunch that are too easy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway go that's cuz I'm an anime fan.
Speaker 1: go on go on.
Speaker 0: so the survey You know they ask people on the internet.
Speaker 1: What was your favorite director, but why don't we answer this first?
Speaker 0: you pick my favorite director?
Speaker 0: Sadly and scarily is Ikuhara.
Speaker 0: But then again, that's just because you 10 is my favorite show.
Speaker 0: I actually really like oshi.
Speaker 1: If I had to pick right now like there's a lot of them.
Speaker 1: I'd have to say Satoshi khan mr.
Speaker 1: paranoia agent Tokyo godfathers.
Speaker 1: you know millennium millennium actors.
Speaker 0: perfect blue perfect blue.
Speaker 0: You know what funny because everyone except Ikuhara that we just mentioned is on the list here near the top.
Speaker 1: Ikuhara is not on the list.
Speaker 0: He's not anywhere near the top of the list.
Speaker 0: good.
Speaker 1: He doesn't belong at the top of the list.
Speaker 1: He's a freak.
Speaker 0: well number one of course.
Speaker 0: He's a far and away Miyazaki number two.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: Good God wait.
Speaker 1: What are the percentages and numbers on those?
Speaker 0: Oh at Miyazaki was like 20 something percent, and I don't know was right under that with a lot and everyone else was single digits.
Speaker 1: Oh wow Where'd Satoshi khan come in?
Speaker 0: Satoshi khan came in one two three four four number four.
Speaker 1: four is not so bad.
Speaker 0: The list was Miyazaki.
Speaker 0: I don't know Watanabe, but what's an abhi?
Speaker 1: is the samurai Champloo?
Speaker 1: Bob guy says I can see where that comes from there.
Speaker 0: They're allowed to vote, but then Satoshi khan I know and then someone who is not on the list and then oshi and the rest.
Speaker 0: I didn't care about because it's the bottom of the list.
Speaker 0: whatever I Think I get.
Speaker 0: Miyazaki's really the only director that is commonly known by anime fans.
Speaker 0: I mean he's really good.
Speaker 0: his stuff is great.
Speaker 0: But I think that part of this is this survey was done in America.
Speaker 0: It's simply that most anime fans in America have no idea who directs anything, but whenever a Miyazaki film comes out It's always I owe Miyazaki's woman something cool.
Speaker 1: Well, I think you know.
Speaker 1: it kind of reminds me again of comics.
Speaker 1: how when I was a kid in the 90s reading comics I didn't pay attention to who the hell created the comics.
Speaker 1: You know I'd watch.
Speaker 1: I would watch cartoons on TV.
Speaker 1: I didn't know who the hell created the cartoons.
Speaker 1: I didn't you know Miyamoto played all the made all the video games of my childhood.
Speaker 1: I didn't know his name.
Speaker 0: Really, I actually looked at the credits of my Nintendo games I remember seeing.
Speaker 1: I looked at him But I didn't you know.
Speaker 1: none of the names really stuck in my mind.
Speaker 1: so it's basically a bunch of Japanese guys.
Speaker 0: I noticed that a few.
Speaker 0: nay like I knew who.
Speaker 0: uh Umatzu was the guy who made the music.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I knew about him pretty much right away.
Speaker 0: Yeah, in fact.
Speaker 0: I imported a CD long before there were mp3 z's,
Speaker 1: but it seems that lately you know Not only am I paying more attention to who creates the works of entertainment and art that I consume But it seems like they're becoming more prominent like they're trying to push it more especially with things like video games.
Speaker 1: used to be the only person who made video games that you knew about it was John Carmack and Sid Meier.
Speaker 1: now all of a sudden you're seeing a lot more Romero Romero Romero He doesn't count.
Speaker 1: he's a woman anyway.
Speaker 0: It's a very pretty woman.
Speaker 1: very They're pushing a lot.
Speaker 1: you know.
Speaker 1: a lot more game developers are coming out to the forefront a lot more comic creators You want to know why are trying to get their names out there besides just Stan Lee?
Speaker 0: Cubby.
Speaker 0: I think it's pretty obvious Why.
Speaker 0: it's a very good move because anyone who wants their name out there is like this is Usually someone who's good, and they're trying to stand out from the pack of rubbish.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I mean me is I mean people here?
Speaker 0: I owe me a Zaki and movie about the environment and everyone just goes oh, it's me a Zaki.
Speaker 1: Oh my god I got it.
Speaker 1: at the next con we go to we're gonna go to the Naruto.
Speaker 1: if they were like no No, we're gonna ask them Can you name anyone who worked on the creation of Naruto the director a character designer anything?
Speaker 1: And we're gonna see if they know who makes the Naruto that they enjoy so much.
Speaker 1: Because I really don't think they do.
Speaker 0: I don't think they care I don't think they carry.
Speaker 0: the thing is if you're there if you're really new to a fandom It's not useful to you right away to know who directs stuff.
Speaker 0: You always didn't care at all, but once you've seen a bunch of stuff, and you think hey I really like that paranoia agent who's really cool, and I really like that perfect blue.
Speaker 0: And hey wait a minute the same guy did both of those.
Speaker 0: oh he also did this thing called Tokyo Godfathers, maybe I should watch that.
Speaker 1: maybe you should cuz it's freaking awesome.
Speaker 0: It is I really liked it.
Speaker 0: It's not my favorite of his works.
Speaker 0: My favorite is still perfect blue.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe I don't know paranoid agents pretty damn.
Speaker 0: I heard our agents really good, but I really like perfect blue speaking of which we should talk about perfect blue.
Speaker 0: on the show.
Speaker 1: I had to watch it again.
Speaker 1: It's been a lot many years.
Speaker 0: I'll put it in the Netflix cuz I really like that movie a lot freaky ending.
Speaker 0: I Remember our friend Lara wouldn't walk home alone from anime club after we showed it.
Speaker 1: now It was funny how the first movie he made was kind of scary But a lot of the other ones he made were light-hearted or just semi weird anyway.
Speaker 0: Well, it was scary in that Hitchcock thriller kind of way not in the oh my god boo way.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I really don't like the oh my god boo because I don't think that.
Speaker 1: I don't think of that as frightening.
Speaker 1: I think that more of his surprise.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, though granted some movies.
Speaker 0: Do that very well.
Speaker 1: Hey some movies.
Speaker 1: Do do that very well.
Speaker 0: things of the day.
Speaker 1: We got hot things of the day today, yeah, we surprised the hottest things of the day that for weeks I had a serious thing of the day that would spark actual discussion.
Speaker 0: But then whatever.
Speaker 0: but then I saw my thing of the day and the thing is really I just got to get this out.
Speaker 0: I got two things in the day today because Scott, but he called dibs, so I can't reveal it But I totally found the thing of the day and showed it to him.
Speaker 1: well I totally just found the thing of the day that you're using ten minutes ago and showed it to you.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna trade here cuz I got dibs.
Speaker 1: therefore Yeah, even though I think that the thing of the day I found as far as superior of course my thing of the day as far as superior to your thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Anyway, Scott's thing of the day.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right is now.
Speaker 0: This is actually really good.
Speaker 0: You know that old thing where Howard Stern fans the call into something and then as soon as they get live on the air They say baba buoy baba buoy.
Speaker 1: Well usually what they do is they make a normal prank call and then they say baba buoy at the end.
Speaker 1: So, you know that it was a Howard Stern prank caller.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, yeah, but what this is?
Speaker 0: it's a whole bunch of videos of people Actually one of the videos of this guy who's kind of famous for calling into c-span all the time with prank jokes Which is people calling into c-span?
Speaker 0: Getting on the air and then saying funny things.
Speaker 1: I love the first one because the guy just calls in.
Speaker 1: he's like hello my on the air.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 0: Fuck Yeah, what was the guy at ball sack teabagger?
Speaker 1: Hello, I am ball sack teabagger now that from Pakistan.
Speaker 0: That is my favorite one in the sense that you see the guy on the air.
Speaker 0: You know The guy is actually moderating all this and he right away figures out that it's a prank call from the name.
Speaker 0: You can see it in his eyes.
Speaker 0: He's sitting there thinking.
Speaker 0: What do I do?
Speaker 0: But then the guy starts talking.
Speaker 0: normally, but he's got his finger sitting on the cutoff button and then he's like Howard Stern's penis clink.
Speaker 0: The Thing is c-span gets pranked a lot.
Speaker 0: I don't know if you all realize that but I'd say a Significant percentage of the people who call into c-span are people who want to say the word penis.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling that it is also a lot of do want to say the word fuck.
Speaker 1: I mean if you have a TV network that's on all the time with barely anyone watching it I mean relatively speaking how many people watch c-span especially at the hours when they have you know free call-ins where they let anyone call In.
Speaker 1: so odds are if you call into the show you're gonna get on the air.
Speaker 1: So I think a lot of people, you know The kind of people are up at those hours watching c-span.
Speaker 1: are either people who are really into c-span like maybe a congressman?
Speaker 1: No, I'm kidding.
Speaker 1: They're watching some freaking porno or something.
Speaker 1: They're people who want to make a prank call.
Speaker 1: So if you watch c-span odds are you're gonna see prank calls once a week?
Speaker 0: I'm surprised that the only thing you can think of that a congressman would be doing is watching pornography.
Speaker 1: Well, if you look at what this news about congressman lately, I think that's what they're doing.
Speaker 0: So because one guy was a I think there's three guys.
Speaker 1: There was like two other stories recently.
Speaker 0: Anyway, okay.
Speaker 0: So now Scott can give you my thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: Well, and was the bomb, okay Everyone knows about the old Batman live-action show probably the Adam West the best Batman movie ever made.
Speaker 1: It's actually from the movie or is it from just the TV show?
Speaker 0: it's from the movie is it?
Speaker 0: Okay, remember that it starts with the shark repellent.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I know but I know the shark repellent movie spoilers.
Speaker 0: And then they turn all the diplomats into powder.
Speaker 0: Yep, and there's a bomb at one point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay We watched it out of the New Year's party.
Speaker 1: I know I don't remember all of it, but I remember the shark repellent.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the old Batman TV show with Adam West had a movie and the movie was so hilarious.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, and there was a scene in this movie in which Batman is holding a giant bomb a bowling ball candle bomb, you know It Boris Bedenov bomb a big black thing with a with a fuse coming out a kaboom bomb.
Speaker 1: Yes, and he was running down a boardwalk holding this bomb and he's running in a hilarious fashion.
Speaker 0: He's holding it over his head He's panicked.
Speaker 0: He's looking for somewhere to get rid of it.
Speaker 1: Like he'll go to he could have just thrown it off the boardwalk Ocean.
Speaker 0: he tries he turns and try goes to throw it off the boardwalk and there's like someone down there He tries to throw it.
Speaker 0: somewhere else is a bunch of nuns no matter what he does.
Speaker 0: He can't get rid of this bomb.
Speaker 1: Yeah, anyway, so many people on the internet have passed around the funny animated gif of Batman running with a bomb which is you know hilarious whenever there's a thread on FARC about terrorism or Batman Batman terrorism.
Speaker 1: Yeah anything like that.
Speaker 0: The most recent one I saw was they replaced Batman's face with Muhammad.
Speaker 1: So anyway Some guy got the idea to combine this with Mario Brothers 2 aka doki-doki panic.
Speaker 1: Mario Brothers 2. some doors in the game can just be opened easily.
Speaker 1: You just go up to them and walk in.
Speaker 1: Some doors have a lock on them and everyone knows to open a lock.
Speaker 1: You need a key.
Speaker 1: The keys were all located in you know, relatively secret places usually in jars.
Speaker 1: You would go in the jar and there would be a key there.
Speaker 1: It would also be these guys around the key these faces called phantos.
Speaker 0: now I would like to describe for you the first time I ever encountered a key in Super Mario Brothers 2 aka doki-doki panic USA Mm-hmm, I go in and I see this key and I see these three masks and I think I wonder what those masks are.
Speaker 0: I immediately stopped caring because there's the key the object of my affection and desire.
Speaker 0: I jumped down, you know I'm probably the princess maybe toad.
Speaker 0: I pick it up and One of the mass starts rumbling.
Speaker 0: now at this point I defecate The mass flies off the screen.
Speaker 0: I think all right.
Speaker 0: I wonder was that was all about?
Speaker 0: and then it comes back and it's trying to get me and I've run out of the pipe and it's still trying to get me and no matter where I go It's always there, but if I drop the key it goes away.
Speaker 1: But if you pick up the key again beeline for your face, yep.
Speaker 1: So it was really crazy in Mario 2 whenever you got a key It was some of the best parts of the game.
Speaker 1: cuz you got that key and then you fucking ran.
Speaker 1: Holy shit Did you run for that?
Speaker 1: Because that phantos is gonna come and freaking kick your ass.
Speaker 1: god damn I can't tell you.
Speaker 1: when I was like a little kid playing that game I was scared to shit.
Speaker 1: a phantos like I would be like, okay ready grab go go go go go.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I would run real quick.
Speaker 0: Remember, I remember the one where you early on like I think it's the four of the first times We got a dig all the way down in the sand.
Speaker 0: There's a key at the bottom.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you're digging down.
Speaker 0: You're digging down you like.
Speaker 0: I'll bet there's something down here.
Speaker 0: Maybe a boss?
Speaker 1: you see that key and you think oh fuck You're at the bottom of this giant giant sand pit and the only way place to go is up.
Speaker 1: and if you didn't pick Luigi You're gonna have a hard time jumping out of there with any speed at all Luigi You want to be towed in that situation?
Speaker 1: So it is good because he digs down real quickly But at the same time Luigi can jump real high and get out of there quickly.
Speaker 0: He jumps real slow.
Speaker 0: You'll get up faster if you're anyone else.
Speaker 1: You got it.
Speaker 1: If you use Luigi he jumps so high that you can jump higher with the same amount of time.
Speaker 1: No, because don't do a full Luigi jump where he hangs in the air all stupidly because he jumps so slowly.
Speaker 0: It's not worth it.
Speaker 0: Plus he goes up like Anyway, you don't want to be Luigi unless you're doing a speedrun.
Speaker 1: Anyway, the point is is The point anyway?
Speaker 1: is my thing of the day is a YTM ND in which they show the picture of you know The animated gif of Batman running with the bomb.
Speaker 1: they replaced the bomb with a key and he's being chased by a fantasy Hot damn.
Speaker 0: when I saw this on 4chan a week ago.
Speaker 0: Did I not laugh my ass off?
Speaker 1: I was also laughing the hysterical and I'm still laughing the hysterical.
Speaker 0: I yelled to Scott.
Speaker 0: you got to see this.
Speaker 0: This is one of the funniest animated gifs I've ever seen and he's all skeptical.
Speaker 0: and then he sees it.
Speaker 1: It's so awesome.
Speaker 1: if you know about Batman, you know about Mario - it's hilarious.
Speaker 0: I'm just trying to think of a way to integrate strokes and all this.
Speaker 1: Batman's got scrotum his utility belt.
Speaker 1: Yeah, maybe he's running away for a lot with his other pokeballs and Digimon's and Whatever else he's got in there.
Speaker 0: So anyway being anime day today We would like to do a preview of a show that I'm sure everyone who is an anime fan has been watching.
Speaker 0: The second episode came out recently the Death Note anime.
Speaker 0: Death Note not the live-action not the manga but the anime.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: There's a Death Note anime.
Speaker 1: It just started.
Speaker 1: It's It's alright, I think.
Speaker 1: yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, it's directed by a Tetsuro Araki, which you might remember from practically nothing.
Speaker 0: He did some storyboards and unit direction for Galaxy Angel and he did some unit direction for Digicarrot And he directed Otoki Jushi Akazuken, which is a new-ish OAV.
Speaker 1: that's kind of lame at least to us.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is the guy doesn't seem to have a lot of experience.
Speaker 0: No, definitely not the most experienced director Though I got to say the Death Note anime has a fairly unique style.
Speaker 0: At least it's something that hasn't been used in high-budget shows before.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean I was.
Speaker 1: I was really wondering when that we know when I knew there was gonna be Death Note anime How were they gonna make this animated?
Speaker 1: because the manga is a whole lot of just people talking Not even just that half the time.
Speaker 0: It's light thinking to himself.
Speaker 0: Well, if I do this then he'll do this.
Speaker 0: so I'd better do this, but then he'll do this.
Speaker 0: So if I do this and this then he'll do this and then I'll do this.
Speaker 0: Oh, but what if blah?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I think they've fixed they've handled it pretty well.
Speaker 1: Actually a lot of times where you know light usually would have been thinking to himself and there would be nothing to animate.
Speaker 1: They've had him talking to Ryuk, which makes me very happy.
Speaker 0: Let's back up a little bit.
Speaker 0: All right, cuz I know a lot of people haven't actually read the manga.
Speaker 0: Oh Death Note is a very very very popular manga Incredibly freakin popular about a Death Note.
Speaker 0: a high school student finds a notebook that was dropped by a Shinigami a god of the dead into the human world.
Speaker 0: He picks it up and it says if you write someone's name in this book They'll die.
Speaker 0: You can choose how they die.
Speaker 0: all these other rules.
Speaker 0: and he thinks whatever and he takes it home and he ends up Trying it out as a joke and it works.
Speaker 0: a normal human being Any if it was a typical anime or manga The character would freak out or throw it away or there'd be some sort of hijinks surrounding it.
Speaker 0: This kid sits there after he realizes what happens and doesn't say oh my god.
Speaker 0: What is that?
Speaker 0: What have I done?
Speaker 0: He says all right.
Speaker 0: He says oh, yeah I'm going to become god of this world and meet out horrible justice unto the wicked.
Speaker 1: Yeah, even though you know, he's the wicked who's just a crazy killer killing everybody.
Speaker 0: well, he starts out with good intentions.
Speaker 0: He basically starts killing anyone who's a criminal.
Speaker 0: if you think that's good And at least it's understandable.
Speaker 0: He thinks he's doing good.
Speaker 0: Yeah then the police go after him and he starts killing them and then he starts killing people who so much has Disrespect him and it just goes on from there.
Speaker 0: But you might think all right.
Speaker 0: This is just stupid fantasy.
Speaker 0: Well, there's a detective named L who is going after him and I'm not going to ruin anything about how that plays out But you'd think how in there?
Speaker 0: how could someone possibly catch someone who can kill by writing names down in a book and L fucking chases him down and It's totally realistic.
Speaker 0: That sounds stupid.
Speaker 0: It might sound stupid But the way it goes plays out is perfectly legitimate and could really happen.
Speaker 0: aside from the whole Death Note part Yeah, it's straight up how they go after people in the logic is pretty flawless All right, if you think so I think so.
Speaker 0: I mean look that the physical things that they do to try to catch light would have worked if that sort of thing existed.
Speaker 1: I guess I think a lot of it.
Speaker 1: what it is is they you know The Death Note has certain rules around it.
Speaker 1: Like, you know if they would have just said yeah You write someone's name in it and they die that would have left you asking a lot of questions and going Oh, why does he just do this?
Speaker 1: Why does he just do that?
Speaker 1: Etc etc.
Speaker 1: And In the manga they put a lot of the rules of how the Death Note works between the chapters and it really fills in Any sort of plot hole that you can think up.
Speaker 1: well See it also creates new plot elements because a lot of those rules, you know Force people to do certain things or act in certain ways.
Speaker 0: Well, that's I mean when I you know, it's realistic It's in the sense that the show is and the show in the manga and everything are Very they really really let you suspend your disbelief easily because everything makes sense.
Speaker 0: Everything is consistent.
Speaker 0: You know, there's craft anime where you know, whenever they need something to happen there's just a new plot device or the robot had an extra gun or Oh magic doesn't actually work that way.
Speaker 0: if you're on the island of blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this show is just straight up a hundred percent self consistent from start to finish.
Speaker 1: That is true.
Speaker 1: It's it's very self consistent and it's one of the thing you won't you'll never.
Speaker 1: it's gonna be real hard for you to go Huh?
Speaker 1: Well, why doesn't he do that?
Speaker 1: Why doesn't he do that?
Speaker 1: You know, you always have an answer.
Speaker 0: you will you'll think well, he could just do this and then maybe a character tries to do that and you find out why it didn't work.
Speaker 1: or Oh, I think the differences in other shows as you say Why didn't he do that?
Speaker 1: or you know and then something comes out of nowhere in Death Note.
Speaker 1: you ask?
Speaker 1: Why didn't he do that?
Speaker 1: and then you think back and you go?
Speaker 1: Oh, that's why.
Speaker 1: because they already covered it as opposed to then covering it up later.
Speaker 0: Yep I mean, it's a made-up story obviously but it it plays out as in very realistically.
Speaker 0: the details that come out early matter later and Any detail is there for a reason and everything happens very very consistently.
Speaker 0: So aside from the story, it was an incredibly popular manga that finished in Japan and is approaching completion in the US Yeah, but pretty slow.
Speaker 1: I think it's a little over half done in the US.
Speaker 1: I mean, I've got volume 7 I think or maybe 8.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think there's 12 right?
Speaker 0: Well 13 there but supposedly the 13th volume is not actually story It's just character stuff.
Speaker 1: Well, who knows if they'll even come out with it then?
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't know how well that would do in the US.
Speaker 0: I could see people getting very angry.
Speaker 0: unless it came with 12 it could as the like the final end piece or something.
Speaker 1: We'll see what happens.
Speaker 0: but the manga was really really really popular really really good.
Speaker 0: the live-action movie No one I know has said anything good about it.
Speaker 0: Emily posted in the forums about the specific faults it had.
Speaker 0: I haven't seen it yet, but I really trust her opinion on this one.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen it.
Speaker 1: I haven't seen the FMA movie either, but I'm getting the same vibes From people who have seen those, you know.
Speaker 1: But both movies seem to get the same feeling going on where it's based on a thing that we like.
Speaker 1: Yet it's not really holding up in the movie theater.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a quote she used that I think probably describes it very well was that for the mood of the Death Note live-action movie?
Speaker 0: She expected a thunderstorm and got a drizzle.
Speaker 0: Oh Pun yeah, but the anime?
Speaker 0: We wondered.
Speaker 0: you know how that Scott talked earlier.
Speaker 0: How are they gonna do this?
Speaker 0: because the manga is very guy talking guy talking guy?
Speaker 0: Thinking guy thinking and then suddenly an action scene and then another you know thousand pages Scenes of the best freaking parts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so but you wonder how could they make this interesting as an anime?
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it turns out that they actually did a decent job.
Speaker 1: The thing is I get this feeling that if I hadn't already read the manga That it would have I would feel it more when I watch the anime, you know, but because I've read the manga I'm not feeling it so much because I already know what's going down
Speaker 0: well.
Speaker 0: instead the feeling I get because I've read the manga is more of a oh Here's when this happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, here's when this hat see.
Speaker 1: the thing is if I didn't read the manga I think I might be getting a oh shit.
Speaker 1: Look what happened, which would be more, you know exciting.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean the way this show plays out.
Speaker 0: I think he kills people by writing names in a book.
Speaker 0: now that's exciting in the manga because it doesn't move.
Speaker 0: How do you Animate a scene where he is writing names in a book and somehow make that interesting?
Speaker 1: Well, you do a montage of people dying all over the place from heart attacks, you know Where you show like a half transparent picture of him writing names furiously in a book with some rockin music Rockin orchestral music I might add.
Speaker 1: right it fits is what matters.
Speaker 0: They managed to make a scene where a dude is writing in a notebook while laughing maniacally.
Speaker 0: one Not cliche or stupid or cheesy and two kind of awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it is pretty cool.
Speaker 1: I mean in the manga you actually see him.
Speaker 1: do other stuff, you know Like you'll.
Speaker 1: you see him like watching TV find a specific criminal pick them out Talk about why he picked that guy.
Speaker 1: and so, you know, that's not gonna work in an anime at all.
Speaker 0: No, it definitely.
Speaker 0: it is pretty much as for the first two episodes at least extremely faithful to the manga.
Speaker 0: It is a straight up port.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, it is.
Speaker 1: I was.
Speaker 1: I was questioning like, you know at certain points they'd be like, oh are they gonna change something?
Speaker 1: Are they gonna change something?
Speaker 1: but no it's it's direct it's exactly what's in the mug.
Speaker 0: Yeah the most they seem to be doing is leaving out really really irrelevant details that you don't really need to know like they show a Couple specific people he killed because those specific people end up mattering later.
Speaker 0: But for all the generic people he killed they even bother with it.
Speaker 1: Yeah They took.
Speaker 1: basically if you went through the manga and you picked out the key scenes They put those in the anime and all the stuff in between Gets glossed over and covered in montages and and other sorts of things like that.
Speaker 0: Now the one thing that they did differently, but they really had to do it differently was you know How do you set up the scenes?
Speaker 0: How do you portray how lights tone of voice?
Speaker 0: How do you do these things?
Speaker 0: How does he speak?
Speaker 0: What does he what does he say?
Speaker 0: How does he say it is they're not gonna follow the dialogue in the manga straight up.
Speaker 0: that wouldn't work at all.
Speaker 1: No, I think they've actually changed it quite a bit Like they have him set calling himself a god and being way crazier way earlier Yeah, but that I think that takes out.
Speaker 1: that takes out his decline into being an insane villain.
Speaker 0: Well, see, I don't know because because it's more real time It seems that I can.
Speaker 0: the person I got in the manga was that he was always the insane villain and he was just looking For an outlet.
Speaker 0: could be could be because in the second episode not not really gonna spoil anything But a policeman is after him and he's sitting there thinking ha ha ha you can't get me.
Speaker 0: I'm so cool.
Speaker 1: I'm so smart So cool, I'm so smart.
Speaker 0: and then the cop he's like, haha, whatever filthy human I'll continue doing what I'm doing.
Speaker 0: and then the cop on the TV says Kira is evil what you were doing is evil.
Speaker 0: and then you see him twitch and then he just freaks out and immediately writes the dude's name down.
Speaker 0: Yep, and It just shows that the kid really is unbalanced and I think they do a good job of portraying that though They might do it a little more quickly than the manga did.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's that's all I really said.
Speaker 1: Is that you know in the manga you see a guy, you know It starts out where they kind of a lot of people get tricked into identifying with him a little bit Especially if you know, you're a pro death penalty kind of person.
Speaker 1: you you know, you think that way, you know.
Speaker 1: And then they slowly make him more and more evil and it isn't until volume two or three that he's really like whoa, dude Whoa Whoa, all right chill out.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, the thing is they gloss over like in the manga.
Speaker 0: He starts killing pretty petty criminals pretty early.
Speaker 0: They just don't make a big deal about it.
Speaker 0: They just he just kind of mentioned, you know They mentioned like but purse snatchers being killed blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: in the anime They definitely, you know hammered into you that this guy is writing down as many criminal names as possible all the time.
Speaker 0: In fact, you know I would actually note that because the in the anime you hear his voice as opposed to just seeing because even early on in the Manga one of the things about this is that light has this characteristic snare.
Speaker 0: He has this light look on his face when he does something evil and you get that in the manga pretty much from the start All the way through.
Speaker 0: but now because you have him saying things with it.
Speaker 0: It might just be that it seems more evil because now we hear his voice.
Speaker 1: It could be it could be.
Speaker 1: the voice acting is definitely highlights the evil pretty well.
Speaker 0: now Probably the best character in Death Note is not Elle the awesome dude who's going after him who is Unique and stylized in a way that if you haven't read the manga, I'm not going to ruin.
Speaker 0: But and then there's light.
Speaker 1: but Ryuk Ryuk is my man.
Speaker 1: Pretty much you can't in Death Note.
Speaker 1: It's really hard to root for anyone full-on.
Speaker 1: I mean Elle is cool and the good guy, but he's a little off.
Speaker 0: I don't think he's a little off.
Speaker 0: I think he's adorable.
Speaker 1: Like I said, he's a little off.
Speaker 1: So the only one I can really root for is Ryuk who is the Shinigami god of death Because it's not evil if he kills people and you don't even really see him killing people.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's his job.
Speaker 1: that would be like rooting against the grim reaper if you're rooted against Ryuk.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean the reason the Death Notes on the planet is that Ryuk a death God was basically bored and wanted to see what would happen.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean in the in the world of the Shinigami where all the Shinigami hang out.
Speaker 1: everyone all the Shinigami are losers and they Sit around gambling and doing nothing all day and they should be killing people.
Speaker 1: So Ryuk says this sucks.
Speaker 1: Everyone here sucks.
Speaker 1: I'm leaving and Ryuk is also an awesome Shinigami.
Speaker 1: He tricked the the super god of death into giving him two Death Notes.
Speaker 1: So, you know, this guy's up to something.
Speaker 1: so he's the only guy I can root for and In the show they do a pretty good job of portraying him.
Speaker 1: I mean he's got that nice happy looking smile and he's real he's acting just like he did in the in the manga.
Speaker 1: He's eating apples all the time.
Speaker 0: Yeah Because one thing that Ryuk provided a lot was in the manga Little bits of comic relief here and there that were really sparse but really really funny.
Speaker 1: I mean this guy this guy if he doesn't eat an apple will get turned upside down and inside out and twisty and twisty.
Speaker 1: It's pretty funny when that happens, but the one thing I think in the anime about Ryuk though I think his voice actor while good isn't really What I imagined.
Speaker 0: see actually I think it's okay.
Speaker 0: the only voice that's okay, it's not bad.
Speaker 0: I think it's great.
Speaker 0: The only voice that didn't really sit with me too.
Speaker 0: Well was Al?
Speaker 0: I think it.
Speaker 0: it sounded a little too deep and cool.
Speaker 1: I think that because we didn't each actually see much of Al because he only appeared for a little bit at the end of the Second episode.
Speaker 1: I think in episode three when you're he's actually like, you know doing the tennis scene and stuff like that That you know, he's gonna talk like a normal guy.
Speaker 1: We'll see better We'll see.
Speaker 0: cuz I know the manga gives you one impression of Al then we meet him you get an entirely different impression.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think that's what they're doing Maybe in the animes because we're still at the point of the first impression of Al and not the second impression.
Speaker 0: now There's one thing that the anime did that wasn't really in the manga.
Speaker 0: well Really - they're really minor.
Speaker 0: but I think these are the kinds of things that are gonna make the anime stand out and make it Sit a little bit above the rest in terms of manga.
Speaker 0: that gets turned into anime And that when Ryuk first appears like he appears and lights writing and light sees him and light freaks out He just freaks out yep, and he falls to the floor and then Ryuk's like blah blah blah and then light gains his composure and he tries with a straight face to say I Knew you'd come.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and Ryuk has this look like whatever dude.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: and then Ryuk is watching him You know writing all these names the death note and he says something along the effect of wow You've been busy and if you pet be pants down and you see that he's written hundreds and hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of names And it's only been like a day or two.
Speaker 1: Yeah, another thing is like they can add a lot more, you know, it's a certain Scenes that the panels in the manga didn't really emphasize so well.
Speaker 1: like when he writes this one guy's name down He writes it real big and real quick diagonally like ah, cuz he's angry, you know.
Speaker 1: and in the manga They just kind of you know, they might have written it that way I don't remember but it's just like one panel with some action lines You know.
Speaker 1: and in an anime that you can you can feel it more when you're watching them when you're reading.
Speaker 0: now One thing this anime does that is a little bit different from pretty much anything else out there right now is that it uses Panels.
Speaker 0: it uses a lot of these kind of like the initial D American release the tricked-out version where they'll take like a black bar and have one guy's face on one side one guy's face on the other side and they're Panning in opposite directions and then something else pans across.
Speaker 1: Yeah that that happened a few times but it wasn't out of control.
Speaker 1: Gundam seed style.
Speaker 0: Well, that's the thing.
Speaker 0: This is probably the first time other than the hit me baby one more time anime music video to antenna Where something like that was used?
Speaker 0: Well at least well enough to where it didn't annoy me.
Speaker 1: It's like I remember back in like my middle school days when you had when the only way you could edit videos the two VCRs and this box that had a few effects built into it and Starwipe yeah star right exactly and Basically any effect in that box was cheesy.
Speaker 1: So it was impossible to make a non cheesy movie with that device.
Speaker 1: but you know it's.
Speaker 1: one of those things that you could do is is stuff like that where you can have you know like half of one tape on the top and half of one of the bottom and kind of move them around a little bit and You know when someone uses those old-school effects, well, it's you know, they're doing something, right?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean pretty much the hit me baby one more time.
Speaker 0: AMV and death note are some of the only things I've ever seen where that was either put to good use or at least Not put to bad use.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think really the way you use that poorly is overuse.
Speaker 1: You know if you keep doing it and doing it and doing it then it's a problem kind of life.
Speaker 0: when Gundam seed Anytime something happened it would cut to every single character in the show who was still alive going.
Speaker 1: Yep They would split the screen into ten pieces with a different face in each piece and split the screen into ten pieces again Then do a full screen on the character who cares the most.
Speaker 0: who directed that?
Speaker 0: I forget Is I wanted cuz?
Speaker 0: I thought oh if I didn't know I would have thought huh, maybe the same guy.
Speaker 1: No, it's not the same.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know.
Speaker 0: It's totally not because Araki hasn't done much.
Speaker 1: Yep anyway Death note anime.
Speaker 1: so far two episodes watch.
Speaker 0: pretty good If you've read the manga, it's worth watching.
Speaker 0: if you haven't read the manga.
Speaker 0: It's worth watching.
Speaker 0: Yeah,
Speaker 1: I really want to know what people who haven't read the manga and don't know anything about death note Think about it, you know because I'm coming from you know, the position of already knowing almost everything that's gonna happen,
Speaker 0: you know Yeah, I
Speaker 1: mean if you go into a movie and you already know
Speaker 0: You don't know everything that happens cuz you don't know how.
Speaker 1: the second Everything but I know most and I'm pretty sure the manga might finish before I see the whole anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I ended up reading these spoiler thread because good job.
Speaker 0: I figured mr Period wouldn't go in there and Scott wasn't gonna go in there.
Speaker 0: and I'll say right now in the manga of death note The only thing that bothers me is that everything comes to a head about halfway through like volume 70 and something crazy happens.
Speaker 0: And then after that, it's like the new characters that come in and the new stuff that happens just really didn't interest me at all.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like there's a season 2 and like I've read up to like the beginning part the few beginning chapters of season 2 of death note.
Speaker 1: And it really, you know while it seems good.
Speaker 1: It's better than a lot of other manga out there It doesn't really compare to the first part of the manga.
Speaker 1: That was so awesome.
Speaker 1: So you get you it feels not good.
Speaker 0: now I have my thoughts as to how Death Note should have ended or at least how the second season should have progressed.
Speaker 0: and I have A thought to the point that if I could get someone to help me draw it I would be all about doing the dreaded fiction the dreaded fan fiction.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, that that is how bad not bad but how Disappointing the second half of Death Note was to that.
Speaker 0: It will drive a man like me to fan fiction.
Speaker 0: Oh god, I think it could have ended better course.
Speaker 0: I haven't read the end.
Speaker 0: I just read the spoiler Yeah, and but - I read a bunch.
Speaker 1: the execution of that could be much different than you think but
Speaker 0: regardless of that I read a bunch of you know after the event happens on Scanslations before I stopped and pretty much from that moment on the manga was kind of and I didn't like any of the new Characters.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I do have to read a few more chapters of you know The season 2 before.
Speaker 1: I think I can you know get a full opinion on it.
Speaker 1: But I have read maybe three or four of those chapters.
Speaker 0: I don't think anyone who's read the manga disagrees that the second after the first story arc it really Is not as good.
Speaker 1: so it all feels worse than it is I think because it's not as good.
Speaker 1: It's like if you make the most amazing manga in the world like a 10 star manga and then halfway through it becomes a 9 star Manga.
Speaker 1: that 9 star part is gonna feel like a 5 star because they're used to 10 star.
Speaker 1: I'm not saying the second half is 9 star because I don't think it is.
Speaker 1: I think it's more like 7 or 6 But it feels like 5 or 4 because the first part is like 9.
Speaker 0: but enough people were talking smack about it that I felt The need to spoil it for myself.
Speaker 1: I think the other Reason that they don't like the second half is because the characters in the first half are a lot better.
Speaker 1: There's only one annoying character Which is Misa Misa.
Speaker 1: and then you know characters get subtracted and then added in the second half.
Speaker 1: and the characters they add no one Likes them.
Speaker 1: they suck.
Speaker 1: They're not interesting.
Speaker 1: No one can identify with them.
Speaker 1: No one cares.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know and that's you know people.
Speaker 1: if you look at what makes an anime popular It's having characters that people like.
Speaker 1: They look at Fullmetal Alchemist.
Speaker 1: most of what that anime's got going for is characters people like huh?
Speaker 0: It's almost like they think with Naruto It's almost like the Fullmetal Alchemist people designed a host of characters that together would have enough Popularity to make a blockbuster.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's like why harem shows are so successful.
Speaker 1: It's because they have one girl for every possible taste in women that a middle school kid can have and that an old Perverted guy can have that no matter who's watching the show.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be a character They really like their harem shows for girls.
Speaker 0: Remember of mine.
Speaker 1: Liebe, which they have one guy character for every possible.
Speaker 0: Hello, I'm the naughty German boy.
Speaker 0: Hello.
Speaker 0: I'm the cute German boy.
Speaker 0: I am the normal awesome German boy.
Speaker 0: I am the bearded German boy Exactly.
Speaker 1: So no matter what your taste is there's a character that you can get with in death note.
Speaker 1: not the case Especially the second half.
Speaker 1: But anyway Ryuk is the man and he is there throughout.
Speaker 0: Yep, it's really hard to get rid of a god of dead and Ryuk and Misa Misa are really the only Comedy in this whole thing.
Speaker 0: It's a really dark manga.
Speaker 0: It's a really dark show.
Speaker 1: Yeah That's I guess that's why I like the lighter parts better.
Speaker 0: Oh His reeks there that was that was terrible pun.
Speaker 0: That was really fucking bad.
Speaker 1: Okay, so Yeah death note.
Speaker 0: cool Yeah, we were also gonna talk about pumpkin scissors tonight But we decided not to mostly because I'd like to spend more than five minutes talking about it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, it's pretty much saying before the show should we talk about both of these shows or just one?
Speaker 1: and we said, okay We'll talk about death note and see how long we talk and if we don't talk long We'll start talking about pumpkin scissors.
Speaker 1: and I guess what we talked long.
Speaker 0: Yep Because a lot of you have been asking is what we think of pumpkin scissors and we haven't watched it yet until just now.
Speaker 1: I think what we'll do is watch the second episode to you know tomorrow.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think I think next week We're probably going to do two previews of two shows that don't deserve quite as much talk as the death note show did.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know I think that the death note show like I don't know if it's a good enough show to really deserve the whole episode But because it's based on such a great manga you gotta gotta give it up.
Speaker 0: Yeah, plus people have been clamoring for that, too.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so clamor no more.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and I will say about pumpkin scissors I'm probably not going to watch more of it.
Speaker 1: No, I'm definitely not gonna watch more pumpkin scissors despite its funny name and awesome logo.
Speaker 0: I think anime world order is is right about their whole gonzo hypothesis, but we'll talk about that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I used to think differently.
Speaker 0: But yeah, well there is one possible exception But I have to see the end of the show to find out anyway done for that next week And that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcasts, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.