Speaker 1: It's Wednesday July 19th, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 1: We talk about comics with 100 bullets.
Speaker 1: also instead of a news We've got a double geek back about Kinetic on.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: Well, we actually are going to do a double geek back today since after the Kinetic on coverage We got not one, but two good and interesting emails about it.
Speaker 0: Oh It looks like this geek bag segment has really taken off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well considering that we got a lot of audio feedback before that we never actually answered on the show.
Speaker 1: We just sent emails back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, you know I guess when you get emails you like to respond to them But eventually you just kind of have to resist the urge.
Speaker 1: yep, so keep in mind if we don't respond to your email It's probably because we're just going to force ourselves to talk about it on the show instead of answering you personally.
Speaker 0: and if we do respond Your chances of being on the show or maybe like 50/50 and then in the distant future if we have a hajillion listeners at some Point then we're probably not going to respond to anybody.
Speaker 0: That's what the forums are for.
Speaker 1: We'll start paying Mr.
Speaker 1: Period and he'll filter all the email for us.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right Yeah, only you know all the emails go to him and then forward us the ones that are worth reading.
Speaker 1: Watch He'll only forward us the ones that have perfect grammar and spelling.
Speaker 1: We'll get like one email a year.
Speaker 1: That'd be awesome All right, anyway, we are first geek back and they're both about Kineticon.
Speaker 1: now is from Michael Moore.
Speaker 1: not not Michael Moore.
Speaker 1: I was gonna say yeah, apparently he gets people make fun of him all the time for that.
Speaker 1: But no, it's Michael Moore of abstract gender a webcomic.
Speaker 1: Okay?
Speaker 1: Hey, I met you guys at Kineticon when I went over to talk to Yuko on Saturday Not sure if you remember me.
Speaker 1: Well, we do but I'm a webcomic artist and was in the uber webcomics panel.
Speaker 1: I've actually been doing it for the last three years.
Speaker 1: of the three I was in this is probably number two.
Speaker 1: last year's was probably the worst But I do think that a lot of the criticisms of the con were pretty dead-on and your ideas for the webcomic panel would Have made it a lot better.
Speaker 1: I've been listening to the recent podcast about the con and the last two years has been in the convention center.
Speaker 1: the first year I went It was at a college nearby and I think it was the Hartford College or something It's University of Hartford because when it was there one year I was Doing like a summer.
Speaker 0: I was a counselor at a summer camp.
Speaker 0: That was there also and I remember being at camp that Friday playing kickball and there was like an Inuyasha cosplayer running around outside.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I didn't actually go to the con that year.
Speaker 0: I just went home that night because I was tired of taking care of bratty kids all day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, Mike obviously isn't a native since he didn't know all that.
Speaker 1: But anyway, actually no he says.
Speaker 1: but anyway when it was prob When it was there It was a 24-hour con and that was really cool and as nice and shiny as the Convention Center is the college probably would work Better for the con since back then they had tons of rooms like each video game had its own room.
Speaker 1: DDR had two rooms and it ran 24 hours a day.
Speaker 1: But I guess the problem with the college is that there weren't any big areas to do main events.
Speaker 1: I do sort of feel like this year they may have been the worst one is so far panel wise.
Speaker 1: But that may be just me because there used to be all sorts of meet-and-greet panels with all the webcomic people's usually doubled up.
Speaker 1: Blah blah blah.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: I'll note me actually that there were a bunch of meet-and-greet panels.
Speaker 1: We didn't actually go to any of them because most of them were on Sunday.
Speaker 0: Yeah, also he's totally right about University Department for not having too many big rooms.
Speaker 0: I mean, I know a bunch of the buildings there and it's really they don't have like giant auditoriums or big wide-open rooms at all that I know of.
Speaker 0: you know Maybe the gymnasium and then they have some outside fields that you could use.
Speaker 0: but if there's bad weather your cons ruined.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he just goes on for a while to talk about how much he likes geek nights And hopefully you'll see us at Otacon and check out our panels and all that.
Speaker 0: Well, he's definitely gonna see us at Otacon.
Speaker 0: Everyone's gonna see us there Except for the blind people.
Speaker 0: The blind people will not see us at Otacon.
Speaker 1: They'd better hear us That's right.
Speaker 1: If they're blind and deaf.
Speaker 1: Well, we'll poke him.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and anyway Since he said he may or may not plug us That was Michael Moore of abstract gender abstractgender.com.
Speaker 0: if you want to read his webcomic Which I have never read and therefore cannot form an opinion about yep
Speaker 1: I guess all I really have to say is that I do think that Kineticon hopefully will do something to make the uber webcomics panel as Good as it apparently was in days of yore.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know, it's it's one thing if something is always sucked And then they can't make it better.
Speaker 0: It's like, okay Well, you know, you can't really say anything, but if someone had a good thing going and they failed to maintain it It's just kind of sad
Speaker 1: yeah, but actually the second email which I rushed through the first one because this geek back is much longer much more thorough and Also much more official probably answers that question in better detail.
Speaker 1: This is from Brianna Ben the vice chairperson of Kineticon, holy crap.
Speaker 1: They apparently she listened to our Show on Kineticon and they had quite a bit to say.
Speaker 1: I don't think I'm gonna read the entire thing.
Speaker 0: Can we break it down point by point?
Speaker 1: Yep I'll break it down Starting with the webcomics in the dealers room because I remember we talked that all the big webcomics were in the dealers room and the small Ones were in the artists colony.
Speaker 1: Yep quote bigger comics get a bit better treatment.
Speaker 1: They do more for the convention.
Speaker 1: They may get a free table in the artist colony or the dealers room based on their popularity.
Speaker 1: Additionally anyone can buy a table in either location.
Speaker 1: Bigger comics usually have a bit more money and buy a table in the dealers room smaller people.
Speaker 1: We feel some people feel we are unfair to the smaller comic, but they miss the boat entirely.
Speaker 1: We help foster the growth of any and all webcomics.
Speaker 1: But yeah, the bigger names are gonna have a bigger presence now.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we really weren't complaining that the big names were in the dealers room as opposed the artists alley.
Speaker 1: It's more that it did seem to detract from the artist alley.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's that was my main problem with.
Speaker 0: it is like, you know Usually like at Otakon you go to the artists alley right and the artists alley is anything that's not Dealing the old and the only webcomic I could think of that was in the dealers room at Otakon was mega Tokyo and that's cuz.
Speaker 1: He was mostly dealing his merchandise and his stuff true But yet at a katsu khan there were many many webcomic artists in the dealers room.
Speaker 1: I think it depends a lot on the Khan.
Speaker 0: I think it does too.
Speaker 0: But yeah, the only problem with that is that the artist alley is kind of you know marginalized Yep.
Speaker 1: Now in terms of the parking lot quote, we hate the parking lot, but we can't restructure the damn thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's a I can't complain.
Speaker 0: Kinetic on has nothing to do with its sucky parking lot.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's completely the Convention Center's sucky parking lot.
Speaker 1: now in regards to food Quote I am told that there will be a mall with a food court built across the street from the CCC.
Speaker 1: Hallelujah, it really sucks about the no outside for food rule.
Speaker 1: They don't even let us bring in food for our staff members guests or volunteers.
Speaker 1: assets We recommend.
Speaker 0: if you want to have a pizza party can't?
Speaker 1: We recommend the arch street tavern across the street where food costs roughly the same, but it is much better quality.
Speaker 0: I didn't know it was there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean anything like in the con book or anywhere.
Speaker 0: that said if you want to eat go to the art street tavern.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't think so cuz I know Otakon and a little book gives you a guide to like food in the area Doesn't it?
Speaker 1: Oh, yes, it does.
Speaker 1: Yeah They do an extensive thing and actually I would really recommend that Kinetic on at least have one small section in the convo detailing The nearest food.
Speaker 1: that isn't terrible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't just get.
Speaker 0: was there a map of the surrounding area or actually This idea is kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: I came up with this just now so it's not fully thought out now.
Speaker 1: Obviously the reason that the Convention Center doesn't allow outside food So they can make a bunch of money from you know, ripping people off with crappy food.
Speaker 1: Every Convention Center does it and the reason they charge so much money is pretty commonly known that Business travelers don't care how much money it costs.
Speaker 1: their company picks it all up.
Speaker 1: So it's kind of a scam for Convention Centers to make a bunch of money off of businesses doesn't really work so well for anime cons and honestly Otakon is really the only con that has the Money and the clout to tell the Convention Center.
Speaker 1: Hey, that doesn't work.
Speaker 1: do something different.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is the first year where they're really trying to muscle them over into doing something different with the food Yep, which apparently was helped a lot by the fact that a different person is in charge of the food.
Speaker 0: now Yeah But I mean seriously if you let's say you were a business and you were taking out a room or two in the Convention Center for like a big meeting or something.
Speaker 0: You could get your own caterer if you want.
Speaker 0: they can't.
Speaker 1: no No, you can't.
Speaker 0: I mean like their way you can pay to get your own caterer in there.
Speaker 1: Usually most Convention Centers require you to get any and all food through them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean they there's food that you can get through them other than oh, yeah, but it's horribly expensive.
Speaker 1: I guarantee it.
Speaker 1: But anyway, here's a crazy idea now.
Speaker 1: obviously you couldn't do this on the grounds of the Convention Center doi, but Depending on the actual city's laws It might be possible to get a permit to have some sort of food vending just outside the Convention Center and sponsor it by the con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but you know, this is the problem of non People without badges taking advantage.
Speaker 0: Oh, no.
Speaker 1: No you charge money.
Speaker 1: You just charge a reasonable amount.
Speaker 1: I haven't thought it through it all and I'm gonna think about this because even if it was Wouldn't work for Kineticon.
Speaker 1: There are probably a lot of other cons where they could pull something off like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, a hotel con you can get catering.
Speaker 0: I know.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 1: Well anime central used to always have a green room that was full of Entire meals for free for anyone who went to the con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and also a college con you can do it out on the lawn.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it really depends on the the specific geographic area.
Speaker 0: Like let's say I was Otakon right and I wasn't as big as I was Taking up the entire Convention Center.
Speaker 0: Yeah And let's say I just used like one or two rooms in the Convention Center in Baltimore.
Speaker 0: what I could what I would do To get food is take out one room in a nearby hotel For the food and then if people wanted food they could just walk over a little bridge to like the Sheraton or something where?
Speaker 0: We have food.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll think about this more because there's got to be a way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like there's that Marriott attached to the Convention Center, right if you took out one room in the Marriott And in Connecticut and put food in there would that work?
Speaker 0: I mean that you can cater whoever you want to the Marriott right.
Speaker 1: see I actually don't know all the details I'm not sure.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's something to check up on.
Speaker 1: yeah I mean there's also the liability of serving food and all the trouble around that of course of course.
Speaker 1: But again, I mean we can't blame Connecticut for the food situation because obviously the CCC is being very heavy-handed.
Speaker 0: Well every Convention Center with its unions and its big fat hand yeah Heaviness 50 bucks to get a power cable.
Speaker 0: Yeah, big B's Convention Center.
Speaker 1: fist All right on an expert quote FYI Otacon now cost $60 pre-reg and they only take pre-reg now, okay It's $50 if you pre-reg before July 7.
Speaker 0: July 7 too late It's $60 now.
Speaker 1: over 14,000 people pre-registered for Otacon back when it was $50 this year.
Speaker 1: Yep, so less than half of the attendees will pay the full $60 price To go on anime next and anime Boston cost the same amount as Connecticut.
Speaker 1: Connecticut does not have the same number in attendance yet, so it gets smaller income.
Speaker 1: however We believe that we provide programming that equals or in some way exceeds that of these other conventions.
Speaker 0: I see I have to disagree on that last point saying that they're programming equals or exceeds.
Speaker 0: I mean anime next head Rintaro and Murayama and Japanese guests, and you know it was.
Speaker 0: it's like one level above Connecticut in programming It's.
Speaker 0: it's hard to deny that anime Boston as well.
Speaker 0: You know I mean the American voice actors who usually go to every single convention weren't at Connecticut.
Speaker 1: a few of them were yeah But not many.
Speaker 0: It's usually you get like the same like ten people can I kind of had maybe like two or three.
Speaker 0: yeah, you know it if If you just look at the guests and you look at the fact that you know a lot of panels were thrown together.
Speaker 0: and right You can't I just can't agree with that last statement.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean the gaming helped a lot But I mean
Speaker 0: the gaming did help a lot considering that a gaming convention of almost that caliber It kind of evens it out
Speaker 1: even an amazement which I don't remember actually But I'm pretty sure it was either less than or at the very most it cost the same as Connecticut.
Speaker 1: Yet their programming was absolutely amazing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, who is that guy you hung out with there?
Speaker 1: Oh, they had a Kira Kamiya and just a pile of awesome Japanese guests they also had in Amazing panels.
Speaker 1: I mean the panels were well done and well researched like a off the top of my head.
Speaker 1: There was a geisha panel And it was run by an actual teacher who had studied this and done like a thesis on it And she really knew her stuff.
Speaker 1: and she put on an amazing lecture.
Speaker 1: Yeah, see and almost every panel was of that quality.
Speaker 1: while here at a Connecticut I mean not to Snipe but we've the only panel we went to was someone who was forced to do the panel at the last minute and Looking at the list of panels none of them even seemed Interesting or exciting you know.
Speaker 1: yeah, I guess it's just that the con does feel a bit overpriced to us.
Speaker 0: still yeah It's not overpriced in terms of just comparing the price to other conventions.
Speaker 0: It's comparing the price to You know when you consider what's at the convention and the fact that you know hey your con has less people Maybe it's because of the price.
Speaker 0: Maybe if you lowered the price you would get more people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean, I just think like Otacon and the amount of programming Otacon has I honestly would pay upwards of $150 for a weekend of Otacon without Otacon is really a deal It's it's sort of a.
Speaker 0: it's like a big steal for all the fans.
Speaker 0: You know but other cons are not Alright.
Speaker 1: now moving on here the no $5 dollar bill issue quote because the Convention Center requested an additional $20,000 up front this year.
Speaker 1: we did not have extra cash on hand to get lots of fives.
Speaker 1: We had to borrow roughly six thousand dollars from family and friends in order to meet the initial pre-con costs.
Speaker 1: We had foresight, but no money.
Speaker 1: research save kinetic on for more information on that.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's right.
Speaker 0: save kinetic on.
Speaker 1: was that thing that Well all the webcomic artists got together and raised a bunch of money to save kinetic on from bankruptcy after last year's debacle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like the Convention Center requested an additional 20,000 again.
Speaker 0: We I think we talked about this before was that either kinetic on failed to read their contract properly and they didn't.
Speaker 0: they should have known that they would have cost more money and therefore probably shouldn't have had it at the Convention Center.
Speaker 0: or if the Convention Center did something that was against the contract kinetic on should have gotten a lawyer.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean honestly.
Speaker 1: I really not have called a lawyer that minute.
Speaker 0: normally I would say false dichotomy You know saying it was either this or that.
Speaker 0: But when I you know research save kinetic on and I look at what the situation was from the available public information Those are the only two things I can conclude is that
Speaker 1: I'd really lean toward it being the latter Just because of other things I've read and heard about the Convention Center.
Speaker 1: But even then I really would have called a lawyer and fought it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway get back on the point.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I can see the Convention Center asking for the additional 120,000 especially after what happened last year.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and as for the fives, uh, I don't know I can.
Speaker 1: I guess I would have set up something.
Speaker 1: in the very least you could have had a bunch of people You know ready.
Speaker 1: or maybe Friday night take all the money you've got from the con all the cash on hand.
Speaker 1: Take it to the bank first thing in the morning Saturday Exchange it for fives and then come back and then you were good to go.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz on Friday a lot of the people showing up were probably pre reg type people who have already paid, you know.
Speaker 1: And then yeah, just set up runners, you know.
Speaker 1: Send people to the bank Constantly getting fives as long as you need him because it's not like they had a bunch of fives and ran out.
Speaker 1: It was that we were some of the first people to register and they didn't have any already.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep But yeah, there's not much you can do if you're already short on money.
Speaker 1: I really think the economy better off being outside of the Convention Center for a couple more years.
Speaker 1: Then they'd have a lot more money to spend on all these other niceties and then when they jump to the Convention Center They'll have enough people to just pay for it not even worry about it.
Speaker 0: I really You know without knowing any of the finances or accounting or the convention at all I have to say that if you have less attendees Then you know anime next anime Boston and other area conventions you had.
Speaker 0: you're charging just as much money You have.
Speaker 0: you know less, you know, you're not at the same level of programming.
Speaker 0: You really shouldn't be in a more expensive Venue plus.
Speaker 1: honestly, I think it would really foster the convention experience at least for a few more years to have it in a hotel.
Speaker 1: because I mean like our previous geek back said Going 24 hours in a con like this is huge because most of the people who go are webcomic people who just want to hang out all night with their webcomic friends.
Speaker 0: and also your gaming is really strong and if your Gaming can go 24 hours as opposed to people having to stop and pick it up again.
Speaker 0: That's also huge.
Speaker 1: I mean if you if you wait in a hotel until you get to the point where the hotel is too small and then you jump Everyone's gonna follow you I can guarantee it because at that point that means that more people want to go to the con than Could fit and you have to go to a bigger venue.
Speaker 1: I just don't think that Connecticut is big enough to need to be in a big venue and I really think it's overpriced.
Speaker 1: for what?
Speaker 1: You get?
Speaker 0: yeah, there are big hotel.
Speaker 0: There have to be big hotels in the capital of Connecticut, which is Hartford.
Speaker 1: or of course I mean, there's always the option of moving to somewhere else in Connecticut.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sure there's some places in New Haven they could go to.
Speaker 1: I mean Otacon wasn't in Baltimore for a while.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know there there are lots of other cities in Connecticut, I think Stanford has some places you could be in.
Speaker 0: you know the Hartford, Connecticut isn't the only city in Connecticut that's big enough to handle an anime convention of this size.
Speaker 1: Alright now regarding the crappy bags quote all conventions this year have been really hit as far as bag sponsors.
Speaker 1: The anime companies are really hurting with the closing of Suncoast and other retailers and providing bags is often a $10,000 investment for them.
Speaker 1: Even anime Boston had to run around to local stores like Newbury comics to try to get enough bags.
Speaker 1: We often supplement our bag supply with the extras of anime Boston.
Speaker 1: We had pretty much no bag.
Speaker 1: So it was either bum sum from the Best Buy or have no bags.
Speaker 1: We decided that having crappy bags is better than no bags for the use in the dealers room.
Speaker 1: since not all dealers have bags.
Speaker 1: We didn't fill in with goodies because we weren't provided with much.
Speaker 1: see the sponsors blur.
Speaker 1: now I can see that I mean that makes perfect sense.
Speaker 1: And my only thing I would say is that I wouldn't have put the program guide in the bag and given it out because that Honestly just look kind of cheap.
Speaker 1: I would have had the bags available at the entrance to the dealers room.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean just usually you get a bag at at registration because it's filled with all sorts of free Advertising.
Speaker 0: shit if it's only has the program guide in it Why are you giving me a bag?
Speaker 0: the bag is to hold other advertising in with the program guide.
Speaker 1: But in terms of the whole anime industry bit Brianna is pretty much dead on.
Speaker 1: the anime industry in the u.s.
Speaker 1: At least for the past few years has been hitting some hard times.
Speaker 0: It's what the way I've heard it explained.
Speaker 0: I don't remember where I heard this.
Speaker 0: possibly anime world order again.
Speaker 0: Is that you know?
Speaker 0: media play was like the bit and Suncoast and all you know?
Speaker 0: What was music land?
Speaker 0: that whole company was the big anime purchaser?
Speaker 0: You know.
Speaker 0: and whether people were buying anime from them.
Speaker 0: It didn't matter.
Speaker 0: It was the fact that they were buying anime from the anime companies.
Speaker 0: therefore the anime companies made a lot of money as media play existed and The belief of those companies with that anime is the way you're gonna make big bucks because you can get DVDs and charge them.
Speaker 0: You know full price MSRP and they're gonna.
Speaker 0: they're gonna sell and you're not gonna have to compete with the best buy or anyone and start selling your DVDs At like 15 bucks 13 bucks, you know to get one lower than the other store down the street with the blockbuster hits Especially since CDs aren't selling that well anymore either.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and the game stops and EVs are killing them on video games.
Speaker 0: and I think what's happened is there's been a shift in the DVD industry away from Anime being what's gonna make you the big bucks to TV on DVD being what's gonna make you the big bucks selling.
Speaker 0: you know seasons of this seasons of that, you know, and Therefore these the stores like Best Buy and everyone are buying less anime and media play no longer exists.
Speaker 0: So there's not too many retailers buying up more lots and lots of stuff.
Speaker 0: So the anime companies are only selling clothes are selling a number of DVDs closer to what?
Speaker 0: Actual fans are buying from them and you know, not what retailers are buying.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, I mean, it's also the fact that there haven't been many big properties in the last few years.
Speaker 1: I mean Fullmetal Alchemist was huge But because most a lot of people watched it on, you know download bit torrent whatnot?
Speaker 1: Cartoon Network Yeah that too and now that the economy is kind of down a lot of people who would normally buy You know every box set that comes out that either don't have enough money or there aren't so many they're interested in.
Speaker 1: I mean of all the anime I've bought recently It's mostly really really old stuff that I've always wanted and now's the time to buy it because there's nothing new to buy.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And the other thing is like the companies that are killing on anime, you know the which is like Cartoon Network and WB shows anime right and and all those guys Those guys never sponsor any cons.
Speaker 0: It's the visits and the You know the Tokyo pops and the edvs that are then in Funimation Of course that needs to sell this stuff and they're not doing as well.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: So there's really nothing you can do about that.
Speaker 0: yeah, Funimation is killing this is begun this and Tokyo pop are killing on the manga, but ADV not doing what he used to do.
Speaker 1: All right now.
Speaker 1: in regards to the program book quote It seems that you ask us somehow to have descriptions of the programming in the schedule.
Speaker 1: I'm not sure how this would be possible.
Speaker 1: in regards to the pocket schedule We greatly want to have it but the cost would be the equivalent of the rest of our entire program book.
Speaker 1: We really want to have this but it will be a while before Finances are forgiving enough to allow it.
Speaker 1: in regards to the full color program book I normally veto all suggestions that involve spending money, but I was out ruled on this issue.
Speaker 1: Additionally, we believe that a full color program book would look better to sponsors for the next year Thereby, hopefully improving our financial standing allowing for a pocket program schedule, etc.
Speaker 1: Honestly if you hadn't spent the money on the full color book you probably could have gotten the pocket schedule instead or the $5 bills.
Speaker 1: Well, that's enough.
Speaker 1: There wouldn't have been enough money for the $5 bill.
Speaker 0: It would have been some $5 bills.
Speaker 1: I guess for me the pocket schedule doesn't have to be anything fancy like a lot of other cons do it could have.
Speaker 0: it could Have been an eight and a half by eleven piece of paper, you know, just a slightly thicker piece of paper.
Speaker 1: I mean that I would have been happy with like two pieces of eight and a half by eleven paper stapled together With just a densely printed schedule.
Speaker 0: What did anime next had they had like?
Speaker 0: it was sort of like a. it was like a two pieces of paper But it was sort of like a legal piece of paper folded in half, right?
Speaker 1: Yeah, I was real wide.
Speaker 1: you could fold it and it was.
Speaker 0: it had the entire schedule on it Yeah, and only it was only like shitty color.
Speaker 0: It wasn't like color color.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I would've con puts theirs in black and white.
Speaker 0: They don't care.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you really could have had I'm sure you could have had some sort of pocket schedule And I really think the con should look into it.
Speaker 0: Just don't try to put too much into the pocket schedule think you know.
Speaker 1: do it light I mean, it should really just look like a spreadsheet out of Microsoft Office and nothing more.
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah, just you know tidied up a little don't put those dotted lines all over the.
Speaker 0: make it easy to read and simple and full Of the most important information you can fit on a page.
Speaker 1: now.
Speaker 1: in regards to the making it look nice for sponsors I don't have much to say about that that's really.
Speaker 1: I'm glad to see that kinetic on is at least forward thinking as to how they're going to be solvent in the Future and that's one way to go about it.
Speaker 1: I haven't really thought about that issue too deeply.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the thing was is looking good for sponsors, but they had a bunch of sponsors.
Speaker 0: What were they doing?
Speaker 1: Well, we can get to that with the next bit.
Speaker 1: Okay quote spot regarding sponsors.
Speaker 1: quote None of our sponsors actually gave us money.
Speaker 1: We decided to give various companies the full treatment so that they get a taste of what sponsoring with us in the future gives them.
Speaker 1: Best Buy provided us with loader frats flat-screen TVs funny girls.
Speaker 1: gave us some cool prize support.
Speaker 1: Funimation was supposed to give us some goodies which didn't happen yada yada yada.
Speaker 1: We basically wanted to pimp out a couple companies in order to show companies that Advertise.
Speaker 1: show companies the advertising we can provide in hopes of gaining further support from these companies and other companies next year.
Speaker 0: Mmm On the one hand it's kind of good.
Speaker 0: It's like hey, you know, no if those companies, you know We're thinking poorly of kinetic on it didn't want to sponsor it because they thought it wasn't worth their time You were able to prove to them that it, you know, possibly was worth their time and you know, that's a good thing.
Speaker 0: but on the other hand, you know if you give it away for free and Maybe they didn't get what they wanted now when you try to charge for it.
Speaker 0: Maybe they'd like no screw you It's a tough call.
Speaker 1: now I don't.
Speaker 1: I think it's actually a good thing because I'm not sure how it'll turn out.
Speaker 1: But like I said in the previous bit I'm very glad to see the con at least considering options and thinking long term as opposed to short term.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I still would you know, I wouldn't have an official sponsor of a con without them, you know doing something It's like hey you sponsored the con.
Speaker 0: We put your logo on things and you don't do anything.
Speaker 0: for us It's like okay, but why not?
Speaker 1: I mean worst case.
Speaker 1: they didn't lose anything That's true.
Speaker 1: And if the company decides not to go with them next year, they still haven't lost anything Yeah, but they also haven't gained anything that they greatly needed.
Speaker 1: So if you didn't lose anything then who cares if you didn't gain anything?
Speaker 1: you're even you might.
Speaker 0: if if the worst case area The question is could they have gained something?
Speaker 1: What do you mean?
Speaker 0: Well, if they let's say they didn't make sponsorship free could they have gotten sponsors to pay?
Speaker 0: why bother?
Speaker 1: They obviously were solvent without that this year anyway, and a comment has already had a lot of financial trouble.
Speaker 1: suddenly Approaching a bunch of sponsors and wanting money probably isn't gonna go over so well.
Speaker 1: this way they can show that one.
Speaker 1: they were solvent Without sponsors - they had treat sponsors very well in the future.
Speaker 1: I think I think it was a fairly good decision on their part.
Speaker 1: I mean the fact is the con was in a very tricky situation Monetarily anyway, and there's really no easy way out of the situation.
Speaker 1: They're in.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, even though honestly, I think if they move to a hotel this situation would be greatly mitigated.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I'm just 50/50 on.
Speaker 0: it's like it could be.
Speaker 0: this could be that you know.
Speaker 0: Like.
Speaker 0: if someone like it would be like if what do we give away free ads on geek nights and then be like Yeah, now you can see how many people visit you and then will they actually pay us if we ask for money later?
Speaker 0: You know, yeah It's just the share where.
Speaker 0: lesson, you know, if you give someone share where for free how many times they actually buy it?
Speaker 0: Not so many.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but who cares?
Speaker 1: they didn't lose anything.
Speaker 0: Yeah until they hack your share where the I'm just being silly.
Speaker 1: I mean one that the closest thing to hacking the convention were the $1 Geek Squad shirts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, there's nothing wrong with that.
Speaker 0: No, not really back.
Speaker 1: I saw a couple of people who claim that they were cosplaying as Best Buy guys, which was moderately funny.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course Geek Squad is terrible.
Speaker 0: Talk about that later.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway, the email goes on for a while.
Speaker 1: you know bother other little points, but I'm really happy that Brianna took the time to respond to us and I'm glad that we could give our response in Kind to the response because once again Connecticut wasn't a bad con by any means and it has a lot of potential.
Speaker 0: Yep Yep.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's just yet to be fulfilled potential.
Speaker 1: Yep I will see what happens next year because I think especially now that they've got a successful year under their belt That next year will go a lot smoother.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm I think what we'll do is we'll just wait for friends who are there on Friday, you know, give us a call Tell us what's going down.
Speaker 1: I might go for the whole weekend.
Speaker 1: We'll see.
Speaker 0: We'll see cuz I'll.
Speaker 1: probably I'm gonna see.
Speaker 1: maybe I'll see about doing the geek nights panel there or Taking over the anime club panel because they obviously are hurting for someone to do it and we do it everywhere else already.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if they're doing something like that, you know any con that I'll actually how we have a panel or something.
Speaker 1: I'll have to go to any con a because I could get you a panel at a con You wouldn't want to go to okay.
Speaker 0: Well, I would just go do the panel and go home.
Speaker 0: All right, what kind are you gonna do?
Speaker 1: Oh You have no idea things of the day, oh my Minds real quick.
Speaker 1: now a lot of people in the forums have been asking and someone's Reminded me outside of the forums that a while ago.
Speaker 1: I talked about an anime music video.
Speaker 1: That was really good and I said I'd post a link and I never did.
Speaker 1: So I didn't have a great thing of the day for today.
Speaker 1: So here we go.
Speaker 1: My thing of the day is that anime music video that I neglected to post talk about a cop-out.
Speaker 1: Yeah, what do you want?
Speaker 1: Actually it works because it's a really good AMV.
Speaker 0: It is a pretty good AMV.
Speaker 0: I think a lot of the appeal has to do with the song which is a really good song.
Speaker 0: That's really good lyrically and Young punk kids won't know the song.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean I barely knew the song.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the song is one of those songs has a funny name and I forget the name off.
Speaker 1: It's something and terminus, but everyone knows it as the 2525 song.
Speaker 1: Yep You know people who don't know about it, yeah, so all of us new punk kids have heard the song exactly now.
Speaker 1: The thing is the video didn't actually win anything normal at Otacon.
Speaker 1: No one voted for it, but it was so bad.
Speaker 0: I'm sure someone voted.
Speaker 1: Well, not enough people.
Speaker 1: Yeah It was so badass that the people in charge of the AMV contest at Otacon gave it an award like the judges pick or something.
Speaker 0: It was like the editors choice equivalent and it was probably the best music video of the whole con At least for us, you know the kind of music videos that we like.
Speaker 1: yeah, it really does seem to say something that the kinds of music videos that a lot of younger fans like are the Naruto people fighting with each other?
Speaker 1: funny But not so much funny even just you know fighting scenes and quick cuts and action.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's it's all about the beat mix.
Speaker 0: if the beat of the video matches the beat of the audio Then you got a good video.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but back in the day It seems like the popular videos were the really really funny ones or else the really really serious.
Speaker 0: Well, it's not so much the funny but the clever It's all.
Speaker 0: it was all about the cleverness.
Speaker 0: like aha you were funny in a clever way cuz it's easy to just.
Speaker 0: I mean That's if I took a funny anime an anime that's already hilarious and then I made an AMV of it.
Speaker 0: It's not hard to be funny.
Speaker 0: still it's hard to be cleverly funny.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, it's like if you hear the song crawling by Linkin Park and you think yeah, that sounds a lot like Shinji.
Speaker 1: I'll do an Ava music video to that anime.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's not clever.
Speaker 1: Everyone thought that.
Speaker 0: you know, we should do is we should take Nana and make an AMV but only when they have funny faces Only funny faces.
Speaker 1: We just need the right song for that.
Speaker 0: Does anyone know any good songs about funny faces?
Speaker 1: Hmm.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let's think on that.
Speaker 1: But anyway, if you don't like anime music videos if you like anime music videos, whatever I highly recommend you download this video and watch it.
Speaker 1: if you don't like him It'll probably change your mind.
Speaker 1: If you do like him, this might show you a kind of video that isn't so well known these days And not frequently made these days.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and whoever made it mad props to you We don't know who you are.
Speaker 0: We can't give you.
Speaker 1: well, we do know.
Speaker 1: I'm linking to his anime music video page.
Speaker 0: Oh, okay.
Speaker 0: I was gonna say how to know who it was.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not only that but he wrote a long thing about why he picked what anime he picked and how he put it all together.
Speaker 1: And now this is the second version of this video.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like stuff like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I like.
Speaker 1: I like meta information about anything.
Speaker 0: I like it's sort of like a DVD extra.
Speaker 0: Yeah, all right.
Speaker 0: My thing today is real short.
Speaker 0: It's a real short.
Speaker 0: It's a tiny tiny clip of video from Japanese TV.
Speaker 0: I don't know what show I don't know what but there's some cops Japanese cops and then There's Darth Vader and that's it and you'll see the joke when you watch it, but it's it's a pretty nice.
Speaker 0: it's a good quick joke of Japanese police and Darth Vader.
Speaker 1: I mean it's set up just like the beginning of episode 4 where you know There's the door and the people waiting and then Darth Vader bus in But then it's just Darth Vader and then something funny happens and that's it.
Speaker 0: It's a real quick and it should make you laugh which is why it's a good pick.
Speaker 1: we can't ruin it.
Speaker 1: It's just too funny.
Speaker 1: No, no, not gonna ruin it Alright, so today because we went long in the first bit talking about Kineticon and all that which I'm sure we're gonna talk about More in the future too because probably next year when there's another Kineticon.
Speaker 1: Yeah, not only that but I really want to talk to the staffers and the people at Kineticon to at least Give more detailed advice and I mean Kineticon is a good con and I really wanted to succeed and maybe we can get more Information out of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and in return, I'm sure we could get more people to go to Kineticon.
Speaker 0: Maybe we could convince them to go to a hotel.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I mean think of this if we brought the whole front row crew to Kineticon, that would be a significant chunk.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that would be a significant portion of the convention population.
Speaker 0: Wow Yeah, we'll have to think on that like the front row crew could probably like conquer the game room.
Speaker 1: All right, all right, so we instead of talking at length about Arcadia of my youth Which we're instead going to talk about next week.
Speaker 0: Yep We're gonna talk about a comic because we hardly ever talk about comics.
Speaker 1: Not only that but even though it's listed right there anime manga comics Wednesdays Yep, and two people have actually asked us to you know lean toward comics a little bit because we've been neglecting them.
Speaker 0: The main reason we neglect them is because I read enough of them and rim doesn't read enough of them.
Speaker 0: So if I talk about them, it's pretty much just me talking and rim going.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: Yeah Well, let's see what I've been reading lately.
Speaker 1: I mean Scott Pilgrim, which a lot of people call it a manga though It's not it's comic but I mean it's in trade form.
Speaker 1: So it doesn't.
Speaker 0: it's a digest.
Speaker 1: It's not A comic the way most people think of the word comic.
Speaker 0: Yeah, whatever.
Speaker 0: It's all.
Speaker 0: as far as I'm concerned.
Speaker 0: They are all works of graphic literature.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and I do the publishing format matters not as so much I think it's just that we don't read so many traditional comics and I don't read any.
Speaker 1: I mean the one I read just now Right before the show that we're gonna talk about is the first non Scott Pilgrim comic I've read since.
Speaker 1: I tried to read that captain Marvell thing Yeah, and I couldn't finish that I couldn't deal with it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I think now that they've canceled Marvel team up They're really like the.
Speaker 0: I'm not getting any superhero comics really like.
Speaker 0: there's almost none except for old ones.
Speaker 0: Well that one I'm trying to get all the old great ones that I've missed without, you know getting any of the Common crap, you know, I'm kind of interested in that fables kind of one about x-men.
Speaker 1: It's like the x-men.
Speaker 0: Oh x-men fairy tales.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, I'm actually really interested.
Speaker 0: but that's not really a superhero comic That's a fairy tale comic that just happens to.
Speaker 0: you know, they put a little bit of x-men hints in there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what it is fanboys by.
Speaker 1: it's like those awesome posters.
Speaker 1: We see an artist allies at cons.
Speaker 1: That's like a character from one anime, but they're dressed up as a character from another anime.
Speaker 0: Yeah, actually it's the guy who I'll talk about it.
Speaker 0: we could read it and then talk about it when it's done.
Speaker 0: Yep, there's only gonna be four issues long and I've already got two of them.
Speaker 1: So yeah, and the other thing I was reading that I really liked was x-makina But Scott Johnson borrowed all of it and now I can't read it until he gives it back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's still going on.
Speaker 0: So there'll be more volumes in the coming months.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but I really like it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's really good.
Speaker 0: All right, but today we decided to talk about the first trade of a hundred bullets now which is a Comic from vertigo.
Speaker 1: Scott and a couple other people had told me about this before and I just hadn't gotten around to it.
Speaker 1: So because we wanted to do a somewhat short episode Scott ripped it out of his room and I read it just now.
Speaker 0: And this I read it earlier today.
Speaker 1: Now.
Speaker 1: The thing is everyone who had told me about it.
Speaker 1: The concept sounds really awesome.
Speaker 1: I mean the concept is just all right.
Speaker 1: Say there's this magic government whatever where you can give someone a gun with a hundred bullets in it and Those bullets are marked in such a way that if anyone Investigates the shooting or anything that happens with this gun or this ammo as soon as they find these bullets The investigation is dropped all records of it are deleted.
Speaker 1: It's as though it never happened.
Speaker 0: Basically, if someone comes up to you and gives you the gun and says here's a gun.
Speaker 0: Here's a hundred bullets Do what you want your that you're above the law.
Speaker 0: You can just go around killing people and you won't get in trouble and nothing will happen to you and you won't go to prison.
Speaker 0: If cops come and harass you then they'll let you go real quick and yeah Yeah, a total carte blanche to kill whoever you want to kill without consequences of law.
Speaker 0: But who knows about other consequences of you know, but there won't be any legal governmental consequences.
Speaker 1: Now at its root this sounds like an awesome Concept for a comic or a novel or a movie or anything.
Speaker 0: I've noticed there are like a lot of the comics I'm picking up like a lot of the ones where I just pick up the Number one are like these awesome Concepts.
Speaker 0: like some guy comes up with this crazy idea that wouldn't work in a movie or a TV show or anything But in a comic you can do any crazy idea you want.
Speaker 1: What was that one?
Speaker 1: We saw at?
Speaker 1: Otacon.
Speaker 1: I think it was two years ago.
Speaker 1: It was a rhinoceros who was a hitman, but everyone else was just a human.
Speaker 1: But for some reason this guy was a rhinoceros.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that was pretty good.
Speaker 1: I forget who it was or what it was, but that kind of thing Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 0: So, you know when you come up if you come up with a really great premise for a story Comics are always the great place to go.
Speaker 0: I mean the American comic industry has really just become R&D for the movie industry.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know it's like they.
Speaker 0: they make some spider-man comics.
Speaker 0: They figured out what works and then they make a spider-man movie, you know.
Speaker 0: so this has a really great premise, but Still I don't know if I'm gonna buy any more than the first one.
Speaker 1: I was really really underwhelmed by this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I was moderately underwhelmed.
Speaker 0: Like I I think the problem was I had a really high expectation and it wasn't met.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well to me it was that one.
Speaker 1: you have the concept right, you know The hundred bullets above the law and that's why my expectation was high because the premise was quality.
Speaker 1: yet The actual premise is almost hardly even looked at least in the first story.
Speaker 1: The very first story is very long in this book and yet the vast majority of it Majority of it is completely unrelated to the 100 bullets.
Speaker 1: It's just these ghetto thugs yelling at each other.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it really feels like I'm watching some police show on you know Primetime TV like a CSI or any of those cops.
Speaker 0: Well not cops, but you know any of those shows Those police shows that are on TV that I don't watch because I don't have TV.
Speaker 1: I mean girl in prison gets out of prison Given the gun turns out that some cops were the ones who killed her Husband and child and then there's a slight twist ending which is kind of actually okay.
Speaker 1: But the bulk of it is just her hanging out with all her different homies and they're all talking to each other in and out.
Speaker 1: The the accents and the speaking are very much represented in the writing which made it very difficult to read for me.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it also made it hard for me to read.
Speaker 0: You know, I pretty much just like skipped over a whole lot of it cuz you know half it wasn't even important.
Speaker 0: It was just like set up and too much set up.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it wasn't even useful set up.
Speaker 1: I mean a lot of a lot of it.
Speaker 1: It was just people talking to each other about stupid crap I don't care about to the point that I just skipped it all and then like I'd flip flip flip flip All right, they stopped talking the guns back.
Speaker 1: What's going on?
Speaker 0: Yep Yeah, I think the first story is actually like three issues of comic book long.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was real long which just dragged it out and I lost.
Speaker 1: I kept.
Speaker 1: I lost interest to the point that I was Just kind of hoping in every scene that she would shoot him and get it over with.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they really could have fit it in.
Speaker 0: like, you know a fewer issues.
Speaker 0: I mean the first story.
Speaker 1: Well, the second one was a little better.
Speaker 1: It went more with the concept.
Speaker 1: Yep, like the except that again, it didn't really go anywhere and it was even aside from the implausibility of the gun thing.
Speaker 1: It was even less plausible.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it was like when they got to the computer stuff.
Speaker 0: I was like just why what's going on?
Speaker 0: That's yeah, it makes no sense.
Speaker 1: I mean it was like hackers computing.
Speaker 0: basically, the story is there's a guy and He's a bartender I think and he used to be an awesome restaurant guy but his career was ruined and his whole life was ruined when he was framed of being a child pornographer and Basically, you know the guy comes and gives him the gun and you know, he says here's the gun here's the bullets You know, you won't get in trouble.
Speaker 0: his evidence to prove that this is the person who did it, you know.
Speaker 0: And then that person, you know, just kind of miraculously shows up.
Speaker 1: Now the thing is the story was good except that it totally petered out at the end Like when you find out the reason she framed him.
Speaker 1: It was just such a letdown like it was the most anticlimactic thing.
Speaker 0: The first story had that kind of twist at the end Which is like the only good part of that story.
Speaker 0: the second story Just if it would have had a twist like the first one it would have been great.
Speaker 1: But it didn't have a twist so much as it had that unrelated thing with the people shooting at each other in the helicopter.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know what that was.
Speaker 1: that has to be set up for yet another story or something random or I mean it felt Like in Watchmen where they had like the parallel like two people would be talking But then they wouldn't show the two people.
Speaker 1: they'd show an Unrelated scene like something going on in the street.
Speaker 1: that was actually parallel to the conversation But this was just like random and completely unrelated and crazy.
Speaker 0: See, you know, I look at this comic and there's actually like three things going on, right?
Speaker 0: There's number one in any individual story arc There's the story of you know, whoever got the gun and what their situation is, right?
Speaker 0: And I care about that.
Speaker 0: But the problem is is that story isn't?
Speaker 0: you know, there's two of them in here and they're both not the greatest stories.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they're pretty mad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they're kind of average.
Speaker 1: now There's also the story of because they seem to be following the thread of why is this gun here?
Speaker 1: Why is this person giving it out?
Speaker 1: He has yet.
Speaker 0: the other two things are the story of the guy who's giving the gun out and Then the story of the gun itself and you know what's happening with it.
Speaker 1: now Don't get the impression that I'm saying that these stories are meh.
Speaker 0: I want to hear more about the guy with the gun because I really don't want to hear about the guy with the gun.
Speaker 1: I was hoping that the whatever the gun was would never be explained and like you wouldn't even care about it.
Speaker 1: I expected a whole bunch of unrelated stories with how people would deal with this responsibility and how people would deal with this gun and if they went into a plot about oh Well, the guy with the gun did it because he wants to do this and this and get these people.
Speaker 1: I just I don't care about that.
Speaker 0: Well, see I do.
Speaker 1: The guy if the story were that if the story was just that I'd be cool with it.
Speaker 1: Well, the
Speaker 0: thing is is I think it feels to me I don't know cuz I haven't read anymore that the story is going to eventually like later on You're like as you go on you'll find out more and more about the guy with the gun, but the guy with the gun I'd like him.
Speaker 0: I don't want to know about him.
Speaker 0: I want him to be like a faceless g-man, you know It's the gun itself.
Speaker 0: I'd like to always be you know, wondering what its story was like.
Speaker 0: Hey, how come?
Speaker 0: you know, you can do this and not get caught and you know who exactly way up is doing something You know, I'd like, you know, I don't want to actually find it out, but I want to want to find it out all the time.
Speaker 1: Yeah I mean I guess the story like this if this concept either has to be all the individual stories of people with the gun or The mystery of where the gun came from.
Speaker 0: I think it feel I don't know if it's going to.
Speaker 0: I Know I don't know but it feels like it's going to start out being stories of people with the gun and eventually Be you know, the other one like it's gonna do both except the second story.
Speaker 1: That's a lie.
Speaker 0: That's how my instinct tells me although I have no evidence.
Speaker 1: the second story almost right away goes into like the person who was the Recipient.
Speaker 1: the person who was the recipient of the gun loses and the person he was supposed to kill Then goes off on this thing Like she's gonna be some sort of recurring character like they.
Speaker 1: they set it up to where she kind of knows what's going on.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you see that's the kind of.
Speaker 0: that's how come.
Speaker 0: I have the feeling that the story will evolve, you know They'll keep showing you individual stories of people who get the gun and along the way you'll get more.
Speaker 0: you'll learn more and more And more about the gun itself and the guy who's giving it out.
Speaker 0: and that's you know.
Speaker 0: That's what comics do.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it just it was really kind of unimpressive and it feels like the concept is solid But it follows the wrong Characters for the wrong amounts of time and focuses on the things that I don't care about.
Speaker 1: Well not even going into the stuff.
Speaker 1: I want to see.
Speaker 0: Yep What I think I'd like to do is look up and see if the same guy right is writing this book like all of it.
Speaker 0: What would be really cool is if they just said hey anyone who wants to?
Speaker 0: or any you know get a whole bunch of different people to write stories about Someone who gets a gun with a hundred bullets that are untraceable and that way you'd see a whole bunch of different stuff.
Speaker 0: Because you know the stories that this guy's writing, you know aren't.
Speaker 0: they're not the greatest in the world to be honest Just the pacing's off.
Speaker 1: Everything's off.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if they got someone else to write, you know stories on the same premise that could be really cool.
Speaker 0: Like maybe they you know get ten guys together and say okay everyone, right, you know 36 page comic about.
Speaker 0: you know this premise.
Speaker 1: Well, this would be good.
Speaker 1: in is like remember when Yuko and Brian were in that compilation of.
Speaker 1: you know Here is a setting or here is a thing.
Speaker 1: everyone writes stories around it Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: Just have a compilation book.
Speaker 1: the book is hundred bullets and then everyone has their story in it.
Speaker 0: Yep I think this is another also a victim of you know, the publishing in the United States.
Speaker 0: This thing is actually coming out in comic book issues Every month and then this is like the first I don't know how many issues.
Speaker 1: If I'd picked up the first or first one or two issues, I never would have bought another one.
Speaker 1: I would have put it right back down because it just felt like it wasn't going anywhere.
Speaker 0: Yep You know, it's really.
Speaker 0: if this was it's like one trade, you know, just we're going to make a book.
Speaker 0: Here is the whole thing at once.
Speaker 0: there, you know, ten different stories about this gun.
Speaker 0: the end I mean, here's that something I would have bought.
Speaker 1: here's how it feels.
Speaker 1: Imagine you're going to see the matrix, right?
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm, and they reveal that he's in the matrix No spoiler spoiler whatever.
Speaker 1: and then you know He's.
Speaker 1: he's learning about this matrix thing and then for a half hour in the movie it shows him just like walking around in the matrix talking to people or Just like not none of the plot or anything just something completely unrelated that you don't care about.
Speaker 1: like show him masturbating in the bathroom.
Speaker 0: It's like they show you characters Like having you know, the moral dilemma like oh look this guy has a moral dilemma.
Speaker 0: He's got a gun and can kill people but at the same time You know, he won't get away with it But he's gonna feel bad and he is killing someone and all that jazz, but they don't actually explore it.
Speaker 0: They just put people in the situation.
Speaker 0: You see the person in the situation You see what they do, but you don't act.
Speaker 0: you know this.
Speaker 0: they're not really Exploring any of the morals or anything like that.
Speaker 0: They're just putting them on show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's a very superficial treatment of what could be a very interesting idea.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they could have gone a lot deeper like show the guy going like, oh, what do I do?
Speaker 0: blah-blah-blah, I Don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't think I'll read anymore.
Speaker 0: No, I don't think I'm gonna get any more either.
Speaker 0: But yeah, so we talked about comics.
Speaker 0: all you people who want us to talk about comics more Yep, if you really want us to talk about comics suggest something.
Speaker 0: Oh, there actually was that one single comic story at the end that was tacked on.
Speaker 1: Oh, I didn't even read that the one with the old lady Basically, yeah, I flipped through it and I realized that it wasn't related to what I was reading.
Speaker 1: So I stopped.
Speaker 0: Yeah, there was it.
Speaker 0: basically it's.
Speaker 0: it's a one comic story about this old lady who apparently had the gun a long time ago and She killed someone and she comes in to confess and they're like, there's nothing about that.
Speaker 0: So yeah, you just go on huh?
Speaker 0: And then at the end like some other guy is given the gun or something and it's you know It's.
Speaker 0: it's just like a little tiny twist story on its own.
Speaker 1: So you just again even there It sounds like the story's just focused on the things I don't care about and completely skip everything I actually want to read a story about yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh It's just.
Speaker 0: you know, someone comes up with a good premise and then they don't you know Execute it and use it in a in the correct way.
Speaker 1: Well, at least the correct way to get rim and Scott to read it exactly exactly.
Speaker 1: So if anyone has read this and disagrees, I don't know you could send us a geek back.
Speaker 0: Yeah, geek backs are cool You know, maybe we could talk about more comics later.
Speaker 0: Try to find something that doesn't.
Speaker 0: it's awesome You know, it seems like a lot of comics that are just based on a premise only Seem to like not always turn out to be the greatest things in the world.
Speaker 1: Well, like Teen Boat was a really funny idea, but I can't see myself reading much more of that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like, you know, I read you know, two Two issues a Teen Boat and it was funny.
Speaker 0: Haha Tina turns into a boat.
Speaker 0: Haha pirates.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's not funny anymore But it's an ongoing Series and you know, he's.
Speaker 0: I guess the guy is making more Teen Boat I guess and you figure out you know you go through.
Speaker 0: It's just the because comics in America keep you know, they shoot for ongoing stuff.
Speaker 0: Things end up that way, you know where even if it's you know, the premise is only good for a cut.
Speaker 0: You know a short bit.
Speaker 0: They just keep going with it and they write it in such a way that it can keep going somewhere.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It'd be much better if just each issue of this comic was one story a good story.
Speaker 0: That was interesting You didn't you know, you had the same premise of a guy gets a hundred bullets and a gun and you know You won't get in trouble, but you never explain why or how or who's giving it to him or anything like that.
Speaker 0: you just there it is is you don't need an explanation and Then each issue is just a story and then if somehow it gets cancelled you just stop making issues and it's like you.
Speaker 0: never you Know it doesn't matter All right.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway next week we'll probably review Arcadia of my youth Which we finally got around to watching hooray.
Speaker 0: Maybe we can watch a lot more that Harlock action in the future.
Speaker 1: We'll also have another geek back.
Speaker 1: it's old and we haven't gotten around to it a while but one of our listeners went to anime Expo and we have his thoughts on the Relative level of awesome that that con is.
Speaker 0: we're gonna have to go to that con eventually You know what?
Speaker 1: I have absolutely no desire to other than from a purely journalistic perspective.
Speaker 1: I have never heard anyone say good things about that con and at least anyone that I would trust.
Speaker 0: It's sort of just like, you know, the San Diego Comic Con of anime.
Speaker 0: it's just all the whole anime industry is there.
Speaker 0: there's crazy guests and There's crazy happenings and there's just a sea of people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's quote unquote 40,000 people.
Speaker 0: Yep, which we don't know.
Speaker 1: Yeah But it is most of the people who go seem to say that it's boring or there's not much to do or it's just like The industry telling you thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't.
Speaker 0: it doesn't seem to have the awesome fan stuff Like.
Speaker 0: you're not gonna go there and find an awesome game room.
Speaker 0: You're not gonna go there and find you know us running an awesome panel.
Speaker 0: you're not gonna go there and Find like a crazy awesome artists alley.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like e3, but at least e3 you can play video games.
Speaker 1: Yep, I guess you can watch anime and anime x-men, but we're already watching everything that's out in Japan right now.
Speaker 0: I know
Speaker 1: what could anime x go possibly offer unless that's
Speaker 0: what Otakon does So great is they offer the things that you're probably you know Haven't seen on bit torrent and you probably aren't haven't seen already or couldn't buy on DVD in the store easily
Speaker 1: Yeah, or the thing that you never would have thought to watch but was actually awesome the
Speaker 0: thing you wouldn't know to watch the thing You didn't know existed.
Speaker 0: That's what it's all about.
Speaker 1: And that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 1: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 1: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 0: It's actually recorded at night.