Speaker 0: It's Wednesday May 31st, and this is geek nights tonight.
Speaker 0: I bring you my somewhat rambling coverage of an amazements.
Speaker 0: Let's do this.
Speaker 0: So I spent most of today in the South South South Bronx doing various odd jobs.
Speaker 1: Now South were you?
Speaker 0: Very very south left claw north right closet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I did something that I haven't done in a long time.
Speaker 0: it's been many months, but while I was driving down I passed one of my favorite restaurants and I had a break.
Speaker 0: so I took the subway back up the way it came and For the first time in many many months.
Speaker 0: I had a White Castle.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I had like ten burgers and some onion rings.
Speaker 0: The best part was the onion rings cost more than two point six burgers.
Speaker 0: Yeah I don't know what you have against White Castle.
Speaker 0: It is perhaps the king of food.
Speaker 1: Maybe because it is in a castle it is a king.
Speaker 1: However, the food itself is of the lowest quality.
Speaker 1: well, not the absolute lowest quality because you mean you could just be eating dog poop or something, but of Restaurants legally established in the United States with no health violations White Castle is among the lowest possible Caliber.
Speaker 0: now the funny thing is I can't stand most fast food.
Speaker 1: I mean the thought of McDonald's makes me kind of ill and only fast food I can really eat Today is like Arby's type and I guess if you count stuff like Quiznos as fast food because it kind of is.
Speaker 0: Yeah All that plus White Castle.
Speaker 0: I Can just any white guess.
Speaker 0: I can pretty much eat White Castle burgers as fast as my body can process them.
Speaker 0: I can eat an infinite number of them.
Speaker 0: Yeah, as long as I have access to a facility of relieving them from my body.
Speaker 0: Maybe because I grew up on White Castle.
Speaker 0: I mean I lived in Detroit and and then I moved to New Baltimore and there was a White Castle right down the street from My house.
Speaker 1: So if you eat a White Castle does a white brick come out?
Speaker 1: No, no, no Cuz I figure that's how they made those places.
Speaker 0: Actually the one I ate at or the one at which I ate is a. mr Perry doesn't yell at me since he's back as you've noticed in the farm.
Speaker 1: He's been there the whole time.
Speaker 1: He just hasn't Noticed any severe enough violations.
Speaker 0: Yeah Well, he kind of went on like a sabbatical or something and he's back and then someone finally went over the line.
Speaker 0: You know who you are.
Speaker 1: Mr.
Speaker 1: Perry had failed to edit the subject line.
Speaker 1: I saw that particular post.
Speaker 0: I wonder if he knows that he can.
Speaker 0: Yeah, anyway I forgot what I was gonna say.
Speaker 0: good So we'll forget all about nasty-ass white cat which is fine because there's actually some big news in the Geekfront today.
Speaker 0: Mmm now reports indicate that the Pirates Bay the Bastion of freedom and awesome has been raided by the Swedish police and is shut down currently.
Speaker 1: well this morning I tried to go to the Pirates Bay because I was looking for some techno song from Norway, oh really?
Speaker 1: I think no.
Speaker 1: was it from Norway.
Speaker 1: I can't even remember.
Speaker 0: now this Norwegian music's really picking up I'm not sure.
Speaker 1: I was looking for something and I knew it was from Northern Europe and Pirate Bay is also is in Sweden.
Speaker 1: so I Was like, huh?
Speaker 1: What's up?
Speaker 1: Why isn't Pirates Bay working?
Speaker 1: I did a little trace route and I realized optimum online wasn't doing the blocking because I made it to the Swedish routers and then I just kind of gave up.
Speaker 1: and Then I got to work and I looked at the news on dig and it said Pirates Bay rated.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, what the fuck.
Speaker 1: and I said, oh shit It's yeah.
Speaker 0: now normally I don't care about anything like this, but this isn't over with the raid.
Speaker 0: I mean there have been countless little porn areas or where's areas or Generally seedy parts of the internet where people would do this sort of thing and they've come and gone over the years.
Speaker 0: But the Pirates Bay has been the highest quality most reliable and most resilient one ever.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean supernova was the big torrent tracker and no one else bothered to be a torrent tracker And supernova really wasn't that great.
Speaker 1: So I'm kind of glad that it got killed.
Speaker 1: But when they came to kill supernova supernova basically bent over and said, all right, and they open the asshole, but the Pirates Bay This gave the two double deuces and stayed on the sinking ship.
Speaker 1: I mean they not sunk yet either.
Speaker 0: the Pirates Bay has received countless legal threats for many years and Every one of them not only have they ignored but they've responded publicly and hilariously.
Speaker 1: Have their own political party the pirates in something.
Speaker 0: Now the thing is I mean a lot of people rely on Pirates Bay and someone noted on slashdot that the average Traffic in Sweden on the internet dropped precipitously as Pirates Bay went down.
Speaker 0: Holy crap.
Speaker 0: And the thing is the people who run Pirates Bay know what they're doing.
Speaker 0: They are well aware of the laws that protect them and I don't think the people rating them will actually have anything on them.
Speaker 1: No because they're pretty much gonna look through all the Pirate Bay computers to see if they violate Swedish laws and they won't.
Speaker 1: because what is On the Pirate Bay computers.
Speaker 1: Well, it's a web server probably Apache and an index of torrent files which aren't copyrighted and They don't actually have the torrent files.
Speaker 1: They just have links to torrent files on other sites.
Speaker 0: Now it looks somewhat like a fishing expedition because I assume the Pirates Bay people because they're very smart Don't have anything infringing on their actual servers, of course not.
Speaker 0: now they also raided the homes of several of the pirate and people.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't doubt that some of them will have at least one or two pirated songs as people tend to have as people who run the Pirates Bay tend to have.
Speaker 0: yeah, but I mean that would be like say if Alcohol was illegal you can bet that in the vast majority of homes in the u.s.
Speaker 0: There would be some amount of alcohol Mm-hmm, same deal.
Speaker 0: So one mp3 they get him and I don't know what's going to come of that.
Speaker 0: Swedish law regarding that is much more open when it comes to personal private non-commercial use.
Speaker 1: see if I was one of those pirate guys I would be double slick.
Speaker 1: I would have stored all my MP threes and all that stuff on Either portable hard drives and such that were hidden away where no one would find them.
Speaker 1: You know when?
Speaker 1: when anyone, you know police came to my house and just hide him in a secret cubby or I?
Speaker 1: Would put all of them on a server far away or in someone else's house and network to it.
Speaker 0: Um, I have a much simpler solution.
Speaker 0: Yeah, when the police officers ask me where I got all these mp3s I say I bought.
Speaker 0: use CDs with cash.
Speaker 0: I then rip them and threw the CDs away because I no longer needed them.
Speaker 0: It's a good one and I and no matter what mp3 they ask about that is my answer because it is completely unverifiable.
Speaker 0: Mmm, it cannot be proven either true or false.
Speaker 1: That's a problem nowadays Isn't a lot of the stupid u.s.
Speaker 1: Courts the people are doing guilty until proven innocent instead of the way it's supposed to be.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know it sucks.
Speaker 0: a thousand guilty men go free before one innocent man.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, what happened to that?
Speaker 1: It seems that a lot of judges and companies Basically care more about money and being stupid and being right, huh and about being You know, I don't know about stupid and right.
Speaker 0: I think money is just really the only factor there.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm thinking justice.
Speaker 1: Maybe you know you're by default Innocent that someone has to prove that you did something.
Speaker 1: if it's impossible to prove beyond a reasonable doubt that you did it You didn't do it.
Speaker 1: Even if you did it.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep now that That's exactly right Woe betide if I go rim and there's no evidence He can't put me in jail.
Speaker 0: woe betide the judge that ever has mere Scott on his jury.
Speaker 0: woe betide or defendant or Complain plaintiff, you know what pretty much anyone involved in that trial is not going to have a good week.
Speaker 1: No, no, they're not.
Speaker 0: But the one thing I really want to note here is that the Pirates Bay people are going to fight to the bitter end.
Speaker 0: They have hinted that if they have to they will take everything and leave the country.
Speaker 0: the Pirates Bay will return.
Speaker 1: It's like the ghost ship.
Speaker 0: Now the other thing about the Pirates Bay is that most of these sites prior to them were very porny and seedy.
Speaker 0: Yep, I mean where sites were generally bastions of wares, but they're also full of terrible porn and just scuzzy people.
Speaker 1: The other thing is a lot of.
Speaker 1: so sites are poorly designed or they're designed like wares sites.
Speaker 1: You know this design of a wares site all cluttered and the interface is shitty and it's hard to figure out what to click on.
Speaker 0: They have that animated gif of a fire.
Speaker 1: Yeah You know, I hate those kind of sites.
Speaker 1: But then there's good sites like mini Nova or Pirates Bay which are designed nicely and they're useful and they work.
Speaker 0: I mean the Pirates Bay was slick user-friendly.
Speaker 0: It was very.
Speaker 0: it was run very professionally.
Speaker 0: everyone involved in it was generally cool.
Speaker 0: and They're not just doing it for reasons of being pirates they're doing it for ideological reasons as well and I really look upon them as the early stages of freedom fighters against the Various takeovers of the internet by I don't want to say capitalist but greedy corporate bucks, I guess.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm Yep.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: So of course we will be covering this developing story as it well develops.
Speaker 0: Ah Now Scott, don't you have some news?
Speaker 1: Oh, I do so.
Speaker 1: CPM Central Park Media, if you don't know the being anime day at all.
Speaker 1: Hey, they're an anime company.
Speaker 1: They put out lots of anime in America that you've probably bought like Gonna.
Speaker 0: watch some of that.
Speaker 0: ootna.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you know, they're not the best.
Speaker 1: They haven't really been able to compete with the likes of these I guess don't?
Speaker 1: the funimation Geni on etcetera.
Speaker 1: there, you know the second tier Anime producing company.
Speaker 1: they were big back in the day, you know, but they haven't been able to get the new licenses.
Speaker 1: So they haven't been doing so.
Speaker 1: well, they're amazingly milking their old licenses.
Speaker 1: They're also not that good at making DVDs To be honest, but they do license some important anime now.
Speaker 1: recently They laid off a bunch of people and everyone said oh no This means that they laid off everyone they don't need and the only people still working for them are some business people.
Speaker 1: and those business people are gonna take care of the bankruptcy and then it'll all be over.
Speaker 1: and I was like, oh, oh, well I guess someone to see which anime companies pick up which of their licenses and which shows Disappear into the void and maybe we can get a whole bunch of cheap CPM DVDs.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'd really like to get some more ootna Martin Yeah, so as much as I love that show all I have for like fifth generation unwatchable fansubs Yeah, and and ootna is a joke.
Speaker 1: The the actual pronunciation is ootana.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I Don't care that.
Speaker 0: sometimes they say ootana in the show.
Speaker 0: You don't call the show ootna.
Speaker 0: In fact, I saw an interview with Ikuhara, you know the crazy man who is partly responsible for ootana And he said shoujo kakumei ootana You can hear them say it in the show.
Speaker 0: Sorry, this is just a pet peeve of ours because we've had we've ran into people who in a non-ironic way would say ootna Yep, and they'd say just like that gonna watch me some ootna you ever watch ootna?
Speaker 0: God ho down.
Speaker 1: Okay, so the latest news is that CPM they're not bankrupt yet.
Speaker 1: They didn't file for bankruptcy yet, and we don't know if they're going to.
Speaker 1: but the real thing that did them in was Media play going out because that was their biggest customer.
Speaker 1: So yeah, their biggest customer died and now they're in big trouble just like a lot of other anime Related companies were in big trouble when media play died.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean media plays Failure was.
Speaker 0: it really sent shockwaves through the anime industry because they were a major major distributor of anime and anime related merchandise.
Speaker 1: the major distributor of anime merchandise I mean compared to there was no company that bought more anime DVDs than Media play I mean consider that by media play went under because the stores were terribly terribly non profitable.
Speaker 0: But there were a few that were profitable and they were doing well But they still had to be shut down because the whole franchise was being collapsed.
Speaker 1: Yep and the reason that the whole thing died was because They sold CDs and that was a large part of their business that they depended on.
Speaker 1: and CD sales *DING* Yep, so as a result all the other profitable parts of the store *DING*.
Speaker 0: Now the what the few media plays that I know of at least that were being successful despite all this Made almost all their money from anime.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: I mean the one in Rochester.
Speaker 0: I think anime was really the only thing they sold.
Speaker 1: It was basically an anime store within the media play.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's like a whole corner of the store.
Speaker 1: It was huge.
Speaker 0: I mean hell.
Speaker 0: we used to run events there.
Speaker 1: Yep alright, so Apparently CPM, you know didn't fuck is saying we didn't fire anyone cuz they suck a lot of all.
Speaker 1: these people are awesome.
Speaker 1: We just had to lay them off cuz we suck.
Speaker 1: if you want to hire anyone who you just got laid off from CPM Then email HR 519 at team CPM calm.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 1: So if you need some anime employees, you know, maybe some.
Speaker 0: I guess we should hire someone for geek nights.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't know if anyone works at CPM has the skills we need maybe DVD producers or something, I don't know.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wouldn't mind an editor.
Speaker 0: So I wouldn't have to do post-production anymore.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but you're paying them if you get.
Speaker 0: oh We're not paying anyone.
Speaker 0: Oh Okay Our first employee we don't pay him anything.
Speaker 0: He just does it because he loves making people suffer.
Speaker 0: I don't think we'll ever pay any employees anything.
Speaker 0: Awesome Okay, what do you think?
Speaker 0: in pain people for labor that's that's almost capitalism.
Speaker 1: Okay, so it's anime day and I do a lot of things of the day about Mario.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you had your all fruity cocky thing the other day.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that one wasn't so great, but it was something and I guess You know a lot of the Mario things I do were commercials Video game things or someone acting out a live-action Mario.
Speaker 1: There's been like two or three of those.
Speaker 1: They do a lot of Mario things today.
Speaker 1: It's crazy.
Speaker 1: So I got another one Just to add to the the glut of Mario things of the day.
Speaker 1: This one though is kind of crazy.
Speaker 1: I didn't even know it existed.
Speaker 1: It's an entire Mario anime.
Speaker 0: Goddamn, is this like a movie or an OAV or what?
Speaker 0: I can't tell.
Speaker 0: when was this made?
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: Why didn't we know about it until just now?
Speaker 1: I don't know but it's old.
Speaker 1: It's got to be 70s 80s time.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, wait, it can't be 70s.
Speaker 1: Mario didn't exist in the 70s.
Speaker 0: No, he didn't.
Speaker 1: it's got to be mid to late 80s early 90s at the latest and it looks like a movie.
Speaker 1: so Given that the production quality looks about equal to the Mario Super Show, which is TV in the early 90s I'm thinking this is an 80s movie.
Speaker 0: I think you forget how absolutely piss-poor the Super Mario Brothers Super Show was.
Speaker 1: I don't think you understand how piss-poor this anime looks.
Speaker 0: Well, the only problem I see with it is Luigi, but you mean blue and yellow Luigi, yeah What's up with that?
Speaker 1: You need to mix the blue and the yellow ink together to get the green people.
Speaker 0: how it works Luigi kind of reminds me of Lupin a little bit.
Speaker 0: just the way the voice actor is and the way Luigi seems to act I Guess kind of barely like a little bit like I thought of Lupin.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I Didn't notice it until you said something and then it was like, okay, maybe the the tiniest tiniest bit anyway.
Speaker 1: This is pretty humorous even without subtitles, but you're not gonna be able to see the whole thing on YouTube.
Speaker 1: They're only three parts the pre credits the credits in the beginning part and then a little bit more the beginning part.
Speaker 1: And then it is that's it.
Speaker 1: They don't have the rest of the movie on YouTube yet But obviously someone has this movie somewhere and someone should fansub it because right now watching it without subtitles I can only get so much of the plot, but there's some crazy stuff in there.
Speaker 1: There's Luigi raiding casinos and coins and eat everyone eating magic mushrooms, and they're working in some sort of grocery store.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and there's a giant paratrooper that brings into a paratrooper nest and there's more magic mushrooms.
Speaker 1: And we're not just talking about the mushrooms that make you big.
Speaker 1: We're talking about all kinds of magic mushrooms here.
Speaker 1: I Think it looks to me like they're trying to figure out which mushrooms are poison and which ones aren't and Luigi's being stupid and eating All the mushrooms.
Speaker 1: and yeah What I like about it though is it definitely only includes Super Mario Brothers.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have regular Mario Brothers.
Speaker 1: There's no pal blocks.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have doki-doki panic.
Speaker 1: It doesn't have Mario 3 or world.
Speaker 1: It's just Super Mario Brothers mushrooms and fire flowers and stars.
Speaker 0: We really need to figure out more about this.
Speaker 1: I Think this needs some research, but you know what?
Speaker 1: I'm willing to bet someone's gonna post all the answers in our forum.
Speaker 0: So if you want to know the answers, yep, and if not, I imagine someone will make a wiki a Wikia which may or may not be deleted.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep, like the juggernaut bitch one was recently.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think for the second time.
Speaker 1: I think the haha wiki and the really wiki is still there.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well the thing is it.
Speaker 0: I think certain.
Speaker 0: I mean they won't let any meme get on Wikipedia.
Speaker 0: But some memes are just so widespread and so well known that they warrant intellectual discussion.
Speaker 0: Hmm, at least that seems to be the general opinion of the editors of Wikipedia.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there was some other meme I was looking for in Wikipedia that just wasn't there which one I forget.
Speaker 0: Oh great Yeah, are you sure it was a thing?
Speaker 0: Are you sure it wasn't nothing?
Speaker 1: I'm sure.
Speaker 0: oh Really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, really?
Speaker 0: All right, so my thing of the day is Related to the main topic of today's show which is my trip to an amazement.
Speaker 0: now I'll talk about this when I was it an amazing.
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I actually forgot that I was gonna say that in every episode until you said it you have inadvertently done my bidding.
Speaker 0: Wait, actually wait till I talk about the musical which I'm going to talk about later because there is a joke there, too.
Speaker 0: But anyway, an amazement.
Speaker 0: I almost said an amazing has this thing they do every year like, you know every con is their little thing like the thing that makes them stand out or their cool thing or the thing they Do really well or the thing people say?
Speaker 0: Oh Like Otakon they always have the musical guest or katsu khan as the awesome cosplay.
Speaker 0: or anime central has the iron guest competition An amazements thing is there's a bunch of people who put on an anime musical every year.
Speaker 0: Apparently this is started recently and it's pretty badass.
Speaker 0: But the thing they did this year was and I'm still this is my thing of the day they did a musical on how to run an anime convention and The what is involved in anime conventions as a whole.
Speaker 0: the title I believe was it seemed like a good idea at the time.
Speaker 0: Now they did in one point.
Speaker 0: They're making fun of the music video You know and V bits and they have an AMV contest and the two judges are sitting there.
Speaker 0: They actually went through the trouble of making The anime music videos that they then showed in the musical to make fun of anime music videos High production values and everything they got.
Speaker 0: whoever did it knows what they're doing.
Speaker 0: and they made high quality good music videos to weird German music and Terrible anime but very well done.
Speaker 0: I Mean what I expected was.
Speaker 0: All right, they're probably gonna have a black 10 Dragon Ball Z Linkin Park videos or Okay, they're gonna do like a million Ava videos or you know something Naruto making fun of AMVs and why they're bad nowadays.
Speaker 0: They did that but they did it with this weird German polka music and at the end like the last four videos all are to the exact same song like this And it's just hilarious.
Speaker 1: It's actually somewhat reminiscent of what actually happens at anime music video competitions.
Speaker 1: I remember thing was Otakon two years ago The AMV competition.
Speaker 1: all the videos were really fancy with all sorts of special effects and high production But like someone spent a long time making those things with fancy software.
Speaker 0: They may have paid for or pirated Yeah, but the videos themselves just weren't good Yep, but these were bad on purpose at least like they went out of their way to make them terrible And it was fantastic that the best one is.
Speaker 0: the very first one they show is to char as in you know Char's counter-attack char from Gundam guy in the mask old school, but it's to that same German polka thing and it's just hilarious.
Speaker 0: The thing I'm linking to is the forum post in the an amazement forums where they're going to eventually post the actual music videos That they showed currently is just a discussion of them.
Speaker 0: I Internet's yet and I wasn't about to go bother the people responsible.
Speaker 1: How come some things take negative time to get on the internet like you go?
Speaker 1: and did someone already put it up before you even?
Speaker 1: Thought to look for it.
Speaker 1: Sometimes people take forever.
Speaker 1: It's like a year later It comes up out of the woodwork and you're like, what the hell this isn't.
Speaker 1: I don't even care anymore.
Speaker 0: Well, I think the reason here is that they also filmed the musical itself and they're trying to put together a thing to have it Available.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but here's the thing.
Speaker 1: is making something like that available Isn't really difficult?
Speaker 1: if they put someone like me in charge of it I would have had it available before the con was over.
Speaker 0: Well, no Does it take people so long to do this or one video is a lot harder to edit and deal with an audio.
Speaker 0: Too many.
Speaker 0: They also have to deal with audio which was spotty at best.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but the thing is if it's if you're making an anime music video then yes video takes a long time to edit and all.
Speaker 1: But if you're video taping an event and you only have one camera now if you have three cameras then is editing because you had To choose which cameras for which scene.
Speaker 0: well There's editing anyway because there were you know some delays between scene changes and bits when the crowd was unruly.
Speaker 0: that you know I got to edit out And they got a splice in.
Speaker 0: because you know, they were filming it and there were actors on stage doing their thing.
Speaker 0: But then when they did the AMVs they showed them on a screen.
Speaker 0: Oh, well, they had the AMVs And they're going to put them up shortly, yeah Still I mean, I got a note that I'm still recovering from this frickin con.
Speaker 0: I'm sure the other staffers are.
Speaker 0: hey if you were there I got almost no sleep.
Speaker 0: even so Even so, yeah, plus I commute now and unlike you I actually do work at work.
Speaker 1: I do kind of work at work today.
Speaker 1: It took me less than a minute to do the work that someone told me to do today.
Speaker 0: I actually drove around the Bronx plugging things into other things and then writing things down about them.
Speaker 1: That's not very difficult.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but it's time-consuming and I can't just like take a nap Like I used to be able to do at IBM.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I don't take naps at work.
Speaker 0: I just kind of yeah, I kind of miss.
Speaker 0: I mean for the last three weeks at IBM I would show up late every day and I left early every day and I took a long lunch Yeah, and I still got all the work done that I would have gotten done anyway.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it made me realize that I probably could have worked about four hours a day and still done everything They ever wanted me to do.
Speaker 1: man.
Speaker 1: I could work an hour a week and do everything.
Speaker 1: I'm doing now.
Speaker 1: I wish they would give me a new project.
Speaker 1: if they don't give me I'm gonna look start looking for a new job.
Speaker 1: For real that's talking.
Speaker 1: I'm not gonna be a shit talker anymore.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: Yeah, really.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: We will see All right.
Speaker 0: So today is anime day.
Speaker 0: Well, it's also manga comics day because we're gonna be covering covering other conventions next weekend and such.
Speaker 0: but today I am covering Animas men, which I alone went to this year, though I think next year I'm going to drag a whole bunch of my crew along because an amazement was freaking awesome.
Speaker 0: Mmm, it I mean I when I go to a con cuz I've been to a lot of cons I have a level of expectations based on what I've heard what I see on their website and everything and I don't want to sound mean but I had middling to low expectations of an amazement.
Speaker 1: I Also had a similar expectation.
Speaker 0: like it seemed like this kind of small southern convention Like I never even been to the Carolinas.
Speaker 1: I expected it to be somewhat similar in size and structure to say Ohio con.
Speaker 1: when we went only I assumed it would be a slightly larger and slightly better run.
Speaker 0: now Many cut like katsu khan basically meets or slightly beats expectations.
Speaker 0: I mean, I like katsu khan, but it's not.
Speaker 0: it's pretty much what I expect.
Speaker 0: Compared to what I expected an amazement blew me away first off and second Regardless of my expectations an amazement was awesome enough to where I am more than willing to go back there every year Despite the massive expense of flying all the way out there.
Speaker 0: I'm not that far out there Yeah, but all told it cost me a lot more money to go to an amazement than it's cost me to go to any other Con ever really?
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean Otakon cost us very little considering, you know, how we take care of the hotel rooms.
Speaker 0: Katsu khan is super super expensive But that's just because the hotel costs a lot and there are only like three of us in it.
Speaker 1: We should go to PAX on the cross-country super trip.
Speaker 0: god, that would kill us.
Speaker 1: We should do it.
Speaker 0: Anyway, yeah, not this year.
Speaker 1: I got it.
Speaker 1: I'll quit my job right after and then I'll be able to do it.
Speaker 0: Well you if you do that and you bring I'll give you my little recording bit and you get coverage of the cross-country thing.
Speaker 1: God.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if I do it though, I'm gonna have to bring some strange gamers in my car.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, you could deal with that.
Speaker 0: Yeah If they'll fit if I won't kill them along the way, yeah, but anyway an amazement is in Raleigh, North Carolina.
Speaker 0: Well, it's actually in I believe Durham, North Carolina, which is right next to Raleigh.
Speaker 1: Raleigh Durham is the same.
Speaker 1: It's it's one place.
Speaker 0: It's like how anime central is in Chicago, but it's actually in Rosemont, but they're the same same deal same deal and It was Memorial Day weekend.
Speaker 0: I was I was there for five days.
Speaker 0: I mean I left Thursday and I came back Monday.
Speaker 0: so it was basically a week-long vacation for me and The convention was awesome.
Speaker 0: Awesome.
Speaker 0: I went because a good friend of ours Nury who you she's been on the show at least once and I we're gonna talk to her again sometime soon, hopefully She invited me to an amazement.
Speaker 0: to you know, do a panel like I always do I do the same panel at every frickin con And I said yes, and I kind of forgot about it.
Speaker 0: And then she reminded me and another the other guy was going reminded me and like oh, oh, yeah that thing.
Speaker 0: So I went and bought my plane tickets and I took care of all my stuff and I took the plane out there.
Speaker 0: I'm not going to now from this point forward.
Speaker 0: I will do my typical Convention coverage style which is semi chronological.
Speaker 0: It seemed to work pretty well for Katsu khan.
Speaker 0: I Will ignore all of my travel because traveling will be covered tomorrow.
Speaker 1: when I rail about the airline industry and how much I hate it I can talk about how many things in the airline industry are stupid But I am awesome when it comes to airplanes and you all suck.
Speaker 0: No problem.
Speaker 0: I've ever had with an airline has had anything to do with me And actually I've avoided many problems that airlines would have caused me by being me.
Speaker 0: Yeah the one time I had a major problem with airlines was mostly because I had to fly somewhere over a holiday when normally I Refuse to travel on holidays and I'll visit my family at other times when they're on a billion mouth breathers in the airport.
Speaker 1: I've traveled during busy holiday season on two occasions with no problem.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because you fly places for jet blue goes I fly places where there's not stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you see I really can't fly to Detroit any other way.
Speaker 0: There's no jet blue.
Speaker 0: They don't go to Detroit But that's where my family is.
Speaker 1: Tell your family to move.
Speaker 0: Yeah Anyway, so I arrived Thursday night and this is the one thing I mean, I'll say this a bunch of times but an amazement is a small con that has all the niceties of a large con.
Speaker 0: It is the best that a small con can be as far as I'm concerned and Along that lot those lines.
Speaker 0: They have Thursday night registration, which many cons do not have or added recently and I didn't bother with that because I was a well I was a panelist and I became staff very shortly as a result at after some things that I'll talk about later.
Speaker 0: But I got there Thursday and it was really kind of today.
Speaker 0: There were a few cosplayers wandering the halls.
Speaker 0: I sat in the artist's alley and watched people sign up for tables and set up and check in and do all their stuff.
Speaker 0: Very uneventful.
Speaker 0: However, unlike most cons who have a Thursday check-in Anamazement had stuff going on on Thursday.
Speaker 0: They had.
Speaker 0: they had some karaoke going on in one room And I think they were showing something in another room like not a lot.
Speaker 0: Definitely not a con but there was stuff to do if you were there Thursday night.
Speaker 1: Whoa the most I can see going on a Thursday night at a con would be swimming in the hotel pool and DS battles.
Speaker 1: Yep, the fact that they actually had a con Sponsored event Thursday is crazy.
Speaker 0: Well, remember the way because it's a small con It's still in a hotel hotel.
Speaker 0: cons can go 24/7 and there's no rules really.
Speaker 0: So if they have the place of reserve Thursday night, they can just use it.
Speaker 0: Otakon they have to kick you out at 2 a.m.
Speaker 1: No matter what Yep, but it's all good.
Speaker 0: Yeah Though I do remember our mini Otakon in the hotel pool last year Thursday night.
Speaker 0: Yeah, don't get me started on that.
Speaker 1: We'll talk about that some other time.
Speaker 0: I believe we already talked about it.
Speaker 1: Did we?
Speaker 0: Yeah, okay, but I have some banana phone stories from this.
Speaker 0: con a great now.
Speaker 0: Friday the business started.
Speaker 0: I got there pretty ass early because Nuri who was the person who was basically taking care of me this weekend since she invited me out her and Evan They she had to be there to do the artist alley stuff because she was staff and I needed a ride to the con.
Speaker 0: So I went with her at the crack of early morning.
Speaker 0: Well crack of early morning, you know, like eight o'clock Yeah, the butt crack of dawn Yeah.
Speaker 0: But we get there and I help out and set stuff up and I have my little badge and then they give me a little Security badge and they're like, hey, could you go take help us with this line over here?
Speaker 0: Because I kind of volunteered to do that sort of thing.
Speaker 0: So I walked over to all these people milling her out and I put them in line to get into the dealers room.
Speaker 0: They're trying to get into the dealers room.
Speaker 0: It wasn't open yet And I just did my thing.
Speaker 0: the thing I've been doing at the RIT anime club for how many years.
Speaker 0: the thing that I did At Katsucon, you know crowd control stuff.
Speaker 0: that while it sounds silly Scott and I really know how to do that stuff Like we're good at it.
Speaker 1: Hey you fools get your asses in line.
Speaker 1: but
Speaker 0: even the little things like how to set up a line like how to make the gap so the fire marshal doesn't get mad or How to keep people from cutting or how to get people to actually listen to you as opposed to just ignore you Yeah,
Speaker 1: that's one thing.
Speaker 1: Is that this typical grumpy security guy?
Speaker 1: He doesn't work So well.
Speaker 1: when I mean in terms of if you're a typical grumpy paid security guy you do one thing really well You prevent people from being violent and stealing and all those sorts of sir.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna need you to move along Exactly.
Speaker 1: That's pretty much all you can do or or my can't do.
Speaker 0: my favorite con security person ever.
Speaker 0: Remember the TMR concert at Otacon way back all of your cell phones and pagers.
Speaker 1: That was a con security.
Speaker 1: That was That was an Otacon staff person who was not pleasant Yes, but she was part.
Speaker 0: well Otacon is a weird staff structure.
Speaker 0: But at this con security and staff were kind of synonymous Like staffers had jobs, but then there were staffers who were security
Speaker 1: mm-hmm,
Speaker 0: and I was given a little security thing and I took care of this line and Then the staffers started coming over and they were basically like wow, you're admiring
Speaker 1: your line
Speaker 0: like wow That was a really good line.
Speaker 0: And over the next few hours.
Speaker 0: I was basically promoted to full-on staff and I became like the security dude You they gave you.
Speaker 1: oh you did such a good job on that line here.
Speaker 0: take care of all our line.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know what?
Speaker 0: It was freakin great because I hate it.
Speaker 1: I yeah, you know what all the anime some people were thinking.
Speaker 1: Haha.
Speaker 1: We got that chump to take care of all the lines.
Speaker 0: It's more that I really like being staff at things like this.
Speaker 0: I mean It's gotten to the point with conventions where if I'm not going to the con for something other than just going as a fan I'm really usually not gonna enjoy myself.
Speaker 0: I'm not I'm not that kind of fan anymore And I really get most of my enjoyment out of I guess giving back or like being the person who provides all this stuff to People as opposed to being the one who consumes it.
Speaker 0: I'm slowly becoming a provider of services as opposed to a consumer of them.
Speaker 1: Yeah, a lot of the services that cons have already been provided so they're no longer entertaining.
Speaker 1: But you know a lot of cons.
Speaker 1: this is all you know, I always do something new that I haven't done at cons before.
Speaker 1: Eventually, it'll run out but not yet.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's run out for me.
Speaker 0: But I've been to a lot more cons than Scott has mainly because I was living alone and bored for a long time.
Speaker 0: so I went to every frickin con I get my hands on uh-huh and Plus also, I mean I ran that RIT anime club for so long and I really liked it.
Speaker 0: And I guess I'm kind of an attention whore.
Speaker 0: You know a little.
Speaker 0: I like to be in charge a bit a bit.
Speaker 0: I like to be a lot.
Speaker 0: Well, it's mostly that I'd like to let
Speaker 1: you buck down
Speaker 0: charge of things because I know that usually I can run them Well, and it bothers me when I see something run poorly when I know that it could have been done Well,
Speaker 1: oh that bothers me like also the most.
Speaker 1: Yeah When you see someone doing a job that you could do that job and it's like when you watch someone play Mario 1 and run Into the first goomba, that's what it's like.
Speaker 1: You're like, oh my god.
Speaker 1: when you see someone playing Mario and maybe they're doing just fine But they're not holding B to make Mario run fast.
Speaker 1: It's like ah You're so uh, yeah someone puts a piece in the wrong place in Tetris.
Speaker 1: It's the same feeling.
Speaker 1: Oh, why don't?
Speaker 1: why aren't you getting these people to line up properly?
Speaker 1: Why don't you know how to do it?
Speaker 1: What's wrong with you?
Speaker 0: Ah, yep And as a result because it bothers me so much Scott is more immune to this because he seems to have avoided most responsibility in most of his life.
Speaker 0: But I love it, I mean I like being that guy.
Speaker 0: I like being the guy who takes care of things.
Speaker 0: I like being in charge.
Speaker 0: I like and it's worked out pretty well for me and I've slowly, you know Like every kind I go to now I'm a panelist or I'm a staffer or I'm some sort of press guy or I'm something.
Speaker 1: the Trick is to do all those things without making any promises.
Speaker 1: that way you can't be the target of blame True, but the thing is being security.
Speaker 0: you really have to accept the fact that you will be blamed if something horrible happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah but it worked out really well because they the crowd was big like it was bigger than they expected.
Speaker 0: a lot of extra people showed up this year and There were some lines that really needed someone to take care of them or else bad things could have happened.
Speaker 0: Now Saturday is the day when I can talk about the big line where I gained a bunch of fans and I even signed an autograph.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right I became very popular about.
Speaker 1: our signatures are terrible.
Speaker 0: I know my signature is a scribble with another scribble.
Speaker 1: Mine is also two scribbles with some big scribbles towards the left edges of each scribble.
Speaker 1: Yeah
Speaker 0: But I you know, I was so I started doing the security thing and basically for the entire con I mean I enjoyed myself and I did a couple events But mostly I walked around and made sure that everything was running smoothly and that no one you know was doing anything stupid.
Speaker 0: Now fun stupid as fun.
Speaker 1: It's an anime convention.
Speaker 1: This is someone doing something stupid every which way.
Speaker 0: actually People always say, you know southern hospitality and southern, you know politeness and all that and Just the how people are down there.
Speaker 0: and I got to say The people I had to deal with at this convention and term from the security standpoint were the most polite Well-mannered kids I have ever run afoul of.
Speaker 0: when I asked people to stand in line They would be like, oh, alright great and they'd stand in line be like is this good enough?
Speaker 1: Are you sure they weren't being like?
Speaker 1: is this good enough for you?
Speaker 0: Now they really were.
Speaker 0: they like everyone like I didn't have to yell at anyone ever for the entire convention.
Speaker 0: now Contrast that with katsu-kan where I did security where half the con was sir Please you can't stand in front of the fire exit move.
Speaker 0: No move.
Speaker 0: No.
Speaker 0: Yes you I'm and I don't ever want to do security at katsu-kan again.
Speaker 0: Luckily.
Speaker 0: We're guests at katsu-kan next year.
Speaker 0: Most likely Or at least panelists again, there's no way I would ever do security there again.
Speaker 0: But I will be staff forever.
Speaker 0: at an amazement if they'll have me back because it was fun and I really got along with the staff.
Speaker 0: I'll talk about that all at the end when I talk about the after party.
Speaker 0: Now as for the con itself an amazements main thing that it seems to have going for it is that they have awesome guests as In they have a whole bunch of cool Japanese guests and whatever American voice actor and such guests they can get.
Speaker 0: But the really cool thing is that the Japanese guests many of them come every year because they like this con And all of the Japanese guests that come really like, you know You see it Otakon or katsu-kan.
Speaker 0: when you have the guests they always have like their entourage around them or they're always kind of shielded from the con goers except for an autograph session and They stay like in a different hotel and they're protected.
Speaker 1: Well, that's because Mostly Otakon specifically if you let a Japanese guest out into the open that they're just so many people Like at a small con, you know, they might be safe because at worst five fanboys come up and bother them.
Speaker 1: Yes, that's just how many people will care enough to go up and make some mischief.
Speaker 1: but but it Otakon the sheer numbers of people that will just you know mob and start being a Stupid fanboys is insane and that's why they have to do it that way.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I guess they don't like doing it that I guess the difference here is that this is a con that has the kind of guests that a big con would get.
Speaker 0: I mean Akira Kamiya was there and that man is my freaking hero.
Speaker 1: All right, what does he do?
Speaker 0: Oh, he was the voice of people in old anime that I like.
Speaker 0: that you either haven't heard of or don't care about Awesome.
Speaker 0: Although he was Roy Fokker.
Speaker 1: Oh Wait, the Roy Fokker guy.
Speaker 0: He was the toga guy.
Speaker 0: He was I'm trying to think all the weird ones that people are not know.
Speaker 1: that's the guy who is toga and because it's all the Same guy, isn't it?
Speaker 0: I'm trying to think of all the weird ones.
Speaker 0: He was professor Tomoe in Sailor Moon which was an I'm a big fan of professor Tomoe.
Speaker 0: Okay, he was sure to remember from Ura Seyed Sura who is another one of my favorite characters.
Speaker 0: He was also now I didn't know this.
Speaker 0: apparently He's also a dub voice actor for American movies that get taken over to Japan.
Speaker 0: He was Eddie Murphy in the golden child and he was Mel Gibson in tequila sunrise.
Speaker 1: I don't know what either of those are but that's okay.
Speaker 0: The golden child is actually kind of a crappy movie.
Speaker 0: Oh, he was bond.
Speaker 0: He's the voice of bond in Japan James Bond.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you know 007 Goldeneye and tomorrow never dies.
Speaker 0: He was bond.
Speaker 0: Now the thing is he he's a really cool guy and he did a panel on voice acting.
Speaker 0: Now, you know normally you see a panel on voice acting and it's always like some amateurs or like some people talking about voice actors.
Speaker 0: This was him like training the audience.
Speaker 0: Here is how to be a good voice actor this and this and this and this and this.
Speaker 0: it was really awesome.
Speaker 0: Like I haven't been to a panel that I've enjoyed at a con in a long time and this guy put on one hell of a panel.
Speaker 0: But I mean they have all the whole bunch of fairly big-name guests like cool people that you'd only see at a big con.
Speaker 0: But they're this little con.
Speaker 0: So there's a good chance.
Speaker 0: You'll see him wander in the hall.
Speaker 0: You can shake their hand or say hi to him.
Speaker 0: If you know Japanese or their translators around you can talk to him.
Speaker 0: There was a Koichi Tsunoda who was trying to think of one of the he was made.
Speaker 0: he did some stuff for Mezinger Z and Galaxy Express 999 Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I'm not gonna list all the guests you can look that up, but they were all awesome.
Speaker 1: That's one thing I noticed about cons.
Speaker 1: is you?
Speaker 1: you know?
Speaker 1: I always look at someone's resume when deciding if they're a guest I care about or not and says oh this guy was a Character designer on blah and I'm kind of like.
Speaker 1: I don't really care about character designing But it does.
Speaker 1: they never tell you if the person is cool or if the PR, you know That's what it's really about is this is a cool person who cares what they did.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and here all the guests were really cool.
Speaker 0: I mean they were kind of big names but they really had a lot of interesting stuff to say and They were really cool about the autograph sessions like Caitlin glass.
Speaker 0: She she's a voice actress and director and all this stuff and Some poor girl in the artist alley had her sketchbook stolen with all of her prints except they left a couple of them in there and one of them was this original thing of a character that she had played.
Speaker 0: actually it was a winery from Fullmetal Alchemist in the dub and The fan wanted like gave it to the staff to give to her as a gift.
Speaker 0: Like this is my last thing that I have from everything that was stolen.
Speaker 0: I want to give it to you because it's your character.
Speaker 0: Ah, and It ended up being where she actually got to meet Caitlin glass and hang out with her a little bit and it was really cool and happy All right But I had all the voice actors were just walking around the con hanging out at the after-party.
Speaker 0: They were talked to anyone who wanted to talk to him.
Speaker 0: They seem to enjoy themselves.
Speaker 1: Hmm
Speaker 0: now aside from that the actual panels one other neat thing about an amazement is that they do they really focus a lot on Japanese culture and language and Apparently they do a lot of outside of Khan stuff like funding Japanese studies and funding schools where people can learn about this stuff.
Speaker 0: So all of their panels really have an educational bent to them.
Speaker 0: I went to this one panel on geisha as You know like Maiko and geisha and that sort of thing from Japan and it was a very informative very awesome panel.
Speaker 0: I'm not sure what else I can say about that.
Speaker 1: It's good to hear that There were a lot of interesting panels because usually I look at the list of panels and most of them are kind of bleh I don't care.
Speaker 1: I've seen a webcomic panel before you seen one.
Speaker 1: you seen them all.
Speaker 1: Yep, you know that sort of thing and you know.
Speaker 1: the first time I went to Otacon I went to.
Speaker 1: You know the industry panel where you know, they had the the trygun guy was there and it actually isn't so exciting.
Speaker 1: The only important part of going is when they announce new things and you can just read that on anime news network the next day.
Speaker 0: Yep, it really the only things are worth going to are where the guest is cool or the person talking has something interesting to say.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and you know don't Don't discount some because I did this allies you discount someone.
Speaker 1: you look at their resume of what they are.
Speaker 1: You know this guy did this and you're like, oh who cares about that guy?
Speaker 1: But then if you actually go see the guy he's way cool and that's why those panels are crowded.
Speaker 1: He used to think oh, why is that panel crowded?
Speaker 1: and sometimes it is because oh He's the American voice actor for some character character and all the teenage girls are going Whenever he talks in the voice, but some of the panelist guys are actually in.
Speaker 1: girls are super cool.
Speaker 0: Now I do have to say that one panel that was particularly awesome was the anime club summit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yeah, that's oh my god.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, you know what Akira Kamiya did.
Speaker 1: hmm non sequitur in When they took Aladdin over to Japan.
Speaker 1: he was.
Speaker 1: he was Iago.
Speaker 1: really Yeah, really it says right here.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you should.
Speaker 0: you should have seen this guy in person.
Speaker 1: this guy This is just to clarify.
Speaker 1: This is not the Toga guy.
Speaker 1: That's um and because the guy who's Toga in utenna and Takahashi ryusuke in initial D is not this guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this guy is just awesome.
Speaker 0: If you ever want he's I think he's gonna be an animasment next year.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't be surprised.
Speaker 0: if you ever see him at a con go to whatever he does because it's always awesome.
Speaker 1: He was Logan and Logan's run in Japan like not to like.
Speaker 0: all the other guests were really cool.
Speaker 0: I'm not really trying to downplay all of them, but this guy is my hero.
Speaker 0: This guy's my man.
Speaker 0: Now other highlights cuz.
Speaker 0: I realized we've been talking for a long time.
Speaker 1: talking for a long time Yeah, mostly me the.
Speaker 0: there was a just a bunch of little highlights about the con And then I'll go back to some more long detailed diatribes now.
Speaker 0: my anime club summon panel was scheduled at 9 a.m.
Speaker 0: On Saturday, which meant I had to get up early again.
Speaker 1: I hate it when Cons really need to start asking the person running the panel.
Speaker 1: You know is well.
Speaker 0: I was fine with it cuz they didn't really know what to expect from me.
Speaker 0: I mean I was just some guy that some staffer said was cool, and they should let come to the con and do stuff.
Speaker 0: They were like all right And they scheduled me there, and I did the panel.
Speaker 0: and actually when I started there was one person in the audience.
Speaker 0: Great the thing is she was really interested in what I had to say.
Speaker 0: so we talked a little bit And then a few minutes later more people trickled in and then more people trickled in and then a frickin gaggle of people came in and at one point this mother and a whole bunch of like high school girls came in and They were interested.
Speaker 0: They were trying to start an anime club at their high school And they came to my panel specifically to hear my wisdom And it was an interesting experience to be giving this lecture and having all these high school aged people taking notes.
Speaker 0: I felt like a teacher whoa scary.
Speaker 1: But the things they were taking notes a lot of people don't listen to what we had to say.
Speaker 0: those panels Yeah, well at this one I mean It's like the Otacon one where we do the same thing.
Speaker 0: people the people who came were people who actually wanted to know about This stuff, and I think the panel went really well.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna try to run it next year with Scott Johnson.
Speaker 0: You know the legendary Scott Johnson.
Speaker 0: And one interesting thing I noticed about an amazement is there was a Disproportionately large number of both furry fans and doll fee fans.
Speaker 0: I Have no Statement to make regarding that other than that there was a significant number of furries, and there is significant number of doll fees.
Speaker 0: Take that as you will.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they were definitely not an overpowering force, and I have nothing against them other than I no offense to.
Speaker 0: people are into doll fee.
Speaker 0: It's cool, but it's also a little creepy, but I know you're not all creepy.
Speaker 0: I think it's just that I noticed the creepy ones because they're the ones who treat the doll like it's a little tiny human being.
Speaker 0: I
Speaker 1: Think when you spend that kind of money on a doll if you're not going to be crazy enough to treat it like a human Being then you're going to recognize how stupid you are for spending the money and hate yourself and sell it to someone who is insane.
Speaker 1: And that's why the only ones you notice are insane because they think the only ones are insane Honestly
Speaker 0: the only doll fee people that really scare me are the ones who are j-rock types and doll fee types combined Because then the doll fee turns into like this Idol avatar of whatever j-rocker they currently have the hots for and it gets kind of weird.
Speaker 0: I tried to interview some doll fee people about their super doll fee And I failed mostly because they I'm not sure if they didn't want to talk to me, or if they're just that anti-social.
Speaker 0: I really couldn't tell but I couldn't get.
Speaker 0: I couldn't approach them in a way where I could ask them if they wanted to be interviewed.
Speaker 0: Huh at least without breaking all of my social I guess rules Which are?
Speaker 0: You know some people like they give off the body language of don't talk to me.
Speaker 0: all the doll fee.
Speaker 0: doll fee people I wanted to talk to constantly exuded that aura kind of like those board gamers I tried to talk to.
Speaker 0: that I talked about yesterday.
Speaker 0: You know the one group of people who were playing a semi-german board game at an amazement.
Speaker 0: Yeah, yeah, yeah Now you know more overview stuff.
Speaker 0: the dealers room was about what you'd expect.
Speaker 0: It was a typical dealers room though.
Speaker 0: They also there was a game seller who had German board games.
Speaker 0: There were the two typical guys selling knives and swords Which luckily I didn't have to deal with anyone buying a sword and then running around the con with it.
Speaker 1: That's always a worry.
Speaker 1: I remembered Otakon the kid who came up to me, and he was like hey, man How old are you?
Speaker 1: and I'm like.
Speaker 1: why is this guy asking me how old I am?
Speaker 1: Does he want me to buy him alcohol?
Speaker 1: He's like I'm like 22.
Speaker 1: What are you coming out to me punk kid?
Speaker 1: He's like you buy a sword for me, and I just said no get the hell away from me.
Speaker 1: but what I should have said was How much does the sword cost?
Speaker 1: and then he would have said something along the lines of?
Speaker 1: $75 I don't know.
Speaker 1: and I would have said give me $200 and I'll buy you the sword.
Speaker 1: And then I would have bought the sword.
Speaker 1: and then he would have come up to me and said give me my sword and be like Why should I give you the sword?
Speaker 1: I just bought And if you would have said something I would have been like who here is holding a sword?
Speaker 1: who?
Speaker 1: you should keep their mouth shut.
Speaker 1: And I'm good if anyone cuts out to me at Otakon next year Asking me to buy them a sword.
Speaker 1: I am totally doing that not even joking all right.
Speaker 1: And if they're stupid enough to give me a pile of money.
Speaker 1: I might not even buy a sword.
Speaker 1: I'll just take the money And be like the kid gave me 200 bucks around for me.
Speaker 0: now in regards to cosplay there were a surprising number of jig ends from Lupin.
Speaker 0: Really for some reason there were at least four of them.
Speaker 0: Maybe five I'm not.
Speaker 0: I'm not entirely sure.
Speaker 0: if there were four or five there were at least four.
Speaker 0: there were two Lupin groups each Of which had their own jig end plus just jig ends on their own.
Speaker 1: It's you know jig ends always been a moderately popular cosplay.
Speaker 1: but what is with the it's?
Speaker 1: you know that number at that small of a con?
Speaker 1: either means there's some sort of local Lupin interest or Something because Lupin hasn't been on Cartoon Network in a while.
Speaker 1: yeah But Lupin is real popular among people who know about it is real popular among people who know about it.
Speaker 1: But how are you know?
Speaker 1: more be I don't know.
Speaker 0: there were also.
Speaker 0: There was also a very large number of Rukia's.
Speaker 1: I don't know who that is.
Speaker 0: there was an awesome Bato.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Bato and my favorite two cosplays at the con.
Speaker 0: number one Well number two.
Speaker 0: I'll start with number two.
Speaker 0: these my second favorite cosplay at this convention was a bunch of guys who dressed up as Fark calm.
Speaker 0: They had a whole bunch of big pieces of paper that basically had Fark posts on them that were like like they were in an anime Thread or really owls and ha ha Their ha ha's and a really owls for real and everything.
Speaker 0: every cliche It was.
Speaker 0: and they.
Speaker 0: the thing is they had markers and pieces of paper And they kept making more posts and walking around constantly.
Speaker 0: There's a point at which they were entertaining a small portion of the cosplay line for quite some time.
Speaker 0: I would have interviewed them, but I was standing in a tree which I'll get to in a minute.
Speaker 1: They already talked about the tree when I wasn't paying attention.
Speaker 0: The I don't think I talked about it fully okay.
Speaker 0: the other Awesome, you know.
Speaker 0: number one thing was someone dressed up as Jameson.
Speaker 1: Yeah, if you don't know who Jameson is you got to be watching some ghost in the shell standalone complex.
Speaker 0: Yeah, Jameson.
Speaker 0: I mean the costume was really well done.
Speaker 0: I mean it could have been done better, but the concept alone was worth a picture of it on fans view.
Speaker 1: Maybe we'll link to it the.
Speaker 0: the item itself was really high quality and the way you did it was really cool.
Speaker 0: And I like costumes like that like the unique costume.
Speaker 0: that isn't what you'd think or what you'd expect.
Speaker 0: I mean you wouldn't expect anyone to dress up as him.
Speaker 0: if you someone said that you'd say you couldn't dress up.
Speaker 0: Is that that's stupid and the way he did it?
Speaker 1: It's not what I would say.
Speaker 1: I would say oh I never would have thought to do that.
Speaker 1: the guy's awesome for thinking of that first.
Speaker 0: well the way He did it was he instead of being Jameson He made a Jameson, and he pulled it around and he dressed up himself as Jameson's assistant.
Speaker 1: That's a good one.
Speaker 0: yeah, no I gotta give props again to the Bato because he did the perfect Bato smile.
Speaker 0: There's also this little kid.
Speaker 0: he was seven years old and he was dressed up as a very good cute link Man.
Speaker 1: all the little kid cosplays kind of freaked me out.
Speaker 1: like when the mom is dragging around a little mega man a little proto Man, I'm always kind of like yay mega man and proto man.
Speaker 0: Well at least in this case it was definitely this kid's idea.
Speaker 0: this kid is all about link and all about anime.
Speaker 0: Okay, yeah, and his mom is like yeah, he's getting into this stuff, and I gave her some recommendations what to watch.
Speaker 0: Actually I talked to a lot of parents.
Speaker 0: Animasment is a very.
Speaker 0: it's probably the most family-friendly con I've ever seen.
Speaker 1: really cos Otakon is pretty family-friendly.
Speaker 1: They just keep the families sequestered in like one or two rooms far away from all the craziness.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but I mean you couldn't just let a 13 year old wander Otakon without worrying as a lot of people do.
Speaker 0: but yeah But a lot of people don't.
Speaker 0: yeah Otakon is a mess in one.
Speaker 0: you couldn't really drag a seven-year-old around Otakon.
Speaker 0: They would get crushed.
Speaker 1: That's why you bring them to the little Oda kindergarten.
Speaker 0: Yep, Oda.
Speaker 0: I forget what they call it.
Speaker 1: I always I also forget what they call it.
Speaker 1: They call it Oda something.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's a name Oda kids Oda-chan Oda-chan, that's it, but animasment.
Speaker 0: There were a lot of parents there who were taking their kids to their first anime con.
Speaker 1: Now remember at ubercon we talked to that cool dad.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I read a Scrooge comics, but I in.
Speaker 0: I talked to a whole bunch of parents.
Speaker 0: I interviewed a bunch of them about it and Overwhelmingly they were all.
Speaker 0: all they could say is that None of them watched the anime like with few exceptions.
Speaker 0: very most of the parents don't have any idea what this anime stuff is about.
Speaker 0: They're not interested in it at all But they know their kids are into it.
Speaker 0: They're happy their kids are into it because now that they've gone to these conventions They've seen that the kids who were into it seemed a very smart polite interesting not druggies not losers.
Speaker 0: Half the parents said things along the lines of at least they're not into drugs They're just perverted now.
Speaker 1: I did find it interesting that- sex, praise, and infomania, and hormone enraged teens.
Speaker 0: None of the parents knew what yaoi and yuri and hentai were but their kids definitely did.
Speaker 1: All I have to say is You should have told the parents what yuri yaoi and hentai meant.
Speaker 0: Nah, nah, cuz.
Speaker 0: I wasn't gonna do that to these kids.
Speaker 0: These kids seem to have their stuff together.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: We should do it to just one to see what happened.
Speaker 0: Wow, real like if you're as you're a daughter ever mentioned to you yaoi.
Speaker 0: She's like, oh, yeah She says it's her favorite book or whatever.
Speaker 0: Do you know what yaoi is?
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's robots and nurses and shit.
Speaker 1: I think you're really gonna like it.
Speaker 0: We could do a whole bit on that explaining to parents what that is.
Speaker 1: Maybe we should Like.
Speaker 1: it's a public service thing because the problem here is that it's a really big problem for manga.
Speaker 1: actually Is that because that's where most of the yaoi that's in this country is?
Speaker 1: it's not you know and hentai DVDs But hentai DVDs, you know, they check those but the yaoi manga isn't checked as much because people don't recognize.
Speaker 0: Well, you know what, how about we just do a show whenever we have a free Wednesday on like a parent's guide to anime?
Speaker 1: That'd be good.
Speaker 0: I think it'd be really good.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but yeah, the thing is is that Right now the yaoi is real and the shounen and I are popular with the teen girls but parents don't realize what the kids are buying and they're just like oh, it's all manga stuff.
Speaker 1: and if they real if someone sees then So, you know all manga might get a bad name because of the yaoi sneaking in you see.
Speaker 1: so in trying to avert this seeming inevitability of There being a big hate against manga like there's a big hate against video games, which are violent Yeah, we should try to you know inform parents.
Speaker 1: Not all of it is yaoi.
Speaker 1: Just don't let your kid buy the shrink-wrap stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah That's pretty much the best rule.
Speaker 0: Yep Now we I've talked a long time So I'm probably gonna try to wrap up this a little bit because I could talk for many hours about all the crazy things that happen.
Speaker 0: I guess I'm gonna turn half of my stories from this con into geek fables for future Thursdays.
Speaker 0: Great, because they're very generic and very just funny like my adventure of trying to get food with Evan on Friday.
Speaker 0: Oh Food it turned into into like the worst ordeal of the entire convention.
Speaker 1: Wasn't there a nearby food place?
Speaker 0: Oh that we would.
Speaker 0: I'll talk about it someday.
Speaker 0: Okay.
Speaker 0: Oh good God.
Speaker 0: now to its credit it ended with me getting some good shawarma Shawarma, yeah.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but some highlights from my duty as security at one point.
Speaker 0: I heard a large group of people going You know getting louder and louder and louder.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I wonder what could be going on over there.
Speaker 0: I turn and I see a bunch of kids with a beach ball and some duct tape and some saran wrap and they're rolling this Beach ball around and then they come across some garbage and they tape it to the beach ball and they continue.
Speaker 1: At least they're keeping the con clean now.
Speaker 0: I let him keep doing it because I'm basically Animasement is probably the laxest in terms of keeping kids out of it not out of trouble But keeping kids in line of any major con I've gone to.
Speaker 0: I mean they let the kids get away with a lot more.
Speaker 0: They just really stop them if they do anything dangerous or stupid or anything that could cause a problem.
Speaker 0: But if kids are just being loud They just kind of let him roam free and get it.
Speaker 0: a lot of their systems and it was kind of refreshing.
Speaker 0: I mean I was allowed to let kids do things that I thought were cool that if they tried to pull that stuff at Otacon or Katsucon I have to stop him Like this katamari thing.
Speaker 0: Now I let him go and I forgot about it.
Speaker 0: The next night the katamari ball had grown substantially.
Speaker 1: That's what katamaris tend to do.
Speaker 0: I Don't know how they fit it out the door of the hotel But apparently they're gonna take it to every con they go to for the rest of the summer.
Speaker 1: Who's gonna store it at their house?
Speaker 0: Someone has a truck.
Speaker 0: They've got it all taken care of.
Speaker 0: like I interviewed the kid about it.
Speaker 0: They have got this planned.
Speaker 1: We'll see how good they are You know?
Speaker 1: That's how you tell the quality of people.
Speaker 1: is you come?
Speaker 1: if it was us making that katamari ball You would see that katamari ball at every goddamn convention.
Speaker 1: We would have a storage shack.
Speaker 1: rent it out.
Speaker 1: But that's how you tell.
Speaker 1: is if someone sucks then they'll say yeah We're gonna do this.
Speaker 1: They'll come up with a plan and then they won't.
Speaker 1: it'll fall apart and just crumble.
Speaker 1: That's sucky people.
Speaker 0: Yep, so my litmus test here is I'm not going to search for them But if I hear about their katamari ball again, I will consider them a success.
Speaker 1: Yep I agree.
Speaker 0: now at one point some kids formed a conga line And it was like ten people.
Speaker 0: so whatever I let him go and they're doing their little thing.
Speaker 1: It came back as a hundred people.
Speaker 0: it came back because the con was this long long line Basically, and everything was this long line long hallway.
Speaker 0: It went to the end of the con and turned around and now it was a danger.
Speaker 0: Now it was a mob that was running at full tilt in a conga line fashion.
Speaker 1: Whoa, whoa, they can't run in a conga line.
Speaker 1: You haven't had the nice slow cool.
Speaker 0: It was basically a line of fans kind of holding out of each other's backs running full bore.
Speaker 1: No, no, no.
Speaker 0: growing and growing and growing.
Speaker 1: You're supposed to do the conga and the guy in front needs maracas.
Speaker 0: now at this point I could not catch them because while I can run faster than a crowd like that I can't run faster than a crowd like that through a crowd.
Speaker 0: And I was yelling at the end of it.
Speaker 0: Like I cut off like I caught the end of it I was like you please just stop and Luckily, they were all still going.
Speaker 0: so I basically set up like a mirror.
Speaker 0: They were running toward one end of the con.
Speaker 0: There was a dead end over there.
Speaker 0: So I ran over and I waited and it hit the wall and if it was gonna turn around I was gonna be like all right, you had your fun, that's enough.
Speaker 0: and Luckily, they ran into the wall and kind of derailed into a mass Mm-hmm and it all collapsed.
Speaker 0: uh-huh, and Actually later on like Saturday because this happened Friday night I was talking to another staffer and they came up and they were like, can we do the conga line again?
Speaker 0: And she had the most brilliant idea.
Speaker 0: She said yeah, you know what if you guys can get one going around the entire outside of the hotel.
Speaker 0: That'd be really awesome.
Speaker 0: And I didn't see those kids for like an hour.
Speaker 0: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: That was brilliant.
Speaker 1: Did they actually get it going around the outside of the hotel?
Speaker 0: You know what?
Speaker 0: I don't actually know but they tried which meant they weren't bothering me.
Speaker 0: At one point a bunch of guys decided to have their own mini rave, you know every con has the dance.
Speaker 0: well every big con.
Speaker 0: They had a little boombox and they set up in the middle of a hallway and started having a dance just in the middle of The day.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, it was awesome.
Speaker 0: Except for the fact that it was completely blocking off any sort of traffic.
Speaker 0: Oh, no Now I walked over and I was like guys guys guys guys and they all look at me and the music turns off with this Look of like.
Speaker 0: you're not gonna stop us.
Speaker 0: Are you?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah And I was like You guys are awesome.
Speaker 0: Could you take it around the corners of that big open space and do whatever you want?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah I've never seen kids be that like thankful and happy and they put on a cool little party for another hour at least.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, wait a minute.
Speaker 0: Now Another group of people I believe this was Saturday or Sunday They decided that they were going to have this out of the blue.
Speaker 0: They did this and they stood in the middle of a big hallway area and they started having a revivalist church meeting.
Speaker 1: Now you tell me this.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that sounds pretty terrible.
Speaker 1: That is pretty terrible.
Speaker 0: But no, it was actually a revivalist Church of the elite master.
Speaker 1: Wait a minute the Church of the master.
Speaker 0: No I Don't think we ever told the story of the Church of the master on this show.
Speaker 1: No, we're tells the church story of the Church of the master in the future.
Speaker 0: Yep That'll be a geek fable because the moral will be we should have bought the Church of the master.
Speaker 1: Yes Should have bought the church.
Speaker 1: real immorality.
Speaker 1: You should have bought the Church of the master.
Speaker 0: But what they were doing is they set up this little congregation and they did like a typical like southern revivalist thing.
Speaker 1: Only can I get a can.
Speaker 0: I get an OM Jesus and it was all funny and silly and and totally in elite speak Like one of them would read a serious sounding scripture II thing and then the other guy would be like OMG WTF Abraham.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and it was just.
Speaker 0: it was really hilarious and I give props to these guys.
Speaker 0: they they.
Speaker 0: they also said I interviewed them that they're going to try and Go around to other conventions and do the same thing and try to make it a thing.
Speaker 0: I give them the best of luck.
Speaker 1: Yeah, as long as they're not using it as a Trojan to actually get some religion going on It's all good.
Speaker 0: Luckily.
Speaker 0: One of the guys involved was that way because I was trying to Trojan horse it.
Speaker 0: Yes now Fortunately the rest of the people involved seemed very much of the mind that this is just funny and cool and no more than that.
Speaker 0: Yeah Yeah.
Speaker 0: And then An amazement as one awesome thing that they do.
Speaker 0: You know every con the most painful experience ever is getting in line for the big event or getting in line for the cosplay.
Speaker 1: No, cuz I don't get in line for the.
Speaker 0: well you get in line for the big event.
Speaker 0: It depends like the laraku concert.
Speaker 1: Well, that wasn't really a line.
Speaker 0: That was a line.
Speaker 0: The fact that was
Speaker 1: there like a snake
Speaker 0: An amazement has a general no lines
Speaker 1: policy
Speaker 0: And the way they did the seating for the cosplay and the musical was that they they said gave everyone who wanted numbers to get into the cosplay like Otakon you have a sticker and At like 10 o'clock in the morning on Saturday you can go to this desk at any time and get a sticker and the sticker has a number one.
Speaker 0: through like seven and an hour before the cosplay or an hour before the musical they'll set up these big poles that have numbers in the top from outside the Otakon and you were guaranteed to.
Speaker 0: if you if you have a number one, you can stand by the number one and When they form the line for the cosplay they take all the number ones first Then they take the number twos then they take the number threes So you don't have to stand in line.
Speaker 0: you just go over to your number right before they take them in.
Speaker 0: Mmm, that way you're standing in line without standing in line.
Speaker 0: It worked really well.
Speaker 0: The only drawback was that the musical is delayed somewhat For various technical difficulties.
Speaker 0: as a result I was standing outside and I realized that I was pretty much for a bit of time the only staffer anywhere.
Speaker 0: There was a large increasingly unruly mob.
Speaker 0: So I did what any sane man would do.
Speaker 0: I climbed a tree and from there dealt with the crowd And I learned that there is one and only one way to get the attention of a crowd of geeks and that is to yell Leroy.
Speaker 1: There are other ways but you do something akin to Leroy.
Speaker 0: it were it worked so well, it was amazing.
Speaker 0: I couldn't get their attention.
Speaker 0: So finally I yelled Leroy and half the crowd yells Jenkins and then they all looked around to try to figure out who yelled Leroy and then they all saw me and then I could Do what I needed to do.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm, and I got to say that is the point at which I became a semi celebrity among the people of the con.
Speaker 0: Because being in the tree I had people call me such thing first.
Speaker 0: I was the tree guy.
Speaker 0: then some a bunch of girls started calling me the tree bishi.
Speaker 0: That was very fun.
Speaker 0: One girl gave me the second oddest compliment I've ever been given in a public place where her and her a second oddest.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 0: I Was told that that I look like some guy.
Speaker 0: she knows and I was like, well, how should I take that?
Speaker 0: She said well, he looks like an elf And I was like, all right, that's a compliment right.
Speaker 0: and she's like yes very much Because you know, I have my long hair and I was like hanging in this tree.
Speaker 0: One group of people called me this bit of the be shown in Dryad quotes Exactly that some two girls wanted to.
Speaker 0: they took they posed with me and had someone else take pictures.
Speaker 0: I signed an autograph for someone.
Speaker 0: someone took a video of me standing in the tree.
Speaker 1: I Don't know what it is like.
Speaker 0: it was just a really good climbing tree.
Speaker 0: like it had a nice spot I could stand on.
Speaker 1: Oh stand so a pretty big branch.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and at one point I had a megaphone up there.
Speaker 1: How high was the lowest branch?
Speaker 0: Oh, the lowest branch was about like shoulder height.
Speaker 0: Oh really above shoulder.
Speaker 1: That's like great.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like the perfect climbing tree.
Speaker 1: That's like perfect.
Speaker 1: now I know it's not so low that it's like a stepping stone, you know.
Speaker 1: Like.
Speaker 1: it's like it's a staircase made of branches, but it's not so high that you have to do a pull-up to get on there.
Speaker 0: Yeah now second oddest compliment.
Speaker 0: Now that's a statement that warrants some sort of explanation.
Speaker 0: I assume I was once complimented by someone at RIT Who said to me and I quote exactly?
Speaker 0: You walk like a vampire All right, and she meant it as a compliment.
Speaker 0: Mmm, freaky freaky.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I found that interesting Freaky larpers and to this day, I'm still not sure.
Speaker 0: Oh, I'm still not sure what that means.
Speaker 1: It means freaky larpers wanted to you.
Speaker 1: So to me Yeah run away very quickly because they want to take their golden goblet and put your blood in it and drink it.
Speaker 0: Yep, but I got to say it was real fun to have a crowd to you know muck with and actually other staffers arrived at at some point to help me and Then they did their awesome thing.
Speaker 0: the staff were all really awesome.
Speaker 0: Like if any of you are listening to this I have to give props.
Speaker 0: you guys pulled off one hell of a con Especially considering how few of you there were.
Speaker 1: I remember before the con you were skeptical of the intelligence of the staff that you'd never met.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz when I basically when I haven't met people who run like an event you assume they're stupid.
Speaker 0: Yeah, mostly because most events I've gone to were run terribly.
Speaker 0: The staff at an amazement are badass.
Speaker 1: Huh most events are run terribly.
Speaker 1: there are some people running some event.
Speaker 1: those people must be terrible.
Speaker 0: Yep But then they'll prove it.
Speaker 0: Otherwise, yeah, we'll look at the New York comic-con Comic-con.
Speaker 1: your comic-con is run by a company that runs conventions and you know what they suck.
Speaker 0: It's funny how the people who volunteer and do it just because they love doing it are always better than the people who are paid To do it.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I wonder.
Speaker 0: well, no, I don't wonder I know exactly why that is open.
Speaker 0: so Actually to explain to some of the people at my new work because I was trying to explain wait a minute.
Speaker 0: So you paid to fly to Raleigh so you could work security and talk at a convention Mm-hmm, and they didn't pay you to do this.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Why would you do that?
Speaker 0: It's fun, yeah, but the you know, why what?
Speaker 0: why would I do work like that for other people?
Speaker 0: they people just don't get it.
Speaker 0: Now the last thing I'd really like to talk about at an amazement is I Wouldn't say was the highlight of the con because I couldn't really pick out one highlight.
Speaker 0: I had a freaking amazing time and Amazing, but last year they did I promised I would say an amazing at every day of this week.
Speaker 0: So I said it again.
Speaker 0: but The previous year they did a musical.
Speaker 0: people got together and did a full-on musical to Evangelion.
Speaker 0: That was supposedly hilarious.
Speaker 0: as A result they decided to do one this year and he talked about this.
Speaker 1: Do you think of the day?
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, I did.
Speaker 0: That's right.
Speaker 0: Well anyway To summer because I said I talked more about it.
Speaker 0: It was called at.
Speaker 0: It seemed like a good idea at the time and you know, this con was called an amazement.
Speaker 0: so they did this parody musical about running a convention called animosity and It was utterly utterly hilarious.
Speaker 0: I didn't get to interview the people who actually did it because I only ran into they actually have songs.
Speaker 0: Yes, they were good.
Speaker 1: any spoken lines or was it all singing spoken lines and singing like a typical Broadway musical?
Speaker 0: All right And the scene changes were actually the funny.
Speaker 0: the scene changes convinced consistent entirely of this.
Speaker 0: lights would go down They would move this potted plant from one part of the stage to another part and the lights would come back on with different people standing around.
Speaker 0: yeah There is supposedly going to be a DVD or a video of the entire Musical and I will let you all know when that appears because this was freaking hilarious Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: I really can't.
Speaker 1: I've heard tale of similar things at other conventions and they're very popular because it's like most Cosplays are a ragtag bunch of guys throw something together at the last second with people They met at the con
Speaker 0: or they're the crazy Professionals who can't do much because you only get a minute and 30 seconds to do your skin.
Speaker 1: You can't control the lighting.
Speaker 1: You can't control the art.
Speaker 1: You can't.
Speaker 1: you can barely control anything.
Speaker 1: All you got is like a CD Costumes maybe a set piece if you can move it really quickly, you know, so it's got to be made of cardboard.
Speaker 1: I mean remember the awesome Muppet Revolution thing at Otacon.
Speaker 1: Yep Whip it out and run through the skit so fast.
Speaker 0: Any other choice, you know, see there's another nice thing in the musical, you know, they did the AMV thing.
Speaker 0: they also made fun of the cosplay and For that they had a whole bunch of actual cosplayers.
Speaker 1: do actual cosplay skits Which were ended with hilarity Because they were I mentioned they were commenting on the cosplay seats on yes.
Speaker 0: Yes.
Speaker 1: Wow, that's Yeah.
Speaker 1: So is that all your an amazement action?
Speaker 0: Actually while I have a lot more I could say I'll probably just hold off and talk about them as stories in general as opposed to coverage of an amazement.
Speaker 0: All right, and while I also have all the interviews I did at an amazement We don't have a Windows computer to get.
Speaker 0: the interview was off so I can put them in this episode.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 0: So because they were mostly generic.
Speaker 0: I didn't ask so much about an amazement, but I asked about anime cons in general.
Speaker 0: Whenever I get a chance I will use them for that.
Speaker 0: I asked a lot of people why they go to anime conventions and I got a lot of very interesting answers.
Speaker 1: You should send them over to those animal order guys so you can do his search for the truth business that he keeps doing.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, or in the very least I'll do a bit about my version of the truth and send it to him.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, that'll be a good idea.
Speaker 1: So yeah It's even better idea cuz.
Speaker 0: I interviewed a lot of people at an amazement and send him like rims search for the truth at an amazement.
Speaker 0: the interviews were mostly awesome.
Speaker 0: almost everyone I ran into was great and Other than one guy who these two guys?
Speaker 0: I tried to interview him and they were really excited and one guy was giving me a normal Interview and they were both normal people like.
Speaker 0: they were smart cool people.
Speaker 0: One guy and he's from the Carolinas like he's a local but he didn't have much of an accent.
Speaker 0: Once I turned the mic on he started talking in the most horrid backwater like Southern Alabama accent I've ever heard some folk don't ever.
Speaker 0: he's gonna bet against some focal likely.
Speaker 0: It is the slack shot yokel.
Speaker 1: Hey mom get off her damn roof.
Speaker 0: oh Dang it.
Speaker 0: But the guy was doing it on purpose and afterward.
Speaker 0: He said something like hey, maybe it'll scare the yanks away from the con.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but he was really funny and cool And he was just basically making fun of.
Speaker 0: he was making fun of people who live down there who don't understand anime cons By pretending to be one of them, but once I turn the mic off He turned back to a normal person and told me what he really thought.
Speaker 1: Yeah, all right This weekend as in June 4th I guess yeah give or take.
Speaker 1: I see tomorrow's June 1st Friday 2nd so 3rd.
Speaker 1: Right.
Speaker 1: today's Wednesday 3rd whatever this weekend right this Saturday Raymond Scott will be Attending Wizard World Philadelphia as Normal con goers.
Speaker 0: yeah, so at best.
Speaker 0: We're gonna be like kind of press, but without any of the press credentials.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna be walking around and we're gonna talk to some other podcasters.
Speaker 1: That'll be there.
Speaker 1: We'll be with our friends We'll be buying comic books.
Speaker 0: We'll be interviewing people.
Speaker 1: We'll be talking to comic book guys.
Speaker 1: You know we'll be go won't go to any panels.
Speaker 0: We might not even say they're all day cuz it's not the biggest con yeah And we'll just jump over to the Jersey Shore as soon as we're done.
Speaker 1: Yeah We're gonna make like the once through.
Speaker 1: then we'll make the twice through where you go digging through all the 50 cent bins and the Dollar bins for the cheap comics, and then we're out.
Speaker 1: so if you are near the Philadelphia's Then head on over there to the little tiny Comic convention in the big Philadelphia Convention Center.
Speaker 1: yep, and on Sunday Don't look for us.
Speaker 1: and on Friday.
Speaker 1: Don't look for us because we will be at the beach.
Speaker 1: Haha cuz Andy juggernaut the beach.
Speaker 0: that was dumb.
Speaker 1: Don't worry dad.
Speaker 1: I couldn't resist And come on comic convention juggernaut beach get it Fuck you Yeah.
Speaker 0: now my final thoughts on an amazement because my coverage was again kind of fractured partly because I Originally intended to go solely as a panelist and as a press guy.
Speaker 0: you know my coverage of the con Because I ended up being staff and doing all the awesome stuff and like this is being staff the whole time I Didn't get to cover the con so much as I was a part of it Which is something I didn't expect to do.
Speaker 0: so I didn't really have any of the notes or anything I usually take when I go to a con Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: so I can promise you that least our coverage of the next few cons We go to will be much more.
Speaker 1: I guess regimented yep Because like I said this weekend wizard word Philly.
Speaker 1: the weekend after that nothing.
Speaker 1: yet The weekend after that anime.
Speaker 1: next we'll probably be going to at least one day of anime next.
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 0: And of course when Otacon comes not only are we going, but we are doing a full-on geek night's show there Now at Otacon.
Speaker 1: and well it's a hundred.
Speaker 1: it's 90% confirmed.
Speaker 0: Yeah, 90% concerned, and I'll tell you this if we somehow don't have our geek night show for whatever reason I'm still doing the anime club summit extravaganza Yep, and in addition always do our geek night show in the hallway in where there's no people walking around.
Speaker 0: yeah.
Speaker 1: so Also, so you know we're gonna be like every day of Otacon and the week after that is the quote-unquote week of awesome.
Speaker 0: We're not sure exactly how we're going to handle geek nights that week because there's no internet content.
Speaker 1: We might prepare like for best of episodes and have them automatically post each day Or we might not do podcast that week or we might podcast from the week of awesome.
Speaker 1: Yeah, like you know when jeopardy is on like you know not where it usually is and it's somewhere else We might get a little bit on the beach.
Speaker 0: We might get someone we know.
Speaker 0: if we don't have any way to get internet connectivity easily We'll just call in on our cell phones every day to a friend who has Skype to record it And then have them upload it and everything.
Speaker 1: That's a little crazy.
Speaker 0: That's not so bad.
Speaker 0: just do a short like like penny arcade.
Speaker 0: when they go to cons They do the sketches will do the sketches on the audio I Guess.
Speaker 0: yeah, we'll see.
Speaker 0: we got a long time to plan that out.
Speaker 0: we do and I can tell you with certainty that I will be at an amazement next year And there's a decent chance that we'll be doing a full-on show there a geek night show.
Speaker 1: Alright, let's see how many conventions we can do geek night shows at.
Speaker 0: well.
Speaker 0: Let's see so far It's gonna be Otakon.
Speaker 0: an amazement on katsu khan.
Speaker 1: We got to start hitting up some non anime conventions.
Speaker 1: We got uber khan.
Speaker 1: Let's go first.
Speaker 1: Let's go for a couple more gaming conventions.
Speaker 0: Oh people talk really well of dragon khan.
Speaker 0: Where is it somewhere far away great?
Speaker 1: Is that origins which I'd like to go to but that's kind of far away.
Speaker 1: Yeah, there's one of those moving cons where it's in a different location all the time.
Speaker 0: You know what I don't actually know.
Speaker 1: I've never been to origins like don't bot khan and gen khan move around all the time.
Speaker 0: Gen khan is complicated.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the state of gen khan is now, but it used to be it exists it's big it used to be in Wisconsin and or Europe and it's England, Wisconsin and somewhere else.
Speaker 1: I don't know.
Speaker 0: I don't know what the deal is with it anymore Mainly because that kind of khan is not my bag usually.
Speaker 0: yeah neither comic cons.
Speaker 0: So I think I'll have Scott do any of the interviewing we do this weekend.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because my interviews would consist of so why the hell do you read comics?
Speaker 0: Why do they bold every other word?
Speaker 0: Yeah, what's wrong with Stan Lee?
Speaker 0: Does he not have a dictionary then?
Speaker 0: Maybe a thesaurus.
Speaker 1: Yeah No, even I'm not too good with the comics, you know I walk around and there really are beside.
Speaker 1: I think Kevin Smith is gonna be there besides him.
Speaker 1: I don't really know.
Speaker 1: Well, no, actually, you know who we can interview.
Speaker 1: That'll be awesome Like the brothers Cubert are gonna be there and one of them Studied medical illustration at RIT.
Speaker 1: So wait if I can remember which one it's either Andy or Adam Which one went to RIT we can talk to him.
Speaker 1: It'll be cool.
Speaker 0: So in closing animasement is fan-fucking-tastic.
Speaker 0: I cannot express to you enough how much I enjoyed this khan.
Speaker 0: I enjoyed it more than katsu khan Mm-hmm and katsu khan is a big khan like one of the full-on cons that I'm used to.
Speaker 0: Animasement is just it.
Speaker 0: It was amazing.
Speaker 0: It's an amazing.
Speaker 1: Oh, no, oh, yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah step into a slim Jim and I was doing the Kool-Aid guy I know but I couldn't resist the slim Jim.
Speaker 1: dude, Randy Savage vs.
Speaker 0: Kool-Aid and My last little bit about animasement will be simply that I subsisted almost entirely on Red Bull multivitamins Starbucks coffee and penguin mints.
Speaker 1: Scott Speed, thanks you for your support.
Speaker 0: Yeah Until the after party when I ate sushi.
Speaker 0: It was the first real food.
Speaker 0: I had pretty much all weekend Yuji ite.
Speaker 1: Thanks you for his Inside jokes.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and once again, I like give a shout out again to the staff of animasement.
Speaker 0: You guys really put on one hell of a con.
Speaker 0: I'm not just saying that because if you listen to my coverage of other cons I will not be polite if I don't like a con.
Speaker 1: No, we're brutally honest me more.
Speaker 0: So but you should hear what we said about the New York comic-con.
Speaker 1: see the way rim is is you know?
Speaker 1: We're both sort of honest.
Speaker 1: The thing is I'm honest in that I say exactly what I think.
Speaker 1: no more no less Will say.
Speaker 1: if something was good, he'll say it's awesome.
Speaker 1: Oh my god, and if something was awesome.
Speaker 1: Oh my god He says it was only crap being in his pants.
Speaker 1: Holy crap.
Speaker 1: Yeah, something was a little bit bad.
Speaker 1: rim will say it's terrible It's bad.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm a bad.
Speaker 0: I Made logarithmic scale in either direction.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and but really all all joking aside animasement was an awesome con.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm And that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is accorded with absolutely no studio and no audience But unlike those other talk shows it's actually recorded at night.