Speaker 0: It's Monday October 30th, and this is geek nuts tonight.
Speaker 0: We whine about wine.
Speaker 1: Let's do this Now.
Speaker 0: normally.
Speaker 0: this is where I say We had a crazy weekend.
Speaker 0: We were out in blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: We're exhausted But I got to say for the first time in a while.
Speaker 0: We didn't really go anywhere We didn't really do a lot, and I'm totally well rested and ready to go.
Speaker 1: Could that be because of our extra hour of awesome man?
Speaker 0: that extra hour this year was so good I mean last year.
Speaker 0: I didn't even notice I totally forgot.
Speaker 0: I got an extra hour today.
Speaker 0: well and yesterday in the day before that extra hour Just seemed to pervade my entire life and as a result I'm totally well rested ready to go and yet I got a lot done over the weekend.
Speaker 1: Not only was I real well rested not only did I get a lot done, but I didn't go to work today.
Speaker 0: now Why pray tell did you not Scott go to work today?
Speaker 1: well cuz about four in the morning I had some stomach pains And there's no way I'm going to work with stomach pains because a if I don't make it to work That's the worst thing ever.
Speaker 0: no because that you know not all right.
Speaker 1: go on because I see if I do make it to work The toilet there is the worst thing ever.
Speaker 0: I submit that attempting to go to work with stomach problems Not making it and going home is not the worst thing in the world because it's a private shame.
Speaker 0: No one sees it.
Speaker 0: I didn't know one.
Speaker 1: no I don't mean it's the worst thing in the world literally But it's something I'd like to avoid.
Speaker 1: is the worst thing is I really don't want to poop all over my nice new car.
Speaker 0: See the worst thing in the world to be if you're going to meet the president of the United States And the premier of China and your future girlfriend.
Speaker 0: And then it happens suddenly and violently.
Speaker 1: and then Hitler is reanimated every orifice and shoots you and oh It's from violent for every orifice at the worst possible moment.
Speaker 1: And then you are the resurrection of Hitler and you get shot.
Speaker 0: someone remind you find out that the resurrection of Hitler.
Speaker 0: Then you get shot by the bionic commando.
Speaker 0: Yeah, let captain rad lad Spencer.
Speaker 0: Yeah exactly something like that.
Speaker 0: Yeah for all Super Joe's awesome.
Speaker 0: He spends that whole game in a POW camp.
Speaker 1: anyway for all my not going to work I didn't tell anyone at my work that I wasn't coming to work today I didn't tell my boss.
Speaker 1: usually I send him an email like hey I'm not coming to work today cuz you know I work in an office in the middle of nowhere all alone.
Speaker 1: I didn't say anything to anyone.
Speaker 1: I wasn't contacted at all today.
Speaker 1: No one noticed that I was gone.
Speaker 1: I did nothing.
Speaker 1: I was at my house, and that was that crazy out of control.
Speaker 0: So anyway as most of you from last week know we got our brand new super fancy dual-chain compressor Last Thursday and bit by bit I'm learning how to use it because it has a lot more functionality and a lot more fine-tuning than the previous compressor we had.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it looks like it has one extra knobbly And the other compressor did.
Speaker 0: it also has more button.
Speaker 1: it also has a lot more buttons And it has two compressors not one.
Speaker 0: so we have a total now of three compressors one of which at one without a power cable Which we'll get eventually eventually.
Speaker 0: so I guess my heads up now is that for the next week at least I'm going to be doing the show as normal listening to the show on my way to work and Learning how to use this compressor better because the compressor is so much more powerful.
Speaker 0: I think at this point I can make the show sound pretty much perfect as in better than your average radio station.
Speaker 1: You have no idea how annoying this is for me because I'll be sitting in my room minding my own business and all I hear From rim is he's basically screaming throughout the house Testing Moving knobbly I often Yell the most or Jack Thompson and power book.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he's just yelling around the house, and he's just sitting there moving knobs and yelling.
Speaker 1: move knobs.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it really sucks to sit in a house trying to do something while someone else is you know moving knobs and yelling?
Speaker 1: And I'm trying to read a book At least when I do my mind.
Speaker 0: I mean that's not most of my testing.
Speaker 0: most of my testing.
Speaker 0: I'm playing savage white witch at crazy volumes while fiddling with the compressor in real time and listening to it on headphones.
Speaker 1: That's why don't you keep the headphones on?
Speaker 0: I have that phones on anyway.
Speaker 1: put up put a box over your head So I don't hear you yelling.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you could deal with my yelling.
Speaker 1: Yeah, whatever old yeller Has it you are.
Speaker 0: yeah, so we're back to normal and hopefully the show is going to sound tiny bits better day by day.
Speaker 0: So once again I've noticed a funny trend that About half the people who've mentioned the compressor said that you couldn't hear a difference and the other half said that the difference was noticeable And important and I noticed a distinct age correlation between the two.
Speaker 0: Granted my sample size is very small so all I ask is that if you notice that a particular episode of geek nights Sounds particularly better or particularly worse or you or anything particularly annoying in the next week.
Speaker 0: Let me know.
Speaker 0: otherwise I think I can handle the optimization of this thing on my own.
Speaker 0: at this point.
Speaker 1: Why don't we try to make like a 128 mp3 one day just to have an extra high-quality episode or something?
Speaker 1: Ah, then people could really see if there's a difference.
Speaker 0: true true because a lot of the difference will be lost in the mp3 NIST though not as much since we use a higher bitrate than most podcasts.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we do.
Speaker 1: Anyway,
Speaker 0: so you got some news being I got a science and so
Speaker 1: Seagate who you might remember bought max store The lot, you know with creating the largest hard drive manufacturer in the universe
Speaker 0: also unifying the house of rim and Scott because I have Been a lifelong max tour user
Speaker 1: and I have been a lifelong Seagate user
Speaker 0: and with their powers combined.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 1: It's funny though.
Speaker 1: How you know, I was the Seagate user.
Speaker 1: You're the max store user and max store is now like the cheap value line and Seagate is the real deal.
Speaker 0: Anyway, I think that has more to do with the names and the target markets because both companies brought a lot of good technology to The table.
Speaker 1: well I think what they found out was what Seagate found out when they bought max store.
Speaker 1: is the people who buy max store drives Really don't intersect to the people who buy Seagate drives at all.
Speaker 1: And that's why it was such a profitable venture.
Speaker 1: They got so many new customers.
Speaker 0: Yep Yep Plus.
Speaker 0: they got max tours crazy tech in addition to their own crazy tech because they both had Innovated in the hard drive market.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but Seagate and Hitachi really do most of the hard drive innovating.
Speaker 1: Anyway, IBM used to yeah, they used to not anymore.
Speaker 1: So Seagate is innovated yet again in hard drive technology.
Speaker 0: Oh, really?
Speaker 1: They have a new You know technology called drive trust and what this does is the hard drive is gonna encrypt itself even right now.
Speaker 1: if I wanted to I could set up a loopback device or Something else in order to encrypt all the data on my hard drive which means that no one can get the data off my hard drive without a key or a Password or maybe a physical key or something like that.
Speaker 1: so if you took my computer and ran away you couldn't get any of my personal information off the disk or if I was arrested or the FBI took my computers and they tried to figure out if I had illegal stuff on there.
Speaker 1: They couldn't find anything because it's encrypted.
Speaker 0: now There are a lot of questions regarding this sort of thing and a lot of pros and cons regardless of the answers.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean right now there aren't too many details other than they're gonna put it in hard drives.
Speaker 1: We don't know if they're gonna put in every hard drive or just some hard drives.
Speaker 1: It's proprietary.
Speaker 1: But if other hard drive manufacturers want to use it, though, I guess they're gonna sell it to them.
Speaker 0: the technology Yeah, they'll probably license it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and You're gonna have to enter the password on the computer or something like that, you know It doesn't say whether that's a BIOS level thing adjust after the BIOS thing or an OS thing.
Speaker 0: Well, I'll imagine that if this comes to pass then it won't be long before there are special motherboard things Where you can have a chip on the motherboard that handles all this for you And you just wherever the chip goes the hard drives will be encrypted.
Speaker 1: I really think the best way to go about this is to have some sort of physical like a USB key.
Speaker 1: I was just about to say that actually little dongle, but it doesn't look like that's what it's gonna be Not yet.
Speaker 1: It also doesn't say the strength of the encryption.
Speaker 1: if this encryption is weak, then what's the point really?
Speaker 0: Well, that depends.
Speaker 0: I mean weak is a relative term.
Speaker 0: Yeah I mean if you use like standard kinds of encryption if a super government entity really wants to get your data They can get it in a reasonable amount of time in a lot of cases.
Speaker 0: The thing is if encryption is ubiquitous if everything is encrypted and people are always encrypting stuff It doesn't matter that a supercomputer can break one guy's encryption Because it now greatly increases the barrier to snooping on anyone.
Speaker 1: Yeah, also even a hundred and twenty eight bit encryption Which is pretty low considering lots of people out there using like 4096 Diffie Hellman crazy batshit stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah with GPG 128 bit takes years and years and years and years and years.
Speaker 1: There's really not a computer that can solve it in a reasonable amount of time.
Speaker 0: now more Importantly this kind of hardware encryption.
Speaker 0: one important drawback is that let's say Something happens and the hard drive is compromised in some way physically.
Speaker 0: You know you break it or something fails in it or the little encryption thing dies.
Speaker 0: It's gonna be a lot harder if not impossible.
Speaker 1: It's gonna be impossible pretty much.
Speaker 1: They said it's gonna be impossible to get the data off.
Speaker 1: a data recovery Company will basically not be able to recover your data if something happens.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean unless I mean obviously if something happens to the encryption mechanism.
Speaker 0: Yeah, because if the actual key is still intact on the hardware then the company can almost always get the data off
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm,
Speaker 0: but even then you have to remember that anytime you encrypt something not just in this specific instant But in general you're also increasing the chance that you will lose that data forever Because it makes it much harder to recover that data if something bad happens.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I mean if you set a password for the drive, and you forget the password you're pretty much screwed.
Speaker 1: There's gonna be no way to recover that password at all.
Speaker 1: You're gonna have to throw the hard drive out or return it to Seagate or something.
Speaker 0: I ran into that.
Speaker 1: a couple data You're certainly not gonna get back.
Speaker 0: at IBM We had these special chips in the motherboards of a lot of systems that were security things and you could implement high security Which meant that if anything fishy happened the computer was rendered permanently inoperable And the motherboard had to be replaced.
Speaker 0: Wow It was.
Speaker 0: that was for high security things.
Speaker 0: that wasn't used often.
Speaker 0: But every now and then I'd try to install Linux on some box to stick out somewhere in the factory And I'd run into that and the only option was to ship the motherboard back to the factory and get a new motherboard.
Speaker 1: Alright, let me just read.
Speaker 1: I want to read three short things from the article here.
Speaker 1: It says even data recovery specialists would not be able to help if the assigned password somehow gets lost said Scott Shimamura Senior product manager at Seagate.
Speaker 1: That's the trade-off.
Speaker 1: anytime you introduce back doors or holes to circumvent the security then you've created vulnerability.
Speaker 1: He said Seagate said it is already implemented technology into one of its drives for laptops and another for digital video recorders.
Speaker 1: So that's not so bad.
Speaker 1: I mean for regular computers.
Speaker 1: That's sort of like alright what I really need it for.
Speaker 1: I can do it in a different way that is guaranteed to work on My computer and that you know, I'm responsible for but for a digital video recorder or a digital camera Or something like that.
Speaker 1: This is actually pretty good because you know, you're switching drives in and out of these things all the time.
Speaker 1: You know, maybe I want to take some pictures that are pretty hot and I don't want anyone to look at him.
Speaker 1: so I password protect my little tiny hard drive that I use in my video camera, then I take that hard drive out and You know, my rim wants to use the camera.
Speaker 1: he pops his hard drive in there which has a different password So you can keep your videos secret from other people.
Speaker 1: that's not dependent on the camera But the drive itself.
Speaker 0: but at the same time this can be used by companies that want to make DVRs to make it more difficult to get at your data when they apply DRM.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it also.
Speaker 0: Now a lot of people think oh if I ever get busted by the MPAA or the government for whatever shady things I'm doing or whatever weird illegal pornography I may have.
Speaker 0: I'll just have it encrypted.
Speaker 0: No one can get me Even if the government can't get the data if they get a hold of the hard drive and you refuse to give up the key.
Speaker 0: There are a lot of laws and methods where the government can punish you at least in the United States For not furnishing the key so they can access your data.
Speaker 1: Yeah, this sort of crazy legal stuff However, that's how the EFF got started was dealing with that issue.
Speaker 1: However,
Speaker 0: one nice thing is that in many cases though it varies widely depending on what's going on and the severity of your crime and All sorts of things it might be better off if you did something bad not giving up the key anyway Because if you've committed a bad enough crime the penalty for not giving up The key is probably less even at maximum than the penalty for whatever you're charged with.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I guess it's good.
Speaker 1: then for people who want to do illegal things Seagate isn't gonna allow any backdoors into the encryption.
Speaker 0: So the thing is I wish I had a way to verify that Seagate really wasn't putting backdoors in the encryption.
Speaker 1: I know but it seems like I can trust them.
Speaker 1: There hasn't been a reason to distrust Seagate yet.
Speaker 1: They've done pretty good stuff.
Speaker 1: All their drives are awesome.
Speaker 0: So hey So anyway in science news straight up science news for a change now.
Speaker 0: there has been a lot of Controversy though.
Speaker 0: when I say controversy, I mean in the same way that there's quote-unquote controversy concerning the theory of evolution.
Speaker 0: There's been a big thing for a long time now about how vaccines that contain Mercury somehow cause autism in children, which I'll say right now is absolutely not true.
Speaker 0: There have been mountains of studies and there's crazy amounts of data saying that this is completely not true in any way shape or form And there's not only not any chance of causation, but there isn't even a correlation.
Speaker 1: As in there are people who didn't get vaccines and have autism.
Speaker 0: No as in there's no statistical link whatsoever and the people who posit this are total nutbags.
Speaker 1: Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: No credible.
Speaker 1: So they have no evidence whatsoever.
Speaker 0: Now basically what happened was in recent years autism has been on the rise Which is a very misleading thing to say though.
Speaker 0: It is technically correct.
Speaker 0: Autism has been reported more frequently in recent years.
Speaker 0: However, it wasn't until recently that autism was better defined and easier to diagnose and more precise to diagnose.
Speaker 0: so we don't know if autism is actually more prevalent or if we've just figured out better how to differentiate between someone who's mentally retarded and someone who is spectrum autistic or spectrum asperger's Asperger's asparagus errs.
Speaker 1: Yeah Okay, yeah.
Speaker 0: so now besides the thing is basically we don't know anything.
Speaker 1: if we or we know relatively little about a lot of this stuff and Some people think that they know and they're saying what something as if it's true without any evidence whatsoever Yeah
Speaker 0: well I mean like 50 years ago Someone who was autistic would probably not be recognized as autistic because it didn't matter.
Speaker 0: the end result was that the child had severe Difficulty and they generally treated them like any other Developmentally challenged child.
Speaker 0: and now that there's a lot of federal funding and science has improved we are able to diagnose it more and a lot of whack jobs are saying that.
Speaker 0: Therefore because we're seeing more autism something must be causing it Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: Now we honestly as humans as scientists still don't know Exactly what causes autism spectrum disorder?
Speaker 0: In fact, we barely understand how it happens or what effects it has or how to treat it or anything.
Speaker 0: It's this huge horrible mystery.
Speaker 1: Is anyone studying the DNA to see as the people have different genes or something?
Speaker 0: Yes, and there are some links but not those links are not universal.
Speaker 0: Oh there are genes that show a predisposition toward autism and things like that and Men are by far more likely to be autistic than women.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm They should start looking in that little Y guy there.
Speaker 1: I bet you'll find something.
Speaker 1: Yeah Probably more complicated than that probably but it still sounds like a right idea to me.
Speaker 0: Yeah So the news here is that because these autism been coming up more and more supposedly people have been looking for a scapegoat especially the parents of children who are autistic.
Speaker 0: they want someone to blame and people preying on this have decided that the cause of autism is Mercury in the Preservatives for vaccines.
Speaker 1: because there's something that I mean does these people really have it against vaccines?
Speaker 1: Yes, are they like those Christian?
Speaker 0: whatever they are as many of them are but not all of them Uh-huh.
Speaker 0: It all comes down.
Speaker 0: The one that gets the most press is the substance called the marisol which contains mercury and is used not only in many vaccines Especially in the third world but in all sorts of other medicines.
Speaker 0: It's actually fairly common Especially outside of the United States.
Speaker 0: It's been in vaccines for a long time.
Speaker 1: So why is it more common outside the United States?
Speaker 0: because it's been phased out for newer better things Uh-huh in the United States, it's not used in that many vaccines anymore though for any of you who got a flu shot.
Speaker 0: It is in most flu vaccines and I know for a fact that it was in the flu vaccine I received as a critical care worker.
Speaker 0: In fact, I have a funny anecdote here where I was sitting ready to get my you know vaccine from my work and I'm sitting there and I asked the guy hey is there any the marisol in this vaccine?
Speaker 0: and he stops and he looks at me and he very cautiously says something like Why do you ask are you one of those people who believes that the marisol causes disorders such as Autism?
Speaker 0: and I looked at him with a straight face and laughed and said no, I'm not one of those nut jobs.
Speaker 0: I was just curious and he expressed to me that I was probably the first person who was not a scientist or doctor He had ever met who said the word the marisol and was not a crazy nut job.
Speaker 1: So did you ask him if he had actually encountered crazy nut jobs and what they were like?
Speaker 0: we had a little small talk and he said that he's had a lot of people refused the vaccine because they were afraid that Like guys would refuse the vaccine because they're afraid that it would give their yet-to-be-born children autism.
Speaker 1: I have a feeling that those people while they might believe that are actually Subconsciously coming up with an excuse because they don't want to get a shot.
Speaker 0: Alright, that's actually not a bad posit there.
Speaker 0: Yeah So anyway the news here because I've gotten kind of off topic is that this group of whack jobs?
Speaker 0: for a long time has been seeking to force the FDA to put restrictions on or ban the use of the marisol and Finally it has been decided and the decision is now public.
Speaker 0: the FDA Rejected it entirely and basically called them nut jobs saying that their claim has absolutely no merit and that all of the evidence points to Contrary.
Speaker 0: now awesome.
Speaker 0: Here's where it gets interesting one.
Speaker 0: I'm glad the system works.
Speaker 0: Hooray FDA.
Speaker 0: Sometimes dr.
Speaker 0: Mark Greer one of the people on the side of the whack job says quote We're not accepting that answer.
Speaker 1: what what are you gonna do?
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: But the whack jobs don't accept it and they still say despite the fact that every scientist in the world with any shred of I don't know what to say.
Speaker 0: These people are just crazy.
Speaker 1: Goddamnit frickin apple juice causes AIDS and I know it.
Speaker 1: you got a bad apple juice, man No more.
Speaker 1: Well, we're not going to because apple juice doesn't cause AIDS apple juice cause they.
Speaker 0: So I bring it up.
Speaker 0: I thought I saw this in the news last week and I made it my news mostly just because this whole of the meri I mean Scott knows there are some hot buttons with me.
Speaker 0: There are certain topics that that were.
Speaker 0: the people involved are just so stupid and they just they're so unwilling to listen to logic reason or evidence that I just like my head catches on fire.
Speaker 0: if Even if the topic comes up if Scott walks into my room, I'm trying to go to sleep and he's like the Marisol I'll just lay there and see you for another hour.
Speaker 0: see Things of the day.
Speaker 1: I got a pretty hot thing of the day.
Speaker 0: I got an okay thing of the day.
Speaker 1: Oh Okay is your thing of the day?
Speaker 0: Well, it involves politics and pornography All right.
Speaker 1: Anyway, my thing it is much better than that.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it involves a sport that probably hardly anyone listening cares about.
Speaker 1: it's not.
Speaker 1: it's not about the sport.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, it's about even I think anyway, Michael Schumacher is Probably statistically speaking the greatest motorsport racer to ever have lived and he still lives.
Speaker 1: he just retired a week ago or so and He is the second highest paid athlete in the entire world as of right now beaten only by what Tiger Woods.
Speaker 1: Tiger Woods is The only one who makes more money than Michael Schumacher.
Speaker 1: In fact, they have a lot in common because they're both individual athletes and not team guys and whatever.
Speaker 1: So being retired and living in Switzerland, even though he's German Michael Schumacher one of his sponsors is shell shell gasoline and So on his day off he went to the shell station and they did some sort of promotional event there.
Speaker 1: and what they did is they put hidden cameras all over the gas station and Michael Schumacher did a whole bunch of funny things and they made I guess these are commercials.
Speaker 1: I don't know if they're actually gonna use them for commercials but they made a bunch of funny little videos and the first one there's a guy pulls into the gas station and Michael Schumacher puts out the little lollipop stick that says stop just like in the pit stops and the real races and The whole pit crew jumps out and soups up this guy's car.
Speaker 0: granted While it is definitely filmed to look like one of those, you know sudden out of the blue catch a guy by surprise thing.
Speaker 0: I wouldn't be surprised if that was totally staged.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that one might have been totally staged But it really kind of seems like they.
Speaker 1: the way I read the article is that they spent all day at this shell station So just doing weird stuff.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then they you know, they had hidden cameras everywhere.
Speaker 1: So they eventually caught a good one.
Speaker 0: probably my favorite one is where they've just got that little display and he's just standing in the middle Of it in the store like hey, I'm yeah.
Speaker 1: in the second video they just had this big red piece of cardboard and he stands there pretending to be a statue of himself and People are like looking at him and poking him and he's just standing there.
Speaker 0: He winks at a guy once and the guy just goes like oh my god is really him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, see we gotta understand that while in America I'll bet most of you have no idea who Michael Schumacher is or care about him at all But in other countries, especially in Switzerland where he is right now He is he's like Michael Jackson.
Speaker 0: everyone who sees him goes.
Speaker 0: That's Michael Schumacher.
Speaker 1: Holy crap Yeah, imagine if he went into a shoe store and Tiger Woods was There's like a big piece of cardboard and he was standing there like a statue and you just walked in.
Speaker 1: you look at him And he doesn't move.
Speaker 1: That's exactly what this is.
Speaker 1: Only it's a guy you might not.
Speaker 0: that's what this is.
Speaker 1: You know Tiger Woods is probably might be the best golfer ever and this guy's the best car driver ever.
Speaker 1: and the third one is actually also kind of funny because he there's a guy comes up to get gas and he has like the loyalty card for shell gasoline.
Speaker 1: and The guy, you know points out that if he has the loyalty card he can get his picture taken with Michael Schumacher.
Speaker 1: So it goes inside to the gas station and Michael Schumacher just like comes right up behind.
Speaker 1: It was like hey what you doing?
Speaker 0: The guy's like, holy crap The guy seems to lose it like he doesn't know what to do.
Speaker 1: He's that kind of celebrity deer in headlights thing Yeah, and he gets his picture taken with him shakes hands and he goes on his way.
Speaker 1: But the funniest part of that is that you can see just how small Michael Schumacher is.
Speaker 1: tiny little dude Guys who drive an f1.
Speaker 1: they're really fit because they have to you know Withstand all those g-forces and have quick reaction times and all that, but they're small.
Speaker 1: I mean if you're a big guy You can have trouble fitting into a tiny tiny car and you're gonna add weight to the car.
Speaker 1: That's unnecessary.
Speaker 0: See the first time I realized they were little because I just never thought about it is when I finally watched some more f1 races And I started noticing that when they bring out the magnum of champagne to spray around at the end It looks real big.
Speaker 1: it is pretty big
Speaker 0: but it looks a lot bigger than that thing should look
Speaker 1: especially because you only see these race car drivers outside of their cars when they're standing on the podium or they're at the press conference and
Speaker 0: It
Speaker 1: is when they're standing next to each other and they're all small.
Speaker 0: It's like if you saw a movie about halflings and the only people in it were halflings.
Speaker 1: They probably wouldn't know they were halflings probably not Squat but and you know wider than they are at all.
Speaker 1: But yeah, but halflings as long as the proportions were correct, you wouldn't know.
Speaker 0: kind of like hobbits kind of like hobbits.
Speaker 1: So yeah, this is this is pretty awesome these videos right here.
Speaker 0: All right, so like I said politics and pornography.
Speaker 0: So some Republican candidate George Allen, he's the one there's even this whole thing in the Political climate and the midterm elections in the US because this is a. in the United States I know we have a lot of foreign listeners So I don't want to just act like US.
Speaker 0: politics is all that matters because it totally isn't.
Speaker 0: but we're having our midterm elections very soon which a week from tomorrow most people in America don't bother with Because you're not electing a president or anything.
Speaker 0: Most people care about.
Speaker 0: you're just electing Various members of our two houses of Congress and a bunch of local stuff.
Speaker 0: So this year it's really important because among other things It looks like the Republicans might lose control of our House of Representatives which has a lot of ramifications for the years to come.
Speaker 0: Big guns now the.
Speaker 0: the interesting thing is that the Republicans this year have by and large been running extremely vicious negative campaigns against the Democrats Accusing them of being pedophiles and evil Nazis on the side of al-qaeda all sorts of stuff.
Speaker 0: It's crazy.
Speaker 0: It's also kind of hilarious to people like us who don't really care about these people.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so this George Allen this Republican ran an ad with excerpts from his opponent's Pornography.
Speaker 0: you see opponent had written Some pornographic literature in his day.
Speaker 1: Wasn't there a guy that was being investigated a while ago that wrote a porn?
Speaker 1: What was his name?
Speaker 0: Scooter Libby, I believe yeah, that was the guy.
Speaker 1: he freakin wrote a porno book.
Speaker 0: So it turns out that a lot of politicians have written pornography.
Speaker 1: Really maybe I should write some porn and then run for office.
Speaker 0: so on slate here.
Speaker 0: They've got this fun little exercise where they list a whole bunch of politicians.
Speaker 1: and how many?
Speaker 0: uh a through M. Holy shit Let's see we got Barbara boxer who I'm a fan of William Buckley Jimmy Carter written porn.
Speaker 0: Jimmy Carter Newt Gingrich Joseph Nye Kenneth Starr.
Speaker 1: They all wrote porn.
Speaker 0: uh Winston Churchill What so?
Speaker 0: and then it lists?
Speaker 0: for a number of Pornographic excerpts, I'm gonna flip through.
Speaker 1: Oh, so they didn't write actual porno.
Speaker 0: some of them did.
Speaker 1: some of them did but they might have just written a paragraph or two That could be skewed as pornographic.
Speaker 0: or some of them are straight-up pornographic.
Speaker 0: some of them just happen to have vicious or Vivid pornography in them.
Speaker 0: They're varying levels of pornography.
Speaker 1: All right, all right cuz I was under the impression that all these people wrote porno books to be sold in porno stores Which is not the case.
Speaker 0: All right, here's a. here's a quote from the first one here.
Speaker 0: Suddenly the pouting sex kitten gave way to Diana the huntress.
Speaker 0: She rolled on to him and somehow was sitting a thwart his chest her knees pinning his shoulders.
Speaker 0: Tell me or I'll make you do terrible things.
Speaker 0: She hissed.
Speaker 0: All right, who wrote that I didn't even read the results part?
Speaker 0: The exercise here is that you have to match each politician with their pornographic excerpts.
Speaker 0: Okay, it's fun to try lol, so anyway today being science tech computers and Considering Scott had some very important success with wine.
Speaker 0: We would like to talk about wine Not the kinds of drink.
Speaker 0: No, no, no, even though the icon for the wine we're talking about is the kind of drink also, not the thing that People who are mad about this the marisol rejection rejection would do after they lost.
Speaker 0: That's good, yeah, I wanted to say the word rejection twice.
Speaker 0: I've been wanting to do that for a while now.
Speaker 1: Dejection is much better All right.
Speaker 0: So we thought we'd talk about it because a lot of people really don't know what it is.
Speaker 0: A lot of people who use Linux don't realize it exists and the fact that it can make their lives a lot easier or harder.
Speaker 0: And also it is in the recent year gotten incredibly better Incredibly better.
Speaker 0: like two years ago wine was very different and very less useful than it is today.
Speaker 1: Well, let's start at the beginning.
Speaker 1: recently Linux has been getting a big push mostly because of Ubuntu and edgy and such.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's becoming real popular and you know I've been encouraging people to just try it out because you can pop the live CD and just try it out.
Speaker 1: We know now risk to your computer no money.
Speaker 1: it costs you one CD and a few minutes of your time.
Speaker 0: In fact, if you really want you can get a free CD from Ubuntu.
Speaker 1: Yeah, they'll send you.
Speaker 1: I have official CDs.
Speaker 1: I'll mail you one.
Speaker 1: I don't have too many though.
Speaker 1: So I can't get too many requests.
Speaker 0: I mean I even gave one of my co-workers an Ubuntu CD Ubuntu and He ended up installing it on some old computer.
Speaker 0: he has and he loves it and he couldn't believe how far Linux has come from The last time he tried it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but one One hang up.
Speaker 1: a lot of people have from totally switching to Ubuntu or Linux in general is that you can't run your Windows Applications.
Speaker 1: I mean sure let's say you used Microsoft Office in Windows.
Speaker 1: Well, you don't really need Microsoft Office in Linux because you have open office so big deal, but let's say you need Visio.
Speaker 1: Well, yeah Visio is a perfect example, even though there's a program called dia that does almost the same thing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, but yeah, if you use Visio at your work You can't use anything else because your files won't work with the people who have Visio.
Speaker 1: or let's say you have some fun games Like steam that you really want to play.
Speaker 1: Well, one solution is to dual boot where you reboot your computer to Windows run your Windows applications Reboot your computer to Linux use your Linux applications.
Speaker 1: That's not really a good thing because now you're wasting all this time rebooting.
Speaker 1: You might as well just use Windows if you really need those applications.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean back at RIT I used Windows instead of Linux as my OS because I played more games than I did anything else on my computer back then.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, absolutely It wasn't until PC gaming slowed down that I was able to go to Linux.
Speaker 0: full-time like that was pretty much the hang-up Yep, but now PC gaming is starting to pick up again at least for us.
Speaker 1: Well, at least it is with on Steam that there's.
Speaker 1: so there's so many games on Steam now.
Speaker 1: Oh my god.
Speaker 0: Well consider this depth between Def Con Half-Life 2 Counter-Strike source the ship and the upcoming natural selection source.
Speaker 0: That's enough to make me buy a badass freaking computer and play games again.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 1: All right.
Speaker 1: So let's say you're really like Linux you want to use it full-time But let you have one or two Windows applications that are Windows only applications that you really need in order to continue doing business and they're preventing you from going to Linux which you might like better or Like equally or whatever.
Speaker 0: or you're just cheap and you don't want a pirate windows or you're cheap and you don't want a pirate windows.
Speaker 1: The solution is wine.
Speaker 0: Now wine is actually an acronym and this is very important.
Speaker 0: We're not gonna go into technical detail But we're gonna try to explain in somewhat layman terms exactly what this does because wine stands for.
Speaker 0: wine is not an emulator.
Speaker 1: WINE is not an emulator.
Speaker 0: a lot of people when they hear about wine the way people describe it and I'm guilty of this Say, oh, yeah, it's a Windows emulator.
Speaker 0: So you run it in Linux and then in that you can run Windows programs and it's like having a tiny little Windows Which is kind of true, but it's really misleading as to what wine actually does.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that an emulator really is something that you know mimics a computer like it will emulate an actual Machine and take machine instructions and carry them out as if it were a different computer.
Speaker 0: Yeah, like Plex 86 is an emulator.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah box Bo CHS is an emulator.
Speaker 1: Yes You run box on like a power PC computer and it pretty much creates an x86 computer in software and then you install an operating system on this fake computer and it.
Speaker 0: Well, I could go into detail.
Speaker 0: basically that sounds really inefficient and that's because it is really inefficient it is now What is wine if it's not an emulator?
Speaker 1: Well When you have a computer you have instructions that you tell that the processor, you know Chip the pen the Pentium chip at the Athlon chip, whatever you got in there that it your Frickin assembly language.
Speaker 1: God, why did I completely lose my mind?
Speaker 1: I look you have a chip and you can send instructions to it to tell it to do things.
Speaker 1: now whether you have Windows or Whether you have Linux you have the same chip in there probably so it understands the same instructions.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you wrote a program in assembler, it would just run.
Speaker 1: Yep The thing is is there are some instructions that you don't send directly to the chip.
Speaker 1: you send them to the operating system And the operating system then tells the chip what to do.
Speaker 0: Yep Now this is basically.
Speaker 0: this is called an API a way to interface with the operating system Which then interfaces with all the hardware?
Speaker 1: So let's say you wrote a game for Windows.
Speaker 1: Right and in that game that when you were writing the software for the game You had an instruction.
Speaker 1: you told Windows draw a line on the screen Right through the middle of the screen draw a black line.
Speaker 1: All right, and that's part of your game.
Speaker 1: Well, if you try to tell that to Linux Linux goes what the fuck you talking about?
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz you're because Windows has a way where you say I want to have a line drawn.
Speaker 0: blah.
Speaker 0: You tell Windows draw the line the way you draw lines.
Speaker 0: It'll do it.
Speaker 0: So nothing understands that.
Speaker 0: but Windows because it makes a call to a function.
Speaker 0: that is in Windows It is a Windows specific thing.
Speaker 0: What wine does is it watches for Windows calls like that and turns them into?
Speaker 0: Linux calls.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so You run a program on Linux.
Speaker 1: That's a Windows program.
Speaker 1: Linux goes.
Speaker 1: I don't know what the hell you're asking for.
Speaker 1: most of the time like this doesn't work.
Speaker 1: forget it.
Speaker 1: But if you put it inside of wine, so you say wine space solitaire dot exe.
Speaker 1: Whenever solitaire wants to draw a window it tells wine and then wine says alright Linux.
Speaker 1: This is this guy over here.
Speaker 1: I'm gonna translate for you what he's saying
Speaker 0: now because you're just Translating instructions and only the instructions that need to be translated and Because wine has been developed over the years to do it in an efficient way This is vastly better than trying to emulate an entire computer
Speaker 1: Extremely superior.
Speaker 0: It also basically allows you to run a Windows program in Linux as though it were in Windows.
Speaker 0: It doesn't care It doesn't know.
Speaker 0: it just opens in a window like any other program and the calls that need to be sent to a Windows thing Get sent to a Windows thing.
Speaker 1: Now all of the you know, the instructions are what to do.
Speaker 1: when certain instructions come in are in libraries.
Speaker 1: You know those DLLs you got all over the place.
Speaker 0: Those are called dynamically linked libraries.
Speaker 1: Yeah, that's where what.
Speaker 1: that's where the instructions are all defined and made up and such.
Speaker 1: But if you want with wine They have a default set of open source libraries that you can use and they work really well.
Speaker 0: A lot of these are reverse engineered or generally mimic functionality from Windows and they've been done very well, but they're not perfect.
Speaker 1: They're not perfect all the time, but when they work they work great and seriously.
Speaker 0: in the last year They've come a long freaking.
Speaker 1: they've come a long freaking way.
Speaker 1: good crap.
Speaker 0: I mean most of my job at IBM involved developing in wine, so I got some stories.
Speaker 1: Yeah But if you want if you have a copy of Windows you can tell wine to use the actual Libraries from Windows instead.
Speaker 0: so go into a Windows install or search on Google and find them Get the DLLs put them in wine and tell wine.
Speaker 0: hey use these actual windows files now.
Speaker 0: There are varying levels of legality in terms of this But essentially if you own a legitimate copy of Windows you are generally within your rights to use the DLLs in that way And if you do that wine will work awesomely.
Speaker 1: But you're gonna have to put in the effort to tell wine to use all these DLLs now.
Speaker 0: We could do a whole show because I was basically a wine developer and Scott has done a bunch of wine stuff Recently and we could tell you exactly what to do.
Speaker 0: But luckily for most of you there are now instructions on to internet that will tell you exactly Type this then this then this then this and this will work in wine.
Speaker 1: The one thing I got to say though whenever I point to anyone to a how-to Especially a Linux how-to with command-line stuff in it You know it wine.
Speaker 1: really you don't need so much command-line stuff these days now.
Speaker 0: It used to need a lot more.
Speaker 0: now.
Speaker 0: I mean it used to be.
Speaker 0: you had to edit this really poorly Thought out text file.
Speaker 0: that didn't make a lot of sense.
Speaker 1: yeah now in Ubuntu You can pretty much do apt-get install wine to install wine And then you can put a program like sol dot exe on your desktop in Ubuntu Which is solitaire double click on it, and it'll run just like if it was Windows.
Speaker 0: yep You really only have to do anything to wine other than install it.
Speaker 1: if you're trying to run something complicated like steam Microsoft Office yes, or Photoshop or Internet Explorer Internet Explorer is not as tricky depends Which version you want.
Speaker 0: it used to be.
Speaker 0: good fucking God it used to be.
Speaker 1: it used to be.
Speaker 0: even now you got to do Some tricks usually to make I you work.
Speaker 1: it depends.
Speaker 1: there's some all.
Speaker 1: there's some wine based things out there like crossover and Sedaga and Basically what those are is wine plus But they're not free like Sedaga is a special is a company.
Speaker 1: they take wine And they add a bunch of stuff to it so that it can play a bunch of games.
Speaker 1: But so you know do you really need it?
Speaker 1: is the question?
Speaker 1: I mean I have to.
Speaker 1: yeah you used to really need it because it just didn't work without it nowadays.
Speaker 1: I just got half-life 2 to work in plain old free wine Without any windows DLLs today, and it works now.
Speaker 0: consider this it was about seven months ago That I tried to do the same with an older version of wine, and it just wouldn't work at all.
Speaker 0: it was terrible.
Speaker 1: I mean there was the newest version of wine which I'm not even using.
Speaker 1: I'm using two versions ago.
Speaker 1: Just added dual monitor support.
Speaker 1: just yeah it you know it's it's a bind.
Speaker 1: Wine is always about a year behind the newest windows and then Vista comes out.
Speaker 1: Vista stuff probably won't work in wine for about a year.
Speaker 0: Yeah, of course I mean the same thing happened with Windows 2000 and XP But luckily well, I guess unluckily wine wasn't that good back then so it didn't matter.
Speaker 1: yeah now wine While I wouldn't depend heavily on wine for a whole mess of applications.
Speaker 0: Yeah, at least not unless you have a competent wine guy who can sit there and help you.
Speaker 0: yeah
Speaker 1: If you've got a lot of Windows applications, and you're not you know trying to replace them with Linux alternatives or open source alternatives You probably should just be using Windows, but if you got one or two Windows applications Wine is a very reasonable and good choice of how to get those things working without having Windows.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and we're not kidding.
Speaker 0: You don't need to know much especially in Ubuntu to make it work.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you basically just type wine space the name of the program that you're trying to run dot exe and you press enter.
Speaker 0: yep It'll probably just work without you doing anything.
Speaker 1: yeah, the general rule with wine is that a program will either just work or It's gonna be a huge pain in the ass and it's not worth it.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: if you don't get it to work with minimal effort It's probably not going to work with any amount of effort
Speaker 1: as unless you start writing code for wine Because the reason something usually doesn't work is because it's trying to tell Windows to do things that they haven't yet implemented in wine.
Speaker 1: So let's say you know you had a game that said draw a line and the guys who develop wine who are writing the wine Software didn't.
Speaker 1: yet You know make the draw line function Then your programs gonna do some weird shit.
Speaker 0: either that or it's when you've got two windows Programs that interact with each other in a not obvious or easy way like now at IBM.
Speaker 0: One of my main jobs was to take this terrible piece of shit old application that was written for like Windows 3 1 and Windows 95 and Make it work in Linux and this program requires the Oracle clients.
Speaker 0: So I had to get the Oracle client for Windows because it wasn't really Possible to make this program interface easily with the Linux version of Oracle, which works great.
Speaker 0: I had to get the Windows version of Oracle to work in wine.
Speaker 0: Then I had to get this application to work in wine.
Speaker 0: Then I had to get them to talk to each other properly.
Speaker 1: Not easy.
Speaker 0: good fucking God it that was.
Speaker 0: I was paid a lot of money to make that work.
Speaker 0: So I'm you're not gonna sit down and do that for free in my spare time.
Speaker 1: now There's good news though.
Speaker 1: And that is the other rule of wine.
Speaker 1: Is that if something works in wine?
Speaker 1: There's a good chance.
Speaker 1: It'll work better than it does.
Speaker 1: on Windows I mean, you know, sometimes it's about the same.
Speaker 1: I mean my half-life - now that I got it working works about the same as it does in Windows.
Speaker 1: But for example, what's a good thing that works a whole lot better?
Speaker 1: Half-life one actually works a whole lot better in wine than it does on Windows.
Speaker 1: Yes, it's just because the software is written more efficiently than the giant bloated Windows operating system.
Speaker 0: I think it has more to do with just the fact that when you have limited system resources Linux as a whole has less overhead.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and the wine is a very thin layer relatively speaking.
Speaker 1: Yeah, so even when you put that thin layer on top of the very efficient Linux kernel It's even it's still more efficient than Windows and all of its blob miss.
Speaker 0: So I guess if you've been thinking about making the switch to Linux and you only use a few Windows applications like Scott said Check out wine.
Speaker 0: see if you can get your stuff to work because that's one more step closer to switch it.
Speaker 0: Don't get us wrong.
Speaker 0: I mean we're computer professionals.
Speaker 0: We're not zealots in any direction.
Speaker 0: use whatever operating system makes sense for what you do.
Speaker 0: If you're a Windows developer run Windows if you're an animator or graphic designer And you need all those programs that only run on Macs or Windows.
Speaker 0: use Macs or Windows Yeah, I mean.
Speaker 1: but wine is an option.
Speaker 1: it does exist and it's getting better every day and we're just trying to make make sure that people Understand that it's out there and how it works and what it does and if it's good for you Maybe it's good for you.
Speaker 0: now the thing is I want to see if we can get iTunes to work in wine.
Speaker 1: people have been trying and There's been mixed results because iTunes is.
Speaker 0: I know I'm one of those people They think the real got a broken iTunes on my Gentoo box.
Speaker 0: right now.
Speaker 1: the real problem with getting iTunes to work in wine is that the only use for iTunes is the iPod support and Getting it to work with a device like a USB peripheral is kind of tricky.
Speaker 0: Actually, usually it's not that tricky at all.
Speaker 0: Yeah, really?
Speaker 0: It really depends on what's going on because in many case look in the config file for wine.
Speaker 0: I just know this because I had to make this crap old printer print through the serial ports and wine.
Speaker 0: Oh, you can just say come one will cat out directly and raw to serial port one Mmm, you can do things like that.
Speaker 0: So serial ports parallel parallel ports are more tricky because there are different standards of parallel port.
Speaker 1: Well, these are USBs.
Speaker 1: So I don't know and especially since the way Linux is handling USB devices lately.
Speaker 1: They keep changing it up with the udev and all that jazz.
Speaker 0: So theoretically.
Speaker 0: now I say this with a grain of salt because I've never tried.
Speaker 1: I've never tried it either.
Speaker 0: but when it comes to parallel ports and serial ports You can make wine just talk through the serial port raw or you can send the the input and output Through a program or anywhere you want.
Speaker 0: because wine program programs running in wine are running in Linux.
Speaker 0: They can interact with Linux straight up.
Speaker 0: You can pipe the output to places you can send stuff in any way that the program would normally accept.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 0: So physical devices are no different, but USB.
Speaker 0: I've never actually looked at how wine supports USB.
Speaker 0: So I can't say but I'm going to look into that soon because I have an old broken recording bit that I want to work In Linux.
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, maybe that's a good idea.
Speaker 1: Give me the recorded bit software.
Speaker 1: I'll try to get it to work tonight.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz I never.
Speaker 0: I never tried to get that to work in wine.
Speaker 0: I've never tried to make USB work and I'll go for give me the CD.
Speaker 1: I'll do it while you're post-productioning the show.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'll go for it.
Speaker 0: We'll see if it goes and of course thus concludes Season one of geek nights.
Speaker 0: Oh notice It's been a year.
Speaker 0: starting tomorrow is season two of geek nights.
Speaker 0: We're gonna start over with episode one.
Speaker 1: Holy crap.
Speaker 0: I'm kind of excited.
Speaker 0: We've been doing this for a whole year.
Speaker 1: Yeah, of course, we're slightly shit talking because we had all these plans We'd have new music.
Speaker 1: We you know changed the format a little and I rejuvenate the show But we're only gonna do a little bit of that not so much.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well part of it was that a lot of people really like our music and though our opening song which we have the blessing Of DJ pretzel 4 really seems to define the show.
Speaker 0: So at least for another year, we're gonna keep it around.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm That sounds good to me.
Speaker 1: Let's work.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: And of course tomorrow to inaugurate season 2 We are going to have for you our very awesome interview with Luke crane the creator of burning wheel.
Speaker 1: Yes in season 2 that is one thing you can expect from geek nights is that we will have more Interviews and Skype action.
Speaker 1: now, we're not gonna go crazy like other podcasts do because we know that if you're listening to the show.
Speaker 1: Maybe you know, if you're not if you're a new listener, this might not be true, but for our old listeners We know the reason you're probably still listening is good like listening to us talk.
Speaker 1: And I know from listening to a lot of podcasts that when they have interviews every day you kind of go All right.
Speaker 1: I listen to the show because the hosts are awesome and I never get to hear them say anything, you know You know cut back the interviews a little bit guys, but we are not gonna go super crazy on the interviews But we will have some more to spice it up the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah starting tomorrow Yeah, we'll be bringing in whenever we need a scientific expert.
Speaker 0: We'll probably just Skype him right in and get him in right then.
Speaker 0: Yep Also, we'd like to have a lot more listener feedback on the show.
Speaker 0: geek back was going well But we figure it'd be better if we really only used audio feedback.
Speaker 0: So if you want to be on the show you have questions you want to talk to us use our audio.
Speaker 0: We are much more likely to respond to you on the show if you send us audio as opposed if you send us an email.
Speaker 1: Yes, go to front row crew comm and on the right side of the page You're gonna scroll down and there's a big.
Speaker 1: there's a black Rectangle and it says send me an audio and it's got a little pink thing in it.
Speaker 0: if he can't find it If nothing else think of it.
Speaker 0: this way we get enough email now to where.
Speaker 0: while we read all of it We by far do not have the time to respond to all of it.
Speaker 1: Yeah It's like a lot of times I see an email and I go man I'm gonna reply to that but then I don't and it goes down by gmail and I forget about it.
Speaker 1: I don't put a star next to it or anything.
Speaker 0: So if you send us an audio, that'll really stand out from the pack.
Speaker 0: Yeah, odios are hot and audio and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special.
Speaker 0: Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 1: Be sure to visit our website at www.front row crew comm.
Speaker 1: if you like our podcast, you'll love our forums.
Speaker 1: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 1: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com And if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 206-333-1537.
Speaker 0: Geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 1: Geek nights is recorded with absolutely no studio and no audience, but unlike those other talk shows.
Speaker 1: It's actually recorded at night.