Speaker 1: It's Wednesday June 28th, and this is geek nights.
Speaker 1: tonight We begin reviewing three experimental works by Osamu Tezuka the god of manga.
Speaker 1: Let's do this.
Speaker 1: I e means aid est.
Speaker 1: it is that is Eg you can say it.
Speaker 0: Oh, I don't know the Latin part.
Speaker 1: eg means what our ergo gratis?
Speaker 0: Yes, that's something like that.
Speaker 0: It means it is example exo exemplia gratis.
Speaker 1: There you go Yeah, not ergo gratis exemplia gratis, whatever.
Speaker 1: anyway people using those words incorrectly Bothers me almost as much as people typing Loose when they mean Lo se.
Speaker 0: you know what.
Speaker 0: it didn't bother me until a few days ago when I learned the difference.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's.
Speaker 0: I've been using them interchangeably and randomly for a long time and now I know that 99% of the time I want to use eg.
Speaker 1: Yeah, very rarely.
Speaker 1: Do you want to use ie?
Speaker 1: because it's usually easier to just say something equivalent in English yep Eg.
Speaker 0: now if I see some ie's where there should be eg's I'm gonna come down.
Speaker 1: Yeah, yep, all right.
Speaker 1: We just we were talking about that right before we started recording so I had to get it in.
Speaker 0: yep Yeah, yeah, yeah, it's Wednesday.
Speaker 1: It's anime day.
Speaker 1: Whoo we're gonna review some anime something crazy something We haven't done in a while
Speaker 0: whoa
Speaker 1: and like to say one because it's anime day and Jim vowels mentioned this to us a few Days ago, I would like to remind all of you out there who are considering going to Otakon that the discount or pre-registered Meaning you get a cheaper registration if you do it online ends on the 4th of July.
Speaker 0: So if between now and the 4th of July you go to the Otakon website and buy a ticket it will cost you $50.
Speaker 0: All right, yep, if you decide that you want to buy a ticket after the 4th of July it will cost you $60.
Speaker 0: I think.
Speaker 1: yeah plus keep in mind that by pre-registering you make the Otakon people's job a lot easier And you make your life much easier.
Speaker 0: yeah, it can and probably will sell out.
Speaker 1: plus I'll note I mean there were at least what like 10,000 people in line on Thursday Maybe slightly less than that last year for the pre pre-registration.
Speaker 1: Yeah that line blew.
Speaker 0: Yeah, so you want to pre-register and get there on Thursday to reduce stress worry and increase your fun.
Speaker 1: Plus you definitely want to be there Thursday for the pre Otakon geek nights pool party.
Speaker 1: of course You'll have to find it to actually go to it, but it we won't be hard to find.
Speaker 0: We will tell the cool people where it is.
Speaker 1: That's a big dichotomy.
Speaker 1: now if we forget to tell someone that we think is cool They're gonna think we don't think they're cool.
Speaker 0: Well.
Speaker 0: Let trust me if you meet us We will let you know if you are uncool.
Speaker 1: Yeah, we're gonna have a posse at Otakon with three S's You and why and an IG EG.
Speaker 0: well any you and a why?
Speaker 1: Talia yeah, all right, yeah, we got a bunch of news, and we were actually arguing about all this just before the show.
Speaker 0: Yeah, good job.
Speaker 0: All right.
Speaker 1: You can go first.
Speaker 0: So this is article.
Speaker 0: It's not really a news.
Speaker 0: and the new the article is titled is it illegal to describe the sporting event you're watching now?
Speaker 0: the short Answer from a legal perspective is yes Absolutely yes, it is illegal because the laws in this country You're screwed up and the sport companies such as Major League Baseball NBA NFL own Absolutely fucking everything that has to do with their sport.
Speaker 0: you can bet you can't even like take a picture of a football at a football game Without a belonging to the NFL.
Speaker 0: It's just insane.
Speaker 1: What's that boat?
Speaker 1: dad that son is a boat that is free broadcasting Major League Baseball with implied oral consent?
Speaker 1: But not written consent expressed.
Speaker 0: written.
Speaker 1: expressed written consent.
Speaker 0: yep.
Speaker 0: Then Major League Baseball has the satellites of evil.
Speaker 0: they're coming around.
Speaker 1: right that was a different episode.
Speaker 0: But yeah the thing is I see that two possibilities for the future and this guy who writes this article sees the same thing.
Speaker 0: kind of.
Speaker 0: either Sports will open up and allow you know Amateurs and people like us to create content around their sport freely or those sports will Gradually fade away and people lose interest in them.
Speaker 1: now consider that I mean the way it is now.
Speaker 1: They make their money off of people coming to the place and buying a lot of beer and soda and tickets.
Speaker 0: they make money from TV and they make money from merchandise and of course advertising which is rolled into TV but also on the game itself they have and at the stadium yeah and food at the stadium and Parking at the stadium.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they make money in a whole jillion ways.
Speaker 1: now There are a whole bunch of laws in place in addition to our standard intellectual property stuff to prevent people from bootlegging broadcasting or in any way doing anything with the sport.
Speaker 1: So if you bring a camera to a baseball game and you film it it is so illegal to show that to anyone.
Speaker 0: Yeah, you might notice that on YouTube.
Speaker 0: You don't see too many sporting videos.
Speaker 0: I mean on Google video There's a lot of soccer stuff, but have you seen a lot of MLB stuff?
Speaker 1: Nope, the best you'll find are hockey fights.
Speaker 1: In fact, I suggest right now type quote hockey space fights Pluralized unquote into Google video and watch everything that comes up or YouTube.
Speaker 1: Yeah, either one, but I digress.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the point is is that right now there are a lot of podcasts and video not so much video podcasts out there For lesser-known or less popular sports that are gaining a lot of support for those sports.
Speaker 1: Also, there are a lot of people who just enjoy announcing sports games or they like to sit and talk about sports so they'll watch a hockey game and Record a podcast where they just do the play-by-play.
Speaker 0: and there are a lot of people out there who might not like particular sportscasters and you don't really have a much choice of which sportscaster to listen to.
Speaker 0: so They will rat they will opt to rather to turn off the audio or listen to the radio on there instead, you know in addition to the television with a device that delays the audio or delays the video to make them match up or They just won't have any announcing at all.
Speaker 0: because it's so painful because the announcers is so terrible now.
Speaker 1: bear in mind that right now Even though this is not a mass market.
Speaker 1: I mean, this is amateur to amateur.
Speaker 1: I think the article even uses those words.
Speaker 1: It does indeed amateur people creating content giving it to other amateur content creators who are also consumers Mm-hmm, and even now the industry is bit by bit realizing they don't like this one bit.
Speaker 0: well, look at this.
Speaker 0: Formula One is I think is the best example and it's one of my current favorite sports and mostly because of this podcast Formula pod.
Speaker 0: it's just two guys who live in the United States where Formula One is not very popular at all.
Speaker 0: It's hardly known at all in this country, but it is the premier motorsport in the entire world.
Speaker 1: Hell you want to know how obscure it is.
Speaker 1: when I worked at IBM there was a guy who raced cars professionally and semi-professionally.
Speaker 1: He didn't watch f1 at all.
Speaker 1: He knew nothing about it.
Speaker 1: He didn't care about it in any way shape or form Yep.
Speaker 0: However, it is crazy popular in places like Spain where the current world champion is from.
Speaker 1: damn you Alonzo just explode already.
Speaker 1: I know seriously Racketing was so close.
Speaker 0: It's so close yet so far anyway Formula pod are these two guys who talk about f1 and They get a lot of listeners and they got a big forum and then they even have all kinds of crazy stuff.
Speaker 0: They teamed up with GP tours, which is a company that you know Is a tourist company that will take you to f1 races for and has parties at f1 races where drivers go and they arranged a?
Speaker 0: Whole party at the US Grand Prix Grand Prix Grand Prix.
Speaker 0: and they got a huge sponsor.
Speaker 0: I think it's I forget the name.
Speaker 0: It's some international travel insurance company is sponsoring these podcast guys I don't know.
Speaker 1: all I can think of are all the sponsors.
Speaker 1: I keep seeing it f1.
Speaker 0: Yeah Petronas no, no, no, it's.
Speaker 0: it's.
Speaker 0: I think it's international Multinational underwriters is their sponsor.
Speaker 1: What are you doing?
Speaker 1: giving them free advertising on geek night?
Speaker 0: I guess no one here.
Speaker 0: It really needs to buy travel insurance.
Speaker 1: watch like ten people immediately going.
Speaker 0: Oh, I need a travel insurance shit.
Speaker 1: Yeah, okay Yeah, we're just kind of we're so anti advertising that yeah any amount of advertising.
Speaker 0: But the thing with Formula One is it is the best example of a sport that keeps everything close to the chest.
Speaker 0: it prides itself on being ultra ultra ultra exclusive Ultra exclusive.
Speaker 1: they sell you the idea of going to f1 is like this big thing and it's this.
Speaker 0: yes It's like this big pomp and royalty ancient tradition big fancy.
Speaker 0: I mean these guys race in Monaco with princes.
Speaker 0: It's crazy.
Speaker 1: There's more fanfare about f1 at f1 than there is at Wimbledon.
Speaker 0: Yeah It's just insane.
Speaker 0: and they don't.
Speaker 0: they don't give up the rights to a damn thing.
Speaker 0: They don't give up a dollar.
Speaker 0: the agreement the the Concord agreement that keeps f1 together is a secret.
Speaker 0: It's so Snobby, it's insane.
Speaker 1: and I would submit I have absolutely no evidence whatsoever to back this up that the fact that F1 races are now trivially pirated and available on the internet right after the races has greatly increased American watching.
Speaker 0: Well, no, there's only about 300 people download those things.
Speaker 1: Oh, how do you know that?
Speaker 0: Where do you look at the bit torrent stats?
Speaker 1: Oh, yeah, I didn't even know where you got them.
Speaker 1: They just appeared periodically and you turn them on.
Speaker 0: Yeah bit torrent stats Oh, okay, cuz it's it's on speed TV, which is and it's also on CBS.
Speaker 0: So here's where I get all the examples, you know, what 300 is a big increase.
Speaker 0: Yeah number one You've got a sport that's ultra exclusive and no one can get access to the sport.
Speaker 0: number two You've got a podcast which is very popular and is bringing together people who enjoy this sport in a in a country where the sport Is not popular and is increasing popularity.
Speaker 0: of the sport number three you've got a sport where when it's this sport is shown in America on speed TV and CBS.
Speaker 0: four races a year are on CBS and the announcers on CBS are God awful and know what they're talking about.
Speaker 0: They're god-awful.
Speaker 0: everyone hates it when the race is on CBS because the announcers are so piss piss shit poor Like they just they really imagine watching a commentary in any sport.
Speaker 1: If you don't like sports just make up a sport and imagine a guy who doesn't know the rules and has no idea what's going On just kind of trying to talk.
Speaker 0: Imagine a guy commentating Mario and it's like up.
Speaker 0: Mario jumped on the goomba.
Speaker 0: that gets you a hundred points and he doesn't die.
Speaker 0: Yeah, if you run into the side of that goomba, you can explode and you'll lose a life.
Speaker 1: Whoa two goombas in a row.
Speaker 0: Whoa, oh, he double jumped.
Speaker 0: He gets more points for doing that.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: I heard a man died trying to double jazz.
Speaker 0: Listen, that's watching formula one on CBS.
Speaker 0: It's terrible.
Speaker 0: So Amateur to amateur, you know creations of commentary and other sorts of sport related, you know arts and videos and audios and Creative works can is is only serves to boost the sport.
Speaker 0: It's the only purpose it has.
Speaker 0: so if sports continue to be exclusive and Go after people who try to make amateur, you know creative works from the sport those sports over the long run are going to be hurting and the other sports that allow this shit to go on are going to be Boomin.
Speaker 1: now, of course don't think we're like crazy idealists who have no idea how the real world works.
Speaker 1: when we say long term We mean like 20 years.
Speaker 0: Well, maybe 10 maybe 10 maybe 10 years sounds right.
Speaker 0: 20 years too long.
Speaker 1: Ah, you see it really depends on how much of our generation stays this way when they get crushed by the reality of an evil world.
Speaker 0: Yep, I see f1 though, you know becoming if the 2008 rules cuz f1 has a problem with the rules I just wrote about on my blog.
Speaker 0: But if the 2008 rules for f1 results in an exciting race Then I can really see f1 s popularity going up a little bit at least to the same Popularity is like Indian kart racing is in the u.s.
Speaker 1: Plus, I mean outside of the south and I'm not to really disparage NASCAR, but there is a very negative Negative kind of connotation around anything involving NASCAR particularly to people in the north and in urban areas,
Speaker 0: yeah, well the thing about NASCAR is that as A thing that gets people excited and you know makes itself interesting and markets itself.
Speaker 0: Well NASCAR is perfect because they did exactly the same thing.
Speaker 0: pro wrestling does but as a sport NASCAR is piss-poor.
Speaker 0: There's no it's whoever has the best car wins the end.
Speaker 1: but there are people who would like racing or like racing but They don't want to watch NASCAR either because they don't like it or they don't want to be associated with it.
Speaker 1: And a lot of these people I think if they saw f1 actually saw it instead of just hearing about it or not hearing about it They'd probably really like it.
Speaker 0: the thing about all About sports is that number one?
Speaker 0: You can't enjoy is watching a sport unless you know the rules.
Speaker 0: if you watch a game of baseball and you don't know the rules Then like a guy hits a home run you're not excited because you don't realize the meaning of it.
Speaker 1: You know, of course, you don't need to know all the rules.
Speaker 0: No, you don't.
Speaker 0: I don't know all the rules of f1.
Speaker 0: They're crazy, you know.
Speaker 1: like even baseball you need to know about the crazy pop-fly stuff or what happens when like the pitch hits a Bird.
Speaker 0: Yeah, that's just interesting.
Speaker 1: when you find it out when it happens strangely or like hockey All you need to know is that they're trying to get the pucks in the nets.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and then you'll learn over the course of time.
Speaker 0: Oh, you can hit them but you can't hit them that way.
Speaker 1: if you do that Put you in the box two minutes.
Speaker 1: you have to sit in the.
Speaker 0: yeah I guess you kind of have to know about power plays to really enjoy hot You know what?
Speaker 1: If you see one power play you figure it out.
Speaker 0: Oh that got that team has more guys now But it's the more you understand a sport the more you are interested in it.
Speaker 0: So and that's something else is that f1 if you just watch it or not even NASCAR?
Speaker 0: there is stuff to NASCAR People.
Speaker 0: if you watch NASCAR and you just you know, no matter you've never seen it before in your life on the surface it is a bunch of cars driving in a circle.
Speaker 0: that is what it is.
Speaker 0: and but if you come to understand You know the strategies of NASCAR the pit strategies the mechanics the you know The way you drive NASCAR drafting and then you know teaming up and passing guys and all this sort of stuff It becomes more interesting.
Speaker 0: you understand the strategies that are being carried out and f1 is the same way.
Speaker 0: If you just watch it and you don't try to learn anything about it, it won't ever be interesting to you.
Speaker 0: But if you go and put in a tiny effort just pay attention to what some guys are saying about it It will become very very interesting because it's very complex and serious and there's a lot going on That's not visible to the eyeball in plain sight without someone pointing it out to you.
Speaker 0: And that is why Creative amateur works usings about sports are very good because those guys point the stuff out to you And make the sport more interesting.
Speaker 0: and the sport doesn't do it on its own.
Speaker 1: Yep, I mean a hockey announcer isn't gonna stop and say a power play is when blah blah blah He just starts screaming and you have no idea why.
Speaker 0: yep Now the f1 announcers actually on speed TV I say are terrific because not only do they you know When the race is just kind of going and nothing exciting is happening.
Speaker 0: They teach you all kinds of stuff about tires and aerodynamics that you don't really know.
Speaker 1: They're also funny.
Speaker 0: They're also funny and you know If you watch a game say between the Mets who are really good this season and I don't know the Kansas City Royals are always Terrible, I don't think they're gonna play against each other, you know this year because it's interleague But you know, let's say you see that game.
Speaker 0: The announcers will never say anything like haha the Royals suck They're gonna get their asses kicked but the f1 announcers are like team super gurry.
Speaker 0: They're terrible.
Speaker 0: Wow, they can't drive.
Speaker 0: Oh look, they're out of the race again.
Speaker 1: Oh, well All right, though, I think we should pry nix the sports.
Speaker 1: we've talked about him for a while and it is anime day.
Speaker 1: It is anime day now since we went long on that because we got on a sports tangent.
Speaker 1: I'll be real quick about this because you've seen this in the news.
Speaker 0: I'm gonna drag it out.
Speaker 1: I don't need to explain this to anyone but the CCC BDA 2006 the communications comma consumers choice and broadband deployment act of 2006 which is the current acronym soup bad legislation Has passed committee in the Senate and it's going to be voted on now.
Speaker 1: real briefly This law is a lot.
Speaker 1: is this law which brings the broadcast flag back?
Speaker 1: Which is that bad thing that prevents you from recording shows from the TV?
Speaker 0: So if this law passes TVs everywhere will be broken.
Speaker 1: Okay next now it also has this other law the safety something wrapped into it and all these other riders and the law also Basically gives the giant dog dick to net neutrality, which is a topic we've talked about at least twice in the past.
Speaker 1: It's the real.
Speaker 1: briefly This is the idea that an ISP like Comcast has the right and in fact the duty to charge Google Money for allowing Google access to their subscribers Because otherwise Google and Yahoo and all those people are getting a free ride on their hard work and their cables Even though they're selling the bandwidth and that's all they sell.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but we're not gonna argue about that.
Speaker 1: It's a bad thing.
Speaker 1: No one who knows anything about technology disagrees on this point.
Speaker 0: This is a bad bad law.
Speaker 0: So we need to call them senators and say wow, you're dumb.
Speaker 0: You don't know anything about technology.
Speaker 1: vote No, I mean, I'm not even kidding.
Speaker 1: among Technological professionals there is no debate on this topic.
Speaker 1: The only people in the entire world who are advocating an end to net neutrality are the heads of ISPs.
Speaker 1: Big ISPs little ISPs want net neutrality and Politicians who were paid by big ISPs.
Speaker 0: That's it.
Speaker 1: go to like open secrets or something.
Speaker 1: You can look at exactly which senators Comcast gave a bunch of money to and then you can look at which senators are pro this and which senators are against this and the results are enlightening and Obvious.
Speaker 1: Yeah, but anyway I normally don't tell people things like this because a million other people do.
Speaker 1: but call your senator write to your senator.
Speaker 0: Go to the EFF website is probably something you can do there.
Speaker 1: Just tell him that the CCC BDA is a bad thing because it is very bad.
Speaker 1: granted to play devil's advocate I love for shit like this to be passed.
Speaker 0: Yeah Cuz when it gets passed it's like the flag burning.
Speaker 0: if it gets passed we can burn flags.
Speaker 0: if this gets passed we can break The broadcast flag only that.
Speaker 1: but the more legislation passes that is just bad and actually takes DRM and shoves it in people's Faces.
Speaker 1: and the more people have to deal with this the more angry they're getting yet.
Speaker 1: and there's a chance a small chance that Eventually, they'll get angry enough to do something.
Speaker 0: The problem is they do it so gradually that no one you know notices they have.
Speaker 0: we have to get them to pass a law.
Speaker 0: That's so drastic that people will get pissed off.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I just fear a future when I'm an old man and I have a DVD and kids say what the hell How are you playing that you don't have those chips in your eye?
Speaker 1: We've got as the music told you things of the day Things of the day and they're both dancing related and one of them is anime related.
Speaker 0: Oh, I love dancing things of the day so much.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you can do yours first.
Speaker 0: Mine is a video that is from the Chicago Breakdancing champion contest of some year.
Speaker 0: I don't know.
Speaker 0: It's just some really cool breakdancing.
Speaker 1: It's a highlights reel.
Speaker 1: It's it's awesome.
Speaker 0: It's very awesome breakdancing video.
Speaker 0: I love watching dancing of awesomeness, and this is awesome dancing.
Speaker 0: Wait for the guy with the broom, that's all I can say.
Speaker 0: Yeah, wait for the guy with the broom.
Speaker 0: He's awesome.
Speaker 1: Now, you know, I actually used to breakdance.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I'm sure.
Speaker 1: actually this is entirely true.
Speaker 1: However, the story I'm about to tell while entirely true will completely dissuade you from my breakdancing skills When I was young and when I young I mean like between the ages of four and six.
Speaker 1: I For some reason really liked breakdancing as a kid and my mom has videos to prove this That what I would do is I'd carry around like my I'd sit with my grandparents at these like outdoor markets and I'd sit up Behind them in the sidewalk and I'd put this piece of cardboard down and I'd play cassettes of music I'd like from my fisher-price tape player and I'd spin around on my butt and act like I was breakdancing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I've done a butt spin too.
Speaker 0: So I used to breakdance.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Well, there you go.
Speaker 1: If I ever find the videos or get my mom to send them to me I will put them on the website.
Speaker 0: I don't think rim breakdancing is something that is as cool as Professionals breakdancing.
Speaker 1: Nah, nah Nah My only real move was spin around on my butt or spin around on my knee and then fall and hurt myself.
Speaker 0: If I get the opportunity, I'm gonna try to take breakdancing lessons.
Speaker 1: Yeah, you do that.
Speaker 1: I'll take my motorcycle lessons.
Speaker 0: I'll take motorcycle breakdancing lessons.
Speaker 1: All right, anyway my thing because it's anime day is very anime related.
Speaker 1: it is a video Funky can't?
Speaker 1: maybe you might have seen why I don't know.
Speaker 1: I just found this kind of randomly not even linked to from us.
Speaker 1: I just don't it.
Speaker 1: I found it and it's basically this music video someone made.
Speaker 1: I have no idea who or why.
Speaker 1: I did absolutely no research.
Speaker 1: It is cel-shaded 3d and it is kind of like Michael Jackson's thriller.
Speaker 0: only it Obviously steals from thriller a lot.
Speaker 1: only it's all these girls who get turned into cat girls by aliens and they dance.
Speaker 1: And there's two girls who weren't turned into cat girls and they're chasing them.
Speaker 1: and it's adorable and simultaneously hilarious.
Speaker 0: Simultaneously awesome dancing.
Speaker 1: Yeah the dancing.
Speaker 1: I mean, it's really high quality even to the point It's not as good as the breakdancing in mind thing of the day.
Speaker 1: The thing I like about it is that there's all like the supporting dancers in the back and they're obviously all kind of time together.
Speaker 1: But it looks like whoever did it introduced some delay and some little variations.
Speaker 1: So it looks like a bunch of unique things dancing as opposed to a bunch of cloned 3d models dancing.
Speaker 0: That's cool.
Speaker 1: And the front it's really cool.
Speaker 1: Watch it.
Speaker 1: The music's cool.
Speaker 1: It's really weird.
Speaker 1: I will do a little bit of research and find out exactly what the hell this was at a later date.
Speaker 0: That's a good idea, but it's anime day.
Speaker 1: This is the first time in many weeks We've had a chance to sit down and review some anime.
Speaker 0: Mm-hmm now the anime we're gonna talk about is an anime that's kind of Weird for most people.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: It is actually three distinct shorts that we watched recently.
Speaker 0: Well, they're not so short one of them They're all.
Speaker 0: they're basically movies of varying length.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Well one is a short definitely.
Speaker 0: Yeah, well, it's a short movie as opposed to a full-length movie.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it was like two minutes long though.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's true.
Speaker 0: Anyway, Osamu Tezuka is the god of manga the god the god undisputed.
Speaker 0: It's not like, you know, you know, some people say oh so and so is the god of rock.
Speaker 0: No, so-and-so is the god of rock.
Speaker 0: No Osamu Tezuka is the undisputed god of manga.
Speaker 0: period the end of the story.
Speaker 0: If you haven't read his manga, you should go to the store now and buy Buddha and Phoenix right now.
Speaker 0: Go do that.
Speaker 1: I haven't even actually read him though.
Speaker 1: I'm going too soon.
Speaker 0: Yes He also invented Astro Boy and you know the first, you know, it spawned.
Speaker 0: every anime you've got now Came out of Astro Boy somehow which came out of Mickey Mouse and now the anime is feeding back into the American Animation.
Speaker 0: so it was American animation Japanese animation stole and now it's getting put back in it's crazy loop.
Speaker 1: now It's all because of Osamu Tezuka and we could do a whole show on him which we might someday.
Speaker 1: But today we just want to talk about three of these short film slash movies that he did over a long period of time.
Speaker 0: Yeah between the years of what 1962 and 1988 something like that something like that.
Speaker 0: He created five or so experimental sorts of animations for film festivals and other things.
Speaker 1: they very Wildly, they do very wildly.
Speaker 0: but and the the art style doesn't even look like it's from him.
Speaker 0: It looks just like really old Animation that you would see on super late night TV in America.
Speaker 0: But you know once you watch it and you realize what's going on.
Speaker 0: It definitely carries his mark very brightly.
Speaker 1: Yes, especially the last one we're gonna talk about the tales of a street corner.
Speaker 1: Yes Basically just like up.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: There is yep.
Speaker 1: That's he always talks about war up there.
Speaker 0: Yep, so all of these things were on bit torrent.
Speaker 0: luckily, you know, we're linking to that Yeah, and I got three of them and we watched them.
Speaker 0: And so let's talk about the first one which is the shortest called male Ma le.
Speaker 1: now it's very unique very.
Speaker 1: it's very like art film or the kind of thing You see at a film festival or at a student art festival.
Speaker 1: It's very short It's very to the point is a very distinct point that it makes through a very Yes, interesting method.
Speaker 1: Mmm, actually a lot of our friends we showed us who didn't like it Which surprised me because I thought it was very well done.
Speaker 0: I thought it was incredibly well done.
Speaker 0: clever unique.
Speaker 0: Poignant I think is a good word.
Speaker 1: Yeah I'm not sure if we should ruin what it's actually about or not because it's so short.
Speaker 1: There was no reason for any of you to not watch this.
Speaker 0: Yes Let's just talk about a little bit.
Speaker 0: there's this.
Speaker 0: it's a black screen and Everything that happens is sort of like the you know is like searchlights sort of light up different parts of the screen Allowing you to see what's going on.
Speaker 0: You know, what's going on over here?
Speaker 0: What's going on over there?
Speaker 0: You know just you know a little bit at a time, you know, you can hear voices you can see you know, the white eyeball with the black background to see where characters are and what they're doing and You figure out really quickly.
Speaker 0: it's about this guy Who is waiting for something or you know, he's doing some stuff not talking much.
Speaker 0: yeah, all the talking is done by his cat and the cat is Down on the bottom left of the screen and the man is on the right side of the screen And the cat is saying all sorts of stuff like, you know I'm trying to get on with my cat woman here
Speaker 1: and there's a. there's a cute female cat right down there with it.
Speaker 0: The cute female cat doesn't talk either but the male cat is trying to get with the female cat and the male human being is You know, he's sitting on the right side of the screen being a you know, a person.
Speaker 0: he's bothering the male cat He's trying to be all romantic and the cat is complaining about this guy.
Speaker 0: and then there's some twists.
Speaker 0: Yeah, then it's over cuz it's real short
Speaker 1: cuz bit by bit It reveals more and more and then it resolves and then the at the very end if you haven't figured out what's going on Which we didn't obviously the spotlight pulls back and you see the whole screen and you see what happened and it's
Speaker 0: you go.
Speaker 1: Oh I'd like to talk about what I think it's saying But I really really don't want to spoil it for all of you out there.
Speaker 0: We can make a spoiler line But then we couldn't.
Speaker 0: then people might stop listening and won't go to the rest of the show.
Speaker 1: You know what?
Speaker 1: next week or a couple weeks from now after we've watched the rest of these We will talk about this again because I'd like to talk about it in more detail.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I once again all of you out there if you have any way to do so download at least that one male It's very short and watch it.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: I can't recommend it enough.
Speaker 0: All right, the next Sony watch which was a middling length was mermaid.
Speaker 1: This was in a completely different style completely different.
Speaker 0: It was very like sketchy and Transparent and just yet like some characters were just outlines and you could see right through them.
Speaker 0: You know, you know what the animation quality reminds me of like those old Alvin and the Chipmunks type of cards We're talking that animation that old but a little bit higher quality than that, but the same style, you know Like old Alvin the not Alvin and the Chipmunks for the 80s old Alvin and the Chipmunks the original real deal.
Speaker 1: Now this one and also the third one we're going to talk about are interesting in that there are no words.
Speaker 1: No one speaks.
Speaker 0: yes in in male the cat is the only one who talks but This in the rest the other two we're going to talk about.
Speaker 0: there is no talking No dialogue whatsoever.
Speaker 1: No fansub needed And in fact it.
Speaker 1: if you just showed this to some small off the street or even some anime fan I doubt highly that anyone would say.
Speaker 1: Oh, that's anime It's you.
Speaker 0: when you see Tezuka's logo, you know his sort of brand, you know that little face He draws and everything.
Speaker 0: if you saw that and you knew then you would know.
Speaker 0: and if you were really knew Tezuka's writing style Then you might be able to know.
Speaker 0: but other than that you'd might have a hard time unless you just knew beforehand already.
Speaker 1: Now I got this one's very good.
Speaker 1: It's just.
Speaker 1: it's the story about a boy and he finds the thing.
Speaker 0: He's a man.
Speaker 1: It's I think it's hard to tell is a guy.
Speaker 1: yeah, this is guy and he finds this fish is a little fishy and he saves it and The fishy.
Speaker 1: he likes the fishy the fishy Becomes a mermaid.
Speaker 1: Whoo-hoo He falls in love and there's this whole thing.
Speaker 1: But then he like he brings her home and he's all excited and he shows he has the fishy and he shows it to his Mom and his parents.
Speaker 1: Yeah, he was a kid because he shows it to his parents.
Speaker 1: That's right and the parents look at it and we watch this actually many weeks ago.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't remember it that clearly.
Speaker 1: Well, he shows it to him and they see a fish but then he looks and he sees the mermaid.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and his parents like you're crazy whatever and it just keeps spiraling like he gets sent But the government is testing him because there's something wrong with him.
Speaker 1: He's he's a delinquent He's insane, but he like he sees the mermaid But they all see the fish and they there's all this interesting dialogue where there's no noise or anything but the like.
Speaker 1: the special secret police officers will have a Speech bubble that shows like a fish and then his will show a mermaid and theirs will show a fish with like an explanation Exclamation point and then his will show the mermaid again and then they throw him in a cell and they inject drugs into him and All this stuff.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's sort of clockwork orangey a little bit.
Speaker 0: Yeah, and you know, they thought they think someone's insane and they're reconditioning him kind of to fit.
Speaker 0: and you know Cuz no one else agrees with them.
Speaker 1: but yeah but also a little tiny bit of 1984 is kind of.
Speaker 1: the government is coming in and preventing this kid from doing what he was doing.
Speaker 0: or yeah how they you know the evil Adult society is stomping all over the imagination of the children Looking at it as insanity rather than is, you know a good thing.
Speaker 1: and there's this terrible and by terrible I mean very just depressing scene where he's locked in this cell and they're torturing him.
Speaker 1: like Every time he thinks of the mermaid they torture him and I mean the animation is very simple, but you get the idea You know what's going on.
Speaker 1: and every time he thinks of the mermaid as he's tortured more and more He can remember less and less of her until eventually all he remembers is the fish.
Speaker 1: And then he finally they let him out and he goes home and he has the fish and he looks at her and he just sees a fish.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's just really kind of sad.
Speaker 0: It is kind of sad You know, I don't know if I agree with the message, but it's still really good.
Speaker 1: Yes Well, I don't.
Speaker 0: I can get enjoyment of things that have messages that I don't agree with a hundred percent Because that isn't the end.
Speaker 0: that's not the end.
Speaker 1: it keeps going.
Speaker 1: I don't know if I want to spoil this one either.
Speaker 0: I don't think we should.
Speaker 0: but after the guy goes home and sees just the fish There is a another poignant ending.
Speaker 1: It's well, I Recommend it again.
Speaker 1: You really should just watch this.
Speaker 1: I this is very well done.
Speaker 1: It's it makes a number of points a number of very classic Tezuka points.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 0: Yep All right.
Speaker 0: The last one we watched is Tales of a street corner.
Speaker 1: It's probably my favorite and also the I guess the longest and most interesting of the three we watched also the most well-animated.
Speaker 0: It is the most well animated.
Speaker 0: This is more animated more like Even though there's not much actual animation going on and much of it No, there were a lot of.
Speaker 0: it is just like, you know, it's still thing where one thing is moving.
Speaker 0: This is more like Scooby-doo quality though Except for that guy's feet.
Speaker 0: Oh Yeah, there was a guy who had like the best animated feet I've ever seen like seriously it right out of like cowboy bebop quality.
Speaker 1: This is just like the most perfectly animated set of army boots walking I've ever seen in my life.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I don't know what it was, but it was just so well done As soon as it happened, it stood out so much from everything else.
Speaker 1: It must have been animated on ones.
Speaker 0: Who knows.
Speaker 1: Anyway, yeah, give us a little bit of knowledge about animation will go nuts.
Speaker 0: Yeah, right So easy to see tales of a street corner is about the story of a street corner.
Speaker 0: all the events take.
Speaker 0: It's all these events taking place on the corner of a street in what must be France or somewhere like that.
Speaker 1: Yeah, it's France.
Speaker 0: I'm reasonably certain it's probably France, but it could be anywhere.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it doesn't really matter But it's France for the most part.
Speaker 1: now as it opens It introduces kind of randomly a whole bunch of completely disparate characters.
Speaker 0: Yeah, it's like as in the opener, which is the credits going by and everything.
Speaker 0: They say.
Speaker 0: here are the characters, you know the balloon the mouse the light the Violin man the army man the girl that you know the moth and it says a little bit about G for them Like the moth is like a local troublemaker or something like that.
Speaker 0: Yep They tell.
Speaker 0: it tells you all who all the characters are and what they're like.
Speaker 1: and think about this cast of characters.
Speaker 1: you've got a poster a tree a light bulb a moth a Little girl's bear and a rat a mouse all kinds of crazy stuff.
Speaker 1: It's all the stuff That's on the street corner and the characters all just come out and have their bit and go away in order But they don't completely go away and the stories all kind of intertwine, but they all don't directly Intertwine with each other.
Speaker 1: It's like there's just all this stuff happening.
Speaker 0: at the beginning It looks like it's gonna be a chain Like you start with one character you go to the next you go to the next you go to the next and they get to The last character and it's over.
Speaker 0: but that's not what it is.
Speaker 0: You know It doesn't just go through all the characters in a chain and then end.
Speaker 0: it goes through some characters then goes back then includes some New ones and goes back and it it Mills about you know cycling through everything That's going on in the street corner as the events take place and as time goes on over the course of what a night Or two.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I think it's just one day.
Speaker 1: I think it is just one day though It does kind of fast forward but it's it's hard to explain.
Speaker 0: really it really doesn't matter.
Speaker 0: You can't assign any strict Chronology to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and it's the basic plot is that it starts out with this girl and she has a balloon or something.
Speaker 1: She drops her teddy bear.
Speaker 0: Oh, there's a balloon outside her window and when she's trying to get it, right?
Speaker 0: Yep, and she drops the teddy bear into the gutter the rain gutter out on the roof.
Speaker 1: now That's it that she said and she wants it back but there's no way she can get it back.
Speaker 1: and then there's a little mousie finds the bear and he thinks it's awesome and she keeps throwing little bits of cheese to feed her stuffed bear because he's stuck out there alone and The mouse is like yes cheese.
Speaker 1: And then he runs back in with all his mouse brothers and they end up destroying the nest.
Speaker 1: and he gets in trouble and kicked Out for a while by his parents.
Speaker 1: and there's this whole thing.
Speaker 0: Yep.
Speaker 1: Again.
Speaker 1: No words.
Speaker 1: It's just action and music.
Speaker 0: There's a lot of music.
Speaker 0: The music is real important in this.
Speaker 0: this.
Speaker 0: basically there's this one There.
Speaker 0: there are a lot of music did different songs in it, but there is one main Musical theme in it.
Speaker 0: I don't think that's what it is.
Speaker 1: Well, no, there's the clapping that goes in the background through the whole song.
Speaker 0: Well, the clapping I think is more like it's like a one two three One two three if I remember right now, it's just one two one two.
Speaker 0: I don't think we got to go listen to it.
Speaker 1: Yeah, I'm sure I was.
Speaker 0: that's not what I remember.
Speaker 1: I will bet money.
Speaker 0: Anyway, there's this main theme that begins playing at one point and you know it fade It cut it goes away and comes back and it changes Moods and it gets.
Speaker 0: you know, it's played happily It's played sadly slowly quickly with and without energy and it always matches what's going on.
Speaker 0: And you can basically if you just listen to that, you know The soundtrack to this you can tell what's going on the whole time think of it as like an early early early Interstellar five five five or like a Fantasia sort of thing.
Speaker 1: Yeah, in fact it and it starts out I mean the first half or so is like the mouse and then the moth and his Misadventures and the tree who is trying to spread his seed before he dies And all these well before the end of the season.
Speaker 1: Yeah, and all these characters interacting and just very animated and lively.
Speaker 1: It's humorous at times.
Speaker 1: It's sad at times.
Speaker 0: It's it goes all over the place and the main action I think really takes place on the wall.
Speaker 1: and it's interesting because once it starts focusing more on the wall itself and the posters The animation all but stops and you literally have scenes where it cuts to a poster of a man playing the violin.
Speaker 0: Then yeah, it's a wall on the side of a building with a bunch of advertising bills posted to it Just covering the whole thing and each different bill on the wall is You know what each advertisement is like a character in itself, you know.
Speaker 0: and they come and go.
Speaker 0: as you know ads are pasted over and Ads fall off the wall and new ads that come on the wall and empty spaces.
Speaker 1: Most of them are little two-frame things dancing along with the music Other than the majors posters the big characters which are an advertisement for a violinist.
Speaker 1: and it's this very Svelte looking violinist guy.
Speaker 0: He's like a cool awesome violin dude all suave an advertisement for a piano playing girl Which is yep, the conducting guy the conductor who was like he's like like the mayor of poster.
Speaker 0: Yeah, this is where the music that I was talking about before comes from.
Speaker 0: is these guys play it They're just posters on the wall.
Speaker 1: Now keep in mind that the character ones are really not animated so much.
Speaker 1: In fact the violinist and the Piano girl are never animated.
Speaker 0: their move very tiny bits I think the eyes move but they don't show it to you.
Speaker 1: They'll show you the poster and the faces changed a little bit, but they never show it to you changing.
Speaker 0: Yeah, they'll zoom in on it.
Speaker 0: They'll show you different angles on it.
Speaker 1: They're they're very poignant scenes where nothing happens.
Speaker 1: It just shows the guy and it's playing the music and you know exactly what that music means and what he's thinking.
Speaker 0: Emotion you see the violin guy and you hear the violin going like.
Speaker 0: You know violin and you know, the guy's all happy in violin.
Speaker 0: and then you hear the music like And you know that he's kind of you know trying to do something or that he's sad or you can tell what the violin guy.
Speaker 0: Everything he does comes out in the sound of the violin and nothing is about him is animated other than the still picture of his.
Speaker 1: And even when they change his face a little bit It's so subtle like they'll make him look a little angry or a little sad or a little determined.
Speaker 0: Yeah I'm not even sure if they actually do that or they do it so well But you can't tell if it's actually been changed or if it's just your mind.
Speaker 1: Yeah We really weren't sure and we didn't want to Rewind to find out because that really would have destroyed it for us a little bit maybe but I it was just there.
Speaker 1: they convey so much emotion and so much pathos in a character that never moves and Never speaks as literally just a two-dimensional poster stuck to a wall.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I mean you didn't even really have to have any animation.
Speaker 0: Just take a bunch of photographs and show one then show the other show one show the other and play music over the whole thing.
Speaker 1: Now up until this point, but there's also the slot.
Speaker 1: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the slot is a character.
Speaker 1: She's also a poster.
Speaker 1: She's a poster for some sort of body woman show.
Speaker 1: Yeah,
Speaker 0: you
Speaker 1: know dancing ladies cabaret kind of thing And she seems to like the violinist guy
Speaker 0: But then the piano girl comes along and she gets upset
Speaker 1: and the violinist guy seems to obviously Fall deeply in love with the piano girl and the the slutty woman as a result is trying to horn in But then the conductor stops her all without interacting in any direct way because
Speaker 0: these are just posters on a wall.
Speaker 0: Now all that comes out in music.
Speaker 1: Yep, and up until this point everything is kind of disparate.
Speaker 1: There's this all the individual stories.
Speaker 1: You know the mouse is a troublemaking mouse.
Speaker 1: with his million brothers and the exhausted mom and dad.
Speaker 1: The little girl is lost her teddy bear.
Speaker 1: The moth is just an evil prick who wanders around causing trouble for people.
Speaker 1: Yeah, the lamp is old and dying But he refuses for two for his light to fade and he's fighting to the end.
Speaker 0: the street lamp is We're using to let everything go dark and the moth is messing with him.
Speaker 0: Yeah, the moss screws at the street lamp and he screws with the tree who's trying to get his seeds planted before the next season.
Speaker 0: There isn't any dirt on the street so the The tree tries to get his seeds over to where the little patch of dirt is.
Speaker 0: Yep, and the the moth pretends to help but then actually just screws everybody All right now rather than spoil the rest of this thing I'm just gonna let you know that eventually this general an actual human being military guy.
Speaker 0: I'll call him the general.
Speaker 1: I'll call him captain boot McBoot.
Speaker 0: captain boot McBoot, you know, it's like a mean-looking Kaiser type of military guy.
Speaker 1: Yeah, well the thing is first off you don't see any actual people except for the tone.
Speaker 1: halfway through the tone of this animation changes completely and You see these boots these obviously World War one arrow army boots walking and Everything stops.
Speaker 1: and then he puts up this poster of this Kaiser looking general guy.
Speaker 1: It's obvious like war probably doesn't.
Speaker 0: he put it on top of some one of the existing pose.
Speaker 1: What's it over the conductor?
Speaker 0: That's right, the conductor goes away and all he gets replaced by this evil general and all the happy music stops and everything's different.
Speaker 0: suddenly yeah, and it goes from there and That is the point.
Speaker 1: I mean before that it's just a very good animation.
Speaker 1: But at this point it's the alright This is Tezuka.
Speaker 0: Yeah.
Speaker 0: Oh, we're trying to say war is bad blah blah blah, but not just that war is bad Not just that war it's not that simple.
Speaker 1: It's not just war is bad or Propaganda is bad or anything like that.
Speaker 1: It has a lot of complex both pro and anti war and pro and anti spirit.
Speaker 1: There's so much to it Mm-hmm.
Speaker 1: And again, we really can't ruin it.
Speaker 1: This is something that I really would like all of you to see.
Speaker 0: Yep But I'll tell the music is.
Speaker 0: actually I kind of want to get the soundtrack thing to it.
Speaker 0: Yes somehow You know, maybe maybe that you know who made that music.
Speaker 0: we should find that out.
Speaker 1: but just like there's the war poster and then it progresses and there are more posters and it's obvious that things are Militarizing and things are getting bad and then war actually breaks out like actual war but you don't actually see it.
Speaker 1: You just see the effects of it on all of these characters Yep, and then it ends in a way that you wouldn't expect and it really it's very thoughtful and poignant.
Speaker 0: The ending of it was really good actually, you know Yeah, because you fight every character has some sort of end and the fact that the whole time I'm thinking all right It's Tezuka.
Speaker 1: It's anti-war great.
Speaker 1: I figured it out This is still cool, but then it actually ended and it wasn't just anti-war.
Speaker 1: There was so much more there.
Speaker 0: Yep You know, it's like he does something different with each, you know I mean he could have done be just the anti-war if he just had the wall with the posters.
Speaker 0: but every different part of it had something different to say and do and Something different to show you and that's why there were so many different things and not just posters on the wall.
Speaker 1: And this is also something I would love to talk about on the show and we will do it the next time.
Speaker 0: we talk about These Tezuka animations after we watch the rest of them.
Speaker 0: Yes after we watch the rest of them and we maybe rim will read some Tezuka manga.
Speaker 1: Yeah Yeah, I'm in the middle of the difference engine.
Speaker 1: Give me a break whatever plus Scott Pilgrim.
Speaker 0: No, Scott Pilgrim takes two seconds to read a volume.
Speaker 1: Yes, but I have one in three and I don't have two.
Speaker 0: So just go buy it.
Speaker 1: I don't have time.
Speaker 1: Where am I gonna go?
Speaker 1: to a bookstore any bookstore?
Speaker 1: I'll probably get it at the show her maybe.
Speaker 1: But yeah these.
Speaker 1: we'll talk about these.
Speaker 1: well Basically what we'll do is we'll talk about the next two that we watch like we did just now.
Speaker 1: Then we'll have the spoiler line and we'll talk about all three of these animations again in excruciating meaningful detail.
Speaker 0: Yeah, cuz right now it's.
Speaker 0: I feel like we just gave Synopses of what they are and we didn't really and we said that they were great But we didn't really discuss.
Speaker 1: You know the meanings and the messages because you didn't want to spoil what went on and there's no way to even really allude to Without spoiling these things because the points hit home really hard.
Speaker 0: That's how it works and they're very good.
Speaker 1: I mean, I Don't know what else I can say.
Speaker 1: I can't recommend these more than I have.
Speaker 0: I can't recommend anything Osamu Tezuka has ever done.
Speaker 0: you know, I mean in my eyes there are two guys Osamu Tezuka and Will Eisner and those two guys are pretty much the only guys that were that good ever at.
Speaker 0: you know, comicking and such and Their works are actually very similar.
Speaker 0: and yet you should do everything you can to read and Ingest everything that has been created by Tezuka and or Eisner.
Speaker 1: Now moving on to the anime related meta bits since we can't talk about these animations anymore without spoiling them.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm one for all of you who are going to Otakon our geek nights live show Unless something changes will be at 10 a.m.
Speaker 0: On Sunday We don't know in one of the panel rooms.
Speaker 1: Yes, we don't know which panel room there will be flyers Everywhere.
Speaker 1: we will announce it multiple times on the show.
Speaker 0: Yep, just look at your Otakon schedule and it will say Podcasting panel in one of the panel rooms on Sunday at 10. in addition will be all over the con Doing interviews doing things and we will arrange probably all sorts of things at the con.
Speaker 0: right now This is all tentative.
Speaker 0: by the way, you know the Thursday pool party At some point, you know some board gaming.
Speaker 1: we're going to bust into the rave and bust up some ravers.
Speaker 1: Maybe I think we will.
Speaker 0: I will at least Of course the late night Saturday horrible movie.
Speaker 1: Yes.
Speaker 1: We want as much of a posse as we can possibly get.
Speaker 1: We're gonna make a ruckus.
Speaker 0: The musical guests who knows if we will enjoy them or not.
Speaker 0: We'll see.
Speaker 1: I think we will.
Speaker 0: I think we will The cosplay which you probably leaning towards not going to to enjoy the rest of the con while it's all empty and airy.
Speaker 1: Yep I want to send at least one geek nights correspondent or front row crew member in to see how the cosplay works in this newer in This new venue.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I am kind of curious.
Speaker 0: I'm thinking maybe what I'll do is I'll go to it for a port like the early part and then leave and Then you know before it's over.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Also.
Speaker 1: I want to plug while I'm here the fact that I'm also.
Speaker 1: There's not Scott just me and the other Scott are doing at what we've done for the past.
Speaker 1: God four years at Otacon and also at almost every other con.
Speaker 1: we've ever been to the anime club summit Which has gotten bigger and bigger over the years and it's at prime time like 1 30 in the afternoon on Saturday.
Speaker 0: So if you care about anime clubs running anime clubs If you're in an anime club, if you want to be in an anime club anything to do with anime clubs Go to the anime club summit.
Speaker 0: We'll be there for sure.
Speaker 0: We're always there at any con We go to all the time.
Speaker 1: I mean not to inflate our egos anymore But we're all really honestly pretty much experts at what it takes to run fan clubs Basically any kind.
Speaker 1: we just happen to have done it with anime Yeah and all the sorts of ramifications around that in social clubs and you know being a master of ceremonies and public speaking and all that and I think we put on a good show.
Speaker 0: So if you care about that or you just want to see us before Sunday and you couldn't find us by other means Anime club summit.
Speaker 1: Yep.
Speaker 1: Also last but not least anime world order our first friend podcast and also a very good anime podcast.
Speaker 1: They said some things we disagreed with on a recent episode and we have sent them some audio feedback some incredibly long audio feedback.
Speaker 0: What's long 16 minutes long something like that?
Speaker 1: I assume they'll edit it at least a little bit.
Speaker 0: I hope they'll edit it because if they play all 16 minutes of it, that's just being too insane except You know cuz they they go on forever.
Speaker 1: they do like two-hour shows.
Speaker 0: they can handle that they do Especially since they don't have to talk for those 16 minutes.
Speaker 0: But good God if we will be taking up like a significant like 5% of their show We're just us.
Speaker 1: if we did a once a week podcast.
Speaker 1: Good God.
Speaker 0: Oh god, it would be five hours long.
Speaker 1: It would also be like the most well researched crazy thing you could imagine.
Speaker 0: Oh god, maybe we should one week Just do one episode.
Speaker 1: That would be nuts.
Speaker 0: I would be not.
Speaker 1: that would have to be one hell of an episode.
Speaker 0: No, I imagine it would just be a bunch of episodes together with like five news is five things of the day each.
Speaker 1: We could just do an episode on like politics or something at that point.
Speaker 0: Yeah, I know I'm getting hiccups.
Speaker 0: It's time to end this episode.
Speaker 1: All right, but once again check out anime world order, especially we'll warn you again But we may or may not be appearing on it in non live form.
Speaker 0: Oh, oh tomorrow the episode of geek nights that we will record and air tomorrow is Going to be an ask rim and Scott anything episode.
Speaker 0: We've gotten a lot of questions already and we're getting more questions by the minute But the time is running out.
Speaker 0: submit your questions either at the front row crew forums at front row crew comm slash forum or Email us at geek nights at front row crew comm with your questions and we will answer them on the show tomorrow.
Speaker 0: You're running out of time to submit your questions and we've gotten a wide variety of interesting questions And there is also a possibility a pretty good possibility tomorrow that we are going to be on Ian Levinson's podcast talking about anime.
Speaker 0: next some more.
Speaker 1: Yep, now I'll note that we kind of made fun of him and his panel a little bit on our previous episodes But he's a cool guy.
Speaker 0: Yeah, he is a cool guy And I think his podcast is just called geek speak and I think it's geek speak geek comm if I recall correctly Speaking.
Speaker 0: Yeah, we'll let you know if and when that episode actually goes up if you want to hear us talk more about anime next on Someone else's show.
Speaker 1: and of course one tiny final bit.
Speaker 1: while we failed to interview Jim Vowels con chair of Otacon live He was gracious enough to answer many of the questions we and our listeners had in our forums.
Speaker 1: So you if you have any interest in what Jim Vowels the top dog for Otacon 2006 has to say and you haven't been to the forums yet go in.
Speaker 1: Read all the things he's written.
Speaker 1: He wrote a lot.
Speaker 0: He wrote a lot and it's very good Yep, and if we had interviewed him, he would have said a lot more.
Speaker 1: Yep Wait, and we're still gonna try to interview and we might have to wait until after Otacon is over for various reasons.
Speaker 0: I think after Otacon is over we're gonna get like the ultimate interview.
Speaker 0: That's what I'm thinking.
Speaker 1: I got a lot of asking.
Speaker 0: Oh, yeah, especially after Otacon.
Speaker 0: We'll just be adding questions to the list.
Speaker 0: Like how was the con?
Speaker 0: blah blah blah.
Speaker 0: What was your favorite thing at the con?
Speaker 0: anything crazy happened?
Speaker 0: You know, did you meet any cool guests?
Speaker 0: who was cool, etc, etc.
Speaker 1: plus also regarding the panel?
Speaker 1: We're doing a geek ed.
Speaker 1: got a geek nights at Otacon the podcasting geek nights panel.
Speaker 1: all you podcasters out there.
Speaker 1: Come to the panel and be in the audience and bring as many people as you can because one We're obviously gonna let other podcasters give shout outs, of course I mean obviously like what kind of assholes would it be to not?
Speaker 1: Yep, and to Podcasting isn't that big outside of podcasting?
Speaker 0: I know right.
Speaker 1: so get a crowd there.
Speaker 1: if we get a big enough crowd and people wonder what the hell's going on We'll all be able to promote podcasting as a media much more efficiently and we'll probably all get a bunch of new listeners.
Speaker 0: I think that's something that we'll talk more about at the panel itself.
Speaker 0: Is that Podcasting's most of its promotion seems to be promos which are played on other podcasts.
Speaker 0: people who aren't into podcasts at all don't get into them and all podcasts either seem to be You know podcasters themselves seem to be the biggest listeners and then there's listeners who listen to a bunch of podcasts.
Speaker 0: And then there are people who listen to just one podcast that has to do with their specific Interest and they don't listen to any other shows.
Speaker 1: or then there was me who did a crazy big Podcast in terms of quantity of episodes and didn't listen to anything.
Speaker 1: didn't listen to any podcast Other than two episodes of anime world order and one episode of artist alley until just now when I bought an iPod Until just now finally gonna have.
Speaker 0: but so if we get a lot of podcasters together at Otacon we can promote Podcasting as a whole and get people who know nothing about podcasting into podcasting.
Speaker 0: and of course and an anime con They're gonna want anime podcasts, which is us and you.
Speaker 1: Plus if we have a bunch of podcasters together after the panel No good can come of that and I think we will form a posse and go cause trouble somewhere.
Speaker 0: Yes We will definitely have the podcast posse of awesome and maybe have.
Speaker 0: maybe we should have like a podcast party or something.
Speaker 1: One of the members of anime world order is coming to Otacon.
Speaker 0: two of them I think are well.
Speaker 1: one of them is as his first Otacon.
Speaker 0: Oh, that's right.
Speaker 0: He's an Otacon virgin.
Speaker 0: Yeah So, uh, we hope to see you there and we will D virgin eyes you in horrid ways And we will show you the mighty ways of traversing the giant that is Otacon in an efficient and pleasurable manner.
Speaker 1: All right, I think we're done.
Speaker 1: we're done and that was geek nights with rim and Scott special Thanks to DJ pretzel for our opening theme.
Speaker 0: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontrowcrew.com.
Speaker 0: if you like our podcast you'll love our forums.
Speaker 0: Make sure you visit them.
Speaker 0: You can send your email feedback to geek nights at gmail.com and if you want you can leave us a voicemail at 1 5 3 7.
Speaker 1: geek nights airs every weeknight Monday through Thursday.
Speaker 0: Geek nights is accorded with absolutely no studio and no audience But unlike those other talk shows it's actually recorded at night.